<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>UFOs spotted off Irish coast under investigation</title>
<link>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-46181662</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-46181662</guid>
<description>&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape has-caption full-width lead&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                &lt;img class=&quot;js-image-replace&quot; alt=&quot;UFOs&quot; src=&quot;https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/320/cpsprodpb/1866B/production/_104274999_mediaitem84151821.jpg&quot; width=&quot;976&quot; height=&quot;549&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image copyright&lt;/span&gt;
                 &lt;span class=&quot;story-image-copyright&quot;&gt;Science Photo Library&lt;/span&gt;
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
            &lt;figcaption class=&quot;media-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image caption&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;media-caption__text&quot;&gt;
                    What did the pilots see off the coast of Ireland?
                &lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;story-body__introduction&quot;&gt;The Irish Aviation Authority is investigating reports of bright lights and UFOs off the south-west coast of Ireland.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It began at 06:47 local time on Friday 9 November when a British Airways pilot contacted Shannon air traffic control.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She wanted to know if there were military exercises in the area because there was something &quot;moving so fast&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The air traffic controller said there were no such exercises.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The pilot, flying from the Canadian city of Montreal to Heathrow, said there was a &quot;very bright light&quot; and the object had come up along the left side of the aircraft before it &quot;rapidly veered to the north&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She was wondering what it could be but said it did not seem to be heading for a collision.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another pilot from a Virgin plane joined in and suggested it might be a meteor or another object re-entering the earth's atmosphere.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape no-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
                 &lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image copyright&lt;/span&gt;
                 &lt;span class=&quot;story-image-copyright&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/span&gt;
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
        &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;He said there were &quot;multiple objects following the same sort of trajectory&quot; and that they were very bright.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The pilot said he saw &quot;two bright lights&quot; over to the right which climbed away at speed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One pilot said the speed was &quot;astronomical, it was like Mach 2&quot; - which is twice the speed of sound.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Following reports from a small number of aircraft on Friday 9 November of unusual air activity the IAA has filed a report,&quot; the Irish Aviation Authority (IAA) said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;This report will be investigated under the normal confidential occurrence investigation process.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A spokesperson for Shannon Airport said it would not be appropriate for the airport to comment while the IAA investigation is ongoing.&lt;/p&gt;
            </description>
<pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 23:49:04 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>dmmalam</dc:creator>
<og:title>Pilots report UFOs off Irish coast</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>The objects were said to be very bright and flying at twice the speed of sound.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.bbc.com/news/world-europe-46181662</og:url>
<og:image>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/1866B/production/_104274999_mediaitem84151821.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-GB</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-46181662</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Improving DuckDuckGo</title>
<link>https://duck.co/help/privacy/atb</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://duck.co/help/privacy/atb</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;At DuckDuckGo, we do not collect or share any personal information. That's our &lt;a href=&quot;https://duckduckgo.com/privacy&quot;&gt;privacy policy&lt;/a&gt; in a nutshell. For example, we do not store IP addresses, and we do not create unique cookies. As such, we do not even have the ability to create search histories or search sessions for any individual — privacy by design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time, we need a way to reliably improve our products for our users in an anonymous way. There are a few methods we've developed to achieve this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, you might notice that when you search DuckDuckGo, there may be an &quot;&lt;code&gt;&amp;amp;atb=&lt;/code&gt;&quot; URL parameter in the web address at the top of your browser. This parameter allows us to anonymously A/B (split) test product changes we make to DuckDuckGo. For example, users in the A group would get blue links and users in the B group would get red links, and we'd be able to measure how usage of DuckDuckGo is impacted by different color links.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, we measure engagement of specific events on the page (e.g. when a misspelling message is displayed, and when it is clicked). This allows us to run experiments where we can test different misspelling messages and use CTR (click through rate) to determine the message's efficacy. If you are looking at network requests, these are the ones going to the one-pixel image at &lt;code&gt;improving.duckduckgo.com&lt;/code&gt;. These requests are anonymous and the information is used only by us to improve our products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Third, you may notice similar &quot;&lt;code&gt;atb.js&lt;/code&gt;&quot; or &quot;&lt;code&gt;exti&lt;/code&gt;&quot; requests made by our browser extensions and mobile apps. These requests help us anonymously count how many devices are using an experience. For example, our browser extensions and mobile apps will only send one type of these requests a day, which means we can count approximately how many devices accessed DuckDuckGo without knowing anything about those devices or the searches they made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of these requests are all fully encrypted in transit to DuckDuckGo, such that nobody else but us can see them. And like with all other requests to DuckDuckGo, there is no personally identifiable information embedded in them, and we do not store IP addresses associated with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be clear, this means &lt;strong&gt;we cannot ever tell what individual people are doing since everyone is anonymous&lt;/strong&gt;, and that is a limit of our statistical methods since we are private by design. We can, however, within this anonymous limitation, reliably determine what changes are generally working, using these anonymous methods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have developed these systems from scratch, instead of using third-party services, because of our privacy promise to never collect or share any personal information. We're proud to be able to improve our site for you in a completely anonymous way!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any concerns, please feel free to reach out to us directly at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:privacy@duckduckgo.com&quot;&gt;privacy@duckduckgo.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 21:13:46 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>fghtr</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://duck.co</og:url>
<og:title>Improving DuckDuckGo</og:title>
<og:description>Learn more about DuckDuckGo and how to make the most of it.</og:description>
<og:image>https://duckduckgo.com/assets/logo_social-media.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://duck.co/help/privacy/atb</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>How to self-publish a book: A handy list of resources</title>
<link>https://blog.datascienceheroes.com/how-to-self-publish-a-book/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.datascienceheroes.com/how-to-self-publish-a-book/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Hello World!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;tl;dr: A list of useful resources aimed to self-publish a book on Amazon using Bookdown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Writing style&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Did I use any editor?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Marketing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to create the book: Bookdown!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Self-publishing on Amazon (Kindle and paperback)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Costs and earnings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Publishing outside Amazon: Gumroad&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Proofreading&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cover&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ISBN&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linking: B&amp;amp;W, color and Kindle on Amazon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;11-tips to write good&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update Ago-28-2018: I published &lt;a href=&quot;http://https://blog.datascienceheroes.com/how-to-self-publish-a-book-customizing-bookdown/&quot;&gt;another blog post&lt;/a&gt; related to this one, which contains more technical aspects of Bookdown.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A friend of mine told me to write down all the details about self-publishing a book.&lt;br/&gt;So here you go—a long post explaining almost all the things I have done and discovered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First of all, my thanks go to Bookdown. This R package allows enthusiastic people to self-publish a book! Although the book is based on R language, this process can be applied to any kind of book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kaylen Sanders from OpenDataScience.com did a poetic &lt;a href=&quot;https://opendatascience.com/the-open-source-project-data-science-live-book-is-now-available&quot;&gt;review of it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;theend&quot;&gt;The end&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two-year journey culminated with two paperback versions available on Amazon (Color and B&amp;amp;W), a Kindle version, an epub version, a PDF, and a &lt;a href=&quot;http://livebook.datascienceheroes.com&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/datascienceheroes.com/img/blog/dslb_2.gif&quot; title=&quot;plot of chunk unnamed-chunk-1&quot; alt=&quot;plot of chunk unnamed-chunk-1&quot; width=&quot;300px&quot;/&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;thestart&quot;&gt;The start&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn't plan to write a book. Around six years ago, I started using R and, as with many programmers, my &quot;personal&quot; library with many shortcuts began to grow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I thought that this library could help more people, so after arranging lots of things in the right place, I published the 'funModeling' package on CRAN in February 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google and the book &lt;a href=&quot;http://r-pkgs.had.co.nz/&quot;&gt;R Packages&lt;/a&gt; from Hadley Wickham (April 2015) were incredibly useful. Don't hesitate to check out that book if you plan to write a package.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/datascienceheroes.com/img/blog/01_r_packages.png&quot; title=&quot;plot of chunk unnamed-chunk-2&quot; alt=&quot;plot of chunk unnamed-chunk-2&quot; width=&quot;250px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;I deeply believe that when there is an explanation behind what we use and what we do, it changes the way we perceive the action. So, I started to document the funModeling package functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The documentation grew rapidly, and soon escaped from the original scope of the package to include general explanations of machine learning and data preparation, and then the first version of the book was born!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two months after the release, I rewrote everything from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two &lt;strong&gt;key points&lt;/strong&gt; here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;We don’t always we have a clear goal—we just &quot;walk&quot; and that goal takes shape.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The first version is not always the ultimate one; start now with the ideas you already have and let them grow.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;writingstyle&quot;&gt;Writing style&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to &quot;write everything I know&quot;—things that took me a lot of time to learn—and expose the concepts with examples, lots of examples, so the reader can check them and extract their own conclusions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other remarkable point was on 'how to interpret all the results.” I found that when someone explains the analytical thinking path, extracting different conclusions from the analysis; then the undersanding around the topic is boosted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These two books are aligned with the last idea:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/datascienceheroes.com/img/blog/02_dm_jiawei.png&quot; title=&quot;plot of chunk unnamed-chunk-3&quot; alt=&quot;plot of chunk unnamed-chunk-3&quot; width=&quot;250px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Data Mining: Concepts and Techniques 3rd Edition&lt;/em&gt; by Jiawei Han, Micheline Kamber and Jian Pei (2012)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/datascienceheroes.com/img/blog/03_dm_torgo.png&quot; title=&quot;plot of chunk unnamed-chunk-4&quot; alt=&quot;plot of chunk unnamed-chunk-4&quot; width=&quot;250px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Data Mining with R: Learning with Case Studies&lt;/em&gt; by Luís Torgo (2011)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: Data Science = Data Mining + some marketing ;) Nowadays: Data Mining = web scraping&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;didiuseanyeditor&quot;&gt;Did I use any editor?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nope, you can 100% self-publish a book on your own, with patience and the Amazon self-publishing service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Editors can help in the book structure, proofreading, marketing, printing, and distribution among others. It saves time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;marketing&quot;&gt;Marketing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A friend of mine surprised me with a Facebook ad campaign for the book when I launched it. Except from that, all marketing was done by word-of-mouth and some posts in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.datascienceheroes.com/&quot;&gt;Data Science Heroes Blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Would you share it? ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;howtocreatethebookbookdown&quot;&gt;How to create the book: Bookdown!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This amazing R package provides all the processes to create Kindle and paperback editions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get started with the minimum reproducible example at&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;https://bookdown.org/yihui/bookdown&quot;&gt;https://bookdown.org/yihui/bookdown&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/datascienceheroes.com/img/blog/05_bookdown_cover.png&quot; title=&quot;plot of chunk unnamed-chunk-5&quot; alt=&quot;plot of chunk unnamed-chunk-5&quot; width=&quot;250px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Data Science Live Book&lt;/em&gt; was 100% done using R and RStudio.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only Bookdown should be a BIG point in any &lt;em&gt;&quot;Why R?&quot;&lt;/em&gt; list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should google all of these terms before starting: Latex, Yaml, Knitr, R markdown, Pandoc, GitBook. None of them are Pokémon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check the RStudio lessons on what is R Markdown: &lt;a href=&quot;https://rmarkdown.rstudio.com/lesson-1.html&quot;&gt;https://rmarkdown.rstudio.com/lesson-1.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.datascienceheroes.com/content/images/2018/08/Screen-Shot-2018-08-25-at-19.13.40.png&quot; alt=&quot;R markdown workflow&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;selfpublishingonamazon&quot;&gt;Self-publishing on Amazon&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/datascienceheroes.com/img/blog/06_amazon.png&quot; title=&quot;plot of chunk unnamed-chunk-6&quot; alt=&quot;plot of chunk unnamed-chunk-6&quot; width=&quot;150px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Amazon runs a program called &lt;a href=&quot;https://kdp.amazon.com/&quot;&gt;Kindle Direct Publishing&lt;/a&gt; (KDP).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;publishingthepaperbackversion&quot;&gt;Publishing the paperback version&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You upload the PDF and Amazon will &lt;strong&gt;print on demand&lt;/strong&gt;. That's it. You don't have to invest any money to buy so many copies before the release. After you publish, if one person from the Antartida buys a copy, then it is printed and delivered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are other print-on-demand publishers, like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lulu.com/&quot;&gt;lulu.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I chose to have both versions: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/dp/9874269049&quot;&gt;Black &amp;amp; White&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/dp/9874273666&quot;&gt;Color&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The quality is excellent in both, but the color one is stunning! I see how colors help us to understand. However, the printing costs are around four times higher for this version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazon will check several layout points before approving the release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check the color version:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/datascienceheroes.com/img/blog/07_dslb.png&quot; title=&quot;plot of chunk unnamed-chunk-7&quot; alt=&quot;plot of chunk unnamed-chunk-7&quot; width=&quot;700px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;And one from the black and white:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/datascienceheroes.com/img/blog/08_dslb.png&quot; title=&quot;plot of chunk unnamed-chunk-8&quot; alt=&quot;plot of chunk unnamed-chunk-8&quot; width=&quot;700px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Note the quality of the plots and code layout —pretty important in a programming book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;publishingthekindleversion&quot;&gt;Publishing the Kindle version&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Easier to publish than the paperback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Kindle version of the Data Science Live Book, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/dp/9874273666&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Amazon is incredibly vast, from printing-publishing books to host deep learning processes in AWS. Someday, Amazon and Google will be countries.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You won't become rich publishing books unless you have a catchy title, like &quot;Fifty Shades of Data in Grey.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;costsandearnings&quot;&gt;Costs and earnings&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;kindle&quot;&gt;Kindle&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two royalty options: 35% or 70%. We always want the higher, right? Well, in the 70% range, the book price must be US$9.99 at the most.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More info: &lt;a href=&quot;https://kdp.amazon.com/en_US/help/topic/G200634560&quot;&gt;https://kdp.amazon.com/en_US/help/topic/G200634560&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;paperback&quot;&gt;Paperback&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Printing costs depend on &lt;strong&gt;several factors&lt;/strong&gt;. On this page, you will find how costs/royalties are calculated as well as a &quot;Printing cost calculator&quot; excel file: &lt;a href=&quot;https://kdp.amazon.com/en_US/help/topic/G201834340&quot;&gt;https://kdp.amazon.com/en_US/help/topic/G201834340&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/datascienceheroes.com/img/blog/09_earnings.png&quot; title=&quot;plot of chunk unnamed-chunk-9&quot; alt=&quot;plot of chunk unnamed-chunk-9&quot; width=&quot;680px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Amazon royalties are around 40% of retail price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Typically, royalties when using a publisher are around 8–12% of the retail price. Source &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.alanjacobson.com/writers-toolkit/the-business-of-publishing/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having a publisher/editor may facilitate several of things, so don't opt out only because of the earnings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;publishingoutsideamazongumroad&quot;&gt;Publishing outside Amazon: Gumroad&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gumroad.com&quot;&gt;Gumroad&lt;/a&gt; is a service that allows users to sell different types of files across the internet, e.g., music, videos, and data science books.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/datascienceheroes.com/img/blog/10_gumroad.png&quot; title=&quot;plot of chunk unnamed-chunk-10&quot; alt=&quot;plot of chunk unnamed-chunk-10&quot; width=&quot;250px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Gumroad provides a shopping cart and, after payment, the buyer automatically receives an email with the download link. It works really well! No one complains about the service. The pricing is affordable: &lt;em&gt;&quot;If you use the Free version of Gumroad, our fee is just 8.5% + 30 cents per transaction. If you get the Premium version of Gumroad for $10 (USD)/month, our fee is 3.5% + 30 cents per sale.&quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started with the free version and then changed to premium.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most useful features is that they allow embedding the payment form into your website. You can check mine &lt;a href=&quot;https://livebook.datascienceheroes.com/download-book.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other useful feature is name your price. The minimum price to download the &lt;em&gt;Data Science Live Book&lt;/em&gt; is US$5 and the buyer gets all three versions: PDF, .mobi, and .epub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I was writing this post, I saw that 37% of buyers spent more than the minimum—&lt;strong&gt;I'm happy&lt;/strong&gt; you like the project!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a list of unique buyers’ countries that bought using Gumroad—so it works worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/datascienceheroes.com/img/blog/11_countries.png&quot; title=&quot;plot of chunk unnamed-chunk-11&quot; alt=&quot;plot of chunk unnamed-chunk-11&quot; width=&quot;600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Did you find the outlier? :P&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;proofreading&quot;&gt;Proofreading&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Try always to share the book before its release.&lt;br/&gt;Proofreading is needed at two levels: &lt;strong&gt;technical and grammatical&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding the technical aspects, the proofreading was mainly done by Pablo Seibelt, Head of Data in Auth0. I have also made some changes based on people’s feedback. (Thanks!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding the grammar check, I hired several English teachers, to finally keep with one outstanding freelancer, Dr. Candy Pettus, from www.fiverr.com (a site to hire freelancers).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/datascienceheroes.com/img/blog/12_gramarly.png&quot; title=&quot;plot of chunk unnamed-chunk-12&quot; alt=&quot;plot of chunk unnamed-chunk-12&quot; width=&quot;200px&quot;/&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/datascienceheroes.com/img/blog/13_deepl.png&quot; title=&quot;plot of chunk unnamed-chunk-13&quot; alt=&quot;plot of chunk unnamed-chunk-13&quot; width=&quot;200px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Because my native language is Spanish (Hola!), I also use tools like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.grammarly.com/&quot;&gt;Grammarly&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.deepl.com&quot;&gt;DeepL&lt;/a&gt; (which works better than Google Translate).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;cover&quot;&gt;Cover&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tree was generated by an iterative and short algorithm.&lt;br/&gt;Representing that simplicity is the seed of complexity.&lt;br/&gt;Like fractals.&lt;br/&gt;Like the Lorenz Attractor.&lt;br/&gt;And like nature itself...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, the designer, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/barbaramercedes/&quot;&gt;Barbara Muños&lt;/a&gt;, took the little tree and made the magic!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/datascienceheroes.com/img/blog/14_cover_dslb.png&quot; title=&quot;plot of chunk unnamed-chunk-14&quot; alt=&quot;plot of chunk unnamed-chunk-14&quot; width=&quot;300px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;And, yes, the curve on the top follows the Fibonacci ratio, a feature present in flowers, art, the human body, and &quot;a big etc.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are plenty of cover designers on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fiverr.com/&quot;&gt;fiverr.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;isbn&quot;&gt;ISBN&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The International Standard Book Number (&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/International_Standard_Book_Number&quot;&gt;ISBN&lt;/a&gt;) is a unique numeric commercial book identifier. Publishers purchase an ISBN from an affiliate of the International ISBN Agency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You will need an ISBN for each book version&lt;/strong&gt;. In my case, I bought three: one for each of the Kindle, B&amp;amp;W, and color versions. Note: the content is the same in all three.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazon can provide you with a &quot;free&quot; ISBN if you sell the book only with them. If you want to sell in other markets, then you will have to get outside of Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;imprint&quot;&gt;Imprint&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;An imprint of a publisher is a trade name under which it publishes a work&quot; Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Imprint_(trade_name)&quot;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The imprint is defined when you register your ISBN. Being a self-publisher means that you can pick your imprint name (it can be your real name or a fictitious one).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you self-publish and you bought an ISBN outside the US, then you have to let &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bowker.com/&quot;&gt;bowker.com&lt;/a&gt; know that you effectively own the ISBN you are uploading. Contact them by email for more information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disclaimer: I'm not an expert on the ISBN or imprint name, therefore, what applies in my case may not in yours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;linkingbwcolorandkindleonamazon&quot;&gt;Linking: B&amp;amp;W, color and Kindle on Amazon&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are selling these three versions, you might except to have all of them linked. You will need to contact Amazon support to do this, because they only support one paperback linked to a kindle. Yet, the final result si some annoying...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.datascienceheroes.com/content/images/2018/08/Screen-Shot-2018-08-25-at-14.25.45.png&quot; alt=&quot;linking different versions on Amazon&quot; width=&quot;300px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Where &lt;em&gt;&quot;Paperback&quot;&lt;/em&gt; links to B&amp;amp;W version and &lt;em&gt;&quot;Paperback, March 27, 2018&quot;&lt;/em&gt; links to color version (🧟‍♂️).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask for adding the legend &quot;Color&quot; and &quot;B&amp;amp;W&quot; at the end of each title.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;howtowritegood&quot;&gt;How to write good&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/datascienceheroes.com/img/blog/15_write_good.png&quot; title=&quot;plot of chunk unnamed-chunk-15&quot; alt=&quot;plot of chunk unnamed-chunk-15&quot; width=&quot;510px&quot;/&gt;&lt;ol start=&quot;11&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;Memes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;nextpost&quot;&gt;Next post&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I prepared a list of issues and Bookdown configurations to keep in mind that took me lot of time to find. Hopefully, it will save you time: &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.datascienceheroes.com/how-to-self-publish-a-book-customizing-bookdown/&quot;&gt;https://blog.datascienceheroes.com/how-to-self-publish-a-book-customizing-bookdown/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;finalwords&quot;&gt;Final words&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is it possible to self-publish a book? Yes, definitely!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some links:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found this post useful on this topic: &lt;a href=&quot;https://msperlin.github.io/2017-02-16-Writing-a-book/&quot;&gt;Writing an R book and self-publishing it in Amazon&lt;/a&gt; by Marcelo Perlin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will leave you with the back of the &lt;em&gt;Data Science Live Book&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/datascienceheroes.com/img/blog/16_back.png&quot; title=&quot;plot of chunk unnamed-chunk-16&quot; alt=&quot;plot of chunk unnamed-chunk-16&quot; width=&quot;250px&quot;/&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading! :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.datascienceheroes.com/how-to-self-publish-a-book/blog.datascienceheroes.com&quot;&gt;Blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/pcasas/&quot;&gt;Linkedin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/pabloc_ds&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 21:08:02 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>vharuck</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>How to self-publish a book on Amazon using Bookdown</og:title>
<og:description>tl;dr: A list of useful resources aimed to self-publish a book on Amazon using Bookdown.</og:description>
<og:url>https://blog.datascienceheroes.com/how-to-self-publish-a-book/</og:url>
<og:image>https://blog.datascienceheroes.com/content/images/2018/08/dslb_wood.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.datascienceheroes.com/how-to-self-publish-a-book/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Web.dev by Google</title>
<link>https://web.dev</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://web.dev</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Except as otherwise noted, the content of this page is licensed under the &lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/&quot;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License&lt;/a&gt;, and code samples are licensed under the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0&quot;&gt;Apache 2.0 License&lt;/a&gt;. For details, see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/site-policies&quot;&gt;Google Developers Site Policies&lt;/a&gt;. Java is a registered trademark of Oracle and/or its affiliates.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 18:54:48 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mxschumacher</dc:creator>
<og:title>Home  |  web.dev</og:title>
<og:description>Let's build the future of the web. With actionable guidance and analysis, web.dev helps developers like you learn and apply the web's modern capabilities to your own sites and apps.</og:description>
<og:url>https://web.dev/</og:url>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://web.dev/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Reasons to Fear Another ‘Great War’</title>
<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/opinion/articles/2018-11-11/100-years-after-world-war-i-there-s-reason-to-fear?srnd=premium-europe</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bloomberg.com/opinion/articles/2018-11-11/100-years-after-world-war-i-there-s-reason-to-fear?srnd=premium-europe</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/opinion/articles/2018-11-11/100-years-after-world-war-i-there-s-reason-to-fear?srnd=premium-europe&quot;&gt;https://www.bloomberg.com/opinion/articles/2018-11-11/100-years-after-world-war-i-there-s-reason-to-fear?srnd=premium-europe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=18433883&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=18433883&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 210&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 322&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 17:14:51 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>montalbano</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bloomberg.com/tosv2.html?vid=&amp;uuid=56c11320-e71a-11e8-9a9c-6bdd5335ac62&amp;url=L29waW5pb24vYXJ0aWNsZXMvMjAxOC0xMS0xMS8xMDAteWVhcnMtYWZ0ZXItd29ybGQtd2FyLWktdGhlcmUtcy1yZWFzb24tdG8tZmVhcj9zcm5kPXByZW1pdW0tZXVyb3Bl</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>YouTube CEO calls EU’s proposed copyright regulation financially impossible</title>
<link>https://www.theverge.com/2018/11/12/18087250/youtube-ceo-copyright-directive-article-13-european-union</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.theverge.com/2018/11/12/18087250/youtube-ceo-copyright-directive-article-13-european-union</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;wTVWRW&quot;&gt;YouTube CEO Susan Wojcicki has once again decried the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2018/9/12/17849868/eu-internet-copyright-reform-article-11-13-approved&quot;&gt;European Union’s proposed copyright directive&lt;/a&gt;, arguing in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/2018/11/i-support-goals-of-article-13-i-also.html&quot;&gt;new blog post&lt;/a&gt; that it’s impossible for a platform like YouTube to comply with the suggested regulations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;ldnNGL&quot;&gt;This is the second blog post Wojcicki has published on Article 13, a part of the copyright directive that calls for stricter copyright infringement enforcement that puts the responsibility on the platform instead of the user. This marks the first time the CEO has vehemently stated that YouTube does not have the technical or financial capabilities to enforce the kind of copyright restriction the European Union is seeking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;dhe3a8&quot;&gt;There are more than 400 hours of video uploaded every minute to the platform, and putting the onus of responsibility on platforms like YouTube to catch every video isn’t fair, according to Wojcicki. She &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kJQP7kiw5Fk&quot;&gt;used “Despacito,”&lt;/a&gt; the most watched video on YouTube, as an example of how complicated the process can become.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;c-float-right&quot;&gt;
&lt;aside id=&quot;pM8fYF&quot;&gt;&lt;q&gt;“The potential liabilities could be so large that no company could take on such a financial risk.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;hmqAdO&quot;&gt;“This video contains multiple copyrights, ranging from sound recording to publishing rights,” Wojcicki wrote. “Although YouTube has agreements with multiple entities to license and pay for the video, some of the rights holders remain unknown. That uncertainty means we might have to block videos like this to avoid liability under article 13. Multiply that risk with the scale of YouTube, where more than 400 hours of video are uploaded every minute, and the potential liabilities could be so large that no company could take on such a financial risk.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;00ddGU&quot;&gt;YouTube has gone on the offensive over the last month to garner support in opposing the EU’s copyright directive. The company’s creators account on Twitter has tweeted out multiple videos from creators condemning the directive, and a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/saveyourinternet/&quot;&gt;site dedicated to informing users about Article 13&lt;/a&gt; launched last month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;Hu8pGj&quot;&gt;It’s not just a campaign to appease creators, either. The company has released a number of updated statistics regarding its Content ID system, which pays copyright holders for their original work if used in another creator’s video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;c-float-right&quot;&gt;
&lt;aside id=&quot;y7yNbK&quot;&gt;&lt;q&gt;“We believe Content ID provides the best solution for managing rights on a global scale.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;ZFG1Tr&quot;&gt;“To date, we have used the system to pay rights holders more than €2.5B for third party use of their content,” Wojcicki wrote. “We believe Content ID provides the best solution for managing rights on a global scale.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;y2PfEu&quot;&gt;YouTube has invested more than $100 million into its Content ID system since it launched in October 2007. Wojcicki still sees it as the best way of tracking copyright infringement and ensuring that copyright owners are paid when their material is used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;rQZwIE&quot;&gt;“Platforms that follow these rules, and make a good effort to help rights holders identify their content, shouldn’t be held directly liable for every single piece of content that a user uploads,” Wojcicki wrote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;c-float-right&quot;&gt;
&lt;aside id=&quot;GY373q&quot;&gt;&lt;q&gt;“EU residents are at risk of being cut off from videos.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;XOkiU0&quot;&gt;Wojcicki’s note also includes some information about YouTube viewing habits in Europe, acknowledging how restrictions imposed by a copyright directive that YouTube will have to enforce to protect itself could affect European users and creators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;VfptPY&quot;&gt;“EU residents are at risk of being cut off from videos that, in just the last month, they viewed more than 90 billion times,” Wojcicki wrote. “Those videos come from around the world, including more than 35 million EU channels, and they include language classes and science tutorials as well as music videos.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;Ga8UGu&quot;&gt;Although the EU’s copyright directive will affect creators and their ability to use copyrighted content — even under the Fair Use Act — YouTube’s primary concern seems to be the financial burden associated with complying. The European Union will have its final vote on whether to pass the copyright directive in January.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 16:45:01 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>doener</dc:creator>
<og:description>&quot;No company could take on such a financial risk.&quot;</og:description>
<og:image>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/tHwKznDbABDFb7BkTJG84yU6BJE=/0x0:4538x2376/fit-in/1200x630/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13311891/1052219774.jpg.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>YouTube CEO calls EU’s proposed copyright regulation financially impossible</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.theverge.com/2018/11/12/18087250/youtube-ceo-copyright-directive-article-13-european-union</og:url>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.theverge.com/2018/11/12/18087250/youtube-ceo-copyright-directive-article-13-european-union</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The poetry and brief life of a Foxconn worker</title>
<link>https://libcom.org/blog/xulizhi-foxconn-suicide-poetry</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://libcom.org/blog/xulizhi-foxconn-suicide-poetry</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field-type-filefield field-field-photo&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field-item odd&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://libcom.org/files/images/blog/xu%20lizhi.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[field_photo][xu lizhi]&quot; class=&quot;imagefield imagefield-lightbox2 imagefield-lightbox2-article imagefield-field_photo imagecache imagecache-field_photo imagecache-article imagecache-field_photo-article&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://libcom.org/files/imagecache/article/images/blog/xu%20lizhi.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;xu lizhi&quot; title=&quot;xu lizhi&quot; width=&quot;386&quot; height=&quot;191&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-type-text field-field-introduction&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field-item odd&quot; readability=&quot;13&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Translations of poems by Xu Lizhi (许立志), the Foxconn worker who took his own life on 30 September 2014, at the age of 24, in Shenzhen, China. Also includes an obituary with some explanatory notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: Below are translations by friends of the Nao project, starting with Xu's departing poem and an obituary, followed by other poems from 2011 to 2014. By translating these poems, we aim to memorialize Xu, share some of his excellent literary work, and spread awareness that the harsh conditions, struggles and aspirations of Chinese migrant workers (including but not limited to Foxconn) have not diminished since &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Foxconn_suicides&quot; class=&quot;bb-url&quot;&gt;the more widely-publicized spate of 18 attempted Foxconn suicides in 2010&lt;/a&gt;, resulting in 14 deaths. Insiders report that thereafter, although the frequency of suicides decreased (mainly due to Foxconn's installation of nets making it more difficult for workers to jump from their dormitories, along with the development of workers' collective resistance), such suicides have continued to the present. Including Xu Lizhi, at least 8 cases have been reported in the media since 2010, but insiders say that many other cases go unreported. We hope that in the future, workers in Foxconn and elsewhere manage to find ways around such companies' military-style discipline and surveillance, come together, and forge collective paths out of this capitalist world of death, into a world worth living in. Don't give up!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several of these poems were included in the &lt;span&gt;Shenzhen Evening News&lt;/span&gt; article linked and translated below; the others are widely available on the web, such as &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.douban.com/note/431282993/&quot; class=&quot;bb-url&quot;&gt;this post on Douban&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Contents:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Obituary + &quot;On My Deathbed&quot; (2014)&lt;br /&gt;&quot;Conflict&quot; (2013)&lt;br /&gt;&quot;I Fall Asleep, Just Standing Like That&quot; (2011)&lt;br /&gt;&quot;A Screw Fell to the Ground (2014)&lt;br /&gt;&quot;A Kind of Prophecy&quot; (2013)&lt;br /&gt;&quot;The Last Graveyard&quot; (2011)&lt;br /&gt;&quot;My Life's Journey is Far From Complete&quot; (2014)&lt;br /&gt;&quot;I Swallowed a Moon Made of Iron&quot; (2013)&lt;br /&gt;&quot;Rented Room&quot; (2013)&lt;br /&gt;&quot;Upon Hearing the News of Xu Lizhi's Suicide&quot; by Zhou Qizao, a fellow worker at Foxconn (2014)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Obituary from &lt;a href=&quot;http://wb.sznews.com/html/2014-10/10/content_3025410.htm&quot; class=&quot;bb-url&quot;&gt;Shenzhen Evening News&lt;/a&gt;, including Xu's departing poem&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;by Li Fei and Zhang Xiaoqi&lt;br /&gt;10 October, 2014&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;《我弥留之际》&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;“On My Deathbed”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我想再看一眼大海，目睹我半生的泪水有多汪洋&lt;br /&gt;I want to take another look at the ocean, behold the vastness of tears from half a lifetime&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我想再爬一爬高高的山头，试着把丢失的灵魂喊回来&lt;br /&gt;I want to climb another mountain, try to call back the soul that I’ve lost&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我还想摸一摸天空，碰一碰那抹轻轻的蓝&lt;br /&gt;I want to touch the sky, feel that blueness so light&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;可是这些我都办不到了，我就要离开这个世界了&lt;br /&gt;But I can’t do any of this, so I’m leaving this world&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;所有听说过我的人们啊&lt;br /&gt;Everyone who’s heard of me&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;不必为我的离开感到惊讶&lt;br /&gt;Shouldn’t be surprised at my leaving&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;更不必叹息，或者悲伤&lt;br /&gt;Even less should you sigh or grieve&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我来时很好，去时，也很好&lt;br /&gt;I was fine when I came, and fine when I left.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-- Xu Lizhi, 30 September 2014&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Shy, quiet, introverted, solitary&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2010, Xu Lizhi went [from his home in rural Jieyang, Guangdong] to work at [a] Foxconn [electronics factory in Shenzhen], beginning life on the assembly line. From 2012 until February of this year [2014], over 30 of his writings were published in Foxconn’s internal newspaper &lt;span&gt;Foxconn People&lt;/span&gt; (富士康人), including poems, essays, film reviews, and news commentaries {…} Xu posted the titles of these writings on his blog in a post called “The Maturation Given to Me by a Newspaper,” indicating his gratitude for this platform for his literary aspirations. The first time his friend Zheng (pseudonym) read Xu’s poetry, he was astonished to discover that this young man could be so talented. Henceforth, Zheng always looked for Xu’s writings in the newspaper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zheng’s impression was that Xu was a shy boy, “of few words, but not silent.” “Xu asserted his convictions, but he seemed quite solitary – very much the air of a poet.” When Zheng heard of Xu’s suicide, his entire [week-long] break for [China’s] National Day was shrouded in grief. He could not go outside for days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Turning feelings into poems; fearing they be read by family&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of Xu’s early poems were descriptions of life on the assembly line. In “Workshop, My Youth Was Stranded Here,” he described his conditions at the time: “Beside the assembly line, tens of thousands of workers [&lt;span&gt;dagongzhe&lt;/span&gt;] line up like words on a page/ 'Faster, hurry up!'/ Standing among them, I hear the supervisor bark.” He felt that “Once you’ve entered the workshop/ The only choice is submission,” and that his youth was coldly slipping away, so he could only “Watch it being ground away day and night/ Pressed, polished, molded/ Into a few measly bills, so-called wages.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first Xu Lizhi found it difficult to adapt to the constant switching between dayshifts and nightshifts. In another poem, he described himself by the assembly line “standing straight like iron, hands like flight,” “How many days, how many nights/ Did I – just like that – standing, fall asleep?” He described his working life as exhausting, “Flowing through my veins, finally reaching the tip of my pen/ Taking root in the paper/ These words can be read only by the hearts of migrant workers.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Xu once said that he never showed his poetry to his parents or other relatives, &quot;because it's something painful; I don't want them to see that.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Failed efforts to get a job related to books&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;　&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although Xu lived in Shenzhen for only a few years, he identified deeply with the city. &quot;Everyone wishes they could put down roots in the city,&quot; he explained, but most migrant-worker [&lt;span&gt;dagong&lt;/span&gt;] poets write for a few years and then return to the countryside, get married and have children; Xu hoped to avoid that fate. He tried setting up a street stall with a friend, but failed. He also tried transferring from the assembly line to a logistics position, where he would have more freedom. He understood that very few such poets could get out [走出来]: &quot;[we] have to constantly fight for our lives [为生活奔波]; it's hard to go any further than that.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In February of this year, Xu quit his job at Foxconn and moved to Suzhou, Jiangsu. His friend explained that Xu's girlfriend worked there, but apparently things did not go well for Xu in Jiangsu. He told Zheng that he had trouble finding a job, but he did not go into detail about what happened there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Half a year later, he moved back to Shenzhen. In an earlier interview, Xu had said that he loved this city, that he derived great pleasure from its Central Book Mall and public libraries. If he were to return home [to rural Jieyang], there were only a few small bookstores, and &quot;even if I tried to order books online, they couldn't be delivered&quot; [to his remote address].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to his love of books, the first job application he submitted upon his return to Shenzhen in early September was to the Central Book Mall. Zheng recalled that Xu had told him, while working at Foxconn, that his dream was to become a librarian. Unfortunately, he did not get the job, and Zheng thinks this was a major disappointment. Two years earlier, Xu had applied for a position as librarian at Foxconn's internal library for employees, in response to a call for applications, and Xu had been turned down then as well. {...}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Returning to the workshop for one day prior to the incident&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Xu was running out of money, so after these disappointments, he returned to Foxconn, beginning work on September 29, in the same workshop where he had worked before. This should have been a new beginning, but it was not. That evening he mentioned to Zheng via online chat that someone had found him another job, so he might leave Foxconn again, but Zheng did not consider this anything special, figuring that Xu would not leave very soon, having just resumed work at Foxconn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next Zheng heard of Xu was two days later, when people forwarded the news of Xu's suicide on WeChat. Zheng could not believe it: &quot;Hadn't we just chatted two nights ago?&quot; Later Zheng learned that Xu had committed suicide only the morning after they had chatted, not two days later as the media had reported.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Refuting online rumors that Xu was an orphan&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Although it has been 10 days since Xu's death,] when it is mentioned, Zheng still cannot bear the grief. He thinks that Xu's suicide resulted from both internal and external factors: not only the disappointments he had undergone, but even more so the solitary poetic spirit in his bones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After Xu's passing, some online obituaries claimed that as a young child he had been orphaned, neglected and insulted until a poor old women adopted and raised him, and that this foster-grandmother had died a few years ago, leaving Xu alone in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zheng [refuted these rumors, pointing out that] Xu's writings often mentioned his mother and homesickness. His second poem published in &lt;span&gt;Foxconn People&lt;/span&gt; [for example], was called &quot;Summertime Homesickness.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Xu's poetry is cold and pensive, directly facing a life of misery. His poems trace a trajectory in which the scent of death becomes more and more pronounced. He had already rehearsed death hundreds of times in his writing, so the final act was merely a small step over the edge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Selected Poems by Xu Lizhi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;《冲突》&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span&gt;&quot;Conflict&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;他们都说&lt;br /&gt;They all say&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我是个话很少的孩子&lt;br /&gt;I'm a child of few words&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;对此我并不否认&lt;br /&gt;This I don't deny&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;实际上&lt;br /&gt;But actually&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我说与不说&lt;br /&gt;Whether I speak or not&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;都会跟这个社会&lt;br /&gt;With this society I'll still&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;发生冲突&lt;br /&gt;Conflict&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-- 7 June 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;《我就那样站着入睡》&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span&gt;&quot;I Fall Asleep, Just Standing Like That&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;眼前的纸张微微发黄&lt;br /&gt;The paper before my eyes fades yellow&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我用钢笔在上面凿下深浅不一的黑&lt;br /&gt;With a steel pen I chisel on it uneven black&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;里面盛满打工的词汇&lt;br /&gt;Full of working words&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;车间，流水线，机台，上岗证，加班，薪水……&lt;br /&gt;Workshop, assembly line, machine, work card, overtime, wages...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我被它们治得服服贴贴&lt;br /&gt;They've trained me to become docile&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我不会呐喊，不会反抗&lt;br /&gt;Don't know how to shout or rebel&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;不会控诉，不会埋怨&lt;br /&gt;How to complain or denounce&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;只默默地承受着疲惫&lt;br /&gt;Only how to silently suffer exhaustion&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;驻足时光之初&lt;br /&gt;When I first set foot in this place&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我只盼望每月十号那张灰色的薪资单&lt;br /&gt;I hoped only for that grey pay slip on the tenth of each month&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;赐我以迟到的安慰&lt;br /&gt;To grant me some belated solace&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;为此我必须磨去棱角，磨去语言&lt;br /&gt;For this I had to grind away my corners, grind away my words&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;拒绝旷工，拒绝病假，拒绝事假&lt;br /&gt;Refuse to skip work, refuse sick leave, refuse leave for private reasons&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;拒绝迟到，拒绝早退&lt;br /&gt;Refuse to be late, refuse to leave early&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;流水线旁我站立如铁，双手如飞&lt;br /&gt;By the assembly line I stood straight like iron, hands like flight,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;多少白天，多少黑夜&lt;br /&gt;How many days, how many nights&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我就那样，站着入睡&lt;br /&gt;Did I - just like that - standing fall asleep?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-- 20 August 2011&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;《一颗螺丝掉在地上》&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span&gt;&quot;A Screw Fell to the Ground&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;一颗螺丝掉在地上&lt;br /&gt;A screw fell to the ground&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在这个加班的夜晚&lt;br /&gt;In this dark night of overtime&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;垂直降落，轻轻一响&lt;br /&gt;Plunging vertically, lightly clinking&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;不会引起任何人的注意&lt;br /&gt;It won’t attract anyone’s attention&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;就像在此之前&lt;br /&gt;Just like last time&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;某个相同的夜晚&lt;br /&gt;On a night like this&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;有个人掉在地上&lt;br /&gt;When someone plunged to the ground&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-- 9 January 2014&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;《谶言一种》&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span&gt;&quot;A Kind of Prophecy&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;村里的老人都说&lt;br /&gt;Village elders say&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我跟我爷爷年轻时很像&lt;br /&gt;I resemble my grandfather in his youth&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;刚开始我不以为然&lt;br /&gt;I didn’t recognize it&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;后来经他们一再提起&lt;br /&gt;But listening to them time and again&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我就深信不疑了&lt;br /&gt;Won me over&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我跟我爷爷&lt;br /&gt;My grandfather and I share&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;不仅外貌越看越像&lt;br /&gt;Facial expressions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;就连脾性和爱好&lt;br /&gt;Temperaments, hobbies&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;也像同一个娘胎里出来的&lt;br /&gt;Almost as if we came from the same womb&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;比如我爷爷外号竹竿&lt;br /&gt;They nicknamed him “bamboo pole”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我外号衣架&lt;br /&gt;And me, “clothes hanger”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我爷爷经常忍气吞声&lt;br /&gt;He often swallowed his feelings&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我经常唯唯诺诺&lt;br /&gt;I'm often obsequious&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我爷爷喜欢猜谜&lt;br /&gt;He liked guessing riddles&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我喜欢预言&lt;br /&gt;I like premonitions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1943年秋，鬼子进&lt;br /&gt;In the autumn of 1943, the Japanese devils invaded&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我爷爷被活活烧死&lt;br /&gt;and burned my grandfather alive&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;享年23岁&lt;br /&gt;at the age of 23.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我今年23岁&lt;br /&gt;This year i turn 23.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-- 18 June 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;《最后的墓地》&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span&gt;&quot;The Last Graveyard&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;机台的鸣叫也打着瞌睡&lt;br /&gt;Even the machine is nodding off&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;密封的车间贮藏疾病的铁&lt;br /&gt;Sealed workshops store diseased iron&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;薪资隐藏在窗帘后面&lt;br /&gt;Wages concealed behind curtains&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;仿似年轻打工者深埋于心底的爱情&lt;br /&gt;Like the love that young workers bury at the bottom of their hearts&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;没有时间开口，情感徒留灰尘&lt;br /&gt;With no time for expression, emotion crumbles into dust&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;他们有着铁打的胃&lt;br /&gt;They have stomachs forged of iron&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;盛满浓稠的硫酸，硝酸&lt;br /&gt;Full of thick acid, sulfuric and nitric&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;工业向他们收缴来不及流出的泪&lt;br /&gt;Industry captures their tears before they have the chance to fall&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;时辰走过，他们清醒全无&lt;br /&gt;Time flows by, their heads lost in fog&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;产量压低了年龄，疼痛在日夜加班&lt;br /&gt;Output weighs down their age, pain works overtime day and night&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;还未老去的头晕潜伏生命&lt;br /&gt;In their lives, dizziness before their time is latent&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;皮肤被治具强迫褪去&lt;br /&gt;The jig forces the skin to peel&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;顺手镀上一层铝合金&lt;br /&gt;And while it's at it, plates on a layer of aluminum alloy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;有人还在坚持着，有人含病离去&lt;br /&gt;Some still endure, while others are taken by illness&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我在他们中间打盹，留守青春的&lt;br /&gt;I am dozing between them, guarding&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;最后一块墓地&lt;br /&gt;The last graveyard of our youth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-- 21 December 2011&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;《我一生中的路还远远没有走完》&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span&gt;&quot;My Life’s Journey is Still Far from Complete&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;这是谁都没有料到的&lt;br /&gt;This is something no one expected&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我一生中的路&lt;br /&gt;My life’s journey&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;还远远没有走完&lt;br /&gt;Is far from over&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;就要倒在半路上了&lt;br /&gt;But now it's stalled at the halfway mark&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;类似的困境&lt;br /&gt;It’s not as if similar difficulties&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;以前也不是没有&lt;br /&gt;Didn’t exist before&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;只是都不像这次&lt;br /&gt;But they didn’t come&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;来得这么突然&lt;br /&gt;As suddenly&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;这么凶猛&lt;br /&gt;As ferociously&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;一再地挣扎&lt;br /&gt;Repeatedly struggle&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;竟全是徒劳&lt;br /&gt;But all is futile&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我比谁都渴望站起来&lt;br /&gt;I want to stand up more than anyone else&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;可是我的腿不答应&lt;br /&gt;But my legs won’t cooperate&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我的胃不答应&lt;br /&gt;My stomach won’t cooperate&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我全身的骨头都不答应&lt;br /&gt;All the bones of my body won’t cooperate&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我只能这样平躺着&lt;br /&gt;I can only lie flat&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在黑暗里一次次地发出&lt;br /&gt;In this darkness, sending out&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;无声的求救信号&lt;br /&gt;A silent distress signal, again and again&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;再一次次地听到&lt;br /&gt;Only to hear, again and again&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;绝望的回响&lt;br /&gt;The echo of desperation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-- 13 July 2014&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;《我咽下一枚铁做的月亮》&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span&gt;&quot;I Swallowed a Moon Made of Iron&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我咽下一枚铁做的月亮&lt;br /&gt;I swallowed a moon made of iron&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;他们把它叫做螺丝&lt;br /&gt;They refer to it as a nail&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我咽下这工业的废水，失业的订单&lt;br /&gt;I swallowed this industrial sewage, these unemployment documents&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;那些低于机台的青春早早夭亡&lt;br /&gt;Youth stooped at machines die before their time&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我咽下奔波，咽下流离失所&lt;br /&gt;I swallowed the hustle and the destitution&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;咽下人行天桥，咽下长满水锈的生活&lt;br /&gt;Swallowed pedestrian bridges, life covered in rust&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我再咽不下了&lt;br /&gt;I can't swallow any more&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;所有我曾经咽下的现在都从喉咙汹涌而出&lt;br /&gt;All that I've swallowed is now gushing out of my throat&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在祖国的领土上铺成一首&lt;br /&gt;Unfurling on the land of my ancestors&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;耻辱的诗&lt;br /&gt;Into a disgraceful poem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-- 19 December 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;《出租屋》&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span&gt;&quot;Rented Room&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;十平米左右的空间&lt;br /&gt;A space of ten square meters&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;局促，潮湿，终年不见天日&lt;br /&gt;Cramped and damp, no sunlight all year&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我在这里吃饭，睡觉，拉屎，思考&lt;br /&gt;Here I eat, sleep, shit, and think&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;咳嗽，偏头痛，生老，病不死&lt;br /&gt;Cough, get headaches, grow old, get sick but still fail to die&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;昏黄的灯光下我一再发呆，傻笑&lt;br /&gt;Under the dull yellow light again I stare blankly, chuckling like an idiot&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;来回踱步，低声唱歌，阅读，写诗&lt;br /&gt;I pace back and forth, singing softly, reading, writing poems&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;每当我打开窗户或者柴门&lt;br /&gt;Every time I open the window or the wicker gate&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我都像一位死者&lt;br /&gt;I seem like a dead man&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;把棺材盖，缓缓推开&lt;br /&gt;Slowly pushing open the lid of a coffin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-- 2 December 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;《惊闻90后青工诗人许立志坠楼有感》&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&quot;Upon Hearing the News of Xu Lizhi's Suicide&quot;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;by Zhou Qizao (周启早), a fellow worker at Foxconn&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;每一个生命的消失&lt;br /&gt;The loss of every life&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;都是另一个我的离去&lt;br /&gt;Is the passing of another me&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;又一枚螺丝松动&lt;br /&gt;Another screw comes loose&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;又一位打工兄弟坠楼&lt;br /&gt;Another migrant worker brother jumps&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;你替我死去&lt;br /&gt;You die in place of me&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我替你继续写诗&lt;br /&gt;And I keep writing in place of you&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;顺便拧紧螺丝&lt;br /&gt;While I do so, screwing the screws tighter&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;今天是祖国六十五岁的生日&lt;br /&gt;Today is our nation's sixty-fifth birthday&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;举国欢庆&lt;br /&gt;We wish the country joyous celebrations&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;二十四岁的你立在灰色的镜框里微微含笑&lt;br /&gt;A twenty-four-year-old you stands in the grey picture frame, smiling ever so slightly&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;秋风秋雨&lt;br /&gt;Autumn winds and autumn rain&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;白发苍苍的父亲捧着你黑色的骨灰盒趔趄还乡&lt;br /&gt;A white-haired father, holding the black urn with your ashes, stumbles home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-- 1 October 2014&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Translators' notes:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 16:31:42 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>isomorph</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://libcom.org/blog/xulizhi-foxconn-suicide-poetry</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Bitwarden Completes Third-Party Security Audit</title>
<link>https://blog.bitwarden.com/bitwarden-completes-third-party-security-audit-c1cc81b6d33</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.bitwarden.com/bitwarden-completes-third-party-security-audit-c1cc81b6d33</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;section-inner sectionLayout--insetColumn&quot; readability=&quot;23.780487804878&quot;&gt;

&lt;p name=&quot;1616&quot; id=&quot;1616&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;We take the security of Bitwarden seriously. In addition to our 100% &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bitwarden&quot; data-href=&quot;https://github.com/bitwarden&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;open source codebase&lt;/a&gt; and public &lt;a href=&quot;https://hackerone.com/bitwarden&quot; data-href=&quot;https://hackerone.com/bitwarden&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;bug bounty program&lt;/a&gt;, we also understand the need for official security assessments and penetration testing from reputable third parties. We are pleased to announce that Bitwarden has completed a thorough security audit and cryptographic analysis from the security experts at &lt;a href=&quot;https://cure53.de/&quot; data-href=&quot;https://cure53.de/&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Cure53&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;b4ff&quot; id=&quot;b4ff&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;In the interest of providing full disclosure, below you will find the technical report that was compiled from the team at Cure53 along with an internal report containing a summary of each issue, impact analysis, and the actions taken/planned by Bitwarden regarding the identified issues and vulnerabilities. Some issues are informational and no action is currently planned or necessary. We are happy to report that no major issues were identified during this audit and that all issues that had an immediate impact have already been resolved in recent Bitwarden application updates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;223f&quot; id=&quot;223f&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;We hope that this assessment reiterates our commitment to the security and integrity of the entire Bitwarden platform and helps further strengthen the trust that our users place in Bitwarden every day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;postList&quot;&gt;&lt;li name=&quot;c0e6&quot; id=&quot;c0e6&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Bitwarden Security Assessment Report — &lt;a href=&quot;https://cdn.bitwarden.net/misc/Bitwarden%20Security%20Assessment%20Report%20-%20v2.pdf&quot; data-href=&quot;https://cdn.bitwarden.net/misc/Bitwarden%20Security%20Assessment%20Report%20-%20v2.pdf&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--li-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Download PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p name=&quot;b94a&quot; id=&quot;b94a&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--li graf--trailing&quot;&gt;If you have any questions regarding this security audit feel free to &lt;a href=&quot;https://bitwarden.com/contact/&quot; data-href=&quot;https://bitwarden.com/contact/&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;contact us&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 15:28:48 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>drpfenderson</dc:creator>
<og:title>Bitwarden Completes Third-party Security Audit – Bitwarden Blog</og:title>
<og:url>https://blog.bitwarden.com/bitwarden-completes-third-party-security-audit-c1cc81b6d33</og:url>
<og:description>Bitwarden has underwent a thorough security assessment, code audit, and cryptographic analysis from experts at a third-party security firm.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.bitwarden.com/bitwarden-completes-third-party-security-audit-c1cc81b6d33?gi=afd51f17dc27</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Show HN: A JavaScript Handbook</title>
<link>https://jshandbook.com/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://jshandbook.com/</guid>
<description>&lt;center readability=&quot;11.097142857143&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The ebook is provided at no cost but requires an email signup &lt;span&gt;😘&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're not sure it's worth it, you can &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/dq20ctse5mrczh7/js-handbook-preview.pdf?dl=0&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;get a preview of the first 30 pages here&lt;/a&gt; (the book has a total of 171 pages). To receive the ebook, please subscribe to my newsletter.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I write &lt;a href=&quot;https://flaviocopes.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;daily tutorials on Frontend Development&lt;/a&gt;, and every week I'll send you a digest of the articles I wrote.&lt;br/&gt;Don’t worry, you can unsubscribe at any time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;I hope that you will find this ebook useful! I put a lot of work into it!&lt;br/&gt;I will send you the ebook in PDF, ePub and Mobi (Kindle) formats.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;table-of-contents&quot;&gt;Table of contents&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Preface&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduction to JavaScript&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ECMAScript&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ES6&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ES2016&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ES2017&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ES2018&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coding style&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lexical Structure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Variables&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Types&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expressions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prototypal inheritance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Classes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exceptions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Semicolons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quotes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Template Literals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Functions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Arrow Functions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Closures&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Arrays&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Loops&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Events&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Event Loop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Asynchronous programming and callbacks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Promises&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Async and Await&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Loops and Scope&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Timers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;this&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strict Mode&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Immediately-invoked Function Expressions (IIFE)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Math operators&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Math object&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ES Modules&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CommonJS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Glossary&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 13:27:31 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>flaviocopes</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://jshandbook.com/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Show HN: WriteFreely – minimalist, federated blogging platform</title>
<link>https://writefreely.org</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://writefreely.org</guid>
<description>&lt;h2&gt;Create a minimalist blog&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WriteFreely is built around writing. There's no news feed, notifications, or unnecessary &lt;em&gt;likes&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;claps&lt;/em&gt; to take you away from your train of thought. You get a &lt;a href=&quot;https://write.as/new&quot; target=&quot;editor&quot;&gt;distraction-free writing environment&lt;/a&gt;, and readers can enjoy a &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.writefreely.org/&quot; target=&quot;reading&quot;&gt;clean reading experience&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Publish to the fediverse&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reach outside your own site with federation via ActivityPub. WriteFreely lets anyone on Mastodon, Pleroma, or any ActivityPub-enabled service follow your blog, bookmark your posts, and share them with their followers. &lt;a href=&quot;https://video.writeas.org/videos/watch/cc55e615-d204-417c-9575-7b57674cc6f3&quot; onclick=&quot;showDemo(); return false;&quot;&gt;See how it works&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Easy on the eyes (and your server)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WriteFreely is written in Go (golang), so it runs anywhere and takes up very few resources — you can even run it on a Raspberry Pi! Installation is as easy as uploading a binary (plus a few files, for now).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 13:02:19 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>thebaer</dc:creator>
<og:title>Write Freely</og:title>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:url>https://writefreely.org/</og:url>
<og:description>Minimalist, federated, self-hosted blogging platform.</og:description>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://writefreely.org/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>