<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>How Discord Won</title>
<link>https://ianvanagas.com/2020/10/19/how-discord-won/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://ianvanagas.com/2020/10/19/how-discord-won/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;It has been a big year for realizing the limits of technology for interacting with people. Gamers have known this for a long time. Lag, disconnections, and coordination issues were problems in gaming since the start. There is a platform that has gone a long way in solving those problems: Discord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discord allows people to talk and chat online. Servers are created by anybody to talk about anything, usually, it is a friend group or a shared interest. They contain chat channels (kind of like Slack) and voice channels that are always on and allow people to join and leave whenever they want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The competition between internet communication platforms is fierce. Discord wasn’t early to voice channels or group chats. They weren’t unique for targeting their offering to gamers. Other platforms have the same features as them. Yet they are a multi-billion dollar business. How? To borrow an idea from &lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot; href=&quot;https://medium.com/@sarahtavel/how-to-build-an-enduring-multi-billion-dollar-business-hint-create-a-10x-product-recast-3527df2b8fcb&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Sarah Tavel&lt;/a&gt;, they built a 10x better product AND capture more value from it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;10x Better&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Voice chat sucked for a long time. Skype, which was long the most popular option, was a mess. It forced you to call people. Servers went down often. The application crashed. Chats were all over the place. There is a good reason people do not use Skype and it is because it sucks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were other competitors like IRC, TeamSpeak, Mumble, Ventrilo. All had basically the same features, voice calls, and chat. Each suffered from a combination of problems like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Complicated setup process. Any new member must also go through a setup process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paid hosting. No one wanted to pay when there were free options. Especially true as servers grow.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unclear benefits. Convincing one person was not enough, you needed to convince your whole group of the benefits of switching.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Weird ideological reasons. Your platform was your tribal affiliation, switching means abandoning your tribe. Everyone looked down on people who didn’t use the same platform as them (even if it was jokingly).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Discord launched in May 2015, long after the competitors listed above. They are now more successful than those same competitors. They did so by making the experience 10x better:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Discord requires nearly no setup. Starting a server on Discord takes two clicks. Creating channels is two clicks. It works instantly and all the time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discord is free.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is easy to switch to Discord. Inviting people is two clicks and a paste. Joining a server (once you have an account) is two clicks. It is so simple you don’t even think about it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Non-core features like emoji support, reactions, bots, integrations, video calls, and screen-sharing all work as well as you could ask.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Big community servers for games, fanbases, organizations, hobbies, and more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Improvements in each of these areas add up to a 10x better experience than other platforms. I complain about Discord way less than I complain about Skype. There are benefits for everyone on Discord, which makes it a 10x experience both for groups and individuals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On top of being 10x better, the core features are free. This causes an obvious business problem, how do you make money? There isn’t an obvious place to put ads. Competitors often charge by the member, but that incentivizes against growth. Discord figured out a way to incentivize growth while capturing value from large and small groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sell Status to Capture Value&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It took Discord a long time to figure out monetization (and they still are figuring it out). Venture capital allowed them to experiment with ideas such as selling games and membership. Neither worked perfectly, but they pointed in the right direction. &lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot; href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/abrambrown/2020/06/30/discord-was-once-the-alt-rights-favorite-chat-app-now-its-gone-mainstream-and-scored-a-new-35-billion-valuation/#article-0-topx-1:~:text=Discord%20is%20on%20track%20to%20top,Discord%20groups%20that%20they%20belong%20to.&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Forbes estimated&lt;/a&gt; they are “on track to top $120 million in sales this year (2020)… up from around $70 million last year.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To understand Discord’s monetization, look at their history. The founders previously started game companies and were &lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot; href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Discord_(software)#cite_ref-vb_2015_funding_9-0:~:text=%5D%20Their%20first%20product%20was%20Fates,and%20based%20on%20more%20modern%20technology.%5B&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;inspired by free-to-play games like League of Legends.&lt;/a&gt; Games like League of Legends sell status. It is free-to-play but you can buy “skins” to make your character look different. If you have a cool or expensive skin, it means you care more about the game. It raises your status. Discord does the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discord allows users to raise their status through a subscription called Nitro. It provides quality improvements (file size and video quality), special profile upgrades (more emojis, animated profile photos, custom tags), and most importantly, the ability to “boost” a server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boosts raise a user’s status in both small and large servers. They allow you to either improve your friend’s online hangout and your communities’ experience by unlocking custom emotes, cosmetic features, and quality improvements. For users, it puts an icon next to their name saying they contribute and gives them a special booster role on the server. In short, it is a way for someone to pay to stand out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;493&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://ianvanagas.com/serverboosts/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://ianvanagas.files.wordpress.com/2020/10/serverboosts.png&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1163,333&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;serverboosts&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://ianvanagas.files.wordpress.com/2020/10/serverboosts.png?w=300&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://ianvanagas.files.wordpress.com/2020/10/serverboosts.png?w=750&quot; src=&quot;https://ianvanagas.files.wordpress.com/2020/10/serverboosts.png?w=1024&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-493&quot; srcset=&quot;https://ianvanagas.files.wordpress.com/2020/10/serverboosts.png?w=1024 1024w, https://ianvanagas.files.wordpress.com/2020/10/serverboosts.png?w=150 150w, https://ianvanagas.files.wordpress.com/2020/10/serverboosts.png?w=300 300w, https://ianvanagas.files.wordpress.com/2020/10/serverboosts.png?w=768 768w, https://ianvanagas.files.wordpress.com/2020/10/serverboosts.png 1163w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot;/&gt;Server Boost Perks
&lt;p&gt;You can buy boosts separately from Nitro at $5 per month or $50 per year. Perks come in uneven tiers: Level 1 is 2 boosts, Level 2 is 15 boosts, Level 3 is 30 boosts. It is unlikely “friend group sized” servers get past two boosts, but large servers often pass thirty. Some examples:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Name&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Boosts&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;MRR (@ $5 per boost)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Minecraft&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;165&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;$825&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Kanye&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;75&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;$375&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Fortnite&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;165&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;$825&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;r/LeagueOfLegends&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;201&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;$1005&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Animal Crossing: New Horizons&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;412&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;$2060&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;r/Overwatch&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;85&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;$425&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Rocket League&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;116&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;$580&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Fall Guys&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;215&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;$1075&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Anime Soul Discord&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;323&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;$1615&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Kenny Beats&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;50&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;$250&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Musicians (Turkish)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;730&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;$3650&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;English&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;94&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;$470&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Python&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;44&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;$220&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;CallMeCarson Discord Cult&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;1153&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;$5765&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here are 14 popular servers accounting for nearly $250,000 in revenue per year. There are tons more, all with varying amounts of boosts. People are willing to pay to stand out, even when there is no obvious benefit. This is universal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every community needs a place to communicate online. Discord has the best offering, and it is free. Other platforms either force you to pay by the member or have a flat rate paid by the community host. Discord doesn’t require either. Servers can grow as large as they want for free, moderators and admins don’t have to pay, and Discord still makes money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As communities continue to grow on Discord, the money Discord makes from those communities goes up as well. Flat rates and tiers limit this. Communities want to grow, Discord provides them with an easy and effective way to do that. Users want status, Discord gives them a shortcut. This aligns incentives better than advertising or paid memberships do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Discord won by building 10x better spaces for communities. By selling status, they have also managed to capture more value from those communities than other platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discord won the competition for the gaming chat platform of choice, and now it wants to be the platform for all internet communities. This means they will be competing with the “big dogs” like Slack, Reddit, Twitter, Facebook, Microsoft, and Epic. Their free-to-play, pay-for-status monetization model is a competitive advantage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discord is a successful company. The question becomes how successful can they become? The key is the number of internet communities who choose Discord as their home. By creating a better product than competitors and being free for growth, Discord puts itself in an excellent position to continue to succeed moving forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me know what you think &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/IanVanagas&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 18:56:53 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ivanagas</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>How Discord Won</og:title>
<og:url>https://ianvanagas.com/2020/10/19/how-discord-won/</og:url>
<og:description>It has been a big year for realizing the limits of technology for interacting with people. Gamers have known this for a long time. Lag, disconnections, and coordination issues were problems in gami…</og:description>
<og:image>https://ianvanagas.files.wordpress.com/2020/10/kingdiscord.jpeg?w=1200</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://ianvanagas.com/2020/10/19/how-discord-won/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Face ID and Touch ID for the Web</title>
<link>https://webkit.org/blog/11312/meet-face-id-and-touch-id-for-the-web/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://webkit.org/blog/11312/meet-face-id-and-touch-id-for-the-web/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;People often see passwords are the original sin of authentication on the web. Passwords can be easy to guess and vulnerable to breaches. Frequent reuse of the same password across the web makes breaches even more profitable. As passwords are made stronger and unique, they can quickly become unusable for many users. Passwords indeed look notorious, but are passwords themselves the problem, or is it their use as a sole factor for authentication?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many believe the latter, and thus &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Multi-factor_authentication&quot;&gt;multi-factor authentication&lt;/a&gt; has become more and more popular. The introduction of a second factor does fix most of the security issues with passwords, but it inevitably makes the whole authentication experience cumbersome with an additional step. Therefore, multi-factor authentication has not become the de facto authentication mechanism on the web. Face ID and Touch ID for the web provides both the security guarantees of multi-factor authentication and ease of use. It offers multi-factor authentication in a single step. Using this technology, available on over a billion capable Apple devices, web developers can now broadly offer traditional multi-factor authentication with a smooth, convenient experience. And being built on top of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w3.org/TR/webauthn-1/&quot;&gt;Web Authentication API&lt;/a&gt; makes Face ID and Touch ID phishing resistant as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This blog post extends the content of &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/videos/play/wwdc2020/10670/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;WWDC 2020 “Meet Face ID and Touch ID for the web” session&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by providing detailed examples to assist developers’ adoption of this new technology, including how to manage different user agent user interfaces, how to propagate user gestures from user-activated events to WebAuthn API calls, and how to interpret Apple Anonymous Attestation. This article will end by summarizing the unique characteristics of Apple’s platform authenticator and the current status of security key support. If you haven’t heard about WebAuthn before, you’re strongly encouraged to first watch the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/videos/play/wwdc2020/10670/&quot;&gt;WWDC 2020&lt;/a&gt; session, which covers the basic concepts. Otherwise, please enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Managing User Experiences&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although user agents are not required to offer UI guidance to users during WebAuthn flows, the reality is that all of them do. This allows user agents to share some of the burden from websites to manage the user experience, but it creates another complexity for websites as each user agent has a different way of presenting the WebAuthn ceremony in its UI. A WebAuthn ceremony could either be the authentication process or the registration process. This section presents how WebAuthn ceremony options map to WebKit/Safari’s UI and the recommended user experience for Face ID and Touch ID for the web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One challenge is to manage different user experiences among the platform authenticator and security keys. Although the WebAuthn API allows presenting both options to the user simultaneously, it’s not the best approach. First, most users are probably only familiar with the branding of the platform authenticator, i.e., Face ID and Touch ID on Apple’s platforms, but are unfamiliar with security keys. Offering both at the same time can confuse users and make it difficult for them to decide what to do. Secondly, the platform authenticator has different behaviors and use cases from security keys. For example, Face ID and Touch ID are suitable for use as a more convenient, alternative mechanism to sign in when most security keys are not. And credentials stored in security keys can often be used across different devices and platforms while those stored in the platform authenticator are typically tied to a platform and a device. Therefore, it is better to present these two options to the user separately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Presenting Face ID and Touch ID Alone&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What follows is the recommended way to invoke Face ID and Touch ID for the web. Below is the corresponding Safari UI for registration ceremonies. Here, the Relying Party ID is picked to be displayed in the dialog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; src=&quot;https://webkit.org/wp-content/uploads/Screen-Shot-2020-08-11-at-2.34.11-PM.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1820&quot; height=&quot;1238&quot; class=&quot;preserve-color wp-image-11314&quot; srcset=&quot;https://webkit.org/wp-content/uploads/Screen-Shot-2020-08-11-at-2.34.11-PM.png 1820w, https://webkit.org/wp-content/uploads/Screen-Shot-2020-08-11-at-2.34.11-PM-300x204.png 300w, https://webkit.org/wp-content/uploads/Screen-Shot-2020-08-11-at-2.34.11-PM-1024x697.png 1024w, https://webkit.org/wp-content/uploads/Screen-Shot-2020-08-11-at-2.34.11-PM-768x522.png 768w, https://webkit.org/wp-content/uploads/Screen-Shot-2020-08-11-at-2.34.11-PM-1536x1045.png 1536w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1820px) 100vw, 1820px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here is the corresponding code snippet to show the above dialog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;js&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;keyword type&quot;&gt;const&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;options&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; {
    &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;publicKey&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;operator&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; {
        &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;rp&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;operator&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; { &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;operator&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;string&quot;&gt;&quot;example.com&quot;&lt;/span&gt; },
        &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;user&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;operator&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; {
            &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;operator&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;string&quot;&gt;&quot;john.appleseed@example.com&quot;&lt;/span&gt;,
            &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;id&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;operator&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;userIdBuffer&lt;/span&gt;,
            &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;displayName&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;operator&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;string&quot;&gt;&quot;John Appleseed&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
        },
        &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;pubKeyCredParams&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;operator&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; [ { &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;type&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;operator&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;string&quot;&gt;&quot;public-key&quot;&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;alg&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;operator&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;operator&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;7&lt;/span&gt; } ],
        &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;challenge&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;operator&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;challengeBuffer&lt;/span&gt;,
        &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;authenticatorSelection&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;operator&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; { &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;authenticatorAttachment&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;operator&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;string&quot;&gt;&quot;platform&quot;&lt;/span&gt; }
    }
};

&lt;span class=&quot;keyword type&quot;&gt;const&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;publicKeyCredential&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;await&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;navigator&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;credentials&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;create&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;options&lt;/span&gt;);
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The essential option is to specify &lt;code&gt;authenticatorSelection: { authenticatorAttachment: &quot;platform&quot; }&lt;/code&gt; , which tells WebKit to only invoke the platform authenticator. After the publicKeyCredential is returned, one of the best practices is to store the Credential ID in a server-set, secure, httpOnly cookie, and mark its transport as &lt;code&gt;&quot;internal&quot;&lt;/code&gt;. This cookie can then be used to improve the user experience of future authentication ceremonies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To protect users from tracking, the WebAuthn API doesn’t allow websites to query the existence of credentials on a device. This important privacy feature, however, requires some extra effort for websites to store provisioned Credential IDs in a separate source and query it before the authentication ceremony. The separate source is often on the backend server. This practice works well for security keys given that they can be used across platforms. Unfortunately, it does not work for the platform authenticator as credentials can only be used on the device where they were created. A server-side source cannot tell whether or not a particular platform authenticator indeed preserves a credential. Hence, a cookie is especially useful. This cookie should not be set through the &lt;code&gt;document.cookie&lt;/code&gt; API since Safari’s Intelligent Tracking Prevention caps the expiry of such cookies to seven days. It’s also important to mark those credentials as &lt;code&gt;&quot;internal&quot;&lt;/code&gt; such that websites could supply it in the authentication ceremony options to prevent WebKit from asking users for security keys at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below are two different UIs for authentication ceremonies. The first one is streamlined for the case where the user agent only has a single credential, while the second one shows how the user agent allows the user to select one of many credentials. For both cases, only &lt;code&gt;user.name&lt;/code&gt; submitted in the registration ceremony is selected to display. For the second case, the order of the list is sorted according to the last used date of the credential. WebKit keeps track of the last used date. Websites thus do not need to worry about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; src=&quot;https://webkit.org/wp-content/uploads/Screen-Shot-2020-08-11-at-7.20.07-PM.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1820&quot; height=&quot;1238&quot; class=&quot;preserve-color wp-image-11318&quot; srcset=&quot;https://webkit.org/wp-content/uploads/Screen-Shot-2020-08-11-at-7.20.07-PM.png 1820w, https://webkit.org/wp-content/uploads/Screen-Shot-2020-08-11-at-7.20.07-PM-300x204.png 300w, https://webkit.org/wp-content/uploads/Screen-Shot-2020-08-11-at-7.20.07-PM-1024x697.png 1024w, https://webkit.org/wp-content/uploads/Screen-Shot-2020-08-11-at-7.20.07-PM-768x522.png 768w, https://webkit.org/wp-content/uploads/Screen-Shot-2020-08-11-at-7.20.07-PM-1536x1045.png 1536w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1820px) 100vw, 1820px&quot;/&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; src=&quot;https://webkit.org/wp-content/uploads/Screen-Shot-2020-08-11-at-7.23.02-PM.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1820&quot; height=&quot;1238&quot; class=&quot;preserve-color wp-image-11319&quot; srcset=&quot;https://webkit.org/wp-content/uploads/Screen-Shot-2020-08-11-at-7.23.02-PM.png 1820w, https://webkit.org/wp-content/uploads/Screen-Shot-2020-08-11-at-7.23.02-PM-300x204.png 300w, https://webkit.org/wp-content/uploads/Screen-Shot-2020-08-11-at-7.23.02-PM-1024x697.png 1024w, https://webkit.org/wp-content/uploads/Screen-Shot-2020-08-11-at-7.23.02-PM-768x522.png 768w, https://webkit.org/wp-content/uploads/Screen-Shot-2020-08-11-at-7.23.02-PM-1536x1045.png 1536w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1820px) 100vw, 1820px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here is the corresponding code snippet to show the above dialogs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;js&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;keyword type&quot;&gt;const&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;options&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; {
    &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;publicKey&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;operator&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; {
        &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;challenge&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;operator&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;challengeBuffer&lt;/span&gt;,
        &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;allowCredentials&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;operator&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; [
            { &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;type&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;operator&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;string&quot;&gt;&quot;public-key&quot;&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;id&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;operator&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;credentialIdBuffer1&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;transports&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;operator&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; [&lt;span class=&quot;string&quot;&gt;&quot;internal&quot;&lt;/span&gt;] },
                    ]
    }
};

&lt;span class=&quot;keyword type&quot;&gt;const&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;publicKeyCredential&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;await&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;navigator&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;credentials&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;get&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;options&lt;/span&gt;);
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be noted, even though an improvement over WebKit can be made such that &lt;code&gt;transports: [&quot;internal&quot;]&lt;/code&gt; is not necessary to prevent WebKit from asking users for security keys as long as all allowed credentials are found within the platform authenticator, it is for the happy path only. In the case where no credentials are found, this extra property can tell WebKit to show an error message instead of asking the user for security keys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Presenting Face ID and Touch ID along with Security Keys&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the fact that the following usage is discouraged, WebKit/Safari has prepared dedicated UI to allow the user to select a security key in addition to the platform authenticator. Below is the one for registration ceremonies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; src=&quot;https://webkit.org/wp-content/uploads/Screen-Shot-2020-08-12-at-1.44.52-AM.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1820&quot; height=&quot;1238&quot; class=&quot;preserve-color wp-image-11323&quot; srcset=&quot;https://webkit.org/wp-content/uploads/Screen-Shot-2020-08-12-at-1.44.52-AM.png 1820w, https://webkit.org/wp-content/uploads/Screen-Shot-2020-08-12-at-1.44.52-AM-300x204.png 300w, https://webkit.org/wp-content/uploads/Screen-Shot-2020-08-12-at-1.44.52-AM-1024x697.png 1024w, https://webkit.org/wp-content/uploads/Screen-Shot-2020-08-12-at-1.44.52-AM-768x522.png 768w, https://webkit.org/wp-content/uploads/Screen-Shot-2020-08-12-at-1.44.52-AM-1536x1045.png 1536w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1820px) 100vw, 1820px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;The above dialog can be obtained by deleting &lt;code&gt;authenticatorSelection: { authenticatorAttachment: &quot;platform&quot; }&lt;/code&gt; from the registration ceremony code snippet above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; src=&quot;https://webkit.org/wp-content/uploads/Screen-Shot-2020-08-12-at-1.45.23-AM.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1820&quot; height=&quot;1238&quot; class=&quot;preserve-color wp-image-11324&quot; srcset=&quot;https://webkit.org/wp-content/uploads/Screen-Shot-2020-08-12-at-1.45.23-AM.png 1820w, https://webkit.org/wp-content/uploads/Screen-Shot-2020-08-12-at-1.45.23-AM-300x204.png 300w, https://webkit.org/wp-content/uploads/Screen-Shot-2020-08-12-at-1.45.23-AM-1024x697.png 1024w, https://webkit.org/wp-content/uploads/Screen-Shot-2020-08-12-at-1.45.23-AM-768x522.png 768w, https://webkit.org/wp-content/uploads/Screen-Shot-2020-08-12-at-1.45.23-AM-1536x1045.png 1536w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1820px) 100vw, 1820px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;The above dialog will be shown if any entry in the &lt;code&gt;allowCredentials&lt;/code&gt; array from the authentication ceremony code snippet above doesn’t have the &lt;code&gt;transports: [&quot;internal&quot;]&lt;/code&gt; property.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be noted, security keys can be used immediately in both cases after the UI is shown. “Use Security Key” and “Account from Security Key” options are there to show instructions of how to interact with security keys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Specifying allowCredentials or not&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;allowCredentials&lt;/code&gt; is optional for authentication ceremonies. However, omitting it will result in undetermined behavior in WebKit/Safari’s UI. If credentials are found, the authentication ceremony UI above will be shown. If no credentials are found, WebKit will ask the user for their security keys. Therefore, it is highly recommended not to omit this option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Propagating User Gestures&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unsolicited permission prompts are annoying. Mozilla has conducted surveys [&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.nightly.mozilla.org/2019/04/01/reducing-notification-permission-prompt-spam-in-firefox/&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.mozilla.org/futurereleases/2019/11/04/restricting-notification-permission-prompts-in-firefox/&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;] that verify this. Even though WebAuthn prompts are not as often seen on the web as notification prompts today, this situation will change with the release of Face ID and Touch ID for the web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Websites don’t ask for notification permission for fun. They ask because notifications can bring users back to their sites and increase their daily active users metric. A similar financial incentive could be found with WebAuthn prompts especially when platform authenticators are available as a fulfilled authentication request results in a high fidelity, persistent unique identifier of the user. This is a universal truth about authentication and that is why many sites ask for it before users even interact with the site. Though it is inevitable that WebAuthn credential will be leveraged to serve targeted ads to users, at least a similar protection that Mozilla did in Firefox for notification permission prompts can be utilized to make those WebAuthn prompts less annoying to users, which is to require user gestures for the WebAuthn API to eliminate annoying ‘on load’ prompts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We foresaw this problem some time ago and filed an &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/w3c/webauthn/issues/1293&quot;&gt;issue&lt;/a&gt; on the WebAuthn specification, but it didn’t get much traction back then. One reason is that it is a breaking change. Another reason is that the risk is not as high with security keys since they are not that popular and not always attached to the platform. The amount of unsolicited prompts has been surprisingly low. The situation is different with the release of Face ID and Touch ID for the web. So, Face ID and Touch ID for the web require user gestures to function. (User gestures are not required for security keys for backward compatibility.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;em&gt;user gesture&lt;/em&gt; is an indicator to signal WebKit that the execution of the current JavaScript context is a direct result of a user interaction, or more precisely from a handler for a user activated event, such as a &lt;code&gt;touchend&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;click&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;doubleclick&lt;/code&gt;, or &lt;code&gt;keydown&lt;/code&gt; event [&lt;a href=&quot;https://webkit.org/blog/6784/new-video-policies-for-ios/&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;]. Requiring user gestures for the WebAuthn API means API calls must happen within the above JavaScript context. Normally, the user gesture will not be propagated to any async executors within the context. Since it is popular for websites to fetch a challenge asynchronously from a server right before invoking WebAuthn API, WebKit allows WebAuthn API to accept user gestures propagated through XHR events and the Fetch API. Here are examples of how websites can invoke Face ID and Touch ID for the web from user activated events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Calling the API Directly from User Activated Events&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;js&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;button&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;addEventListener&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;string&quot;&gt;&quot;click&quot;&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;async&lt;/span&gt; () &lt;span class=&quot;operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;operator&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; {
    &lt;span class=&quot;keyword type&quot;&gt;const&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;options&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; {
        &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;publicKey&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;operator&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; {
            ...
            &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;challenge&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;operator&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;challengeBuffer&lt;/span&gt;,
            ...
        }
    };

    &lt;span class=&quot;keyword type&quot;&gt;const&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;publicKeyCredential&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;await&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;navigator&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;credentials&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;create&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;options&lt;/span&gt;);
});
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Propagating User Gestures Through XHR Events&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;js&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;button&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;addEventListener&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;string&quot;&gt;&quot;click&quot;&lt;/span&gt;, () &lt;span class=&quot;operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;operator&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; {
    &lt;span class=&quot;keyword type&quot;&gt;const&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;xhr&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;keyword operator&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;XMLHttpRequest&lt;/span&gt;();
    &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;xhr&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;onreadystatechange&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;async&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;keyword type&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt;() {
        &lt;span class=&quot;keyword control&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; (&lt;span class=&quot;keyword&quot;&gt;this&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;readyState&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;4&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;operator&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;operator&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;keyword&quot;&gt;this&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;status&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;200&lt;/span&gt;) {
            &lt;span class=&quot;keyword type&quot;&gt;const&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;challenge&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;keyword&quot;&gt;this&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;responseText&lt;/span&gt;;
            &lt;span class=&quot;keyword type&quot;&gt;const&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;options&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; {
                &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;publicKey&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;operator&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; {
                    ...
                    &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;challenge&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;operator&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;hexStringToUint8Array&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;challenge&lt;/span&gt;),                     ...
                }
            };

            &lt;span class=&quot;keyword type&quot;&gt;const&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;publicKeyCredential&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;await&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;navigator&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;credentials&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;create&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;options&lt;/span&gt;);
        }
    };
    &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;xhr&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;open&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;string&quot;&gt;&quot;POST&quot;&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;string&quot;&gt;&quot;/WebKit/webauthn/challenge&quot;&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;keyword literal&quot;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;);
    &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;xhr&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;setRequestHeader&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;string&quot;&gt;&quot;Content-type&quot;&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;string&quot;&gt;&quot;application/x-www-form-urlencoded&quot;&lt;/span&gt;);
    &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;xhr&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;send&lt;/span&gt;();
});
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Propagating User Gestures Through Fetch API&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;js&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;button&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;addEventListener&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;string&quot;&gt;&quot;click&quot;&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;async&lt;/span&gt; () &lt;span class=&quot;operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;operator&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; {
    &lt;span class=&quot;keyword type&quot;&gt;const&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;response&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;await&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;fetch&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;string&quot;&gt;&quot;/WebKit/webauthn/challenge&quot;&lt;/span&gt;, { &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;method&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;operator&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;string&quot;&gt;&quot;POST&quot;&lt;/span&gt; });
    &lt;span class=&quot;keyword type&quot;&gt;const&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;challenge&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;await&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;response&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;text&lt;/span&gt;();

    &lt;span class=&quot;keyword type&quot;&gt;const&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;options&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; {
        &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;publicKey&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;operator&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; {
            ...
            &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;challenge&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;operator&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;hexStringToUint8Array&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;challenge&lt;/span&gt;),             ...
        }
    };
    &lt;span class=&quot;keyword type&quot;&gt;const&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;publicKeyCredential&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;await&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;navigator&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;credentials&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;create&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;options&lt;/span&gt;);
});
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be noted, readable streams cannot propagate user gestures yet (related &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugs.webkit.org/show_bug.cgi?id=214722&quot;&gt;bug&lt;/a&gt;). Also, the user gesture will expire after 10 seconds for both XHR events and Fetch API.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Easter Egg: Propagating User Gestures Through setTimeout&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;js&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;button&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;addEventListener&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;string&quot;&gt;&quot;click&quot;&lt;/span&gt;, () &lt;span class=&quot;operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;operator&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; {
    &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;setTimeout&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;async&lt;/span&gt; () &lt;span class=&quot;operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;operator&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; {
        &lt;span class=&quot;keyword type&quot;&gt;const&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;options&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; { ... };
        &lt;span class=&quot;keyword type&quot;&gt;const&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;publicKeyCredential&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;await&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;navigator&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;credentials&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;create&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;options&lt;/span&gt;);
    }, &lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;500&lt;/span&gt;);
});
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The user gesture in the above example will expire after 1 second.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On iOS 14, iPadOS 14 and macOS Big Sur Beta Seed 1, only the very first case is supported. Thanks to early feedback from developers, we were able to identify limitations and add the later cases. This also helped us recognize that user gestures are not a well understood concept among web developers. Therefore, we are going to contribute to the HTML specification and help establish a well established concept of a user gesture for consistency among browser vendors. Depending on how it goes, we might reconsider expanding the user gesture requirement to security keys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Interpreting Apple Anonymous Attestation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attestation is an optional feature which provides websites a cryptographic proof of the authenticator’s provenance such that websites that are restricted by special regulations can make a trust decision. Face ID and Touch ID for the web offers Apple Anonymous Attestation. Once verified, this attestation guarantees that an authentic Apple device performed the WebAuthn registration ceremony, but it does not guarantee the operating system running on that device is untampered. If the operating system is untampered, it also guarantees that the private key of the just generated credential is protected by the &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.apple.com/guide/security/secure-enclave-overview-sec59b0b31ff/web&quot;&gt;Secure Enclave&lt;/a&gt; and the usage of the private key is guarded with Face ID or Touch ID. (A note: the guard falls back to device passcode if biometric fails multiple times in a row.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple Anonymous Attestation is first of its kind, providing a service like an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w3.org/TR/webauthn/#anonymization-ca&quot;&gt;Anonymization CA&lt;/a&gt;, where the authenticator works with a cloud operated CA owned by its manufacturer to dynamically generate per-credential attestation certificates such that no identification information of the authenticator will be revealed to websites in the attestation statement. Furthermore, among data relevant to the registration ceremony, only the public key of the credential along with a hash of the concatenated authenticator data and client data are sent to the CA for attestation, and the CA will not store any of these. This approach makes the whole attestation process privacy preserving. In addition, this approach avoids the security pitfall of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w3.org/TR/webauthn/#basic-attestation&quot;&gt;Basic Attestation&lt;/a&gt; that the compromising of a single device results in revoking certificates from all devices with the same attestation certificate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Enabling Apple Anonymous Attestation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;js&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;keyword type&quot;&gt;const&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;options&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; {
    &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;publicKey&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;operator&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; {
        ...
        &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;attestation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;operator&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;string&quot;&gt;&quot;direct&quot;&lt;/span&gt;,         ...
    }
};

&lt;span class=&quot;keyword type&quot;&gt;const&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;publicKeyCredential&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;await&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;navigator&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;credentials&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;create&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;options&lt;/span&gt;);
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Verifying the Statement Format&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the definition of the Apple Anonymous Attestation statement format. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/w3c/webauthn/issues/1453&quot;&gt;Issue 1453&lt;/a&gt; is tracking the progress of adding this statement format to the WebAuthn standard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;$$attStmtType //= (
                       fmt: &quot;apple&quot;,
                       attStmt: appleStmtFormat
                   )

appleStmtFormat = {
                       x5c: [ credCert: bytes, * (caCert: bytes) ]
                   }
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The semantics of the above fields are as follows:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;x5c&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;credCert&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; followed by its certificate chain, each encoded in X.509 format.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;credCert&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The credential public key certificate used for attestation, encoded in X.509 format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the verification procedure given inputs &lt;em&gt;attStmt&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;authenticatorData&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;clientDataHash&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Verify that &lt;em&gt;attStmt&lt;/em&gt; is valid CBOR conforming to the syntax defined above and perform CBOR decoding on it to extract the contained fields.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Concatenate &lt;em&gt;authenticatorData&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;clientDataHash&lt;/em&gt; to form &lt;em&gt;nonceToHash&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perform SHA-256 hash of &lt;em&gt;nonceToHash&lt;/em&gt; to produce &lt;em&gt;nonce&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Verify &lt;em&gt;nonce&lt;/em&gt; matches the value of the extension with OID ( 1.2.840.113635.100.8.2 ) in &lt;em&gt;credCert&lt;/em&gt;. The &lt;em&gt;nonce&lt;/em&gt; here is used to prove that the attestation is live and to protect the integrity of the &lt;em&gt;authenticatorData&lt;/em&gt; and the client data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Verify credential public key matches the Subject Public Key of &lt;em&gt;credCert&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If successful, return implementation-specific values representing attestation type Anonymous CA and attestation trust path &lt;em&gt;x5c&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;The final step is to verify &lt;em&gt;x5c&lt;/em&gt; is a valid certificate chain starting from the &lt;em&gt;credCert&lt;/em&gt; to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/certificateauthority/private/&quot;&gt;Apple WebAuthn root certificate&lt;/a&gt;, which then proves the attestation. (This step is usually shared among different types of attestations that utilize &lt;em&gt;x5c&lt;/em&gt; [&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w3.org/TR/webauthn/#registering-a-new-credential&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;].) To be noted, the AAGUID is all zeros even if the attestation is enabled as all Apple devices that support Face ID and Touch ID for the web should have the same properties as explained at the beginning of this section and no other devices can request Apple Anonymous Attestation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Unique Characteristics of Apple’s Platform Authenticator&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a summary about unique characteristics of Apple’s platform authenticator, i.e., Face ID and Touch ID for the web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Different option set results in different UI, and therefore please specify it wisely.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only RP ID and &lt;a href=&quot;http://user.name/&quot;&gt;user.name&lt;/a&gt; are selected to display in the UI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;User gestures are required to invoke the platform authenticator.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apple Anonymous Attestation is available. Use it only if attestation is necessary for you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AAGUID is all zero even if attestation is used.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Face ID and Touch ID for the web is available in Safari, SFSafariViewController and ASWebAuthenticationSession on iOS 14, iPadOS 14 and macOS Big Sur. For macOS, Safari 14 with downlevel OS will not get this feature because the attestation relies on a new system framework.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All public key credentials generated by the platform authenticator are resident keys regardless of what option is specified.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Credentials can only be cleared for all via Safari &amp;gt; History &amp;gt; Clear History… on Mac Safari or Settings &amp;gt; Safari &amp;gt; Clear History and Website Data on iOS &amp;amp; iPadOS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The signature counter is not implemented and therefore it is always zero. Secure Enclave is used to prevent the credential private key from leaking instead of a software safeguard.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Current Status of Security Key Support&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides the introduction of Face ID and Touch ID for the web, iOS 14, iPadOS 14 and Safari 14 on all supported macOS also have improved security key support including PIN entry and account selection. Here is a list of features that are currently supported. All of them have been supported since iOS 13.3, iPadOS 13.3 and Safari 13 except the two aforementioned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;All MUST features in WebAuthn Level 1 and all optional features except CollectedClientData.tokenBinding and most of the extensions. Only the appid extension is supported.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All CTAP 2.0 authenticator API except setPin and changePin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;USB, Lightning, and NFC transports are supported on capable devices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;U2F security keys are supported via CTAP 2.0 but not CTAP 1/U2F JS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Like Face ID and Touch ID for the web, security key support is available in Safari, SFSafariViewController and ASWebAuthenticationSession.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Feedback&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this blog post, we introduced Face ID and Touch ID for the web. We believe it is a huge leap forward for authentication on the web. It serves as a great alternative way to sign in, especially for traditional multi-factor authentication mechanisms. With the assistance of this technology, we believe multi-factor authentication will replace sole-factor password as the de facto authentication mechanism on the web. Developers, please start testing this feature today and let us know how it works for you by sending feedback on Twitter (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/webkit&quot;&gt;@webkit&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alanwaketan&quot;&gt;@alanwaketan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jonathandavis&quot;&gt;@jonathandavis&lt;/a&gt;) or by &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugs.webkit.org/&quot;&gt;filing a bug&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 18:50:09 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Austin_Conlon</dc:creator>
<og:title>Meet Face ID and Touch ID for the Web</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://webkit.org/blog/11312/meet-face-id-and-touch-id-for-the-web/</og:url>
<og:image>https://webkit.org/wp-content/uploads/Screen-Shot-2020-08-11-at-2.34.11-PM.png</og:image>
<og:description>People often see passwords are the original sin of authentication on the web.</og:description>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://webkit.org/blog/11312/meet-face-id-and-touch-id-for-the-web/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>First Bitcoin “mixer” penalized for violating anti-money laundering laws</title>
<link>https://www.fincen.gov/news/news-releases/first-bitcoin-mixer-penalized-fincen-violating-anti-money-laundering-laws</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.fincen.gov/news/news-releases/first-bitcoin-mixer-penalized-fincen-violating-anti-money-laundering-laws</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WASHINGTON&lt;/strong&gt;—The Financial Crimes Enforcement Network (FinCEN) has assessed a $60 million &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fincen.gov/sites/default/files/enforcement_action/2020-10-19/HarmonHelix%20Assessment%20and%20SoF_508_101920.pdf&quot;&gt;civil money penalty&lt;/a&gt; against Larry Dean Harmon, the founder, administrator, and primary operator of Helix and Coin Ninja, convertible virtual currency “mixers,” or “tumblers,” for violations of the Bank Secrecy Act (BSA) and its implementing regulations.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Mr. Harmon operated Helix as an unregistered money services business (MSB) from 2014 to 2017 and Coin Ninja from 2017 to 2020.  Mr. Harmon is currently being prosecuted in the U.S. District Court for the District of Columbia on charges of conspiracy to launder monetary instruments and the operation of an unlicensed money transmitting business in connection with his operation of Helix.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;As FinCEN clarified in its &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fincen.gov/sites/default/files/shared/FIN-2013-G001.pdf&quot;&gt;2013 Guidance&lt;/a&gt;, exchangers and administrators of convertible virtual currency are money transmitters under the BSA.  As such, they have an obligation to register with FinCEN; to develop, implement, and maintain an anti-money laundering compliance program; and to meet all applicable reporting and recordkeeping requirements.  FinCEN issued further &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fincen.gov/resources/statutes-regulations/guidance/application-fincens-regulations-certain-business-models&quot;&gt;clarification in 2019&lt;/a&gt; that financial institutions that are mixers and tumblers of convertible virtual currency must also meet these same requirements.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Mr. Harmon, doing business as Helix and Coin Ninja, operated as an exchanger of convertible virtual currencies by accepting and transmitting bitcoin through a variety of means.  From June 2014 through December 2017, Helix conducted over 1,225,000 transactions for its customers and was associated with virtual currency wallet addresses that sent or received over $311 million dollars.  FinCEN’s investigation has identified at least 356,000 bitcoin transactions through Helix.  Mr. Harmon operated Helix as a bitcoin mixer, or tumbler, and advertised its services in the darkest spaces of the internet as a way for customers to anonymously pay for things like drugs, guns, and child pornography.  Mr. Harmon subsequently founded, and acted as Chief Executive Officer of, Coin Ninja, which operated as an unregistered MSB and in the same manner as Helix.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;FinCEN’s investigation revealed that Mr. Harmon willfully violated the BSA’s registration, program, and reporting requirements by failing to register as a MSB, failing to implement and maintain an effective anti-money laundering program, and failing to report suspicious activities.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Specifically, the investigation demonstrated that Mr. Harmon deliberately disregarded his obligations under the BSA and implemented practices that allowed Helix to circumvent the BSA’s requirements.  This included a failure to collect and verify customer names, addresses, and other identifiers on over 1.2 million transactions.  Harmon, operating through Helix, actively deleted even the minimal customer information he did collect.  The investigation revealed that Mr. Harmon engaged in transactions with narcotics traffickers, counterfeiters and fraudsters, as well as other criminals.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;FinCEN closely coordinated today’s action with the U.S. Department of Justice’s Computer Crimes and Intellectual Property Section, the U.S. Attorney’s Office for the District of Columbia, the Federal Bureau of Investigation, and the Internal Revenue Service Criminal Investigation division.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 18:16:48 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>propter_hoc</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.fincen.gov/news/news-releases/first-bitcoin-mixer-penalized-fincen-violating-anti-money-laundering-laws</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Many of the root certificates on Windows are not needed</title>
<link>https://hexatomium.github.io/2020/10/17/001.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://hexatomium.github.io/2020/10/17/001.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;As of today, Windows trusts 322 root certificates issued by 122 different organizations from 47 countries. This number is quite high, and has been steadily growing over the last few years. And it turns out many of those certificates are not needed at all by the vast majority of Windows users, can be distrusted with no ill effects of any sort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each of these CAs is given tremendous power over your Internet traffic, so it makes great sense to minimize the number of CAs your computer trusts. One simple way to achieve this goal is to replace the default Windows list of root CAs with the much stricter Mozilla trust list, which includes 142 roots (52 organizations - 21 countries). An even stricter option is using the Google CTL, which currently includes just 127 root certificates (48 organizations - 21 countries). For the vast majority of users, applying either set is a great way to reduce your exposure to unnecessary CAs, with no negative impact whatsoever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Replacing the default Windows list of root CAs with the Mozilla or Google trust lists can be done manually, but is extremely time-consuming and error prone. The free version of RootIQ(*) offers a much simpler way to perform this system change:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot; readability=&quot;33&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;1. Use the Quick select dropdown to select the Mozilla trust set
2. Right-click the selection and click Invert selection
3. Right-click the selection and click Distrust
   Click Yes on the confirmation dialog
   This will distrust all roots that are not part of the Mozilla trust set, except for any Microsoft OS-critical roots.
4. Use the Quick select dropdown to select the Mozilla trust set (again)
5. Right-click the selection and Trust
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://nsa40.casimages.com/img/2020/10/17/201017023914436079.png&quot; alt=&quot;img123&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of this writing, on a standard Windows 10 system, you will end up with 145 trusted roots (rather than 322 roots for the default Microsoft CTL)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(*) RootIQ, our own root certificate manager for Windows, is now &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.metasudo.com/&quot;&gt;available&lt;/a&gt;. A free version of RootIQ is available for home and evaluation use.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 15:53:16 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>svenfaw</dc:creator>
<og:description>As of today, Windows trusts 322 root certificates issued by 122 different organizations from 47 countries. This number is quite high, and has been steadily growing over the last few years. And it turns out many of those certificates are not needed at all by the vast majority of Windows users, can be distrusted with no ill effects of any sort.</og:description>
<og:title>You don't need all those root certificates</og:title>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://hexatomium.github.io/2020/10/17/001.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Launch HN: StartPlaying.Games (YC W20) – Tabletop RPGs run by pro game masters</title>
<link>https://startplaying.games/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://startplaying.games/</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://startplaying.games/&quot;&gt;https://startplaying.games/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24827162&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24827162&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 231&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 120&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 15:22:55 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>kntucker</dc:creator>
<og:title>StartPlaying.Games | Hire A Dungeon Master | Find D&amp;D Games Online</og:title>
<og:description>Find And Join Online Dungeons &amp; Dragons Games. Browse Over 100 Tabletop RPG Games Run By Professional Dungeon Masters.</og:description>
<og:image>https://s3.amazonaws.com/appforest_uf/f1594018047721x693621852998191200/startplaying-games.jpg</og:image>
<og:url>https://startplaying.games/</og:url>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://startplaying.games/?_escaped_fragment_=</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Voyagers Detect an Increase in the Density of Space Outside the Solar System</title>
<link>https://www.sciencealert.com/for-some-reason-the-density-of-space-is-higher-just-outside-the-solar-system</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.sciencealert.com/for-some-reason-the-density-of-space-is-higher-just-outside-the-solar-system</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;In November 2018, after an epic, 41-year voyage, Voyager 2 finally crossed the boundary that marked the limit of the Sun's influence and entered interstellar space. But the little probe's mission isn't done yet - it's now sending home information about the space beyond the Solar System.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;And it's revealing something surprising. As Voyager 2 moves farther and farther from the Sun, the &lt;em&gt;density&lt;/em&gt; of space is increasing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's not the first time this density increase has been detected. Voyager 1, which entered interstellar space in 2012, detected a similar density gradient at a separate location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Voyager 2's new data show that not only was Voyager 1's detection legit, but that the increase in density may be a large-scale feature of the very local interstellar medium (VLIM).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Solar System's edge can be defined by a few different boundaries, but the one crossed by the Voyager probes is known as the heliopause, and it's defined by the solar wind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a constant supersonic wind of ionised plasma that streams out from the Sun in all directions, and the heliopause is the point at which the outward pressure of that wind is no longer strong enough to push into the wind from interstellar space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot; wf_caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.sciencealert.com/images/2020-10/heliopause.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;heliopause&quot; width=&quot;700&quot;/&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&lt;a href=&quot;https://voyager.jpl.nasa.gov/news/details.php?article_id=112&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;NASA/JPL-Caltech&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The space inside the heliopause is the heliosphere, and the space outside it is the VLIM. But the heliosphere isn't a round sphere. It's more like an oval, with the Solar System at one end, and a streaming tail behind; the &quot;nose&quot; is pointed in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nationalgeographic.com/news/2011/4/110407-sun-nose-scorpius-solar-system-nasa-ibex-ribbon-space-science/&quot;&gt;direction of the Solar System's orbit&lt;/a&gt; in the Milky Way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both Voyagers crossed the heliopause at the nose, but with a difference of 67 degrees in heliographic latitude and 43 degrees difference longitude.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Space is generally thought of as a vacuum, but it isn't, not completely. The density of matter is extremely low, but it still exists. In the Solar System, the solar wind has an average proton and electron density of &lt;a href=&quot;https://umbra.nascom.nasa.gov/spartan/the_solar_wind.html&quot;&gt;3 to 10 particles per cubic centimetre&lt;/a&gt;, but it grows lower the farther out you go from the Sun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mean electron density of the interstellar medium in the Milky Way, out among the stars, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ias.ac.in/article/fulltext/joaa/003/04/0399-0412&quot;&gt;has been calculated&lt;/a&gt; to be around 0.037 particles per cubic centimetre. And the plasma density in the outer heliosphere is around 0.002 electrons per cubic centimetre.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the Voyager probes crossed beyond the heliopause, their Plasma Wave Science instruments detected the electron density of the plasma through plasma oscillations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Voyager 1 crossed the heliopause on 25 August 2012, at a distance of 121.6 astronomical units from Earth (that's 121.6 times the distance between the Earth and Sun, so roughly 18.1 billion km).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it first measured the plasma oscillations after crossing the heliopause on 23 October 2013 at a distance of 122.6 astronomical units (18.3 billion km), Voyager 1 detected a plasma density of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41550-019-0918-5?proof=t&quot;&gt;0.055 electrons per cubic centimetres&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Voyager 2, which took the long way around, flying by Jupiter, Saturn, Uranus and Neptune, crossed the heliopause on 5 November 2018 at a distance of 119 astronomical units (17.8 billion km). It measured the plasma oscillations on 30 January 2019 at a distance of 119.7 astronomical units (17.9 billion), finding a plasma density of 0.039 electrons per cubic centimetre, very close to the Voyager 1 measurement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And both instruments reported an increase in density. After travelling another 20 astronomical units (2.9 billion km) through space, Voyager 1 reported an increase to about 0.13 electrons per cubic centimetre.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But detections made by Voyager 2 in June 2019 showed a much sharper increase in density to about 0.12 electrons per cubic centimetre, at a distance of 124.2 astronomical units (18.5 billion units).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given that &lt;a href=&quot;https://iopscience.iop.org/article/10.1088/0022-3727/33/18/310/meta&quot;&gt;plasma at Earth's atmospheric pressure&lt;/a&gt; has an electron density of 10^13 per cubic centimetre, those amounts may seem tiny, but they're significant enough to warrant our interest - especially since it's not clear what causes them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One theory is that the interstellar magnetic field lines become stronger as they drape over the heliopause. This could generate an electromagnetic ion cyclotron instability that depletes the plasma from the draping region. Voyager 2 did detect &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41550-019-0920-y&quot;&gt;a stronger magnetic field than expected&lt;/a&gt; when it crossed the heliopause.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another theory is that material blown by the interstellar wind should slow as it reaches the heliopause, causing a sort of traffic jam. This has possibly been detected by outer Solar System probe New Horizons, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencealert.com/nasa-new-horizons-probe-detects-ultraviolet-neutral-hydrogen-wall-solar-system-heliopause&quot;&gt;which in 2018 picked up the faint ultraviolet glow&lt;/a&gt; resulting from a buildup of neutral hydrogen at the heliopause.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's also possible that both explanations play a role. Future measurements taken by both Voyager probes as they continue their journey out into interstellar space could help figure it out. But that might be a long bet to take.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;It is not certain,&quot; the researchers wrote in their paper, &quot;whether the Voyagers will be able to operate far enough to distinguish between these two classes of models.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe in you, space probes!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The research was published in &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iopscience.iop.org/article/10.3847/2041-8213/abae58&quot;&gt;The Astrophysical Journal Letters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 13:28:32 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>daegloe</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Voyager Spacecraft Detect an Increase in The Density of Space Outside The Solar System</og:title>
<og:description>In November 2018, after an epic, 41-year voyage, Voyager 2 finally crossed the boundary that marked the limit of the Sun's influence and entered interstellar space. But the little probe's mission isn't done yet - it's now sending home information abo</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.sciencealert.com/for-some-reason-the-density-of-space-is-higher-just-outside-the-solar-system</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.sciencealert.com/images/2020-10/processed/1-PIA22835_1_1024.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-gb</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.sciencealert.com/for-some-reason-the-density-of-space-is-higher-just-outside-the-solar-system</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>No-till no-herbicide farming system in trial since 1981</title>
<link>https://rodaleinstitute.org/science/farming-systems-trial/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://rodaleinstitute.org/science/farming-systems-trial/</guid>
<description>&lt;div id=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;container container--slim&quot; readability=&quot;29&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;flex-section__content-title h1 section-title--tab&quot;&gt;The Philosophy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Farming Systems Trial was designed to &lt;strong&gt;assist farmers&lt;/strong&gt; looking to transition from conventional to organic, and is intended to yield &lt;strong&gt;practical data&lt;/strong&gt;. We utilize an advisory board of farmers from around the country who make sure our methods are consistent with contemporary practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We analyze &lt;strong&gt;grain cropping systems&lt;/strong&gt; because 70% of crops grown in the United States are grains including corn, soy, oats, and wheat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FST is intended to be a model of standard agricultural techniques, so &lt;strong&gt;GMO&lt;/strong&gt; crops and &lt;strong&gt;no-till&lt;/strong&gt; were introduced to the conventional plots in 2008 when their use became widespread across the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FST is a &lt;strong&gt;long-term study&lt;/strong&gt; by intent. Short-term studies that take place over only a few years can’t measure longer-term weather effects, like drought, that will inevitably occur, or biological changes to the soil, which can happen slowly. We need long-term studies to find real solutions to problems affecting the future of global food production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;container container--slim&quot; readability=&quot;33&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;flex-section__content-title h1 section-title--tab&quot;&gt;The Latest&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Chemical Runoff&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://mk0rodaleinstitydwux.kinstacdn.com/wp-content/uploads/atrazine-fst-data.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-2277 size-thumbnail&quot; src=&quot;https://mk0rodaleinstitydwux.kinstacdn.com/wp-content/uploads/atrazine-fst-data-300x180.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;180&quot; srcset=&quot;https://mk0rodaleinstitydwux.kinstacdn.com/wp-content/uploads/atrazine-fst-data-300x180.jpg 300w, https://mk0rodaleinstitydwux.kinstacdn.com/wp-content/uploads/atrazine-fst-data.jpg 600w, https://mk0rodaleinstitydwux.kinstacdn.com/wp-content/uploads/atrazine-fst-data-450x269.jpg 450w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Figure 1. Atrazine concentration in lysimeter leachate between conventional and organic cropping systems at the FST in 2017
&lt;p&gt;Recent results reveal that conventional farming systems leach atrazine, an herbicide known to disrupt human and animal endocrine systems, in amounts between 1 and 3 parts per billion into the water table (Figure 1). Replicated controlled studies on frogs have shown that exposure to atrazine at just 0.1ppb causes significant changes to male frogs’ hormonal profiles, rendering them hermaphroditic. Humans may tolerate higher levels of atrazine than amphibians, but the chemical’s marked effect on animals and ecosystems at levels lower than previously thought is cause for concern. Organic systems, which do not rely on synthetic inputs, leach zero atrazine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Nutrient Density&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://mk0rodaleinstitydwux.kinstacdn.com/wp-content/uploads/Oat-protein-data-chart-FST.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-2278&quot; src=&quot;https://mk0rodaleinstitydwux.kinstacdn.com/wp-content/uploads/Oat-protein-data-chart-FST.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;383&quot; height=&quot;198&quot; srcset=&quot;https://mk0rodaleinstitydwux.kinstacdn.com/wp-content/uploads/Oat-protein-data-chart-FST.jpg 640w, https://mk0rodaleinstitydwux.kinstacdn.com/wp-content/uploads/Oat-protein-data-chart-FST-300x156.jpg 300w, https://mk0rodaleinstitydwux.kinstacdn.com/wp-content/uploads/Oat-protein-data-chart-FST-600x311.jpg 600w, https://mk0rodaleinstitydwux.kinstacdn.com/wp-content/uploads/Oat-protein-data-chart-FST-450x233.jpg 450w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 383px) 100vw, 383px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Figure 2. Crude and total protein as affected by the main effects of cropping systems. T/NT=tilled/no-till; LEG=legume; MNR=manure; CNV=conventional
&lt;p&gt;Organic oats grown in systems utilizing legume cover crops contain significantly greater total protein concentration (Figure 2) along with a suite of essential and non-essential amino acids. We also found significantly greater soil carbon and nitrogen (the building blocks of proteins) in both organic systems compared to the conventional system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Yields&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://mk0rodaleinstitydwux.kinstacdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2016-Record-corn-yields-chart-FST.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-2279&quot; src=&quot;https://mk0rodaleinstitydwux.kinstacdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2016-Record-corn-yields-chart-FST.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;341&quot; height=&quot;258&quot; srcset=&quot;https://mk0rodaleinstitydwux.kinstacdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2016-Record-corn-yields-chart-FST.jpg 582w, https://mk0rodaleinstitydwux.kinstacdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2016-Record-corn-yields-chart-FST-300x228.jpg 300w, https://mk0rodaleinstitydwux.kinstacdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2016-Record-corn-yields-chart-FST-450x342.jpg 450w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 341px) 100vw, 341px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Figure 3. Results from analysis of crop yield in 2016
&lt;p&gt;In 2016, our no-till organic manure systems produced 200 bushels of corn per acre—a record-breaking yield for our county that was almost twice the conventional no-till system (Figure 3).&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 12:08:09 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>sudoaza</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Farming Systems Trial - Rodale Institute</og:title>
<og:description>The Farming Systems Trial (FST)® at Rodale Institute is America’s longest running, side-by-side comparison of organic and chemical agriculture. Learn more about the thirty-year organic farming study.</og:description>
<og:url>https://rodaleinstitute.org/science/farming-systems-trial/</og:url>
<og:image>https://mk0rodaleinstitydwux.kinstacdn.com/wp-content/uploads/rodale-institute_218-e1539354281211.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://rodaleinstitute.org/science/farming-systems-trial/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Rdrview – Firefox Reader View as a Linux command line tool</title>
<link>https://github.com/eafer/rdrview</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/eafer/rdrview</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Command line tool to extract the main content from a webpage, as done by the &quot;Reader View&quot; feature of most modern browsers. It's intended to be used with terminal RSS readers, to make the articles more readable on web browsers such as lynx. The code is closely adapted from &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mozilla/readability&quot;&gt;the Firefox version&lt;/a&gt; and the output is expected to be mostly equivalent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Security&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This tool is young and written in C, so it's reasonable to wonder about the potential for memory issues. To be safe, all HTML parsing happens inside a sandboxed subprocess. Seccomp is used for this purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Usage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are three direct dependencies: libxml2, libseccomp and libcurl. On Debian/Ubuntu, you can install the first two by running (as root):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;apt install libxml2-dev libseccomp-dev
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The libcurl package comes in different flavours, depending on the backend that provides the SSL support. Any of them will do. To install the GnuTLS version:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;apt install libcurl4-gnutls-dev
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For &lt;em&gt;rdrview&lt;/em&gt; to be useful, you should also get a character mode web browser such as lynx:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;apt install lynx
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The name of the packages might differ in your distribution. On Fedora, for example, you can install everything with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;dnf install libcurl-devel libxml2-devel libseccomp-devel lynx
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To build &lt;em&gt;rdrview&lt;/em&gt;, just cd to its directory and run&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;make
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now it should be ready to be used. You can try:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;./rdrview 'https://github.com/eafer/rdrview'
./rdrview &amp;lt; local_file.html
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information, see the man page:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;man ./rdrview.1
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you find &lt;em&gt;rdrview&lt;/em&gt; useful and want to install it, become root again and run&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;make install
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now you can just call it with &lt;code&gt;rdrview&lt;/code&gt; and get help with &lt;code&gt;man rdrview&lt;/code&gt;, like you would for any other tool in your system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Credits&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;rdrview&lt;/em&gt; was written by &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:ernesto.mnd.fernandez@gmail.com&quot;&gt;Ernesto A. Fernández&lt;/a&gt;, but it's mainly a transpilation done by hand of Mozilla's &lt;em&gt;Readability.js&lt;/em&gt;; which was itself, in their own words, &quot;heavily based on Arc90's readability.js&quot;. This is the original license:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;Copyright (c) 2010 Arc90 Inc

Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the &quot;License&quot;);
you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
You may obtain a copy of the License at

   http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
distributed under the License is distributed on an &quot;AS IS&quot; BASIS,
WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
limitations under the License.
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 11:45:47 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ashitlerferad</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars0.githubusercontent.com/u/38570712?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>eafer/rdrview</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/eafer/rdrview</og:url>
<og:description>Firefox Reader View as a Linux command line tool. Contribute to eafer/rdrview development by creating an account on GitHub.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/eafer/rdrview</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>This page is a truly naked, brutalist HTML quine</title>
<link>https://secretgeek.github.io/html_wysiwyg/html.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://secretgeek.github.io/html_wysiwyg/html.html</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;title&gt;This page is a truly naked, brutalist html quine.&lt;/title&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot; readability=&quot;139.87801778907&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite things is to misuse technology in creative ways. Breaking the rules without breaking the rules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, a hobby project I built long ago was &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/secretGeek/dod&quot;&gt;DOS-on-dope&lt;/a&gt;, a working Ruby-on-rails parody, billed as &lt;em&gt;the last batch-file based MVC framework you'll ever need&lt;/em&gt;. And there was &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.secretgeek.net/console_log&quot;&gt;a console.log() adventure&lt;/a&gt; in which you played an old school console-adventure-game from inside the chrome developer tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The world of esoteric programming is filled with examples of people stretching the rules to breaking point, and misusing technology in creative ways. In particular (for example) I love &lt;a href=&quot;http://wiki.secretgeek.net/quine&quot;&gt;quines&lt;/a&gt;. Quines are programs which output their own source code. Life is a Quine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A different but somehow related topic I like is &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brutalist_architecture&quot;&gt;brutalism&lt;/a&gt;, in particular, this often overlooked aspect:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another common theme in Brutalist designs is the exposure of the building's functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...the tendency to &lt;strong&gt;make the internal external&lt;/strong&gt;, and reveal the secrets of the building, in a somehow.... &lt;em&gt;brutaful&lt;/em&gt; way. ;-).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A similarly intriguing idea which has fallen into disuse is the idea of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Naked_objects&quot;&gt;naked objects&lt;/a&gt;, wherein:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The user interface should be a direct representation of the domain objects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Putting all this together I decided to make a truly naked, brutalist html page, that is itself a quine. And this page is it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Viewing &lt;a href=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/secretGeek/html_wysiwyg/master/html.html&quot;&gt;the source&lt;/a&gt; of this page should reveal a page identical to the page you are now seeing. Nothing is hidden. It's a true &quot;What you see is what you get.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How it works.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did you know that the rules of html and css allow you to make &lt;strong&gt;every&lt;/strong&gt; element visible, even elements like 'title' or 'style' or 'script', that are normally hidden from view? Those are just elements like any other. You can expose them &lt;strong&gt;all&lt;/strong&gt; like so:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that snippet of code (which is &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; a snippet of code, but an &lt;strong&gt;actual&lt;/strong&gt; style block itself!) you can now see every element of this page, including that style block, the html and title tags, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It does have one downside: every element on the page is now a &quot;block&quot; element, even some which should be &quot;inline&quot;, such as &quot;code&quot; and &quot;anchor&quot; elements. We can correct this like so:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To give the code a more 'view source' feel, I've also applied &lt;code&gt;monospace&lt;/code&gt; fonts, and a generally simple and consistent style to all elements, using a &quot;*&quot; selector, like so:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far I've put style declarations all on one line, because ordinary html refuses to treat line breaks as &quot;br&quot; tags. But there is a way to make line-breaks display as line-breaks, and that is with this piece of styling:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Make the internal external.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next trick is to make the internal external. We can start by ensuring that the tags themselves, such as paragraph tags, are exposed in their stark, brutal, beauty:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That works for &quot;p&quot; elements, but do we need to have custom styling for &lt;strong&gt;every&lt;/strong&gt; element? If there was a way to output the &quot;name&quot; of a tag in html, then we could reduce all of the necessary style rules above to something like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*::before { '&amp;lt;' name() '&amp;gt;' }&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*::after { '&amp;lt;\/' name() '&amp;gt;' }&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But alas there is no &quot;name()&quot; function (yet!). So we are forced to generate a chunk of style information like this (via &lt;a href=&quot;https://nimbletext.com/Live/1105905186/&quot;&gt;NimbleText&lt;/a&gt; of course)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please scroll happily past the next 28 offensively repetitive lines...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some elements are a little trickier because they have attributes. Consider for example the &quot;anchor&quot; which often has a &lt;code&gt;href&lt;/code&gt; attribute. We &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt; that attribute to be visible, including its value. This is done like so:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;attr()&lt;/code&gt; function, see &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/CSS/attr&quot;&gt;mozilla docs&lt;/a&gt; is a nifty trick, &quot;supported&quot; since CSS 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only other style that is special is &quot;style&quot; itself, which has to include an escape character to avoid being taken literally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside&gt;I like to think that may be a parser bug created by browser developers who did not suspect that people would engage in such an atrocity.&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally to reduce the visual weight of the before and after pseudo elements we can give them a soft purple color and a low weight font:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside&gt;A different though similar thing I wanted to do was to make a &quot;markdown.css&quot; file that displays html as markdown. Fortunately I found that some other twisted person had &lt;a href=&quot;https://mrcoles.com/demo/markdown-css/&quot;&gt;already done exactly that.&lt;/a&gt; Nice work Mr Coles.&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally, because I believe brutalist design, even when applied to truly naked brutal html quines, is about function, not about deliberate ugliness, I'd like to apply these humble styles that improve the readability of this brutiful missive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...they're derived from &lt;a href=&quot;https://jrl.ninja/etc/1/&quot;&gt;&quot;58 bytes of css to look great nearly everywhere&quot;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One last thing. Although this idea has bounced around in my head for a decade, the thing that reminded me to pipe it into a file was seeing this piece of &quot;Code as Art&quot; from Geoff Huntley: &lt;a href=&quot;https://noyaml.com/&quot;&gt;no yaml&lt;/a&gt;. Bring back the world weird web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kind regards&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://secretGeek.net&quot;&gt;Leon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;p.s. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/secretGeek/html_wysiwyg/&quot;&gt;source code here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 10:30:45 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Symmetry</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://secretgeek.github.io/html_wysiwyg/html.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Monospace: A JavaScript demo in 1021 bytes, winner of the demo competition</title>
<link>http://www.p01.org/MONOSPACE/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.p01.org/MONOSPACE/</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;meta charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;/&gt;&lt;title&gt;MONOSPACE by @p01&lt;/title&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;shortcut icon&quot; type=&quot;image/ico&quot; href=&quot;/favicon.ico&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;preload&quot; as=&quot;image&quot; href=&quot;http://www.p01.org/MONOSPACE/monospace.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;viewport&quot; content=&quot;width=device-width,initial-scale=1&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;theme-color&quot; content=&quot;#012&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;author&quot; content=&quot;Mathieu 'p01' Henri,@p01&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;home&quot; href=&quot;/&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;next&quot; href=&quot;/&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;prev&quot; href=&quot;/&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;author&quot; href=&quot;/about/&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;description&quot; content=&quot;MONOSPACE: Flip dots with feelings, a JavaScript demo in 1021 bytes, winner of the 1024 bytes demo competition at Assembly 2020.&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:card&quot; content=&quot;summary_large_image&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:site&quot; content=&quot;@p01&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:creator&quot; content=&quot;@p01&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:title&quot; property=&quot;og:title&quot; content=&quot;MONOSPACE by @p01&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:description&quot; property=&quot;og:description&quot; content=&quot;MONOSPACE: Flip dots with feelings, a JavaScript demo in 1021 bytes, winner of the 1024 bytes demo competition at Assembly 2020.&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:image&quot; property=&quot;og:image&quot; content=&quot;http://www.p01.org/MONOSPACE/monospace.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot; readability=&quot;147.78528827038&quot;&gt;
&lt;header&gt;&lt;nav&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;il&quot; href=&quot;http://www.p01.org/&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;144&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; src=&quot;data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAJAAAAAYBAMAAADni2k+AAAAIVBMVEUAAAAAAAD///8AAAAAAAAAAAD///////+qqqrj4+P////AxbuLAAAACnRSTlMAQA0TIQlVrX/GVjIPEAAAAXpJREFUOMu1lTFPwzAQhc+UlnKTo3bK2JEpkfgBdGWFH9ANKVNWmDJ3YkPKdBaoTe9X8s5VpUgtigzhJU4sX/T56Z3k0I+aUrL0JOrraSzQ80igaTKI9fjsa1TQ/YggFZG3WjFEmJVJVKoNMSYXAhLLyEASodwDBf/xHiT4IKLKGYvkPhQASSJI5fEBDIFCDke5MLU1QHmyo9dam+C1EWE4cgCtBSB3GQQdWeeOviQUKkFOGTFVjWWUCMo8hKfJucyRd1QW5DBJAkFmAmO2m+nNnnGj9BLXq021UTO6Z2IUY0ZREXcGmu3YxgIJ5QjZBaKOCJhQ4PKqWCYrDoHwHcatbQvFcLYVUZC2bmu1ZnbmiHkQpPOO9dq27Zg7A4VggaxxBS98dISKnqkPOnA++eR81s3VvC0M1G7NUdVUTczoAD8oDoCWzlrlJotJ5iCydq1LvHxZlEVmzVyinSgOgJIPo9Xdn48RjSL+NxClglZRdLXq6xeH/2i/o2/w6T7UtOinugAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==&quot; alt=&quot;www.p01.org&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.p01.org/about/&quot;&gt;ABOUT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/nav&gt;
&lt;p&gt;651 words ~ 3-6 mins&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/header&gt;&lt;p&gt;MONOSPACE: Flip dots with feelings, a JavaScript demo in 1021 bytes, winner of the 1024 bytes demo competition at Assembly 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;fw&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;il&quot; href=&quot;http://www.p01.org/MONOSPACE/monospace-compatible.htm&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.assembly.org/online2020/&quot;&gt;Assembly&lt;/a&gt; is a demoscene event with the most anticipated 1kb, 4kb and full size demo competitions. I am absolutely thrilled to win, again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year, it has been difficult to find the mental energy to focus, but working on a creative project was a breath of fresh air. I began to work on MONOSPACE 4 months ago, going through prototypes and fine tuning many details, trying to bring a level of camera work never seen in 1k demos before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Flip dots feelings in 1021 bytes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For MONOSPACE, the main inspiration came from plot writers and flip dots displays like the ones in train stations. After experimenting with speech synthesis in previous productions in 1kb and 256 bytes, I wanted to break the fourth wall. Another thing dear to me was to mimic a handheld camera that slightly shakes and goes out focus to increase the immersion in this monospace world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Techincal tidbits&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, Mozilla still hasn't fixed the &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1190398&quot;&gt;performance bug 1190398 around ShadowBlur&lt;/a&gt;, filled for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.p01.org/BLCK4777/&quot;&gt;BLCK4777&lt;/a&gt; 5 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore you need to use a Chromium or Webkit browser to enjoy MONOSPACE live. To watch the packed version, you might have to allow Audio/Sound in the Permisions or Site or Settings of your browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Otherwise, I recommend the video capture of the final result as that is often easier to watch than a production highly optimized for size and the hardware used for the competition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/2HN139WkcCY&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Compression&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the technical side, MONOSPACE is compressed using the PNG bootstrapping technique I described multiple times. The hand minified code takes 1497 bytes before compression and fits into 818 bytes of DEFLATE stream + the PNG headers and the bootstrapper = 1021 bytes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Minified code&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the setup of MONOSPACE. It takes 59 bytes to provide a canvas and rendering context.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-javascript&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;canvas id=&quot;c&quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/canvas&amp;gt;&amp;lt;script&amp;gt;b=c.getContext`2d`&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The minified code of MONOSPACE itself is 1438 bytes long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-javascript&quot;&gt;d=[2280,1280,1520,c.width=1920,document.body.style.font=&quot;0px MONOSPACE&quot;],g=new AudioContext,o=g.createScriptProcessor(4096,document.body.style.margin=t=n=0,1),o.connect(g.destination),o.onaudioprocess=o=&amp;gt;{o=o.outputBuffer.getChannelData(e=Math.sin(t/16%1,m=Math.sin(Math.min(1,y=t/128)*Math.PI)**.5+.1,c.height=1080,b.shadowOffsetY=32420,c.style.background=&quot;radial-gradient(#&quot;+[222,222,222,222,155,155,102,102][t/16&amp;amp;7]+&quot;,black&quot;,b.font=&quot;920 32px MONOSPACE&quot;,f=[(x,y,t)=&amp;gt;x/y*2-t,(x,y,t)=&amp;gt;(x**2+y**2)**.5-t,(x,y,t)=&amp;gt;x/4^y/4-t,(x,y,t)=&amp;gt;y%x-t][t/16&amp;amp;3],u=&quot;&quot;+[[,f,f,&quot; CAN YOU HEAR ME&quot;,f,f,,&quot;MONOSPACE&quot;,&quot;THE END&quot;][t/16|0]],t&amp;gt;n&amp;amp;&amp;amp;speechSynthesis.speak(new SpeechSynthesisUtterance(u,n+=16))));for(i=0;4096&amp;gt;4*i;i++)g[i]=r=(f(x=16-i%32,a=16-(i/32|0),t)/2&amp;amp;1)+(g[i]||0)/2,x+=o[0]/4+4*(1-m**.3)*Math.sin(i+t+8),a+=o[64]/4+4*(1-m**.3)*Math.sin(i+t),h=x*Math.sin(y*2+8)+a*Math.sin(y*2),p=4096/(m*32+4*h*Math.sin(e)+t%16),b.beginPath(f[i]=r/p),b.arc(h*Math.sin(e+8)*p+1280,x*Math.sin(y*2)*p-a*Math.sin(y*2+8)*p-31920,p&amp;gt;0&amp;amp;&amp;amp;p/(2+32-r*16),0,8),b.shadowBlur=o[0]**2*32+32-m*32+4+h*h/2,b.shadowColor=&quot;hsl(&quot;+[f(x,y,t)&amp;amp;2?t-a*8:180,(t&amp;amp;64)*m+&quot;%&quot;,(t&amp;amp;64)*m+&quot;%&quot;],b.fill();b.shadowBlur=o[0]**2*32,b.shadowColor=&quot;#fee&quot;;for(i=0;4096&amp;gt;i;i++)o[i]=o[i]/2+((Math.sin(t*d[t/[4,4,4,4,1/4,1/4,16,4][t/16&amp;amp;7]&amp;amp;3]*Math.PI)*8+(t*d[t/8&amp;amp;3]/2&amp;amp;6)+t*d[t/16&amp;amp;3]/4%6)/64+f[i/4|0])*m,64&amp;gt;i&amp;amp;t%16*6&amp;gt;i&amp;amp;&amp;amp;b.fillText([u[i+(o[i]*2&amp;amp;1)]],i%9*32+o[0]*16+180,(i/9|0)*64+o[64]*16-t-31920),t+=1/g.sampleRate}&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal is keep the heatmap of the DEFLATE stream as cool as possible which means that most characters take a few bits to endode, while a few charachters are red hot and take 8 or more bits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;fw&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Visual, Audio &amp;amp; Speech in a nutshell&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rendering uses 2D Canvas, abusing ShadowBlur to render everything with the depth of field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Audio uses scriptProcessingNode, abusing the onAudioProcess event to render the Audio and Visuals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Audio and Visuals feed each other to get perfect synch of the camera shake, depth of field and soundscape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The speech synthesis, allows to speak out the function feeding the visuals, and the &quot;feelings&quot; of the flip dots display.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Chef kiss&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, yes &lt;strong&gt;MONOSPACE&lt;/strong&gt; is named after the font family used to write the text, to gain a few bytes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Additional links&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Other recent experiments&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many experiments and projects like &lt;strong&gt;MONOSPACE&lt;/strong&gt; to discover other here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Let's talk&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don't be shy; get in touch by &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:mathieu@p01.org&quot;&gt;mail&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/p01&quot;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/p01&quot;&gt;github&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://no.linkedin.com/in/iamp01/&quot;&gt;linkedin&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pouet.net/user.php?who=59&quot;&gt;pouet&lt;/a&gt; if you have any questions, feedback, speaking, workshop or performance opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;footer&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.p01.org/about/&quot;&gt;Mathieu 'p01' Henri on October 16th, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/footer&gt;&lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 08:28:40 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>pekko</dc:creator>
<og:title>MONOSPACE by @p01</og:title>
<og:description>MONOSPACE: Flip dots with feelings, a JavaScript demo in 1021 bytes, winner of the 1024 bytes demo competition at Assembly 2020.</og:description>
<og:image>http://www.p01.org/MONOSPACE/monospace.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.p01.org/MONOSPACE/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>