<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>A California mall operator is sharing license plate tracking data with ICE</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2018/07/10/alpr-license-plate-recognition-ice-irvine-company/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2018/07/10/alpr-license-plate-recognition-ice-irvine-company/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;A chain of California shopping centers is sharing its license plate reader data with a well-known U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE) contractor, giving that agency the ability to track license plate numbers it captures in near real-time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2018/07/california-shopping-centers-are-spying-ice-contractor&quot;&gt;report from the Electronic Frontier Foundation&lt;/a&gt; revealed that real estate group Irvine Company shares that data with Vigilant Solutions, a private surveillance tech company that sells automated license plate recognition (ALPR) equipment to law enforcement and government agencies. Irvine Company owns nearly &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.shopirvinecompany.com/centers/&quot;&gt;50 shopping centers across California&lt;/a&gt; with locations in Irvine, La Jolla, Newport Beach, Redwood City, San Jose, Santa Clara and Sunnyvale. ICE finalized its contract with Vigilant Solutions in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2018/1/26/16932350/ice-immigration-customs-license-plate-recognition-contract-vigilant-solutions&quot;&gt;January of this year&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EFF investigative researcher Dave Maass discovered Irvine Company’s data-sharing activities in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.shopirvinecompany.com/legal/alpr-policy/&quot;&gt;page detailing its ALPR policy&lt;/a&gt;, a disclosure required by California law. Ironically, while Irvine Company’s ALPR usage and privacy policy does describe its own practice of deleting the license data it collects once transmitted, it admits that it does in fact transmit all of it straight to Vigilant Solutions, which has no such qualms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Vigilant describes, the key offering in its “advanced suite” of license reading tech is unfettered access to a massive trove of license plate data:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A hallmark of Vigilant’s solution, the ability for agencies to share real-time data nationwide amongst over 1,000 agencies and tap into our exclusive commercial LPR database of over 5 billion vehicle detections, sets our platform apart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Irvine Company is only one example of this kind of data sharing, but it illustrates the ubiquity of the kind of privately owned modern surveillance technology at the fingertips of anyone willing to pay for it. While we’re likely to see more &lt;a href=&quot;https://acluva.org/en/press-releases/virginia-supreme-court-rules-random-surveillance-police-not-exempt-virginias&quot;&gt;state-level legal challenges&lt;/a&gt; to license plate tracking technology, for now the powerful pairing of license plate numbers and location data is mostly fair game for anyone who wants to make money off collecting and aggregating it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 22:56:42 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>srameshc</dc:creator>
<og:title>California malls are sharing license plate tracking data with ICE</og:title>
<og:description>A chain of California shopping centers is sharing its license plate reader data with a well-known U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE) contractor, giving that agency the ability to track license plate numbers it captures in near real-time. A report from the Electronic Frontier Foundation …</og:description>
<og:image>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/surveillance.png?w=711</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2018/07/10/alpr-license-plate-recognition-ice-irvine-company/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2018/07/10/alpr-license-plate-recognition-ice-irvine-company/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Trial wipes out over 80% of Australian disease-spreading mosquito</title>
<link>https://www.csiro.au/en/News/News-releases/2018/Trial-wipes-out-more-than-80-per-cent-of-disease-spreading-mozzie?featured=F29EDEB1728C4A92B579C7A5DC28BAD5</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.csiro.au/en/News/News-releases/2018/Trial-wipes-out-more-than-80-per-cent-of-disease-spreading-mozzie?featured=F29EDEB1728C4A92B579C7A5DC28BAD5</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;One of the world’s most widespread disease-spreading mosquitoes, the Aedes aegypti, has been suppressed by more than 80 per cent in a landmark Australian trial.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;101&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an international partnership between CSIRO, Verily and James Cook University, scientists used specialised technology to release millions of sterilised male &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Aedes aegypti&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mosquitoes across the Cassowary Coast in Queensland in a bid to combat the global pest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CSIRO Director of Health and Biosecurity Dr Rob Grenfell said the results were a major win in the fight against diseases-spreading mosquitoes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;The invasive &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Aedes aegypti&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mosquito is one of the world’s most dangerous pests, capable of spreading devastating diseases like dengue, Zika and chikungunya and responsible for infecting millions of people with disease around the world each year,&quot; Dr Grenfell said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Increased urbanisation and warming temperatures mean that more people are at risk, as these mosquitoes which were once relegated to areas near the equator forge past previous climatic boundaries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Although the majority of mosquitoes don’t spread diseases, the three mostly deadly types the &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Aedes, Anopheles&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Culex&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; are found almost all over the world and are responsible for around 17 per cent of infectious disease transmissions globally.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From November 2017 to June this year, non-biting male &lt;em&gt;Aedes aegypti&lt;/em&gt; mosquitoes sterilised with the natural bacteria &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Wolbachia&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; were released in trial zones along the Cassowary Coast in North Queensland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They mated with local female mosquitoes, resulting in eggs that did not hatch and a significant reduction of their population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Our heartfelt thanks goes out to the Innisfail community who literally opened their doors to our team, letting us install mosquito traps around their homes and businesses – we couldn’t have done this without your support,&quot; Dr Grenfell said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The process, known as the Sterile Insect Technique, has been successfully used since the 1950s but the challenge in making it work for mosquitoes like the &lt;em&gt;Aedes aegypti&lt;/em&gt; has been rearing enough mosquitoes, removing biting females, identifying the males and then releasing the huge numbers needed to suppress a population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To address this challenge, Verily, an affiliate of Alphabet Inc, developed a mosquito rearing and sex sorting and release technology as part of its global &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Debug&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;We're very pleased to see strong suppression of these dangerous biting female &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Aedes aegypti&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mosquitoes,&quot; Verily’s Nigel Snoad said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;We are particularly thankful to the people of Innisfail for their strong support, which has been incredible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;We came to Innisfail with CSIRO and JCU to see how this approach worked in a tropical environment where these mosquitoes thrive, and to learn what it was like to operate our technology with research collaborators as we work together to find new ways to tackle these dangerous mosquitoes.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientists compared the number of &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Aedes aegypti&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; mosquitoes trapped in release sites and control zones to monitor and track populations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The millions of mosquitoes needed for the trial were reared at James Cook University in Cairns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To produce the three million male mosquitoes needed for the trial, researchers at James Cook University (JCU) in Cairns set out to raise almost 20 million &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Aedes aegypti&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;We allowed for the possibility of deaths during the process, as well as the need to sift out the female half of the population,&quot; Dr Kyran Staunton from James Cook University said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Verily's technology enabled us to do the sex sorting faster and with much higher accuracy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;We learnt a lot from collaborating on this first tropical trial and we’re excited to see how this approach might be applied in other regions where &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Aedes aegypti&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; poses a threat to life and health.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;The health of our nation is paramount as we help Australia achieve its vision to become one of the healthiest nations on earth,&quot; CSIRO Chief Executive Dr Larry Marshall said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;By enabling industry partners like Verily to leverage the world-leading health capability we have built in CSIRO we can deliver this moonshot and tackle some of the world’s most wicked challenges with science.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 17:48:40 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>sjbase</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.csiro.au/en/News/News-releases/2018/Trial-wipes-out-more-than-80-per-cent-of-disease-spreading-mozzie?featured=F29EDEB1728C4A92B579C7A5DC28BAD5</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Nearly 1,000 Paintings and Drawings by Vincent van Gogh Digitized and Put Online</title>
<link>http://www.openculture.com/2018/07/nearly-1000-paintings-drawings-vincent-van-gogh-now-digitized-put-online-view-download-collection.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.openculture.com/2018/07/nearly-1000-paintings-drawings-vincent-van-gogh-now-digitized-put-online-view-download-collection.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1053740&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn8.openculture.com/2018/07/08215020/The-Bedroom-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1920&quot; height=&quot;1516&quot; srcset=&quot;http://cdn8.openculture.com/2018/07/08215020/The-Bedroom-1.jpg 1920w, http://cdn8.openculture.com/2018/07/08215020/The-Bedroom-1-150x118.jpg 150w, http://cdn8.openculture.com/2018/07/08215020/The-Bedroom-1-300x237.jpg 300w, http://cdn8.openculture.com/2018/07/08215020/The-Bedroom-1-768x606.jpg 768w, http://cdn8.openculture.com/2018/07/08215020/The-Bedroom-1-1024x809.jpg 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every artist explores dimensions of space and place, orienting themselves and their works in the world, and orienting their audiences. Then there are artists like Vincent van Gogh, who make space and place a primary subject. In his early paintings of peasant homes and fields, his figures’ muscular shoulders and hands interact with sturdy walls and gnarled trees. Later country scenes—whether curling and delicate, like &lt;em&gt;Wheatfield with a Reaper, &lt;/em&gt;or heavy and ominous, like &lt;em&gt;Wheatfield with Crows &lt;/em&gt;(both below)—give us the sense of the landscape as a single living entity, pulsating, writhing, blazing in brilliant yellows, reds, greens, and blues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1053741&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn8.openculture.com/2018/07/08215102/Van-Gogh-Wheatfield-with-Reaper.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1920&quot; height=&quot;1518&quot; srcset=&quot;http://cdn8.openculture.com/2018/07/08215102/Van-Gogh-Wheatfield-with-Reaper.jpg 1920w, http://cdn8.openculture.com/2018/07/08215102/Van-Gogh-Wheatfield-with-Reaper-150x119.jpg 150w, http://cdn8.openculture.com/2018/07/08215102/Van-Gogh-Wheatfield-with-Reaper-300x237.jpg 300w, http://cdn8.openculture.com/2018/07/08215102/Van-Gogh-Wheatfield-with-Reaper-768x607.jpg 768w, http://cdn8.openculture.com/2018/07/08215102/Van-Gogh-Wheatfield-with-Reaper-1024x810.jpg 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Van Gogh painted interior scenes, such as his famous &lt;em&gt;The Bedroom&lt;/em&gt;, at the top (the first of three versions), with an eye toward using color as the means of making space purposeful: “It’s just simply my bedroom,” he wrote to Paul Gauguin of the 1888 painting, “only here color is to do everything… to be suggestive here of rest or of sleep in general. In a word, looking at the picture ought to rest the brain, or rather the imagination.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1053742&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn8.openculture.com/2018/07/08215146/Van-Gogh-Wheatfield-with-Crows.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1920&quot; height=&quot;920&quot; srcset=&quot;http://cdn8.openculture.com/2018/07/08215146/Van-Gogh-Wheatfield-with-Crows.jpg 1920w, http://cdn8.openculture.com/2018/07/08215146/Van-Gogh-Wheatfield-with-Crows-150x72.jpg 150w, http://cdn8.openculture.com/2018/07/08215146/Van-Gogh-Wheatfield-with-Crows-300x144.jpg 300w, http://cdn8.openculture.com/2018/07/08215146/Van-Gogh-Wheatfield-with-Crows-768x368.jpg 768w, http://cdn8.openculture.com/2018/07/08215146/Van-Gogh-Wheatfield-with-Crows-1024x491.jpg 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So taken was the painter with the concept of using color to induce “rest or sleep” in his viewers’ imaginations that when water damage threated the “stability” of the first painting, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.artic.edu/exhibition/van-goghs-bedrooms&quot;&gt;Chicago’s Art Institute notes&lt;/a&gt;, “he became determined to preserve the composition by painting a second version while at an asylum in Saint-Rémy in 1889,” then demonstrated the deep emotional resonance this scene had for him by painting a third, smaller version for his mother and sister.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1053743&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn8.openculture.com/2018/07/08215316/Van-Gogh-Old-Vineyard.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1920&quot; height=&quot;1558&quot; srcset=&quot;http://cdn8.openculture.com/2018/07/08215316/Van-Gogh-Old-Vineyard.jpg 1920w, http://cdn8.openculture.com/2018/07/08215316/Van-Gogh-Old-Vineyard-150x122.jpg 150w, http://cdn8.openculture.com/2018/07/08215316/Van-Gogh-Old-Vineyard-300x243.jpg 300w, http://cdn8.openculture.com/2018/07/08215316/Van-Gogh-Old-Vineyard-768x623.jpg 768w, http://cdn8.openculture.com/2018/07/08215316/Van-Gogh-Old-Vineyard-1024x831.jpg 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The opportunity to see all of Van Gogh’s bedroom paintings in one place may have passed us by for now—an exhibit in Chicago brought them together in 2016. But we can see the original bedroom at the yellow house in Arles in a virtual space, along with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vangoghmuseum.nl/en/search/collection?q=&amp;amp;artist=Vincent%20van%20Gogh&amp;amp;pagesize=105&quot;&gt;almost 1,000 more Van Gogh paintings and drawings, at the Van Gogh Museum in Amsterdam's site&lt;/a&gt;. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vangoghmuseum.nl/en/search/collection?q=&amp;amp;artist=Vincent%20van%20Gogh&amp;amp;pagesize=105&quot;&gt;digitized collection&lt;/a&gt; showcases a vast amount of Van Gogh’s work—including not only landscapes, but also his many portraits, self-portraits, drawings, city scenes, and still-lifes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1053744&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn8.openculture.com/2018/07/08215336/Van-Gogh-Shoes.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1920&quot; height=&quot;1595&quot; srcset=&quot;http://cdn8.openculture.com/2018/07/08215336/Van-Gogh-Shoes.jpg 1920w, http://cdn8.openculture.com/2018/07/08215336/Van-Gogh-Shoes-150x125.jpg 150w, http://cdn8.openculture.com/2018/07/08215336/Van-Gogh-Shoes-300x249.jpg 300w, http://cdn8.openculture.com/2018/07/08215336/Van-Gogh-Shoes-768x638.jpg 768w, http://cdn8.openculture.com/2018/07/08215336/Van-Gogh-Shoes-1024x851.jpg 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One way to approach these works is through the unifying themes above: how does van Gogh use color to communicate space and place, and to what effect? Even in portraits and still-lifes, his figures compete with the ground. The scored and scalloped paintings of walls, floors, and wallpaper force our attention past the staring eyes of the painter or the finely-rendered fruits and shoes, and into the depths and textures of shadow and light. We begin to see people and objects as inseparable from their surroundings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1053745&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn8.openculture.com/2018/07/08215400/Van-Gogh-The-Sower.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1920&quot; height=&quot;1542&quot; srcset=&quot;http://cdn8.openculture.com/2018/07/08215400/Van-Gogh-The-Sower.jpg 1920w, http://cdn8.openculture.com/2018/07/08215400/Van-Gogh-The-Sower-150x120.jpg 150w, http://cdn8.openculture.com/2018/07/08215400/Van-Gogh-The-Sower-300x241.jpg 300w, http://cdn8.openculture.com/2018/07/08215400/Van-Gogh-The-Sower-768x617.jpg 768w, http://cdn8.openculture.com/2018/07/08215400/Van-Gogh-The-Sower-1024x822.jpg 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Painting is a faith,” Van Gogh once wrote, and it is as if his paintings ask us to contemplate the spiritual unity of all things; the same animating flame brings every object in his blazing worlds to life. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vangoghmuseum.nl/en/search/collection?q=&amp;amp;artist=Vincent%20van%20Gogh&amp;amp;pagesize=105&quot;&gt;Van Gogh Museum&lt;/a&gt; houses the largest collection of the artist’s work in the world. On &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vangoghmuseum.nl/en&quot;&gt;their website&lt;/a&gt; you can read essays about his life and work, plan a visit, or shop at the online store. But most importantly, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vangoghmuseum.nl/en/search/collection?q=&amp;amp;artist=Vincent%20van%20Gogh&amp;amp;pagesize=105&quot;&gt;you can experience the stunning breadth of his art through your screen&lt;/a&gt;—no replacement for the physical spaces of galleries, but a worthy means nonetheless of communing with Van Gogh’s vision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1053746&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn8.openculture.com/2018/07/08215417/Van-Gogh-Self-Portrait-with-pipe.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1300&quot; height=&quot;1580&quot; srcset=&quot;http://cdn8.openculture.com/2018/07/08215417/Van-Gogh-Self-Portrait-with-pipe.jpg 1300w, http://cdn8.openculture.com/2018/07/08215417/Van-Gogh-Self-Portrait-with-pipe-123x150.jpg 123w, http://cdn8.openculture.com/2018/07/08215417/Van-Gogh-Self-Portrait-with-pipe-247x300.jpg 247w, http://cdn8.openculture.com/2018/07/08215417/Van-Gogh-Self-Portrait-with-pipe-768x933.jpg 768w, http://cdn8.openculture.com/2018/07/08215417/Van-Gogh-Self-Portrait-with-pipe-843x1024.jpg 843w, http://cdn8.openculture.com/2018/07/08215417/Van-Gogh-Self-Portrait-with-pipe-300x365.jpg 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1300px) 100vw, 1300px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Related Content:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.openculture.com/2017/11/2000-impressionist-post-impressionist-early-modern-paintings-now-free-online-thanks-to-the-barnes-foundation.html&quot;&gt;2,000+ Impressionist, Post-impressionist &amp;amp; Early Modern Paintings Now Free Online, Thanks to the Barnes Foundation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.openculture.com/2012/06/simon_schama_presents_vincent_van_gogh_and_the_beginning_of_modern_art.html&quot;&gt;Simon Schama Presents Van Gogh and the Beginning of Modern Art&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.openculture.com/2017/02/vincent-van-gogh-will-be-made-out-of-65000-van-gogh-style-paintings.html&quot;&gt;New Animated Film About Vincent Van Gogh Will Be Made Out of 65,000 Van Gogh-Style Paintings: Watch the Trailer and Making-Of Video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://about.me/jonesjoshua&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Josh Jones&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; is a writer and musician based in Durham, NC. Follow him at &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jdmagness&quot;&gt;@jdmagness&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;







&lt;br/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 15:50:42 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>leephillips</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>http://www.openculture.com/2018/07/nearly-1000-paintings-drawings-vincent-van-gogh-now-digitized-put-online-view-download-collection.html</og:url>
<og:title>Nearly 1,000 Paintings &amp; Drawings by Vincent van Gogh Now Digitized and Put Online: View/Download the Collection</og:title>
<og:image>http://cdn8.openculture.com/2018/07/08215020/The-Bedroom-1.jpg</og:image>
<og:description> Every artist explores dimensions of space and place, orienting themselves and their works in the world, and orienting their audiences. Then there are artists like Vincent van Gogh, who make space and place a primary subject.</og:description>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.openculture.com/2018/07/nearly-1000-paintings-drawings-vincent-van-gogh-now-digitized-put-online-view-download-collection.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Goodbye Microservices: From 100s of problem children to 1 superstar</title>
<link>https://segment.com/blog/goodbye-microservices/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://segment.com/blog/goodbye-microservices/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Unless you’ve been living under a rock, you probably already know that microservices is the architecture &lt;em&gt;du jour&lt;/em&gt;. Coming of age alongside this trend, Segment &lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com/blog/why-microservices/&quot;&gt;adopted this as a best practice&lt;/a&gt; early-on, which served us well in some cases, and, as you’ll soon learn, not so well in others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Briefly, microservices is a service-oriented software architecture in which server-side applications are constructed by combining many single-purpose, low-footprint network services. The touted benefits are improved modularity, reduced testing burden, better functional composition, environmental isolation, and development team autonomy. The opposite is a Monolithic architecture, where a large amount of functionality lives in a single service which is tested, deployed, and scaled as a single unit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In early 2017 we reached a tipping point with a core piece of &lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com/product&quot;&gt;Segment’s product&lt;/a&gt;. It seemed as if we were falling from the microservices tree, hitting every branch on the way down. Instead of enabling us to move faster, the small team found themselves mired in exploding complexity. Essential benefits of this architecture became burdens. As our velocity plummeted, our defect rate exploded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually, the team found themselves unable to make headway, with 3 full-time engineers spending most of their time just keeping the system alive. Something had to change. This post is the story of how we took a step back and embraced an approach that aligned well with our product requirements and needs of the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Segment’s customer data infrastructure ingests hundreds of thousands of events per second and forwards them to partner APIs, what we refer to as &lt;strong&gt;server-side destinations&lt;/strong&gt;. There are over one hundred types of these destinations, such as Google Analytics, Optimizely, or a custom webhook. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Years back, when the product initially launched, the architecture was simple. There was an API that ingested events and forwarded them to a distributed message queue. An event, in this case, is a JSON object generated by a web or mobile app containing information about users and their actions. A sample payload looks like the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre data-language=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;{
  &quot;type&quot;: &quot;identify&quot;,
  &quot;traits&quot;: {
    &quot;name&quot;: &quot;Alex Noonan&quot;,
    &quot;email&quot;: &quot;anoonan@segment.com&quot;,
    &quot;company&quot;: &quot;Segment&quot;,
    &quot;title&quot;: &quot;Software Engineer&quot;
  },
  &quot;userId&quot;: &quot;97980cfea0067&quot;
}&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As events were consumed from the queue, customer-managed settings were checked to decide which destinations should receive the event. The event was then sent to each destination’s API, one after another, which was useful because developers only need to send their event to a single endpoint, Segment’s API, instead of building potentially dozens of integrations. Segment handles making the request to every destination endpoint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If one of the requests to a destination fails, sometimes we’ll try sending that event again at a later time. Some failures are safe to retry while others are not. Retry-able errors are those that could potentially be accepted by the destination with no changes. For example, HTTP 500s, rate limits, and timeouts. Non-retry-able errors are requests that we can be sure will never be accepted by the destination. For example, requests which have invalid credentials or are missing required fields.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.contents.io/asset_QhV9GV3m.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;At this point, a single queue contained both the newest events as well as those which may have had several retry attempts, across all destinations, which resulted in &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Head-of-line_blocking&quot;&gt;head-of-line blocking&lt;/a&gt;. Meaning in this particular case, if one destination slowed or went down, retries would flood the queue, resulting in delays across &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; our destinations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine destination X is experiencing a temporary issue and every request errors with a timeout. Now, not only does this create a large backlog of requests which have yet to reach destination X, but also every failed event is put back to retry in the queue. While our systems would automatically scale in response to increased load, the sudden increase in queue depth would outpace our ability to scale up, resulting in delays for the newest events. Delivery times for all destinations would increase because destination X had a momentary outage. Customers rely on the timeliness of this delivery, so we can’t afford increases in wait times anywhere in our pipeline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.contents.io/asset_joMYeSNt.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;To solve the head-of-line blocking problem, the team created a separate service and queue for each destination. This new architecture consisted of an additional router process that receives the inbound events and distributes a copy of the event to each selected destination. Now if one destination experienced problems, only it’s queue would back up and no other destinations would be impacted. This microservice-style architecture isolated the destinations from one another, which was crucial when one destination experienced issues as they often do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.contents.io/asset_ElKl4CZv.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each destination API uses a different request format, requiring custom code to translate the event to match this format. A basic example is destination X requires sending birthday as &lt;code&gt;traits.dob&lt;/code&gt; in the payload whereas our API accepts it as &lt;code&gt;traits.birthday&lt;/code&gt;. The transformation code in destination X would look something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre data-language=&quot;c-plus-plus&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;const traits = {}
traits.dob = segmentEvent.birthday&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many modern destination endpoints have adopted Segment’s request format making some transforms relatively simple. However, these transforms can be very complex depending on the structure of the destination’s API. For example, for some of the older and most sprawling destinations, we find ourselves shoving values into hand-crafted XML payloads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initially, when the destinations were divided into separate services, all of the code lived in one repo. A huge point of frustration was that a single broken test caused tests to fail across all destinations. When we wanted to deploy a change, we had to spend time fixing the broken test even if the changes had nothing to do with the initial change. In response to this problem, it was decided to break out the code for each destination into their own repos. All the destinations were already broken out into their own service, so the transition was natural.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The split to separate repos allowed us to isolate the destination test suites easily. This isolation allowed the development team to move quickly when maintaining destinations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As time went on, we added over 50 new destinations, and that meant 50 new repos. To ease the burden of developing and maintaining these codebases, we created shared libraries to make common transforms and functionality, such as HTTP request handling, across our destinations easier and more uniform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, if we want the name of a user from an event, &lt;code&gt;event.name()&lt;/code&gt; can be called in any destination’s code. The shared library checks the event for the property key &lt;code&gt;name&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Name&lt;/code&gt;. If those don’t exist, it checks for a first name, checking the properties &lt;code&gt;firstName&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;first_name&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;FirstName&lt;/code&gt;. It does the same for the last name, checking the cases and combining the two to form the full name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre data-language=&quot;javascript&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;Identify.prototype.name = function() {
  var name = this.proxy('traits.name');
  if (typeof name === 'string') {
    return trim(name)
  }
  
  var firstName = this.firstName();
  var lastName = this.lastName();
  if (firstName &amp;amp;&amp;amp; lastName) {
    return trim(firstName + ' ' + lastName)
  }
}&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The shared libraries made building new destinations quick. The familiarity brought by a uniform set of shared functionality made maintenance less of a headache.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, a new problem began to arise. Testing and deploying changes to these shared libraries impacted all of our destinations. It began to require considerable time and effort to maintain. Making changes to improve our libraries, knowing we’d have to test and deploy dozens of services, was a risky proposition. When pressed for time, engineers would only include the updated versions of these libraries on a single destination’s codebase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over time, the versions of these shared libraries began to diverge across the different destination codebases. The great benefit we once had of reduced customization between each destination codebase started to reverse. Eventually, all of them were using different versions of these shared libraries. We could’ve built tools to automate rolling out changes, but at this point, not only was developer productivity suffering but we began to encounter other issues with the microservice architecture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The additional problem is that each service had a distinct load pattern. Some services would handle a handful of events per day while others handled thousands of events per second. For destinations that handled a small number of events, an operator would have to manually scale the service up to meet demand whenever there was an unexpected spike in load.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While we did have auto-scaling implemented, each service had a distinct blend of required CPU and memory resources, which made tuning the auto-scaling configuration more art than science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The number of destinations continued to grow rapidly, with the team adding three destinations per month on average, which meant more repos, more queues, and more services. With our microservice architecture, our operational overhead increased linearly with each added destination. Therefore, we decided to take a step back and rethink the entire pipeline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first item on the list was to consolidate the now over 140 services into a single service. The overhead from managing all of these services was a huge tax on our team. We were literally losing sleep over it since it was common for the on-call engineer to get paged to deal with load spikes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the architecture at the time would have made moving to a single service challenging. With a separate queue per destination, each worker would have to check every queue for work, which would have added a layer of complexity to the destination service with which we weren’t comfortable. This was the main inspiration for &lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com/blog/introducing-centrifuge/&quot;&gt;Centrifuge&lt;/a&gt;. Centrifuge would replace all our individual queues and be responsible for sending events to the single monolithic service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.contents.io/asset_a0ViVzT6.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given that there would only be one service, it made sense to move all the destination code into one repo, which meant merging all the different dependencies and tests into a single repo. We knew this was going to be messy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For each of the 120 unique dependencies, we committed to having one version for all our destinations. As we moved destinations over, we’d check the dependencies it was using and update them to the latest versions. We fixed anything in the destinations that broke with the newer versions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this transition, we no longer needed to keep track of the differences between dependency versions. All our destinations were using the same version, which significantly reduced the complexity across the codebase. Maintaining destinations now became less time consuming and less risky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also wanted a test suite that allowed us to quickly and easily run all our destination tests. Running all the tests was one of the main blockers when making updates to the shared libraries we discussed earlier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, the destination tests all had a similar structure. They had basic unit tests to verify our custom transform logic was correct and would execute HTTP requests to the partner’s endpoint to verify that events showed up in the destination as expected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recall that the original motivation for separating each destination codebase into its own repo was to isolate test failures. However, it turned out this was a false advantage. Tests that made HTTP requests were still failing with some frequency. With destinations separated into their own repos, there was little motivation to clean up failing tests. This poor hygiene led to a constant source of frustrating technical debt. Often a small change that should have only taken an hour or two would end up requiring a couple of days to a week to complete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The outbound HTTP requests to destination endpoints during the test run was the primary cause of failing tests. Unrelated issues like expired credentials shouldn’t fail tests. We also knew from experience that some destination endpoints were much slower than others. Some destinations took up to 5 minutes to run their tests. With over 140 destinations, our test suite could take up to an hour to run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To solve for both of these, we created Traffic Recorder. Traffic Recorder is built on top of &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flickr/yakbak&quot;&gt;yakbak&lt;/a&gt;, and is responsible for recording and saving destinations’ test traffic. Whenever a test runs for the first time, any requests and their corresponding responses are recorded to a file. On subsequent test runs, the request and response in the file is played back instead requesting the destination’s endpoint. These files are checked into the repo so that the tests are consistent across every change. Now that the test suite is no longer dependent on these HTTP requests over the internet, our tests became significantly more resilient, a must-have for the migration to a single repo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember running the tests for every destination for the first time, after we integrated Traffic Recorder. It took milliseconds to complete running the tests for all 140+ of our destinations. In the past, just one destination could have taken a couple of minutes to complete. &lt;em&gt;It felt like magic.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the code for all destinations lived in a single repo, they could be merged into a single service. With every destination living in one service, our developer productivity substantially improved. We no longer had to deploy 140+ services for a change to one of the shared libraries. One engineer can deploy the service in a matter of minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The proof was in the improved velocity. In 2016, when our microservice architecture was still in place, we made 32 improvements to our shared libraries. Just this year we’ve made 46 improvements. We’ve made more improvements to our libraries in the past 6 months than in all of 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The change also benefited our operational story. With every destination living in one service, we had a good mix of CPU and memory-intense destinations, which made scaling the service to meet demand significantly easier. The large worker pool can absorb spikes in load, so we no longer get paged for destinations that process small amounts of load.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving from our microservice architecture to a monolith overall was huge improvement, however, there are trade-offs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol readability=&quot;10.5&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fault isolation is difficult.&lt;/strong&gt; With everything running in a monolith, if a bug is introduced in one destination that causes the service to crash, the service will crash for all destinations. We have comprehensive automated testing in place, but tests can only get you so far. We are currently working on a much more robust way to prevent one destination from taking down the entire service while still keeping all the destinations in a monolith.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In-memory caching is less effective.&lt;/strong&gt; Previously, with one service per destination, our low traffic destinations only had a handful of processes, which meant their in-memory caches of control plane data would stay hot. Now that cache is spread thinly across 3000+ processes so it’s much less likely to be hit. We could use something like Redis to solve for this, but then that’s another point of scaling for which we’d have to account. In the end, we accepted this loss of efficiency given the substantial operational benefits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Updating the version of a dependency may break multiple destinations.&lt;/strong&gt; While moving everything to one repo solved the previous dependency mess we were in, it means that if we want to use the newest version of a library, we’ll potentially have to update other destinations to work with the newer version. In our opinion though, the simplicity of this approach is worth the trade-off. And with our comprehensive automated test suite, we can quickly see what breaks with a newer dependency version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our initial microservice architecture worked for a time, solving the immediate performance issues in our pipeline by isolating the destinations from each other. However, we weren’t set up to scale. We lacked the proper tooling for testing and deploying the microservices when bulk updates were needed. As a result, our developer productivity quickly declined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moving to a monolith allowed us to rid our pipeline of operational issues while significantly increasing developer productivity. We didn’t make this transition lightly though and knew there were things we had to consider if it was going to work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol readability=&quot;1.5&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We needed a rock solid testing suite to put everything into one repo. Without this, we would have been in the same situation as when we originally decided to break them apart. Constant failing tests hurt our productivity in the past, and we didn’t want that happening again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We accepted the trade-offs inherent in a monolithic architecture and made sure we had a good story around each. We had to be comfortable with some of the sacrifices that came with this change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;When deciding between microservices or a monolith, there are different factors to consider with each. In some parts of our infrastructure, microservices work well but our server-side destinations were a perfect example of how this popular trend can actually hurt productivity and performance. It turns out, the solution for us was a monolith.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;The transition to a monolith was made possible by &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/stephenmathieson&quot;&gt;Stephen Mathieson&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rbranson&quot;&gt;Rick Branson&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/achille-roussel&quot;&gt;Achille Roussel&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tsholmes&quot;&gt;Tom Holmes&lt;/a&gt;, and many more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Special thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rbranson&quot;&gt;Rick Branson&lt;/a&gt; for helping review and edit this post at every stage.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 15:49:10 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>manigandham</dc:creator>
<og:title>Goodbye Microservices: From 100s of problem children to 1 superstar</og:title>
<og:url>https://segment.com/blog/goodbye-microservices/</og:url>
<og:description>Unless you’ve been living under a rock, you probably already know that microservices is the architecture du jour. Coming of age alongside this trend, Segment adopted this as a best practice early-on, which served us well in some cases, and, as you’ll soon learn, not so well in others.</og:description>
<og:image>https://og-images.segment.com/?author=Alexandra%20Noonan&amp;title=Goodbye%20Microservices%3A%20From%20100s%20of%20problem%20children%20to%201%20superstar&amp;cache=0</og:image>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://segment.com/blog/goodbye-microservices/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Firefox Lockbox</title>
<link>https://testpilot.firefox.com/experiments/firefox-lockbox/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://testpilot.firefox.com/experiments/firefox-lockbox/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Test Pilot zahteva JavaScript. Žal nam je.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Test Pilot vyžaduje JavaScript. Ospravedlňujeme sa za problémy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Test Pilot fereasket JavaScript. Sorry derfoar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Test Pilot lyp JavaScript. Na ndjeni për këtë.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Test Pilot memerlukan JavaScript. Harap maaf.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Test Pilot krev JavaScript. Lei for det.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Test Pilot requiere JavaScript. Lo sentimos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Testpilot kræver JavaScript. Beklager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Test Pilot requiere JavaScript. Lo sentimos por ello.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Test Pilot を使うには JavaScript が必要です。申し訳ありません&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Το Test Pilot απαιτεί JavaScript. Λυπούμαστε γι' αυτό.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Test Pilot requiere JavaScript. Disculpe&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Siamo spiacenti, Test Pilot richiede JavaScript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Omlouváme se, ale Test Pilot vyžaduje JavaScript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Test Pilot requiere JavaScript. Lo sentimos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Для работы Лётчика-испытателя необходимо включить JavaScript. Извините.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Je nam žel, ale TestPilot sej JavaScript wužaduje.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ri Test Pilot nrajo' JavaScript. Kojakuyu'.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;很抱歉，Test Pilot 需要 JavaScript 来运行。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Вибачте, але для роботи Test Pilot необхідний JavaScript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Test Pilot захтева JavaScript. Жао нам је због овога.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O Test Pilot requer JavaScript. Pedimos desculpa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Test Pilot zahtjeva JavaScript. Žao nam je zbog toga.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;很抱歉，需要開啟 JavaScript 才能使用 Test Pilot&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Desculpe, o Test Pilot requer JavaScript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Tesztpilótához JavaScript szükséges. Sajnáljuk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Test Pilot vereist JavaScript. Sorry daarvoor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Test Pilot საჭიროებს JavaScript-ს. ვწუხვართ, ამის გამო.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Test Pilot benötigt JavaScript. Das tut uns leid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Test Pilot을 쓰려면 JavaScript가 필요합니다. 죄송합니다.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Désolé, Test Pilot nécessite JavaScript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Test Pilot kräver JavaScript. Ledsen för det.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mae Test Pilot angen JavaScript. Ymddiheuriadau.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Test Pilot requires JavaScript. Sorry about that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jo nam luto, ale TestPilot se JavaScript pomina.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Test Pilotu için JavaScript şarttır. Kusura bakmayın.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Test Pilot vereist JavaScript. Sorry daarvoor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Test Pilot საჭიროებს JavaScript-ს. ვწუხვართ, ამის გამო.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Test Pilot benötigt JavaScript. Das tut uns leid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Test Pilot을 쓰려면 JavaScript가 필요합니다. 죄송합니다.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Désolé, Test Pilot nécessite JavaScript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Test Pilot kräver JavaScript. Ledsen för det.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mae Test Pilot angen JavaScript. Ymddiheuriadau.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Test Pilot requires JavaScript. Sorry about that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jo nam luto, ale TestPilot se JavaScript pomina.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Test Pilotu için JavaScript şarttır. Kusura bakmayın.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 14:58:25 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>sahin-boydas</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:title>Firefox Test Pilot - Firefox Lockbox</og:title>
<og:description>Take your passwords everywhere with the Firefox Lockbox App for iPhone.</og:description>
<og:image>https://testpilot.firefox.com/static/images/experiments/lockbox/social/share-facebook.jpg</og:image>
<og:url>https://testpilot.firefox.com/experiments/firefox-lockbox/</og:url>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://testpilot.firefox.com/experiments/firefox-lockbox/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Fathom – Simple, trustworthy website analytics</title>
<link>https://usefathom.com</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://usefathom.com</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Collecting information on the internet is important, but it’s broken. We’ve become complacent in trading information for free access to web services, and then complaining when those web services do crappy things with that data. (Hey Zuck, how was Congress?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem is this: &lt;strong&gt;if we aren’t paying for the product, we are the product&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Current analytics platforms, like Google Analytics, give you free access to their services but in turn, they’re assembling data profiles on your website visitors, which they can then use for better targeting of advertisements across their network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need to stop giving away our data and our users privacy for free access to a tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;A different, better way forward&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if you could have 100% ownership of your data without it being used to line the pockets of a huge tech giant? What if you could respect and protect what you knew about your users? What if there was a website analytic platform that only tracked and analyzed what was important and could be acted upon?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fathom does just that&lt;/strong&gt;. It tracks users on a website (without collecting personal data) and give you a non-nerdy breakdown of your top content and top referrers. It does so with user-centric rights and privacy, and without selling, sharing or giving away the data you collect. It's a simple and easy to use for website owners at any technical level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;a href=&quot;https://usefathom.com/fathom.jpg&quot; title=&quot;See it larger...&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://usefathom.com/fathom.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Fathom demo screenshot&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Want to see a demo of Fathom? &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://stats.usefathom.com/&quot;&gt;View our live stats here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;(user: demo@demo.com, password: demo)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fathom is currently open-source, so anyone can see how our software works. Eventually there will also be a hosted + paid-for version so anyone can simply paste the code onto their site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the internet is ours, we should get to steer its future—let's start taking it back today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/usefathom/fathom&quot;&gt;View Fathom on GitHub&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.producthunt.com/posts/fathom-analytics&quot;&gt;View Fathom on ProductHunt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 13:09:52 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jhabdas</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://usefathom.com/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Thailand cave rescue: all 12 boys and coach successfully rescued</title>
<link>https://www.theguardian.com/news/live/2018/jul/10/thai-cave-rescue-third-mission-planned-to-bring-out-remaining-boys-and-coach-live-updates</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.theguardian.com/news/live/2018/jul/10/thai-cave-rescue-third-mission-planned-to-bring-out-remaining-boys-and-coach-live-updates</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;block-elements block-elements--no-byline&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Michael Safi, the Guardian’s South Asia correspondent, reacts to the news that all 12 boys and their football coach have been successfully rescued from a cave in northern &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/thailand&quot; data-link-name=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; data-component=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Thailand&lt;/a&gt; after more than two weeks trapped underground.&lt;/p&gt;

Thailand cave rescue: Guardian video dispatch from Mae Sai&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;block-elements block-elements--no-byline&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All twelve members of a boy’s football team and their coach have been rescued, after being trapped in a cave in Thailand for 18 days.&lt;/strong&gt; The Thai navy Seals, who have been running the operation, confirmed that all 13 were out. “We are not sure if this is a miracle, a science or what”, the Seals said on their Facebook page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Three navy seals and a doctor, who had been with the boys, emerged safely from the cave several hours later.&lt;/strong&gt; The four boys and their coach rescued on Tuesday have been airlifted to hospital to join their eight teammates rescued on Sunday and Monday.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The news has been greeted by global jubilation and the rescue workers have been lauded by world leaders.&lt;/strong&gt; Donald Trump tweeted “great job” and Theresa May said: “The world was watching and will be saluting the bravery of all those involved.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fifa has confirmed that the rescued boys will not be able to attend the World Cup final on Sunday as previously hoped.&lt;/strong&gt; Doctors have said they need to remain in hospital for at least seven days. Manchester United, who most of the boys support, have invited the boys to Old Trafford next season.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The final rescue operation began at 10.08am local time&lt;/strong&gt; on Tuesday as the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/news/2018/jul/09/divers-prepare-to-re-enter-cave-as-thai-rescue-restarts&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;first eight boys, freed in operations on Sunday and Monday&lt;/a&gt;, recuperated at a hospital in the nearest city, Chiang Rai. The authorities said preparations for the final rescue mission were unaffected by heavy overnight rain.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jesada Chokedamrongsuk, a physician from the Thai ministry of public health, said the eight boys rescued on Sunday and Monday were “cheerful”.&lt;/strong&gt; Two boys among the first batch to be freed, who he said were aged between 14 and 16, had shown possible signs of pneumonia and all had low temperatures when they arrived.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The rescued boys are being kept in isolation to avoid the risk of infection,&lt;/strong&gt; but the first batch have been seen by their parents through a glass window. They are not yet allowed to eat the rich Thai food they’ve been requesting - so far it’s diluted porridge, bread, and some chocolate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The office of Thailand’s prime minister has thanked the tech entrepreneur Elon Musk for his offers of help&lt;/strong&gt;. Officials praised his mini-submarine but said it was not needed. Musk praised the “outstanding rescue team” but questioned the expertise of the official who turned down his submarine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;We’re pausing the blog for now but will update if there are more major developments. For now here’s our full report:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;element element-rich-link element-rich-link--not-upgraded&quot; data-component=&quot;rich-link&quot; data-link-name=&quot;rich-link-1 | 1&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;And there’ll be more on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/news/thailand-cave-rescue&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Thai cave rescue section&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;block-elements block-elements--no-byline&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The remaining doctor and three Thai navy Seals are now also safely out of the cave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;js-tweet tweet&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;tweet__user-name&quot;&gt;michael safi&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;tweet__user-id&quot;&gt;(@safimichael)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot; class=&quot;tweet-body&quot;&gt;Seals and medics are now out &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/thamluangrescue?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;#thamluangrescue&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/safimichael/status/1016692528383291392?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;tweet-date&quot;&gt;July 10, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;js-tweet tweet&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;tweet__user-name&quot;&gt;michael safi&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;tweet__user-id&quot;&gt;(@safimichael)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot; class=&quot;tweet-body&quot;&gt;Doctor and three seals have passed chamber two and everybody will be out in 15 mins &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/thamluangcave?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;#thamluangcave&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/safimichael/status/1016691118962966530?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;tweet-date&quot;&gt;July 10, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;block-elements block-elements--no-byline&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elon Musk has been getting tetchy with Narongsak Osatanakorn, the head of the joint command centre coordinating the operation, after he politely turned down Musk’s offer of help and said his mini sub was not needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Even though their equipment is technologically sophisticated, it doesn’t fit with our mission to go in the cave,” Osatanakorn told reporters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Musk suggested Osatanakorn was no expert on the matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;js-tweet tweet&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;tweet__user-name&quot;&gt;Elon Musk&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;tweet__user-id&quot;&gt;(@elonmusk)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot; class=&quot;tweet-body&quot;&gt;The former Thai provincial governor (described inaccurately as “rescue chief”) is not the subject matter expert. That would be Dick Stanton, who co-led the dive rescue team. This is our direct correspondence: &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/dmC9l3jiZR&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/dmC9l3jiZR&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1016684366083190785?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;tweet-date&quot;&gt;July 10, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;block-elements block-elements--no-byline&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The US first lady, Melania Trump, has praised the “amazing &amp;amp; heroic global effort” of the rescue. Is there a coded message there aimed at her husband who is not a great advocate of heroic global efforts?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;js-tweet tweet&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;tweet__user-name&quot;&gt;Melania Trump&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;tweet__user-id&quot;&gt;(@FLOTUS)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot; class=&quot;tweet-body&quot;&gt;Wonderful to hear all 12 boys &amp;amp; their coach are out of the cave in &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/Thailand?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;#Thailand&lt;/a&gt;. What an amazing &amp;amp; heroic global effort! Wishing them all a speedy recovery.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/FLOTUS/status/1016688176474161153?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;tweet-date&quot;&gt;July 10, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;block-elements block-elements--no-byline&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s a video report on the final rescue day.&lt;/p&gt;

Cave rescue hailed as Thailand's 'mission impossible' – video&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;block-elements block-elements--no-byline&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The incredible scenes we have witnessed are a model of international cooperation and coordinated selflessness,” writes Guardian columnist Suzanne Moore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;quoted&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;quoted__contents&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This story touches us because it is elemental, but also because every detail runs counter to the egomania and selfishness and fake bravado that appears to be running the world. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/news/2018/jul/07/parents-boys-trapped-thai-cave-tell-coach-dont-blame-yourself-rescuers-race-against-time&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;parents of the boys wrote to reassure the young coach&lt;/a&gt; that they didn’t blame him. Some say he had got the boys meditating in the cave. The Thai government has calmly insisted on protecting the boys and their families from cameras.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;element element-rich-link element-rich-link--not-upgraded&quot; data-component=&quot;rich-link&quot; data-link-name=&quot;rich-link-1 | 1&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;block-elements block-elements--no-byline&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thai TV has shown footage of an ambulance believed to be carrying the coach, Ekaphol Chantawong to the hospital in Chiang Rai. Here’s what we know about him:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;quoted&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;quoted__contents&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chantawong, 25, took his squad into the cave on 23 June. He was once ordained as a Buddhist monk, and since leaving the monkhood has spent much of his time caring for his grandmother. Thai news outlets have reported that the authorities have not ruled out charging him with a crime, but Thai government spokesman Lt Gen Werachon Sukondhapatipak told the Guardian that “no one is talking about that”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Werachon said the coach’s presence had been a comfort to the boys: “The coach is advising them that they need to lie down, of course [try] meditation, try not to move their bodies too much, try not to waste their energy. And of course, by meditation, they stay conscious all the time, so their mind will not be wandering around.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The parents of the boys wrote the coach telling him: “Please don’t blame yourself.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“To all the kids,” one letter, written by the mother of Nattawut Takamsai, 14, said: “We are not mad at you at all. Do take good care of yourself. Don’t forget to cover yourself with blankets as the weather is cold. We’re worried. You will come out soon.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Addressing the coach she said: “We want you to know that no parents are angry with you at all, so don’t you worry about that.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;js-tweet tweet&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;tweet__user-name&quot;&gt;Richard Barrow in Thailand&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;tweet__user-id&quot;&gt;(@RichardBarrow)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot; class=&quot;tweet-body&quot;&gt;UPDATE at 8:50pm: Ambulance carrying Coach Aek, the 13th and last member of The Wild Boars, has arrived at the hospital in Chiang Rai. Mission complete.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;RT &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mthai?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;@mthai&lt;/a&gt;: รถพยาบาลนำส่ง โค้ชเอกถึง รพ. เชียงรายประชานุเคราะห์ &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/ThamLuang?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;#ThamLuang&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/%E0%B8%96%E0%B9%89%E0%B8%B3%E0%B8%AB%E0%B8%A5%E0%B8%A7%E0%B8%87?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;#ถ้ำหลวง&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/Thailand?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;#Thailand&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/ThaiCaveRescue?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;#ThaiCaveRescue&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/WhsHCMX06h&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/WhsHCMX06h&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/RichardBarrow/status/1016684197656739840?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;tweet-date&quot;&gt;July 10, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;block-elements&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last three navy seals and the medic, who were with the boys for the last few days, are still in the cave. It is unclear when they will emerge, but they are said to be on their way out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The weakest boys were the last to be taken out, sources have said. They are understood to include the youngest in the group – 11-year-old Chanin Wiboonrungrueng.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;js-tweet tweet&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;tweet__user-name&quot;&gt;michael safi&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;tweet__user-id&quot;&gt;(@safimichael)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot; class=&quot;tweet-body&quot;&gt;Sources telling us the boys brought out last were the weakest in the group – hope to find out more at press conference later tonight &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/thamluangcave?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;#thamluangcave&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/safimichael/status/1016683191040557057?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;tweet-date&quot;&gt;July 10, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;block-elements block-elements--no-byline&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The city of Chiang Rai is starting to party as drivers honk their horns, according to Reuters.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“This is an important event in my life. It is something I will remember,” said a visibly emotional Rachapol Ngamgrabuan, an official at Chiang Rai’s provincial press office.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“There were times when I cried,” he added. “Happy. Very happy to see all Thai people love each other.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Monday, Prime Minister Prayuth Chan-o-cha said he would host a celebration for all of those involved in the multinational rescue effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We will host a meal for all sides,” said Prayuth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;u-responsive-ratio&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;gu-image&quot; itemprop=&quot;contentUrl&quot; alt=&quot;People react near a hospital, where the children’s football team members are being treated.&quot; src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/394597263b164e004c3d86fa645d6e2e282aba8e/0_161_4928_2957/master/4928.jpg?w=300&amp;amp;q=55&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;usm=12&amp;amp;fit=max&amp;amp;s=5975e75d7e2d16f4059fe5ed844da81a&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
People react near a hospital, where the children’s football team members are being treated. Photograph: Lillian Suwanrumpha/AFP/Getty Images&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;block-elements block-elements--no-byline&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All twelve members of a boy’s football team and their coach have been rescued, after being trapped in a cave in Thailand for 18 days.&lt;/strong&gt; The Thai navy Seals, who have been running the operation, confirmed that all 13 were out. “We are not sure if this is a miracle, a science or what”, the Seals said on their Facebook page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The news has been greeted by global jubilation and the rescue workers have been lauded by world leaders.&lt;/strong&gt; Donald Trump tweeted “great job” and Theresa May said: “The world was watching and will be saluting the bravery of all those involved.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Three navy seals and a doctor, who had been with the boys, are expected to emerge from the cave soon.&lt;/strong&gt; The four boys and their coach rescued on Tuesday have been airlifted to hospital to join their eight teammates rescued on Sunday and Monday.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fifa has confirmed that the rescued boys will not be able to attend the World Cup final on Sunday as previously hoped.&lt;/strong&gt; Doctors have said they need to remain in hospital for at least seven days. Manchester United have invited the boys to Old Trafford next season.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The final rescue operation began at 10.08am local time&lt;/strong&gt; on Tuesday as the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/news/2018/jul/09/divers-prepare-to-re-enter-cave-as-thai-rescue-restarts&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;first eight boys, freed in operations on Sunday and Monday&lt;/a&gt;, recuperated at a hospital in the nearest city, Chiang Rai. The authorities said preparations for the final rescue mission were unaffected by heavy overnight rain.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jesada Chokedamrongsuk, a physician from the Thai ministry of public health, said the eight boys rescued on Sunday and Monday were “cheerful”.&lt;/strong&gt; Two boys among the first batch to be freed, who he said were aged between 14 and 16, had shown possible signs of pneumonia and all had low temperatures when they arrived.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The rescued boys are being kept in isolation to avoid the risk of infection,&lt;/strong&gt; but the first batch have been seen by their parents through a glass window. They are not yet allowed to eat the rich Thai food they’ve been requesting - so far it’s diluted porridge, bread, and some chocolate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The office of Thailand’s prime minister has thanked the tech entrepreneur Elon Musk for his offers of help&lt;/strong&gt;. Officials praised his mini-submarine but said it was not needed. Musk praised the “outstanding rescue team”.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;block-elements block-elements--no-byline&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fifa has confirmed that the boys won’t be able to make the World Cup final on Sunday while they recover from their ordeal, the BBC’s Richard Conway reports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Medics said the boys would have stay in hospital for at least seven days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;js-tweet tweet&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;tweet__user-name&quot;&gt;Richard Conway&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;tweet__user-id&quot;&gt;(@richard_conway)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot; class=&quot;tweet-body&quot;&gt;Breaking: Fifa expresses “its great joy at the news of the rescue of the 12 young footballers and their coach.”&lt;br/&gt;Confirms due to medical reasons “the boys will not be in a position to travel to Moscow for the World Cup final. Priority remains the health of everyone involved.”&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/richard_conway/status/1016674640033349632?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;tweet-date&quot;&gt;July 10, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;block-elements block-elements--no-byline&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last of the rescued boys are being airlifted to hospital as night falls over the area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;js-tweet tweet&quot; data-conversation=&quot;none&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://pbs.twimg.com/ext_tw_video_thumb/1016672699127508992/pu/img/cop_QE8Kj85BBbTn.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;js-tweet-main-image tweet-main-image&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;tweet__user-name&quot;&gt;Jacob Goldberg&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;tweet__user-id&quot;&gt;(@yayqe)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot; class=&quot;tweet-body&quot;&gt;Helicopter picking up today’s rescued Boars to take them to the hospital. &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/VguD607t3C&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/VguD607t3C&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/yayqe/status/1016672865133838338?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;tweet-date&quot;&gt;July 10, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;block-elements block-elements--no-byline&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Volunteer rescue workers have been shown singing and dancing on Thai TV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;js-tweet tweet&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://pbs.twimg.com/media/Dhvq6UgWsAAzpJk.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;js-tweet-main-image tweet-main-image&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;tweet__user-name&quot;&gt;ThaiPBS&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;tweet__user-id&quot;&gt;(@ThaiPBS)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;th&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot; class=&quot;tweet-body&quot;&gt;อาสาสมัครสกัดน้ำเข้า &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/%E0%B8%96%E0%B9%89%E0%B8%B3%E0%B8%AB%E0%B8%A5%E0%B8%A7%E0%B8%87?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;#ถ้ำหลวง&lt;/a&gt; ดีใจภารกิจลุล่วง &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/%E0%B8%9E%E0%B8%B2%E0%B8%97%E0%B8%B5%E0%B8%A1%E0%B8%AB%E0%B8%A1%E0%B8%B9%E0%B8%9B%E0%B9%88%E0%B8%B2%E0%B8%81%E0%B8%A5%E0%B8%B1%E0%B8%9A%E0%B8%9A%E0%B9%89%E0%B8%B2%E0%B8%99?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;#พาทีมหมูป่ากลับบ้าน&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/ThaiCaveRescue?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;#ThaiCaveRescue&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/ThaiPBS?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;#ThaiPBS&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/5qxvQjBlIx&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/5qxvQjBlIx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ThaiPBS/status/1016664524538118144?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;tweet-date&quot;&gt;July 10, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;block-elements block-elements--no-byline&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amid global jubilation many are pausing to remember &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2018/jul/06/former-thai-navy-seal-diver-saman-kunan-dies-from-lack-of-air-inside-cave&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Saman Kunan, the former Thai Navy Seal who died last week trying to save the boys.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They include the Italian football team AS Roma and the Spanish royal family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;js-tweet tweet&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;tweet__user-name&quot;&gt;AS Roma English&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;tweet__user-id&quot;&gt;(@ASRomaEN)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot; class=&quot;tweet-body&quot;&gt;The best football news of the summer – ALL 12 young Thai players and their coach have been rescued after being trapped in a cave in Thailand for two weeks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our thoughts are with the family of ex-Navy SEAL diver Saman Kunan who died after delivering the boys oxygen. A real hero &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/UKW5tXfGei&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/UKW5tXfGei&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ASRomaEN/status/1016666023368495104?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;tweet-date&quot;&gt;July 10, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;js-tweet tweet&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;tweet__user-name&quot;&gt;Casa de S.M. el Rey&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;tweet__user-id&quot;&gt;(@CasaReal)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;es&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot; class=&quot;tweet-body&quot;&gt;Nuestra admiración y reconocimiento al buzo español Fernando Raigal, que ha trabajado sin descanso en un rescate memorable. También nuestro recuerdo para Sanan Gunan, voluntario fallecido en los trabajos. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/ThaiCaveRescue?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;#ThaiCaveRescue&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/ThaiRescueMission?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;#ThaiRescueMission&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/MFAThai?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;@MFAThai&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/CasaReal/status/1016655466577977345?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;tweet-date&quot;&gt;July 10, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;block-elements block-elements--no-byline&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bhutan’s prime minister, Tshering Tobgay, joins the international celebrations. “Hooyah!!!” he tweeted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;js-tweet tweet&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;tweet__user-name&quot;&gt;Tshering Tobgay&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;tweet__user-id&quot;&gt;(@tsheringtobgay)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot; class=&quot;tweet-body&quot;&gt;Bhutan celebrates the rescue of the thirteen Wild Boars. Congratulations Thailand!&lt;br/&gt;Hooyah!!!&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/ThailandCaveRescue?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;#ThailandCaveRescue&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/tsheringtobgay/status/1016665983153422339?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;tweet-date&quot;&gt;July 10, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 12:29:35 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>wallflower</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://www.theguardian.com/news/live/2018/jul/10/thai-cave-rescue-third-mission-planned-to-bring-out-remaining-boys-and-coach-live-updates</og:url>
<og:description>Last three Thai navy divers and medic have also left cave, ending perilous operation in northern Thailand</og:description>
<og:image>https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/4adef247d2dfa7403aaceac13cbb27187da932ce/8_4_2565_1539/master/2565.jpg?w=1200&amp;h=630&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;fit=crop&amp;crop=faces%2Centropy&amp;bm=normal&amp;ba=bottom%2Cleft&amp;blend64=aHR0cHM6Ly9hc3NldHMuZ3VpbS5jby51ay9pbWFnZXMvb3ZlcmxheXMvZmQ2MTg4YTJlMWFhNThmNWM5Y2VkODlkNjQxOWU1OTgvdGctbGl2ZS5wbmc=&amp;s=94d62357479b7d2a0f080db80ca242ae</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>All 12 boys and coach successfully rescued from Thai cave – as it happened</og:title>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.theguardian.com/news/live/2018/jul/10/thai-cave-rescue-third-mission-planned-to-bring-out-remaining-boys-and-coach-live-updates</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Lessons learned scraping 100B product pages</title>
<link>https://blog.scrapinghub.com/web-scraping-at-scale-lessons-learned-scraping-100-billion-products-pages</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.scrapinghub.com/web-scraping-at-scale-lessons-learned-scraping-100-billion-products-pages</guid>
<description>&lt;span id=&quot;hs_cos_wrapper_post_body&quot; class=&quot;hs_cos_wrapper hs_cos_wrapper_meta_field hs_cos_wrapper_type_rich_text&quot; data-hs-cos-general-type=&quot;meta_field&quot; data-hs-cos-type=&quot;rich_text&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;hs_cos_wrapper_post_body&quot; class=&quot;hs_cos_wrapper hs_cos_wrapper_meta_field hs_cos_wrapper_type_rich_text&quot; data-hs-cos-general-type=&quot;meta_field&quot; data-hs-cos-type=&quot;rich_text&quot;&gt;Web scraping can look deceptively easy these days. There are numerous open-source libraries/frameworks, visual scraping tools and data extraction tools that make it very easy to scrape data from a website. However, when you want to scrape websites at scale things start to get very tricky, very fast.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;hs_cos_wrapper_post_body&quot; class=&quot;hs_cos_wrapper hs_cos_wrapper_meta_field hs_cos_wrapper_type_rich_text&quot; data-hs-cos-general-type=&quot;meta_field&quot; data-hs-cos-type=&quot;rich_text&quot;&gt;In this series of articles, we will share with you the lessons we’ve learned scraping over 100 billion product pages since 2010, give you an &lt;span&gt;in-depth look at the challenges you will face when extracting product data from e-commerce stores at scale and share with you some of the best practices to address those challenges.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;In this article, the first of the series, we will give you a overview of the main challenges you will face scraping product data at scale and the lessons Scrapinghub has learned from scraping 100 billion product pages.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;su-note&quot; readability=&quot;10.899248120301&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;su-note-inner su-clearfix&quot; readability=&quot;17.257142857143&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2010, Scrapinghub is one of the leading data extraction companies and the author of Scrapy, the most robust and popular web scraping framework available today. Currently, Scrapinghub scrapes over 8 billion pages per month (3 billion of which are product pages) for many of the largest e-commerce companies in the world. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;For those of you who are interested in scraping the web at scale but are wrestling with the decision of whether or not you should build up a dedicated web scraping team in-house or outsource it to a dedicated web scraping firm then be sure to check out our free guide, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://info.scrapinghub.com/enterprise-web-scraping-scraping-at-scale&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enterprise Web Scraping: A Guide to Scraping the Web at Scale&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s Important When Scraping At Scale?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike your standard web scraping application, scraping e-commerce product data at scale has a unique set of challenges that make web scraping vastly more difficult.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At its core, these challenges can be boiled down to two things: &lt;strong&gt;speed&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;data quality&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As time is usually a limiting constraint, scraping at scale requires your crawlers to scrape the web at very high speeds without compromising data quality. This need for speed makes scraping large volumes of product data very challenging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.scrapinghub.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Articles/Lessons%20Learned%20Scraping%20Product%20Data/web%20scraping%20product%20data%20scale%20-%20sloppy%20code.jpg?t=1531244940161&amp;amp;width=600&amp;amp;name=web%20scraping%20product%20data%20scale%20-%20sloppy%20code.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;web scraping product data scale - sloppy code&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; srcset=&quot;https://blog.scrapinghub.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Articles/Lessons%20Learned%20Scraping%20Product%20Data/web%20scraping%20product%20data%20scale%20-%20sloppy%20code.jpg?t=1531244940161&amp;amp;width=300&amp;amp;name=web%20scraping%20product%20data%20scale%20-%20sloppy%20code.jpg 300w, https://blog.scrapinghub.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Articles/Lessons%20Learned%20Scraping%20Product%20Data/web%20scraping%20product%20data%20scale%20-%20sloppy%20code.jpg?t=1531244940161&amp;amp;width=600&amp;amp;name=web%20scraping%20product%20data%20scale%20-%20sloppy%20code.jpg 600w, https://blog.scrapinghub.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Articles/Lessons%20Learned%20Scraping%20Product%20Data/web%20scraping%20product%20data%20scale%20-%20sloppy%20code.jpg?t=1531244940161&amp;amp;width=900&amp;amp;name=web%20scraping%20product%20data%20scale%20-%20sloppy%20code.jpg 900w, https://blog.scrapinghub.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Articles/Lessons%20Learned%20Scraping%20Product%20Data/web%20scraping%20product%20data%20scale%20-%20sloppy%20code.jpg?t=1531244940161&amp;amp;width=1200&amp;amp;name=web%20scraping%20product%20data%20scale%20-%20sloppy%20code.jpg 1200w, https://blog.scrapinghub.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Articles/Lessons%20Learned%20Scraping%20Product%20Data/web%20scraping%20product%20data%20scale%20-%20sloppy%20code.jpg?t=1531244940161&amp;amp;width=1500&amp;amp;name=web%20scraping%20product%20data%20scale%20-%20sloppy%20code.jpg 1500w, https://blog.scrapinghub.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Articles/Lessons%20Learned%20Scraping%20Product%20Data/web%20scraping%20product%20data%20scale%20-%20sloppy%20code.jpg?t=1531244940161&amp;amp;width=1800&amp;amp;name=web%20scraping%20product%20data%20scale%20-%20sloppy%20code.jpg 1800w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Challenge #1 - Sloppy and Always Changing Website Formats&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It might be obvious and it might not be the sexiest challenge, but sloppy and always changing website formats is by far the biggest challenge you will face when extracting data at scale. Not necessarily because of the complexity of the task, but the time and resources you will spend dealing with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have spent any length of time building crawlers for e-commerce stores you’ll know that there is a epidemic of sloppy code on e-commerce stores. There’s more to it than HTML well-formedness or the occasional character encoding problem. We’ve run into all sorts of colorful issues over the years - misused HTTP response codes, broken JavaScripts, or misuse of Ajax:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Stores that remove pages when they discontinue products and suddenly begin to return 200 response codes on its 404 error handler after a website upgrade.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improperly escaped JSON data that break javascript on some pages (e.g. ‘b0rk’d’), resulting in you needing to scrape that data using regular expressions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stores that abuse Ajax calls so much that you can only get the information you’re after by either rendering the page (resulting in much slower crawls) or mimicking the API calls (resulting in more development effort).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sloppy code like this can make writing your spider a pain, but can also make visual scraping tools or automatic extraction tools unviable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When scraping at scale, not only do you have to navigate potentially hundreds of websites with sloppy code, you will also have to deal with constantly evolving websites. A good rule of thumb is to expect your target website to make changes that will break your spider (drop in data extraction coverage or quality) every 2-3 months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That mightn’t sound like too big a deal but when you are scraping at scale, those incidents really add up. For example, one of Scrapinghub’s larger e-commerce projects has ~4,000 spiders targeting about 1,000 e-commerce websites, meaning they can experience 20-30 spiders failing per day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Variations in website layouts from regional and multilingual websites, A/B split testing and packaging/pricing variants also create a world of problems that routinely break spiders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No Easy Solution&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, there is no magic bullet that will completely solve these problems. A lot of the time it just a matter of committing more resources to your project as you scale. To take the previous project as a example again, that project has a team of full-time 18 crawl engineers and 3 dedicated QA engineers to ensure the client always has reliable data feed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With experience however, your team will learn to create ever more robust spiders that can detect and deal with quirks in your target websites format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of having multiple spiders for all the possible layouts a target website might use, it is best practice to have only one product extraction spider that can deal with all the possible rules and schemes used by different page layouts. The more configurable your spiders are the better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although these practices will make your spiders more complex (some of our spiders are thousands of lines long), it will ensure that your spiders are easier to maintain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As most companies need to extract product data on a daily basis, waiting a couple days for your engineering team to fix any broken spiders isn’t an option. When these situations arise, Scrapinghub uses a machine learning based data extraction tool that we’ve developed as a fallback until the spider has been repaired. This ML-based extraction tool automatically identifies the target fields on the target website (product name, price, currency, image, SKU, etc.) and returns the desired result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the coming weeks, we’ll be releasing this tool to the public and articles on how you can incorporate machine learning into your data extraction processes. However, in the meantime you can gain early access by &lt;a href=&quot;https://scrapinghub.com/enterprise-solutions&quot;&gt;contacting our sales team&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.scrapinghub.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Articles/Lessons%20Learned%20Scraping%20Product%20Data/earthquake-taipei-101-640x640.jpg?t=1531244940161&amp;amp;width=600&amp;amp;name=earthquake-taipei-101-640x640.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;earthquake-taipei-101-640x640&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; srcset=&quot;https://blog.scrapinghub.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Articles/Lessons%20Learned%20Scraping%20Product%20Data/earthquake-taipei-101-640x640.jpg?t=1531244940161&amp;amp;width=300&amp;amp;name=earthquake-taipei-101-640x640.jpg 300w, https://blog.scrapinghub.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Articles/Lessons%20Learned%20Scraping%20Product%20Data/earthquake-taipei-101-640x640.jpg?t=1531244940161&amp;amp;width=600&amp;amp;name=earthquake-taipei-101-640x640.jpg 600w, https://blog.scrapinghub.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Articles/Lessons%20Learned%20Scraping%20Product%20Data/earthquake-taipei-101-640x640.jpg?t=1531244940161&amp;amp;width=900&amp;amp;name=earthquake-taipei-101-640x640.jpg 900w, https://blog.scrapinghub.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Articles/Lessons%20Learned%20Scraping%20Product%20Data/earthquake-taipei-101-640x640.jpg?t=1531244940161&amp;amp;width=1200&amp;amp;name=earthquake-taipei-101-640x640.jpg 1200w, https://blog.scrapinghub.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Articles/Lessons%20Learned%20Scraping%20Product%20Data/earthquake-taipei-101-640x640.jpg?t=1531244940161&amp;amp;width=1500&amp;amp;name=earthquake-taipei-101-640x640.jpg 1500w, https://blog.scrapinghub.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Articles/Lessons%20Learned%20Scraping%20Product%20Data/earthquake-taipei-101-640x640.jpg?t=1531244940161&amp;amp;width=1800&amp;amp;name=earthquake-taipei-101-640x640.jpg 1800w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Challenge 2: Scalable Architecture&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next challenge you will face is building a crawling infrastructure that will scale as the number of requests per day increases, without degrading in performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When extracting product data at scale a simple web crawler that crawls and scrapes data serially just won’t cut it. Typically, a serial web scraper will make requests in a loop, one after the other, with each request taking 2-3 seconds to complete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This approach is fine if your crawler is only required to make &amp;lt;40,000 requests per day (request every 2 seconds equals 43,200 request per day). However, past this point you will need to transition to a crawling architecture that will allow you to scrape millions of requests per day with no decrease in performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As this topic warrants a article onto itself, in the coming weeks we will publish a dedicated article discussing the how to design and build your own high throughput scraping architecture. However, for the remainder of this section we will discuss some of the higher level principles and best practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we’ve discussed, speed is key when it comes to scraping product data at scale. You need to ensure that you can find and scrape all the required product pages in the time allotted (often one day). To do this you need to do the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Separate Product Discovery From Product Extraction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To scrape product data at scale you need to separate your product discovery spiders from your product extraction spiders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of the product discovery spider should be for it to navigate to the target product category (or “shelf”) and store URLs of the products in that category for the product extraction spiders. As the product discovery spider adds product URLs to the queue the product extraction spiders scrape the target data from that product page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This can be accomplished with the aid of a crawl frontier such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scrapinghub/frontera&quot;&gt;Frontera&lt;/a&gt;, the open source crawl frontier developed by Scrapinghub. While Frontera was originally designed for use with Scrapy, it’s completely agnostic and can be used with any other crawling framework or standalone project. In this article, we share how you could &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.scrapinghub.com/2015/04/22/frontera-the-brain-behind-the-crawls/&quot;&gt;use Frontera to scrape HackerNews at scale&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Allocate More Resources To Product Extraction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As each product category “shelf” can contain anywhere from 10 to 100 products and extracting product data is more resource heavy than extracting a product URL, discovery spiders typically run faster than product extraction spiders. When this is the case, you need to have multiple extraction spiders for every discovery spider. A good rule of thumb is to create a separate extraction spider for each ~100,000 page bucket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.scrapinghub.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Articles/Lessons%20Learned%20Scraping%20Product%20Data/sp02-vettel.jpg?t=1531244940161&amp;amp;width=600&amp;amp;name=sp02-vettel.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;sp02-vettel&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; srcset=&quot;https://blog.scrapinghub.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Articles/Lessons%20Learned%20Scraping%20Product%20Data/sp02-vettel.jpg?t=1531244940161&amp;amp;width=300&amp;amp;name=sp02-vettel.jpg 300w, https://blog.scrapinghub.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Articles/Lessons%20Learned%20Scraping%20Product%20Data/sp02-vettel.jpg?t=1531244940161&amp;amp;width=600&amp;amp;name=sp02-vettel.jpg 600w, https://blog.scrapinghub.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Articles/Lessons%20Learned%20Scraping%20Product%20Data/sp02-vettel.jpg?t=1531244940161&amp;amp;width=900&amp;amp;name=sp02-vettel.jpg 900w, https://blog.scrapinghub.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Articles/Lessons%20Learned%20Scraping%20Product%20Data/sp02-vettel.jpg?t=1531244940161&amp;amp;width=1200&amp;amp;name=sp02-vettel.jpg 1200w, https://blog.scrapinghub.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Articles/Lessons%20Learned%20Scraping%20Product%20Data/sp02-vettel.jpg?t=1531244940161&amp;amp;width=1500&amp;amp;name=sp02-vettel.jpg 1500w, https://blog.scrapinghub.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Articles/Lessons%20Learned%20Scraping%20Product%20Data/sp02-vettel.jpg?t=1531244940161&amp;amp;width=1800&amp;amp;name=sp02-vettel.jpg 1800w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Challenge 3: Maintaining Throughput Performance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scraping at scale can easily be compared to Formula 1 where you goal is to shave every unnecessary gram of weight from your car and squeeze that last fraction of a horsepower from the engine all in the name of speed. The same is true for web scraping at scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When extracting large volumes of data you are always on the lookout for ways to minimise the request cycle time and maximise your spiders performance of the available hardware resources. All in the hope that you can shave a couple milliseconds off each request.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To do this your team will need to develop a deep understanding of the web scraping framework, proxy management and hardware you are using so you can tune them for optimal performance. You will also need to focus on:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Crawling Efficiency&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When scraping at scale you should always be focused on solely extracting the exact data you need in as few requests as possible. Any additional requests or data extraction slow the pace at which you can crawl a website. Keep these tips in mind when designing your spiders:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Only use a headless browsers, such as Splash or Puppeteer, to render javascript as a last resort. Rendering javascript with a headless browser whilst crawling is very resource intensive and severely impacts the speeds at which you can crawl.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you can get the data you need from the shelf page (e.x. Product names, price, ratings, etc.) without requesting each individual product page, then don’t request the product pages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t request or extract images unless you really have to.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt; &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.scrapinghub.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Articles/Lessons%20Learned%20Scraping%20Product%20Data/Web%20scraping%20at%20scale%20-%20bot%20detection.jpg?t=1531244940161&amp;amp;width=600&amp;amp;name=Web%20scraping%20at%20scale%20-%20bot%20detection.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Web scraping at scale - bot detection&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; srcset=&quot;https://blog.scrapinghub.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Articles/Lessons%20Learned%20Scraping%20Product%20Data/Web%20scraping%20at%20scale%20-%20bot%20detection.jpg?t=1531244940161&amp;amp;width=300&amp;amp;name=Web%20scraping%20at%20scale%20-%20bot%20detection.jpg 300w, https://blog.scrapinghub.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Articles/Lessons%20Learned%20Scraping%20Product%20Data/Web%20scraping%20at%20scale%20-%20bot%20detection.jpg?t=1531244940161&amp;amp;width=600&amp;amp;name=Web%20scraping%20at%20scale%20-%20bot%20detection.jpg 600w, https://blog.scrapinghub.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Articles/Lessons%20Learned%20Scraping%20Product%20Data/Web%20scraping%20at%20scale%20-%20bot%20detection.jpg?t=1531244940161&amp;amp;width=900&amp;amp;name=Web%20scraping%20at%20scale%20-%20bot%20detection.jpg 900w, https://blog.scrapinghub.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Articles/Lessons%20Learned%20Scraping%20Product%20Data/Web%20scraping%20at%20scale%20-%20bot%20detection.jpg?t=1531244940161&amp;amp;width=1200&amp;amp;name=Web%20scraping%20at%20scale%20-%20bot%20detection.jpg 1200w, https://blog.scrapinghub.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Articles/Lessons%20Learned%20Scraping%20Product%20Data/Web%20scraping%20at%20scale%20-%20bot%20detection.jpg?t=1531244940161&amp;amp;width=1500&amp;amp;name=Web%20scraping%20at%20scale%20-%20bot%20detection.jpg 1500w, https://blog.scrapinghub.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Articles/Lessons%20Learned%20Scraping%20Product%20Data/Web%20scraping%20at%20scale%20-%20bot%20detection.jpg?t=1531244940161&amp;amp;width=1800&amp;amp;name=Web%20scraping%20at%20scale%20-%20bot%20detection.jpg 1800w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Challenge 4: Anti-Bot Countermeasures&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are scraping e-commerce sites at scale you are guaranteed to run into websites employing anti-bot countermeasures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For most smaller websites their anti-bot countermeasures will be quite basic (ban IPs making excess requests). However, larger e-commerce websites such as Amazon, etc. make use of sophisticated anti-bot countermeasures such as Distil Networks, Incapsula, or Akamai, that make extracting data significantly more difficult.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Proxies&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that in mind the first and most essential requirement for any project scraping product data at scale is to use proxy IPs. When scraping at scale you will need a sizeable list of proxies, and will need to implement the necessary IP rotation, request throttling, session management and blacklisting logic to prevent your proxies from getting blocked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unless, you have or are willing to commit a sizeable team to manage your proxies you should outsource this part of the scraping process. There are a huge number of proxy services available who provide varying levels of service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, our recommendation is to go with a proxy provider who can provide a single endpoint for proxy configuration and hide all the complexities of managing your proxies. Scraping at scale is resource intensive enough without trying to reinvent the wheel by developing and maintaining your own internal proxy management infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the approach most of the large e-commerce companies use. A number of the worlds largest e-commerce companies use &lt;a href=&quot;https://scrapinghub.com/crawlera&quot;&gt;Crawlera&lt;/a&gt;, the smart downloader developed by Scrapinghub, that completely outsource their proxy management. When your crawlers are making 20 million requests per day, it makes much more sense to focus on analysing the data not managing proxies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Beyond Proxies&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, just using a proxy service won’t be enough to ensure you can evade bot countermeasures on larger e-commerce websites. More and more websites are using sophisticated anti-bot countermeasures that monitor your crawlers behaviour to detect that it isn’t a real human visitor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only do these anti-bot countermeasures make scraping e-commerce sites more difficult, overcoming them can significantly dent your crawlers performance if done incorrectly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A large proportion of these bot countermeasures use javascript to determine if the request is coming from a crawler or a human (Javascript engine checks, font enumeration, WebGL and Canvas, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However as mentioned previously, when scraping at scale you want to limit your usage of scriptable headless browsers such as Splash or Puppeteer, that render any javascript on the page as they are very heavy on resources and slow the speed at which you can scrape a website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This means that to ensure you can achieve the necessary throughput from your spiders to deliver daily product data you often need to painstakingly reverse engineer the anti-bot countermeasures used on the site and design your spider to counteract them without using a headless browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Challenge 5: Data Quality&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From a data scientists perspective the most important consideration of any web scraping project is the quality of the data being extracted. Scraping at scale only makes this focus on data quality even more important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When extracting millions of data points every single day, it is impossible to manually verify that all your data is clean and intact. It is very easy for dirty or incomplete data to creep into your data feeds and disrupt your data analysis efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is especially true when scraping products on multiple versions of the same store (different languages, regions, etc.) or separate stores.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outside of a careful QA process during the design phase of the building the spider, where the code of the spider is peer reviewed and tested to ensure that it is extracting the desired data in the most reliable way possible. The best method of ensuring the highest possible data quality is the development of a automated QA monitoring system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of any data extraction project you need to plan and develop a monitoring system that will alert you of any data for inconsistencies and spider errors. At Scrapinghub we’ve developed machine learning algorithms designed to detect:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data Validation Errors&lt;/strong&gt; - Every data item has a defined data type and values that follow a consistent pattern. Our data validation algorithms will flag to the projects QA team any data items that are inconsistent with what is to expected for that data type, from which point the data is manually checked and alert verified or been flagged as a error.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Product Variation Errors&lt;/strong&gt; - When scraping the same product data from multiple versions of the same website (different languages, regions, etc.) it is possible that variable and supposedly fixed values such as product weight or dimensions can vary. This can be the result of a websites anti-bot countermeasures giving one or more of your crawlers falsified information. Again, you need to have algorithms in place to identify and flag any occurrences such as this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Volume Based Inconsistencies -&lt;/strong&gt; Another key monitoring script is one that detects any abnormal variations in the number of records returned. This could signify that there have been changes made to the website or that your crawler is being fed falsified information.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Site Changes -&lt;/strong&gt; Structural changes happening to the target websites is the main reason why crawlers break. This is monitored by our dedicated monitoring system, quite aggressively. The tool performs frequent checks on the target site to make sure nothing has changed since the previous crawl. If changes are found, it sends out notifications for the same.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;All of which we will discuss in a later article dedicated to automated quality assurance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wrapping Things Up&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you have seen scraping product data at scale creates its own unique set of challenges. Hopefully, this article has made you more aware of the challenges you will face and how you should go about solving them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, this is just the first article in this series so if you are interested in reading the next articles as soon as they are published be sure to sign up to our email list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those of you who are interested in scraping the web at scale but are wrestling with the decision of whether or not you should build up a dedicated web scraping team in-house or outsource it to a dedicated web scraping firm then be sure to check out our guide, &lt;a href=&quot;https://info.scrapinghub.com/enterprise-web-scraping-scraping-at-scale&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enterprise Web Scraping: A Guide to Scraping the Web at Scale&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cta_image&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;hs-cta-wrapper&quot; id=&quot;hs-cta-wrapper-421a097a-aaa9-4d4a-9db3-0f8630a76792&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;hs-cta-node hs-cta-421a097a-aaa9-4d4a-9db3-0f8630a76792&quot; id=&quot;hs-cta-421a097a-aaa9-4d4a-9db3-0f8630a76792&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cta-redirect.hubspot.com/cta/redirect/4367560/421a097a-aaa9-4d4a-9db3-0f8630a76792&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;hs-cta-img&quot; id=&quot;hs-cta-img-421a097a-aaa9-4d4a-9db3-0f8630a76792&quot; height=&quot;282&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;https://no-cache.hubspot.com/cta/default/4367560/421a097a-aaa9-4d4a-9db3-0f8630a76792.png&quot; alt=&quot;New call-to-action&quot; align=&quot;middle&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Scrapinghub we specialize in turning unstructured web data into structured data. If you would like to learn more about how you can use web scraped product data in your business then feel free to &lt;a href=&quot;https://scrapinghub.com/enterprise-solutions&quot;&gt;contact our sales team,&lt;/a&gt; who will talk you through the services we offer startups right through to Fortune 100 companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Scrapinghub we always love to hear what our readers think of our content and any questions you might. So please leave a comment below with what you thought of the article and what you are working on.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;share-it&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Share this:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;hs_cos_wrapper_module_1523032069834331_blog_social_sharing&quot; class=&quot;hs_cos_wrapper hs_cos_wrapper_widget hs_cos_wrapper_type_blog_social_sharing&quot; data-hs-cos-general-type=&quot;widget&quot; data-hs-cos-type=&quot;blog_social_sharing&quot;/&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 11:41:43 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Ian_Kerins</dc:creator>
<og:description>The first in a series of articles about scraping the web at scale. Find out the challenges Scrapinghub as experienced from scraping over 100 billion product pages and how we managed to overcome them.</og:description>
<og:title>For E-Commerce Data Scientists: Lessons Learned Scraping 100 Billion Products Pages</og:title>
<og:image>https://blog.scrapinghub.com/hubfs/web%20scraping%20at%20scale.jpg?t=1531244940161#keepProtocol</og:image>
<og:url>https://blog.scrapinghub.com/web-scraping-at-scale-lessons-learned-scraping-100-billion-products-pages</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.scrapinghub.com/web-scraping-at-scale-lessons-learned-scraping-100-billion-products-pages</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ask HN: Have you ever chosen Postgres over Mongo and regretted it?</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17497164</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17497164</guid>
<description>&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.55737704918033&quot;&gt;&lt;td bgcolor=&quot;#FF6600&quot;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.606149341142&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table class=&quot;fatitem&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.9546120058565&quot;&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing&quot; id=&quot;17497164&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;right&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;title&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17497164&quot; class=&quot;storylink&quot;&gt;Ask HN: Have you ever chosen Postgres over Mongo and regretted it?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.72289156626506&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;subtext&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;score&quot; id=&quot;score_17497164&quot;&gt;209 points&lt;/span&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/user?id=chatmasta&quot; class=&quot;hnuser&quot;&gt;chatmasta&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;age&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17497164&quot;&gt;20 hours ago&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span id=&quot;unv_17497164&quot;/&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/hide?id=17497164&amp;amp;goto=item%3Fid%3D17497164&quot;&gt;hide&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://hn.algolia.com/?query=Ask%20HN%3A%20Have%20you%20ever%20chosen%20Postgres%20over%20Mongo%20and%20regretted%20it%3F&amp;amp;sort=byDate&amp;amp;dateRange=all&amp;amp;type=story&amp;amp;storyText=false&amp;amp;prefix&amp;amp;page=0&quot; class=&quot;hnpast&quot;&gt;past&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=Ask%20HN%3A%20Have%20you%20ever%20chosen%20Postgres%20over%20Mongo%20and%20regretted%20it%3F&quot;&gt;web&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/fave?id=17497164&amp;amp;auth=7312baeabb432720b069c0cd9b0473e88db2372c&quot;&gt;favorite&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17497164&quot;&gt;143 comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;12.5&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;The past 2 years seem to have been the death knell for Mongo and the &quot;NoSQL&quot; hype, with Mongo moving toward SQL parity and SQL databases supporting JSON storage, like Postgres with JSONB.
&lt;p&gt;At this point it seems that there are very few workloads for which Mongo is the best option compared to Postgres+JSONB. I'm wondering...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1) Have you ever chosen Postgres over Mongo, and &lt;em&gt;regretted it&lt;/em&gt;? Why? Did you end up switching to Mongo? Was it better?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2) Can anyone name a use case where Mongo is clearly a better choice than Postgres+JSONB?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td&gt;

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;yclinks&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/newsguidelines.html&quot;&gt;Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/newsfaq.html&quot;&gt;FAQ&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:hn@ycombinator.com&quot;&gt;Support&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/HackerNews/API&quot;&gt;API&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/security.html&quot;&gt;Security&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/lists&quot;&gt;Lists&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/bookmarklet.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Bookmarklet&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ycombinator.com/legal/&quot;&gt;Legal&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ycombinator.com/apply/&quot;&gt;Apply to YC&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:hn@ycombinator.com&quot;&gt;Contact&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 11:37:34 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>chatmasta</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17497164</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Microsoft announces Surface Go</title>
<link>https://blogs.windows.com/devices/2018/07/09/meet-surface-go-starting-at-399-msrp-its-the-smallest-and-most-affordable-surface-yet/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blogs.windows.com/devices/2018/07/09/meet-surface-go-starting-at-399-msrp-its-the-smallest-and-most-affordable-surface-yet/</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;post-lede&quot; readability=&quot;25.826086956522&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, Microsoft &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/p/surface-go/8V9DP4LNKNSZ/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;announces Surface Go&lt;/a&gt;: the most portable and affordable Surface product yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.windows.com/uploads/mswbprod/sites/43/2018/07/bff008f2279d614e4f3433f7717d9676.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-261858 aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;https://blogs.windows.com/uploads/mswbprod/sites/43/2018/07/bff008f2279d614e4f3433f7717d9676-1024x977.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;668&quot; srcset=&quot;https://blogs.windows.com/uploads/mswbprod/sites/43/2018/07/bff008f2279d614e4f3433f7717d9676-1024x977.jpg 1024w, https://blogs.windows.com/uploads/mswbprod/sites/43/2018/07/bff008f2279d614e4f3433f7717d9676-300x286.jpg 300w, https://blogs.windows.com/uploads/mswbprod/sites/43/2018/07/bff008f2279d614e4f3433f7717d9676-768x733.jpg 768w, https://blogs.windows.com/uploads/mswbprod/sites/43/2018/07/bff008f2279d614e4f3433f7717d9676-25x25.jpg 25w, https://blogs.windows.com/uploads/mswbprod/sites/43/2018/07/bff008f2279d614e4f3433f7717d9676-435x415.jpg 435w, https://blogs.windows.com/uploads/mswbprod/sites/43/2018/07/bff008f2279d614e4f3433f7717d9676-870x830.jpg 870w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 700px) 100vw, 700px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of us play different roles throughout the day, moving from work or school to home and everywhere in between. Our team designs every Surface to adapt to that dynamic lifestyle, to strike a balance between performance and versatility, form and function. Our products don’t do just one thing because people don’t do just one thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We pioneered categories like the 2:1 to provide the mobility of a tablet with the performance of a laptop, inspiring new ways of creating. As you pursue your passions, connect with friends and family, and work with your team, the products you’re able to take on the go with you are the ones that can keep up with the huge range of things you want to accomplish. This is true whether you’re a parent and a product-maker like me or a student and amateur photographer like my daughter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;15&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s the idea behind the design of Surface Go – our smallest, lightest, and most affordable Surface yet. When we designed this device, we had to ask ourselves what people want and need from a 10” Surface. The answers seem obvious – lightweight, productive, and accessible to more people. I’m pumped to introduce you to Surface Go, because it’s all those things, and so much more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The power and connectivity in a device this small gives you the style and productivity Surface is known for in a more convenient package. At just 1.15 pounds and 8.3 mm thin, Surface Go packs portable performance into a 10” device. Starting at $399 MSRP, it represents a new entry point for the Surface family, while keeping the premium qualities that have come to define it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surface Go offers a stunning, custom-built high-resolution PixelSense Display that supports Surface Pen with 4096 levels of pressure sensitivity, low pen parallax, low latency, and precision for accurate note taking, drawing and computer-aided design. The custom calibrated 3:2 display is soft on your eyes while you’re working and vibrantly high-contrast when you want to watch videos, create art, or edit photos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In portrait mode, the screen was designed to render the page to the scale of most school textbooks, and in landscape mode, it can render pages side by side as if you were holding a paperback book in hand. At the approximate size of a composition notebook, writing on the screen feels natural and intuitive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since my two youngest daughters have started using Surface Go, I see them watching movies, reading, and drawing on it every day. It’s the perfect device for them. And for me, whether I’m at home, in the office, or on a plane, putting my Surface Pen on the screen and letting my thoughts flow is a necessary step in my creative process. It’s how I work. It’s so easy to carry Surface Go with me so I can capture those moments, instantly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.windows.com/uploads/mswbprod/sites/43/2018/07/a22846a66a9efc6e928501b2d30471a4.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-261867 aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;https://blogs.windows.com/uploads/mswbprod/sites/43/2018/07/a22846a66a9efc6e928501b2d30471a4-1024x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;700&quot; srcset=&quot;https://blogs.windows.com/uploads/mswbprod/sites/43/2018/07/a22846a66a9efc6e928501b2d30471a4-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://blogs.windows.com/uploads/mswbprod/sites/43/2018/07/a22846a66a9efc6e928501b2d30471a4-150x150.jpg 150w, https://blogs.windows.com/uploads/mswbprod/sites/43/2018/07/a22846a66a9efc6e928501b2d30471a4-300x300.jpg 300w, https://blogs.windows.com/uploads/mswbprod/sites/43/2018/07/a22846a66a9efc6e928501b2d30471a4-768x768.jpg 768w, https://blogs.windows.com/uploads/mswbprod/sites/43/2018/07/a22846a66a9efc6e928501b2d30471a4-25x25.jpg 25w, https://blogs.windows.com/uploads/mswbprod/sites/43/2018/07/a22846a66a9efc6e928501b2d30471a4-70x70.jpg 70w, https://blogs.windows.com/uploads/mswbprod/sites/43/2018/07/a22846a66a9efc6e928501b2d30471a4-140x140.jpg 140w, https://blogs.windows.com/uploads/mswbprod/sites/43/2018/07/a22846a66a9efc6e928501b2d30471a4-400x400.jpg 400w, https://blogs.windows.com/uploads/mswbprod/sites/43/2018/07/a22846a66a9efc6e928501b2d30471a4-800x800.jpg 800w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 700px) 100vw, 700px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Surface Go is small and mighty, giving you the performance you need to be productive. A device powered by the 7th Generation Intel Pentium Gold Processor 4415Y, in a fanless design, offering up to nine hours of battery. Our team worked closely with Intel to optimize power, performance, and battery for the most critical tasks people perform every day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being able to run Office apps on this device with its portability is one of the things that was critical to the experience we had in mind when we designed Surface Go – the productivity of having the apps you use for work and school with the flexibility to relax and read or watch a show on Netflix or Hulu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our new Surface Go Signature Type Cover is custom-made for Surface Go integrating design features that give the user the best typing experience possible, with ergonomic key pitch and exceptional key travel. It also has high precision tuning and Windows Precision Trackpad that supports five-point multi-finger gestures, and you can connect the new Surface Mobile Mouse to work the way that you want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A built-in kickstand with full friction hinge that extends to 165 degrees helps you stay in your flow from tablet to studio mode, and a Windows Hello camera allows for familiar, quick, and secure sign-in using face recognition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surface Go also has the ports you need, including Surface Connect for charging and docking; USB-C 3.1 for data, video, and charging; a headphone jack; and a MicroSD card reader for storage expansion. All designed to help you be more productive whether you’re studying in a library, working on a plane, or sharing your content in a boardroom on a 4K monitor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.windows.com/uploads/mswbprod/sites/43/2018/07/7e8a40ec706b5e5133f458696fb8f71b.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-261852 aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;https://blogs.windows.com/uploads/mswbprod/sites/43/2018/07/7e8a40ec706b5e5133f458696fb8f71b-1024x576.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;701&quot; height=&quot;394&quot; srcset=&quot;https://blogs.windows.com/uploads/mswbprod/sites/43/2018/07/7e8a40ec706b5e5133f458696fb8f71b-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://blogs.windows.com/uploads/mswbprod/sites/43/2018/07/7e8a40ec706b5e5133f458696fb8f71b-300x169.jpg 300w, https://blogs.windows.com/uploads/mswbprod/sites/43/2018/07/7e8a40ec706b5e5133f458696fb8f71b-768x432.jpg 768w, https://blogs.windows.com/uploads/mswbprod/sites/43/2018/07/7e8a40ec706b5e5133f458696fb8f71b-780x440.jpg 780w, https://blogs.windows.com/uploads/mswbprod/sites/43/2018/07/7e8a40ec706b5e5133f458696fb8f71b-1560x880.jpg 1560w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 701px) 100vw, 701px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Surface Go with Wi-Fi will be &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/p/surface-go/8V9DP4LNKNSZ/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;available for pre-order tomorrow&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, July 10 in select countries*, with products beginning to hit shelves on August 2. We’re also happy to share that an LTE model will be arriving later this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a family at home or on the move, an expert on the front line of a business interacting with customers, or a school that wants to provide its students with the most versatile tools for learning, this device offers a premium experience with incredible value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wherever the day takes you, and whatever unique tasks await you along the way, Surface Go moves with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;blue wb-es-quote aligncenter&quot; readability=&quot;6.3137254901961&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meet Surface Go, starting at $399 MSRP, it’s the smallest and most affordable Surface yet&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;javascript:void(0);&quot; title=&quot;Tweet This&quot; id=&quot;tweetThis-blue&quot; class=&quot;wb-es-tweetThis&quot; data-es-share-data=&quot;https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?text=Meet+Surface+Go%2C+starting+at+%24399+MSRP%2C+it%E2%80%99s+the+smallest+and+most+affordable+Surface+yet&amp;amp;url=https://blogs.windows.com/devices/2018/07/09/meet-surface-go-starting-at-399-msrp-its-the-smallest-and-most-affordable-surface-yet/&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Tweet This&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;*Availability:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Surface Go will be available for pre-order beginning on July 10 in the following markets, US, Canada, Australia, New Zealand, UK, Ireland, France, Germany, Austria, Belgium, Luxembourg, Netherlands, Switzerland, Denmark, Finland, Norway, Sweden, Poland, Italy, Portugal, and Spain.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In the coming weeks, Surface Go will be available for pre-order in Japan, Singapore, Korea, Taiwan, Malaysia, Thailand, Hong Kong, and in China with more markets to follow.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;** To learn more &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/Surface/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;join us on our Facebook page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; at 6AM PT on July 10. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;post-modified&quot;&gt;Updated July 10, 2018 7:37 am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 05:10:50 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ductionist</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Meet Surface Go, starting at $399 MSRP, it’s the smallest and most affordable Surface yet - Microsoft Devices Blog</og:title>
<og:description>Today, Microsoft announces Surface Go: the most portable and affordable Surface product yet.</og:description>
<og:url>https://blogs.windows.com/devices/2018/07/09/meet-surface-go-starting-at-399-msrp-its-the-smallest-and-most-affordable-surface-yet/</og:url>
<og:image>https://blogs.windows.com/uploads/mswbprod/sites/43/2018/07/486302f090ce96357798b263513d3970-1024x498.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blogs.windows.com/devices/2018/07/09/meet-surface-go-starting-at-399-msrp-its-the-smallest-and-most-affordable-surface-yet/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>