<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>You can now run Linux apps on Chrome OS</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2018/05/08/you-can-now-run-linux-apps-on-chrome-os/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2018/05/08/you-can-now-run-linux-apps-on-chrome-os/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;For the longest time, developers have taken Chrome OS machines and run tools like &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/dnschneid/crouton&quot;&gt;Crouton&lt;/a&gt; to turn them into Linux-based developer machines. That was a bit of a hassle, but it worked. But things are getting easier. Soon, if you want to run Linux apps on your Chrome OS machine, all you’ll have to do is switch a toggle in the Settings menu. That’s because Google is going to start shipping Chrome OS with a custom virtual machine that runs Debian Stretch, the current stable version of the operating system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s worth stressing that we’re not just talking about a shell here, but full support for graphical apps, too. That means you could now, for example, run Microsoft’s Linux version of Visual Studio Code right on your Chrome OS machine. Or build your Android app in Android Studio and test it right on your laptop, thanks to the built-in support for Android apps that came to Chrome OS last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;breakout aligncenter size-full wp-image-1636019&quot; src=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/img_20180508_132119.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;768&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first preview of Linux on Chrome OS is now available on the Pixelbook, with support for more devices coming soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/google/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;google&quot;&gt;Google’s&lt;/a&gt; PM director for Chrome OS Kan Liu told me the company was obviously aware that people were using Crouton to do this before. But doing this also meant doing away with all of the security features that come with Google’s operating system. And as more powerful Chrome OS machines hit the market in recent years, the demand for a feature like this also grew.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To enable support for graphical apps, the team opted to integrate the Wayland display server; from the user’s perspective, the actual window dressing will look the same as any other Android or web app on Chrome OS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most regular users won’t necessarily benefit from built-in Linux support, but this will make Chrome OS machines even more attractive to developers — especially the more high-end ones like Google’s own Pixelbook. Liu stressed that his team spent quite a bit of work optimizing the virtual machine, too, so there isn’t a lot of overhead when you run Linux apps — meaning that even less powerful machines should be able to handle a code editor without issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, it’s probably only a matter of hours before somebody starts running Windows apps in Chrome OS with the help of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.winehq.org/&quot;&gt;Wine emulator&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/tag/google-i-o-2018&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/google-io-2018-banner.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 20:23:04 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>willsinclair</dc:creator>
<og:title>You can now run Linux apps on Chrome OS</og:title>
<og:description>For the longest time, developers have taken Chrome OS machines and run tools like Crouton to turn them into Linux-based developer machines. That was a bit of a hassle, but it worked. But things are getting easier. Soon, if you want to run Linux apps on your Chrome OS machine, all you’ll have …</og:description>
<og:image>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/chrome-linux-apps.png?w=753</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2018/05/08/you-can-now-run-linux-apps-on-chrome-os/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2018/05/08/you-can-now-run-linux-apps-on-chrome-os/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Google Duplex: An AI System for Accomplishing Real World Tasks Over the Phone</title>
<link>https://ai.googleblog.com/2018/05/duplex-ai-system-for-natural-conversation.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://ai.googleblog.com/2018/05/duplex-ai-system-for-natural-conversation.html</guid>
<description></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 17:51:44 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ivank</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Google Duplex: An AI System for Accomplishing Real World Tasks Over the Phone</og:title>
<og:image>http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-qRz-hnwUdY4/WulXSQ6Rv4I/AAAAAAAATvQ/shk7KsphA0c3E3nUMsDVASqYaH0PhLPNwCK4BGAYYCw/s1600/GoogleAI_logo_horizontal_color_rgb.png</og:image>
<og:url>http://ai.googleblog.com/2018/05/duplex-ai-system-for-natural-conversation.html</og:url>
<og:description>Posted by Yaniv Leviathan, Principal Engineer and Yossi Matias, Vice President, Engineering, Google A long-standing goal of human-comput...</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://ai.googleblog.com/2018/05/duplex-ai-system-for-natural-conversation.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>iOS 11.4 to Disable USB Port After 7 Days: What It Means for Mobile Forensics</title>
<link>https://blog.elcomsoft.com/2018/05/ios-11-4-to-disable-usb-port-after-7-days-what-it-means-for-mobile-forensics/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.elcomsoft.com/2018/05/ios-11-4-to-disable-usb-port-after-7-days-what-it-means-for-mobile-forensics/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;A new iOS update is about to roll out in the next few weeks or even days. Reading Apple documentation and researching developer betas, we discovered a major new security feature that is about to be released with iOS 11.4. The update will disable the Lightning port after 7 days since the device has been last unlocked. What is the meaning of this security measure, what reasons are behind, and what can be done about it? Let’s have a closer look.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;USB Restricted Mode in iOS 11.4&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the iOS 11.4 Beta, Apple introduced a new called USB Restricted Mode. In fact, the feature made its first appearance in the iOS 11.3 Beta, but was later removed from the final release. This is how it works:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“To improve security, for a locked iOS device to communicate with USB accessories you must connect an accessory via lightning connector to the device while unlocked – or enter your device passcode while connected – at least once a week.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The functionality of USB Restricted Mode is actually very simple. Once the iPhone or iPad is updated to the latest version of iOS supporting the feature, the device will disable the USB data connection over the Lightning port one week after the device has been last unlocked.&lt;span id=&quot;more-4802&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, it is still unclear whether the USB port is blocked if the device has not been unlocked with a passcode for 7 consecutive days; if the device has not been unlocked at all (password or biometrics); or if the device has not been unlocked or connected to a trusted USB device or computer. In our test, we were able to confirm the USB lock after the device has been left idle for 7 days. During this period, we have not tried to unlock the device with Touch ID or connect it to a paired USB device. What we do know, however, is that after the 7 days the Lightning port is only good for charging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Forensic Consequences of USB Restricted Mode&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Restricted USB Mode requires an iPhone running 11.3 to be unlocked at least once every 7 days. Otherwise, the Lightning port will lock down to charge only mode. The iPhone or iPad will still charge, but it will no longer attempt to establish a data connection. Even the “Trust this computer?” prompt will not be displayed once the device is connected to the computer, and any existing lockdown records (iTunes pairing records) will not be honoured until the user unlocks the device with a passcode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other words, law enforcement will have at most 7 days from the time the device was last unlocked to perform the extraction using any known forensic techniques, be it logical acquisition or passcode recovery via GreyKey or other services . Even the 7 days are not a given, since the exact date and time the device was last unlocked may not be known.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;USB Restricted Mode and Lockdown Records&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before iOS 11, one could use an existing lockdown record to access the iPhone or iPad device for the purpose of creating a new local backup (&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.elcomsoft.com/2016/11/acquisition-of-a-locked-iphone-with-a-lockdown-record/&quot;&gt;logical acquisition&lt;/a&gt;). Essentially, this is exactly how experts perform logical acquisition in the vast majority of cases of iPhone and iPad devices that are &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.elcomsoft.com/2017/01/how-can-i-break-into-a-locked-ios-10-iphone/&quot;&gt;locked with an unknown passcode&lt;/a&gt;. The lockdown record (a small file extracted from the suspect’s computer) allows accessing essential information about the device and initiating the backup sequence &lt;strong&gt;without the passcode&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to iTunes-style backups, the lockdown record &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.elcomsoft.com/2018/04/understanding-logical-acquisition-of-ios-devices/&quot;&gt;could be used&lt;/a&gt; for pulling media files (pictures and videos), list installed apps, and access general information about the device. Once created, the lockdown records would not expire; however, if you &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.elcomsoft.com/2017/11/the-iphone-is-locked-down-dealing-with-cold-boot-situations/&quot;&gt;power-cycle or reboot the iPhone&lt;/a&gt;, even a valid lockdown record will be of little use until you unlock the device with a passcode because of full-disk encryption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;iOS 11 brought limitations to the use of lockdown records. In iOS 11.0 through 11.2.1, lockdown records would expire after a certain unspecified time. Once a lockdown record expired, it could no longer be used to establish communication with the iOS device; the user would need to enter their passcode on the device to establish a new pairing relationship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;iOS 11.3 further limited the lifespan of iTunes pairing records, making the records &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.elcomsoft.com/2018/01/ios-11-3-adds-expiry-date-to-lockdown-pairing-records/&quot;&gt;expire after 7 days&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What Happens After 7 Days?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apparently, iOS stores information about the date and time the device was last unlocked or had a data connection to a USB port. After the seven days elapse, the Lightning port will be disabled. Once this happens, you will no longer be able to pair the device to a computer or USB accessory, or use an existing lockdown record, without unlocking the device with a passcode. The only thing you’ll be able to do is charging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether or not iPhone unlocking solutions developed by GreyShift and Cellerbrite will work is still an open question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Mitigation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;USB Restricted Mode is aimed squarely at law enforcement, preventing device acquisition after the device has been stored for 7 consecutive days without being unlocked or connected to a (paired) computer or USB accessory. At this time, we suggest two possible mitigations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Extract the device during the first 7 days using a lockdown record (if available).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Attempt to unlock the device during the first 7 days. Unlocking solutions (e.g. by GreyShift) will disable USB Restricted Mode if the initial connection is made while the Lightning port is still active.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If a lockdown record is available, connecting the device to a paired accessory or computer may extend the time the USB port remains active. However, bear in mind that lockdown records now carry a 7-day expiry date of their own.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;In addition, managed devices may disable USB Restricted Mode for good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The success rate will receive on the condition in which the phone is delivered to the lab. If the phone was seized while it was still powered on, and kept powered on in the meanwhile, than the chance of successfully connecting the phone to a computer for the purpose of making a local backup will depend on whether or not the expert has access to a non-expired lockdown file (pairing record). If, however, the phone is delivered in a powered-off state, and the passcode is not known, the chance of successful extraction is slim at best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why Apple Needed USB Restricted Mode&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actually, it was only a matter of time. Companies such as Cellerbrite and the recent newcomer &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2018/03/greykey_iphone_.html&quot;&gt;GreyShift&lt;/a&gt; make their business by unlocking protected iPhones. While Cellerbrite offers this exclusively as an in-house service, and the service is only available to select law enforcement agencies with proper court orders, GreyKey supplies the actual unlocking hardware to North American law enforcement. Both companies keep their lips shut as to the details of their techniques, so the exact method they use to gain access to the devices is not known to Apple. However, their ability to unlock even the latest hardware running the latest version of iOS is worrisome, so Apple is taking action with the USB Restricted Mode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In responce to the latest developments, Apple made an attempt to prevent device exploitation. USB Restricted Mode effectively disables the iPhone or iPad Lightning ports after 7 days without an unlock. While this undoubtedly strengthens overall security of iOS devices, effectively disabling logical acquisition through lockdown records after 7 days the device has been in storage, its effect on passcode unlocking techniques developed by Cellerbrite and GreyShift is yet to be seen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What else is Apple baking in iOS 11.4? Without going through the lengthy list of bug fixes and improvements, there is the possibility of iMessage sync with iCloud being finally released in iOS 11.4. iMessage sync showed up in early betas of iOS 11.0, but didn’t make it into the final release. The feature appeared again in iOS 11.3 betas, but was stripped from the final release at the last minute. There are signs the feature might be ready for prime time in iOS 11.4. How will iMessage sync work? How will it be different from Continuity, and what challenges and benefits will it present to the mobile forensic crowd? Stay tuned to find out!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;nodash&quot; readability=&quot;13.508771929825&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tags: &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.elcomsoft.com/tag/ios-11-4/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;ios 11.4&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.elcomsoft.com/tag/ipad/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;iPad&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.elcomsoft.com/tag/iphone/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;iPhone&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.elcomsoft.com/tag/lightning/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;lightning&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.elcomsoft.com/tag/logical-acquisition/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;logical acquisition&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.elcomsoft.com/tag/passcode-recovery/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;passcode recovery&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.elcomsoft.com/tag/physical-acquisition/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;physical acquisition&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;postmetadata alt&quot;&gt;&lt;small&gt;This entry was posted on Tuesday, May 8th, 2018 at 1:25 pm and is filed under &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.elcomsoft.com/category/did-you-know-that/&quot; rel=&quot;category tag&quot;&gt;Did you know that...?&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.elcomsoft.com/category/industry-news/&quot; rel=&quot;category tag&quot;&gt;Industry News&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.elcomsoft.com/category/security/&quot; rel=&quot;category tag&quot;&gt;Security&lt;/a&gt;. You can follow any responses to this entry through the &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.elcomsoft.com/2018/05/ios-11-4-to-disable-usb-port-after-7-days-what-it-means-for-mobile-forensics/feed/&quot;&gt;RSS 2.0&lt;/a&gt; feed. Both comments and pings are currently closed.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 15:19:47 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Artemis2</dc:creator>
<og:title>iOS 11.4 to Disable USB Port After 7 Days: What It Means for Mobile Forensics</og:title>
<og:url>https://blog.elcomsoft.com/2018/05/ios-11-4-to-disable-usb-port-after-7-days-what-it-means-for-mobile-forensics/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>A new iOS update is about to roll out in the next few weeks or even days. Reading Apple documentation and researching developer betas, we discovered a major new security feature that is about to be released with iOS 11.4. The update will disable the Lightning port after 7 days since the device has b</og:description>
<og:image>https://blog.elcomsoft.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/ios11.4_1200x630.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.elcomsoft.com/2018/05/ios-11-4-to-disable-usb-port-after-7-days-what-it-means-for-mobile-forensics/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>How Mapbox Is Winning Over Developers to Challenge Google&amp;#039;s Mapping Dominance</title>
<link>https://www.forbes.com/sites/bizcarson/2018/05/08/mapbox-maps-developers/#79431e78164d</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.forbes.com/sites/bizcarson/2018/05/08/mapbox-maps-developers/#79431e78164d</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/bizcarson/2018/05/08/mapbox-maps-developers/#79431e78164d&quot;&gt;https://www.forbes.com/sites/bizcarson/2018/05/08/mapbox-maps-developers/#79431e78164d&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17021205&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17021205&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Points: 265&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 90&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 14:42:09 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>coloneltcb</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.forbes.com/forbes/welcome/?toURL=https://www.forbes.com/sites/bizcarson/2018/05/08/mapbox-maps-developers/&amp;refURL=http://www.google.co.uk/url?sa=t&amp;source=web&amp;cd=1&amp;referrer=http://www.google.co.uk/url?sa=t&amp;source=web&amp;cd=1</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Amazon Froze My Account and I Still Don’t Know Why</title>
<link>https://bardsandsages.com/juliedawson/2018/05/06/amazon-froze-my-account-and-i-still-dont-know-why/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://bardsandsages.com/juliedawson/2018/05/06/amazon-froze-my-account-and-i-still-dont-know-why/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Where do I begin…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On May 2nd, I got an accusatory email from Amazon, claiming that one of my Society of Misfit Stories ebooks had “misleading metadata” and had been deactivated. Now before I get too far into this story, for those of you that are not tuned in to the soap opera that has become Amazon publishing as of late, metadata abuse is a major problem on Amazon. If you ever came across a book with a title like &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In Love With the Werewolf Billionaire&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;(billionaire alpha shifter romance bestseller book three Sexy Werewolf Billionaire Series)&lt;/strong&gt; then you know things like keyword stuffing and bad metadata is a thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the thing is, my metadata is pristine. Because, you know, I’ve been involved in publishing for over a dozen years now and understand professional norms. So, the title and author name in the metadata for EVERY BOOK matches the title and author on the cover, and both match the title and author on the title page. Because, that is what you are supposed to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And while the ebook was in Select, there was no weirdness going on with it. Each ebook in the series is literally: title page, story, one-page author bio. THAT IS IT. No links to competitors. No stuffing of books within other books to increase page reads. No funny coding to trick the system into thinking more pages have been read than were actually read. &lt;strong&gt;Title page, story, author bio.&lt;/strong&gt; That is ALL that is in each entry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was some vague reference to the name of a famous author or personality. No, the email did not NAME the famous personality, and when I used Amazon search to see if there was another author with the same name as my author, nothing came up. So I sent Amazon an email that I didn’t understand what they were talking about. The author name was correct. Please reactivate the story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A short time later, I tried to log into my KDP account to upload the newest Misfit story and…I was frozen out of my account. I couldn’t even access KDP support. I had to go through regular Amazon support to reach a person, who forwarded my complaint to KDP support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus begin the bizarre story of my argument with the Bots of Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most people have suspected for a while now that Amazon was relying way too much on automation. The story you are about to read is evidence of just how ridiculous this has gotten.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following day, I received this email:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During a quality assurance review of your catalog, we found that you have published books with intentionally misleading metadata.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some examples of the books you have submitted:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Society of Misfit Stories Presents…[I have removed the title to avoid embarrassing the affected author]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As stated in our metadata guidelines, we don’t accept content that is meant to advertise, promote, or mislead, because such content may lead to inaccurate or overwhelming search results or impair our readers’ ability to make good buying decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result, we have temporarily suspended your account and we request that you respond to content-review@amazon.com with the following declaration: “I confirm that I have read and will comply with the Content Guidelines [https://kdp.amazon.com/self-publishing/help?topicId=A2TOZW0SV7IR1U] and [https://kdp.amazon.com/self-publishing/help?topicId=A294SHSUYLKTA6], and that I will remove any previously published books that do not meet these guidelines.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until we receive a response from you regarding this issue, your account will remain blocked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you would like to review the KDP Content Guidelines, please visit: https://kdp.amazon.com/self-publishing/help?topicId=A2TOZW0SV7IR1U.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So instead of explaining what they think I did, they send me a notice requiring me to promise not to do again what I have no idea what I have done. So I email them AGAIN asking them to please explain what, exactly, they think I did. Because I am very familiar with the TOS and for the life of me I have no idea what I am being accused of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few hours later, I get the following reply:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For information regarding your account, please reference the message that we sent you on May 3, 2018:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;we request that you respond to content-review@amazon.com with the following declaration: “I confirm that I have read and will comply with the Content Guidelines [https://kdp.amazon.com/self-publishing/help?topicId=A2TOZW0SV7IR1U] and [https://kdp.amazon.com/self-publishing/help?topicId=A294SHSUYLKTA6], and that I will remove any previously published books that do not meet these guidelines.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To reinstate your account please follow the instructions provided in the above email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazon.com&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, I send ANOTHER email asking them what they think I did. I can’t fix something that I don’t know what the problem is. I also forwarded the whole thing to Jeff Bezos’ email address, as sometimes he will get involved or, at least, whomever answers his emails gets involved. Because I NEED TO TALK TO A HUMAN BEING!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On May 4th, I get the following response:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have temporarily suspended your account and we request that you respond to content-review@amazon.com with the following declaration: “I confirm that I have read and will comply with the Content Guidelines and , and that I will remove any previously published books that do not meet these guidelines.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until we receive a response from you regarding this issue, your account will remain blocked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you would like to review the KDP Content Guidelines, please visit: https://kdp.amazon.com/self-publishing/help?topicId=A2TOZW0SV7IR1U.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Best Regards,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Camila H&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Best Regards,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ian S&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bangs head on table&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A short time later, I DID get an email from someone at KDP Executive Customer Relations, that they were investigating my problem and would get back to me. FINALLY! A human being was involved!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, on the 5th, I got another generic email from Amazon, making the same, identical statement demanding that I promise not to do what I have no idea what they think I did ever again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now at this point, your Sithiness here is ready to Force Choke someone. Because it is so painfully….HILARIOUSLY….obvious that no human being is reading my email queries that I decide to set a trap for the bot. So at 6 PM Saturday night, I sent the following email to their content-review address:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As per the request below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;”I confirm that I have read and will comply with the Content Guidelines [https://kdp.amazon.com/self-publishing/help?topicId=A2TOZW0SV7IR1U] and [https://kdp.amazon.com/self-publishing/help?topicId=A294SHSUYLKTA6], and that I will remove any previously published books that do not meet these guidelines.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I have repeated the requested statement, please unfreeze my account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am repeating this statement at your request. This is not an admission of guilt, as you have not actually informed me of what I an allegedly guilty of. I am complying with an arbitrary request to repeat information in an automated email. Repeating this statement in no way acknowledges the validity of the accusations Implied, since the accusations have never actually be clarified in any way, shape, or form.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what do you think are the chances that the bot scanned the response for the required phrase and then unfroze my account without a human being ever reading it? If you answered “Highly likely…YOU WOULD BE CORRECT! Because by Sunday morning, my account was unfrozen, and I got a lovely, accusatory bot response informing me not to do it again or I could lose BOTH my KDP and Createspace accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still have no idea what I did, however. Since the offending story was reinstated with no changes to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started publishing in 2004, before the Kindle was a thing. I started with mobipocket.com and was part of the initial transition into KDP when it launched. I was an early adopter of the Createspace platform. I have been publishing with Amazon for over a decade and have always strived to present professional material. To have a robot accuse me of unethical behavior and demand that I promise not to do it again is insulting and borderline libel. Anyone who has ever worked with me knows I am one of the most open and transparent publishing in the indie community. To have an automated algorithm make an arbitrary decision that I broke some unexplained rule is enough to make me breath fire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what does all this mean?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For starters, it means I will no longer be making any Bards and Sages Publishing titles available exclusively through Select. All current Society of Misfit Stories locked into the 90-day exclusivity will remain available in Select until the 90-day window expires. Future Society of Misfit Stories entries will be published at Smashwords.com. This means they will also be available in epub and PDF formats, as well as mobi format. They will still be removed from sale after the six-month window.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly, I’ve already stopped using Createspace for new releases. I’m going to start transitioning all of our older titles off Createspace platform. The books will still be available in print on Amazon, but they will no longer be under Amazon’s bot-tastic thumb where they will be able to lock me out of my own books.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, while I will continue to upload ebooks to Amazon for now, I’m going to pursue other affiliate programs and stop driving traffic to Amazon listings entirely. In truth, Amazon has never been my primary market anyway, and if they don’t care enough about their publishers to have actual people make decisions that impact author livelihoods, I don’t know how much more business I want to pursue with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t expect Amazon will even notice or care about these changes. I’m not a seven-figure seller, and therefore I don’t matter to them. That is apparent from the treatment I received this weekend. Unfortunately, the treatment I received this weekend is indicative of how they treat everyone that is not a seven-figure seller. Amazon is not a friend of authors. They see us as interchangeable commodities to be used up, worn out, and replaced: like widgets.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 12:57:54 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ilamont</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://bardsandsages.com/juliedawson/2018/05/06/amazon-froze-my-account-and-i-still-dont-know-why/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Fonts for Complex Data</title>
<link>https://www.typography.com/blog/fonts-for-complex-data</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.typography.com/blog/fonts-for-complex-data</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;small-caps&quot;&gt;Type designers work with a diverse clientele,&lt;/span&gt; and yet common themes always seem to emerge in our conversations. This seems to be the season of complex typography, in which designers everywhere are faced with the challenge of presenting different and competing kinds of information to readers. An agency we’re working with is designing a demanding identity for a fast-moving consumer goods brand; an in-house art department is creating a responsive website for complex financial disclosures; a freelance graphic designer is doing the identity for a local coffeeshop, and discovering the joys and perils of digital menu boards. As always, the wrong fonts can lead designers into sticky dead ends, but the right ones can be immeasurably helpful. Here are some of the things our clients consider when faced with complex typography, and some of the typographic strategies that can be the quickest routes to success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Strategies for Small Sizes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Information can often be divided into data and annotations. A web form needs a way to distinguish entry fields from labels; a graph needs not only labels for its &lt;em&gt;x&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;y&lt;/em&gt; axes, but most crucially a verifiable reference for the source of its data. (#fakenews, I’m looking at you.) The most familiar and obvious way to establish this hierarchy is through type size, using palpably smaller type to distinguish the content from its notes. But at smaller-than-text sizes, even the most lucid typefaces can become difficult to read, their spacing overly tight, their counters congested, and their x-heights measly. Compare the tiny type in these two examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typography.com/fonts/whitney/styles/screensmart/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d31td5fkd89rr1.cloudfront.net/assets/images/blog/designing-captions.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;750&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typography.com/fonts/whitney/overview/&quot;&gt;Whitney&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typography.com/fonts/whitney/styles/screensmart/&quot;&gt;Whitney ScreenSmart&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Helpfully, there’s an adaptation designed for the web that proves useful in any medium: a typeface’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typography.com/collections/screensmart/&quot;&gt;ScreenSmart&lt;/a&gt; fonts, which are designed to compensate for the effects of scale. Above, two compositions using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typography.com/fonts/whitney/overview/&quot;&gt;Whitney&lt;/a&gt; typeface, the one at the right substituting &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typography.com/fonts/whitney/styles/screensmart/&quot;&gt;Whitney ScreenSmart&lt;/a&gt; for the tiny annotations below the graph. ScreenSmart fonts always deliver greater clarity and more comfortable reading at smaller-than-text sizes, making them a useful companion to a multipurpose typeface for setting the fine print.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Dealing with Lists&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fine print is the bugbear of typography not only for its tiny size, but often its prodigious length. Disclosures, disclaimers, and lists of ingredients may be the sections that readers most often ignore, yet they’re among the most heavily regulated part of any typographic object, and therefore the content that’s most heavily scrutinized by an alarmingly large portion of an organization. Hands up if you’ve ever received a request from Legal to fit in a few more sentences once a design has been approved. Hands up if this wasn’t exacly a “request.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typography.com/fonts/gotham/styles/gothamnarrowbundle&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d31td5fkd89rr1.cloudfront.net/assets/images/blog/designing-ingredients-3.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;750&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typography.com/fonts/gotham/styles/gothamcondensedbundle&quot;&gt;Gotham Condensed&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typography.com/fonts/gotham/styles/gothamnarrowbundle&quot;&gt;Gotham Narrow&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A non-designer’s first impulse is often to reach for a condensed typeface, on the principle that narrower letters take up less space. Yet it’s almost always a better option to make the counter-intuitive choice of a &lt;em&gt;wider&lt;/em&gt; typeface, and to set the type in a smaller size with tighter leading. Wider letters have more comfortable proportions, they’re more generously spaced, and they have more ample counters, collectively making them the more legible choice. Above, two ingredient lists in Gotham: at left the passable &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typography.com/fonts/gotham/styles/gothamcondensedbundle&quot;&gt;Gotham Condensed&lt;/a&gt;, but at right the far more inviting &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typography.com/fonts/gotham/styles/gothamnarrowbundle&quot;&gt;Gotham Narrow&lt;/a&gt;, a family that’s two steps wider. &lt;strong class=&quot;alternate&quot;&gt;TIP:&lt;/strong&gt; Use not only a wider font, but a wider &lt;em&gt;ScreenSmart&lt;/em&gt; font as well, for maximum clarity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Working the Character Set&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The humble &lt;em&gt;annotation&lt;/em&gt; can give designers the chance to flex their creativity, and an excuse to explore the more colorful quarters of the character set. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typography.com/blog/house-of-flying-reference-marks&quot;&gt;Reference marks&lt;/a&gt;, starting with the asterisk and dagger, are sometimes a welcome grace note whenever the subject matter becomes dry, but beware their use if there are more than three notes in a document. Readers can be counted upon to recognize the cycle of *, †, and ‡, but probably not the longer series of **, ††, and ‡‡ — or §, || and #, depending on your house style. If there are more than three footnotes, stick with unambiguously numbered &lt;em&gt;superscripts&lt;/em&gt; instead:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typography.com/fonts/chronicle-text/overview/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d31td5fkd89rr1.cloudfront.net/assets/images/blog/designing-footnotes.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;750&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typography.com/fonts/chronicle-text/overview/&quot;&gt;Chronicle Text Grade 2 Pro&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Superscripts are included in every H&amp;amp;Co font that has a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typography.com/collections/charts-tables/&quot;&gt;Pro&lt;/a&gt; edition, as well as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typography.com/fonts/gotham/features/gotham-numerics&quot;&gt;Gotham&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typography.com/fonts/ringside/features/ringside-numerics&quot;&gt;Ringside&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typography.com/fonts/inkwell/features/inkwell-numerics&quot;&gt;Inkwell&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;strong class=&quot;alternate&quot;&gt;TIP:&lt;/strong&gt; In the text, mark your footnotes with &lt;em&gt;superscripts,&lt;/em&gt; which ascend above the cap height. But in the notes themselves, use &lt;em&gt;numerators&lt;/em&gt; instead, which are lower on the body. This connects them more clearly with the explanations that follow, and gives them greater clearance from the preceding lines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Numerics, Numerics, Numerics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.typography.com/collections/charts-tables/&quot;&gt;Pro&lt;/a&gt; packages that contain superscripts and numerators contain &lt;em&gt;tabular figures,&lt;/em&gt; the most vital part of any composition that includes numbers. Unlike a font’s traditional &lt;em&gt;proportional figures,&lt;/em&gt; whose widths vary with the natural shape of each number — from a narrow &lt;strong class=&quot;alternate&quot;&gt;1&lt;/strong&gt; to a wide &lt;strong class=&quot;alternate&quot;&gt;0&lt;/strong&gt; — tabular figures are all built on the same horizontal measure, ensuring that columns of data always align correctly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typography.com/collections/symbols-technical/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d31td5fkd89rr1.cloudfront.net/assets/images/blog/sans-serif-numbers.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;750&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tabular figures have a second and equally important characteristic: they maintain their equal widths across a range of &lt;em&gt;weights. (&lt;/em&gt;This runs counter to the typical behavior in a typeface, in which heavier weights become progressively wider.) Known as “duplexing,” this is one of the essential characteristics of tabular figures, because it allows designers to highlight individual lines in boldface without disrupting the width of the column.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typography.com/collections/symbols-technical/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d31td5fkd89rr1.cloudfront.net/assets/images/blog/serif-numbers.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;750&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;alternate&quot;&gt;TIP:&lt;/strong&gt; The word “tabular” may imply the dense tables that are annexed to annual reports and financial disclosures, but don’t forget how often stacks of numbers appear in other contexts. Tabular figures are essential in menus, indexes, and directories, and anywhere that a design includes prices, statistics, account numbers, or scores — or any kind of dynamic data online. Any digital experience that shows changing numbers such as stock prices, sports scores, product &lt;span class=&quot;small-caps&quot;&gt;sku&lt;/span&gt;s, exchange rates, flight numbers, timetables, or membership points will absolutely demand tabular figures. Design your projects with tabular figures from the outset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typography.com/fonts/archer/styles/archer3pro&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d31td5fkd89rr1.cloudfront.net/assets/images/blog/designing-menus.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;750&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Making Creative Choices&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advanced numeric characters like tabular figures and superscripts aren’t the exclusive province of workhorse type families, and not every project demands a sober serif or sans. When a project’s complexity requires a hard-working typeface, but its subject matter invites a more individual tone, look for unexpected typefaces that feature extended numerics. The handwritten &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typography.com/fonts/inkwell/features/inkwell-numerics&quot;&gt;Inkwell&lt;/a&gt; contains all the features needed to articulate demanding content, but its relaxed demeanor has a natural affinity for entertainment, retail, food services, the arts, hospitality, pediatric care, and even philanthropy:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typography.com/fonts/inkwell/styles/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d31td5fkd89rr1.cloudfront.net/assets/images/blog/designing-annual-reports.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;750&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typography.com/fonts/inkwell/overview/&quot;&gt;Inkwell&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;alternate&quot;&gt;TIP:&lt;/strong&gt; If your tables will use only a single weight, consider a typeface whose numbers have &lt;em&gt;equal widths&lt;/em&gt; without the regular-and-bold &lt;em&gt;duplexing&lt;/em&gt; of true tabular figures. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typography.com/fonts/numbers/inside/indicia&quot;&gt;Indicia&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typography.com/fonts/numbers/inside/claimcheck&quot;&gt;Claimcheck&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typography.com/fonts/numbers/inside/revenue&quot;&gt;Revenue&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typography.com/fonts/numbers/inside/greenback&quot;&gt;Greenback&lt;/a&gt; typefaces in our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typography.com/fonts/numbers/overview/&quot;&gt;Numbers&lt;/a&gt; collection are designed on a fixed width, as are the cheeky digits in each weight of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typography.com/fonts/inkwell/inside/inkwell-blackletter&quot;&gt;Inkwell Blackletter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typography.com/collections/symbols-technical/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d31td5fkd89rr1.cloudfront.net/assets/images/blog/decorative-numbers3.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;750&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Branding Custom Collateral&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last mile of visual communications are often the things created not by designers, but by software. It’s frequently the operators of word processors, spreadsheets, and presentation packages who need to speak in the organization’s voice, but lack the tools to do so properly. For these projects, we’ve created &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typography.com/blog/office-fonts&quot;&gt;Office Fonts&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typography.com/collections/office/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d31td5fkd89rr1.cloudfront.net/assets/images/blog/designing-statements.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;750&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typography.com/fonts/isotope/overview/&quot;&gt;Isotope&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typography.com/fonts/whitney/styles/office/&quot;&gt;Whitney Office&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Office Fonts are adaptations of H&amp;amp;Co’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typography.com/collections/office/&quot;&gt;hardest-working typefaces&lt;/a&gt;, specifically engineered for use in business packages such as Word, Excel, and PowerPoint. These are the same families whose ScreenSmart fonts invite use at small sizes, and whose Pro character sets can tackle complex data. Reimagined for the non-designer, Office Fonts are limited to a familiar four styles per family (roman, italic, bold, and bold italic), and feature exclusively tabular figures, to avoid typographic mishaps that might go undetected. (And they ship in TrueType format, for maximum backward compatibility with even the most antiquated operating systems.) &lt;strong class=&quot;alternate&quot;&gt;TIP:&lt;/strong&gt; If a brand’s communications will ultimately include custom collateral like reports, proposals, statements, and presentations, design these documents from the outset using Office Fonts, to take advantage of their unique characteristics. —JH&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 02:46:01 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>privong</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.typography.com/blog/fonts-for-complex-data</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Tech watchdogs call on Facebook, Google for transparency around censored content</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2018/05/07/santa-clara-principles-eff-cdt-aclu-facebook-google-twitter/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2018/05/07/santa-clara-principles-eff-cdt-aclu-facebook-google-twitter/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;If a company like &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/facebook/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;facebook&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; can’t even understand why its moderation tools work the way they do, then its users certainly don’t have a fighting shot. Anyway, that’s the idea behind what a coalition of digital rights groups are calling The &lt;a href=&quot;https://cdt.org/files/2018/05/Santa_Clara_Principles.pdf&quot;&gt;Santa Clara Principles&lt;/a&gt; (PDF), “a set of minimum standards” aimed at Facebook, Google, Twitter and other tech companies that moderate the content published on their platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The suggested guidelines grew out of a set of events addressing “&lt;a href=&quot;http://comoatscale.com/&quot;&gt;Content Moderation and Removal at Scale&lt;/a&gt;,” the second of which is taking place &lt;a href=&quot;http://comoatscale.com/video/&quot;&gt;today&lt;/a&gt; in Washington, D.C. The group participating in these conversations shared the goal of coming up with a suggested ruleset for how major tech companies should disclose which content is being censored, why it is being censored and how much speech is censored overall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Users deserve more transparency and greater accountability from platforms that play an outsized role — in Myanmar, Australia, Europe, and China, as well as in marginalized communities in the U.S. and elsewhere — in deciding what can be said on the internet,” Electronic Frontier Foundation (EFF) Director for International Freedom of Expression Jillian C. York said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the Center for Democracy and Technology explains, The &lt;a href=&quot;https://cdt.org/files/2018/05/Santa_Clara_Principles.pdf&quot;&gt;Santa Clara principles&lt;/a&gt; (PDF) ask tech companies to disclose three categories of information:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Numbers (of posts removed, accounts suspended);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Notice (to users about content removals and account suspensions); and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Appeals (for users impacted by content removals or account suspensions).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The Santa Clara Principles are the product of years of effort by privacy advocates to push tech companies to provide users with more disclosure and a better understanding of how content policing works,” EFF Senior Staff Attorney Nate Cardozo added.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Facebook and &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/google/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;google&quot;&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt; have taken some steps recently to improve transparency, and we applaud that. But it’s not enough. We hope to see the companies embrace The Santa Clara Principles and move the bar on transparency and accountability even higher.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Participants in drafting The Santa Clara Principles include the ACLU Foundation of Northern California, Center for Democracy and Technology, Electronic Frontier Foundation, New America’s Open Technology Institute and a handful of scholars from departments studying ethics and communications.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 20:10:31 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>cfadvan</dc:creator>
<og:title>Tech watchdogs call on Facebook and Google for transparency around censored content</og:title>
<og:description>If a company like Facebook can’t even understand why its moderation tools work the way they do, then its users certainly don’t have a fighting shot. Anyway, that’s the idea behind what a coalition of digital rights groups are calling The Santa Clara Principles (PDF), “a set …</og:description>
<og:image>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/fb-hate-speech-censor1.jpg?w=711</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2018/05/07/santa-clara-principles-eff-cdt-aclu-facebook-google-twitter/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2018/05/07/santa-clara-principles-eff-cdt-aclu-facebook-google-twitter/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Conversations with a six-year-old on functional programming</title>
<link>https://byorgey.wordpress.com/2018/05/06/conversations-with-a-six-year-old-on-functional-programming/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://byorgey.wordpress.com/2018/05/06/conversations-with-a-six-year-old-on-functional-programming/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;My six-year-old son walked up to me yesterday. “What are you reading?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the time, I was reading part of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.janis-voigtlaender.eu/papers/TypesForProgrammingAndReasoning.pdf&quot;&gt;Janis Voigtländer’s habilitation thesis&lt;/a&gt;. Unsure where to even start, I decided to just answer straightforwardly: “I’m reading a very long story about free theorems.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He persisted. “What are free theorems?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Never one to shrink from a pedagogical challenge, I thought for a moment, then began: “Do you know what a &lt;em&gt;function&lt;/em&gt; is?” He didn’t. “A function is like a machine where you put something in one end and something comes out the other end. For example, maybe you put a number in, and the number that is one bigger comes out. So if you put in three, four comes out, or if you put in six, seven comes out.” This clearly made sense to him, so I continued, “The &lt;em&gt;type&lt;/em&gt; of a function machine tells you what kinds of things you put in and what kinds of things come out. So maybe you put a number in and get a number out. Or maybe you put in a &lt;em&gt;list&lt;/em&gt; of numbers and get a number out.” He interrupted excitedly, “Or maybe you could put &lt;em&gt;words&lt;/em&gt; in??” “Yes, exactly! Maybe you can put words in and get words out. Or maybe there is a function machine where you put &lt;em&gt;other function machines&lt;/em&gt; in and get function machines out!” He gasped in astonishment at the idea of putting function machines into function machines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“So,” I concluded, “a free theorem is when you can say something that is always true about a function machine if you &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; know its type, but you &lt;em&gt;don’t&lt;/em&gt; know anything about what it does on the inside.” This seemed a bit beyond him (and to be fair, free theorems are only interesting when polymorphism is involved which I definitely didn’t want to go into). But the whole conversation had given me a different idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Hey, I have a good idea for a game,” I said. “It’s called the function machine game. I will think of a function machine. You tell me things to put into the function machine, and I will tell you what comes out. Then you have to guess what the function machine does.” He immediately liked this game and it has been a huge hit; he wants to play it all the time. We played it while driving to a party yesterday, and we played it this morning while I was in the shower. So far, he has correctly guessed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried &lt;img src=&quot;https://s0.wp.com/latex.php?latex=%5Clambda+x.%5C%2C+%5Cmin%28x%2B2%2C10%29&amp;amp;bg=ffffff&amp;amp;fg=333333&amp;amp;s=0&quot; alt=&quot;\lambda x.\, \min(x+2,10)&quot; title=&quot;\lambda x.\, \min(x+2,10)&quot; class=&quot;latex&quot;/&gt; but that was a bit tough for him. I realized that in some cases he may understand intuitively what the function does but have trouble expressing it in words (this was also a problem with &lt;img src=&quot;https://s0.wp.com/latex.php?latex=%5Clambda+x.%5C%2C+10+%5Clfloor+x%2F10+%5Crfloor&amp;amp;bg=ffffff&amp;amp;fg=333333&amp;amp;s=0&quot; alt=&quot;\lambda x.\, 10 \lfloor x/10 \rfloor&quot; title=&quot;\lambda x.\, 10 \lfloor x/10 \rfloor&quot; class=&quot;latex&quot;/&gt;), so we started using the obvious variant where once the guesser thinks they know what the function does, the players switch roles and the person who came up with function specifies some inputs in order to test whether the guesser is able to produce the correct outputs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s0.wp.com/latex.php?latex=%5Clambda+x.%5C%2C+6&amp;amp;bg=ffffff&amp;amp;fg=333333&amp;amp;s=0&quot; alt=&quot;\lambda x.\, 6&quot; title=&quot;\lambda x.\, 6&quot; class=&quot;latex&quot;/&gt; was also surprisingly difficult for him to guess (though he did get it right eventually). I think he was just stuck on the idea of the function doing something arithmetical to the input, and was having trouble coming up with some sort of arithmetic procedure which would result in &lt;img src=&quot;https://s0.wp.com/latex.php?latex=6&amp;amp;bg=ffffff&amp;amp;fg=333333&amp;amp;s=0&quot; alt=&quot;6&quot; title=&quot;6&quot; class=&quot;latex&quot;/&gt; no matter what you put in! It simply hadn’t occurred to him that the machine might &lt;em&gt;not care&lt;/em&gt; about the input. (Interestingly, many students in my functional programming class this semester were also confused by constant functions when we were learning about the lambda calculus; they really wanted to substitute the input &lt;em&gt;somewhere&lt;/em&gt; and were upset/confused by the fact that the bound variable did not occur in the body at all!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a few rounds of guessing my functions, he wanted to come up with his own functions for me to guess (as I knew he would). Sometimes his functions are great and sometimes they don’t make sense (usually because his idea of what the function does changes over time, which of course he, in all sincerity, denies), but it’s fun either way. And after he finally understood &lt;img src=&quot;https://s0.wp.com/latex.php?latex=%5Clambda+x.+%5Cmin%28x%2B2%2C+10%29&amp;amp;bg=ffffff&amp;amp;fg=333333&amp;amp;s=0&quot; alt=&quot;\lambda x. \min(x+2, 10)&quot; title=&quot;\lambda x. \min(x+2, 10)&quot; class=&quot;latex&quot;/&gt;, he came up with his own function which was something like&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s0.wp.com/latex.php?latex=%5Clambda+x%3A%5Cmathbb%7BN%7D.+%5Cbegin%7Bcases%7D+10+-+x+%26+x+%5Cleq+10+%5C%5C+10+%26+%5Ctext%7Botherwise%7D+%5Cend%7Bcases%7D&amp;amp;bg=ffffff&amp;amp;fg=333333&amp;amp;s=0&quot; alt=&quot;\lambda x:\mathbb{N}. \begin{cases} 10 - x &amp;amp; x \leq 10 \\ 10 &amp;amp; \text{otherwise} \end{cases}&quot; title=&quot;\lambda x:\mathbb{N}. \begin{cases} 10 - x &amp;amp; x \leq 10 \\ 10 &amp;amp; \text{otherwise} \end{cases}&quot; class=&quot;latex&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;inspired, I think, by his kindergarten class where they were learning about pairs of numbers that added up to &lt;img src=&quot;https://s0.wp.com/latex.php?latex=10&amp;amp;bg=ffffff&amp;amp;fg=333333&amp;amp;s=0&quot; alt=&quot;10&quot; title=&quot;10&quot; class=&quot;latex&quot;/&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Definitely one of my better parenting days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;wpcnt&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wpa wpmrec&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;wpa-about&quot;&gt;Advertisements&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;jp-post-flair&quot; class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-like-enabled sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;robots-nocontent sd-block sd-social sd-social-icon-text sd-sharing&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Share this:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 19:24:11 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>weatherlight</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Conversations with a six-year-old on functional programming</og:title>
<og:url>https://byorgey.wordpress.com/2018/05/06/conversations-with-a-six-year-old-on-functional-programming/</og:url>
<og:description>My six-year-old son walked up to me yesterday. “What are you reading?” At the time, I was reading part of Janis Voigtländer’s habilitation thesis. Unsure where to even start, I decided to just ans…</og:description>
<og:image>https://s0.wp.com/i/blank.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://byorgey.wordpress.com/2018/05/06/conversations-with-a-six-year-old-on-functional-programming/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Who controls glibc?</title>
<link>https://lwn.net/SubscriberLink/753646/a6ebb50040c5862c/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://lwn.net/SubscriberLink/753646/a6ebb50040c5862c/</guid>
<description>&lt;center&gt;
&lt;table width=&quot;90%&quot; cellspacing=&quot;5&quot; readability=&quot;4.1829745596869&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;11.154598825832&quot;&gt;&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Welcome to LWN.net&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following subscription-only content has been made available to you by an LWN subscriber. Thousands of subscribers depend on LWN for the best news from the Linux and free software communities. If you enjoy this article, please consider accepting the trial offer on the right. Thank you for visiting LWN.net!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;
&lt;table class=&quot;Form&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; readability=&quot;1.2016574585635&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.6049723756906&quot;&gt;&lt;td readability=&quot;4.8066298342541&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Free trial subscription&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Try LWN for free for 1 month: no payment or credit card required. &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/Promo/slink-trial2-2/claim&quot;&gt;Activate your trial subscription now&lt;/a&gt; and see why thousands of readers subscribe to LWN.net.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By &lt;strong&gt;Jonathan Corbet&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;May 7, 2018&lt;/p&gt;
The removal of an old joke from the GNU C Library manual might not seem like the sort of topic that would inspire a heated debate. At times, though, a small action can serve as an inadvertent proxy for a more significant question, one which is relevant to both the developers and the users of the project. In this case, that question would be: how is the project governed and who makes decisions about which patches are applied?
&lt;p&gt;Toward the end of April, Raymond Nicholson posted &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/Articles/753647/&quot;&gt;a patch to the glibc manual&lt;/a&gt; removing a joke that he didn't think was useful to readers. The joke played on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/libc/manual/html_node/Aborting-a-Program.html&quot;&gt;documentation for &lt;tt&gt;abort()&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to make a statement about US government policy on providing information about abortions. As Nicholson noted: &quot;&lt;span&gt;The joke does not provide any useful information about the abort() function so removing it will not hinder use of glibc&lt;/span&gt;&quot;. On April 30, Zack Weinberg &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/Articles/753649/&quot;&gt;applied the patch&lt;/a&gt; to the glibc repository.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Richard Stallman, who added the joke sometime in the 1990s, &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/Articles/753651/&quot;&gt;asked&lt;/a&gt; that it not be removed. The resulting discussion touched on a number of issues. Carlos O'Donell, who has been trying hard to resolve the issue with some degree of consensus, &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/Articles/753653/&quot;&gt;suggested&lt;/a&gt; that the joke could hurt people who have had bad experiences associated with abortion. He proposed a couple of possible alternatives, including avoiding jokes entirely or discussing such issues in a different forum. Stallman, however, &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/Articles/753654/&quot;&gt;replied&lt;/a&gt; that &quot;&lt;span&gt;a GNU manual, like a course in history, is not meant to be a 'safe space'&lt;/span&gt;&quot;. He suggested the possibility of adding a trigger warning about functions that create child processes, since childbirth is &quot;&lt;span&gt;far more traumatic than having an abortion&lt;/span&gt;&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether the joke belongs in the glibc manual is an issue for the glibc developers to decide and wouldn't normally be of much interest beyond the project itself. But in this case, it raises the question of how the developers make this decision. &lt;a href=&quot;https://sourceware.org/glibc/wiki/Consensus&quot;&gt;The project's wiki&lt;/a&gt; states that the project &quot;&lt;span&gt;uses a consensus-based community-driven development model&lt;/span&gt;&quot;. In this case, there seems to be a fairly clear consensus among the actual glibc developers that this joke is not appropriate in the project's manual. Weinberg's application of the patch was based on this consensus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stallman, however, has made it clear that there are limits to the extent to which glibc is consensus-based; his &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/Articles/753655/&quot;&gt;response&lt;/a&gt; was: &quot;&lt;span&gt;My decision is to keep the joke&lt;/span&gt;&quot;. Weinberg &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/Articles/753656/&quot;&gt;stated&lt;/a&gt; his refusal to revert the change; Stallman &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/Articles/753657/&quot;&gt;answered&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;&lt;span&gt;I stand by my decision to keep the joke&lt;/span&gt;&quot;. O'Donell &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/Articles/753658/&quot;&gt;apologized&lt;/a&gt; for not contacting Stallman directly about the removal, but also stood by the decision to remove it. He asked:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A large group of developers, serious senior developers, at least 3 project stewards (GNU Developers for the project), are indicating that they do not share your same view on the joke. Please consider their input and work with me to reach a consensus position.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Weinberg &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/Articles/753688/&quot;&gt;defended&lt;/a&gt; his application of the patch:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't think I did anything wrong procedurally. RMS may be the project leader, but he is not a glibc maintainer. His wishes regarding glibc are perhaps to be given _some_ more weight than those of any other individual, particularly when he is also the author of text under dispute, but we have never, to my knowledge, treated them as mandates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stallman was unimpressed, though, and fell back to a pure authority play, &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/Articles/753660/&quot;&gt;saying&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;&lt;span&gt;As the head of the GNU Project, I am in charge of what we publish in GNU manuals. I decide the criteria to decide by, too&lt;/span&gt;&quot;. He later &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/Articles/753661/&quot;&gt;added&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I exercise my authority over Glibc very rarely -- and when I have done so, I have talked with the official maintainers. So rarely that some of you thought that you are entirely autonomous. But that is not the case. On this particular question, I made a decision long ago and stated it where all of you could see it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O'Donell &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/Articles/753662/&quot;&gt;repeated&lt;/a&gt; that a discussion was underway and that the maintainers did not intend to revert the patch. He also asked whether the change violated any GNU policies — a question that went unanswered as of this writing. He also &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/Articles/753663/&quot;&gt;stated clearly&lt;/a&gt; that the joke would not return in any form until some sort of consensus was reached.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One could argue that the consensus is already there if one looks at the developers who actually work on glibc; it is difficult to find any of them arguing for the joke's return. The number of people arguing for the joke in general is quite small. That did not stop Alexandre Oliva, who evidently &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/Articles/753666/&quot;&gt;has a high opinion&lt;/a&gt; of Stallman's sense of humor, from &lt;a href=&quot;https://sourceware.org/git/?p=glibc.git;a=commitdiff;h=ffa81c22a3ac0fb75ad9bf2b1c3cdbf9eafa0bc9&quot;&gt;reverting&lt;/a&gt; the change early on May 7 — his first glibc change in 2018. He did not post his change to the mailing list (and only &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/Articles/753699/&quot;&gt;explained it&lt;/a&gt; after being asked); his attempt to justify it as a return to consensus &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/Articles/753700/&quot;&gt;did not fly&lt;/a&gt; with O'Donell. This discussion, one suspects, is not done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each project has its own governance model. The &quot;authoritarian leader&quot; model is quite common in this space, with many projects subject to the will of a (hopefully benevolent) dictator who can decide to accept or reject any change. Sometimes that model works better than others; glibc itself improved its processes and inclusiveness considerably when its single leader was replaced by a more consensus-oriented model. Usually, though, such leaders are at least active developers in the projects they manage; that is not the case for the GNU projects. It can be discouraging for a developer to discover that their changes are subject to a veto from on high by somebody who is not otherwise involved with the project's development. The echoes of this action may thus persist in the glibc community for some time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;br clear=&quot;all&quot; /&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;table class=&quot;Form&quot; readability=&quot;1.2534246575342&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.5068493150685&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Did you like this article?&lt;/strong&gt; Please accept our &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/Promo/slink-trial2-2/claim&quot;&gt;trial subscription offer&lt;/a&gt; to be able to see more content like it and to participate in the discussion.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr width=&quot;60%&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;
(&lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/login?target=/Articles/753646/&quot;&gt;Log in&lt;/a&gt; to post comments)</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 19:22:30 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>CJefferson</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://lwn.net/SubscriberLink/753646/a6ebb50040c5862c/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Cutting Edge Deep Learning for Coders, Part 2</title>
<link>http://course.fast.ai/part2.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://course.fast.ai/part2.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;item&quot; readability=&quot;13.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;I’ve tried (and if I’m honest) failed to scale the steep deep learning curve many times. I realise with hindsight it was the equations that were preventing me from becoming a deep learning practitioner. Jeremy brought me up to speed with the state-of-the-art, and within two weeks I was in the top half of the leaderboard for three Kaggle competitions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;author-avatar&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://course.fast.ai/images/people/chrisk.jpeg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;author-name&quot;&gt;- &lt;strong&gt;Christopher Kelly&lt;/strong&gt; , CEO- Nourish, Balance, Thrive&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;item&quot; readability=&quot;15&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;If you are looking to venture into the Deep learning field, look no further and take this course. It is very hands-on and adopts a top-down approach, which means everyone irrespective of varying knowledge can get started with implementing Deep learning models immediately. Another major factor why this course is very appealing is its emphasis on social relevance. That is, how can we use this awesome technology to serve the world better?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;author-avatar&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://course.fast.ai/images/people/sravya.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;author-name&quot;&gt;- &lt;strong&gt;Sravya Tirukkovalur&lt;/strong&gt; , Vice President, Apache Sentry&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;item&quot; readability=&quot;15&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;This course filled a gap I couldn't find anywhere else—there really is no other source where I could learn from a 'code first' perspective. This means you can prod, poke, and cajole these networks in different ways, and see how they respond. You can quickly feel an intuitive perspective growing as you explore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;author-avatar&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://course.fast.ai/images/people/mattob.jpeg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;author-name&quot;&gt;- &lt;strong&gt;Matt O'Brien&lt;/strong&gt; , Data Scientist, UCSF Neurology&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;item&quot; readability=&quot;13&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;I teach machine learning in a master’s degree program. After this course, I cannot ignore the new developments in deep learning—I will devote one third of my machine learning course to the subject. Also, I now have the tools to apply deep learning models to real world problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;author-avatar&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://course.fast.ai/images/people/yannet.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;author-name&quot;&gt;- &lt;strong&gt;Yannet Interian&lt;/strong&gt; , Assistant Professor of Analytics, University of San Francisco&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;item&quot; readability=&quot;11.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;It was very empowering to be able to start training a model within minutes downloading the Jupyter notebooks. Jeremy and Rachel were excellent instructors and the content was high quality and enlightening. It was very cool to be able to read blogposts about the latest Deep Learning research and actually be able to understand it. I was surprised to be able to match academic results from just 2 years ago with pretty simple architectures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;author-avatar&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://course.fast.ai/images/people/robink.jpeg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;author-name&quot;&gt;- &lt;strong&gt;Robin Kraft (@robinkraft)&lt;/strong&gt; , Product Manager at Planet Labs (Satellites)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;item&quot; readability=&quot;13.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;I'm a CEO, not a coder, so the idea that I'd be able to create a GPU deep learning server in the cloud meant learning a lot of new things—but with all the help on the wiki and from the instructors and community on the forum I did it! Jeremy is an incredible instructor and is able to make what might seem like a difficult subject completely accessible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;author-avatar&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://course.fast.ai/images/people/nichol.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;author-name&quot;&gt;- &lt;strong&gt;Nichol Bradford&lt;/strong&gt; , Executive Director of Transformative Tech Lab at Sofia University&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;item&quot; readability=&quot;13.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;Sometimes I feared whether I would be able to solve any deep learning problems, as all the research papers I read were very mathy beyond reach of simple intuitive terms. But Jeremy and Rachel (Course Professors) believe in the theory of 'Simple is Powerful', by virtue of which anyone who takes this course will be able to confidently understand the simple techniques behind the 'magic' Deep Learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;author-avatar&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://course.fast.ai/images/people/shetty.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;author-name&quot;&gt;- &lt;strong&gt;Janardhan Shetty&lt;/strong&gt; , Senior Big Data Engineer at Salesforce&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;item&quot; readability=&quot;14.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;Running a company is extremely time intensive, so I was a weary of taking on the commitment of the course. It was definitely worth it, though. It smashed my preconceptions about the technological obstructions to doing deep learning, and showed again and again examples where just a small subset of the training data and just a few epochs of training on standard GPU hardware could get most of the way towards a really good model&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;author-avatar&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://course.fast.ai/images/people/dario.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;author-name&quot;&gt;- &lt;strong&gt;Dario Fanucchi&lt;/strong&gt; , Co-founder and CTO at Isazi Consulting&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;item&quot; readability=&quot;13.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;It can take years to develop the necessary skills and knowledge for Deep Learning, especially without the support of mentors and peers. Not only did Jeremy teach us the most valuable methods and practices, he provided us with an invaluable community and environment. The course exceeded my expectations and showed me first hand how both Deep Learning and ourselves could change the world for better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;author-avatar&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://course.fast.ai/images/people/taro.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;author-name&quot;&gt;- &lt;strong&gt;Taro-Shigenori Chiba&lt;/strong&gt; , Organizer of the SF Deep Learning Study Group&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 19:15:16 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mlboss</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://course.fast.ai/part2.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>