<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Magic Leap One Unveiled</title>
<link>https://www.magicleap.com/?utm_source=reveal&amp;utm_medium=TW&amp;utm_campaign=WTDO</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.magicleap.com/?utm_source=reveal&amp;utm_medium=TW&amp;utm_campaign=WTDO</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;AttributesContent__TextEl-s1v7p212-2 iiWdod&quot; readability=&quot;36&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;H1-s1crb85x-0-h2 kwEeQg&quot; spacing=&quot;none small&quot;&gt;Digital Lightfield&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;AttributesContent__StyledText-s1v7p212-3 iGNOOF base__StyledText-s18jarbn-0 fzeabY&quot; spacing=&quot;none&quot;&gt;Our lightfield photonics generate digital light at different depths and blend seamlessly with natural light to produce lifelike digital objects that coexist in the real world. This advanced technology allows our brain to naturally process digital objects the same way we do real-world objects, making it comfortable to use for long periods of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;AttributesContent__TextEl-s1v7p212-2 dOObLD&quot; readability=&quot;39&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;H1-s1crb85x-0-h2 kwEeQg&quot; spacing=&quot;none small&quot;&gt;Visual Perception&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;AttributesContent__StyledText-s1v7p212-3 iGNOOF base__StyledText-s18jarbn-0 fzeabY&quot; spacing=&quot;none&quot;&gt;The robust sensor suite on Magic Leap One detects surfaces, planes and objects, allowing for digital reconstruction of your physical surroundings. The result is a system that sees what you see, allowing lightfield objects to not only exist in the physical world but actually interact with it. Whether it’s virtual displays sitting alongside the computer monitor on your desk or a virtual panda that climbs across your living room couch, visual perception with machine learning unlocks the power of spatial computing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;AttributesContent__TextEl-s1v7p212-2 dOObLD&quot; readability=&quot;38&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;H1-s1crb85x-0-h2 kwEeQg&quot; spacing=&quot;none small&quot;&gt;Persistent Objects&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;AttributesContent__StyledText-s1v7p212-3 iGNOOF base__StyledText-s18jarbn-0 fzeabY&quot; spacing=&quot;none&quot;&gt;Our visual perception and room-mapping technology builds a digital replica of your physical environment – detecting and storing the precise location of walls, surfaces and other physical objects. Lightfield objects stay where you put them, just as they would in real life. Place a virtual TV on the wall over your fireplace and when you return later, the TV will be right where you &lt;span class=&quot;AttributesContent__StickySpace-s1v7p212-4 gIHnok&quot;&gt;left it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;AttributesContent__TextEl-s1v7p212-2 dOObLD&quot; readability=&quot;36&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;H1-s1crb85x-0-h2 kwEeQg&quot; spacing=&quot;none small&quot;&gt;Soundfield Audio&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;AttributesContent__StyledText-s1v7p212-3 iGNOOF base__StyledText-s18jarbn-0 fzeabY&quot; spacing=&quot;none&quot;&gt;To feel real, it must sound real. Our soundfield audio mimics the real world and relays distance and intensity with amazing quality. This allows you to hear exactly where a sound is coming from, meaning you’ll know how close a virtual T-Rex is as it stomps up &lt;span class=&quot;AttributesContent__StickySpace-s1v7p212-4 gIHnok&quot;&gt;behind you.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;AttributesContent__TextEl-s1v7p212-2 dOObLD&quot; readability=&quot;40&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;H1-s1crb85x-0-h2 kwEeQg&quot; spacing=&quot;none small&quot;&gt;High-Powered Chipset&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;AttributesContent__StyledText-s1v7p212-3 iGNOOF base__StyledText-s18jarbn-0 fzeabY&quot; spacing=&quot;none&quot;&gt;Our integrated processing unit delivers high-fidelity, gaming-quality graphics, with the power and performance of a laptop computer. From editing an elaborate 3D model to playing a first-person shooter in your living room, Magic Leap One produces lightfield objects in intricate detail, all on a highly responsive, self-contained wearable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;AttributesContent__TextEl-s1v7p212-2 dOObLD&quot; readability=&quot;39&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;H1-s1crb85x-0-h2 kwEeQg&quot; spacing=&quot;none small&quot;&gt;Next Generation Interface&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;AttributesContent__StyledText-s1v7p212-3 iGNOOF base__StyledText-s18jarbn-0 fzeabY&quot; spacing=&quot;none&quot;&gt;We live and think in a 3D world, not on a flat screen. Our spatial interface includes multiple input modes including voice, gesture, head pose and eye tracking. This collective input system provides the tools needed to break free from outdated conventions of point and click interfaces, delivering a more natural and intuitive way to interact with technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 14:02:33 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>runesoerensen</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.magicleap.com/</og:url>
<og:title>Welcome</og:title>
<og:image>https://www.magicleap.com/static/icons/magicleap-og.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.magicleap.com/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Uber is officially a cab firm, says European court</title>
<link>http://www.bbc.com/news/business-42423627</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.bbc.com/news/business-42423627</guid>
<description>&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape no-caption full-width lead&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                &lt;img class=&quot;js-image-replace&quot; alt=&quot;Uber app on a smartphone in front of a car&quot; src=&quot;https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/320/cpsprodpb/140DB/production/_99293128_ubergetty.jpg&quot; width=&quot;976&quot; height=&quot;549&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image copyright&lt;/span&gt;
                 &lt;span class=&quot;story-image-copyright&quot;&gt;Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
        &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;story-body__introduction&quot;&gt;Uber is officially a transport company and not a digital service, the European Court of Justice (ECJ) has ruled.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The ride-hailing firm argued it was an information society service - helping people to make contact with each other electronically - and not a cab firm.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The case arose after Uber was told to obey local taxi rules in Barcelona.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Uber said the verdict would make little difference to the way it operated in Europe, but experts say the case could have implications for the gig economy.  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;An Uber spokesperson said: &quot;This ruling will not change things in most EU countries where we already operate under transportation law. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;However, millions of Europeans are still prevented from using apps like ours. As our new CEO has said, it is appropriate to regulate services such as Uber and so we will continue the dialogue with cities across Europe. This is the approach we'll take to ensure everyone can get a reliable ride at the tap of a button.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In its ruling, the ECJ said that a service whose purpose was &quot;to connect, by means of a smartphone application and for remuneration, non-professional drivers using their own vehicle with persons who wish to make urban journeys&quot; must be classified as &quot;a service in the field of transport&quot; in EU law.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It added: &quot;As EU law currently stands, it is for the member states to regulate the conditions under which such services are to be provided in conformity with the general rules of the treaty on the functioning of the EU.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape no-caption body-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
        &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;story-body__crosshead&quot;&gt;Analysis: Theo Leggett, BBC business correspondent&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape no-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
                 &lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image copyright&lt;/span&gt;
                 &lt;span class=&quot;story-image-copyright&quot;&gt;EPA&lt;/span&gt;
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
        &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;This ruling is another example of how the courts and regulators are struggling to make sense of the phenomenon known as the gig economy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since Uber was first launched less than a decade ago, it has repeatedly fallen foul of regulators in different countries - and has frequently been forced to change its business model as a result.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This ruling sets out clearly that Uber is, in legal terms at least, a transport company. Uber itself insists that there won't be a huge immediate impact on its business, but it could still affect how it operates in future and how it liaises with national governments. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Uber itself has previously said this will undermine the reform of what it calls outdated laws.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On a wider basis, it could have implications for other gig economy businesses that try to portray themselves as little more than an app on a phone, connecting providers with customers; it appears the courts, so far, are taking a different view.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That could ultimately have an impact, not just on ride-hailing services, but on other gig economy services - such as couriers and accommodation providers - who operate a similar model.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape no-caption body-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
        &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;TUC general secretary Frances O'Grady said the verdict meant Uber must &quot;play by the same rules as everybody else&quot;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She added: &quot;Their drivers are not commodities. They deserve at the very least the minimum wage and holiday pay.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Advances in technology should be used to make work better, not to return to the type of working practices we thought we'd seen the back of decades ago.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The verdict comes after Uber was told last month that &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-england-london-42012719&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link&quot;&gt;the appeal to renew its licence in London could take years,&lt;/a&gt; according to Mayor Sadiq Khan.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;story-body__crosshead&quot;&gt;Benefits&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Uber's presence around the world has often been controversial, with protests staged against it in various cities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, Rohan Silva, a tech entrepreneur and former adviser to David Cameron, says the firm has made competitors up their game.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Millions of people use these ride-hailing apps every day - not just Uber, but dozens of others too. They have brought real benefits, making it cheaper, easier and more convenient to get around the city,&quot; he told &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/b006qj9z&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link&quot;&gt;Radio 4's Today programme.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;There has also been a benefit in incumbent London taxi cabs, which are now taking credit cards, which they resisted for years. That is a response to competition.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He added that similar services could soon face regulation as a result of the ECJ ruling.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;There could be big implications for a sharing economy service like Airbnb, which will probably be regulated by the EU,&quot; he said. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;What is fascinating about this right now is that different countries are taking very different views. Portugal has legalised Uber and Airbnb, whereas France is clamping down.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Prof Andre Spicer, from the Cass Business School, welcomed the ruling. He told Today: &quot;Many people see the EU is actually leading the way in pushing back the almost unlimited power of tech firms and beginning to provide some limits around that.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;We also claim this fosters competition, but what Uber's model is based on is pricing, so much that they basically drove everyone else out of the market.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;This judgement will allow normal competition, so what we will see is lots of other smaller apps appearing around Europe.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
    </description>
<pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 08:51:45 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>chrisper</dc:creator>
<og:title>Uber is officially a cab firm, says court</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>The ride-hailing firm had argued that it was an information society service.</og:description>
<og:url>http://www.bbc.com/news/business-42423627</og:url>
<og:image>https://ichef-1.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/cpsprodpb/140DB/production/_99293128_ubergetty.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.bbc.com/news/business-42423627</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Buy, sell, send and receive Bitcoin Cash on Coinbase</title>
<link>https://blog.coinbase.com/buy-sell-send-and-receive-bitcoin-cash-on-coinbase-65f1b2c7214b</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.coinbase.com/buy-sell-send-and-receive-bitcoin-cash-on-coinbase-65f1b2c7214b</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;section-inner sectionLayout--insetColumn&quot; readability=&quot;52.600941176471&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*icfZmzq9EV_eGw-fDRnb8w.png&quot; data-width=&quot;1600&quot; data-height=&quot;617&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*icfZmzq9EV_eGw-fDRnb8w.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*icfZmzq9EV_eGw-fDRnb8w.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;aa2c&quot; id=&quot;aa2c&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;We’re excited to announce that customers will be able to buy, sell, send and receive Bitcoin Cash on Coinbase. You can read more about Bitcoin Cash on our FAQ page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;1b39&quot; id=&quot;1b39&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;Sends and receives are available immediately.&lt;/strong&gt; Buys and sells will be available to all customers once there is sufficient liquidity on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gdax.com/&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.gdax.com/&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;GDAX&lt;/a&gt;. We anticipate that this will take a few hours. S&lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;ee our update below.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 name=&quot;d19b&quot; id=&quot;d19b&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Our customers should benefit from forks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;a88a&quot; id=&quot;a88a&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;Coinbase operates by the principle that our customers should benefit to the greatest extent possible from forks or other networks events. This is essential in our mission to make Coinbase the most trusted, safe, and easy-to-use digital currency exchange.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;7237&quot; id=&quot;7237&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Bitcoin Cash was created by a fork on August 1st, 2017. All customers who held a Bitcoin balance on Coinbase at the time of the fork will now see an equal balance of Bitcoin Cash available in their Coinbase account. Your Bitcoin Cash balance will reflect your Bitcoin balance at the time of the Bitcoin Cash Fork, which occurred at 13:20 UTC, August 1, 2017. You can read more about what a bitcoin fork is &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.coinbase.com/what-is-a-bitcoin-fork-cba07fe73ef1&quot; data-href=&quot;https://blog.coinbase.com/what-is-a-bitcoin-fork-cba07fe73ef1&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and our previous update on Bitcoin Cash &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.coinbase.com/update-on-bitcoin-cash-8a67a7e8dbdf&quot; data-href=&quot;https://blog.coinbase.com/update-on-bitcoin-cash-8a67a7e8dbdf&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;01cf&quot; id=&quot;01cf&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;We have been monitoring the Bitcoin Cash network over the last few months and have decided to enable full support including the ability to buy, sell, send and receive. Factors we considered include developer and community support, security, stability, market price and trading volume. You can learn more about Bitcoin Cash &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bitcoincash.org/&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.bitcoincash.org/&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noopener noopener noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;f909&quot; id=&quot;f909&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;We will abbreviate Bitcoin Cash as BCH on our platform. Customers will be able to buy Bitcoin Cash using all of our supported fiat currencies: USD, EUR, GBP, CAD, AUD and SGD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;f149&quot; id=&quot;f149&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;Coinbase maintains a strict trading policy and internal guidelines for employees. Coinbase employees have been prohibited from trading in Bitcoin Cash for several weeks.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 name=&quot;970f&quot; id=&quot;970f&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Update on December 19 at 8:15pm&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;7273&quot; id=&quot;7273&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3 graf--trailing&quot;&gt;Bitcoin Cash sends and receives are functional. Buys and sells on the Coinbase website and in our mobile apps will be available to all customers once there is sufficient liquidity on GDAX. We anticipate that this will happen tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 00:17:23 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>wlj</dc:creator>
<og:title>Buy, sell, send and receive Bitcoin Cash on Coinbase</og:title>
<og:url>https://blog.coinbase.com/buy-sell-send-and-receive-bitcoin-cash-on-coinbase-65f1b2c7214b</og:url>
<og:image>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*icfZmzq9EV_eGw-fDRnb8w.png</og:image>
<og:description>We’re excited to announce that customers will be able to buy, sell, send and receive Bitcoin Cash on Coinbase. You can read more about…</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.coinbase.com/buy-sell-send-and-receive-bitcoin-cash-on-coinbase-65f1b2c7214b?gi=66f4e44ff67b</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Google Maps&amp;#039; Moat</title>
<link>https://www.justinobeirne.com/google-maps-moat</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.justinobeirne.com/google-maps-moat</guid>
<description>&lt;p data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot; id=&quot;note4&quot;&gt;&lt;strong data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot;&gt;4&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;em data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot;&gt;“Google has said surprisingly little about how it’s making AOIs...”&lt;/em&gt; Google’s secretiveness in how it’s making AOIs has been somewhat to its detriment, as &lt;a data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;http://www.slate.com/blogs/future_tense/2016/07/27/google_maps_new_redesign_doesn_t_hide_its_biases.html&quot;&gt;bloggers&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.citylab.com/design/2016/08/google-maps-areas-of-interest/493670/&quot;&gt;journalists&lt;/a&gt; have drawn their own (sometimes unflattering) conclusions. &lt;a data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.justinobeirne.com/google-maps-moat#back-note4&quot;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot; id=&quot;note5&quot;&gt;&lt;strong data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot;&gt;5&lt;/strong&gt;  AOIs also say a lot about Google’s confidence in the accuracy of its place data and its ability to keep AOIs up-to-date. (I.e., Google feels its place data is accurate enough to build new features off of it.) &lt;a data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.justinobeirne.com/google-maps-moat#back-note5&quot;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot; id=&quot;note6&quot;&gt;&lt;strong data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot;&gt;6&lt;/strong&gt;  This whole “byproduct” thing reminds of Kingsford Charcoal’s &lt;a data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kingsford_%28charcoal%29#History&quot;&gt;origin story&lt;/a&gt;. From &lt;em data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot;&gt;Rework&lt;/em&gt; by Jason Fried and David Heinemeier Hansson:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot;&gt;Henry Ford learned of a process for turning wood scraps from the production of Model T’s into charcoal briquets. He built a charcoal plant and Ford Charcoal was created (later renamed Kingsford Charcoal). Today, Kingsford is still the leading manufacturer of charcoal in America.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot;&gt;It’s cool to see how cleverly Google is using its own byproducts. &lt;a data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.justinobeirne.com/google-maps-moat#back-note6&quot;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot; id=&quot;note7&quot;&gt;&lt;strong data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot;&gt;7&lt;/strong&gt;  There’s a small number of buildings, such as Apple’s Cupertino campuses, that Apple is making itself. But these buildings are handmade by &lt;a data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;http://ecady.com&quot;&gt;artists&lt;/a&gt; rather than by algorithms. &lt;a data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.justinobeirne.com/google-maps-moat#back-note7&quot;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot; id=&quot;note8&quot;&gt;&lt;strong data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot;&gt;8&lt;/strong&gt;  Given how many Apple employees live in and around San Francisco, you’d expect that San Francisco would be one of the first places where Apple would be extracting place data from imagery. (I.e., San Francisco would seem to be the perfect &lt;strong data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot;&gt;test ground&lt;/strong&gt;, given its high density of businesses and year-round good weather, minus &lt;a data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/KarlTheFog&quot;&gt;Karl&lt;/a&gt;.) &lt;a data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.justinobeirne.com/google-maps-moat#back-note8&quot;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot; id=&quot;note9&quot;&gt;&lt;strong data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot;&gt;9&lt;/strong&gt;  It’s interesting to ponder what this means for Google’s competitors. It’s no longer enough to simply collect data. Now to compete with Google, you also have to process that data and make new features out of it. Hence, the “moat”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot;&gt;It’s also interesting to ponder what this means for OpenStreetMap. &lt;a data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.justinobeirne.com/google-maps-moat#back-note9-10-11&quot;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot; id=&quot;note10&quot;&gt;&lt;strong data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot;&gt;10&lt;/strong&gt;  Another advantage of Google collecting its own data is that &lt;strong data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot;&gt;it owns everything it collects&lt;/strong&gt;. And because of this, it can do things with its data that Apple might be restricted from doing (because Apple seems to license most of its data from &lt;a data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://gspe21-ssl.ls.apple.com/html/attribution-94.html&quot;&gt;third-parties&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot;&gt;(Often in map licensing agreements, if you stop licensing the data, you lose the right to anything that was derived from it.) &lt;a data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.justinobeirne.com/google-maps-moat#back-note9-10-11&quot;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot; id=&quot;note11&quot;&gt;&lt;strong data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot;&gt;11&lt;/strong&gt;  Assuming Google’s efforts don’t slow (and they show &lt;a data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/viticci/status/930899943266639873&quot;&gt;no sign of slowing&lt;/a&gt;), is it even possible for Apple to catch up to Google?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot;&gt;Google’s lead in data is reminiscent of Apple’s lead in smartphones in 2007. &lt;a data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.justinobeirne.com/google-maps-moat#back-note9-10-11&quot;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 23:51:17 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>rafaelc</dc:creator>
<og:title>Google Maps’s Moat</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.justinobeirne.com/google-maps-moat/</og:url>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:description>How far ahead of Apple Maps is Google Maps?</og:description>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.justinobeirne.com/google-maps-moat</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>iPhone Performance Degrades as Battery Ages</title>
<link>https://www.geekbench.com/blog/2017/12/iphone-performance-and-battery-age/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.geekbench.com/blog/2017/12/iphone-performance-and-battery-age/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/iphone/comments/7inu45/psa_iphone_slow_try_replacing_your_battery/&quot;&gt;Reddit post&lt;/a&gt; from last week has sparked a discussion regarding iPhone performance as a function of battery age. While we expect battery capacity to decrease as batteries age, we expect processor performance to stay the same. However, users with older iPhones with lower-than-expected Geekbench 4 scores have reported that replacing the battery increases their score (as well as the performance of the phone). What’s going on here? How many phones are experiencing decreased Geekbench 4 score?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To answer these questions I’ve plotted the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kernel_density_estimation&quot;&gt;kernel density&lt;/a&gt; of Geekbench 4 single-core scores for the iPhone 6s and the iPhone 7 running different versions of iOS. Scores obtained in low-power mode are not included in the distribution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;iphone-6s&quot;&gt;iPhone 6s&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the charts for the iPhone 6s:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.geekbench.com/img/blog/2017/iPhone%206s%20-%2010.2.0.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.geekbench.com/img/blog/2017/iPhone%206s%20-%2010.2.0.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.geekbench.com/img/blog/2017/iPhone%206s%20-%2010.2.1.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.geekbench.com/img/blog/2017/iPhone%206s%20-%2010.2.1.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.geekbench.com/img/blog/2017/iPhone%206s%20-%2011.2.0.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.geekbench.com/img/blog/2017/iPhone%206s%20-%2011.2.0.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The distribution of iPhone 6s scores for iOS 10.2.0 appears unimodal with a peak around the average score. However, the distribution of iPhone 6s scores for iOS 10.2.1 appears multimodal, with one large peak around the average and several smaller peaks around lower scores. Under iOS 11.2.0 the effect is even more pronounced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;iphone-7&quot;&gt;iPhone 7&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the charts for the iPhone 7:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.geekbench.com/img/blog/2017/iPhone%207%20-%2010.2.0.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.geekbench.com/img/blog/2017/iPhone%207%20-%2010.2.0.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.geekbench.com/img/blog/2017/iPhone%207%20-%2010.2.1.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.geekbench.com/img/blog/2017/iPhone%207%20-%2010.2.1.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.geekbench.com/img/blog/2017/iPhone%207%20-%2011.1.2.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.geekbench.com/img/blog/2017/iPhone%207%20-%2011.1.2.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.geekbench.com/img/blog/2017/iPhone%207%20-%2011.2.0.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.geekbench.com/img/blog/2017/iPhone%207%20-%2011.2.0.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The distribution of iPhone 7 scores under iOS 10.2.0, iOS 10.2.1, and iOS 11.1.2 appears identical. However, the distribution changes with iOS 11.2.0 and starts to look like the iPhone 6s distribution from 10.2.1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;performance-and-battery-age&quot;&gt;Performance and Battery Age&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what’s going on here?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, it appears the problem is widespread, and will only get worse as phones (and their batteries) continue to age. See, for example, the difference between the distribution of iPhone 6s scores between 10.2.1 and 11.2.0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, the problem is due, in part, to a change in iOS. The difference between 10.2.0 and 10.2.1 is too abrupt to be just a function of battery condition. I believe (as do others) that Apple introduced a change to limit performance when battery condition decreases past a certain point. Why did Apple do this? &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/user/kadupse&quot;&gt;kadupse&lt;/a&gt; on Reddit offers the following explanation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many iPhone 6s devices were shutting down unexpectedly, even after the battery replacement program (Which many people weren’t entitled to use). Because degraded batteries last much less and end up with a lower voltage Apple’s solution was to scale down CPU performance, it doesn’t solve anything and is a bad experience… but it’s better than having your device shutdown at 40% when you need it the most.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple acknowledged the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zdnet.com/article/iphone-6-6s-sudden-shutdown-weve-almost-fully-cured-issue-with-ios-10-2-1-says-apple/&quot;&gt;sudden shutdown&lt;/a&gt; issue that affected the iPhone 6 and iPhone 6s earlier this year. However, does the same issue affect the iPhone 7? Apple appears to have added a similar change to iOS 11.2.0 for the iPhone 7.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the performance drop is due to the “sudden shutdown” fix, users will experience reduced performance without notification. Users expect either full performance, or reduced performance with a notification that their phone is in low-power mode. This fix creates a third, unexpected state. While this state is created to mask a deficiency in battery power, users may believe that the slow down is due to CPU performance, instead of battery performance, which is triggering an Apple introduced CPU slow-down. This fix will also cause users to think, “my phone is slow so I should replace it” not, “my phone is slow so I should replace its battery”. This will likely feed into the “planned obsolecense” narritive.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 22:41:41 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Deinos</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.geekbench.com/blog/2017/12/iphone-performance-and-battery-age/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>120M American Households Exposed In &amp;#039;Massive&amp;#039; ConsumerView Database Leak</title>
<link>https://www.forbes.com/sites/thomasbrewster/2017/12/19/120m-american-households-exposed-in-massive-consumerview-database-leak/#412ed5e37961</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.forbes.com/sites/thomasbrewster/2017/12/19/120m-american-households-exposed-in-massive-consumerview-database-leak/#412ed5e37961</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/thomasbrewster/2017/12/19/120m-american-households-exposed-in-massive-consumerview-database-leak/#412ed5e37961&quot;&gt;https://www.forbes.com/sites/thomasbrewster/2017/12/19/120m-american-households-exposed-in-massive-consumerview-database-leak/#412ed5e37961&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=15965060&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=15965060&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Points: 420&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 139&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 22:33:39 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>wglb</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.forbes.com/forbes/welcome/?toURL=https://www.forbes.com/sites/thomasbrewster/2017/12/19/120m-american-households-exposed-in-massive-consumerview-database-leak/&amp;refURL=http://www.google.co.uk/url?sa=t&amp;source=web&amp;cd=1&amp;referrer=http://www.google.co.uk/url?sa=t&amp;source=web&amp;cd=1</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>How the Winklevoss Twins Found Vindication in a Bitcoin Fortune</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2017/12/19/technology/bitcoin-winklevoss-twins.html?hp&amp;action=click&amp;pgtype=Homepage&amp;clickSource=story-heading&amp;module=second-column-region&amp;region=top-news&amp;WT.nav=top-news&amp;_r=0</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2017/12/19/technology/bitcoin-winklevoss-twins.html?hp&amp;action=click&amp;pgtype=Homepage&amp;clickSource=story-heading&amp;module=second-column-region&amp;region=top-news&amp;WT.nav=top-news&amp;_r=0</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;255&quot; data-total-count=&quot;3954&quot; id=&quot;story-continues-7&quot;&gt;Over a few months, the brothers bought 1 percent of all the outstanding Bitcoin at the time — some 120,000 tokens. As they did, the price soared, making their Bitcoin portfolio worth around $11 million by the time they went public with it in April 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;273&quot; data-total-count=&quot;4227&quot;&gt;Their buying spree was mocked at the time, and a few of their early decisions fueled that derision. They also invested in Bitinstant, one of the first companies to trade Bitcoins online. Bitinstant’s executives, in fact, had tutored the brothers in the basics of Bitcoin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;325&quot; data-total-count=&quot;4552&quot;&gt;The chief executive of Bitinstant, Charlie Shrem, was arrested in 2014, accused of helping to supply Bitcoins to users of online drug markets. Mr. Shrem pleaded guilty to lesser charges and was sentenced to a year in jail. The Winklevosses were never implicated in the wrongdoing, which happened before they became investors.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;348&quot; data-total-count=&quot;4900&quot;&gt;While that drama was unfolding, the twins applied to create the first Bitcoin exchange traded fund, or E.T.F., an investment product that would hold Bitcoins but be traded on stock exchanges. That brought more criticism from people who wondered why someone would buy a fund rather than Bitcoin itself. In March, regulators &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/03/10/business/dealbook/winkelvoss-brothers-bid-to-create-a-bitcoin-etf-is-rejected.html&quot;&gt;rejected the application&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;249&quot; data-total-count=&quot;5149&quot;&gt;On top of all that, until last year the price of Bitcoin was sliding and the virtual currency concept was looking wobbly. But the Winklevosses, who once bet that years of punishing rowing practices would take them to the Olympics, held their ground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;225&quot; data-total-count=&quot;5374&quot;&gt;“We are very comfortable in very high-risk environments with absolutely no guarantee of success,” Tyler Winklevoss said. “I don’t mean existing in that environment for days, weeks or months. I mean year after year.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;story-ad-3&quot; class=&quot;story-ad ad ad-placeholder nocontent robots-nocontent&quot;&gt;

&lt;a class=&quot;visually-hidden skip-to-text-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/12/19/technology/bitcoin-winklevoss-twins.html?hp&amp;amp;action=click&amp;amp;pgtype=Homepage&amp;amp;clickSource=story-heading&amp;amp;module=second-column-region&amp;amp;region=top-news&amp;amp;WT.nav=top-news&amp;amp;_r=0#story-continues-8&quot;&gt;Continue reading the main story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;226&quot; data-total-count=&quot;5600&quot; id=&quot;story-continues-8&quot;&gt;They sold &lt;a href=&quot;https://dealbook.nytimes.com/2015/01/22/winklevoss-twins-aim-to-take-bitcoin-mainstream-with-a-regulated-exchange/&quot;&gt;some of their tokens to pay for Gemini&lt;/a&gt;, a name that means twins in Latin. Like the Bitcoin E.T.F., their investment in Gemini was driven by their experience with the difficulty of buying and securely storing Bitcoin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;436&quot; data-total-count=&quot;6036&quot;&gt;Every Bitcoin sits in an address that can be accessed only with the corresponding password, or private key. The problem with this system is that anyone who gets hold of a private key can easily take the Bitcoin. And unlike money taken from a bank account, stolen Bitcoin are essentially impossible to retrieve. A number of virtual currency exchanges and wallets have collectively lost billions of dollars’ worth of Bitcoin to thieves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;visually-hidden&quot;&gt;Photo&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2017/12/20/business/20winklevossJMP-2/00winklevoss3-master1050.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;media-viewer-candidate&quot; data-mediaviewer-src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2017/12/20/business/20winklevossJMP-2/00winklevoss3-superJumbo.jpg&quot; data-mediaviewer-caption=&quot;The Winklevoss brothers recorded parts of the security code for their Bitcoin on papers stored in safe deposit boxes around the country.&quot; data-mediaviewer-credit=&quot;Vincent Tullo for The New York Times&quot; itemprop=&quot;url&quot; itemid=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2017/12/20/business/20winklevossJMP-2/00winklevoss3-master1050.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption-text&quot;&gt;The Winklevoss brothers recorded parts of the security code for their Bitcoin on papers stored in safe deposit boxes around the country.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;visually-hidden&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt; Vincent Tullo for The New York Times&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;302&quot; data-total-count=&quot;6338&quot;&gt;The Winklevosses came up with an elaborate system to store and secure their own private keys. They cut up printouts of their private keys into pieces and then distributed them in envelopes to safe deposit boxes around the country, so if one envelope were stolen the thief would not have the entire key.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;234&quot; data-total-count=&quot;6572&quot;&gt;With Gemini, they have created a high-tech version of this process to hold customer money. Getting into the company’s wallets requires multiple signatures from cryptographically sealed devices that were never linked to the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;288&quot; data-total-count=&quot;6860&quot;&gt;Gemini got a license from New York State regulators that allows them to hold Bitcoins for regulated banks and asset managers — something essentially no other virtual currency companies can do. That has turned Gemini into one of the most trusted destinations for sophisticated investors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;183&quot; data-total-count=&quot;7043&quot;&gt;“Gemini is an underappreciated exchange, one of the few exchanges I trust as a custodian,” said Ari Paul, a managing partner at the virtual currency hedge fund BlockTower Capital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;122&quot; data-total-count=&quot;7165&quot;&gt;Gemini is now expanding from its old 5,000-square-foot offices to new, 35,000-square-foot facilities in Midtown Manhattan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;188&quot; data-total-count=&quot;7353&quot;&gt;This doesn’t mean Gemini or the Winklevosses have ironed out all the kinks. Like many other exchanges, Gemini has struggled to stay online in the deluge of new customers in recent weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;story-ad-4&quot; class=&quot;story-ad ad ad-placeholder nocontent robots-nocontent&quot;&gt;

&lt;a class=&quot;visually-hidden skip-to-text-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/12/19/technology/bitcoin-winklevoss-twins.html?hp&amp;amp;action=click&amp;amp;pgtype=Homepage&amp;amp;clickSource=story-heading&amp;amp;module=second-column-region&amp;amp;region=top-news&amp;amp;WT.nav=top-news&amp;amp;_r=0#story-continues-9&quot;&gt;Continue reading the main story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;181&quot; data-total-count=&quot;7534&quot; id=&quot;story-continues-9&quot;&gt;These growing pains are part of the reason the brothers say they are holding on to their Bitcoin. They believe virtual currencies are still a long way from real mainstream adoption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;424&quot; data-total-count=&quot;7958&quot;&gt;They said they might look at selling when the value of all the Bitcoin in circulation approaches the value of all gold in the world — some $7 trillion or $8 trillion compared with the $310 billion value of all Bitcoin on Tuesday — given that they think Bitcoin is set to replace gold as a rare commodity. But then Tyler Winklevoss questioned even that, pointing out the ways that he believes Bitcoin is better than gold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;172&quot; data-total-count=&quot;8130&quot;&gt;“In a funny way, I’m not sure we’d even sell there,” he said. “Bitcoin is more than gold — it’s a programmable store of money. It may continue to innovate.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;visually-hidden skip-to-text-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/12/19/technology/bitcoin-winklevoss-twins.html?hp&amp;amp;action=click&amp;amp;pgtype=Homepage&amp;amp;clickSource=story-heading&amp;amp;module=second-column-region&amp;amp;region=top-news&amp;amp;WT.nav=top-news&amp;amp;_r=0#whats-next&quot;&gt;Continue reading the main story&lt;/a&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 20:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>rafaelc</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2017/12/19/technology/bitcoin-winklevoss-twins.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>How the Winklevoss Twins Found Vindication in a Bitcoin Fortune</og:title>
<og:description>The virtual currency stockpile that Cameron and Tyler Winklevoss began amassing in 2012 is now worth around $1.65 billion. They have no plans to sell.</og:description>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2017/12/16/business/00winklevoss1/00winklevoss1-facebookJumbo.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2017/12/19/technology/bitcoin-winklevoss-twins.html?hp&amp;action=click&amp;pgtype=Homepage&amp;clickSource=story-heading&amp;module=second-column-region&amp;region=top-news&amp;WT.nav=top-news&amp;_r=0</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Firefox 57 delays requests to tracking domains</title>
<link>https://www.janbambas.cz/firefox-57-delays-requests-tracking-domains/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.janbambas.cz/firefox-57-delays-requests-tracking-domains/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Firefox Quantum – version 57 – introduced number of changes to the network requests scheduler.  One of them is using data of the Tracking Protection database to &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1358060&quot;&gt;delay load of scripts from tracking domains&lt;/a&gt; when possible during the time a page is actively loading and rendering – I call it &lt;strong&gt;tailing&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This has a positive effect on page load performance as we save some of the network bandwidth, I/O and CPU for loading and processing of images and scripts running on the site so the web page is complete and ready sooner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tracking scripts are not disabled, we only delay their load for few seconds when we can.  Scripts are delayed only when added dynamically or as async.  Tracking images are always delayed.  This is legal according all HTML specifications and it’s assumed that well built sites will not be affected regarding functionality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, sites that are either &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1423373&quot;&gt;not well built&lt;/a&gt; or their &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1420885&quot;&gt;rendering is influenced by scripts&lt;/a&gt; from tracking domains there can be a visible or even functional effect.  Simply said some sites may need to be fixed to be able to adopt this change in scheduling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One example is &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/optimize/&quot;&gt;Google’s Page-Hiding Snippet&lt;/a&gt;, which may cause a web page to be blank for whole 4 seconds since the navigation start.  What happens?  Google’s A/B testing initially hides the whole web page with opacity: 0.  The test script first has to do its job to prepare the page for the test and only then it unhides the page content.  The test script is dynamically loaded by the analytics.js script.  Both the analytics.js and the test script are loaded from www.google-analytics.com, a tracking domain, for which we engage the tailing delay.  As the result the page is blank until one of the following wins: 4 seconds timeout elapses or we load both the scripts and execute them.  For a common user this appears as a performance drawback and not a win.  One possible solution may be to self-host the scripts so they are not recognized as trackers, but this is more work for web administrators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other example can be a web page referring an API of an async tracking script from a sync script, which obviously is a race condition, since there is no guarantee that an async script loads before a sync script.  There is a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lequipe.fr/Football/match/422947&quot;&gt;real life example&lt;/a&gt; of such not-well-built site using a Twitter API – window.twttr.  The twttr object is simply not there when the site’s script calls on it.  An exception is thrown and the rest of the site script is not executed breaking some of the page’s functionality.  That effected web page worked before tailing just because Twitter’s servers were fast to respond and executed sooner than the site script using the window.twttr object.  Hence, worked only by a lucky accident.  Note that sites with such race condition issues are 100% broken also when opened in Private Browsing windows or when Tracking Protection with just the default list is turned on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To conclude on how useful the tailing feature is – unfortunately, at the moment I don’t have enough data to provide (it’s on its way, though.)  So far testing was made mostly locally and on our Web Page Test internal testing infrastructure.  The effect was unfortunately just hidden in the overall noise, hence more scientific and wide testing needs to be done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EDIT: Interesting reactions on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/software/firefox-will-now-delay-the-loading-of-tracking-scripts/&quot;&gt;www.bleepingcomputer.com&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=15963802&quot;&gt;Hacker News&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;(Note: few somewhat off-topic comments have been trashed in case you wonder why they don’t appear here ; I will only accept comments bringing a benefit to discussion of this feature and its issues, thanks for understanding)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 20:16:02 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>bzbarsky</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.janbambas.cz/firefox-57-delays-requests-tracking-domains/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>New Thunderbird Releases and New Thunderbird Staff</title>
<link>https://blog.mozilla.org/thunderbird/2017/12/new-thunderbird-releases-and-new-thunderbird-staff/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.mozilla.org/thunderbird/2017/12/new-thunderbird-releases-and-new-thunderbird-staff/</guid>
<description>&lt;section class=&quot;section section--body section--first&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;section-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section-inner sectionLayout--insetColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_738&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ffp4g1ylyit3jdyti1hqcvtb-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/thunderbird/files/2017/12/TB59-Win10.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-738 size-large&quot; src=&quot;https://ffp4g1ylyit3jdyti1hqcvtb-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/thunderbird/files/2017/12/TB59-Win10-600x405.png&quot; alt=&quot;Thunder 57 “Photon” Visual Refresh&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;405&quot; srcset=&quot;https://blog.mozilla.org/thunderbird/files/2017/12/TB59-Win10-600x405.png 600w, https://blog.mozilla.org/thunderbird/files/2017/12/TB59-Win10-252x170.png 252w, https://blog.mozilla.org/thunderbird/files/2017/12/TB59-Win10-768x518.png 768w, https://blog.mozilla.org/thunderbird/files/2017/12/TB59-Win10.png 1278w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Thunder 57 “Photon” Visual Refresh&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;2306&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;Thunderbird is going strong at version 52 (ESR) and 57, 58 beta&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;582f&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;In April 2017 Thunderbird released its successful Extended Service Release (ESR) version 52. This release has just seen it’s fifth “dot update” 52.5.0, where fixes, stability and minor functionality improvements were shipped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;b373&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Thunderbird 57 beta was also very successful. While Thunderbird 58 is equally stable and offers further cutting-edge improvements to Thunderbird users, the user community is starting to feel the impact of Mozilla platform changes which are phasing out so-called legacy add-ons. The Thunderbird technical leadership is working closely with add-on authors who face the challenge of updating their add-ons to work with the Mozilla interface changes. With a few usually simple changes most add-ons can be made to work in Thunderbird 58 beta. &lt;a class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://wiki.mozilla.org/Thunderbird/Add-ons_Guide_57&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot; data-href=&quot;https://wiki.mozilla.org/Thunderbird/Add-ons_Guide_57&quot;&gt;https://wiki.mozilla.org/Thunderbird/Add-ons_Guide_57&lt;/a&gt; explains what needs to be done, and Thunderbird developers are happy to lend a hand to add-on authors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;e612&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;There has been some discussion about the modernisation of Thunderbird’s user interface. Thunderbird 57 is now following Mozilla’s Photon design, and there is also a new theme available based on the design by the Monterail team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;8164&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p graf--trailing&quot;&gt;You can download the &lt;a class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://www.thunderbird.net/en-US/channel/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.thunderbird.net/en-US/channel/&quot;&gt;current Thunderbird beta here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section class=&quot;section section--body section--last&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section-inner sectionLayout--insetColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;17e2&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf--leading&quot;&gt;New Staff at Thunderbird&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;fc09&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;Since November 2016 the Thunderbird project has contracted the services of long-time Thunderbird volunteer contributor Jörg Knobloch. Since Jörg moved from being a volunteer to being a contractor, his focus has changed from chasing his favourite pet-hate bugs to taking on responsibility for the product. As the continuous integration engineer, he guarantees that Thunderbird Daily is always in sync with Mozilla core changes to keep Daily in a working order. Jörg manages all code for releases (beta and ESR) and monitors regressions as reported at BMO. As a Thunderbird and Mailnews peer he reviews the work of others and is part of the Engineering Steering Committee which is in charge of the code base.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;d33f&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;In March 2017 Andrei Hajdukewycz joined the project. Andrei is the project’s infrastructure engineer. He’s been working on transitioning the project from using Mozilla infrastructure to procuring its own. He administers all the websites used by the project. There are many: Thunderbird.net*), the ISPDB, websites for telemetry, updates and release notes. And last not least: Add-ons. Soon Thunderbird add-ons will transition to Thunderbird’s own add-ons site. Watch this space!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;2f69&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;In June 2017 Tom Prince joined the project as a build and release engineer. He makes sure that we can always build Daily, beta and ESR in en-US English and all localisations. He also helps out when diagnosing test and other miscellaneous failures. Most recently Tom has been migrating the Thunderbird build system from Buildbot to TaskCluster to future-proof this aspect of the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;738f&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;The project’s last hire in December 2017 has been Ryan Sipes (the guy posting this) as Community Manager. His task is to organise the community of voluntary contributors including add-on authors, spread the good news about Thunderbird, engage with donors to guarantee a solid income stream and be in touch with Thunderbird users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;1625&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;These four staff members are just the beginning. The project is currently in the process of hiring developers to address some technical debt, fix some sore points in the software and transition the codebase from a mix of C++, JavaScript, XUL and XPCOM to be increasingly based on web technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;bfc0&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p graf--trailing&quot;&gt;The Thunderbird project has taken control of the Thunderbird.net domain, of which the project will make increasing use. The &lt;a class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; href=&quot;http://www.thunderbird.net&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot; data-href=&quot;http://www.thunderbird.net&quot;&gt;www.thunderbird.net&lt;/a&gt; domain is being updated to be more helpful to users and eventually become Thunderbird’s home on the web. The in-product Thunderbird start page has already been served via this domain for several months. And, the members of the Thunderbird Council have received email accounts @ thunderbird.net, powered by Fastmail, a gift that we are very grateful for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 19:22:24 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>discreditable</dc:creator>
<og:title>New Thunderbird Releases and New Thunderbird Staff</og:title>
<og:url>https://blog.mozilla.org/thunderbird/2017/12/new-thunderbird-releases-and-new-thunderbird-staff/</og:url>
<og:description>Thunder 57 “Photon” Visual Refresh Thunderbird is going strong at version 52 (ESR) and 57, 58 beta In April 2017 Thunderbird released its successful Extended Service ...</og:description>
<og:image>https://blog.mozilla.org/thunderbird/files/2017/12/TB59-Win10-252x170.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.mozilla.org/thunderbird/2017/12/new-thunderbird-releases-and-new-thunderbird-staff/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Tesla big battery outsmarts lumbering coal units</title>
<link>http://reneweconomy.com.au/tesla-big-battery-outsmarts-lumbering-coal-units-after-loy-yang-trips-70003/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://reneweconomy.com.au/tesla-big-battery-outsmarts-lumbering-coal-units-after-loy-yang-trips-70003/</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;printfriendly pf-alignright&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://reneweconomy.com.au/tesla-big-battery-outsmarts-lumbering-coal-units-after-loy-yang-trips-70003/#&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; onclick=&quot;window.print(); return false;&quot; class=&quot;noslimstat&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.printfriendly.com/button-print-blu20.png&quot; alt=&quot;Print Friendly&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://reneweconomy.com.au/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/HPR-frequency-fig-copy.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-105009&quot; src=&quot;http://reneweconomy.com.au/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/HPR-frequency-fig-copy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;HPR frequency fig copy&quot; width=&quot;549&quot; height=&quot;343&quot; srcset=&quot;http://reneweconomy.com.au/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/HPR-frequency-fig-copy.jpg 576w, http://reneweconomy.com.au/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/HPR-frequency-fig-copy-300x188.jpg 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 549px) 100vw, 549px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Tesla big battery is having a big impact on Australia’s electricity market, far beyond the South Australia grid where it was expected to time shift a small amount of wind energy and provide network services and emergency back-up in case of a major problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last Thursday, one of the biggest coal units in Australia, Loy Yang A 3, tripped without warning at 1.59am, with the sudden loss of 560MW and causing a slump in frequency on the network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What happened next has stunned electricity industry insiders and given food for thought over the near to medium term future of the grid, such was the rapid response of the Tesla big battery to an event that happened nearly 1,000km away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even before the Loy Yang A unit had finished tripping, the 100MW/129MWh had responded, injecting 7.3MW into the network to help arrest a slump in frequency that had fallen below 49.80Hertz.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Data from AEMO (and gathered above by Dylan McConnell from the Climate and Energy College) shows that the Tesla big battery responded four seconds ahead of the generator contracted at that time to provide FCAS (frequency control and ancillary services), the Gladstone coal generator in Queensland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://reneweconomy.com.au/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/HPR-frequeny-fig-2-copy.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-105008&quot; src=&quot;http://reneweconomy.com.au/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/HPR-frequeny-fig-2-copy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;HPR frequeny fig 2 copy&quot; width=&quot;549&quot; height=&quot;343&quot; srcset=&quot;http://reneweconomy.com.au/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/HPR-frequeny-fig-2-copy.jpg 576w, http://reneweconomy.com.au/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/HPR-frequeny-fig-2-copy-300x188.jpg 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 549px) 100vw, 549px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But in reality, the response from the Tesla big battery was even quicker than that – in milliseconds – but too fast for the AEMO data to record.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Importantly, by the time that the contracted Gladstone coal unit had gotten out of bed and put its socks on so it can inject more into the grid – it is paid to respond in six seconds – the fall in frequency had already been arrested and was being reversed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gladstone injected more than Tesla did back into the grid, and took the frequency back up to its normal levels of 50Hz, but by then Tesla had already put its gun back in its holster and had wandered into the bar for a glass of milk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So why did the Tesla big battery respond when not contracted?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One reason is because it can, and so it did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other reason is less clear, but more intriguing. It is contracted to provide such grid services by the South Australia government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The details of that contract are not released, but it wouldn’t surprise if that contract allowed, or even encouraged, such intervention – just to rub in the message about a cleaner, faster, smarter grid to the technology dinosaurs in the eastern states.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marvellous stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is just the latest in a series of interventions since the &lt;a href=&quot;http://reneweconomy.com.au/tesla-big-battery-officially-switched-on-in-south-australia-55285/&quot;&gt;Tesla big battery was officially opened&lt;/a&gt; in early December.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://reneweconomy.com.au/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/hornsdale-power-reserve-copy-2.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-105015&quot; src=&quot;http://reneweconomy.com.au/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/hornsdale-power-reserve-copy-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;hornsdale power reserve copy&quot; width=&quot;549&quot; height=&quot;343&quot; srcset=&quot;http://reneweconomy.com.au/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/hornsdale-power-reserve-copy-2.jpg 576w, http://reneweconomy.com.au/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/hornsdale-power-reserve-copy-2-300x188.jpg 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 549px) 100vw, 549px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has provided, at the request of AEMO, &lt;a href=&quot;http://reneweconomy.com.au/tesla-big-battery-shows-off-its-flexibility-in-final-testing-56982/&quot;&gt;70MW of back-up to help meet a critical peak&lt;/a&gt; in the day before its opening, &lt;a href=&quot;http://reneweconomy.com.au/what-is-the-tesla-big-battery-actually-selling-its-not-just-energy-70252/&quot;&gt;entered into the FCAS market,&lt;/a&gt; as &lt;a href=&quot;http://reneweconomy.com.au/what-is-the-tesla-big-battery-actually-selling-its-not-just-energy-70252/&quot;&gt;we highlight here,&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://reneweconomy.com.au/tesla-big-battery-goes-full-discharge-100mw-first-time-37826/&quot;&gt;discharged at full capacity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the weekend was again illustrating its rapid fire charging and discharging. (See graph above). The rapid re-bidding is likely to change the market forever, particularly when the 5-minute settlement rule finally comes into effect in 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It should be an interesting 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: The Tesla big battery is known to the grid as the Hornsdale Power Reserve, as it is located near the Hornsdale wind farm in South Australia, also owned and operated by Neoen. Hence the acronym HPR in such tables.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Update: We just realised that a paragraph explaining the timings of the Tesla intervention went missing in the transfer from one document to another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be clear, on the timing of the response of this generators, some did some minor adjustments (1MW) as part of regulation FCAS, the moment they dropped below 50Hz.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The interesting thing here is the speed with which Tesla responded to the contingency FCAS market, which is triggered after frequency gets to 49.8Hz. That was pretty much instantaneous. And they did it from a standing start, unlike the other generators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tesla weren’t officially playing in that market, but just wanted to show what they could do. And they did. That’s what’s impressive, and what’s game changing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for timing, Loy Yang A started to lose it at 1.58:59 (NEM time). Its biggest drop, from 364MW to 176MW, was at 1.59:19, which is where frequency hit 49.8Hz, and which is where Tesla came in a matter of milliseconds (but recorded in the 1.59:23 time frame).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gladstone 1, a contingency FCAS supplier, hopped in at 1.59:27. Loy Yang was down to 44MW by then and completely gone in the next 4 second period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And no, we never suggested this averted a blackout. The point of the story was what Tesla could do. Now, imagine if there was actually a proper market (fast frequency control) for this stuff.&lt;/p&gt;



</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 19:08:58 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>beardicus</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Tesla big battery outsmarts lumbering coal units after Loy Yang trips</og:title>
<og:url>http://reneweconomy.com.au/tesla-big-battery-outsmarts-lumbering-coal-units-after-loy-yang-trips-70003/</og:url>
<og:description>Tesla big battery steps in after big Loy Yang coal unit trips, and arrests and reverses a dramatic fall in frequency – before the contracted coal unit had time to respond.</og:description>
<og:image>http://reneweconomy.com.au/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/HPR-frequency-fig-copy.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://reneweconomy.com.au/tesla-big-battery-outsmarts-lumbering-coal-units-after-loy-yang-trips-70003/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>