<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>The strength of a monopoly can be guessed at by calling customer support</title>
<link>http://blogs.harvard.edu/bugeja/2018/09/16/the-strength-of-a-monopoly-can-be-guessed-at-by-the-quality-of-its-customer-support/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://blogs.harvard.edu/bugeja/2018/09/16/the-strength-of-a-monopoly-can-be-guessed-at-by-the-quality-of-its-customer-support/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;If you were an alien hovering above planet earth on a quick visit and trying to find out quickly which were its most dominant companies, you could probably do worse than try to reach their customer support representatives with some test queries. One who does not need to worry about losing customers does not need to worry about supporting them either. Just a few from my recent personal experience:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google Ads (formerly Adwords): terrible support from an inexperienced foreign support center – if you’re in the USA. I’ve heard it’s not too bad in some other regions where they’re presumably more concerned about customer acquisition. Strangely enough, these particular support reps are very confident in the quality of their answers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook Ads: these days they seem particularly fond of inserting greenhorns into the ranks, who generally know way less than the customer asking the questions, but have no hesitation about making up stuff on the fly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazon (the consumer site, &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; AWS): used to be known for legendary support in the early days. Increasingly difficult to find out how to reach them now. Link gets buried deeper and deeper in their site as time goes on, and they’re more likely to require a return if there’s a problem with even a small order. Also, this is new: &lt;a href=&quot;http://time.com/money/5288702/amazon-return-policy-ban/&quot;&gt;http://time.com/money/5288702/amazon-return-policy-ban/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comcast: the less said about those guys, the better really.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AT&amp;amp;T: see Comcast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The IRS… threw this one in just for fun. Try calling their customer support line with any question more complex than when is the next estimated tax deadline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conversely, companies scrambling to gain market share from incumbents tend to have outstanding customer support. Common examples of this are &lt;a href=&quot;http://paulgraham.com/ds.html&quot;&gt;startups doing things that don’t scale&lt;/a&gt;, where routine customer support questions are often thoroughly answered by a founder, even at odd weekend hours. But you’ll find much larger companies behaving similarly, in all kinds of industries, so long, it seems, as there are obvious competitors which prevent them from establishing monopoly positions. Uline is one which readily comes to mind if you’re involved with ecommerce… their customer support is ridiculously responsive. There are plenty of places you can buy corrugated boxes after all…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once a monopoly position is established, all bets seem to be off. The temptation to tweak with all cost centers to see what exactly affects the bottom line and what doesn’t seems to be too much for those in the C-suite to resist, and customer support seems to get it every time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;robots-nocontent sd-block sd-social sd-social-icon sd-sharing&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Share this:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;jp-relatedposts-headline&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Related&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 20:13:42 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>arbuge</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>The strength of a monopoly can be guessed at by calling customer support</og:title>
<og:url>http://blogs.harvard.edu/bugeja/2018/09/16/the-strength-of-a-monopoly-can-be-guessed-at-by-the-quality-of-its-customer-support/</og:url>
<og:description>If you were an alien hovering above planet earth on a quick visit and trying to find out quickly which were its most dominant companies, you could probably do worse than try to reach their customer…</og:description>
<og:image>https://i1.wp.com/blogs.harvard.edu/bugeja/files/2018/09/cropped-small.jpg?fit=200%2C200</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://blogs.harvard.edu/bugeja/2018/09/16/the-strength-of-a-monopoly-can-be-guessed-at-by-the-quality-of-its-customer-support/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Linus Torvalds apologizes for his behavior, takes time off</title>
<link>https://lore.kernel.org/lkml/CA+55aFy+Hv9O5citAawS+mVZO+ywCKd9NQ2wxUmGsz9ZJzqgJQ@mail.gmail.com/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://lore.kernel.org/lkml/CA+55aFy+Hv9O5citAawS+mVZO+ywCKd9NQ2wxUmGsz9ZJzqgJQ@mail.gmail.com/</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;meta http-equiv=&quot;Content-Type&quot; content=&quot;text/html; charset=UTF-8&quot; /&gt;&lt;title&gt;Linux 4.19-rc4 released, an apology, and a maintainership note - Linus Torvalds&lt;/title&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;alternate&quot; title=&quot;Atom feed&quot; href=&quot;../new.atom&quot; type=&quot;application/atom+xml&quot; /&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot; readability=&quot;105.04724409449&quot;&gt;

&lt;pre id=&quot;b&quot;&gt;
From: Linus Torvalds &amp;lt;torvalds@linux-foundation.org&amp;gt;
To: Linux Kernel Mailing List &amp;lt;linux-kernel@vger.kernel.org&amp;gt;
Subject: &lt;a href=&quot;https://lore.kernel.org/lkml/CA+55aFy+Hv9O5citAawS+mVZO+ywCKd9NQ2wxUmGsz9ZJzqgJQ@mail.gmail.com/#r&quot; id=&quot;t&quot; name=&quot;t&quot;&gt;Linux 4.19-rc4 released, an apology, and a maintainership note&lt;/a&gt;
Date: Sun, 16 Sep 2018 12:22:43 -0700
Message-ID: &amp;lt;CA+55aFy+Hv9O5citAawS+mVZO+ywCKd9NQ2wxUmGsz9ZJzqgJQ@mail.gmail.com&amp;gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://lore.kernel.org/lkml/CA+55aFy+Hv9O5citAawS+mVZO+ywCKd9NQ2wxUmGsz9ZJzqgJQ@mail.gmail.com/raw&quot;&gt;raw&lt;/a&gt;)

[ So this email got a lot longer than I initially thought it would
get,  but let's start out with the &quot;regular Sunday release&quot; part ]

Another week, another rc.

Nothing particularly odd stands out on the technical side in the
kernel updates for last week - rc4 looks fairly average in size for
this stage in the release cycle, and all the other statistics look
pretty normal too.

We've got roughly two thirds driver fixes (gpu and networking look to
be the bulk of it, but there's smaller changes all over in various
driver subsystems), with the rest being the usual mix: core
networking, perf tooling updates, arch updates, Documentation, some
filesystem, vm and minor core kernel fixes.

So it's all fairly small and normal for this stage.  As usual, I'm
appending the shortlog at the bottom for people who want to get an
overview of the details without actually having to go dig in the git
tree.

The one change that stands out and merits mention is the code of
conduct addition...

[ And here comes the other, much longer, part... ]

Which brings me to the *NOT* normal part of the last week: the
discussions (both in public mainly on the kernel summit discussion
lists and then a lot in various private communications) about
maintainership and the kernel community.  Some of that discussion came
about because of me screwing up my scheduling for the maintainer
summit where these things are supposed to be discussed.

And don't get me wrong.  It's not like that discussion itself is in
any way new to this week - we've been discussing maintainership and
community for years. We've had lots of discussions both in private and
on mailing lists.  We have regular talks at conferences - again, both
the &quot;public speaking&quot; kind and the &quot;private hallway track&quot; kind.

No, what was new last week is really my reaction to it, and me being
perhaps introspective (you be the judge).

There were two parts to that.

One was simply my own reaction to having screwed up my scheduling of
the maintainership summit: yes, I was somewhat embarrassed about
having screwed up my calendar, but honestly, I was mostly hopeful that
I wouldn't have to go to the kernel summit that I have gone to every
year for just about the last two decades.

Yes, we got it rescheduled, and no, my &quot;maybe you can just do it
without me there&quot; got overruled.  But that whole situation then
started a whole different kind of discussion.  And kind of
incidentally to that one, the second part was that I realized that I
had completely mis-read some of the people involved.

This is where the &quot;look yourself in the mirror&quot; moment comes in.

So here we are, me finally on the one hand realizing that it wasn't
actually funny or a good sign that I was hoping to just skip the
yearly kernel summit entirely, and on the other hand realizing that I
really had been ignoring some fairly deep-seated feelings in the
community.

It's one thing when you can ignore these issues.  Usually it’s just
something I didn't want to deal with.

This is my reality.  I am not an emotionally empathetic kind of person
and that probably doesn't come as a big surprise to anybody.  Least of
all me.  The fact that I then misread people and don't realize (for
years) how badly I've judged a situation and contributed to an
unprofessional environment is not good.

This week people in our community confronted me about my lifetime of
not understanding emotions.  My flippant attacks in emails have been
both unprofessional and uncalled for.  Especially at times when I made
it personal.  In my quest for a better patch, this made sense to me.
I know now this was not OK and I am truly sorry.

The above is basically a long-winded way to get to the somewhat
painful personal admission that hey, I need to change some of my
behavior, and I want to apologize to the people that my personal
behavior hurt and possibly drove away from kernel development
entirely.

I am going to take time off and get some assistance on how to
understand people’s emotions and respond appropriately.

Put another way: When asked at conferences, I occasionally talk about
how the pain-points in kernel development have generally not been
about the _technical_ issues, but about the inflection points where
development flow and behavior changed.

These pain points have been about managing the flow of patches, and
often been associated with big tooling changes - moving from making
releases with &quot;patches and tar-balls&quot; (and the _very_ painful
discussions about how &quot;Linus doesn't scale&quot; back 15+ years ago) to
using BitKeeper, and then to having to write git in order to get past
the point of that no longer working for us.

We haven't had that kind of pain-point in about a decade.  But this
week felt like that kind of pain point to me.

To tie this all back to the actual 4.19-rc4 release (no, really, this
_is_ related!) I actually think that 4.19 is looking fairly good,
things have gotten to the &quot;calm&quot; period of the release cycle, and I've
talked to Greg to ask him if he'd mind finishing up 4.19 for me, so
that I can take a break, and try to at least fix my own behavior.

This is not some kind of &quot;I'm burnt out, I need to just go away&quot;
break.  I'm not feeling like I don't want to continue maintaining
Linux. Quite the reverse.  I very much *do* want to continue to do
this project that I've been working on for almost three decades.

This is more like the time I got out of kernel development for a while
because I needed to write a little tool called &quot;git&quot;.  I need to take
a break to get help on how to behave differently and fix some issues
in my tooling and workflow.

And yes, some of it might be &quot;just&quot; tooling.  Maybe I can get an email
filter in place so at when I send email with curse-words, they just
won't go out.  Because hey, I'm a big believer in tools, and at least
_some_ problems going forward might be improved with simple
automation.

I know when I really look “myself in the mirror” it will be clear it's
not the only change that has to happen, but hey...  You can send me
suggestions in email.

I look forward to seeing you at the Maintainer Summit.

                Linus

---

Aaron Knister (1):
      IB/ipoib: Avoid a race condition between start_xmit and cm_rep_handler

AceLan Kao (1):
      HID: i2c-hid: Fix flooded incomplete report after S3 on Rayd touchscreen

Adrian Hunter (1):
      perf tools: Fix maps__find_symbol_by_name()

Ahmed S. Darwish (1):
      staging: gasket: TODO: re-implement using UIO

Alan Stern (1):
      USB: net2280: Fix erroneous synchronization change

Alexander Usyskin (1):
      mei: ignore not found client in the enumeration

Amir Goldstein (6):
      ovl: respect FIEMAP_FLAG_SYNC flag
      ovl: fix GPF in swapfile_activate of file from overlayfs over xfs
      Documentation/filesystems: update documentation of file_operations
      vfs: add the fadvise() file operation
      vfs: implement readahead(2) using POSIX_FADV_WILLNEED
      ovl: add ovl_fadvise()

Andreas Bosch (1):
      HID: intel-ish-hid: Enable Sunrise Point-H ish driver

Andreas Kemnade (1):
      mmc: omap_hsmmc: fix wakeirq handling on removal

Andrew Murray (1):
      asm-generic: io: Fix ioport_map() for !CONFIG_GENERIC_IOMAP &amp;amp;&amp;amp;
CONFIG_INDIRECT_PIO

Anton Vasilyev (1):
      usb: gadget: fotg210-udc: Fix memory leak of fotg210-&amp;gt;ep[i]

Anurag Kumar Vulisha (1):
      usb: host: xhci-plat: Iterate over parent nodes for finding quirks

Arnaldo Carvalho de Melo (7):
      perf tools: Streamline bpf examples and headers installation
      tools headers uapi: Update tools's copy of linux/perf_event.h
      tools headers uapi: Update tools's copy of asm-generic/unistd.h
      tools headers uapi: Update tools's copy of drm/drm.h
      tools headers uapi: Update tools's copies of kvm headers
      tools headers uapi: Update tools's copy of linux/vhost.h
      tools headers uapi: Update tools's copy of linux/if_link.h

Arnd Bergmann (2):
      staging: wilc1000: revert &quot;fix TODO to compile spi and sdio
components in single module&quot;
      usb: dwc3: of-simple: avoid unused function warnings

Artemy Kovalyov (1):
      IB/core: Release object lock if destroy failed

Ben Hutchings (3):
      USB: yurex: Fix buffer over-read in yurex_write()
      USB: yurex: Check for truncation in yurex_read()
      locking/lockdep: Delete unnecessary #include

Ben Skeggs (8):
      drm/nouveau: fix oops in client init failure path
      drm/nouveau/mmu: don't attempt to dereference vmm without valid
instance pointer
      drm/nouveau/TBDdevinit: don't fail when PMU/PRE_OS is missing from VBIOS
      drm/nouveau/disp: remove unused struct member
      drm/nouveau/disp: move eDP panel power handling
      drm/nouveau/disp: fix DP disable race
      drm/nouveau/disp/gm200-: enforce identity-mapped SOR assignment
for LVDS/eDP panels
      drm/nouveau/devinit: fix warning when PMU/PRE_OS is missing

Benjamin Fair (1):
      ipmi: kcs_bmc: don't change device name

Benjamin Tissoires (2):
      HID: multitouch: fix Elan panels with 2 input modes declaration
      HID: core: fix grouping by application

Bin Yang (1):
      pstore: Fix incorrect persistent ram buffer mapping

Boris Ostrovsky (1):
      x86/EISA: Don't probe EISA bus for Xen PV guests

Borislav Petkov (1):
      jump_label: Fix typo in warning message

Bruno Meirelles Herrera (1):
      usb: dwc2: Fix call location of dwc2_check_core_endianness

Bryant G. Ly (1):
      misc: ibmvsm: Fix wrong assignment of return code

Chris Phlipot (2):
      perf util: Fix bad memory access in trace info.
      perf event-parse: Use fixed size string for comms

Chris Wilson (1):
      drm/i915/overlay: Allocate physical registers from stolen

Christian König (2):
      drm/amdgpu: fix amdgpu_mn_unlock() in the CS error path
      drm/amdgpu: fix error handling in amdgpu_cs_user_fence_chunk

Chunfeng Yun (2):
      usb: mtu3: fix error of xhci port id when enable U3 dual role
      usb: xhci: fix interrupt transfer error happened on MTK platforms

Colin Ian King (1):
      locking/ww_mutex: Fix spelling mistake &quot;cylic&quot; -&amp;gt; &quot;cyclic&quot;

Cong Wang (6):
      tipc: orphan sock in tipc_release()
      tipc: call start and done ops directly in __tipc_nl_compat_dumpit()
      net_sched: properly cancel netlink dump on failure
      netfilter: xt_hashlimit: use s-&amp;gt;file instead of s-&amp;gt;private
      rds: fix two RCU related problems
      tipc: check return value of __tipc_dump_start()

Corey Minyard (3):
      ipmi: Rework SMI registration failure
      ipmi: Move BT capabilities detection to the detect call
      ipmi: Fix I2C client removal in the SSIF driver

Dan Carpenter (4):
      cifs: prevent integer overflow in nxt_dir_entry()
      CIFS: fix wrapping bugs in num_entries()
      cifs: integer overflow in in SMB2_ioctl()
      cifs: read overflow in is_valid_oplock_break()

Daniel Jurgens (1):
      net/mlx5: Consider PCI domain in search for next dev

Daniel Vetter (1):
      staging/fbtft: Update TODO and mailing lists

Davide Caratti (1):
      net/sched: fix memory leak in act_tunnel_key_init()

Dennis Dalessandro (2):
      PCI: Fix faulty logic in pci_reset_bus()
      IB/hfi1,PCI: Allow bus reset while probing

Emily Deng (1):
      drm/amdgpu: move PSP init prior to IH in gpu reset

Felix Kuehling (1):
      PCI: Fix enabling of PASID on RC integrated endpoints

Florian Westphal (5):
      netfilter: xt_checksum: ignore gso skbs
      netfilter: conntrack: place 'new' timeout in first location too
      netfilter: nf_tables: rework ct timeout set support
      netfilter: kconfig: nat related expression depend on nftables core
      netfilter: conntrack: reset tcp maxwin on re-register

Gao Xiang (2):
      Revert &quot;staging: erofs: disable compiling temporarile&quot;
      staging: erofs: rename superblock flags (MS_xyz -&amp;gt; SB_xyz)

Greg Kroah-Hartman (1):
      Code of Conduct: Let's revamp it.

Guenter Roeck (2):
      riscv: Do not overwrite initrd_start and initrd_end
      x86/efi: Load fixmap GDT in efi_call_phys_epilog() before setting %cr3

Gustavo A. R. Silva (4):
      ipmi: Fix NULL pointer dereference in ssif_probe
      HID: core: fix NULL pointer dereference
      switchtec: Fix Spectre v1 vulnerability
      misc: hmc6352: fix potential Spectre v1

Haishuang Yan (2):
      erspan: return PACKET_REJECT when the appropriate tunnel is not found
      erspan: fix error handling for erspan tunnel

Hans de Goede (3):
      HID: sensor-hub: Restore fixup for Lenovo ThinkPad Helix 2
sensor hub report
      staging: vboxvideo: Fix IRQs no longer working
      staging: vboxvideo: Change address of scanout buffer on page-flip

Harry Mallon (1):
      HID: hid-saitek: Add device ID for RAT 7 Contagion

Hauke Mehrtens (1):
      MIPS: lantiq: dma: add dev pointer

Heinz Mauelshagen (5):
      dm raid: fix reshape race on small devices
      dm raid: fix stripe adding reshape deadlock
      dm raid: fix rebuild of specific devices by updating superblock
      dm raid: fix RAID leg rebuild errors
      dm raid: bump target version, update comments and documentation

Hisao Tanabe (1):
      perf evsel: Fix potential null pointer dereference in
perf_evsel__new_idx()

Huang Shijie (1):
      dmaengine: mic_x100_dma: use devm_kzalloc to fix an issue

Huy Nguyen (1):
      net/mlx5: Check for error in mlx5_attach_interface

Imre Deak (1):
      drm/i915/bdw: Increase IPS disable timeout to 100ms

Ingo Franzki (1):
      s390/crypto: Fix return code checking in cbc_paes_crypt()

Jacek Tomaka (1):
      perf/x86/intel: Add support/quirk for the MISPREDICT bit on
Knights Landing CPUs

Jack Morgenstein (2):
      net/mlx5: Fix use-after-free in self-healing flow
      net/mlx5: Fix debugfs cleanup in the device init/remove flow

James Morse (1):
      arm64: kernel: arch_crash_save_vmcoreinfo() should depend on
CONFIG_CRASH_CORE

Jann Horn (1):
      RDMA/ucma: check fd type in ucma_migrate_id()

Jens Axboe (2):
      blk-cgroup: increase number of supported policies
      null_blk: fix zoned support for non-rq based operation

Jia-Ju Bai (3):
      usb: host: u132-hcd: Fix a sleep-in-atomic-context bug in u132_get_frame()
      usb: misc: uss720: Fix two sleep-in-atomic-context bugs
      usb: cdc-wdm: Fix a sleep-in-atomic-context bug in
service_outstanding_interrupt()

Jiada Wang (1):
      sched/debug: Fix potential deadlock when writing to sched_features

Jiri Olsa (5):
      perf tests: Add breakpoint modify tests
      perf/hw_breakpoint: Modify breakpoint even if the new attr has
disabled set
      perf/hw_breakpoint: Remove superfluous bp-&amp;gt;attr.disabled = 0
      perf/hw_breakpoint: Enable breakpoint in modify_user_hw_breakpoint
      perf/hw_breakpoint: Simplify breakpoint enable in
perf_event_modify_breakpoint

Joao Pinto (1):
      MAINTAINERS: Add Gustavo Pimentel as DesignWare PCI maintainer

Joe Thornber (1):
      dm thin metadata: try to avoid ever aborting transactions

Joerg Roedel (1):
      Revert &quot;x86/mm/legacy: Populate the user page-table with user pgd's&quot;

Johan Hovold (3):
      USB: serial: io_ti: fix array underflow in completion handler
      USB: serial: ti_usb_3410_5052: fix array underflow in completion handler
      mmc: meson-mx-sdio: fix OF child-node lookup

John Hubbard (1):
      mei: fix use-after-free in mei_cl_write

Josh Abraham (1):
      xen: fix GCC warning and remove duplicate EVTCHN_ROW/EVTCHN_COL usage

Juergen Gross (2):
      xen/netfront: fix waiting for xenbus state change
      x86/xen: Disable CPU0 hotplug for Xen PV

Julian Wiedmann (6):
      net/af_iucv: drop inbound packets with invalid flags
      net/af_iucv: fix skb handling on HiperTransport xmit error
      net/iucv: declare iucv_path_table_empty() as static
      s390/qeth: indicate error when netdev allocation fails
      s390/qeth: switch on SG by default for IQD devices
      s390/qeth: don't dump past end of unknown HW header

K. Y. Srinivasan (1):
      Tools: hv: Fix a bug in the key delete code

Kai-Heng Feng (2):
      HID: i2c-hid: Don't reset device upon system resume
      r8169: Clear RTL_FLAG_TASK_*_PENDING when clearing RTL_FLAG_TASK_ENABLED

Keith Busch (1):
      PCI: pciehp: Fix hot-add vs powerfault detection order

Kim Phillips (2):
      perf arm64: Fix include path for asm-generic/unistd.h
      perf annotate: Fix parsing aarch64 branch instructions after
objdump update

Kristian Evensen (1):
      qmi_wwan: Support dynamic config on Quectel EP06

Kuninori Morimoto (1):
      ethernet: renesas: convert to SPDX identifiers

Leon Romanovsky (1):
      RDMA/mlx4: Ensure that maximal send/receive SGE less than supported by HW

Linus Torvalds (2):
      mm: get rid of vmacache_flush_all() entirely
      Linux 4.19-rc4

Lorenzo Bianconi (1):
      iio: imu: st_lsm6dsx: take into account ts samples in wm configuration

Louis Peens (1):
      nfp: flower: reject tunnel encap with ipv6 outer headers for offloading

Lyude Paul (13):
      drm/nouveau/drm/nouveau: Fix bogus drm_kms_helper_poll_enable() placement
      drm/nouveau: Remove duplicate poll_enable() in pmops_runtime_suspend()
      drm/nouveau/drm/nouveau: Fix deadlock with fb_helper with async
RPM requests
      drm/nouveau/drm/nouveau: Use pm_runtime_get_noresume() in
connector_detect()
      drm/nouveau: Fix deadlocks in nouveau_connector_detect()
      drm/nouveau: Remove useless poll_enable() call in switcheroo_set_state()
      drm/nouveau: Remove useless poll_disable() call in switcheroo_set_state()
      drm/nouveau: Remove useless poll_enable() call in drm_load()
      drm/nouveau: Only write DP_MSTM_CTRL when needed
      drm/nouveau: Reset MST branching unit before enabling
      drm/nouveau/drm/nouveau: Prevent handling ACPI HPD events too early
      drm/nouveau/drm/nouveau: Don't forget to cancel hpd_work on suspend/unload
      drm/nouveau: Fix nouveau_connector_ddc_detect()

Maciej S. Szmigiero (1):
      r8169: set TxConfig register after TX / RX is enabled, just like RxConfig

Marek Marczykowski-Górecki (1):
      xen/balloon: add runtime control for scrubbing ballooned out pages

Martin Liška (1):
      perf annotate: Properly interpret indirect call

Martin Schwidefsky (1):
      s390/zcrypt: remove VLA usage from the AP bus

Martin Willi (1):
      netfilter: xt_cluster: add dependency on conntrack module

Masahiro Yamada (1):
      xtensa: remove unnecessary KBUILD_SRC ifeq conditional

Mathias Nyman (3):
      xhci: Fix use after free for URB cancellation on a reallocated endpoint
      usb: Don't die twice if PCI xhci host is not responding in resume
      usb: Avoid use-after-free by flushing endpoints early in
usb_set_interface()

Matt Ranostay (1):
      Revert &quot;iio: temperature: maxim_thermocouple: add MAX31856 part&quot;

Max Filippov (2):
      xtensa: ISS: don't allocate memory in platform_setup
      xtensa: enable SG chaining in Kconfig

Maxence Duprès (1):
      USB: add quirk for WORLDE Controller KS49 or Prodipe MIDI 49C
USB controller

Michal 'vorner' Vaner (1):
      netfilter: nfnetlink_queue: Solve the NFQUEUE/conntrack clash
for NF_REPEAT

Michal Hocko (1):
      xen/gntdev: fix up blockable calls to mn_invl_range_start

Miguel Ojeda (1):
      arm64: jump_label.h: use asm_volatile_goto macro instead of &quot;asm goto&quot;

Mika Westerberg (1):
      Revert &quot;PCI: Add ACS quirk for Intel 300 series&quot;

Mike Christie (1):
      scsi: iscsi: target: Fix conn_ops double free

Miklos Szeredi (1):
      ovl: fix oopses in ovl_fill_super() failure paths

Mikulas Patocka (2):
      dm verity: fix crash on bufio buffer that was allocated with vmalloc
      dm: disable CRYPTO_TFM_REQ_MAY_SLEEP to fix a GFP_KERNEL
recursion deadlock

Minchan Kim (1):
      android: binder: fix the race mmap and alloc_new_buf_locked

Netanel Belgazal (7):
      net: ena: fix surprise unplug NULL dereference kernel crash
      net: ena: fix driver when PAGE_SIZE == 64kB
      net: ena: fix device destruction to gracefully free resources
      net: ena: fix potential double ena_destroy_device()
      net: ena: fix missing lock during device destruction
      net: ena: fix missing calls to READ_ONCE
      net: ena: fix incorrect usage of memory barriers

Nicholas Piggin (3):
      tty: hvc: hvc_poll() fix read loop hang
      tty: hvc: hvc_poll() fix read loop batching
      tty: hvc: hvc_write() fix break condition

Nilesh Javali (1):
      scsi: qedi: Add the CRC size within iSCSI NVM image

Olaf Hering (1):
      xen: avoid crash in disable_hotplug_cpu

Oliver Neukum (2):
      usb: uas: add support for more quirk flags
      Revert &quot;cdc-acm: implement put_char() and flush_chars()&quot;

Pablo Neira Ayuso (2):
      netfilter: conntrack: timeout interface depend on
CONFIG_NF_CONNTRACK_TIMEOUT
      netfilter: cttimeout: ctnl_timeout_find_get() returns incorrect
pointer to type

Parav Pandit (2):
      RDMA/uverbs: Fix error cleanup path of ib_uverbs_add_one()
      RDMA/cma: Protect cma dev list with lock

Paul Burton (1):
      pinctrl: ingenic: Fix group &amp;amp; function error checking

Paulo Zanoni (1):
      tracing/Makefile: Fix handling redefinition of CC_FLAGS_FTRACE

Peter Zijlstra (1):
      perf/UAPI: Clearly mark __PERF_SAMPLE_CALLCHAIN_EARLY as internal use

Petr Machata (1):
      mlxsw: spectrum_buffers: Set up a dedicated pool for BUM traffic

Petr Mladek (1):
      Revert &quot;printk: make sure to print log on console.&quot;

Petr Oros (1):
      be2net: Fix memory leak in be_cmd_get_profile_config()

Pieter Jansen van Vuuren (1):
      nfp: flower: fix vlan match by checking both vlan id and vlan pcp

Raed Salem (1):
      net/mlx5: E-Switch, Fix memory leak when creating switchdev mode
FDB tables

Randy Dunlap (9):
      usb/dwc3/gadget: fix kernel-doc parameter warning
      usb: typec: fix kernel-doc parameter warning
      usb/typec: fix kernel-doc notation warning for typec_match_altmode
      linux/mod_devicetable.h: fix kernel-doc missing notation for
typec_device_id
      sched/fair: Fix kernel-doc notation warning
      x86/doc: Fix Documentation/x86/earlyprintk.txt
      arch/hexagon: fix kernel/dma.c build warning
      hexagon: modify ffs() and fls() to return int
      x86/APM: Fix build warning when PROC_FS is not enabled

Richard Fitzgerald (1):
      pinctrl: madera: Fix possible NULL pointer with pdata config

Rishabh Bhatnagar (1):
      firmware: Fix security issue with request_firmware_into_buf()

Rob Herring (1):
      of: fix phandle cache creation for DTs with no phandles

Roi Dayan (2):
      net/mlx5: Fix not releasing read lock when adding flow rules
      net/mlx5: Fix possible deadlock from lockdep when adding fte to fg

Saeed Mahameed (1):
      net/mlx5e: Ethtool steering, fix udp source port value

Sagi Grimberg (1):
      nvmet-rdma: fix possible bogus dereference under heavy load

Sandipan Das (1):
      perf probe powerpc: Ignore SyS symbols irrespective of endianness

Sasha Levin (3):
      tools/lib/lockdep: Update Sasha Levin email to MSFT
      tools/lib/lockdep: Add empty nmi.h
      tools/lib/lockdep: Add dummy task_struct state member

Sean O'Brien (1):
      HID: add support for Apple Magic Keyboards

Somnath Kotur (1):
      bnxt_re: Fix couple of memory leaks that could lead to IOMMU call traces

Srikar Dronamraju (1):
      sched/topology: Set correct NUMA topology type

Stefan Agner (2):
      HID: input: fix leaking custom input node name
      HID: core: fix memory leak on probe

Stefan Metzmacher (1):
      fs/cifs: require sha512

Stefan Wahren (1):
      net: qca_spi: Fix race condition in spi transfers

Stephen Boyd (1):
      pinctrl: msm: Really mask level interrupts to prevent latching

Stephen Hemminger (1):
      vmbus: don't return values for uninitalized channels

Stephen Rothwell (1):
      fs/cifs: suppress a string overflow warning

Steve Muckle (1):
      sched/fair: Fix vruntime_normalized() for remote non-migration wakeup

Steve Wise (1):
      iw_cxgb4: only allow 1 flush on user qps

Taehee Yoo (2):
      netfilter: nf_tables: release chain in flushing set
      ip: frags: fix crash in ip_do_fragment()

Tao Zhou (1):
      drm/amdgpu: Fix SDMA hang in prt mode v2

Tariq Toukan (2):
      net/mlx5: Use u16 for Work Queue buffer fragment size
      net/mlx5: Use u16 for Work Queue buffer strides offset

Tejun Heo (1):
      MAINTAINERS: Make Dennis the percpu tree maintainer

Thomas Hellstrom (1):
      locking/mutex: Fix mutex debug call and ww_mutex documentation

Tim Anderson (1):
      USB: Add quirk to support DJI CineSSD

Todd Poynor (1):
      MAINTAINERS: Switch a maintainer for drivers/staging/gasket

Tomas Winkler (2):
      mei: bus: fix hw module get/put balance
      mei: bus: need to unlink client before freeing

Trond Myklebust (5):
      NFSv4: Fix a tracepoint Oops in initiate_file_draining()
      pNFS: Ensure we return the error if someone kills a waiting layoutget
      NFSv4: Fix a tracepoint Oops in initiate_file_draining()
      NFSv4.1 fix infinite loop on I/O.
      NFS: Don't open code clearing of delegation state

Tyrel Datwyler (1):
      MAINTAINERS: Add entries for PPC64 RPA PCI hotplug drivers

Vakul Garg (1):
      net/tls: Set count of SG entries if sk_alloc_sg returns -ENOSPC

Vincent Guittot (3):
      sched/pelt: Fix update_blocked_averages() for RT and DL classes
      sched/fair: Fix scale_rt_capacity() for SMT
      sched/fair: Fix load_balance redo for !imbalance

Vincent Pelletier (1):
      scsi: iscsi: target: Set conn-&amp;gt;sess to NULL when
iscsi_login_set_conn_values fails

Vincent Whitchurch (1):
      tcp: really ignore MSG_ZEROCOPY if no SO_ZEROCOPY

Vitaly Kuznetsov (1):
      xen/manage: don't complain about an empty value in control/sysrq node

Wei Yongjun (2):
      usb: dwc3: pci: Fix return value check in dwc3_byt_enable_ulpi_refclock()
      fpga: dfl: fme: fix return value check in in pr_mgmt_init()

Weinan Li (1):
      drm/i915/gvt: Fix the incorrect length of child_device_config issue

Wenjia Zhang (1):
      s390/qeth: use vzalloc for QUERY OAT buffer

Willem de Bruijn (1):
      tcp: rate limit synflood warnings further

Yabin Cui (1):
      perf/core: Force USER_DS when recording user stack data

Yoshihiro Shimoda (2):
      usb: gadget: udc: renesas_usb3: fix maxpacket size of ep0
      usb: Change usb_of_get_companion_dev() place to usb/common

Yue Haibing (1):
      netfilter: conntrack: remove duplicated include from
nf_conntrack_proto_udp.c

Zhenyu Wang (1):
      drm/i915/gvt: Fix life cycle reference on KVM mm
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://lore.kernel.org/lkml/20180916214226.nmjqk55cxobsjayd@angband.pl/&quot; rel=&quot;next&quot;&gt;next&lt;/a&gt;             &lt;a href=&quot;https://lore.kernel.org/lkml/CA+55aFy+Hv9O5citAawS+mVZO+ywCKd9NQ2wxUmGsz9ZJzqgJQ@mail.gmail.com/#R&quot;&gt;reply&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://lore.kernel.org/lkml/&quot;&gt;index&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;strong&gt;Thread overview: &lt;/strong&gt;9+ messages / expand[&lt;a href=&quot;https://lore.kernel.org/lkml/CA+55aFy+Hv9O5citAawS+mVZO+ywCKd9NQ2wxUmGsz9ZJzqgJQ@mail.gmail.com/T/#u&quot;&gt;flat&lt;/a&gt;|&lt;a href=&quot;https://lore.kernel.org/lkml/CA+55aFy+Hv9O5citAawS+mVZO+ywCKd9NQ2wxUmGsz9ZJzqgJQ@mail.gmail.com/t/#u&quot;&gt;nested&lt;/a&gt;]  &lt;a href=&quot;https://lore.kernel.org/lkml/CA+55aFy+Hv9O5citAawS+mVZO+ywCKd9NQ2wxUmGsz9ZJzqgJQ@mail.gmail.com/t.mbox.gz&quot;&gt;mbox.gz&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;https://lore.kernel.org/lkml/CA+55aFy+Hv9O5citAawS+mVZO+ywCKd9NQ2wxUmGsz9ZJzqgJQ@mail.gmail.com/t.atom&quot;&gt;Atom feed&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;https://lore.kernel.org/lkml/CA+55aFy+Hv9O5citAawS+mVZO+ywCKd9NQ2wxUmGsz9ZJzqgJQ@mail.gmail.com/#b&quot;&gt;top&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;2018-09-16 19:22 &lt;a id=&quot;r&quot; href=&quot;https://lore.kernel.org/lkml/CA+55aFy+Hv9O5citAawS+mVZO+ywCKd9NQ2wxUmGsz9ZJzqgJQ@mail.gmail.com/#t&quot; name=&quot;r&quot;&gt;Linus Torvalds [this message]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
2018-09-16 21:42 ` &lt;a href=&quot;https://lore.kernel.org/lkml/20180916214226.nmjqk55cxobsjayd@angband.pl/&quot;&gt;[...]&lt;/a&gt; &quot; Adam Borowski
2018-09-16 23:59   ` &lt;a href=&quot;https://lore.kernel.org/lkml/15434a7a-d411-435e-5f3a-3006c0522c88@bluebirdmountain.de/&quot;&gt;Moritz Obermeier&lt;/a&gt;
2018-09-17  0:18 ` &lt;a href=&quot;https://lore.kernel.org/lkml/20180917001813.15290-1-rene.herman@gmail.com/&quot;&gt;Linux 4.19-rc4 released,&lt;/a&gt; &quot; Rene Herman
2018-09-17  0:20 ` &lt;a href=&quot;https://lore.kernel.org/lkml/20180917002021.GA8515@hexapodia.org/&quot;&gt;[...]&lt;/a&gt; &quot; Andy Isaacson
2018-09-17  0:23 ` &lt;a href=&quot;https://lore.kernel.org/lkml/20180917002342.15342-1-rene.herman@gmail.com/&quot;&gt;Linux 4.19-rc4 released,&lt;/a&gt; &quot; Rene Herman
2018-09-17  6:57 ` &lt;a href=&quot;https://lore.kernel.org/lkml/20180917065712.45d321f9@clamav.local/&quot;&gt;opal hart&lt;/a&gt;
2018-09-17  7:57 ` &lt;a href=&quot;https://lore.kernel.org/lkml/2882117.Jnuu2veLAZ@merkaba/&quot;&gt;[…]&lt;/a&gt; &quot; Martin Steigerwald
2018-09-17  2:15 &lt;a href=&quot;https://lore.kernel.org/lkml/CAPweEDwKzoxoVFSNbSnsHtqNhxB+AbdjD9XMXW0MEwNPGdr3Xg@mail.gmail.com/&quot;&gt;Linux 4.19-rc4 released,&lt;/a&gt; &quot; Luke Kenneth Casson Leighton
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;pre id=&quot;R&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Reply instructions:&lt;/strong&gt;

You may reply publically to &lt;a href=&quot;https://lore.kernel.org/lkml/CA+55aFy+Hv9O5citAawS+mVZO+ywCKd9NQ2wxUmGsz9ZJzqgJQ@mail.gmail.com/#t&quot;&gt;this message&lt;/a&gt; via plain-text email
using any one of the following methods:

* Save the following mbox file, import it into your mail client,
  and reply-to-all from there: &lt;a href=&quot;https://lore.kernel.org/lkml/CA+55aFy+Hv9O5citAawS+mVZO+ywCKd9NQ2wxUmGsz9ZJzqgJQ@mail.gmail.com/raw&quot;&gt;mbox&lt;/a&gt;

  Avoid top-posting and favor interleaved quoting:
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Posting_style#Interleaved_style&quot;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Posting_style#Interleaved_style&lt;/a&gt;

* Reply using the &lt;strong&gt;--to&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;--cc&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;--in-reply-to&lt;/strong&gt;
  switches of git-send-email(1):

  git send-email \
    --in-reply-to=CA+55aFy+Hv9O5citAawS+mVZO+ywCKd9NQ2wxUmGsz9ZJzqgJQ@mail.gmail.com \
    --to=torvalds@linux-foundation.org \
    --cc=linux-kernel@vger.kernel.org \
    /path/to/YOUR_REPLY

  &lt;a href=&quot;https://kernel.org/pub/software/scm/git/docs/git-send-email.html&quot;&gt;https://kernel.org/pub/software/scm/git/docs/git-send-email.html&lt;/a&gt;

* If your mail client supports setting the &lt;strong&gt;In-Reply-To&lt;/strong&gt; header
  via mailto: links, try the &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:torvalds%40linux-foundation.org?In-Reply-To=%3CCA+55aFy+Hv9O5citAawS+mVZO+ywCKd9NQ2wxUmGsz9ZJzqgJQ@mail.gmail.com%3E&amp;amp;Cc=linux-kernel%40vger.kernel.org&amp;amp;Subject=Re%3A%20Linux%204.19-rc4%20released%2C%20an%20apology%2C%20and%20a%20maintainership%20note&quot;&gt;mailto: link&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;pre&gt;
LKML Archive on lore.kernel.org

Archives are clonable:
        git clone --mirror https://lore.kernel.org/lkml/0 lkml/git/0.git
        git clone --mirror https://lore.kernel.org/lkml/1 lkml/git/1.git
        git clone --mirror https://lore.kernel.org/lkml/2 lkml/git/2.git
        git clone --mirror https://lore.kernel.org/lkml/3 lkml/git/3.git
        git clone --mirror https://lore.kernel.org/lkml/4 lkml/git/4.git
        git clone --mirror https://lore.kernel.org/lkml/5 lkml/git/5.git
        git clone --mirror https://lore.kernel.org/lkml/6 lkml/git/6.git

        # If you have public-inbox 1.1+ installed, you may
        # initialize and index your mirror using the following commands:
        public-inbox-init -V2 lkml lkml/ https://lore.kernel.org/lkml \
                linux-kernel@vger.kernel.org linux-kernel@archiver.kernel.org
        public-inbox-index lkml


Newsgroup available over NNTP:
        &lt;a href=&quot;nntp://nntp.lore.kernel.org/org.kernel.vger.linux-kernel&quot;&gt;nntp://nntp.lore.kernel.org/org.kernel.vger.linux-kernel&lt;/a&gt;


AGPL code for this site: git clone &lt;a href=&quot;https://public-inbox.org/&quot;&gt;https://public-inbox.org/&lt;/a&gt; public-inbox
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 19:44:57 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>fejkp</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://lore.kernel.org/lkml/CA+55aFy+Hv9O5citAawS+mVZO+ywCKd9NQ2wxUmGsz9ZJzqgJQ@mail.gmail.com/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Apple Lightning Connector Serial Access (2015)</title>
<link>http://ramtin-amin.fr/#tristar</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://ramtin-amin.fr/#tristar</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;navbar navbar-inverse navbar-fixed-top&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;navbar-inner&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;container&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;btn btn-navbar&quot; data-toggle=&quot;collapse&quot; data-target=&quot;.nav-collapse&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;icon-bar&quot;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;icon-bar&quot;&gt;b&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;icon-bar&quot;&gt;c&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;brand&quot; href=&quot;http://ramtin-amin.fr/#&quot;&gt;Ramtin Amin&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;nav-collapse collapse&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;nav&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;active&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ramtin-amin.fr/#home&quot; onclick=&quot;loadpage('home.html')&quot;&gt;Home&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ramtin-amin.fr/#About&quot; onclick=&quot;loadpage('about.html')&quot;&gt;About&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ramtin-amin.fr/#contact&quot; onclick=&quot;loadpage('contact.html')&quot;&gt;Contact&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/key2fr&quot; class=&quot;twitter-follow-button&quot; data-show-count=&quot;false&quot; data-size=&quot;large&quot;&gt;Follow @key2fr&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;container&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;span3&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;FemtoCell&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ramtin-amin.fr/#femto_ubi2&quot; onclick=&quot;loadpage('femto_ubi2.html');&quot;&gt;Ubiquisys v2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ramtin-amin.fr/#femto_ubi&quot; onclick=&quot;loadpage('femto_ubi.html');&quot;&gt;Ubiquisys v1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ramtin-amin.fr/#femto_voda&quot; onclick=&quot;loadpage('femto_voda.html');&quot;&gt;Vodaphone&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Nand Dumping&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ramtin-amin.fr/#bga_unsolder&quot; onclick=&quot;loadpage('bga_unsolder.html');&quot;&gt;BGA Unsoldering&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ramtin-amin.fr/#in_situ&quot; onclick=&quot;loadpage('in_situ.html');&quot;&gt;In Situs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;SIM Card&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ramtin-amin.fr/#sim_mitm&quot; onclick=&quot;loadpage('sim_mitm.html');&quot;&gt;Man in the middle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ramtin-amin.fr/#sim_emul&quot; onclick=&quot;loadpage('sim_emul.html');&quot;&gt;Emulation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Misc&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ramtin-amin.fr/#fairplay&quot; onclick=&quot;loadpage('fairplay.html');&quot;&gt;Fairplay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ramtin-amin.fr/#kalmia&quot; onclick=&quot;loadpage('kalmia.html');&quot;&gt;Samsung LTE USB Dongle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ramtin-amin.fr/#tristar&quot; onclick=&quot;loadpage('tristar.html');&quot;&gt;Apple Lightning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ramtin-amin.fr/#nvmepcie&quot; onclick=&quot;loadpage('nvmepcie.html');&quot;&gt;Apple NVMe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ramtin-amin.fr/#nvmedma&quot; onclick=&quot;loadpage('nvmedma.html');&quot;&gt;iPhone PCIe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Telco protocol&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ramtin-amin.fr/#umagan&quot; onclick=&quot;loadpage('umagan.html');&quot;&gt;Uma / Gan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ramtin-amin.fr/#apsd&quot; onclick=&quot;loadpage('apsd.html');&quot;&gt;Apple Push&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ramtin-amin.fr/#epc_dissector&quot; onclick=&quot;loadpage('epc_dissector.html');&quot;&gt;4G EPC Wireshark Dissector&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;span9&quot;&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 16:24:46 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>walterbell</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://ramtin-amin.fr/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ask HN: Favorite teachers on YouTube?</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17999659</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17999659</guid>
<description>&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.55737704918033&quot;&gt;&lt;td bgcolor=&quot;#FF6600&quot;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.5824847250509&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table class=&quot;fatitem&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.9368635437882&quot;&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing&quot; id=&quot;17999659&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;right&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;title&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17999659&quot; class=&quot;storylink&quot;&gt;Ask HN: Favorite teachers on YouTube?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.75&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;subtext&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;score&quot; id=&quot;score_17999659&quot;&gt;558 points&lt;/span&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/user?id=akudha&quot; class=&quot;hnuser&quot;&gt;akudha&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;age&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17999659&quot;&gt;15 hours ago&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span id=&quot;unv_17999659&quot;/&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/hide?id=17999659&amp;amp;goto=item%3Fid%3D17999659&quot;&gt;hide&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://hn.algolia.com/?query=Ask%20HN%3A%20Favorite%20teachers%20on%20YouTube%3F&amp;amp;sort=byDate&amp;amp;dateRange=all&amp;amp;type=story&amp;amp;storyText=false&amp;amp;prefix&amp;amp;page=0&quot; class=&quot;hnpast&quot;&gt;past&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=Ask%20HN%3A%20Favorite%20teachers%20on%20YouTube%3F&quot;&gt;web&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/fave?id=17999659&amp;amp;auth=d5a801efcb02d3e051a0d9b55f2104a3a175957e&quot;&gt;favorite&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17999659&quot;&gt;152 comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;9.5&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;Currently I am watching Daniel Shiffman (example : https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_p5IH0L63wo) and I really like his enthusiasm. I've watched a whole bunch of high production, paid courses (udemy, udacity etc) and somehow Shiffman's free videos are more fun to watch and learn.
&lt;p&gt;Any other teachers you like? Doesn't need to be math or computers, other subjects welcome too&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td&gt;

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.73972602739726&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ycombinator.com/apply/&quot;&gt;Applications are open for YC Winter 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;yclinks&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/newsguidelines.html&quot;&gt;Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/newsfaq.html&quot;&gt;FAQ&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:hn@ycombinator.com&quot;&gt;Support&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/HackerNews/API&quot;&gt;API&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/security.html&quot;&gt;Security&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/lists&quot;&gt;Lists&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/bookmarklet.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Bookmarklet&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ycombinator.com/legal/&quot;&gt;Legal&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ycombinator.com/apply/&quot;&gt;Apply to YC&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:hn@ycombinator.com&quot;&gt;Contact&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 16:19:07 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>akudha</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17999659</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Amazon Investigates Employees Leaking Data for Bribes</title>
<link>https://www.wsj.com/articles/amazon-investigates-employees-leaking-data-for-bribes-1537106401</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.wsj.com/articles/amazon-investigates-employees-leaking-data-for-bribes-1537106401</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;is-lead-inset&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div data-layout=&quot;header&amp;#10;              &quot; data-layout-mobile=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;&amp;#10;        media-object&amp;#10;        article__inset&amp;#10;        type-InsetMediaIllustration&amp;#10;          header article__inset--header&amp;#10;  &quot;&gt;
      
      
          
    &lt;div class=&quot;media-object-image enlarge-image renoImageFormat- img-header article__inset__image&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/ImageObject&quot;&gt;
    
      
      &lt;div data-mobile-ratio=&quot;66.66666666666666%&quot; data-layout-ratio=&quot;66.66666666666666%&quot; data-subtype=&quot;photo&quot; class=&quot;image-container  responsive-media article__inset__image__image&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img srcset=&quot;https://images.wsj.net/im-26450?width=140&amp;amp;aspect_ratio=1.5 140w,&amp;#10;https://images.wsj.net/im-26450?width=540&amp;amp;aspect_ratio=1.5 540w,&amp;#10;https://images.wsj.net/im-26450?width=620&amp;amp;aspect_ratio=1.5 620w,&amp;#10;https://images.wsj.net/im-26450?width=700&amp;amp;aspect_ratio=1.5 700w,&amp;#10;https://images.wsj.net/im-26450?width=860&amp;amp;aspect_ratio=1.5 860w,&amp;#10;https://images.wsj.net/im-26450?width=1260&amp;amp;aspect_ratio=1.5 1260w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 140px) 100px,&amp;#10;(max-width: 540px) 500px,&amp;#10;(max-width: 620px) 580px,&amp;#10;(max-width: 700px) 660px,&amp;#10;(max-width: 860px) 820px,&amp;#10;1260px&quot; src=&quot;https://images.wsj.net/im-26450?width=620&amp;amp;aspect_ratio=1.5&quot; data-enlarge=&quot;https://images.wsj.net/im-26450?width=1260&amp;amp;aspect_ratio=1.5&quot; alt=&quot;Internal corruption is the latest challenge Amazon faces in upholding its platform’s integrity.&quot; title=&quot;Internal corruption is the latest challenge Amazon faces in upholding its platform’s integrity.&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
      &lt;div class=&quot;wsj-article-caption article__inset__image__caption&quot; itemprop=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;wsj-article-caption-content&quot;&gt;Internal corruption is the latest challenge Amazon faces in upholding its platform’s integrity.&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;wsj-article-credit&quot; itemprop=&quot;creator&quot;&gt;
          &lt;span class=&quot;wsj-article-credit-tag&quot;&gt;
            Photo: 
          &lt;/span&gt;
          Matt Alexander/Zuma Press
        &lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      &lt;/div&gt; 
    &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;clearfix byline-wrap&quot;&gt;


    

        
    &lt;div class=&quot;byline article__byline&quot;&gt;
    
    
        &lt;span&gt;By&lt;/span&gt;
    
              &lt;div class=&quot;author mobile-scrim hasMenu&quot; data-scrim=&quot;{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;author&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;header&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Jon Emont&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;subhead&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;The Wall Street Journal&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;list&amp;quot;:[{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;icon&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;bio&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.wsj.com/news/author/8732&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Biography&amp;quot;},{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;icon&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;twitter&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;http://twitter.com/JonathanEmont&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;@JonathanEmont&amp;quot;},{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;icon&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;email&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;mailto:jonathan.emont@wsj.com&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;jonathan.emont@wsj.com&amp;quot;}]}&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemprop=&quot;author&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/Person&quot;&gt;
                  &lt;span class=&quot;name&quot; itemprop=&quot;name&quot;&gt;Jon Emont&lt;/span&gt; in Hong Kong and 
                  &lt;/div&gt;

              &lt;div class=&quot;author mobile-scrim hasMenu&quot; data-scrim=&quot;{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;author&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;header&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Laura Stevens&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;subhead&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;The Wall Street Journal&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;list&amp;quot;:[{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;icon&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;bio&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.wsj.com/news/author/7516&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Biography&amp;quot;},{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;icon&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;twitter&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;http://twitter.com/laurastevenswsj&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;@laurastevenswsj&amp;quot;},{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;icon&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;facebook&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;http://facebook.com/laurastevens11&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;laurastevens11&amp;quot;},{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;icon&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;google&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://plus.google.com/?gpsrc=gplp0&amp;amp;partnerid=gplp0#117310352307792952773/posts&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Google+&amp;quot;},{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;icon&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;email&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;mailto:Laura.Stevens@wsj.com&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Laura.Stevens@wsj.com&amp;quot;}]}&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemprop=&quot;author&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/Person&quot;&gt;
                  &lt;span class=&quot;name&quot; itemprop=&quot;name&quot;&gt;Laura Stevens&lt;/span&gt; and 
                  &lt;/div&gt;

              &lt;div class=&quot;author mobile-scrim hasMenu&quot; data-scrim=&quot;{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;author&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;header&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Robert McMillan&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;subhead&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;The Wall Street Journal&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;list&amp;quot;:[{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;icon&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;bio&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.wsj.com/news/author/8244&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Biography&amp;quot;},{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;icon&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;twitter&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;http://twitter.com/bobmcmillan&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;@bobmcmillan&amp;quot;},{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;icon&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;facebook&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;http://facebook.com/therealrobertmcmillan&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;therealrobertmcmillan&amp;quot;},{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;icon&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;email&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;mailto:robert.mcmillan@wsj.com&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;robert.mcmillan@wsj.com&amp;quot;}]}&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemprop=&quot;author&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/Person&quot;&gt;
                  &lt;span class=&quot;name&quot; itemprop=&quot;name&quot;&gt;Robert McMillan&lt;/span&gt; in San Francisco
                  &lt;/div&gt;

    &lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;time class=&quot;timestamp article__timestamp flexbox__flex--1&quot;&gt;
      Updated Sept. 16, 2018 9:43 p.m. ET
    &lt;/time&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

  

  &lt;div class=&quot;article-content &quot;&gt;

      &lt;p&gt;






            &lt;a href=&quot;http://quotes.wsj.com/AMZN&quot;&gt;Amazon.com&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;company-name-type&quot;&gt; Inc.&lt;/span&gt;

      &lt;a href=&quot;http://quotes.wsj.com/AMZN?mod=chiclets&quot; class=&quot;media-object-chiclet down &quot; data-channel=&quot;/quotes/zigman/63011/composite&quot; data-symbol=&quot;AMZN&quot; data-changepercent=&quot;-0.99&quot;&gt;
        AMZN &lt;span&gt;-0.99%&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;

      is investigating suspected data leaks and bribes of its employees as it fights to root out fake reviews and other seller scams from its website.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;Employees of Amazon, primarily with the aid of intermediaries, are offering internal data and other confidential information that can give an edge to independent merchants selling their products on the site, according to sellers who have been offered and purchased the data, as well as brokers who provide it and people familiar with internal investigations.&lt;/p&gt;




      




      &lt;p&gt;The practice, which violates company policy, is particularly pronounced in China, according to some of these people, because the number of sellers there is skyrocketing. As well, Amazon employees in China have relatively small salaries, which might embolden them to take risks.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;div class=&quot;paywall&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;In exchange for payments ranging from about $80 to more than $2,000, brokers for Amazon employees in Shenzhen are offering internal sales metrics and reviewers’ email addresses, as well as a service to delete negative reviews and restore banned Amazon accounts, the people said. &lt;/p&gt;






       




      &lt;p&gt;Amazon is investigating a number of incidents involving employees, including some in the U.S., suspected of accepting these bribes, according to people familiar with the matter. An internal probe began in May after Eric Broussard,  Amazon’s vice president who oversees international marketplaces, was tipped off to the practice in China, people familiar with the matter said. Amazon has since shuffled the roles of key executives in China to try to root out the bribery, one of these people said.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;Internally, Amazon has worked hard to stop sellers from gaming its systems, but it can sometimes be a Whac-A-Mole situation as swindlers get more creative, according to former Amazon executives and other people familiar with the company’s thinking.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;An Amazon spokeswoman said the company has strict policies and a code of business conduct and ethics, and it has installed systems to restrict and audit what employees can access.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;The company confirmed it is investigating the claims. “We hold our employees to a high ethical standard and anyone in violation of our Code faces discipline, including termination and potential legal and criminal penalties,” the spokeswoman added in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;That goes for sellers, too. “We have zero tolerance for abuse of our systems and if we find bad actors who have engaged in this behavior, we will take swift action against them,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;Potential internal corruption is the latest challenge Amazon faces in upholding its platform’s integrity, after well-publicized problems with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/how-sellers-trick-amazon-to-boost-sales-1532750493?mod=article_inline&quot; class=&quot;icon none&quot;&gt;fake product reviews &lt;/a&gt;and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/on-amazon-fake-products-plague-smaller-brands-1532001601?mod=article_inline&quot; class=&quot;icon none&quot;&gt;counterfeit merchandise&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;For the past few years, Amazon has recruited independent merchants to sell their products on the company’s marketplace, something that both widens the variety of products offered on the site and reduces prices. More than two million merchants now sell an estimated 550 million products on Amazon, representing more than half of all units sold on the site and contributing an estimated $200 billion in gross merchandise volume last year, according to FactSet estimates.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;Sellers must aggressively compete to get their products noticed on the first page of search results, where customers typically make most of their purchase decisions.&lt;/p&gt;






      &lt;div data-layout=&quot;inline&amp;#10;              &quot; data-layout-mobile=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;&amp;#10;        media-object&amp;#10;        article__inset&amp;#10;        type-InsetDynamic&amp;#10;          inline article__inset--inline&amp;#10;    scope-web|mobileapps&amp;#10;  &quot;&gt;
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
        &lt;div class=&quot;dynamic-inset-container&quot;&gt;
              
&lt;/div&gt;

      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      &lt;/div&gt; 




      &lt;p&gt;Amazon’s automated system ranks the products based on several factors, including the quality of verified reviews, the number of times customers click on a product and its sales volume. Some sellers have sought to game the system by employing tricks such as paying someone to click repeatedly on a listing or create fake positive reviews, The Wall Street Journal has reported. Amazon has fought these attempts.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;One of the newer ways some sellers are seeking an edge over rivals is getting access to Amazon employees.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;Some midlevel Amazon employees in China have the power to delete negative reviews and can access the email addresses of users who have purchased specific items and written reviews of them, said a person who has facilitated illicit transactions between third-party sellers and Amazon employees in southern China.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;Brokers are the middlemen between Amazon employees and sellers who want negative reviews deleted or access to internal sales information. Brokers search for Amazon employees on Chinese messaging platform






            &lt;a href=&quot;http://quotes.wsj.com/TCEHY&quot;&gt;WeChat&lt;/a&gt;
            


      and send messages asking them if they would like to provide these services in exchange for cash, according to brokers and sellers who say they have been approached by brokers.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;The going rate for having an Amazon employee delete negative reviews is about $300 per review, according to people familiar with the practice. Brokers usually demand a five-review minimum, meaning that sellers typically must pay at least $1,500 for the service, the people said.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;For less money, sellers can buy from Amazon employees the email addresses of customers who write reviews. This gives sellers the opportunity to reach out to customers who have written negative reviews and try to persuade them to adjust or delete those reviews, sometimes by offering free or discounted products, the sellers and brokers say. Amazon prohibits this practice.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;Brokers also offer proprietary sales information, such as the keywords customers typically use to search for items on Amazon’s site, sales volume and other statistics about buyers’ habits, according to the people. Having this information enables Amazon sellers to craft product descriptions and advertisements in a way that boosts their rankings in search results. Amazon doesn’t disclose this type of detailed sales information.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;At a recent conference hosted for sellers—which wasn’t run by Amazon—a broker pulled up internal keyword results on his laptop. The broker said $80 can buy information on sales data; the number of times users searched for a certain product and clicked on a product page; which sellers are bidding for advertisements; and how much those cost, according to the person who viewed the results.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;One Chinese Amazon seller said competition on the website had become so heated that he is tempted to use illicit tactics to gain an edge. “If I don’t do bad things, I will die,” he said of his business.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Write to &lt;/strong&gt;Jon Emont at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:jonathan.emont@wsj.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;icon &quot;&gt;jonathan.emont@wsj.com&lt;/a&gt;, Laura Stevens at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:laura.stevens@wsj.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;icon &quot;&gt;laura.stevens@wsj.com&lt;/a&gt; and Robert McMillan at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:Robert.Mcmillan@wsj.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;icon &quot;&gt;Robert.Mcmillan@wsj.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;/div&gt;



  &lt;/div&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 15:09:40 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ikeboy</dc:creator>
<og:title>Amazon Investigates Employees Leaking Data for Bribes</og:title>
<og:description>Amazon.com is investigating suspected data leaks and bribes of its employees as it fights to root out fake reviews and other seller scams from its website.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.wsj.com/articles/amazon-investigates-employees-leaking-data-for-bribes-1537106401</og:url>
<og:image>https://images.wsj.net/im-26450/social</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.wsj.com/articles/amazon-investigates-employees-leaking-data-for-bribes-1537106401</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Getting started with Tmux</title>
<link>https://linuxize.com/post/getting-started-with-tmux/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://linuxize.com/post/getting-started-with-tmux/</guid>
<description>&lt;aside class=&quot;aside-wrapper relative&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;This guide will go through the installation and basic usage of Tmux to get you up and running.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-tmux&quot;&gt;What is tmux?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tmux is a terminal multiplexer an alternative to &lt;a href=&quot;https://linuxize.com/post/how-to-use-linux-screen/&quot;&gt;GNU Screen&lt;/a&gt;. In other words, it means that you can start a Tmux session and then open multiple windows inside that session. Each window occupies the entire screen and can be splitted into rectangular panes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Tmux you can easily switch between multiple programs in one terminal, detach them and reattach them to a different terminal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tmux sessions are persistent which means that programs running in Tmux will continue to run even if you get disconnected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All commands in Tmux start with a prefix, which by default is &lt;code&gt;ctrl+b&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;installing-tmux&quot;&gt;Installing Tmux&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can easily install Tmux using the package manager of your distro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;installing-tmux-on-ubuntu-and-debian&quot;&gt;Installing Tmux on Ubuntu and Debian&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;chroma&quot;&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;sudo apt install tmux&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;installing-tmux-on-centos-and-fedora&quot;&gt;Installing Tmux on CentOS and Fedora&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;chroma&quot;&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;sudo yum install tmux&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;installing-tmux-on-macos&quot;&gt;Installing Tmux on macOS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;chroma&quot;&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;brew install tmux&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;starting-your-first-tmux-session&quot;&gt;Starting Your First Tmux Session&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To start your first Tmux session, simply type &lt;code&gt;tmux&lt;/code&gt; in your console:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will open a new session, create a new window and start a shell in that window.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you are in Tmux you’ll notice a status line at the bottom of the screen which shows information about the current session.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can now run your first Tmux command. For example to get a list of all commands you would type:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Ctrl+b&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;?&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;creating-named-tmux-sessions&quot;&gt;Creating Named Tmux Sessions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By default Tmux sessions are named numerically. Named sessions are useful when you run multiple tmux sessions. To create a new named session, run the &lt;code&gt;tmux&lt;/code&gt; command with the following arguments:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;chroma&quot;&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;tmux new -s session_name&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s always a good idea to choose a descriptive session name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;detaching-from-tmux-session&quot;&gt;Detaching from Tmux Session&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can detach from the Tmux session and return to your normal shell by typing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Ctrl+a&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;d&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The program running in the Tmux session will continue to run after you detach from the session.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;re-attaching-to-tmux-session&quot;&gt;Re-attaching to Tmux Session&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To attach a session first you need to find the name of the session. To get a list of the current running sessions type:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The name of the session is the first column of the output.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;chroma&quot;&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-output&quot; data-lang=&quot;output&quot;&gt;0: 1 windows (created Sat Sep 15 09:38:43 2018) [158x35]
my_named_session: 1 windows (created Sat Sep 15 10:13:11 2018) [78x35]&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see from the output, there are two running Tmux sessions, the first one is named &lt;code&gt;0&lt;/code&gt; and the second one &lt;code&gt;my_named_session&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, to attach to the session &lt;code&gt;0&lt;/code&gt; we would type:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;chroma&quot;&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;tmux attach-session -t &lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;working-with-tmux-windows-and-panes&quot;&gt;Working with Tmux Windows and Panes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you start a new tmux session by default it creates a single window with a shell in it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To create a new window with shell type &lt;code&gt;Ctrl+a&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;c&lt;/code&gt;, the first available number from the range &lt;code&gt;0...9&lt;/code&gt; will be assigned to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A list of all windows is shown on the status line at the bottom of the screen .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bellow are some most common commands for managing Tmux windows and panes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Ctrl+b&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;c&lt;/code&gt; Create a new window (with shell)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Ctrl+b&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;w&lt;/code&gt; Choose window from a list&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Ctrl+b&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;0&lt;/code&gt; Switch to window 0 (by number )&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Ctrl+b&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;,&lt;/code&gt; Rename the current window&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Ctrl+b&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;%&lt;/code&gt; Split current pane horizontally into two panes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Ctrl+b&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;&quot;&lt;/code&gt; Split current pane vertically into two panes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Ctrl+b&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;o&lt;/code&gt; Go to the next pane&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Ctrl+b&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;;&lt;/code&gt; Toggle between current and previous pane&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Ctrl+b&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;x&lt;/code&gt; Close the current pane&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;small class=&quot;text-grey&quot;&gt;&lt;small&gt;Advertisement&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;customizing-tmux&quot;&gt;Customizing Tmux&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Tmux is started it reads its configuration parameters from &lt;code&gt;~/.tmux.conf&lt;/code&gt; if the file is present.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a sample &lt;code&gt;~/.tmux.conf&lt;/code&gt; configuration with customized status line and few additional options:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;~/.tmux.conf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;chroma&quot;&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-tmux&quot; data-lang=&quot;tmux&quot;&gt;# Improve colors
set -g default-terminal 'screen-256color'

# Set scrollback buffer to 10000
set -g history-limit 10000

# Customize the status line
set -g status-fg  green
set -g status-bg  black&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;w-full mx-auto relative block my-0&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;w-full h-full absolute m-auto pin overflow-hidden text-center&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://linuxize.com/post/getting-started-with-tmux/tmux-terminal.jpg&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;basic-tmux-usage&quot;&gt;Basic Tmux Usage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below are the most basic steps for getting started with Tmux:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;On the command prompt, type &lt;code&gt;tmux new -s my_session&lt;/code&gt;,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run the desired program.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use the key sequence &lt;code&gt;Ctrl-b&lt;/code&gt; + &lt;code&gt;d&lt;/code&gt; to detach from the session.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reattach to the Tmux session by typing &lt;code&gt;tmux attach-session -t my_session&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial, you learned how to use Tmux. Now you can start creating multiple Tmux windows in a single session, split windows by creating new panes, navigate between windows, detach and resume sessions and personalize your Tmux instance using the &lt;code&gt;.tmux.conf&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s lots more to learn about Tmux at &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/OpenBSD-current/man1/tmux.1&quot;&gt;Tmux User’s Manual&lt;/a&gt; page.&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 12:42:36 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>eaguyhn</dc:creator>
<og:title>Getting started with Tmux</og:title>
<og:description>Tmux is a terminal multiplexer an alternative to GNU Screen. In other words, it means that you can start a Tmux session and then open multiple windows inside that session. Each window occupies the entire screen and can be splitted into rectangular panes.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>/post/getting-started-with-tmux/</og:url>
<og:image>https://linuxize.com/post/getting-started-with-tmux/featured.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://linuxize.com/post/getting-started-with-tmux/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>A new CSS-based web attack will crash and restart your iPhone</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2018/09/15/a-new-css-based-web-attack-will-crash-and-restart-your-iphone/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2018/09/15/a-new-css-based-web-attack-will-crash-and-restart-your-iphone/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;A security researcher has found a new way to crash and restart any iPhone — with just a few lines of code.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sabri Haddouche tweeted &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/pwnsdx/status/1040944750973595649&quot;&gt;a proof-of-concept&lt;/a&gt; webpage with just 15 lines of code which, if visited, will crash and restart an iPhone or iPad. Those on macOS may also see Safari freeze when opening the link.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The code exploits a weakness in iOS’ web rendering engine WebKit, which &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://crunchbase.com/organization/apple&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;apple&quot;&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt; mandates all apps and browsers use, Haddouche told TechCrunch. He explained that nesting a ton of elements — such as &lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; tags — inside a backdrop filter property in CSS, you can use up all of the device’s resources and cause a kernel panic, which shuts down and restarts the operating system to prevent damage.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Anything that renders HTML on iOS is affected,” he said. That means anyone sending you a link on Facebook or Twitter, or if any webpage you visit includes the code, or anyone sending you an email, he warned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;26.833333333333&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TechCrunch tested the exploit running on the most recent mobile software iOS 11.4.1, and confirm it crashes and restarts the phone. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/thomasareed&quot;&gt;Thomas Reed&lt;/a&gt;, director of Mac &amp;amp; Mobile at security firm Malwarebytes confirmed that  the most recent iOS 12 beta also froze when tapping the link.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lucky whose devices won’t crash may just see their device restart (or “respring”) the user interface instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those curious, you can &lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/pwnsdx/ce64de2760996a6c432f06d612e33aea&quot;&gt;see how it works&lt;/a&gt; without it running the crash-inducing code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The good news is that as annoying as this attack is, it can’t be used to run malicious code, he said, meaning malware can’t run and data can’t be stolen using this attack. But there’s no easy way to prevent the attack from working. One tap on a booby-trapped link sent in a message or opening an HTML email that renders the code can crash the device instantly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Haddouche contacted Apple on Friday about the attack, which is said to be investigating. A spokesperson did not immediately respond to a request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 06:20:01 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>MrCzar</dc:creator>
<og:title>A new CSS-based web attack will crash and restart your iPhone</og:title>
<og:description>A security researcher has found a new way to crash and restart any iPhone — with just a few lines of code. Sabri Haddouche tweeted a proof-of-concept webpage with just 15 lines of code which, if visited, will crash and restart an iPhone or iPad. Those on macOS may also see Safari freeze when openin…</og:description>
<og:image>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/GettyImages-10099498321.jpg?w=600</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2018/09/15/a-new-css-based-web-attack-will-crash-and-restart-your-iphone/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2018/09/15/a-new-css-based-web-attack-will-crash-and-restart-your-iphone/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Was ditching the headphone jack a good idea?</title>
<link>https://www.soundguys.com/was-ditching-the-headphone-jack-a-good-idea-13825/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.soundguys.com/was-ditching-the-headphone-jack-a-good-idea-13825/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;With the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.androidauthority.com/apple-iphone-xs-xs-max-iphone-xr-apple-watch-903491/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;new iPhones coming out today&lt;/a&gt;, I wanted to revisit the whole Apple vs. headphone jack fiasco. If you’re reading this article, you’ve probably got some strong opinions on this one—as do I. However, I want to approach this topic as a matter-of-fact discussion of the industry and not simply a venting of frustrations. We’re going to answer the title of this article in plain terms with little room for debate. As this article is like the countless others that follow &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Betteridge%27s_law_of_headlines&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Betteridge’s law of headlines&lt;/a&gt;, Journalism wonks already know the answer to that question: but it’s a subject worthy of complete exploration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You see, I’m very disturbed by the trend of Android manufacturers affirming the false notion that Apple is a “tech leader” in ditching what is easily the cheapest, best, and most-used solution to audio on the go: &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Phone_connector_(audio)&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;The TRRS connector&lt;/a&gt;. While it’s understandable that many look to Apple as a leader in the tech world, in this case the headphone jack fiasco was nothing more than an attempt at a hostile takeover of the headphone industry, and Android may be the only thing standing in the way of that.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The main question here has several parts to it, so we should define some key ideas. Namely, we need to know:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;What makes a good phone?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What’s the benefit of a headphone jack?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is Bluetooth good enough to replace it?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why would Apple ditch it?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’ll try to answer these as briefly as possible, but some of these need to be truncated for readability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Editor’s note: this article was updated September 13, 2018 to reflect updates in Apple’s business strategy.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What makes a good smartphone?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_13840&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption alignright&quot; readability=&quot;34&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/apple-iphone-headphone-jack-bluetooth-early-man-tools.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-medium wp-image-13840&quot; src=&quot;https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/apple-iphone-headphone-jack-bluetooth-early-man-tools-251x300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;An illustration of the early hand-axes created by Homo Erectus.&quot; width=&quot;251&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/apple-iphone-headphone-jack-bluetooth-early-man-tools-251x300.jpg 251w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/apple-iphone-headphone-jack-bluetooth-early-man-tools-768x917.jpg 768w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/apple-iphone-headphone-jack-bluetooth-early-man-tools-858x1024.jpg 858w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/apple-iphone-headphone-jack-bluetooth-early-man-tools-13x16.jpg 13w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/apple-iphone-headphone-jack-bluetooth-early-man-tools-27x32.jpg 27w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/apple-iphone-headphone-jack-bluetooth-early-man-tools-23x28.jpg 23w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/apple-iphone-headphone-jack-bluetooth-early-man-tools-47x56.jpg 47w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/apple-iphone-headphone-jack-bluetooth-early-man-tools-54x64.jpg 54w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/apple-iphone-headphone-jack-bluetooth-early-man-tools-1000x1194.jpg 1000w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/apple-iphone-headphone-jack-bluetooth-early-man-tools-1200x1433.jpg 1200w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/apple-iphone-headphone-jack-bluetooth-early-man-tools-419x500.jpg 419w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/apple-iphone-headphone-jack-bluetooth-early-man-tools-243x290.jpg 243w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/apple-iphone-headphone-jack-bluetooth-early-man-tools-385x460.jpg 385w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/apple-iphone-headphone-jack-bluetooth-early-man-tools-335x400.jpg 335w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/apple-iphone-headphone-jack-bluetooth-early-man-tools-197x235.jpg 197w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/apple-iphone-headphone-jack-bluetooth-early-man-tools.jpg 1226w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 251px) 100vw, 251px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Early hand-axes created by Homo Erectus. Like smartphones, their users cared only if they worked—and threw them out if they didn’t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stick with me, I’m going somewhere with this. When you want to do something that can’t be accomplished by just your words or hands, humans use tools. Tools to eat, tools to create, tools to destroy—we rely on the use of machines to accomplish most of the tasks we set out to accomplish in a day, and that’s how it’s been for millennia. Tools are an extension of the human experience at this point, and it’s no wonder: we simply can’t reach the heights we’re at now without mechanical help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A full 2.5 million years after the first tools created by &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://humanorigins.si.edu/evidence/human-fossils/species/australopithecus-garhi&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Australopithecus garhi&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; our tools perform stupendously complicated tasks—often thousands at once. While the capabilities of our tools have exploded past the wildest dreams of our early ancestors, the core metric by which we assess their quality hasn’t: &lt;em&gt;Do they perform their task well?&lt;/em&gt; If the tool you hold in your hand can’t perform the function you want it to, it’s the wrong tool for the job… or it’s a bad tool. You don’t use pencils that can’t write, or an air conditioner that can’t cool, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enter the smartphone. In the short time it’s been on Earth, it’s probably one of the most useful and ubiquitous tools humankind has created, second only to the thing that makes it so useful: the internet. The reasons for its success is that it’s a wildly useful tool: over the years, it’s been able to successfully assimilate and murder simpler tools by the dozen by offering them all in one tiny package. The point-and-shoot camera? &lt;a href=&quot;https://petapixel.com/2017/03/03/latest-camera-sales-chart-reveals-death-compact-camera/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Dead as hell&lt;/a&gt;. The portable DVD player? Murdered in cold blood. The MP3 player? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dailymail.co.uk/sciencetech/article-2547435/Death-iPod-Sales-Apples-iconic-music-player-fallen-HALF-past-year.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Gone the way of the Dodo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;quote_new&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For better or worse, the ability to get music to your ears in a convenient fashion is now an essential part of what the world thinks a smartphone should do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s that last little item I mentioned that brings us to our problem today. While the smartphone has been able to leverage its ability to stream massive content libraries over its data connection, it hasn’t quite yet provided a perfect alternative to headphones, nor the headphone jack. This is especially important because among 18-29 year olds, 87% of them have used their smartphones &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pewresearch.org/fact-tank/2016/01/29/us-smartphone-use/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;to listen to music streaming services&lt;/a&gt; in 2015. That number will go up the longer these services are available, and as those same kids age. For better or worse, the ability to get music to your ears in a convenient fashion is now—and will likely always be—an essential part of what the world thinks a smartphone should do. Consequently, a phone that eschews the most-used standard to consume audio also eschews its utility to consumers. It has become the wrong tool for the job: It just &lt;em&gt;doesn’t work&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why include a headphone jack?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems weird to extol the virtues of a piece of nearly 140-year-old technology in this day and age, but the reason why it’s persisted this long is that… it &lt;em&gt;works&lt;/em&gt;. It’s a solved issue: not only is a TRRS plug cheap, but it’s durable, small, and high-quality. It can support inexpensive headphones, and it can support the best headphones—all with one universal standard. Not only that, but it’s an easy way to enable the use of microphones, as well. It’s a fantastically versatile piece of tech that hasn’t really been changed all that much since the plug was reduced in size to 3.5mm in the 1950s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously, a headphone jack isn’t the only way you can listen to music. Bluetooth headphones exist, and they work well for most people. But the problem is: they don’t work well for &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; people. Audiophiles probably aren’t too keen on being unable to listen to high-bitrate files, and there’s no shortage of reasons why you wouldn’t want to deal with the added hassles of wireless tech… Which is why smartphone companies have used both in tandem for so long: it offers the pickiest listeners quality that Bluetooth can’t currently touch, while enabling users who want to ditch the cable. There’s almost no reason &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; to have both, especially when the cost to manufacture is so cheap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_13450&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; readability=&quot;33&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/beyerdynamic-DT-880-pro-plug.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-13450&quot; src=&quot;https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/beyerdynamic-DT-880-pro-plug-1024x683.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;683&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/beyerdynamic-DT-880-pro-plug-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/beyerdynamic-DT-880-pro-plug-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/beyerdynamic-DT-880-pro-plug-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/beyerdynamic-DT-880-pro-plug-16x11.jpg 16w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/beyerdynamic-DT-880-pro-plug-32x21.jpg 32w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/beyerdynamic-DT-880-pro-plug-28x19.jpg 28w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/beyerdynamic-DT-880-pro-plug-56x37.jpg 56w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/beyerdynamic-DT-880-pro-plug-64x43.jpg 64w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/beyerdynamic-DT-880-pro-plug-1000x667.jpg 1000w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/beyerdynamic-DT-880-pro-plug-1200x800.jpg 1200w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/beyerdynamic-DT-880-pro-plug-560x373.jpg 560w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/beyerdynamic-DT-880-pro-plug-365x243.jpg 365w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/beyerdynamic-DT-880-pro-plug-690x460.jpg 690w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/beyerdynamic-DT-880-pro-plug-600x400.jpg 600w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/beyerdynamic-DT-880-pro-plug-352x235.jpg 352w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Another primitive tool, the headphone plug does its job fantastically well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given that so many people have decided that the smartphone is the heir to the portable MP3 player, consumers’ buying habits when it comes to smartphones are extremely important. And when it comes to which types of cans consumers prefer, wired headphones absolutely &lt;em&gt;crush &lt;/em&gt;Bluetooth headsets in gross sales, despite how badly tech blogs misread &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npd.com/wps/portal/npd/us/news/press-releases/2016/bluetooth-capable-headphone-sales-surpass-non-bluetooth-sales/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;this study&lt;/a&gt; that claims Bluetooth overtook wired headphones in 2016. The issue is that people lose sight of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.businessinsider.com/apple-iphone-7-wireless-headphones-sales-chart-2016-9&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;gross figures&lt;/a&gt; in favor of the dollar sales figure. For those keeping score at home: before the arrival of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.soundguys.com/apple-airpods-review-good-11072/&quot;&gt;AirPods&lt;/a&gt;, wired headphones were outselling Bluetooth units with 83% of the total units to Bluetooth’s 17% share.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Considering that we’re talking about a base of consumers that probably don’t buy headphones every single year—especially if they spent more than $100 on their last pair—it doesn’t seem likely that 83% is an accurate assessment of how many people use the good ol’ analog plug as their primary vehicle for sweet, sweet music. That figure is probably higher, and wired headphones won’t be in the minority for a long, &lt;em&gt;long&lt;/em&gt; time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_13839&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; readability=&quot;21.169811320755&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;thumb_image&quot; href=&quot;https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/apple-iphone-headphone-jack-bluetooth-sales-chart-NPD.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-13839&quot; src=&quot;https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/apple-iphone-headphone-jack-bluetooth-sales-chart-NPD.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A chart detailing the gross sale and revenues of wireless and wired headphones.&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;684&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/apple-iphone-headphone-jack-bluetooth-sales-chart-NPD.jpg 960w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/apple-iphone-headphone-jack-bluetooth-sales-chart-NPD-300x214.jpg 300w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/apple-iphone-headphone-jack-bluetooth-sales-chart-NPD-768x547.jpg 768w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/apple-iphone-headphone-jack-bluetooth-sales-chart-NPD-16x11.jpg 16w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/apple-iphone-headphone-jack-bluetooth-sales-chart-NPD-32x23.jpg 32w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/apple-iphone-headphone-jack-bluetooth-sales-chart-NPD-28x20.jpg 28w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/apple-iphone-headphone-jack-bluetooth-sales-chart-NPD-56x40.jpg 56w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/apple-iphone-headphone-jack-bluetooth-sales-chart-NPD-64x46.jpg 64w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/apple-iphone-headphone-jack-bluetooth-sales-chart-NPD-560x399.jpg 560w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/apple-iphone-headphone-jack-bluetooth-sales-chart-NPD-365x260.jpg 365w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/apple-iphone-headphone-jack-bluetooth-sales-chart-NPD-646x460.jpg 646w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/apple-iphone-headphone-jack-bluetooth-sales-chart-NPD-561x400.jpg 561w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/apple-iphone-headphone-jack-bluetooth-sales-chart-NPD-330x235.jpg 330w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;source_link_wrap&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.statista.com/chart/5733/headphone-sales-in-the-united-states/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Data: NPD Group, Visualization: Statista&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; There’s a lot more wired headsets than wireless ones out there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So why on &lt;em&gt;Earth&lt;/em&gt; would you deign to alienate such an enormous segment of your potential audience? Well, if that data is any indication: it’s all about the money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The Bluetooth situation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To say that Bluetooth is bad is completely unfair, as there are several advantages it enjoys over the traditional headphone jack. Not only can it wirelessly transmit audio of an acceptable quality, but it can also be used to control your listening device, and other peripherals. But Bluetooth still has a long way to go in order to dethrone the headphone jack in terms of performance. Bluetooth itself meets the needs of a large number of people, while the inherent tradeoffs make this debate about Bluetooth’s downsides a little more hazy. Nobody’s wrong for liking Bluetooth or wired cans more—so long as they’re honest about what they value in a set of headphones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve had this debate on SoundGuys before, me snarkily &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.soundguys.com/5-reasons-not-to-buy-bluetooth-headphones-12150/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;siding with wired cans&lt;/a&gt;, and Kris taking up arms &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.soundguys.com/5-reasons-to-buy-bluetooth-headphones-12362/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;for Bluetooth&lt;/a&gt;. However, I should point out that Bluetooth’s downsides are largely limited to consequences of having yet another battery, and a lack of cross-platform compatibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_12718&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; readability=&quot;33&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/akg-n-60-nc-review-wear-4.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-12718&quot; src=&quot;https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/akg-n-60-nc-review-wear-4-1024x683.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A photo of the AKG N60 NC being worn by Adam Molina.&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;683&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/akg-n-60-nc-review-wear-4-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/akg-n-60-nc-review-wear-4-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/akg-n-60-nc-review-wear-4-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/akg-n-60-nc-review-wear-4-16x11.jpg 16w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/akg-n-60-nc-review-wear-4-32x21.jpg 32w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/akg-n-60-nc-review-wear-4-28x19.jpg 28w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/akg-n-60-nc-review-wear-4-56x37.jpg 56w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/akg-n-60-nc-review-wear-4-64x43.jpg 64w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/akg-n-60-nc-review-wear-4-1000x667.jpg 1000w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/akg-n-60-nc-review-wear-4-1200x800.jpg 1200w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/akg-n-60-nc-review-wear-4-560x373.jpg 560w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/akg-n-60-nc-review-wear-4-365x243.jpg 365w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/akg-n-60-nc-review-wear-4-690x460.jpg 690w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/akg-n-60-nc-review-wear-4-600x400.jpg 600w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/akg-n-60-nc-review-wear-4-352x235.jpg 352w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Wireless headphones have an undeniable appeal, with slowly diminishing tradeoffs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The latest and greatest headphones that support aptX or Apple’s proprietary AAC almost solve the quality gripes of years past, but not all phones support these standards. The market is extremely fractured in the Android universe, and while the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.androidauthority.com/samsung-galaxy-note-8-review-795053/&quot;&gt;Note 8&lt;/a&gt; will deliver you the best version of aptX out there, the Google Pixel will not—making entry into Apple’s ecosystem extremely enticing for wireless headphone fans. By going all-in on Bluetooth, Apple has a major advantage over its competitors by guaranteeing the best performance with that tech while side-stepping the pitfalls of fractured compatibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, excluding the headphone jack is still an extreme action that isn’t completely explained away by “Apple is better at Bluetooth.” Why would a company ditch the jack when the cost to meet the needs of every single one of your consumers’ listening habits is so easy to do? While the official line of ditching the headphone jack has been “not enough space,” we now know that excuse &lt;a href=&quot;http://strangeparts.com/bringing-back-the-iphone-headphone-jack-in-china/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;to be a lie&lt;/a&gt;: it’s definitely possible to cram in a headphone jack, it’s just not easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why Apple ditched the headphone jack&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe it’s my provincial New Hampshire upbringing, but I place very little stock in people’s words. Instead, I pay very close attention to their actions to figure out what they’re all about. You could spin all sorts of yarn about God-knows-what, but I ain’t buying it unless I see a reason to believe you. That’s probably why I always curse and groan when I see statements like that of LeEco’s CEO Liang Jun &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2016/6/9/11893044/leeco-headphone-jack-usb-c-smartphones&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;explaining that headphone jack isn’t a necessity&lt;/a&gt;, or Apple’s insistence that ditching the headphone jack &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.businessinsider.com/why-apple-got-rid-of-the-headphone-jack-in-the-iphone-7-2016-9&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;takes “courage.”&lt;/a&gt; Seriously, after reading the above section and noting how big a margin there seems to be on Bluetooth headphones, is it any wonder why Apple chose to abuse its status as a “market leader” to seize the opportunity to dominate &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npd.com/wps/portal/npd/us/blog/2017/totally-wireless-earbuds-bring-the-loud-to-stereo-headphone-sales/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;another product category&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;quote_new&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...Apple has essentially cornered the market on Bluetooth headphones, and they're eating up more and more of the developing segment&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Money is a great motivator to do really crappy things&lt;em&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; and Apple has done exactly that for decades now. You may think that Apple’s semi-predatory dongle addiction might be how they make cash off of killing the headphone jack, but the real answer is much more banal than that. It’s because they’ve basically bought Bluetooth headphones as a &lt;em&gt;category,&lt;/em&gt; and are trying to eat up another market. Don’t believe me? Let’s take a look at who wins when Bluetooth overtakes wired headphones in sales.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ever since Apple &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.soundguys.com/the-history-of-beats-13289/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;purchased a majority stake in Beats Audio&lt;/a&gt; for $3.2 billion in 2015, they’ve earned nearly &lt;em&gt;half&lt;/em&gt; of all money spent buying Bluetooth headphones. When Apple kills headphone jacks on their products, they’re simultaneously trying to lock people into their own ecosystem, and increase demand for other high-margin products they peddle. On top of that, a smartphone without the headphone jack means Bluetooth headphones will be a major cash cow simply because the vast majority of listeners do not currently own Bluetooth headphones. It’s a smart business plan—but &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.androidauthority.com/apple-iphone-dongle-904121/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;a &lt;em&gt;giant&lt;/em&gt; middle finger&lt;/a&gt; to consumers, who now have to spend &lt;a href=&quot;http://tyvm.ly/Si71Tqe&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;hundreds&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;of dollars fixing a problem that didn’t exist until some literal Monopoly men in Cupertino decided it needed to be one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_13867&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; readability=&quot;24.018348623853&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;thumb_image&quot; href=&quot;https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/apple-headphone-jack-chart-market-share.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-13867&quot; src=&quot;https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/apple-headphone-jack-chart-market-share.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A chart showing the market share of different companies in wireless audio.&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;684&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/apple-headphone-jack-chart-market-share.jpg 960w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/apple-headphone-jack-chart-market-share-300x214.jpg 300w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/apple-headphone-jack-chart-market-share-768x547.jpg 768w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/apple-headphone-jack-chart-market-share-16x11.jpg 16w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/apple-headphone-jack-chart-market-share-32x23.jpg 32w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/apple-headphone-jack-chart-market-share-28x20.jpg 28w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/apple-headphone-jack-chart-market-share-56x40.jpg 56w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/apple-headphone-jack-chart-market-share-64x46.jpg 64w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/apple-headphone-jack-chart-market-share-560x399.jpg 560w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/apple-headphone-jack-chart-market-share-365x260.jpg 365w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/apple-headphone-jack-chart-market-share-646x460.jpg 646w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/apple-headphone-jack-chart-market-share-561x400.jpg 561w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/apple-headphone-jack-chart-market-share-330x235.jpg 330w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;source_link_wrap&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.statista.com/chart/7993/headphone-market-share/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Data: NPD Group, Chart: Statista&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; Apple and Beats combine to earn roughly half of all sales in wireless audio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The crazy thing is, it seems to be working… for now. Every market indication that I can find paints the same picture: Apple has essentially cornered the market on Bluetooth headphones, and they’re eating up more and more of the developing segment. And the situation is even more extreme if you take a look at the new category of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.soundguys.com/best-truly-wireless-earbuds-14313/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;“truly wireless” earphones&lt;/a&gt;. After the success it’s seen so far, why not continue strangling a nascent market in the crib? From the report linked above:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;20&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“More than 900,000 totally wireless headphone units were sold in the U.S. since the start of the year (2017), according to The NPD Group’s Retail Tracking Service… Since launching in December, Apple’s AirPods have accounted for &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;85 percent&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; of totally wireless headphone dollar sales in the U.S., according to NPD’s Retail Tracking Service…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple’s early domination of the category will continue to challenge competing brands entering the totally wireless market. New entrants will have to provide some differentiation in features, sound quality, or associated services and applications in order to stand out. Consumer reception of wireless earbuds is still forming, even as their use case continues to evolve.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This doesn’t even touch the issue of headphone manufacturers being required to pay for licenses to use Bluetooth, or the increased difficulty in competing in this market, or even the environmental impact of using yet more batteries that fail over time and need to be replaced. Apple is behaving as if it were helmed by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1635815/quotes/qt3407147&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;fictional business tycoon Jack Donaghy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;So what’s the problem?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Killing the headphone jack was good—for Apple’s bottom line. For the headphone industry, less so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the part of the article where I get around to telling you something you already know. That is, a smartphone without a headphone jack isn’t a good tool. It’s an incomplete one, and one you shouldn’t buy. But it goes so much further than that—it’s profiteering off of people who might not be able to afford the changes Apple is foisting on them, and that’s something I take extreme issue with. Some people can &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.soundguys.com/best-earbuds-under-20-10059/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;only afford $20 headphones&lt;/a&gt;, and by God I want them to be able to use affordable units to enjoy their music. I have a sneaking suspicion that more than a few of you are a little pissed off at paying more for getting less, but there’s a lot to unpack in this discussion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_12716&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; readability=&quot;33&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/akg-n-60-nc-review-wear.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-12716&quot; src=&quot;https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/akg-n-60-nc-review-wear-1024x683.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A photo of the AKG N60 NC being worn.&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;683&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/akg-n-60-nc-review-wear-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/akg-n-60-nc-review-wear-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/akg-n-60-nc-review-wear-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/akg-n-60-nc-review-wear-16x11.jpg 16w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/akg-n-60-nc-review-wear-32x21.jpg 32w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/akg-n-60-nc-review-wear-28x19.jpg 28w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/akg-n-60-nc-review-wear-56x37.jpg 56w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/akg-n-60-nc-review-wear-64x43.jpg 64w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/akg-n-60-nc-review-wear-1000x667.jpg 1000w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/akg-n-60-nc-review-wear-1200x800.jpg 1200w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/akg-n-60-nc-review-wear-560x373.jpg 560w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/akg-n-60-nc-review-wear-365x243.jpg 365w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/akg-n-60-nc-review-wear-690x460.jpg 690w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/akg-n-60-nc-review-wear-600x400.jpg 600w, https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/akg-n-60-nc-review-wear-352x235.jpg 352w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Bluetooth headphones are rising in popularity, but they cost for quality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While it’s not exactly a mystery that a company will do whatever nets it more profit in the long run, pulling the headphone jack without a suitable replacement is one of those decisions that’s so cold and consumer-hostile that people &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; be angry about it. Bluetooth just isn’t where it needs to be to replace wired headphones completely, and that’s all there is to it. Include both the jack, and the Bluetooth, dammit.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 05:42:54 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>bunderbunder</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://www.soundguys.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/Propaganda-Fist.jpg</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Was ditching the headphone jack a good idea?</og:title>
<og:description>Much like Boston basketball legend Bill Russell, it's time for Chris Thomas to throw an elbow.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.soundguys.com/was-ditching-the-headphone-jack-a-good-idea-13825/</og:url>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.soundguys.com/was-ditching-the-headphone-jack-a-good-idea-13825/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>In killing Inbox, Google takes another swipe at its most passionate users</title>
<link>https://www.computerworld.com/article/3305946/email/in-killing-inbox-google-takes-another-swipe-at-its-most-passionate-users.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.computerworld.com/article/3305946/email/in-killing-inbox-google-takes-another-swipe-at-its-most-passionate-users.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;For all its skill and dominance in artificial intelligence, Google can be surprisingly lacking in the natural kind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In move after move, Google snatches defeat from the jaws of victory. And all because the company’s culture is blind to the value of passionate users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m quite certain that Google watches user numbers and applies analytics to everything it can measure. A radically analytical approach is powerful, but it can blind you to the factors that cannot be measured. Factors such as user passion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id=&quot;fsb-2055&quot; class=&quot;fakesidebar fakesidebar-auto&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[ To comment on this story, visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/Computerworld/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Computerworld's Facebook page&lt;/a&gt;. ]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;My favorite example is Google+. After an initial surge of usage in the first couple of years, the social network gradually fizzled — smothered by a reputation for low engagement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;nativo-promo nativo-promo-1 smartphone&quot; id=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;That reputation was largely false. But over time it became a self-fulfilling prophecy as Google took repeated action to hide and suppress engagement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It killed Circle sharing, the best way to discover high-quality active users. It added Communities, which reduced attention aimed at users. Its dumb algorithms flagged (and thereby hid from public view) high-quality comments, while simultaneously failing to flag obvious spam. (Eventually, Google’s algorithms got much better, but only after most users had already abandoned the platform.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a great plan — if your objective is to minimize user engagement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id=&quot;fsb-2602&quot; class=&quot;fakesidebar fakesidebar-auto fakesidebar-sponsored&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[ &lt;a href=&quot;https://pluralsight.pxf.io/c/321564/424552/7490?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.pluralsight.com%2Fcourses%2Fadministering-office-365-quick-start&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Become a Microsoft Office 365 administrator in record time with this quick start course from PluralSight.&lt;/a&gt; ]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;Google+ was, and still is, the online playground for Google’s most loyal fans. Google could have brought a billion people into this playground, where Google fans could hold sway and persuade everybody else to share their enthusiasm for Android, Pixel phones, Pixelbooks, Google Search, Google Assistant, Google Home, Gmail, YouTube and all the rest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;nativo-promo nativo-promo-1 tablet desktop&quot; id=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Instead, it actively buried or suppressed user engagement until Google+ became a shell of its former self. It has robbed its own most passionate users of audience, demonstrating that it doesn’t understand the value of those users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now it’s doing something comparable with email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Google giveth, and Google taketh away&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google this week announced the end of two email-related products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first is the experimental alternative to Gmail called Inbox. The other is a Chrome app for offline Gmail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;nativo-promo nativo-promo-2 tablet desktop smartphone&quot; id=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Gmail Offline Chrome app, which Google introduced seven years ago and hasn’t updated for five years, will be removed from the Chrome Web Store on Dec. 3. It has been superseded in functionality by the web version of Gmail, which has supported superior offline capability for years. (You can turn on the offline feature by going into Gmail Settings, choosing the Offline tab and making sure the “enable offline mail” checkbox is checked.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But nobody cares about the Gmail Offline Chrome app. Good riddance to it. Technically, it never even made it out of beta.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The termination of Google Inbox, on the other hand, is more problematic. Inbox will be killed in March, according to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.blog.google/products/gmail/inbox-signing-find-your-favorite-features-new-gmail/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;a Google blog post&lt;/a&gt; this week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inbox, which is officially and oddly branded Inbox by Gmail, was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.computerworld.com/article/2841885/an-open-email-to-google-inbox.html&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;launched as an experimental app&lt;/a&gt; in 2014. And probably in a panic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in 2013, Gmail was proudly text-based and largely devoid of significant interface design. The service was popular and growing, and it looked as if Google would rule the email roost indefinitely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then catastrophe struck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In early 2013, a startup announced an app for iPhone called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xDHywvDhCAg&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Mailbox&lt;/a&gt;. More than a million people signed up to try it before it even launched, based on the innovation and appeal of its user interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key Mailbox innovation — common now but revelatory then — was the use of swiping left or right to move or snooze messages. Mailbox emphasized other interface elements as well, including the containment of elements into boxes or “cards.” The combination of Mailbox features facilitated the quick achievement of “zero inbox” — Mailbox made it easy to skim and process emails.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s possible that the interface of Mailbox, and the obvious appeal of it, shocked Google into rethinking its hyper-minimalist design and may have influenced the course of its design language, Material Design, which the company introduced in the summer of 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google announced Inbox — one of the first Material Design products — a few months later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google may have rushed Inbox to market to stave off the loss of users to swipe-centric, card-happy upstarts such as Mailbox and its subsequent imitators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alas, poor Mailbox never had a chance. Its fatal flaw was that it wasn’t an email service, but a front end to the email services owned by other companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The companies that did control email services, including Google, easily copied the most appealing user interface elements of Mailbox, making them ubiquitous and Mailbox, therefore, worthless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dropbox, having acquired Mailbox one month after its launch, killed it in December 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gmail itself gradually got a Material Design makeover, as well as many (but not all) of the features popular in Inbox, such as Smart Replies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gmail still lacks Inbox’s Reminders integration, mobile app inbox swiping to manage messages, message bundling, inbox pinning and what fans call a “cleaner” UI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Importantly, the overall feel of Inbox and Gmail — and the muscle memory required to use each — are still very different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why killing Inbox is a mistake&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google probably has around 1.3 billion email users by now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of them use only Gmail. A sizable minority uses only Inbox. And lots of people — including yours truly — switch back and forth between the two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That switching is facilitated by a number of factors. One of these is that filters created in Gmail Settings function inside Inbox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many users prefer using Gmail in their desktop browser because they like the granular control over everything, but they prefer Inbox on mobile for the Mailbox-like ease of use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google’s thinking appears to be that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;One email system is better than two.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More people use Gmail than Inbox.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gmail is close enough now to Inbox in interface and features,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;And, therefore, it’s time to kill Inbox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem with this thinking is that all users are being treated equally here. If Google were able to measure the passion of users, it would almost certainly realize that far more passionate users are using Inbox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which is not to say that passionate Google users don’t use Gmail. They do. Some power users love Gmail because it allows more user control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, many users stick to Gmail because they really don’t care that much. They’re used to it and don’t feel like changing anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inbox users are the users looking for the newest thing, the users who can more quickly adapt to a new way of doing things, the users who jump on all of Google’s newly launched innovations because they trust Google.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most cynical summary of this history is that Google had Gmail and everybody was happy. Then Google created a more innovative alternative, and its best and most active and engaged users loved that alternative. Then it killed that alternative after its most loyal fans had dedicated countless precious hours mastering it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a great plan — if your objective is to minimize confidence and loyalty among your most passionate users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that’s why killing Inbox is a mistake. It’s yet another slap in the face of the passionate minority.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What Google doesn’t understand is that not all users are the same. Passionate users are far more valuable to Google than indifferent users. They try new things. They buy stuff. They persuade the public in Google’s favor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By mismanaging Google+, killing Reader and now killing Inbox, Google has been making passionate users less passionate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If it keeps this up, its most passionate users are going to take their passion somewhere else.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2018 21:33:43 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Signez</dc:creator>
<og:title>In killing Inbox, Google takes another swipe at its most passionate users</og:title>
<og:description>It fits a pattern that tells us that Google sees everyone as having equal value, which just isn’t true.</og:description>
<og:image>https://images.idgesg.net/images/article/2018/09/google_inbox_by_gmail_logo-100772449-large.3x2.jpg</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.computerworld.com/article/3305946/email/in-killing-inbox-google-takes-another-swipe-at-its-most-passionate-users.html</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.computerworld.com/article/3305946/email/in-killing-inbox-google-takes-another-swipe-at-its-most-passionate-users.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Raytracing a Black Hole</title>
<link>http://rantonels.github.io/starless/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://rantonels.github.io/starless/</guid>
<description>&lt;img src=&quot;http://rantonels.github.io/starless/pics/hm_out_small.jpg&quot; class=&quot;align-center img-responsive&quot;/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-md-12&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;lead text-center&quot;&gt;Geodesic raytracing in curved spacetime&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot; readability=&quot;28.243947858473&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's now clear I'm on a Black Hole binge (I can stop when I want, by the way). They're endlessly fascinating. My recent interest was in particular focused on simulating visualizations of the Schwarzschild geometry. I was preoccupied by the problem of generating a decent accurate representation of how the curvature of such a spacetime affects the appearance of the sky (since photons from distance sources ride along geodesics bent by the Black Hole), for the purpose of creating an interactive simulation. &lt;a href=&quot;http://spiro.fisica.unipd.it/~antonell/schwarzschild/&quot;&gt;This&lt;/a&gt; was the result (it runs in your browser). The trick was of course to precalculate as much as possible about the deflection of light rays. It worked ok-ish, but the simulation is of course very lacking in features, since it's not actually doing any raytracing (for the laymen: reconstructing the whereabouts of light rays incoming in the camera back in time) on its own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project, instead, aims to shatter these shortcoming by ditching efficiency/interactivity in the most naive way: it's a &lt;strong&gt;full CPU raytracer&lt;/strong&gt;, taking all the time it needs to render pictures. The image above was rendered with this program - it took &lt;s&gt;15&lt;/s&gt; 5 minutes (thanks, RK4) on my laptop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is neither anything new nor is it any better than how it's been done before. It's just really fun for me. I'm writing this page to share not only end-results such as the image above (&lt;a href=&quot;http://imgur.com/a/kocqC&quot;&gt;also because some people did it better&lt;/a&gt;) but also the &lt;strong&gt;process of building these pictures&lt;/strong&gt;, with a discussion/explanation of the physics involved and the implementation. Ideally, this could be of inspiration or guidance to people with a similar intent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot; readability=&quot;58.779850746269&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The shadow&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have already tried my &lt;a href=&quot;http://spiro.fisica.unipd.it/~antonell/schwarzschild/&quot;&gt;live applet&lt;/a&gt;, you should be familiar with this view:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://rantonels.github.io/starless/pics/00_new.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rantonels.github.io/starless/pics/00_new_small.jpg&quot; class=&quot;center-block img-responsive img-mrg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You shouldn't have problems making out the salient feature of the image, namely the black disk and the weird distortion ring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's often pointed out that it's incorrect to say that the black disk is the event horizon. In fact, it's incorrect to say that &lt;em&gt;a region of an image&lt;/em&gt; is &lt;em&gt;an object&lt;/em&gt;. These are &lt;strong&gt;images&lt;/strong&gt; of things. Now, it's true that there will be rays that, when backtraced from your eye, will end up in the event horizon. These will be black pixels, since no photon could ever have followed that path goin forward, from inside the black hole to your eye. This black disk is thus very clearly the &lt;strong&gt;image of the event horizon&lt;/strong&gt;, in the sense that if you draw (in the far past) something right above the horizon, outside observers will be able to see it right on that black disk (we will actually perform this experiment later). This black region is also called &quot;shadow&quot; of the BH in some pulbications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://rantonels.github.io/starless/pics/bhscattersmall.png&quot; class=&quot;center-block img-responsive img-mrg&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;What it's interesting to note, however, is that this is at the same time &lt;strong&gt;the image of the photon sphere&lt;/strong&gt;. The gnuplot graph above depicts geodesics of incoming photons from infinity (looking at the BH from far away zooming in) along with the EH (black) and the PS (green). The photon sphere is \( \frac{3}{2} \) times the event horizon (in Schwarzschild \(r\)) and is the location where circular orbits of light around the BH are allowed (though unstable). In the graph, identify rays that fall to their death and those who get only scattered (and thus end up on another point on the celestial sphere). You see that absorbed rays are those arriving with an impact parameter of less than ~ 2.5 radii. This is the apparent radius of the black disk, and it's &lt;strong&gt;significantly larger&lt;/strong&gt; than both the EH and the PS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways, the relevant trivia here is this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A light ray infalling in the photon sphere in free fall will also reach the event horizon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This implies that the image of the photon sphere is included in that of the horizon. However, since the horizon is very clearly inside the photon sphere, the image of the former must also be a subset of that of the latter. Then the two images should coincide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why should you care that the black disk is also the image of the PS? Because it means that the &lt;em&gt;edge&lt;/em&gt; of the black disk is populated by photons that &lt;strong&gt;skim&lt;/strong&gt; the photon sphere. A pixel right outside the black disk corresponds to a photon that (when tracing backwards) spirals into the photon sphere, getting closer and closer to the unstable circular orbit, winding many times (the closer you look, the more it winds), then spiraling out - since the orbit is unstable - and escaping to infinity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This behaviour will produce an interesting optical phenomenon and is basically getting close to a separatrix in a dynamical system. In the limit, a ray thrown exactly on the edge will spiral in forever, getting closer and closer to the photon sphere circular orbit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot; readability=&quot;32.712133227597&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The effect on the celestial sphere&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm not gonna focus a lot on this, because this was the main goal of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://spiro.fisica.unipd.it/~antonell/schwarzschild&quot;&gt;live applet&lt;/a&gt;, and you can get a much better idea of the distortions induced on the sky through that (which also includes an UV grid option so the distortion is clearer).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just a couple of things about the Einstein ring. The Einstein ring is distinguishable as an optical feature because it is the image of a single point, namely that on the sky directly opposite the observer. The ring forms at the view angle where rays from the observer are bent parallel. Outside of it, rays are not bent enough and remain divergent; inside, they are bent too much and converge and in fact can go backwards, or even wind around multiple times, as we've seen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But then, think about this: if we get close enough to the black disk, light rays should be able to wind around once and then walk away parallel. There we should see a secondary Einstein ring. In fact, rings of any order (any number of windings.) Also, there should be &quot;odd&quot; rings inbetween where light rays are bent parallel, but directed towards the viewer. This infinite series of rings is there, but it's absolutely invisible in this image (in fact, in most of them) as they are very close to the disk edge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot; readability=&quot;51.000231053604&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The distortion of the Event Horizon&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://rantonels.github.io/starless/pics/01_new.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rantonels.github.io/starless/pics/01_new_small.jpg&quot; class=&quot;center-block img-responsive img-mrg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this new image, there are a couple of things that have changed. First of all, this was rendered at a higher resolution and with filtering for the background, so as to be more readable. Then, I've zoomed in on the hole (haven't gotten closer, we're still at ~ 10 radii, just zoomed in). But most importantly, I have drawn &lt;strong&gt;a grid on the horizon.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The horizon is &quot;just a sphere&quot;. Technically, it does not work like a standard Riemannian sphere with a spacial metric. The horizon is lightlike! A pictorial way of saying this is that it's going outwards at the speed of light. However, in Schwarzschild coordinates, it's still a \(r=1\) surface, and we can use \(\phi\) and \(\theta\) as longitude and latitude. So it's possible to draw a coordinate grid in a canonical way. Then what you're seeing is how that grid would look.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The grid allows us to take note of a peculiar fact we could have also deduced by analizing the photon scattering/absorption graph above:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The whole surface of the horizon is visible at the same time, from any point&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is very interesting. When you look at a stationary sphere in standard flat spacetime, you can see at most 50% of its surface at any given time (less if you're closer, because of perspective). The horizon, instead, is &lt;strong&gt;all visible simultaneously&lt;/strong&gt;, mapped in the black disk: notice in particular the North and South poles. However, while the surface of the EH is all there, &lt;strong&gt;it doesn't cover all of the black disk&lt;/strong&gt;: if you zoomed in on the edge, you'd see that this image of the EH ends &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt; the shadow ends. Namely you'll find a ring, very close to the outside edge, but not equal, which is an image of the point opposite the observer and delimits this &quot;first&quot; image of the EH inside. So what's inbetween this ring and the actual edge? I haven't yet bothered making a zoom to show this, but there's &lt;em&gt;another whole image of the event horizon squeezed in there&lt;/em&gt;. And then another, and then another, ad infinitum. There are infinite concentric images of the whole horizon, squeezed on the shadow. &lt;em&gt;(Many thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/xXxDeAThANgEL99xXx&quot;&gt;/u/xXxDeAThANgEL99xXx&lt;/a&gt; for pointing out this phenomenon, which I had overlooked.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot; readability=&quot;48&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Adding an accretion disk&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://rantonels.github.io/starless/pics/02smalledit.png&quot; class=&quot;center-block img-responsive img-mrg&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;What modern black hole rendering would it be without an accretion disk? While it's certainly debatable whether Nolan's &lt;em&gt;Interstellar&lt;/em&gt; was actually watchable, not to mention accurate, we can certainly thank the blockbuster for popularizing the particular way the image of an accretion disk is distorted. Here we have an infinitely thin, flat, horizontal accretion disk extending from the photon sphere (this is very unrealistic, orbits below \(3 r_S \) are unstable. More below) to 4 radii, coloured checkered white and blue on the top and white and green on the bottom. It is evident, with this colouring, that we've encountered another case of seeing 100% of something at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this image, I moved the observer up a bit, so he can take a better look at the disk. You can see &lt;strong&gt;two main images of the disk&lt;/strong&gt;, one of the upper face, and one, inside, of the lower. The blue image has the far section of the upper disk distorted to arch above the shadow of the BH. This happens because a ray pointing right above the black hole is bent down to meet the upper surface of the disk behind the hole, opposite the observer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This also explains the very existence of the green image: rays going below are bent to meet the lower surface, still behind the hole. The green image, if you look closely, extends all around the shadow, but it's much thinner in the upper section. This corresponds to light rays that go above the BH, are bent into an almost full circle around the hole and hit the lower surface in the &lt;strong&gt;front&lt;/strong&gt; section of the disk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, it's easy to deduce that there is an infinite series of accretion disk images, getting very quickly thinner and closer to the edge. The next-order image, in blue, is already very thin but faintly visible in the lower portion of the edge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot; readability=&quot;22&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;GIFs are still cool in 2015&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://rantonels.github.io/starless/pics/curvaturesmall.gif&quot; class=&quot;center-block img-responsive img-mrg&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this spastic animation I turn the deflection of light on/off (formally, Schwarzschild/Minkowski) to make clear some of the points we went over before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lower surface is blue and not green because I'm lazy, use your imagination or something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://rantonels.github.io/starless/pics/sbreng.gif&quot; class=&quot;center-block img-responsive img-mrg&quot;/&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rantonels.github.io/starless/pics/horizon.gif&quot; class=&quot;center-block img-responsive img-mrg&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;These trippy .gifs, instead, were requested by some people. The observer is circling the black hole at 10 radii. This is not to be understood as an actual orbit, as there are no effect such as aberration from orbital velocity. This is to be understood as the observer taking a series of snapshots of the black hole while stationary, and moving from place to place inbetween frames; it's an &quot;adiabatic&quot; orbit, if you want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Also stereo pics are still cool&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://rantonels.github.io/starless/pics/stereo.png&quot; class=&quot;center-block img-responsive img-mrg&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Interesting how the shadow looks pretty much flat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot; readability=&quot;29.465290806754&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enough with the informative pixelated 90's uni mainframe renderings with garish colors. Here's some &quot;pop&quot; renders (click for full size)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col-xs-6 col-md-6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;thumbnail&quot; readability=&quot;5.1724137931034&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rantonels.github.io/starless/pics/xuWzJRn.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rantonels.github.io/starless/pics/xuWzJRn_thumb.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot; readability=&quot;6.0344827586207&quot;&gt;This image was rendered by &lt;a href=&quot;http://reddit.com/u/dfzxh&quot;&gt;/u/dfzxh&lt;/a&gt; with x4 supersampling.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col-xs-6 col-md-6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;thumbnail&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rantonels.github.io/starless/pics/wpmaterial.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rantonels.github.io/starless/pics/wpmaterial_thumb.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A closer look.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col-xs-6 col-md-6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;thumbnail&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rantonels.github.io/starless/pics/3dorder.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rantonels.github.io/starless/pics/3dorder_thumb.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zoom on the ring images.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col-xs-6 col-md-6&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;thumbnail&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rantonels.github.io/starless/pics/taglio.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rantonels.github.io/starless/pics/taglio_thumb.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Iconic &quot;ring of light&quot; effect when looking from the equatorial plane.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col-xs-6 col-md-6&quot; readability=&quot;6.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;thumbnail&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rantonels.github.io/starless/pics/hm_out_small.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rantonels.github.io/starless/pics/hm_out.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you download the program, this is the current default scene.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col-xs-6 col-md-6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;thumbnail&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rantonels.github.io/starless/pics/blackhole2.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rantonels.github.io/starless/pics/blackhole2_thumb.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A much wider disc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah, they're nothing special. Not an artist here. Let's get back temporarily to the science: the &lt;a href=&quot;http://rantonels.github.io/starless/pics/3dorder.jpg&quot;&gt;third image&lt;/a&gt;, the one that doesn't seem to make any sense, is actually very precious. It's a zoom on the region between the upper edge of the black disk and the main (&quot;first blue&quot;) image of the accretion disk. The observer is placed on the outer rim of the accretion disk itself and zooms in on this detail. The goal was to image as many orders of rings as possible. Three orders are visible: the lighter zone at the top is just the lower rim of the first image of the top-far surface of the disk. The strip at the bottom, below a calm sea of outstretched stars, is the superior part of the second image, the &quot;first green&quot; one, of the bottom-front of the disk. At the very bottom is a thin line of light not more than a pixel wide, glued to the black disk of the photon sphere. This is mainly the third image, the &quot;second blue&quot;: it's the image again of the top-far surface, but after the light has completed an additional winding around the black hole. Merged with it, but increasingly thin, are all subsequent higher-order images. Ok, this is something worthy of &amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt; tags:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are infinite images of both the upper and lower surface of the accretion disk, and they all show the whole surface simultaneously. Moreover, except for the very first, these images don't pass in front of the black disk nor eachother, and are thus &quot;concentric&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marvelous.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;panel panel-default&quot; readability=&quot;6.9722222222222&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;panel-body&quot; readability=&quot;32.537037037037&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;I'm taking render requests&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you interest in a specific render, but aren't willing to go through the trouble of installing the program and rendering it yourself? Just &lt;a href=&quot;http://reddit.com/u/rantonels&quot;&gt;hit me up on Reddit&lt;/a&gt; or send me an e-mail. It takes no more than 10-20 minutes for 1080p on my laptop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot; readability=&quot;107.7875188537&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The accretion disc in the renders above is cartoony. It's just a disc with a stupid texture splattered on it. What happens when in the visual appearance of the disc we include physics-aware information? What happens when we include redshift from orbital motion, for example?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A popular model for an accretion disc is an infinitely thin disc of matter in almost circular orbit, starting at the ISCO (Innermost Stable Circular Orbit, \(3 r_s\)), with a power law temperature profile \(T \sim r^{-a} \). I'll use the extremely simple \[ T \sim r^{-3/4} \] which is most definitely not ok in GR for realistic fluids, but it'll do (you'll see it's not like you can tell the difference anyway).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A free parameter now is the overall scale for the temperatures, for example the temperature at the ISCO. This temperature is &lt;strong&gt;immense&lt;/strong&gt; for most black holes. We're talking &lt;strong&gt;hundreds of millions&lt;/strong&gt; of Kelvin; it's difficult to imagine any human artefact that could &lt;em&gt;survive&lt;/em&gt; being exposed to the light (peaking in X-rays) of a disc at those temperatures, let alone capture anything meaningful on a CCD. We then really have to tone it down. Apparently supermassive black holes are colder, but not enough. We need to pull it down to around 10 000 K at the ISCO for us to be able to see anything. This is highly unaccurate, but it's all I can do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need to ask ourselves two questions. One: &lt;strong&gt;what colour&lt;/strong&gt; is a blackbody at that temperature. Two: &lt;strong&gt;how bright&lt;/strong&gt; is it? Formally, the answer to those two questions is in the scalar product of the functions describing R,G,B channels with the black body spectrum. In practice, one uses some approximations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For colour, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tannerhelland.com/4435/convert-temperature-rgb-algorithm-code/&quot;&gt;this formula&lt;/a&gt; by Tanner Helland is accurate and efficient, but it involves numerous conditionals which are not feasible with my raytracing setup (see below for details). The fastest way is to use a lookup texture:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.vendian.org/mncharity/dir3/blackbody/UnstableURLs/scale03_E.jpg&quot; class=&quot;center-block img-responsive img-mrg&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;This texture is one of many goodies from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vendian.org/mncharity/dir3/blackbody/&quot;&gt;Mitchell Charity's &quot;What color is a blackbody?&quot;&lt;/a&gt;. (For reference, it corresponds to whitepoint E).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This runs from 1000 K to 30 000 K, higher temperatures are basically the same shade of blue. Since there is an immense difference in brightness between temperatures, this texture cannot and does not encode brightness; rather, the colours are normalized. It is our duty to compute relative brightness and multiply. We can use an analytic formula for that. If we assume that the visible spectrumis very narrow, then the total visible intensity is proportional to the blackbody spectrum itself: \[ \frac{1}{\lambda^5} \frac{1}{ \exp( \frac{hc}{\lambda k_B T}) - 1 } \] where I got rid of stupid overall constants (we're going to rescale brightness anyway to see anything). We can just plug in \(\lambda\) roughly in the visible spectrum range and we get that brightness is proportional to: \[ ( e^ { \frac{29622.4 \text{K}}{T} } - 1 )^{-1} \] That's easy enough. As a check, we note that relative intensity quickly drops to zero when T goes to zero, and is only linear in T as T goes to infinity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Redshift&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I discusses the orbital speeds in the Schwarzschild geometry in the explanation for the live applet. To compute redshift, we use the special-relativistic redshift formula: \[(1+z)_\text{Doppler} = \frac{ 1 - \beta \cos(\theta) } {\sqrt{1-\beta^2} } \] Where as \(\cos(\theta) \) is the cosine of the angle between the ray direction when it's emitted by the disc and the disc local velocity, all computed in the local inertial frame associated with the Schwarzschild coordinates. This formula is correct in this context because muh equivalence principle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is to be multiplied with the gravitational redshift factor: \[(1+z)_\text{Gravitational} = (1 - r^{-1})^{-1/2} \] this factor does not depend on the path of the light ray, only on the emission radius, because the Schwarzschild geometry is stationary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This also means that the contribution to gravitational redshift due to the position of the observer is constant over the whole field of view. All our image gets a constant overall blueshift because we're deep in the hole's well. This effect therefore is just applying a tint over our image, and we ignore it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also neglect redshift from observer motion, because our observer is Schwarzschild-stationary. The final result is this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rantonels.github.io/starless/pics/bab_yesint.jpg&quot; class=&quot;center-block img-responsive img-mrg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see, most of the disc is completely white, because it saturates the colour channels. If I scale down those channels to fit in the 0.0-1.0 range, the outer parts of the disk become faint or black. The growth in brightness is too large for us to appreciate. I've tried to depict it in postprocessing through a bloom effect to make really bright parts bleed instead of just clip, but it's hardly sufficient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quite a confusing picture. Here's a picture with the intensity ignored, so you can appreciate the colours:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://rantonels.github.io/starless/pics/bab_noint.jpg&quot; class=&quot;center-block img-responsive img-mrg&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;These are at a smaller resolution because they take &lt;em&gt;so long&lt;/em&gt; to render on my laptop (square roots are bad, kids).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways, it looks thousands of time less scenographic than the other renders (mostly because the inner edge of the disk is already far away enough from the EH that lensing looks quite underwhelming), but at least it's &lt;em&gt;accurate&lt;/em&gt;, if you managed to find a 10 000 K black hole and some really good sunglasses, that is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another shot from a closer distance. I tweaked saturation unnaturally up so you can tell better:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://rantonels.github.io/starless/pics/bab_front.jpg&quot; class=&quot;center-block img-responsive img-mrg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot; readability=&quot;18.603133159269&quot;&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rantonels/starless&quot;&gt;Source on Github&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is very obviously a massive difference between understanding the qualitative aspects of black hole optics and building a numerical integrator that spits out 1080p ok-ish wallpaper material. Last time I neglected the aspect of explaining my thought processes in coding and I put up a really messy git repo. I want to go a little more in detail now and will try to mantain the code tidier and commented.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't want this raytracer to be good, solid, fast. I want it to be easy and hackable, so that people can be &lt;em&gt;inspired&lt;/em&gt; by it, may it be because they see potential for improvement or because it's so sh***y it makes them want to make their own. So here's a quick walkthrough of the algorithms and implementation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot; readability=&quot;53.811262135922&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The &quot;magic&quot; potential&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, General Relativity, right. Easy. Take the Schwarzschild metric, find the Christoffel symbols, find their derivative, write down the geodesic equation, change to some cartesian coordinates to avoid endless suffering, get an immense multiline ODE, integrate. That's pretty much it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just kidding. Of course there's a trick.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you remember &lt;a href=&quot;http://spiro.fisica.unipd.it/~antonell/schwarzschild/&quot;&gt;last time&lt;/a&gt;, I derived the following equation for the orbit of a massless particle in its orbital plane in a Schwarzschild geometry (\(u=1/r\)): \[ u''(\phi) + u = \frac{3}{2} u^3 \] The trick is to recognize that this is in the form of a &lt;strong&gt;Binet equation&lt;/strong&gt;. If you have an absolutely massive and Newtonian particle in a Newtonian central potential: \[ \frac{d^2}{dt^2} \vec x = \frac{1}{m} F(r) \] then the particle will obviously move in its orbital plane, and will satisfy the Binet equation for \(u(\phi)\): \[ u'' + u = - \frac{1}{m h^2 u^2} F(u) \] Where the prime is \(\frac{d}{d\phi}\), \(m\) is the mass and \(h \) is the angular momentum per unit mass. This is an equation for the orbit, not an equation of motion. It does not tell you anything about \(u(t)\) or \(\phi(t)\), just the relationship between \(u\) and \(\phi\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's pause a moment to ponder what this is actually telling us. It says that &lt;em&gt;if&lt;/em&gt; we were to evolve an hypothetical mechanical system of a particle under a certain central force, its trajectory will be a solution to the Binet equation. Then the mechanical system becomes a computational tool to solve the latter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I propose here it's exactly this. We put \(m=1\) and take the (unphysical, whatever) simple system of a point particle in this specific force field: \[ \vec F(r) = - \frac{3}{2} h^2 \frac{\hat r}{r^5} \] where \(h\) is some constant, and integrate that numerically - it's very easy. Then the solution \(\vec x (T) \), where \(T\) is the abstract time coordinate for this system, is actually a parametrization of the unique solution for the corresponding Binet equation, &lt;strong&gt;which is exactly the geodesic equation&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So we solve Newton's equation in cartesian coordinates, which is the easiest thing ever; &lt;s&gt;I use the leapfrog method instead of RK4 because it's simple, reversible and preserves the constants of motion.&lt;/s&gt; (I now switched to Runge-Kutta to be able to increase step size and reduce render times, but with the future possibility of leaving the choice of integration method to the user). Then what I obtain is just the actual lightlike geodesic; with \(T\) a parameter running along it (distinct from both Schwarzschild \(t\) and proper time, that doesn't exist).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2018 17:09:01 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>pablode</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://rantonels.github.io/starless/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>