<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Cancer Complications: Confusing Bills, Maddening Errors And Endless Phone Calls</title>
<link>https://www.npr.org/sections/health-shots/2019/02/26/696321475/cancer-complications-confusing-bills-maddening-errors-and-endless-phone-calls</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.npr.org/sections/health-shots/2019/02/26/696321475/cancer-complications-confusing-bills-maddening-errors-and-endless-phone-calls</guid>
<description>&lt;div id=&quot;res696364835&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap image large&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;imagewrap&quot; data-crop-type=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2019/02/20/cancer-bils-1_custom-44765deae50cd53f6d1070357d608f8191f8ad39-s1100-c15.jpg&quot; data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2019/02/20/cancer-bils-1_custom-44765deae50cd53f6d1070357d608f8191f8ad39-s1100.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img lazyOnLoad&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;credit-caption&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-wrap&quot; readability=&quot;7.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image caption&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carol Marley, a hospital nurse with private insurance, says coping with the financial fallout of her pancreatic cancer has been exhausting. &lt;strong class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Anna Gorman/KHN&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong class=&quot;hide-caption&quot;&gt;hide caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;strong class=&quot;toggle-caption&quot;&gt;toggle caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Anna Gorman/KHN&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;enlarge_measure&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img_wrap&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2019/02/20/cancer-bils-1_enl-d225099ba04402ea4dd1a3f37f204aecfea6491e-s1200.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;enlarge_html&quot; readability=&quot;7.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image_data&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Carol Marley, a hospital nurse with private insurance, says coping with the financial fallout of her pancreatic cancer has been exhausting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Anna Gorman/KHN&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carol Marley wants everyone to know what a life-threatening cancer diagnosis looks like in America today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, it's the chemotherapy that leaves you weak and unable to walk across the room. Yes, it's the litany of tests and treatments – the CT scans and MRIs and biopsies and endoscopies and surgeries and blood draws and radiation and doctor visits. Yes, it's envisioning your funeral, which torments you day and night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But none of these is her most gnawing, ever present concern.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That would be the convoluted medical bills that fill multiple binders, depleted savings accounts that destroy early retirement plans and so, so many phone calls with insurers and medical providers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;I have faith in God that my cancer is not going to kill me,&quot; says Marley, who lives in Round Rock, Texas. &quot;I have a harder time believing that this is gonna get straightened out and isn't gonna harm us financially. That's the leap of faith that I'm struggling with.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coping with the financial fallout of cancer is exhausting — and nerve-wracking. But the worst part, Marley says, is that it's unexpected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When she was diagnosed with adenocarcinoma of the pancreas head in July, she didn't anticipate so many bills, or so many billing mistakes. After all, she is a hospital nurse with good private insurance that has allowed her access to high-quality doctors and hospitals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id=&quot;ad-backstage-wrap&quot; aria-label=&quot;advertisement&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;Randall Marley, a computer systems engineer, says he frequently comes home from work to find his wife feeling unwell and frustrated about having spent a precious day of her recovery making phone calls to understand and dispute medical bills. One recent night she was in tears and &quot;emotionally at a breaking point,&quot; he says. &quot;The hardest part of this is seeing the toll it's taken on my wife.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stress-inducing bills accumulate&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More than 42 percent of the 9.5 million people diagnosed with cancer from 2000 to 2012 drained their life's assets within two years, according to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amjmed.com/article/S0002-9343(18)30509-6/fulltext&quot;&gt;study published last year&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;em&gt;American Journal of Medicine&lt;/em&gt;. Cancer patients are 2.65 times &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4240626/&quot;&gt;more likely to file&lt;/a&gt; for bankruptcy than those without cancer, and bankruptcy puts them at a higher risk for early death, according to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4933128/&quot;&gt;research&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But those statistics don't convey the daily misery of a patient with a life-threatening disease trying to navigate the convoluted financial demands of the U.S. health care system while simultaneously facing a roller coaster of treatment and healing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stephanie Wheeler, a professor at the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, said the number of bills coming from different providers can be overwhelming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;It's oftentimes multiple different bills that are rolling in over a period of several months and sometimes years,&quot; says Wheeler, who has conducted &lt;a href=&quot;https://meetinglibrary.asco.org/record/166359/abstract&quot;&gt;survey research&lt;/a&gt; with metastatic cancer patients. &quot;As those bills start to accumulate, it can be very stress inducing.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given that many patients can't work during treatment, these bills may force even relatively well-to-do cancer patients to take out second mortgages, spend college savings or worry about leaving debt behind for their families, Wheeler says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carol Marley is a slight woman who dotes on her two dogs and is involved in her church. Her 88-year-old father, who has dementia, had moved in a few years earlier. She and her husband, Randall, pride themselves on living frugally. They pay their credit card off every month and don't have car payments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carol and her daughter, June Marley, who is a second-year college student, have health insurance through Carol's employer, Ascension Health, a large faith-based health care system with facilities across the nation. Carol's husband has separate insurance through his job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They were hoping to retire early, buy an RV and drive around the country. Instead, they see their meticulous plans disappearing, even if Carol recovers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their high-deductible insurance policy meant they had to spend $6,000 before their insurance started covering her treatment expenses. They hit their annual out-of-pocket maximum of $10,000 well before the year was over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Carol says she was prepared for that. &quot;What I didn't anticipate is the knock-down, drag-out fight that I would have to engage in to get people to see there were errors and address it.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since she's unable to work, the family lost her nursing salary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Money is not coming in, and it's going out by the thousands,&quot; she says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;From nurse to patient&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carol had treated cancer patients before. She had seen them come in with unexplained aches and leave with devastating diagnoses. Now it was her turn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though she didn't recognize it at the time, her symptoms were textbook. Fatigue. Back pain. Weight loss. In July, doctors told her she had pancreatic cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her first thought was that she was going to die. One nurse friend asked if she had her affairs in order. That's because pancreatic cancer is usually discovered too late. Just 9 percent of patients are alive five years after diagnosis, compared with 90 percent of breast cancer patients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carol knew she was lucky. Hers hadn't spread. She might be able to undergo surgery. But first, four months of chemotherapy and five weeks of radiation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;res696366892&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap image medium&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;imagewrap&quot; data-crop-type=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2019/02/20/cancer-bills-2_custom-a97c6d29c7656321001f39d6bcb9c38f0295323b-s800-c15.jpg&quot; data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2019/02/20/cancer-bills-2_custom-a97c6d29c7656321001f39d6bcb9c38f0295323b-s800.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img lazyOnLoad&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;credit-caption&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-wrap&quot; readability=&quot;7.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image caption&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After Carol Marley was diagnosed with pancreatic cancer last July, she worried what it would mean for her family, including her 88-year-old father with dementia. &lt;strong class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Anna Gorman/KHN&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong class=&quot;hide-caption&quot;&gt;hide caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;strong class=&quot;toggle-caption&quot;&gt;toggle caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Anna Gorman/KHN&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;enlarge_measure&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img_wrap&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2019/02/20/cancer-bills-2_enl-d5b5722ce1690e853cfd767850de5eb5dd7f82ae-s1200.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;enlarge_html&quot; readability=&quot;7.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image_data&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;After Carol Marley was diagnosed with pancreatic cancer last July, she worried what it would mean for her family, including her 88-year-old father with dementia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Anna Gorman/KHN&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The chemotherapy — seven or eight rounds, she can't quite remember — drained her. &quot;I couldn't put words together in my head,&quot; she says. She had muscle spasms and developed fevers that landed her in the emergency room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As she became weaker, Carol realized she could no longer care for her father at home. On a recent morning in early January, she sat down with a nurse from a memory-care facility where a space had become available. Holding back tears, Carol told the nurse she knew this day would come. &quot;I didn't think it would be so soon, and I didn't know under these circumstances.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Different insurers lead to different bills&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later that same day, Carol's energy was up. She adjusted the colorful scarf on her head, turned on her computer and pulled out a pen. Some days she spends hours trying to clarify and fix medical bills. &quot;But I don't do that frequently because it is so fruitless and it is stressful,&quot; she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Often, she is just trying to figure out what different bills mean. &quot;Even as a nurse, I feel like it's impossible to understand,&quot; she said. &quot;I can't make heads or tails of it.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes there are errors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part of the problem, she contends, is that one insurance company covers visits with Ascension providers and hospitals and another company covers pharmacy claims, specialty drugs and providers outside Ascension's network. Some of the bills, including a $1,400 one from an ER visit — were sent to the wrong insurer, she says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carol cites other issues. An $18,400 chemotherapy bill was submitted with missing information and then denied because it arrived late. An $870 MRI bill was denied because the provider said there was no pre-authorization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;It's not any one individual. It's not any one system or provider,&quot; she says. &quot;The whole system is messed up. ... There's no recourse for me except to just keep making phone calls.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On this particular afternoon, Carol has a long list of calls to make. One to figure out why she couldn't access her insurance claims online. Another to a medical provider that urged her to pay $380, even though it acknowledged that it owed her about $80 of that total.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Someone who answers the phone suggests again that Carol pay the entire amount. &quot;Once it's posted to your account and it goes through, we would send you a check,&quot; the woman says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carol shakes her head. &quot;I'm sure y'all are fine people over there, but I'm not trusting a refund to come,&quot; she responds, reflecting on her experience as a consumer of cancer care. &quot;The problem is, they want their money and they are going to get it one way or the other.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for her hospital bills, Ascension declined to comment, citing protected health information. But spokesman Nick Ragone said, &quot;The matter at issue was favorably resolved.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He didn't say which issue was resolved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kaiser Health News is a nonprofit news service covering health issues. It is an editorially independent program of the Kaiser Family Foundation and is not affiliated with Kaiser Permanente.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 16:29:50 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>thebent</dc:creator>
<og:title>Cancer Complications: Confusing Bills, Maddening Errors And Endless Phone Calls</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.npr.org/sections/health-shots/2019/02/26/696321475/cancer-complications-confusing-bills-maddening-errors-and-endless-phone-calls</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>A Texas woman with pancreatic cancer spends most of her days on the phone doing battle with insurers and billing departments. Finances are her most gnawing, ever present concern.</og:description>
<og:image>https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2019/02/20/cancer-bils-1_wide-20763e82a078ce5c13ecf1c7807d6be5f1dd26cf.jpg?s=1400</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.npr.org/sections/health-shots/2019/02/26/696321475/cancer-complications-confusing-bills-maddening-errors-and-endless-phone-calls</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Immersive Linear Algebra</title>
<link>http://immersivemath.com/ila/index.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://immersivemath.com/ila/index.html</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;meta http-equiv=&quot;content-type&quot; content=&quot;text/html; charset=utf-8&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;viewport&quot; content=&quot;width=device-width initial-scale=1.0, user-scalable=no&quot;/&gt;&lt;title&gt;Immersive Math&lt;/title&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; href=&quot;css/la.css&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta http-equiv=&quot;X-UA-Compatible&quot; content=&quot;IE=edge&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;viewport&quot; content=&quot;width=device-width, initial-scale=1&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;description&quot; content=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;author&quot; content=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;title&gt;immersivemath: Immersive Linear Algebra&lt;/title&gt;&lt;link href=&quot;../bootstrap/css/bootstrap.min.css&quot; rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot;/&gt;&lt;link href=&quot;../bootstrap/jumbotron-narrow.css&quot; rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot;/&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body onload=&quot;onLoad()&quot; onresize=&quot;onResize()&quot; oncontextmenu=&quot;return false;&quot; id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot; readability=&quot;20.144952545298&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;container&quot; readability=&quot;7.7480586712683&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will be replaced with browser width stuff!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;jumbotron&quot; readability=&quot;9.7723214285714&quot;&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot;&gt;by J. Ström, K. Åström, and T. Akenine-Möller&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;v0.82.1. ISBN: 978-91-637-9354-7&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot;&gt;The world's first linear algebra book with fully interactive figures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;btn btn-lg btn-success&quot; href=&quot;http://immersivemath.com/ila/learnmore.html&quot; role=&quot;button&quot;&gt;Learn More&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Check us out on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/immersivemath&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/immersivemath&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 16:05:07 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>reverse</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://immersivemath.com/ila/index.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Heat Your House with a Water Brake Windmill</title>
<link>https://www.lowtechmagazine.com/2019/02/heat-your-house-with-a-water-brake-windmill.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.lowtechmagazine.com/2019/02/heat-your-house-with-a-water-brake-windmill.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Illustration: &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ronabinay.com&quot;&gt;Rona Binay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; for Low-tech Magazine.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Given the right conditions, a mechanical windmill with an oversized brake system is a cheap, effective, and sustainable heating system.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span&gt;Heat versus Electricity&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a global scale, thermal energy demand corresponds to one third of the primary energy supply, while electricity demand is only one-fifth. [&lt;span&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;] In temperate or cold climates, the share of thermal energy is even higher. For example in the UK, heat counts for almost half of total energy use. [&lt;span&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;] If we only look at households, thermal energy for space and water heating in temperate and cold climates can be 60-80% of total domestic energy demand. [&lt;span&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In spite of this, renewable energy sources play a negligible role in heat production. The main exception is the traditional use of biomass for cooking and heating – but in the “developed” world even biomass is often used to produce electricity instead of heat. The use of direct solar heat and geothermal heat provide less than 1% and 0.2% of global heat demand, respectively [&lt;span&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;] [&lt;span&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;]. While renewable energy sources account for more than 20% of global electricity demand (mostly hydroelectric), they only account for 10% of global heat demand (mostly biomass). [&lt;span&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;] [&lt;span&gt;6&lt;/span&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span&gt;Direct versus Indirect Heat Production&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Electricity produced by renewable energy sources can be – and is being – converted to heat in an indirect way. For example, a wind turbine converts its rotational energy into electricity by the use of its electrical generator, and this electricity can then be converted into heat using an electric heater, an electric boiler, or an electric heat pump. The result is heat generated by wind energy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In particular, the electric heat pump is promoted by many governments and organisations as a sustainable solution for renewable heat generation. However, solar and wind energy can also be used in a direct way, without converting them to electricity first – and of course the same applies to biomass. Direct heat production is cheaper, more energy efficient, and more sustainable than indirect heat production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;asset-img-link&quot; href=&quot;https://krisdedecker.typepad.com/.a/6a00e0099229e88833022ad3c530c2200d-pi&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;asset asset-image at-xid-6a00e0099229e88833022ad3c530c2200d img-responsive&quot; alt=&quot;heat generating windmills&quot; title=&quot;heat generating windmills&quot; src=&quot;https://krisdedecker.typepad.com/.a/6a00e0099229e88833022ad3c530c2200d-500wi&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Prototypes of heat generating windmills, built by Esra L. Sorensen in 1974. Photo by Claus Nybroe. Source: [13]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The direct alternative for solar photovoltaic power is solar thermal power, a technology that appeared in the nineteenth century following cheaper production technologies for glass and mirrors. Solar thermal energy can be used for water heating, space heating or industrial processes, and this is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lowtechmagazine.com/2011/07/solar-powered-factories.html&quot;&gt;2-3 times as energy efficient compared to following the indirect path involving electricity conversion&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Almost nobody knows that a windmill can produce heat directly.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The direct alternative for wind power that everybody knows is the old-fashioned windmill, which is at least 2.000 years old. It transferred the rotational energy from its wind rotor directly to the axis of a machine, for example for sawing wood or grinding grain. This &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lowtechmagazine.com/2009/10/history-of-industrial-windmills.html&quot;&gt;old-fashioned approach remains relevant&lt;/a&gt;, also in combination with new technology, because it would be more energy efficient compared to first converting the energy to electricity, and then back to rotational energy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, an old-fashioned windmill can not only provide mechanical energy, but also thermal energy. The problem is that almost nobody knows this. Even the International Energy Agency doesn't mention direct conversion of wind into heat when it presents all possible options for renewable heat production. [&lt;span&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span&gt;The Water Brake Windmill&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heat generating windmills convert rotational energy directly into heat by generating friction in water, using a so-called “water brake” or “Joule Machine”. A heat generator based on this principle is basically a wind-powered mixer or impeller installed into an insulated tank filled with water. Due to friction among molecules of the water, mechanical energy is converted into heat energy. The heated water can be pumped into a building for heating or washing, and the same concept could be applied to industrial processes in a factory that require relatively low temperatures. [&lt;span&gt;7&lt;/span&gt;] [&lt;span&gt;8&lt;/span&gt;] [&lt;span&gt;9&lt;/span&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;asset-img-link&quot; href=&quot;https://krisdedecker.typepad.com/.a/6a00e0099229e88833022ad39f1e05200c-pi&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;asset asset-image at-xid-6a00e0099229e88833022ad39f1e05200c img-responsive&quot; alt=&quot;Drawing of heat generating windmill&quot; title=&quot;Drawing of heat generating windmill&quot; src=&quot;https://krisdedecker.typepad.com/.a/6a00e0099229e88833022ad39f1e05200c-500wi&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;Drawing of a heating system based on a water brake windmill. Source: [8]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Joule Machine was originally conceived as a measuring apparatus. James Joule built it in the 1840s for his famous measurement of the mechanical equivalent of heat: one &lt;span&gt;Joule&lt;/span&gt; calorie equals the amount of energy required to raise the temperature of 1 cubic centimeter of water by 1 degree Celsius. [&lt;span&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;A heat generator based on this principle is basically a wind-powered mixer or impeller installed into an insulated tank filled with water&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most fascinating thing about water brake windmills is that, hypothetically, they could have been built hundreds or even thousands of years ago. They require simple materials: wood and/or metal. But although we cannot exclude their use in pre-industrial times, the first reference to heat producing windmills dates from the 1970s, when the Danes started building them in the wake of the first oil crisis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;asset-img-link&quot; href=&quot;https://krisdedecker.typepad.com/.a/6a00e0099229e88833022ad3e4dc65200b-pi&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;asset asset-image at-xid-6a00e0099229e88833022ad3e4dc65200b img-responsive&quot; alt=&quot;heat generator windmill&quot; title=&quot;heat generator windmill&quot; src=&quot;https://krisdedecker.typepad.com/.a/6a00e0099229e88833022ad3e4dc65200b-500wi&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;Drawing of the heat generator of a heat generating windmill. Source: [8]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the time, Denmark was almost entirely dependent on imported oil for heating, which left many households in the cold when the oil supply was disturbed. Because the Danes already had a strong DIY-culture for small wind turbines generating electricity on farms, they started building windmills to heat their houses. Some chose the indirect path, converting wind generated electricity into heat using electric heating appliances. Others, however, developed mechanical windmills that produced heat directly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span&gt;Cheaper to Build and More Efficient to Operate&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The direct approach to heat production is considerably cheaper and more sustainable than converting wind or solar generated electricity into heat by using electric heating devices, including an electric heat pump. There’s two reasons for this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, mechanical windmills are less complex, which makes them more affordable and less resource-intensive to build, and which increases their lifetime. In a water brake windmill, electric generator, power converters, transformer and gearbox can be excluded, and because of the weight savings, the windmill needs to be less sturdy built. The Joule Machine has lower weight, smaller size, and lower costs than an electrical generator. [&lt;span&gt;11&lt;/span&gt;] Equally important is that the cost of thermal storage is 60-70% lower compared to batteries or the use of backup thermal power plants. [&lt;span&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;asset-img-link&quot; href=&quot;https://krisdedecker.typepad.com/.a/6a00e0099229e88833022ad3c536a7200d-pi&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;asset asset-image at-xid-6a00e0099229e88833022ad3c536a7200d img-responsive&quot; alt=&quot;Heat-generating-windmill-water-brake&quot; title=&quot;Heat-generating-windmill-water-brake&quot; src=&quot;https://krisdedecker.typepad.com/.a/6a00e0099229e88833022ad3c536a7200d-500wi&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;A water brake windmill built at the Institute for Agricultural Techniques in 1974. Photo by Ricard Matzen. Source: [13]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, converting wind or solar energy directly into heat (or mechanical energy) is more energy efficient than when electric conversion is involved. This means that less solar and wind energy converters – and thus less space and resources – are needed to supply a certain amount of heat. In short, the heat generating windmill addresses the main disadvantages of wind power: its low power density, and its &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lowtechmagazine.com/2017/09/how-to-run-modern-society-on-solar-and-wind-powe.html&quot;&gt;intermittency&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Mechanical windmills are less complex, which makes them more affordable and less resource-intensive to build, and which increases their lifetime&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, direct heat generation greatly improves the economics and the sustainability of smaller types of windmills. Tests have shown that small wind turbines – producing electricity – are &lt;a href=&quot;http://theoildrum.com.s3-website.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/node/6954&quot;&gt;very inefficient and don’t always generate as much energy as was needed to produce them&lt;/a&gt;. [&lt;span&gt;12&lt;/span&gt;] However, using similar models for heat production decreases embodied energy and costs, increases lifetime, and improves efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span&gt;How Much Heat Can a Windmill Produce?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Danish water brake windmill from the 1970s was a relatively small machine, with a rotor diameter of around 6 meters and a height of around 12 meters. Larger heat generating windmills were built in the 1980s. Most used simple wooden blades. In total, at least a dozen different models have been documented, both DIY and commercial models. [&lt;span&gt;7&lt;/span&gt;] Many were built with used car parts and other discarded materials. [&lt;span&gt;13&lt;/span&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the smaller early Danish heat generating windmills was officially tested. The Calorius type 37 – which had a rotor diameter of 5 meters and a height of 9 meters – produced 3.5 kilowatt of heat at a wind speed of 11 m/s (a strong breeze, Beaufort 6). This is comparable to the heat output of the smallest electric boilers for space heating. From 1993 to 2000, the Danish firm Westrup built a total of 34 water brake windmills based on this design, and by 2012 there were still 17 in operation. [&lt;span&gt;7&lt;/span&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;asset-img-link&quot; href=&quot;https://krisdedecker.typepad.com/.a/6a00e0099229e88833022ad39f5c4e200c-pi&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;asset asset-image at-xid-6a00e0099229e88833022ad39f5c4e200c img-responsive&quot; alt=&quot;Calorius-windmill&quot; title=&quot;Calorius-windmill&quot; src=&quot;https://krisdedecker.typepad.com/.a/6a00e0099229e88833022ad39f5c4e200c-320wi&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;A Calorius windmill producing up to 4 kW of heat. Image provided by the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.folkecenter.eu&quot;&gt;Nordic Folkecenter in Denmark&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A much larger water brake windmill (7.5m rotor diameter, 17m tower) was built in 1982 by the Svaneborg brothers, and heated the house of one of them (the other brother opted for a wind turbine and an electric heating system). The windmill, which had three fiberglass blades, produced up to 8 kilowatt of heat according to non-official measurements – comparable to the heat output of an electric boiler for a modest home. [&lt;span&gt;7&lt;/span&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further into the 1980s, Knud Berthou built the most sophisticated heat generating windmill to date: the LO-FA. In other models, heat generation happened at the bottom of the tower – from the top of the windmill there was a shaft down to the bottom where the water brake was installed. However, in the LO-FA windmill all mechanical parts for energy conversion were moved to the top of the tower. The lower 10 meters of the 20 meter high tower were filled up with 15 tonnes of water in an insulated reservoir. Consequently, hot water could literally be tapped out of the windmill. [&lt;span&gt;7&lt;/span&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The tower of the LO-FA windmill was filled up with 15 tonnes of water in an insulated tank: hot water could literally be tapped out of the windmill.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The LO-FA was also the largest of the heat generating windmills, with a 12 meter diameter rotor. Its heat output was estimated to be 90 kilowatt at a wind speed of 14 m/s (Beaufort 7). This results seems to be excessive compared to the other heat generating windmills, but the energy output of a windmill increases more than proportionally with the rotor diameter and the wind speed. Furthermore, the friction liquid in the water brake was not water but hydraulic oil, which can be heated up to much higher temperatures. The oil then transferred its heat to the water storage in the tower. [&lt;span&gt;7&lt;/span&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span&gt;Renewed Interest&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interest in heat generating windmills resurfaced a few years ago, although for now it concerns only a handful of scientific studies. In a 2011 paper, German and UK scientists write that “small and remote households in northern regions demand thermal energy rather than electricity, and therefore wind turbines in such places should be build for thermal energy generation”. [&lt;span&gt;8&lt;/span&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers explain and illustrate the workings of the water brake windmill, and calculate the optimal performance of the technology. It was found that the torque-speed characteristics of wind rotor and impeller should be carefully matched to achieve maximum efficiency. For example, for the very small Savonius windmill that the scientists used as a model (0.5m rotor diameter, 2m tower), it was calculated that the impeller diameter should be 0.388m. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;asset-img-link&quot; href=&quot;https://krisdedecker.typepad.com/.a/6a00e0099229e88833022ad39f1e9a200c-pi&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;asset asset-image at-xid-6a00e0099229e88833022ad39f1e9a200c img-responsive&quot; alt=&quot;heat production direct wind energy&quot; title=&quot;heat production direct wind energy&quot; src=&quot;https://krisdedecker.typepad.com/.a/6a00e0099229e88833022ad39f1e9a200c-700wi&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers then ran simulations over a period of fifty hours to calculate the windmill’s heat output. Although the Savonius is a low speed windmill which is ill-suited for electricity generation, it turns out to be an excellent producer of heat: the small windmill produced up to 1 kW of thermal power (at wind speeds of 15 m/s). [&lt;span&gt;8&lt;/span&gt;] A 2013 study using a prototype obtained similar results, and calculated the efficiency of the system to be 91%. [&lt;span&gt;9&lt;/span&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;A 2013 study using a prototype calculated the efficiency of the system to be 91%&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously, it’s not always stormy weather, which means that the average wind speed is at least as important. A 2015 study investigates the possibilities of heat generating windmills in Lithuania, a Baltic country with a cold climate that’s dependent on expensive fuel imports. [&lt;span&gt;14&lt;/span&gt;] The researchers calculated that at the average wind speed in the country (4 m/s of Beaufort 3), generating one kilowatt of heat requires a windmill with a rotor diameter of 8.2 meters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;asset-img-link&quot; href=&quot;https://krisdedecker.typepad.com/.a/6a00e0099229e88833022ad3c53115200d-pi&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;asset asset-image at-xid-6a00e0099229e88833022ad3c53115200d img-responsive&quot; alt=&quot;heat generating windmill 1975&quot; title=&quot;heat generating windmill 1975&quot; src=&quot;https://krisdedecker.typepad.com/.a/6a00e0099229e88833022ad3c53115200d-500wi&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;A heat generating windmill with a water brake, placed inside the bottom of the tower. The mill was built by Jorgen Andersen in 1975, and stood in Serritslev. Photo by Claus Nybroe. Source: [13]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They compare this with the thermal energy demand of a 120 m2 energy efficient new building, heated to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lowtechmagazine.com/2015/02/heating-people-not-spaces.html&quot;&gt;modern comfort standards&lt;/a&gt;, and conclude that a heat generating windmill could cover from 40-75% of the annual heating needs (depending on the energy efficiency class of the construction). [&lt;span&gt;14&lt;/span&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span&gt;Heat Storage&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The average wind speed is not guaranteed either, which means that a heat generating windmill requires heat storage – otherwise it would only provide heating when the wind blows. One cubic meter of heated water (1 ton, 1,000 liters) can hold up to 90 kWh of heat, which is roughly one to two days of supply for a household of four persons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;asset-img-link&quot; href=&quot;https://krisdedecker.typepad.com/.a/6a00e0099229e88833022ad3e522c5200b-pi&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;asset asset-image at-xid-6a00e0099229e88833022ad3e522c5200b img-responsive&quot; alt=&quot;Thermal-windmill&quot; title=&quot;Thermal-windmill&quot; src=&quot;https://krisdedecker.typepad.com/.a/6a00e0099229e88833022ad3e522c5200b-500wi&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The same windmill as the one pictured above, seen from below. Source: [7]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Providing enough storage to bridge a week without wind thus requires up to 7 tonnes of water, which corresponds to a volume of 7 cubic meters plus insulation. However, energy losses (self-discharge) should also be taken into account, and this explains why the Danish heat generating windmills usually had a storage tank holding ten to twenty thousand liters of water. [&lt;span&gt;13&lt;/span&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;A heat generating windmill can be combined with a solar boiler, so that both sun and wind can supply direct thermal energy using a smaller water tank.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A heat generating windmill can also be combined with a solar boiler, so that both sun and wind can supply direct thermal energy using the same heat storage reservoir. In this case, it becomes possible to build a pretty reliable heating system with a smaller heat storage tank, because the combination of two – often complementary – energy sources increases the chances of direct heat supply. Especially in less sunny climates, heat generating windmills are a great addition to a solar thermal system, because the latter produces relatively less heat during winter, when heat demand is at its maximum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span&gt;Retarders and Mechanical Heat Pumps&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most recent and extensive studies to date are from 2016 and 2018, and compare different types of heat generating windmills with different types of indirect heat generation. [&lt;span&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;] [&lt;span&gt;15&lt;/span&gt;] In this case, the windmills no longer make use of the original water brake, but produce heat with mechanical heat pumps or hydrodynamic retarders. A mechanical heat pump is simply a heat pump without the electric motor – instead, the wind rotor is directly connected to the compressor(s) of the heat pump, involving one less energy conversion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hydrodynamic retarder is well known as a brake system in heavy vehicles. Like a joule machine, it converts rotational energy into heat without the involvement of electricity. Retarders and mechanical heat pumps have the same advantages as Joule Machines, in the sense that they are much smaller, lighter, cheaper and more efficient than electrical generators. However, in this case a gearbox is required to achieve optimal efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;asset-img-link&quot; href=&quot;https://krisdedecker.typepad.com/.a/6a00e0099229e88833022ad39f1ed2200c-pi&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;asset asset-image at-xid-6a00e0099229e88833022ad39f1ed2200c img-responsive&quot; alt=&quot;direct versus indirect heat production wind&quot; title=&quot;direct versus indirect heat production wind&quot; src=&quot;https://krisdedecker.typepad.com/.a/6a00e0099229e88833022ad39f1ed2200c-500wi&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Different types of direct and indirect heating production compared. Source: [15]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The study compares heat generating windmills based on retarders and mechanical heat pumps with indirect heat production using electric boilers and electric heat pumps. It compares these four technologies for three system sizes: a small windmill aimed at heating an off-the-grid household, a large windmill aimed at supplying heat to a village, and a wind farm producing heat for 20,000 inhabitants. The four heating concepts are ranked based on their yearly capital and operational expenditures, assuming a lifespan of 20 years. [&lt;span&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;] [&lt;span&gt;15&lt;/span&gt;] &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Directly coupling a mechanical windmill to a mechanical heat pump is cheaper than using a gas boiler or the combination of a wind turbine and an electric heat pump.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the off-grid system, directly coupling a mechanical windmill to a mechanical heat pump is the cheapest option, while the combination of a wind turbine and an electric boiler is the most expensive one. All other technologies are in between. Taking into account both investment and operational costs, small-scale heat generating windmills with mechanical heat pumps are equally expensive or cheaper than conventional gas boilers when assuming the typical performance of a small windmill (which produces – over a period of one year – 12% to 22% of its maximum energy output).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;asset-img-link&quot; href=&quot;https://krisdedecker.typepad.com/.a/6a00e0099229e88833022ad3e522e5200b-pi&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;asset asset-image at-xid-6a00e0099229e88833022ad3e522e5200b img-responsive&quot; alt=&quot;Thermal-windmill3&quot; title=&quot;Thermal-windmill3&quot; src=&quot;https://krisdedecker.typepad.com/.a/6a00e0099229e88833022ad3e522e5200b-500wi&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Image: Water brake windmill developed by O. Helgason (left), water brake with variable load system (right). Images from “Test at very high wind speed of a windmill controlled by a water brake”, O. Helgason and &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;A.S.&lt;/span&gt; Sigurdson, Science Institute, University of Iceland. Source: [7]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, the combination of a small wind turbine and an electric heat pump requires a windmill with a “capacity factor” of at least 30% to become cost-competitive with gas heating – but such high performance is very unusual. Larger systems present the same rankings – the combination of mechanical windmills and mechanical heat pumps is the cheapest option – but they have up to three times lower capital costs due to economies of scale. Larger windmills have higher capacity factors (16-40%), which result in even larger cost savings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Due to the large energy losses for heat transportation, the heat generating windmill is at its best as a decentralised energy source, providing heat to an off-the-grid household or – in the optimal case – a small city.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, larger systems also reveal a problem when scaling up the technology: storing heat may be cheaper and more efficient than storing electricity, but the opposite holds true for transportation: the energy losses for heat transportation are much larger than the energy losses for electricity transmission. The scientists calculate that the maximum distance that is cost-achievable under optimal wind conditions is 50 km. [&lt;span&gt;15&lt;/span&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consequently, the heat generating windmill is at its best as a decentralised energy source, providing heat to an off-the-grid household or – in the optimal case – a relatively small town or city. For even larger systems, energy needs to be transported in the form of electricity, and in that case direct generation of heat – with all its benefits – becomes unattractive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span&gt;Blinded by Electricity&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heat generating windmills are also investigated for renewable electricity production, mainly because they offer a better solution for energy storage &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lowtechmagazine.com/2015/05/sustainability-off-grid-solar-power.html&quot;&gt;compared to batteries or other common technologies&lt;/a&gt;. [&lt;span&gt;16&lt;/span&gt;] In these systems, the generated heat is converted to electricity by the use of a steam turbine. The storage system is similar to that of a concentrated solar power plant (CSP), and the solar concentrators are replaced by heat generating windmills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;asset-img-link&quot; href=&quot;https://krisdedecker.typepad.com/.a/6a00e0099229e88833022ad3c5315d200d-pi&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;asset asset-image at-xid-6a00e0099229e88833022ad3c5315d200d img-responsive&quot; alt=&quot;Eddy current heater sobor&quot; title=&quot;Eddy current heater sobor&quot; src=&quot;https://krisdedecker.typepad.com/.a/6a00e0099229e88833022ad3c5315d200d-500wi&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;An &quot;eddy current heater&quot;. Source: [9]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because high temperatures are needed to produce electricity efficiently with a steam turbine, these systems can’t make use of joule machines or hydrodynamic retarders, but instead rely on a type of retarder called an “eddy current heater” (or “induction heater”). These are comprised of a magnet mounted on a rotating shaft, and can reach temperatures of up to 600 degrees Celsius. Using eddy current heaters, windmills could provide direct heat at higher temperatures, making their potential use in industry even larger. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, using the stored heat for electricity production is considerably more costly and less sustainable compared to using heat generating windmills for direct heat production. Converting the stored heat into electricity is at most 30% efficient, meaning that two thirds of the wind energy is lost due to needless energy conversions -- and the same is true &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lowtechmagazine.com/2011/07/solar-powered-factories.html&quot;&gt;when solar thermal is used for power production&lt;/a&gt;. [&lt;span&gt;15&lt;/span&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Direct heat production thus offers the possibility to save three times more greenhouse gas emissions and fossil fuels using the same number of windmills, which are also cheaper and more sustainable to build. Hopefully, direct heat production will be given the priority it deserves. Despite a warming climate, the demand for thermal energy is as high as ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kris De Decker&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Support Low-tech Magazine via &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.paypal.me/lowtechmagazine&quot;&gt;PayPal&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.patreon.com/lowtechmagazine&quot;&gt;Patreon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Nitto, Dipl-Ing Alejandro Nicolás, Carsten Agert, and Yvonne Scholz. &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://elib.dlr.de/103317/1/20160224%20-%20Master%20Thesis_NITTO.pdf&quot;&gt;WIND POWERED THERMAL ENERGY SYSTEMS (WTES)&lt;/a&gt;&quot;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.grin.com/document/384572&quot;&gt;Integration of Thermal Energy Storage into Energy Network&lt;/a&gt;, Sharyar Ahmed, 2017&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lowtechmagazine.com/2011/07/solar-powered-factories.html&quot;&gt;The bright future of solar thermal powered factories&lt;/a&gt;, Kris De Decker, Low-tech Magazine, 2011&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.iea-shc.org/Data/Sites/1/publications/Solar-Heat-Worldwide-2018.pdf&quot;&gt;Solar Heat Worldwide&lt;/a&gt;, edition 2018, International Energy Agency (IEA). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.iea.org/renewables2018/heat/&quot;&gt;Renewables 2018, Heat&lt;/a&gt;, International Energy Agency (IEA). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://data.worldbank.org/indicator/EG.ELC.RNEW.ZS&quot;&gt;World Bank: Renewable electricity output&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Rise of Modern Wind Energy: Wind Power for the World&lt;/em&gt;. Pan Stanford Publishing, 2013. See chapter 13 (&quot;Water brake windmills&quot;, Jørgen Krogsgaard) and chapter 16 (&quot;Consigned to Oblivion&quot;, Preben Maegaard). These seem to be the only English language documents on Danish water brake windmills.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chakirov, Roustiam, and Yuriy Vagapov. &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ipcbee.com/vol19/3-ICECS2011R00007.pdf&quot;&gt;Direct conversion of wind energy into heat using joule machine.&lt;/a&gt;&quot; &lt;em&gt;Fourth International Conference on Environmental and Computer Science (ICECS 2011), Singapore, Sept&lt;/em&gt;. 2011.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bulipi-eee.tuiasi.ro/archive/2013/fasc.4/p12_f4_2013.pdf&quot;&gt;SMALL WIND ENERGY SYSTEM WITH PERMANENT MAGNET EDDY CURRENT HEATER&lt;/a&gt;, BY ION SOBOR, VASILE RACHIER, ANDREI CHICIUC and RODION CIUPERCĂ. BULETINUL INSTITUTULUI POLITEHNIC DIN IAŞI. Publicat de Universitatea Tehnică „Gheorghe Asachi” din Iaşi Tomul LIX (LXIII), Fasc. 4, 2013&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://diposit.ub.edu/dspace/bitstream/2445/67342/1/TFG-Pou-Gallo-Marcos.pdf&quot;&gt;Joule’s experiment: An historico-critical approach&lt;/a&gt;, Marcos Pou Gallo Advisor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Okazaki, Toru, Yasuyuki Shirai, and Taketsune Nakamura. &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0960148115003079&quot;&gt;Concept study of wind power utilizing direct thermal energy conversion and thermal energy storage&lt;/a&gt;.&quot; &lt;em&gt;Renewable energy&lt;/em&gt; 83 (2015): 332-338.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://theoildrum.com.s3-website.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/node/6954&quot;&gt;Real-world tests of small wind turbines in Netherlands and the UK&lt;/a&gt;, Kris De Decker, The Oil Drum, 2010.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://windsofchange.dk/WOC-selfbuilders.php&quot;&gt;Selfbuilders&lt;/a&gt;, Winds of Change website, Erik Grove-Nielsen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Černeckienė, Jurgita, and Tadas Ždankus. &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Jurgita_Cerneckiene/publication/277568122_Usage_of_the_Wind_Energy_for_Heating_of_the_Energy-Efficient_Buildings_Analysis_of_Possibilities/links/5669301f08ae9da364ba0534.pdf&quot;&gt;Usage of the Wind Energy for Heating of the Energy-Efficient Buildings: Analysis of Possibilities&lt;/a&gt;.&quot; &lt;em&gt;Journal of Sustainable Architecture and Civil Engineering&lt;/em&gt; 10.1 (2015): 58-65.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cao, Karl-Kiên, et al. &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.researchgate.net/publication/327508878_Expanding_the_horizons_of_power-to-heat_Cost_assessment_for_new_space_heating_concepts_with_Wind_Powered_Thermal_Energy_Systems&quot;&gt;Expanding the horizons of power-to-heat: Cost assessment for new space heating concepts with Wind Powered Thermal Energy Systems&lt;/a&gt;.&quot; &lt;em&gt;Energy&lt;/em&gt; 164 (2018): 925-936.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Okazaki, Toru, Yasuyuki Shirai, and Taketsune Nakamura. &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0960148115003079&quot;&gt;Concept study of wind power utilizing direct thermal energy conversion and thermal energy storage&lt;/a&gt;.&quot; &lt;em&gt;Renewable energy&lt;/em&gt; 83 (2015): 332-338.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 15:30:35 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>nyc111</dc:creator>
<og:title>Heat your House with a Water Brake Windmill</og:title>
<og:type>blog</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.lowtechmagazine.com/2019/02/heat-your-house-with-a-water-brake-windmill.html</og:url>
<og:description>Given the right conditions, a mechanical windmill with an oversized brake system is a cheap, effective, and sustainable heating system.</og:description>
<og:image>https://krisdedecker.typepad.com/.a/6a00e0099229e88833022ad3c52bd2200d-600wi</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.lowtechmagazine.com/2019/02/heat-your-house-with-a-water-brake-windmill.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>We Need Chrome No More</title>
<link>https://redalemeden.com/blog/2019/we-need-chrome-no-more</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://redalemeden.com/blog/2019/we-need-chrome-no-more</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.chriskrycho.com/2018/assumed-audiences.html&quot;&gt;Assumed Audience&lt;/a&gt; — People interested in the open Web as a platform.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ten years ago, we needed Google Chrome to break the Web free from corporate greed, and we managed to do so for a brief period. Today, its dominance is stifling the very platform it once saved from the clutches of Microsoft. And no one, beside Google, needs that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-link&quot; href=&quot;https://redalemeden.com/static/5a553755771cf917fe6e9d36b9c125da/882d1/header-image.jpg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-background-image&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-image&quot; alt=&quot;Google Chrome&quot; title=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://redalemeden.com/static/5a553755771cf917fe6e9d36b9c125da/b89bd/header-image.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/static/5a553755771cf917fe6e9d36b9c125da/884cb/header-image.jpg 185w, /static/5a553755771cf917fe6e9d36b9c125da/2f2b6/header-image.jpg 370w, /static/5a553755771cf917fe6e9d36b9c125da/b89bd/header-image.jpg 740w, /static/5a553755771cf917fe6e9d36b9c125da/de5d7/header-image.jpg 1110w, /static/5a553755771cf917fe6e9d36b9c125da/09a4a/header-image.jpg 1480w, /static/5a553755771cf917fe6e9d36b9c125da/882d1/header-image.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 740px) 100vw, 740px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s 2008. Microsoft still held a firm grip on the browser market. Six years had gone by since Mozilla released Firefox, a direct competitor to Internet Explorer. Google—the search engine company that everyone grew to love at the time—announced that they’re entering the ring. Chrome was born.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within two years, Chrome accounted for 15% of all Web traffic on desktop—for comparison, it took Firefox 6 years to get there. Google managed to deliver a fast, thoughtfully designed browser that was an instant hit among users and Web developers alike. Their product innovation and engineering prowess was a breath of fresh air, and their commitment to open-source was the cherry on top. Over the years, Google‘s adoption of Web standards continued to set the example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast-forward a decade later. The browser landscape looks vastly different. Chrome is the most ubiquitous browser on the planet, making Google the de facto gatekeeper of the Web on both mobile and desktop in all but a handful of regions around the world. The browser comes preinstalled in most Android handsets sold outside of China, and serves as the UI layer of &lt;em&gt;Chrome OS&lt;/em&gt;, Google’s foray into desktop and tablet operating systems. What started as an avant-garde, standard-compliant browser is now a sprawling platform that spares no area of modern computing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the Chrome browser itself is not open-source, most of its innards are. Chromium, the non-proprietary subset of Chrome, was open-sourced early on with a generously permissive license as a sign of commitment to the open Web community. As a full-featured browser, Chromium became widely popular among Linux users. As an open-source project, it has gained a large following in the open-source ecosystem, often used as a the foundation of other browsers and applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both Chrome and Chromium run Blink under the hood, the rendering engine that started as a WebKit fork in 2013 when Google grew dissatisfied with the Apple-led project. Blink continued to grow since and will pick even more steam when Microsoft will &lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.windows.com/windowsexperience/2018/12/06/microsoft-edge-making-the-web-better-through-more-open-source-collaboration/&quot;&gt;start using it&lt;/a&gt; for their Edge browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Chrome platform has profoundly changed the Web. And then some. The adoption of Web technologies in desktop software development has seen an unprecedented rise in the last 5 years, with projects like Github’s Electron sweeping every major desktop OS as the de facto standard for cross-platform applications. Chrome OS, while still tiny compared to Windows and macOS, is gaining both mind and market share.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chrome is effectively everywhere you look. And that’s bad news.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;dont-be-evil&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://redalemeden.com/blog/2019/we-need-chrome-no-more/#dont-be-evil&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt; Don’t Be Evil&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dominance of Chrome has a major detrimental effect on the Web as an open platform: developers are increasingly shunning other browsers in their testing and bug-fixing routines. If it works as intended on Chrome, it’s ready to ship. This in turn results in more users flocking to the browser as their favorite Web sites and apps no longer work elsewhere, making developers less likely to spend time testing on other browsers. A vicious cycle that, if not broken, will result in most other browsers disappearing in the oblivion of irrelevance. And that’s exactly how you suffocate the open Web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to promoting this mono-browser culture, Google is leading the pack. Poor quality assurance and questionable design choices are just the tip of the iceberg when you look at Google’s apps and services outside the Chrome ecosystem. Making matters worse, the blame often lands on other vendors for “holding back the Web”. The Web is Google’s turf as it stands now; you either do as they do, or you are called out for being a laggard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without a healthy and balanced competition, any open platform will regress into some form of corporate control. For the Web, this means that its strongest selling points—freedom and universal accessibility—are eroded with every per-cent that Chrome gains in market share. This alone is cause for concern. But when we consider Google’s business model, the situation takes a scary turn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The raison d’être of any business is to make profit and keep shareholders happy. When growth happens to align with a good cause, it’s considered a competitive advantage. When it doesn’t, the PR and marketing departments are put to work. Google’s mantra of “Don’t be evil” fit their narrative at a time when their growth aligned with making the Web more open and accessible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alas, not anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company’s focus gradually shifted towards transforming their browser dominance into business growth. It also happens that Google’s business &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; search engine advertising and AdSense. Everything else is a measly 10% of their annual revenue. That in and of itself is not an issue, but when the line between the browser, the search engine, and online services is blurred, we have a problem. And a big one at that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Successful businesses capitalize on their competitive advantages. Unscrupulous ones abuse them when given free rein. When your browser &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.cryptographyengineering.com/2018/09/23/why-im-leaving-chrome/&quot;&gt;forces you to sign in&lt;/a&gt;, places cookies that &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.softpedia.com/news/chrome-69-does-not-delete-google-cookies-when-clearing-all-website-data-522884.shtml&quot;&gt;you can’t delete&lt;/a&gt;, and seeks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnet.com/news/google-may-break-ad-blockers-with-upcoming-chrome-change/&quot;&gt;neutralize ad-blocking and privacy extensions&lt;/a&gt;, something’s gone terribly wrong&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref-1&quot;/&gt;. Even more so when you factor the fact that every website contains at least one snippet of code that pings Google’s servers to track visitors, show them ads, or serve them custom fonts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In theory, these malpractices could be overlooked if the company involved had a good track record with handling personal data. In practice, however, Google is institutionally creepy, and they can’t help themselves. You might think that your personal data is nobody’s business, but they don’t seem to agree.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google’s business model requires a steady stream of data that can be analyzed and used to serve targeted ads. As a result, everything they do has to ultimately lead to expanding their user base and the time they spend on their properties. Even as personal computing shifted to mobile, Chrome remains an important cog in Google’s data aggregation machinery. Websites you visit and keywords you search are tracked and used to offer you a more “personalized” experience. Without a clear boundary between the browser and the search engine, it’s impractical to keep track of which knows what about you. In the end, we accept the trade-off and move on with our lives, just as Google’s product designers and engineers wanted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, Google have proven, on several occasions, that they have no empathy towards their end users. Their utmost priority was and remains advertisers’ interests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-look-ahead&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://redalemeden.com/blog/2019/we-need-chrome-no-more/#a-look-ahead&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt; A Look Ahead&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Healthy, user-centric competition is what brought us the best products and experiences since the early days of computers. With Chrome dominating the browser market at 60% and Chromium invading desktop computing on all 3 major platforms, we are entrusting a lot to a single company and ecosystem. An ecosystem that doesn’t seem concerned with performance, user experience, privacy, or pushing computing forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But we still have time to turn things around. We did this a decade ago and we &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; do it again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both Mozilla and Apple are doing a remarkable job at closing the Web standards gap that widened in the early years of Chrome. They are even noticeably ahead in areas such as performance, battery usage, privacy, and security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re stuck with Google services that don’t work on other engines, or rely on the Chrome DevTools to do your job, consider using Vivaldi&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref-2&quot;/&gt; instead. It’s not ideal—Chromium is still a Google property—but a step in the right direction nonetheless. Supporting smaller vendors and fostering browser diversity is critical to reverse, or at least slow down, the unhealthy growth of Chrome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been Chrome-free since 2014, and I’ve never looked back. Chances are you will do just as fine without it. You might like it as a browser. And you might not mind the privacy trade-offs it comes with. But the stakes are much higher than our individual preferences and affinities; an entire platform is on the verge of becoming yet another walled garden. And we have enough of those already. So let’s do what we can, while we can, to prevent that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;sources--further-reading&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://redalemeden.com/blog/2019/we-need-chrome-no-more/#sources--further-reading&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt; Sources &amp;amp; Further Reading&lt;/h3&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 15:07:33 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>kaishin</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://redalemeden.com/blog/2019/we-need-chrome-no-more/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>K3s – Lightweight Kubernetes</title>
<link>https://k3s.io</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://k3s.io</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;generator&quot; content=&quot;Hugo 0.54.0&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;viewport&quot; content=&quot;width=device-width, initial-scale=1&quot;/&gt;&lt;title&gt;k3s - Lightweight Kubernetes | k3s&lt;/title&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; href=&quot;https://k3s.io/sass/main.min.d3a5d0a15b7678e5ba69fc645b15666ef77270f91c55022856cddcbca2b3d39a.css?1551291115&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;apple-touch-icon&quot; sizes=&quot;76x76&quot; href=&quot;/apple-touch-icon.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;icon&quot; type=&quot;image/png&quot; sizes=&quot;32x32&quot; href=&quot;/favicon-32x32.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;icon&quot; type=&quot;image/png&quot; sizes=&quot;16x16&quot; href=&quot;/favicon-16x16.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;manifest&quot; href=&quot;/site.webmanifest&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;mask-icon&quot; href=&quot;/safari-pinned-tab.svg&quot; color=&quot;#5BBAD5&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;msapplication-TileColor&quot; content=&quot;#da532c&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;theme-color&quot; content=&quot;#ffffff&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:title&quot; content=&quot;k3s: Lightweight Kubernetes&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:description&quot; content=&quot;Easy to install. A binary of less than 40 MB. Uses only 512 MB of RAM.&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:image&quot; content=&quot;/thumbnail.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:image&quot; content=&quot;https://k3s.io/img/logo-square.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:url&quot; content=&quot;https://k3s.io&quot;/&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body class=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot; readability=&quot;25.706525911708&quot;&gt;
&lt;header&gt;
&lt;nav class=&quot;main-nav&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;flex-between wrap&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://k3s.io/&quot; class=&quot;logo&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://k3s.io/img/logo.svg?1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/nav&gt;&lt;/header&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;section&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wrap intro&quot; readability=&quot;9.3798449612403&quot;&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;7.7307692307692&quot;&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Easy to install. A binary of less than &lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;40 MB&lt;/span&gt;. Only &lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;512 MB of RAM&lt;/span&gt; required to run.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Join us on March 13, 2019 for an online meetup where we will demo k3s and answer your questions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;btn&quot; href=&quot;https://info.rancher.com/meetup-k3s-lightweight-kubernetes&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Sign up&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bg-light&quot; readability=&quot;10.85393258427&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;This shouldn’t take long…&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;
    curl -sfL https://get.k3s.io | sh -
    # Check for Ready node, takes maybe 30 seconds
    k3s kubectl get node
    &lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For detailed installation, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rancher/k3s/blob/master/README.md&quot;&gt;refer to the docs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section class=&quot;bg-primary text-center&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wrap&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;grid-two&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Great For&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;grid-four&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edge&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IoT&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CI&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ARM&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wrap&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why use k3s?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;grid-three&quot; readability=&quot;11.453793103448&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;box&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Optimized for ARM&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both ARM64 and ARMv7 are supported with binaries and multiarch images available for both. k3s works great from something as small as a Raspberry Pi or as large as an AWS a1.4xlarge 32GiB server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;box&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Simplified Operations&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;k3s is wrapped in a simple package that reduces the dependencies and steps needed to run a production Kubernetes cluster. Packaged as a single binary, k3s makes installation and upgrade as simple as copying a file. TLS certificates are automatically generated to ensure that all communication is secure by default.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;box&quot; readability=&quot;8.1142857142857&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Perfect for Edge&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;K3s is a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cncf.io/certification/software-conformance/&quot;&gt;Certified Kubernetes distribution&lt;/a&gt; designed for production workloads in unattended, resource-constrained, remote locations or inside IoT appliances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section class=&quot;bg-light&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;grid-two wrap&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What is this?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;k3s is a fully compliant production-grade Kubernetes distribution with the following changes:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://k3s.io/img/certified-kubernetes.png&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Legacy, alpha, non-default features are removed. Many of these features are not available in most Kubernetes clusters already.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed in-tree plugins (cloud providers and storage plugins) which can be replaced with out-of-tree add-ons.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added sqlite3 as the default storage mechanism. etcd3 is still available, but not the default.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wrapped in a simple launcher that handles a lot of the complexity of TLS and options.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;box&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Minimum System Requirements&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;underlined&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;Linux 3.10+&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;512 MB of ram per server&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;75 MB of ram per node&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;200 MB of disk space&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;x86_64, ARMv7, ARM64&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section class=&quot;black-white&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;black&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;black-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Removes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;underlined&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;Legacy and non-default features&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alpha features&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In-tree cloud providers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In-tree storage drivers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Docker (optional)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;white&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;white-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Adds&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;underlined&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;Simplified installation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SQLite3 support in addition to etcd&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TLS management&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automatic Manifest and Helm Chart management&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;containerd, CoreDNS, Flannel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wrap&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;How it Works&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://k3s.io/img/how-it-works.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section class=&quot;bg-light&quot; readability=&quot;1.9263157894737&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wrap&quot; readability=&quot;8.6684210526316&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;Quick Start&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;underlined&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;1. Download k3s - &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rancher/k3s/releases/latest&quot;&gt;latest release&lt;/a&gt;, x86_64, ARMv7, and ARM64 are supported&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2. Run server&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
      &lt;code&gt;
        sudo k3s server &amp;amp;
        # Kubeconfig is written to /etc/rancher/k3s/k3s.yaml
        sudo k3s kubectl get node

        # On a different node run the below. NODE_TOKEN comes from /var/lib/rancher/k3s/server/node-token
        # on your server
        sudo k3s agent —server https://myserver:6443 —token ${NODE_TOKEN}
      &lt;/code&gt;
    
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;footer class=&quot;bg-primary&quot; readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;© 2014-2019 Rancher Labs, INC. All rights Reserved.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;small&gt;k3s...almost as small as this fine print&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/footer&gt;&lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 06:29:19 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>kadel</dc:creator>
<og:title>k3s: Lightweight Kubernetes</og:title>
<og:description>Easy to install. A binary of less than 40 MB. Uses only 512 MB of RAM.</og:description>
<og:image>/thumbnail.jpg</og:image>
<og:url>https://k3s.io</og:url>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://k3s.io/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Nasa Happily Reports the Earth Is Greener</title>
<link>https://www.goodnewsnetwork.org/nasa-says-earth-is-greener-than-ever-thanks-to-china-and-india/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.goodnewsnetwork.org/nasa-says-earth-is-greener-than-ever-thanks-to-china-and-india/</guid>
<description>&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-120356&quot; src=&quot;https://www.goodnewsnetwork.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Asia-Greenery-Full-NASA-Earth-Observatory.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;750&quot; height=&quot;565&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.goodnewsnetwork.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Asia-Greenery-Full-NASA-Earth-Observatory.jpg 750w, https://www.goodnewsnetwork.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Asia-Greenery-Full-NASA-Earth-Observatory-326x246.jpg 326w, https://www.goodnewsnetwork.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Asia-Greenery-Full-NASA-Earth-Observatory-80x60.jpg 80w, https://www.goodnewsnetwork.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Asia-Greenery-Full-NASA-Earth-Observatory-696x524.jpg 696w, https://www.goodnewsnetwork.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Asia-Greenery-Full-NASA-Earth-Observatory-558x420.jpg 558w, https://www.goodnewsnetwork.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Asia-Greenery-Full-NASA-Earth-Observatory-600x452.jpg 600w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px&quot;/&gt;NASA Earth Observatory
&lt;p&gt;The world is literally a greener place than it was 20 years ago, and the data from NASA satellites has revealed a counterintuitive source for much of this new foliage: China and India.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This surprising new study shows that the two emerging countries with the world’s biggest populations are leading the improvement in greening on land. The effect stems mainly from ambitious &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodnewsnetwork.org/china-reassigning-60000-troops-plant-trees/&quot;&gt;tree planting programs in China&lt;/a&gt; and intensive agriculture in both countries. In 2017 alone, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodnewsnetwork.org/india-plants-record-breaking-66-million-trees-12-hours/&quot;&gt;India broke its own world record&lt;/a&gt; for the most trees planted after volunteers gathered to plant 66 million saplings in just 12 hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The greening phenomenon was first detected by researchers using satellite data in the mid-1990s, but they did not know whether human activity was one of its chief, direct causes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This new insight was made possible by a nearly 20-year-long data record from a NASA instrument orbiting the Earth on two satellites. It’s called the Moderate Resolution Imaging Spectroradiometer, or MODIS, and its high-resolution data provides very accurate information, helping researchers work out details of what’s happening with Earth’s vegetation, down to the level of 500 meters, or about 1,600 feet, on the ground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WATCH&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a title=&quot;Island on the Brink of Disaster Plants Thousands of Trees and is Now a Poster Kid for Adapting to Climate Change&quot; href=&quot;https://www.goodnewsnetwork.org/kokota-island-adapts-to-climate-change-by-planting-thousands-of-trees/&quot; rel=&quot;bookmark&quot;&gt;Island on the Brink of Disaster Plants Thousands of Trees and is Now a Poster Kid for Adapting to Climate Change&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taken all together, the greening of the planet over the last two decades represents an increase in leaf area on plants and trees equivalent to the area covered by all the Amazon rainforests. There are now more than two million square miles of extra green leaf area per year, compared to the early 2000s – which amounts to a 5% increase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“China and India account for one-third of the greening, but contain only 9% of the planet’s land area covered in vegetation – a surprising finding, considering the general notion of land degradation in populous countries from overexploitation,” said Chi Chen of the Department of Earth and Environment at Boston University and lead author of the study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MORE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a title=&quot;People Have Passively Planted Over 30 Million Trees Simply by Surfing the Web&quot; href=&quot;https://www.goodnewsnetwork.org/people-have-passively-planted-over-30-million-trees-simply-by-surfing-the-web/&quot; rel=&quot;bookmark&quot;&gt;People Have Passively Planted Over 30 Million Trees Simply by Surfing the Web&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An advantage of the MODIS satellite sensor is the intensive coverage it provides, both in space and time: MODIS has captured as many as four shots of every place on Earth, every day for the last 20 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This long-term data lets us dig deeper,” said Rama Nemani, a research scientist at NASA’s Ames Research Center and a co-author of the new work. “When the greening of the Earth was first observed, we thought it was due to a warmer, wetter climate and fertilization from the added carbon dioxide in the atmosphere, leading to more leaf growth in northern forests, for instance. Now, with the MODIS data that lets us understand the phenomenon at really small scales, we see that humans are also contributing.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodnewsnetwork.org/tag/china/&quot;&gt;China’s&lt;/a&gt; outsized contribution to the global greening trend comes in large part (42%) from programs to conserve and expand forests. These were developed in an effort to reduce the effects of soil erosion, air pollution and climate change. Another 32% there – and 82% of the greening seen in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodnewsnetwork.org/tag/india/&quot;&gt;India&lt;/a&gt; – comes from intensive cultivation of food crops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHECK OUT&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a title=&quot;German 12-Year-old Boy Plants 1Million Trees, Takes Over UN Program to Plant a Trillion More&quot; href=&quot;https://www.goodnewsnetwork.org/german-12-year-old-boy-plants-1million-trees-takes-over-un-program-to-plant-a-trillion-more/&quot; rel=&quot;bookmark&quot;&gt;German 12-Year-old Boy Plants 1Million Trees, Takes Over UN Program to Plant a Trillion More&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The land area used to grow crops – more than 770,000 square miles – is comparable in China and India and it has not changed much since the early 2000s; yet these regions have greatly increased both their annual total green leaf area and their food production. This was achieved through multiple cropping practices, where a field is replanted to produce another harvest several times a year. Production of grains, vegetables, fruits, and more have increased by about 35-40% since 2000 to feed their large populations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How the greening trend may change in the future depends on numerous factors, both on a global scale and the local human level. For example, increased food production in India is facilitated by groundwater irrigation. If the groundwater is depleted, this trend may change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“But, now that we know direct human influence is a key driver of the greening Earth, we need to factor this into our climate models,” Nemani said. “This will help scientists make better predictions about the behavior of different Earth systems, which will help countries make better decisions about how and when to take action.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LOOK&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a title=&quot;700 Acres of Massive 1,000-Year-old Redwoods Are Being Turned into a Public Park&quot; href=&quot;https://www.goodnewsnetwork.org/700-acres-of-massive-1000-year-old-redwoods-are-being-turned-into-a-public-park/&quot; rel=&quot;bookmark&quot;&gt;700 Acres of Massive 1,000-Year-old Redwoods Are Being Turned into a Public Park&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers point out that the gain in greenness seen around the world, which is dominated by India and China, does not offset the damage from loss of natural vegetation in tropical regions, such as Brazil and Indonesia. The consequences for sustainability and biodiversity in those ecosystems remain, but overall, Nemani sees a positive message in the new findings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Once people realize there’s a problem, they tend to fix it,” he said. “In the 70s and 80s in India and China, the situation around vegetation loss wasn’t good; in the 90s, people realized it; and today things have improved. Humans are incredibly resilient. That’s what we see in the satellite data.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This research was published online this week in the journal &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41893-019-0220-7&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nature Sustainability&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nasa.gov/feature/ames/human-activity-in-china-and-india-dominates-the-greening-of-earth-nasa-study-shows&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;NASA Ames&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Plant Some Positivity Amongst Your Friends By Sharing The Good News To Social Media…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 03:11:12 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ph0rque</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://www.goodnewsnetwork.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Asia-Greenery-Cropped-NASA-Earth-Observatory.jpg</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>NASA Happily Reports the Earth is Greener, With More Trees Than 20 Years Ago–and It's Thanks to China, India</og:title>
<og:description>This heartening reserach from the last 20 years has spurred NASA researchers to encourage optimism for humanity's future on Earth.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.goodnewsnetwork.org/nasa-says-earth-is-greener-than-ever-thanks-to-china-and-india/</og:url>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.goodnewsnetwork.org/nasa-says-earth-is-greener-than-ever-thanks-to-china-and-india/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Redis Turns 10 – How it started with a single post on Hacker News</title>
<link>https://redislabs.com/blog/redis-turns-10/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://redislabs.com/blog/redis-turns-10/</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;row align-center&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;small-12 columns&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;10 years ago,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=494649&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;a link was posted&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;on Hacker News to a new software project called Redis. In&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=494649&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;the comments&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, its creator Salvatore Sanfilippo (a.k.a.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://antirez.com/news/127&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;antirez&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;) says “one of the major points of Redis is to support more complex types as values”. From Day 1, Salvatore knew what he wanted to build. And to his credit,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://oldblog.antirez.com/post/one-year-of-redis.html&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;he stayed focused&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;. Redis now has 10 complex types and a module system that enables developers to build more. And as a result, Redis is&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://db-engines.com/en/ranking/key-value+store&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;the most popular key-value store&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;on the planet.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;But Salvatore could not have done this alone. Someone had to be the first to share the link, and someone had to be the first to try the software. That first post was shared by David Welton (a.k.a.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/user?id=davidw&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;davidw&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;). I have no idea if he tried the software, or just thought it seemed cool, but he took a risk and shared it on Hacker News.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Only five people commented on that first post: three promoted alternative data stores; one suggested Salvatore re-write Redis in Erlang; and one, JUST ONE, offered some help. That one person turned out to be Ezra Zygmuntowicz (a.k.a.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/user?id=ezmobius&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;ezmobius&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.newrelic.com/culture/ezra-zygmuntowicz/&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;RIP&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;), a very popular Ruby on Rails (RoR) developer and one of the founders of Engine Yard.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Ezra not only encouraged Salvatore, but implemented the first Ruby client library for Redis. Then he&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ezmobius/status/1252368007&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;tweeted about it&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, which spread the word to the Rails community  At the time, RoR was helping developers create beautiful websites, but users of the framework struggled to make it scale. Thanks to Ezra’s efforts, Redis spread among RoR developers, and helped thousands of RoR websites scale. One of those websites was Twitter. Eventually, Redis went on to be a wildly popular add-on for Heroku developers, and then&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://redis.io/clients&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;many, many others&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;There were others after David and Ezra. But, as&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fW8amMCVAJQ&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Derek Sivers says&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, “It takes guts to be a first follower. You stand out, you brave ridiculing yourself. Being a first follower is an underappreciated form of leadership”. Nine years ago,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://oldblog.antirez.com/post/one-year-of-redis.html&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Salvatore said&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;“Your early adopters are not brave because they are irresponsible, just they can evaluate something without the need to follow the mass”. So thanks to Salvatore, David and Ezra, and other early risk takers, an open source community called Redis was born. And to those first adopters of the Redis community, as we turn 10 years old today, we say thank you.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/fW8amMCVAJQ&quot; width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fW8amMCVAJQ&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;First Follower&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;by Derek Silvers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Want to meet the Redis community and see what all the fuss is about? Join us as we celebrate 10 years of Redis at &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://redislabs.com/redisconf19/&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;RedisConf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, the yearly gathering of Redis developers, implementers and other community members. This year it takes place April 2-3 on Pier 27 in San Francisco. Perhaps you’ll find something new that will inspire you to take a risk.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 02:16:45 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mrburton</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Redis Turns 10 - How it started with a single post on Hacker News | Redis Labs</og:title>
<og:description>Redis Labs, the home of Redis and provider of Redis Enterprise, announced that Redis is marking a major milestone. 10 years ago Redis was born when a link was posted on Hacker News to a new software project called Redis by creator Salvatore Sanfilippo (a.k.a. antirez).</og:description>
<og:url>https://redislabs.com/blog/redis-turns-10/</og:url>
<og:image>https://redislabs.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/400x400-10th-anniv.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://redislabs.com/blog/redis-turns-10/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>How does the Hololens 2 matter?</title>
<link>http://stevesspace.com/2019/02/how-does-hololens2-matter/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://stevesspace.com/2019/02/how-does-hololens2-matter/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;So that happened, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=c1CZsqwnWtM&quot;&gt;the Hololens 2 has been released&lt;/a&gt;. A few people have asked me what I think, so it’s about time I got my thoughts down on &lt;del&gt;paper&lt;/del&gt; the interwebs. I’ve had a day or 2 to mull over it now - so here it is for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main features touted are improved FOV, fully articulated hand tracking and increased engagement and collaboration - partnerships and technology enablements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But how will this play out? How much is smoke and mirrors? What are the effects here? Read on for my thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;field-of-view&quot;&gt;Field of view&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The elephant in the room (that you can’t see much of because it doesn’t fit in viewport).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you gave a Hololens 1 user/dev a handful of Microsoft dollars to improve the headset, chances are they’d spend it all improving the field of view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, that’s what they’ve done. 2x improvement is their numbers. But let’s look at the numbers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-much-better&quot;&gt;How much better?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fortunately &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/akipman/status/1100069645661495298&quot;&gt;Alex Kipman tweeted&lt;/a&gt; the FOV details for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hololens 1 has a FOV of &lt;strong&gt;30° horizontally&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;17.5° vertically&lt;/strong&gt; (source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Microsoft_HoloLens&quot;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;). So, thanks to pythagoras, we get a &lt;strong&gt;diagonal FOV of around 35°&lt;/strong&gt;. Note the aspect ratio - approx 16:9&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hololens 2 now has a &lt;strong&gt;52° diagonal FOV&lt;/strong&gt; and a 3:2 aspect ratio - so &lt;strong&gt;43° horizontally&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;29° vertically&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just for reference, the magic leap has &lt;strong&gt;40° horizontally&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;30° vertically&lt;/strong&gt; - so a &lt;strong&gt;diagonal of 50°&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The image on &lt;a href=&quot;https://uploadvr.com/hololens-2-field-of-view/&quot;&gt;UploadVR&lt;/a&gt; is a good view comparing all 3, but I’m gonna do it here in CSS &lt;em&gt;because I can&lt;/em&gt; (and so you can view the source to check my measurements for yourself).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Hololens 2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Magic Leap&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hololens 1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The take home: It’s pretty much the same as the Magic Leap, and calling it double is pretty misleading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt; I mistakingly said it is 4x the area (&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;2236°²&lt;/code&gt;) below - it is actually 2.4x (&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;1247°²&lt;/code&gt;). Thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/WithinRafael&quot;&gt;Rafael&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/WithinRafael/status/1100540006706438144&quot;&gt;picking that up&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not even double the perimeter (&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;95°&lt;/code&gt; vs &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;144°&lt;/code&gt;) but it &lt;strong&gt;IS&lt;/strong&gt; ~2.4x the area (&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;525°²&lt;/code&gt; vs &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;1247°²&lt;/code&gt;) - but IMHO these units don’t even make sense* ! &lt;strong&gt;Comparing diagonals gets about 1.5x improvement&lt;/strong&gt;, which I think it the more realistic number.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(*ok, so a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Square_degree&quot;&gt;square degree&lt;/a&gt; is apparently a valid measurement, if not SI-compliant. There are apparently 41,252.96 square degrees in a sphere, so if we stack 34 Hololens 2 units perfectly, we have ourselves a fully Holographic sphere)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So don’t get hyped on that! It’s a nice improvement, certainly, but it’s not mind blowing as it sounds - and certainly not “double the FOV” unless you &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; stretch the definition of FOV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-does-it-mean&quot;&gt;What does it mean?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll throw this out there - a bigger FOV is not better because you can fit more on - it’s better because you can &lt;em&gt;get &lt;strong&gt;closer&lt;/strong&gt; to your holograms&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft recommends the holograms do not show any nearer than 85cm for the original Hololens - any closer and your eyes go all funky. Why? Because at that distance, some of the hologram is hanging off the side of one of your eyes, and not the other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To show what I mean, I’ve done a quick Unity scene - a single sphere with a radius 15cm sitting 50cm* from the eyes. This is the approximate view on each hololens for the sphere:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(*I chose these sizes because that makes the sphere take up a similar viewport % on the Hololens 2 as the same size sphere at 85cm on the original Hololens)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://stevesspace.com/images/2019-02-26-fov-example.png&quot; alt=&quot;Comparing Hololens and Hololens 2 FOV impact&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure&lt;/strong&gt;: Comparison of Hololens 1 and 2 rendering from the left and right eyes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first view will make you feel cross-eyed, with about 20% of the object cut off on each eye. Comparitively, on the Hololens2, most of the sphere is in view - it will appear close to you, but your eyes still agree on what they’re seeing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;THIS is why the FOV is &lt;em&gt;so important&lt;/em&gt; - at 85cm, you can only &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; reach the holograms. at 50cm though? It’s within reach. This is a big deal. Arguably the high quality finger/hand recognition wouldn’t have worked well without this proximity anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;gestures&quot;&gt;Gestures&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You know what you get sick of when showing people the Hololens? Teaching someone to Air-Tap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The always want to be reaching forward and touching the Holograms - but it’s been impossible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m gonna say it - I think this high-accuracy hand and finger tracking is the killer feature for this device. Assuming minimal smoke-and-mirrors, &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/c1CZsqwnWtM?t=2200&quot;&gt;Julia Schwarz played a freakin’ holographic piano&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think this is what the Holographics UIs have been waiting for - simple, intuitive interaction. No longer do I need to make a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;+&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;-&lt;/code&gt; button for a number in put - sliders will work! No longer does someone have to be looking &lt;em&gt;directly&lt;/em&gt; at a button to tap it - the can just… &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; tap it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will greatly reduce the main issue with using the Hololens in educational environments - having a no-training-required experience to learn the app. It’s important!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, there’s an issue. Notice Julia is always an arms length away from what she’s interacting with? My guess is the near-clip plane sits at about 40-50cm for the Hololens 2 by default, so we’re not getting any small-and-up-close UI elements any time soon. Expect to have to reach out to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Admittedly this is a very minor issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;performance&quot;&gt;Performance&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We got ourselves a pretty big upgrade here!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hololens 1 was pretty bad performance-wise. You’re lucky to push 400k triangles, even with the simplest of shaders. Want reflections? Hope you’re not using too many pixels! And do you have a lot of transparency? Are you overdrawing? Not on this device, my friend!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enter Hololens 2 - it has a &lt;a href=&quot;https://mspoweruser.com/full-tech-specs-of-microsoft-hololens-2/&quot;&gt;Qualcomm Snapdragon 850 Compute Platform&lt;/a&gt; for a CPU/GPU - compared to the 1Ghz Atom processor in the Hololens 1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re talking nearly a tripling of maximum clock rate, and a huge jump in GPU power too. If Hololens 1 was an iPhone 5 (a good comparison), then Hololens 2 is an iPhone X + 20% ish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So we’ve got some actual (comparative) horsepower now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The flipside? We’re having to push many more pixels with the FOV increase. With a viewing area jump of about 2.4x, we have about 2.4x the number of pixels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So it’s gonna &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt; that extra GPU power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And honestly? CPU power hasn’t been a problem in any of the apps I’ve created.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll have to wait and see how this performance pans out. Having recently done a fairly graphics intensive iPad-Pro ARKit application, I know first hand that graphics power unlocks a lot of that “wow” factor that’s hard to get on the original Hololens. I hope we can get that same “wow” on the Hololens 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;partners-and-open-tech&quot;&gt;Partners and open tech&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In case you missed it, &lt;a href=&quot;https://readify.net&quot;&gt;Readify&lt;/a&gt; made a front and center appearance on the stage with Alex Kipman!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot; readability=&quot;8.5555555555556&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Oh hi there &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/readify?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@readify&lt;/a&gt; logo 🧐&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recognition for some great work done, and being done, by our teams! 💪 Great to be part of this journey with &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/HoloLens?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@HoloLens&lt;/a&gt;, and their HoloLens 2 launch this morning. &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/FI5Cd8IpHf&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/FI5Cd8IpHf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
— Tatham Oddie (@tathamoddie) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/tathamoddie/status/1099797151943553024?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;February 24, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, so more like… rear and slightly to the right. You get the point. I’m pretty sure he picked his stage position careuflly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft have been putting in the hard yards attracting, partnering and equipping partners to deliver this stuff well - and I must say, it’s been super useful to partner with them in this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They really are thinking of developers for this journey - with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Microsoft/MixedRealityToolkit-Unity&quot;&gt;MRTK&lt;/a&gt; and a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Microsoft/VisualProfiler-Unity&quot;&gt;other tools&lt;/a&gt; that I use on every gig (and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Microsoft/MRLightingTools-Unity&quot;&gt;probably future gigs&lt;/a&gt;), it makes everything easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, the next version of this tooling goes &lt;em&gt;beyond&lt;/em&gt; Mixed Reality devices - Microsoft seem to be bringing in other AR devices (Android, iOS) into the fold and enabling them to work. My guess is this is part of the “use whatever OS you want, as long as it’s in Azure” aspect - providing services like cloud anchors and speech understanding transcends devices, and brings in the bacon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve heard enterprises are squeamish about this openness - but I whole-heartedly embrace it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shameless plug&lt;/strong&gt;: Do you want the chance to work on this stuff? Reach out - Readify are always hiring. Reach out on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/xwipeoutx&quot;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt; or hit up &lt;a href=&quot;https://join.readify.net&quot;&gt;https://join.readify.net&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;unfortunately&quot;&gt;Unfortunately…&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sadly, some things are missing here that I was really hoping for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, there’s no talk of GPS/Compass/4g/5g support. Outdoor is not a thing. I get it - this sort display does not lend itself to outdoor - but I was kinda hoping, y’know?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven’t heard any word on the development story being improved - specifically, holographic remoting and build times (IL2CPP is a slow way to go about things). Native code is a bit of a second class citizen here, so I don’t have much hope for this improving. But dang it would be nice to go from pressing “build” to on device in seconds rather than &lt;em&gt;several&lt;/em&gt; minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;final-bits&quot;&gt;Final bits&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven’t touched on a lot of the cool things to watch out for - mostly because they were cool, but I didn’t have any insight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Windows Hello integration and eye tracking is super cool - finally some simple (automatic) IPD adjustment, which should sharpen things up a bit! I’m pretty interested in how the eye tracking will work from an interaction perspective. I suspect &lt;em&gt;really annoying&lt;/em&gt; - we’re not used to things moving with our eyes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The comfort factor is a big one, and it does look much better in this regard. I’m torn about the location of the computing device (keeping it on the unit instead of offloading it a.l.a. Magic Leap). Center of Mass is important, and I’m glad it’s to the geometric center now - but overall weight is, too. We’ll see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Azure Kinect might be a bit of a game changer. I see this becoming a 3d room scanner, a remote-assist companion, a game enabler and a cheap way to get a high quality spectator view for an application (c’mon first party support out of the box for this!). When I watched the MWC announcement, &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; was the most exciting to me (though mostly because I’d assumed the rest was happening already).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This release is &lt;em&gt;super&lt;/em&gt; exciting, I can’t wait to get my hands on one and see what it can do.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 22:46:28 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>xwipeoutx</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>http://stevesspace.com/2019/02/how-does-hololens2-matter/</og:url>
<og:image>http://stevesspace.com/images/steve.jpeg</og:image>
<og:description>So that happened, the Hololens 2 has been released. A few people have asked me what I think, so it’s about time I got my thoughts down on paper the interwebs. I’ve had a day or 2 to mull over it ...</og:description>
<og:title>How does the Hololens 2 matter?</og:title>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://stevesspace.com/2019/02/how-does-hololens2-matter/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Pi-Hole – A black hole for Internet advertisements</title>
<link>https://github.com/pi-hole/pi-hole</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/pi-hole/pi-hole</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;Box-body p-6&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;markdown-body entry-content&quot; itemprop=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pi-hole.net&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/73fd8305ca1a62929a093f3923ba25659c825757/68747470733a2f2f70692d686f6c652e6769746875622e696f2f67726170686963732f566f727465782f566f727465785f776974685f746578742e706e67&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; height=&quot;255&quot; alt=&quot;Pi-hole&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://pi-hole.github.io/graphics/Vortex/Vortex_with_text.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Network-wide ad blocking via your own Linux hardware&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Pi-hole&lt;a href=&quot;https://pi-hole.net/trademark-rules-and-brand-guidelines/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;®&lt;/a&gt; is a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DNS_Sinkhole&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;DNS sinkhole&lt;/a&gt; that protects your devices from unwanted content, without installing any client-side software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Easy-to-install&lt;/strong&gt;: our versatile installer walks you through the process, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vKWjx1AQYgs&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;takes less than ten minutes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resolute&lt;/strong&gt;: content is blocked in &lt;em&gt;non-browser locations&lt;/em&gt;, such as ad-laden mobile apps and smart TVs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Responsive&lt;/strong&gt;: seamlessly speeds up the feel of everyday browsing by caching DNS queries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lightweight&lt;/strong&gt;: runs smoothly with &lt;a href=&quot;https://discourse.pi-hole.net/t/hardware-software-requirements/273&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;minimal hardware and software requirements&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Robust&lt;/strong&gt;: a command line interface that is quality assured for interoperability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Insightful&lt;/strong&gt;: a beautiful responsive Web Interface dashboard to view and control your Pi-hole&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Versatile&lt;/strong&gt;: can optionally function as a &lt;a href=&quot;https://discourse.pi-hole.net/t/how-do-i-use-pi-holes-built-in-dhcp-server-and-why-would-i-want-to/3026&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;DHCP server&lt;/a&gt;, ensuring &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; your devices are protected automatically&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scalable&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;https://pi-hole.net/2017/05/24/how-much-traffic-can-pi-hole-handle/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;capable of handling hundreds of millions of queries&lt;/a&gt; when installed on server-grade hardware&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Modern&lt;/strong&gt;: blocks ads over both IPv4 and IPv6&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Free&lt;/strong&gt;: open source software which helps ensure &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; are the sole person in control of your privacy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.codacy.com/app/Pi-hole/pi-hole?utm_source=github.com&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=pi-hole/pi-hole&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Badge_Grade&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/31b63b2702ba707eeb0e6a7546cd8322d82cb73d/68747470733a2f2f6170692e636f646163792e636f6d2f70726f6a6563742f62616467652f47726164652f6335353861306638643731323463393962303262383466306635353634323338&quot; alt=&quot;Codacy Grade&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://api.codacy.com/project/badge/Grade/c558a0f8d7124c99b02b84f0f5564238&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://travis-ci.org/pi-hole/pi-hole&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/001cfaebfaffbddad0fbd83ef14b437b1175e19c/68747470733a2f2f7472617669732d63692e6f72672f70692d686f6c652f70692d686f6c652e7376673f6272616e63683d646576656c6f706d656e74&quot; alt=&quot;Travis Build Status&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://travis-ci.org/pi-hole/pi-hole.svg?branch=development&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bountysource.com/trackers/3011939-pi-hole-pi-hole?utm_source=3011939&amp;amp;utm_medium=shield&amp;amp;utm_campaign=TRACKER_BADGE&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/05e86b03b7b1abcdbf9f2ac7dd4d06f0a884ef0c/68747470733a2f2f7777772e626f756e7479736f757263652e636f6d2f62616467652f747261636b65723f747261636b65725f69643d33303131393339&quot; alt=&quot;BountySource&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://www.bountysource.com/badge/tracker?tracker_id=3011939&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;One-Step Automated Install&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those who want to get started quickly and conveniently may install Pi-hole using the following command:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;curl -sSL https://install.pi-hole.net | bash&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Alternative Install Methods&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pi-hole.net/2016/07/25/curling-and-piping-to-bash&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Piping to &lt;code&gt;bash&lt;/code&gt; is controversial&lt;/a&gt;, as it prevents you from &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pi-hole/pi-hole/blob/master/automated%20install/basic-install.sh&quot;&gt;reading code that is about to run&lt;/a&gt; on your system. Therefore, we provide these alternative installation methods which allow code review before installation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Method 1: Clone our repository and run&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;git clone --depth 1 https://github.com/pi-hole/pi-hole.git Pi-hole
cd &quot;Pi-hole/automated install/&quot;
sudo bash basic-install.sh
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Method 2: Manually download the installer and run&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;wget -O basic-install.sh https://install.pi-hole.net
sudo bash basic-install.sh
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Post-install: Make your network take advantage of Pi-hole&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the installer has been run, you will need to &lt;a href=&quot;https://discourse.pi-hole.net/t/how-do-i-configure-my-devices-to-use-pi-hole-as-their-dns-server/245&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;configure your router to have &lt;strong&gt;DHCP clients use Pi-hole as their DNS server&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; which ensures that all devices connecting to your network will have content blocked without any further intervention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If your router does not support setting the DNS server, you can &lt;a href=&quot;https://discourse.pi-hole.net/t/how-do-i-use-pi-holes-built-in-dhcp-server-and-why-would-i-want-to/3026&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;use Pi-hole's built-in DHCP server&lt;/a&gt;; just be sure to disable DHCP on your router first (if it has that feature available).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a last resort, you can always manually set each device to use Pi-hole as their DNS server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Pi-hole is free, but powered by your support&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many reoccurring costs involved with maintaining free, open source, and privacy-respecting software; expenses which &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/orgs/pi-hole/people&quot;&gt;our volunteer developers&lt;/a&gt; pitch in to cover out-of-pocket. This is just one example of how strongly we feel about our software, as well as the importance of keeping it maintained.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make no mistake: &lt;strong&gt;your support is absolutely vital to help keep us innovating!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Donations&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sending a donation using our links below is &lt;strong&gt;extremely helpful&lt;/strong&gt; in offsetting a portion of our monthly expenses:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Alternative support&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you'd rather not &lt;a href=&quot;https://pi-hole.net/donate/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;donate&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;em&gt;which is okay!&lt;/em&gt;), there are other ways you can help support us:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Contributing via GitHub&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We welcome &lt;em&gt;everyone&lt;/em&gt; to contribute to issue reports, suggest new features, and create pull requests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have something to add - anything from a typo through to a whole new feature, we're happy to check it out! Just make sure to fill out our template when submitting your request; the questions that it asks will help the volunteers quickly understand what you're aiming to achieve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You'll find that the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pi-hole/pi-hole/blob/master/automated%20install/basic-install.sh&quot;&gt;install script&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pi-hole/pi-hole/blob/master/advanced/Scripts/piholeDebug.sh&quot;&gt;debug script&lt;/a&gt; have an abundance of comments, which will help you better understand how Pi-hole works. They're also a valuable resource to those who want to learn how to write scripts or code a program! We encourage anyone who likes to tinker to read through it and submit a pull request for us to review.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Presentations about Pi-hole&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Word-of-mouth continues to help our project grow immensely, and so we are helping make this easier for people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are going to be presenting Pi-hole at a conference, meetup or even a school project, &lt;a href=&quot;https://pi-hole.net/2017/05/17/giving-a-presentation-on-pi-hole-contact-us-first-for-some-goodies-and-support/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;get in touch with us&lt;/a&gt; so we can hook you up with free swag to hand out to your audience!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Getting in touch with us&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While we are primarily reachable on our &lt;a href=&quot;https://discourse.pi-hole.net/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Discourse User Forum&lt;/a&gt;, we can also be found on a variety of social media outlets. &lt;strong&gt;Please be sure to check the FAQ's&lt;/strong&gt; before starting a new discussion, as we do not have the spare time to reply to every request for assistance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Breakdown of Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Command Line Interface&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;pihole&lt;/code&gt; command has all the functionality necessary to be able to fully administer the Pi-hole, without the need of the Web Interface. It's fast, user-friendly, and auditable by anyone with an understanding of &lt;code&gt;bash&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pi-hole.github.io/graphics/Screenshots/blacklist-cli.gif&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/57f15d9665575a98275d3511f8f591863733b8c0/68747470733a2f2f70692d686f6c652e6769746875622e696f2f67726170686963732f53637265656e73686f74732f626c61636b6c6973742d636c692e676966&quot; alt=&quot;Pi-hole Blacklist Demo&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://pi-hole.github.io/graphics/Screenshots/blacklist-cli.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some notable features include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can read our &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pi-hole/pi-hole/wiki/Core-Function-Breakdown&quot;&gt;Core Feature Breakdown&lt;/a&gt;, as well as read up on &lt;a href=&quot;https://discourse.pi-hole.net/t/the-pihole-command-with-examples/738&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;example usage&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Web Interface Dashboard&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pi-hole/AdminLTE&quot;&gt;optional dashboard&lt;/a&gt; allows you to view stats, change settings, and configure your Pi-hole. It's the power of the Command Line Interface, with none of the learning curve!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/732bd6d32141d492f987d9f0940d900fba5b4443/68747470733a2f2f70692d686f6c652e6769746875622e696f2f67726170686963732f53637265656e73686f74732f7069686f6c652d64617368626f6172642e706e67&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/732bd6d32141d492f987d9f0940d900fba5b4443/68747470733a2f2f70692d686f6c652e6769746875622e696f2f67726170686963732f53637265656e73686f74732f7069686f6c652d64617368626f6172642e706e67&quot; alt=&quot;Pi-hole Dashboard&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://pi-hole.github.io/graphics/Screenshots/pihole-dashboard.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some notable features include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Mobile friendly interface&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Password protection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Detailed graphs and doughnut charts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Top lists of domains and clients&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A filterable and sortable query log&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Long Term Statistics to view data over user-defined time ranges&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The ability to easily manage and configure Pi-hole features&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;... and all the main features of the Command Line Interface!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are several ways to &lt;a href=&quot;https://discourse.pi-hole.net/t/how-do-i-access-pi-holes-dashboard-admin-interface/3168&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;access the dashboard&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;http://&amp;lt;IP_ADDPRESS_OF_YOUR_PI_HOLE&amp;gt;/admin/&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;http://pi.hole/admin/&lt;/code&gt; (when using Pi-hole as your DNS server)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;http://pi.hole/&lt;/code&gt; (when using Pi-hole as your DNS server)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Faster-than-light Engine&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FTLDNS is a lightweight, purpose-built daemon used to provide statistics needed for the Web Interface, and its API can be easily integrated into your own projects. As the name implies, FTLDNS does this all &lt;em&gt;very quickly&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the statistics you can integrate include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Total number of domains being blocked&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Total number of DNS queries today&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Total number of ads blocked today&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Percentage of ads blocked&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unique domains&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Queries forwarded (to your chosen upstream DNS server)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Queries cached&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unique clients&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The API can be accessed via &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pi-hole/FTL&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;telnet&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the Web (&lt;code&gt;admin/api.php&lt;/code&gt;) and Command Line (&lt;code&gt;pihole -c -j&lt;/code&gt;). You can out find &lt;a href=&quot;https://discourse.pi-hole.net/t/pi-hole-api/1863&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;more details over here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;The Origin Of Pi-hole&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pi-hole being an &lt;strong&gt;advertising-aware DNS/Web server&lt;/strong&gt;, makes use of the following technologies:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thekelleys.org.uk/dnsmasq/doc.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;dnsmasq&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; - a lightweight DNS and DHCP server&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://curl.haxx.se&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;curl&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; - A command line tool for transferring data with URL syntax&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lighttpd.net&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;lighttpd&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; - web server designed and optimized for high performance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://secure.php.net&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;php&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; - a popular general-purpose web scripting language&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/almasaeed2010/AdminLTE&quot;&gt;AdminLTE Dashboard&lt;/a&gt; - premium admin control panel based on Bootstrap 3.x&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;While quite outdated at this point, &lt;a href=&quot;https://jacobsalmela.com/2015/06/16/block-millions-ads-network-wide-with-a-raspberry-pi-hole-2-0/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;this original blog post about Pi-hole&lt;/a&gt; goes into &lt;strong&gt;great detail&lt;/strong&gt; about how Pi-hole was originally set up and how it works. Syntactically, it's no longer accurate, but the same basic principles and logic still apply to Pi-hole's current state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Coverage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lifehacker.com.au/2015/02/turn-a-raspberry-pi-into-an-ad-blocker-with-a-single-command/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Lifehacker: Turn A Raspberry Pi Into An Ad Blocker With A Single Command&lt;/a&gt; (Feburary, 2015)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.makeuseof.com/tag/adblock-everywhere-raspberry-pi-hole-way/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;MakeUseOf: Adblock Everywhere: The Raspberry Pi-Hole Way&lt;/a&gt; (March, 2015)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.catchpoint.com/2015/09/14/ad-blocking-apple/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Catchpoint: Ad-Blocking on Apple iOS9: Valuing the End User Experience&lt;/a&gt; (September, 2015)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=p7-osq_y8i8&amp;amp;t=100m26s&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Security Now Netcast: Pi-hole&lt;/a&gt; (October, 2015)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/8Co59HU2gY0?t=2m&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;TekThing: Raspberry Pi-Hole Makes Ads Disappear!&lt;/a&gt; (December, 2015)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/bYyena0I9yc?t=2m4s&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Foolish Tech Show&lt;/a&gt; (December, 2015)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@robleathern/block-ads-on-all-home-devices-for-53-18-a5f1ec139693#.gj1xpgr5d&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Block Ads on All Home Devices for $53.18&lt;/a&gt; (December, 2015)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.boyter.org/2015/12/pi-hole-ubuntu-14-04/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Pi-Hole for Ubuntu 14.04&lt;/a&gt; (December, 2015)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.macobserver.com/tmo/podcast/macgeekgab-585&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;MacObserver Podcast 585&lt;/a&gt; (December, 2015)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://channel9.msdn.com/Shows/The-Defrag-Show/Defrag-Endoscope-USB-Camera-The-Final-HoloLens-Vote-Adblock-Pi-and-more?WT.mc_id=dlvr_twitter_ch9#time=20m39s&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;The Defrag Show: Endoscope USB Camera, The Final [HoloLens] Vote, Adblock Pi and more&lt;/a&gt; (January, 2016)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.adafruit.com/2016/03/04/pi-hole-is-a-black-hole-for-internet-ads-piday-raspberrypi-raspberry_pi/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Adafruit: Pi-hole is a black hole for internet ads&lt;/a&gt; (March, 2016)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/QwrKlyC2kdM?t=1m42s&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Digital Trends: 5 Fun, Easy Projects You Can Try With a $35 Raspberry Pi&lt;/a&gt; (March, 2016)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eg4u2j1HYlI&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Adafruit: Raspberry Pi Quick Look at Pi Hole ad blocking server with Tony D&lt;/a&gt; (June, 2016)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.devacron.com/orangepi-zero-as-an-ad-block-server-with-pi-hole/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Devacron: OrangePi Zero as an Ad-Block server with Pi-Hole&lt;/a&gt; (December, 2016)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.linuxpromagazine.com/Issues/2017/200/The-sysadmin-s-daily-grind-Pi-hole&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Linux Pro: The Hole Truth&lt;/a&gt; (July, 2017)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://learn.adafruit.com/pi-hole-ad-blocker-with-pi-zero-w/install-pi-hole&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Adafruit: installing Pi-hole on a Pi Zero W&lt;/a&gt; (August, 2017)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.cryptoaustralia.org.au/2017/10/05/5-privacy-focused-raspberry-pi-projects/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;CryptoAUSTRALIA: How We Tried 5 Privacy Focused Raspberry Pi Projects&lt;/a&gt; (October, 2017)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.cryptoaustralia.org.au/2017/11/02/pi-hole-network-wide-ad-blocker/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;CryptoAUSTRALIA: Pi-hole Workshop&lt;/a&gt; (November, 2017)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.twit.tv/shows/know-how/episodes/355&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Know How 355: Killing ads with a Raspberry Pi-Hole!&lt;/a&gt; (November, 2017)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://hobo.house/2018/02/27/block-advertising-with-pi-hole-and-raspberry-pi/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Hobohouse: Block Advertising on your Network with Pi-hole and Raspberry Pi&lt;/a&gt; (March, 2018)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://scotthelme.co.uk/securing-dns-across-all-of-my-devices-with-pihole-dns-over-https-1-1-1-1/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Scott Helme: Securing DNS across all of my devices with Pi-Hole + DNS-over-HTTPS + 1.1.1.1&lt;/a&gt; (April, 2018)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://scotthelme.co.uk/catching-naughty-devices-on-my-home-network/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Scott Helme: Catching and dealing with naughty devices on my home network&lt;/a&gt; (April, 2018)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2018-05-10/inside-the-brotherhood-of-pi-hole-ad-blockers&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Bloomberg Business Week: Brotherhood of the Ad blockers&lt;/a&gt; (May, 2018)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://softwareengineeringdaily.com/2018/05/29/pi-hole-ad-blocker-hardware-with-jacob-salmela/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Software Engineering Daily: Interview with the creator of Pi-hole&lt;/a&gt; (May, 2018)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/pi-hole-raspberry-pi/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Raspberry Pi: Block ads at home using Pi-hole and a Raspberry Pi&lt;/a&gt; (July, 2018)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.troyhunt.com/mmm-pi-hole/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Troy Hunt: Mmm... Pi-hole...&lt;/a&gt; (September, 2018)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jerseystudios.net/2018/10/11/150-pi-hole/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;PEBKAK Podcast: Interview With Jacob Salmela&lt;/a&gt; (October, 2018)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Pi-hole Projects&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 22:02:01 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>tosh</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars3.githubusercontent.com/u/16827203?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>pi-hole/pi-hole</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/pi-hole/pi-hole</og:url>
<og:description>A black hole for Internet advertisements. Contribute to pi-hole/pi-hole development by creating an account on GitHub.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/pi-hole/pi-hole</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>USB 3.2 is going to make the current USB branding even worse</title>
<link>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2019/02/usb-3-2-is-going-to-make-the-current-usb-branding-even-worse/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2019/02/usb-3-2-is-going-to-make-the-current-usb-branding-even-worse/</guid>
<description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/USB_Type-C_rendering-800x557.png&quot; alt=&quot;USB Type-C cable and port.&quot;/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;caption-text&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/USB_Type-C_rendering.png&quot; class=&quot;enlarge-link&quot; data-height=&quot;4842&quot; data-width=&quot;6959&quot;&gt;Enlarge&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;sep&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; USB Type-C cable and port.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;aside id=&quot;social-left&quot; aria-label=&quot;Read the comments or share this article&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;comment-count-before&quot;&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;227 posters participating&quot; class=&quot;comment-count icon-comment-bubble-down&quot; href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2019/02/usb-3-2-is-going-to-make-the-current-usb-branding-even-worse/?comments=1&quot;&gt;reader comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;a title=&quot;227 posters participating&quot; class=&quot;comment-count icon-comment-bubble-down&quot; href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2019/02/usb-3-2-is-going-to-make-the-current-usb-branding-even-worse/?comments=1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;comment-count-number&quot;&gt;323&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;visually-hidden&quot;&gt;with 227 posters participating&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;share-links&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Share this story&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2017/07/usb-3-2-will-make-your-cables-twice-as-fast-once-youve-bought-new-devices/&quot;&gt;USB 3.2&lt;/a&gt;, which doubles the maximum speed of a USB connection to 20Gb/s, is likely to materialize in systems later this year. In preparation for this, the USB-IF—the industry group that together develops the various USB specifications—has announced the branding and naming that the new revision is going to use, and... it's awful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;USB 3.0 was straightforward enough. A USB 3.0 connection ran at 5Gb/s, and slower connections were USB 2 or even USB 1.1. The new 5Gb/s data rate was branded &quot;SuperSpeed USB,&quot; following USB 2's 480Mb/s &quot;High Speed&quot; and USB 1.1's 12Mb/s &quot;Full Speed.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But then USB 3.1 came along and muddied the waters. Its big new feature was doubling the data rate to 10Gb/s. The logical thing would have been to identify existing 5Gb/s devices as &quot;USB 3.0&quot; and new 10Gb/s devices as &quot;USB 3.1.&quot; But that's not what the USB-IF did. For reasons that remain hard to understand, the decision was made to retroactively rebrand USB 3.0: 5Gb/s 3.0 connections became &quot;USB 3.1 Gen 1,&quot; with the 10Gb/s connections being &quot;USB 3.1 Gen 2.&quot; The consumer branding is &quot;SuperSpeed USB 10Gbps.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What this branding meant is that many manufacturers say that a device supports &quot;USB 3.1&quot; even if it's only a &quot;USB 3.1 Gen 1&quot; device running at 5Gb/s. Meanwhile, other manufacturers do the sensible thing: they use &quot;USB 3.0&quot; to denote 5Gb/s devices and reserve &quot;USB 3.1&quot; for 10Gb/s parts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;USB 3.2 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usb.org/sites/default/files/usb_3_2_language_product_and_packaging_guidelines_final.pdf&quot;&gt;doubles down on this confusion&lt;/a&gt;. 5Gb/s devices are now &quot;USB 3.2 Gen 1.&quot; 10Gb/s devices become &quot;USB 3.2 Gen 2.&quot; And 20Gb/s devices will be... &quot;USB 3.2 Gen 2×2.&quot; Because they work by running two 10Gb/s connections along different pairs of wires simultaneously, and it's just obvious from arithmetic that you'd number the generations &quot;1, 2, 2×2.&quot; Perhaps they're named for powers of two, starting with zero? The consumer branding is a more reasonable &quot;SuperSpeed USB 20Gbps.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The good part of all this is that USB 3.2 could mean 5, 10, or 20Gbps. You can bet that there will be manufacturers who are going to exploit that confusion wherever and whenever they can.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 21:42:38 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>nottorp</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2019/02/usb-3-2-is-going-to-make-the-current-usb-branding-even-worse/</og:url>
<og:title>USB 3.2 is going to make the current USB branding even worse</og:title>
<og:image>https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/USB_Type-C_rendering-760x380.png</og:image>
<og:description>People already get the names wrong, so the USB group has doubled down on bad naming.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2019/02/usb-3-2-is-going-to-make-the-current-usb-branding-even-worse/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>