<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Why Do Keynote Speakers Keep Suggesting That Improving Security Is Possible?</title>
<link>https://www.usenix.org/conference/usenixsecurity18/presentation/mickens</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.usenix.org/conference/usenixsecurity18/presentation/mickens</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;@conference {218395,&lt;br/&gt;author = {James Mickens},&lt;br/&gt;title = {Q: Why Do Keynote Speakers Keep Suggesting That Improving Security Is Possible? A: Because Keynote Speakers Make Bad Life Decisions and Are Poor Role Models},&lt;br/&gt;year = {2018},&lt;br/&gt;address = {Baltimore, MD},&lt;br/&gt;publisher = {{USENIX} Association},&lt;br/&gt;}&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 19:34:46 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>zdw</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.usenix.org/conference/usenixsecurity18/presentation/mickens</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Arm Announces Client CPU Roadmap For Laptops</title>
<link>https://www.arm.com/company/news/2018/08/accelerating-mobile-and-laptop-performance</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.arm.com/company/news/2018/08/accelerating-mobile-and-laptop-performance</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;By Nandan Nayampally, vice president and general manager, Client Line of Business, Arm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;News highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Arm unveils its first-ever public CPU forward-looking roadmap and performance numbers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Client CPU’s expected to deliver year-over-year performance improvements of &amp;gt;15% for compute through 2020&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Arm positioned for laptop share gain with roadmap designed for 5G always-on, always-connected devices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over the last five years, advances in Arm technology have brought desktop-class PC performance into our smartphones, fundamentally changing how we use technology in our daily lives. This is a direct result of Arm’s annual cadence of introducing new world-class CPU designs, which have delivered double-digit gains every year in instructions-per-clock (IPC) performance since 2013. Arm is now applying this same design leadership, along with optimizing for the latest advances in process technology from our foundry partners, to enable the PC industry to overcome their reliance on Moore’s law – which has definitely slowed – and deliver a high-performance, always-on, always-connected laptop experience. It’s an experience that will be a necessity as 5G enables an entirely new world of connected possibilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The latest example of this is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.arm.com/company/news/2018/05/arm-announces-new-suite-of-ip-for-premium-mobile-experiences&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot; title=&quot;our recently launched Cortex-A76 CPU&quot;&gt;our recently launched Cortex-A76 CPU&lt;/a&gt;.  The &lt;a href=&quot;https://community.arm.com/processors/b/blog/posts/cortex-a76-laptop-class-performance-with-mobile-efficiency&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Cortex-A76 is delivering an unprecedented 35% gain in performance compared to the previous generation&quot;&gt;Cortex-A76 is delivering an unprecedented 35% gain in performance compared to the previous generation&lt;/a&gt;, without compromising Arm’s efficiency leadership. This is an industry milestone for multiple reasons. Firstly, it’s the foundational CPU IP for the first 7nm SoCs expected to be in production later this year. More importantly, Cortex-A76 represents the continuation of the trajectory that will increase performance at a staggering pace, enabling consumers to do more with their smartphones and level the performance playing field against mass-market laptop CPUs from the competition.   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;                         &lt;img alt=&quot;Arm client roadmap performance comparison chart&quot; src=&quot;https://www.arm.com/-/media/global/news/arm-client-roadmap-performance-comparison-chart-2.jpg?revision=0179f0d5-3f22-4e75-9920-467301a6b8f3&amp;amp;h=494.75&amp;amp;w=1055.25&amp;amp;la=en&amp;amp;hash=6D78932D4F021387B14574EE5C3FDCFDD76972A8&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Looking ahead: Breakthrough performance for the always-on, always-connected user&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today is another milestone for Arm as we’re publicly disclosing both forward-looking compute performance data and a CPU roadmap for Arm’s Client Line of Business from now through 2020. It’s the first time we’ve ever shared a roadmap of any kind publicly, and it won’t be the last (hint: come to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.armtechcon.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Arm TechCon&quot;&gt;Arm TechCon&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;                         &lt;img alt=&quot;Arm client Compute CPU roadmap&quot; src=&quot;https://www.arm.com/-/media/global/news/Arm_Client_Compute_CPU_roadmap_lo-res_FINAL.JPG?revision=ce4ecc5f-6945-4c94-9c3e-90bba7af1178&amp;amp;h=529&amp;amp;w=1000&amp;amp;la=en&amp;amp;hash=185C194B716D5D10B33EE8A8623A9B86C65C905D&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some important details you need to know about our client CPU roadmap:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The follow-up to Cortex-A76 will be codenamed ‘Deimos’ and delivered to our partners in 2018. Optimized for the latest 7nm nodes, ‘Deimos’ is based on Arm DynamIQ technology and is expected to deliver a 15+ percent increase in compute performance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;In 2019, the CPU codenamed ‘Hercules’ will be available to Arm partners. ‘Hercules’, also based on DynamIQ technology, will be optimized for both the latest 5nm and 7nm nodes. ‘Hercules’ continues the trajectory of increased compute performance, while also improving power and area efficiency by 10 percent (in addition to the efficiency gains achievable from the 5nm process node).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why it matters&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our roadmap of client CPUs has been designed to take advantage of the disruptive innovation 5G will bring to all client devices. This combined with innovations from our silicon and foundry partners will enable Arm SoCs to break through the dominance of x86 and gain substantial market share in Windows laptops and Chromebooks over the next five years.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, the Arm Artisan Physical IP platform and Arm POP IP will also help Arm partners get every bit of performance-per-watt they can out of their SoCs on whatever process node they choose. Artisan is a key part of building industry-leading process nodes for our foundry partners from 130nm down to 5nm, while POP IP has helped our partners realize market-leading performance, power, and area (PPA) over many generations of Arm cores. Arm POP IP is already helping to enable laptop-class performance in 7nm SoCs based on Cortex-A76 by giving our partners the opportunity to push the clock-speed past 3.0GHz and up to 3.3GHz within power envelopes around half that of today’s mass-market x86 processors.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A robust and rapidly-expanding laptop ecosystem&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leading PC OEMs already recognize that efficiency is a key differentiator for the always-on, always-connected, laptop experience which is characterized by very slim, light form factors, full day battery, and excellent responsiveness. Windows 10 systems powered by Arm-based Qualcomm Snapdragon SoCs are already available from ASUS, Lenovo, HP, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.qualcomm.com/news/releases/2018/06/04/qualcomm-announces-snapdragon-850-mobile-compute-platform-windows-10-pcs&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Qualcomm Announces Snapdragon 850 Mobile Compute Platform for Windows 10 PCs&quot;&gt;and Samsung have also announced they will join the mix as well&lt;/a&gt;. Along with Microsoft, these partners have given users a new choice for connectivity and an always-on experience that was not possible a year ago. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Arm didn’t build the mobile ecosystem by just relying on its efficiency leadership. We accelerated the performance gain through our annual design cadence, while improving efficiency and silicon footprint. This has enabled our ecosystem of silicon, software, and OEM partners to bring smartphones to market every year with new innovations and features. Our latest roadmap highlights that we’re bringing these same annual PPA improvements to the PC industry which now has both the opportunity and headroom to accelerate innovation like never before. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The CPU roadmap Arm has laid out coupled with Qualcomm’s heterogenous approach to computing across our various IP block and integrated connectivity, will allow for new advancements in the always-on, always-connected PC experience offered by the Qualcomm Snapdragon Mobile Compute Platform,” said Alex Katouzian, senior vice president and general manager, mobile, Qualcomm Technologies, Inc. “Our mission continues to bring the best of the mobile world to the PC, with great battery life, sleek innovative form factors, and Windows 10 for on-the-go productivity.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2018 was an important first step in expanding the Arm PC ecosystem and showing the world that we’re no longer bound to the idea that process technology will only incrementally improve every two years and that a laptop will need charging every few hours.  The pace of innovation that transformed smartphones into the compute platform of choice is now powering  and transforming the larger screen devices.  The question now for the broader PC industry is: Are you ready to liberate yourselves from the slowing pace of Moore’s law and deliver the mobile productivity experience consumers and businesses will need as we enter the 5G era? &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 14:09:49 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>redial</dc:creator>
<og:title>Arm acquires Treasure Data to set the stage for IoT transformation</og:title>
<og:description>Arm unveils its first-ever public CPU forward-looking roadmap and performance numbers</og:description>
<og:image>https://www.arm.com:443</og:image>
<og:url>https://www.arm.com/company/news/2018/08/accelerating-mobile-and-laptop-performance</og:url>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.arm.com/company/news/2018/08/accelerating-mobile-and-laptop-performance</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Pre-sleep treatment with galantamine stimulates lucid dreaming</title>
<link>http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;abstract toc-section&quot; readability=&quot;24&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lucid dreaming is a remarkable state of consciousness in which one is aware of the fact that one is dreaming while continuing to dream. Based on the strong relationship between physiological activation during rapid eye-movement sleep and lucid dreaming, our pilot research investigated whether enhancing cortical activation via acetylcholinesterease inhibition (AChEI) would increase the frequency of lucid dreams and found AChEI to be a promising method for lucid dream induction. In the current study we sought to quantify the size and reliability of the effect of AChEI on lucid dreaming, dream recall and dream content as well as to test the effectiveness of an integrated lucid dream induction protocol which combined cholinergic stimulation with other methods for lucid dream induction. Participants (N = 121) with high dream recall and an interest in lucid dreaming were randomly assigned counterbalanced orders of 3 doses of galantamine (0, 4 and 8 mg). On 3 consecutive nights, they awoke approximately 4.5 hours after lights out, recalled a dream, ingested the capsules and stayed out of bed for at least 30 minutes. Participants then returned to bed and practiced the Mnemonic Induction of Lucid Dreams technique while returning to sleep. The percentage of participants who reported a lucid dream was significantly increased for both 4 mg (27%, odds ratio = 2.29) and 8 mg doses (42%, odds ratio = 4.46) compared to the active placebo procedure (14%). Galantamine also significantly increased dream recall, sensory vividness and complexity (&lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt;&amp;lt;0.05). Dream recall, cognitive clarity, control, positive emotion, vividness and self-reflection were increased during lucid compared to non-lucid dreams (&lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt;&amp;lt;0.0001). These results show that galantamine increases the frequency of lucid dreams in a dose-related manner. Furthermore, the integrated method of taking galantamine in the last third of the night with at least 30 minutes of sleep interruption and with an appropriately focused mental set is one of the most effective methods for inducing lucid dreams available today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;articleinfo&quot; readability=&quot;64.950432730134&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Citation:&lt;/strong&gt; LaBerge S, LaMarca K, Baird B (2018) Pre-sleep treatment with galantamine stimulates lucid dreaming: A double-blind, placebo-controlled, crossover study. PLoS ONE 13(8): e0201246. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0201246&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Editor:&lt;/strong&gt; Raffaele Ferri, Associazione OASI Maria SS, ITALY&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Received:&lt;/strong&gt; December 4, 2017; &lt;strong&gt;Accepted:&lt;/strong&gt; July 11, 2018; &lt;strong&gt;Published:&lt;/strong&gt; August 8, 2018&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Copyright:&lt;/strong&gt; © 2018 LaBerge et al. This is an open access article distributed under the terms of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/&quot;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution License&lt;/a&gt;, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data Availability:&lt;/strong&gt; All data files are available from the Open Science Framework (OSF) database (DOI &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.17605/OSF.IO/VA3X6&quot;&gt;10.17605/OSF.IO/VA3X6&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Funding:&lt;/strong&gt; B.B. was supported by the National Institutes of Health under Ruth L. Kirschstein National Research Service Award F32NS089348 from the NINDS. The content is solely the responsibility of the authors and does not necessarily represent the official views of the National Institutes of Health. The funder had no role in study design, data collection and analysis, decision to publish, or preparation of the manuscript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Competing interests:&lt;/strong&gt; The authors have declared that no competing interests exist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;section1&quot; class=&quot;section toc-section&quot; readability=&quot;90.414522058824&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During a lucid dream one becomes aware that one is dreaming while continuing to dream. In this remarkable state of consciousness, one can reflect rationally and engage in purposeful, volitional actions within the dream. For example, lucid dreamers can recognize that their current sensory experience is a mental construction unrestricted by the usual limits of the waking physical world and often recall details about waking conditions. These details can include autobiographical memories from waking, as well as preset intentions to carry out specific actions in the dream [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.ref001&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.ref002&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;]. Awareness of dreaming, and the increased volition and autobiographical memory that often accompany it, occurs while the dreamer remains in unequivocal REM sleep [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.ref003&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;], immersed in a dream environment that can appear strikingly realistic. Lucid dreaming presents a unique opportunity for entertainment, exploration and personal growth [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.ref004&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;]. Furthermore, the scientific study of lucid dreaming opens novel experimental approaches for studying the psychophysiology of REM sleep that have the potential to expand our understanding of the relationship between consciousness and brain activity [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.ref005&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;]. However, while the majority of people report having experienced a lucid dream at least once in their lives, for most people lucid dreams occur very infrequently [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.ref006&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;]. Accordingly, the development of reliable methods of inducing lucid dreams is an important focus of research [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.ref004&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.ref007&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;–&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.ref013&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;13&lt;/a&gt;].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his dissertation, LaBerge [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.ref014&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;14&lt;/a&gt;] developed one of the first reliable techniques for lucid dream induction based on scientific research, referred to as the Mnemonic Induction of Lucid Dreams (MILD). The purpose of MILD is to increase the frequency of lucid dreams using the intention to remember to do something in the future, a behavior now termed prospective memory. To effectively practice MILD requires good dream recall. One begins by remembering a dream, either from a previous night or, ideally, from which one has just awakened. One then identifies an anomaly within the dream that is characteristic of one’s dreams (called a “dreamsign” [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.ref001&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;]). Then, one visualizes returning to the dream, and rehearses recognizing that this anomaly only occurs in dreams, thereby becoming lucid. During this visualization, the practitioner mentally recites, “The next time I’m dreaming I want to remember to recognize that I’m dreaming.” In addition, the technique involves visualizing carrying out a preselected action when one becomes lucid. A meditative focus is required to use MILD effectively. The practitioner repeatedly lets go of distracting thoughts, returning focus on the visualization of recognizing the dreamsign, becoming lucid, and performing the preselected goal, consistently until falling back to sleep. In a case report, LaBerge [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.ref007&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;] found that MILD was approximately 800% more effective than autosuggestion for inducing signal-verified lucid dreams in the sleep laboratory. Follow-up studies have confirmed that MILD can increase lucid dream frequency [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.ref015&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;15&lt;/a&gt;].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another lucid dream induction technique is to use a sensory stimulus as a cue, such as a flashing light applied over the sleeper’s eyes via a sleep mask during REM sleep [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.ref008&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.ref010&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;10&lt;/a&gt;]. Such stimuli are frequently incorporated into an ongoing dream, and with proper mental preparation, individuals can learn to identify the stimulus as a cue and thereby become lucid. Again, prospective memory—the intention to recognize the cue—is required for success with this technique of lucid dream induction. A third approach to lucid dream induction arose from reports that lucid dreaming was more likely after engaging in certain activities during the night, such as meditation, sexual intercourse or reading (e.g., [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.ref016&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;16&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.ref017&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;17&lt;/a&gt;]). Given the diversity of these activities, LaBerge [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.ref007&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;] suggested that it was not the particular activity but rather the period of alert wakefulness that made lucid dreaming more likely during subsequent sleep. A period of 10–15 minutes of wakefulness was therefore incorporated into the MILD technique [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.ref007&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;]. Subsequent studies showed that combining MILD with a longer period of wakefulness of either 30 to 60 minutes late in the sleep cycle was associated with even higher increases in lucid dream frequency in the ensuing sleep period [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.ref018&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;18&lt;/a&gt;]. Consistent with these findings, a recent study found that participants who practiced a combination of MILD and sleep interruption nightly for two weeks demonstrated increased lucid dreaming frequency [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.ref019&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;19&lt;/a&gt;].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In earlier research we found that lucid dreams tend to occur during periods of increased physiological activation during REM sleep, and that measures of phasic central nervous system activation, such as increased eye movement density, are associated with lucid dreams [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.ref005&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.ref020&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;20&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.ref021&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;21&lt;/a&gt;]. Therefore, increasing physiological activation in REM sleep is another potentially fruitful avenue to explore for stimulating lucidity in dreams. Given the strong evidence that REM sleep is modulated by acetylcholine [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.ref022&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;22&lt;/a&gt;–&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.ref024&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;24&lt;/a&gt;] and furthermore that acetylcholinesterease inhibition increases REM sleep phasic activity [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.ref025&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;25&lt;/a&gt;], we tested whether enhancing cortical activation via cholinergic stimulation would increase the frequency of lucid dreaming. In an initial pilot study [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.ref026&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;26&lt;/a&gt;], we evaluated the influence of either 0 mg (placebo), 5 mg, or 10 mg of donepezil (Aricept®), an acetylcholinesterease inhibitor (AChEI), administered at bedtime in a within-subjects counter-balanced order on three nights in a small group of individuals with prior experience in lucid dreaming. Nine of the ten participants (90%) reported one or more lucid dreams on the experimental nights on donepezil, with only one participant reporting a lucid dream on a placebo night (&lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt;&amp;lt;0.01).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the current study we sought to quantify the size and reliability of the effect of AChEIs on lucid dreaming, dream recall and dream content. We evaluated the effect of galantamine, a fast acting AChEI with a mild side effect profile, in a large group of individuals (N = 121) with an interest in lucid dreaming. We tested the effect of galantamine taken during a period of sleep interruption after approximately the third REM cycle. This design allowed us to examine the combined effectiveness of an integrated lucid dream induction protocol, incorporating sleep interruption and the MILD technique together with cholinergic enhancement. Data was collected using a double blind, placebo-controlled, cross-over design across six lucid dreaming training programs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;section2&quot; class=&quot;section toc-section&quot; readability=&quot;75.481025383262&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Materials and methods&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;section1&quot; class=&quot;section toc-section&quot; readability=&quot;34&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Participants&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Volunteers were recruited from a high-interest group attending one of six, 8-day training programs on lucid dreaming, titled “Dreaming and Awakening”, presented by the Lucidity Institute. The study was approved by the Lucidity Institute research ethics committee and was conducted in accordance with the Declaration of Helsinki. Participation in the study was voluntary. All participants provided signed informed consent prior to the experiment. Participants’ responses were treated confidentially and anonymously. Exclusion criteria included asthma, taking beta-blockers, severe mental illness or cardiac arrhythmias. However, no exclusions were made for biomedical reasons as no participants presented with any of the exclusionary criteria. The details, study rationale, and possible side effects of cholinergic stimulation, as described above, were explained, including the possibility of unpleasant side effects such as insomnia or nausea. Participants were aware that on at least one of the experiment nights they would be receiving an active dose of an over-the-counter supplement. All workshop participants who met the eligibility criteria and wished to participate in the experiment were included in the study. Extensive piloting of the procedures in previous workshops allowed us to hold all aspects of the protocol constant throughout the entire duration of the study.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One hundred twenty nine participants participated in the study. Eight participants were not included in analysis due to not completing at least two nights of the experiment or following instructions, including one participant who discontinued the study due to nausea, and one to avoid the sleep disturbance from completing the nightly procedures. The final group included in the analysis consisted of 121 participants (63 males, 58 females), age 43 ± 12, 19–75 years [mean ± SD, range]. Participants reported median rates of 1 dream recalled per night and 3–5 lucid dreams recalled per year, similar to pre-experiment estimates of the number of lucid dreams recalled in the last six months (median = 2), and most recalled in any 6-month period (median = 3). Ten participants reported no previous lucid dreams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;section2&quot; class=&quot;section toc-section&quot; readability=&quot;92.224483455026&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Procedures&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Participants engaged in an integrated lucid dream induction protocol, which combined sleep interruption and the Mnemonic Induction of Lucid Dreams (MILD) technique together with cholinergic enhancement. As part of the workshop, participants attended lectures about lucid dreaming, which explained what lucid dreams are, reviewed examples of lucid dreams, and provided time for discussion and questions. Participants therefore obtained a thorough conceptual understanding of lucid dreaming during the training workshop before the experiment began. As part of their training in MILD (described above), they learned specific strategies for recognizing cues that they are dreaming [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.ref027&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;27&lt;/a&gt;], prolonging the lucid dream state [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.ref028&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;28&lt;/a&gt;], and responding adaptively to nightmares and sleep paralysis [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.ref004&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Participants were instructed on the nightly reporting procedures and the protocol for sleep interruption, which included a modified sleep schedule in which participants interrupted their sleep with a 30-minute period of wakefulness after approximately 4.5 hours of sleep (a rough estimate of 3 REM periods) [see &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone-0201246-g001&quot;&gt;Fig 1&lt;/a&gt; for a schematic diagram of the experimental procedure]. The 30-minute sleep interruption period was selected based on previous research, as noted above, showing that 30 minutes of sleep interruption is more effective than shorter amounts of time [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.ref018&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;18&lt;/a&gt;]. We did not set the sleep interruption period for longer than 30 minutes because it does not lead to further increases in lucid dream frequency. Furthermore, galantamine reaches peak serum concentration (Cmax) approximately 1 hour after oral ingestion [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.ref029&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;29&lt;/a&gt;], and we wanted to align Cmax to occur during the next sleep (and dream) period after allowing participants time to fall back to sleep. Participants practiced MILD while returning to sleep for all awakenings after the sleep interruption period. 94 participants also wore a sleep mask which recorded physiological variables and provided additional memory cues during sleep [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.ref008&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.ref010&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;10&lt;/a&gt;] (see &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.s002&quot;&gt;S2 Appendix&lt;/a&gt;). Participants who opted to sleep with the mask were required to use it on all three nights of the experiment after the sleep interruption period. Participants used a paper-pencil form to track their nightly experiences and time variables, including their lights out time, the time they started the sleep interruption period, the length of the sleep interruption period, the time they ingested the capsules, and their rising time in the morning. Participants were given two nights prior to the experiment to practice the induction and reporting protocol. The experiment was initiated on the fifth night of the workshop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;figure&quot; data-doi=&quot;10.1371/journal.pone.0201246.g001&quot; readability=&quot;17.449494949495&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-box&quot;&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;Click for larger image&quot; href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/figure/image?size=medium&amp;amp;id=info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0201246.g001&quot; data-doi=&quot;info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0201246&quot; data-uri=&quot;info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0201246.g001&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/figure/image?size=inline&amp;amp;id=info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0201246.g001&quot; alt=&quot;thumbnail&quot; class=&quot;thumbnail&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Fig 1.&lt;/span&gt; Schematic diagram of experimental procedure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Note: figure not to scale, timing approximate). &lt;strong&gt;A.&lt;/strong&gt; LO: Lights Out. Sleep for approximately 3 REM cycles. &lt;strong&gt;B.&lt;/strong&gt; DREC: Recall and memorize dream upon awakening to use with MILD procedure at &lt;strong&gt;E&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;C.&lt;/strong&gt; Ingest galantamine capsules. (All participants received all three doses (0, 4, and 8 mg) in one of 6 counterbalanced orders.) &lt;strong&gt;D.&lt;/strong&gt; Sleep interruption (out of bed for 30 min). Engage in quiet activity with focus on lucid dreaming. (“Wake back to bed&quot;) &lt;strong&gt;E.&lt;/strong&gt; Return to sleep practicing MILD using the dream recalled at &lt;strong&gt;B. F.&lt;/strong&gt; Experimental Nap(s). &lt;strong&gt;G.&lt;/strong&gt; REPORT: On awakening, dream recall, content scales, and full reports for lucid dreams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption_object&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0201246.g001&quot;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0201246.g001&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Participants were randomly assigned subject numbers. On each night (A, B, C), they received a coded packet, according to their subject numbers and appropriate night, containing capsules with 0 mg (G0), 4 mg (G4), or 8 mg (G8) of galantamine hydrobromide (Life Enhancement Products Galantamind; &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.s002&quot;&gt;S2 Appendix&lt;/a&gt;). Numbered packets were arranged to provide a counterbalanced order of doses; however, the participants and experimenters were unaware which dose individuals would be receiving on a particular night (double-blind design). Each night, participants awoke after approximately 4.5 hours of sleep, recalled and memorized a dream, ingested the capsules, and then remained awake for the sleep interruption period while engaged in a quiet wakeful activity of their choice (e.g., reading about lucid dreaming or recording or reviewing their dreams). Participants then returned to bed, practicing MILD until they fell asleep. For all awakenings after the period of sleep interruption, participants completed the report form and recorded the time they woke up and the type of dream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As noted above, lucidity can arise during an ongoing dream (often through the recognition of a cue or an anomaly indicating that one is dreaming) or, less commonly, by maintaining awareness while transitioning directly from the waking state into a dream. These two types of lucid dream onset are referred to respectively as dream-initiated lucid dreams (DILDs) and wake-initiated lucid dreams (WILDs) [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.ref015&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;15&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.ref020&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;20&lt;/a&gt;]. On the dream report forms, participants categorized their dream as none (did not recall a dream), non-lucid dream, DILD or WILD. If participants recalled a dream, they rated their extent of dream recall and rated the dream on several dimensions of conscious experience, including sensory vividness, clarity of thinking, negative and positive emotion, bizarreness, complexity, self-reflection, public self-consciousness, and degree of dream control (all on a 0 to 4 scale with 0 = none, 4 = high). Participants also reported &quot;odd somatic sensations&quot;, such as strange bodily feelings, paralysis, tingling, vibrations, etc. as well as any perceived side effects (&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.s002&quot;&gt;S2 Appendix&lt;/a&gt;). For lucid dreams participants wrote a full narrative report of the dream. In the reports, participants were asked to specify the point in the dream report at which they became lucid as well as how they knew they were dreaming (e.g., if it was triggered by a particular event or associated with a specific thought during the dream). Participants also gave a follow-up oral report of all lucid dreams the following morning. Two complementary criteria had to be met in order for a dream report to be classified as lucid. First, the participant himself or herself had to rate their dream as lucid (either a DILD or a WILD). Second, dream reports had to include a reference to the current state as a dream (for example, “It was at this point I knew it was a dream”; “I realized I am dreaming”; “I said aloud, ‘&lt;em&gt;This is a dream&lt;/em&gt;.’”).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;section3&quot; class=&quot;section toc-section&quot; readability=&quot;25.975655430712&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Statistical analysis&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Linear mixed models were used to account for repeated measures with varied numbers of repeated observations within subjects. The model for evaluating the effect of DOSE (&lt;em&gt;active placebo (G0)&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;galantamine 4 mg (G4)&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;galantamine 8 mg (G8))&lt;/em&gt; on STATE (&lt;em&gt;lucid&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;non-lucid&lt;/em&gt;) used restricted maximum likelihood estimation (REML) and included DOSE and NIGHT (&lt;em&gt;1&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;2&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;3&lt;/em&gt;) as fixed effects and STATE as the outcome variable. The model for responses to the dimensions of consciousness (DIMs) scale used restricted maximum likelihood estimation (REML) and included participant as a random factor, and NIGHT, DOSE, and STATE as fixed effects. As questionnaire responses as well as outcome measures were not normally distributed, we used nonparametric bootstrapping for all significance tests. (We also evaluated the effect of DOSE on STATE using binary logistic regression, for which identical significance thresholds were obtained compared to the bootstrap method). Hypothesis testing of regression coefficients (pairwise tests) from the mixed models was obtained by the following steps: &lt;em&gt;i&lt;/em&gt;) constructing a model based on the null hypothesis of no differences between STATE (&lt;em&gt;H&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sub&gt;&lt;em&gt;0&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;), &lt;em&gt;ii&lt;/em&gt;) resampling with replacement the distribution of the response residuals under the null model, reconstructing a bootstrap &lt;em&gt;y&lt;/em&gt; response vector, and refitting the &lt;em&gt;H&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sub&gt;&lt;em&gt;1&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; model to the bootstrap response vectors to generate 10,000 bootstrap estimates of the regression coefficients (&lt;em&gt;ß&lt;/em&gt;) under &lt;em&gt;H&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sub&gt;&lt;em&gt;0&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;iii&lt;/em&gt;) comparing the observed value of &lt;em&gt;ß&lt;/em&gt; against the null bootstrap distribution (two-tailed frequentist &lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt;-value). Mixed model construction and mixed model bootstrapping were performed with the lme4 package [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.ref030&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;30&lt;/a&gt;] in the R environment (R Development Core Team, 2006). Mixed model fixed effects were assessed by means of a bootstrap likelihood ratio test on mixed effects models (PBmodcomp in R) specified with maximum likelihood estimation (MLE). We tested 10 DIMs variables for both STATE and DOSE effects (40 total tests); we therefore corrected the type I error rate for these multiple comparisons with the Bonferroni correction (critical α = 0.05/40 = 0.0012).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;section4&quot; class=&quot;section toc-section&quot; readability=&quot;15.971580817052&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Bayesian classification&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We evaluated the extent to which STATE (&lt;em&gt;lucid&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;non-lucid&lt;/em&gt;) could be classified using a Bayesian classification procedure developed and validated by Allen et al. [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.ref031&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;31&lt;/a&gt;]. We performed a 2-step split-half classification: in the first half, we used binary logistic regression to determine the content variables with the highest predictive value (regression coefficients); in the second half, we then used Bayesian combination of these multiple indicators (predictor variables) to calculate the Bayesian Posterior Probability (BPP) (i.e., the probability that a dream was either lucid or non-lucid given an observed combination of indicators, for example high control and high positive emotionality). The cutpoint for each variable was set at 2 on the 0–4 scale; thus, scores of 0–2 were categorized as low and scores of 3–4 were categorized as high. The BPP is equal to the proportion of dream reports associated with lucid dreams that show the combination of indicators divided by the proportion of all trials (lucid and non-lucid) showing the combination of indicators (1.00 = perfect classification).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;section3&quot; class=&quot;section toc-section&quot; readability=&quot;71.233858510967&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Results&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On average, participants reported a total sleep period (lights out to rising time) of 8.1 ± 1.3 [mean ± SD] hours. The sleep interruption period was started on average at 4.54 ± 0.86 [mean ± SD] hours after lights out and lasted 36 ± 18 [mean ± SD] minutes. Lights out to rising time after the sleep interruption period lasted an average of 3.3 ± 1.1 [mean ± SD] hours. In total, 485 dreams were reported: 85 (17%) were DILDs, 32 (7%) were WILDs, and 368 (76%) non-lucid dreams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;section1&quot; class=&quot;section toc-section&quot; readability=&quot;54.152812762385&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Lucidity&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;75 participants (62%) reported one or more lucid dreams during the study—69 (57%) on one or more nights with galantamine and 17 (14%) with the active placebo procedure (including sleep interruption and MILD); 33 (27%) participants with the 4 mg dose, and 51 (42%) participants with the 8 mg dose [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone-0201246-g001&quot;&gt;Fig 1&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone-0201246-t001&quot;&gt;Table 1&lt;/a&gt;; see &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.s001&quot;&gt;S1 Appendix&lt;/a&gt; for examples of lucid dreams participants reported during the study]. There was a main effect of galantamine on lucidity [likelihood ratio: 25.54, &lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt;&amp;lt;0.001]. Significantly increased incidence of lucid dreaming was observed for both 4 mg (&lt;em&gt;ß&lt;/em&gt; = 0.12, &lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; = 0.03, odds ratio = 2.29, 95% CI = 1.19–4.38) and 8 mg doses (&lt;em&gt;ß&lt;/em&gt; = 0.28, &lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt;&amp;lt;0.0001, odds ratio = 4.46, 95% CI = 2.38–8.35) compared to the active placebo [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone-0201246-g002&quot;&gt;Fig 2&lt;/a&gt;]. The 8 mg dose resulted in significantly higher incidence of lucid dreams compared to the 4 mg dose (&lt;em&gt;ß&lt;/em&gt; = 0.16, &lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; = 0.004, odds ratio = 1.94, 95% CI = 1.13–3.33). A dose response analysis confirmed a dose-related response (linear trend) for lucid dreaming probability by galantamine exposure (Mantel-Haenszel &lt;em&gt;χ&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; for linear trend = 23.03, &lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; = 0.000001). Compared to the expected frequency of lucid dreams (4%, based on self-reported frequency of lucid dreaming during the 6 months prior to the experiment), lucid dream frequency was approximately three times higher (14%, &lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; = 0.01) for the active placebo procedure (including MILD and sleep interruption). For the combined protocol with 4 mg galantamine, lucid dream frequency was approximately 6 times higher than expected (27%, &lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt;&amp;lt;10&lt;sup&gt;−5&lt;/sup&gt;), and approximately 9 times higher than expected for the combined protocol with 8 mg galantamine (42%, &lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt;&amp;lt;10&lt;sup&gt;−10&lt;/sup&gt;) [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone-0201246-t001&quot;&gt;Table 1&lt;/a&gt;].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;figure&quot; data-doi=&quot;10.1371/journal.pone.0201246.g002&quot; readability=&quot;17.423469387755&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-box&quot;&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;Click for larger image&quot; href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/figure/image?size=medium&amp;amp;id=info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0201246.g002&quot; data-doi=&quot;info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0201246&quot; data-uri=&quot;info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0201246.g002&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/figure/image?size=inline&amp;amp;id=info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0201246.g002&quot; alt=&quot;thumbnail&quot; class=&quot;thumbnail&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Fig 2.&lt;/span&gt; Percent of participants (N = 121) reporting at least one lucid dream (LD) on returning to sleep following ingestion of one of three masked doses of galantamine (0 mg [G0], 4 mg [G4], and 8 mg [G8]) prior to 30–40 minutes out of bed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The baseline estimate (“BASE”, 4%) of lucid dreaming frequency for one night was calculated from the self-reported estimates of how many LDs participants experienced in the previous six months, divided by 180. [95% CI computed by resampling.] Error bars show estimated standard error of the conditional means. Asterisks indicate statistically significant differences between conditions: * p&amp;lt;0.05; ** p&amp;lt;0.01; *** p&amp;lt;0.001.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption_object&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0201246.g002&quot;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0201246.g002&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;figure&quot; data-doi=&quot;10.1371/journal.pone.0201246.t001&quot; readability=&quot;9.6492307692308&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-box&quot;&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;Click for larger image&quot; href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/figure/image?size=medium&amp;amp;id=info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0201246.t001&quot; data-doi=&quot;info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0201246&quot; data-uri=&quot;info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0201246.t001&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/figure/image?size=inline&amp;amp;id=info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0201246.t001&quot; alt=&quot;thumbnail&quot; class=&quot;thumbnail&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Table 1.&lt;/span&gt; Percent of 121 participants reporting at least one lucid dream in a double-blind, randomized crossover design comparing pre-sleep administration of three doses of Galantamine (0 mg, 4 mg, and 8 mg).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption_object&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0201246.t001&quot;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0201246.t001&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was no main effect of night on lucidity [likelihood ratio: 1.33, &lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; = 0.52], indicating that participants were not more likely to have a lucid dream on subsequent nights of the experiment independently of other effects. Furthermore, there was no effect of dose order on the likelihood of having a lucid dream (&lt;em&gt;F&lt;/em&gt;(1,5) = 0.31, &lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; = 0.90), supporting that consecutive nights were not too close together. Across all dream reports, participants reported a total of 15 DILDs on placebo, 27 DILDs on the 4 mg dose and 43 DILDs on the 8 mg dose, while 3 WILDs were reported on placebo, 10 WILDs on the 4 mg dose and 19 WILDs on the 8 mg dose. Both DILDs (&lt;em&gt;ß&lt;/em&gt; = 0.096, &lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; = 0.006) and WILDs (&lt;em&gt;ß&lt;/em&gt; = 0.063, &lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; = 0.004) were significantly increased on an active dose of galantamine compared to placebo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;section2&quot; class=&quot;section toc-section&quot; readability=&quot;19&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Age and gender effects&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall there was no significant association between age and the frequency of lucid dreams reported during the study (&lt;em&gt;ß&lt;/em&gt; = -0.003, &lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; = 0.09). Additionally, there was no difference in age between participants who had a lucid dream on an active dose of galantamine and those who did not (&lt;em&gt;t&lt;/em&gt;(119) = 1.16, &lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; = 0.25). Older individuals did, however, report overall reduced levels of dream recall (&lt;em&gt;ß&lt;/em&gt; = -0.016, &lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; = 0.02). There were no gender differences in lucid dream frequency during the study overall (males = 36, females = 39, &lt;em&gt;t&lt;/em&gt;(119) = 1.14, &lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; = 0.26) or on an active dose of galantamine (females: 33 out of 58 participants (56.8%); males: 36 out of 63 participants (57.1%)).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;section3&quot; class=&quot;section toc-section&quot; readability=&quot;19&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Prior experience with lucid dreaming&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Participants with higher baseline levels of lucid dreams, as estimated by the number of lucid dreams in the last 6 months, were more likely to have lucid dreams during the experiment overall (&lt;em&gt;ß&lt;/em&gt; = 0.04, &lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; = 0.0001). Furthermore, individuals who had a lucid dream on an active dose of galantamine reported higher baseline lucid dreaming frequency than those who did not have a lucid dream on the active dose [&lt;em&gt;t&lt;/em&gt;(119) = 2.65, &lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; = 0.009]. As noted above, 10 participants reported never experiencing a lucid dream before the experiment. Four of these participants (40%) were able to achieve lucidity during the study, all with the 8 mg dose of galantamine. This was similar to the 42% success rate (47/111) with the same dose for individuals reporting at least one lucid dream prior to the study. No difference in the success rate was observed between individuals who reported a lucid dream prior to the study and those who had never had a lucid dream (&lt;em&gt;χ&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; (1,N = 121) = 1.28, &lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; = 0.25).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;section4&quot; class=&quot;section toc-section&quot; readability=&quot;16.663063063063&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;MILD and sleep interruption&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Participants who practiced MILD for at least 10 minutes (the recommended minimum amount of time) were more likely to have a lucid dream (&lt;em&gt;ß&lt;/em&gt; = 0.09, &lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt;&amp;lt;0.01, one-tailed). However, the total number of minutes practicing MILD did not predict success in having a lucid dream (&lt;em&gt;ß&lt;/em&gt; = 0.003, &lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; = 0.80). Participants were more likely to have a lucid dream if they engaged in at least 30 minutes of sleep interruption (&lt;em&gt;ß&lt;/em&gt; = 0.11, &lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; = 0.03, one-tailed; &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.s002&quot;&gt;S2 Appendix&lt;/a&gt;), confirming the value of sleep interruption for lucid dreaming induction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;section5&quot; class=&quot;section toc-section&quot; readability=&quot;28.425672113864&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Dream cognition and recall&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During lucid compared to non-lucid dreams, participants reported significantly higher sensory vividness, clarity, positive emotion, control, and self-reflection (all &lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt;&amp;lt;0.05, Bonferroni corrected; &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone-0201246-t002&quot;&gt;Table 2&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone-0201246-g003&quot;&gt;Fig 3&lt;/a&gt;). Increased complexity and bizarreness and decreased negative emotion were also observed (&lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt;&amp;lt;0.05), though these differences did not survive correction for multiple comparisons. Compared to placebo, both 4 mg and 8 mg doses of galantamine significantly increased sensory vividness and environmental complexity (all &lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt;&amp;lt;0.05, Bonferroni corrected; &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone-0201246-t003&quot;&gt;Table 3&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone-0201246-g003&quot;&gt;Fig 3&lt;/a&gt;). Increased bizarreness was observed under the 8 mg dose compared to placebo (&lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt;&amp;lt;0.05, Bonferroni corrected); 4 mg and 8 mg doses did not significantly differ on any dimension (all &lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt;&amp;gt;0.05; &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone-0201246-t003&quot;&gt;Table 3&lt;/a&gt;). Dream recall was higher for lucid compared to non-lucid dreams (&lt;em&gt;ß&lt;/em&gt; = 0.57, &lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt;&amp;lt;0.0001), and was higher under both the 4 mg (&lt;em&gt;ß&lt;/em&gt; = 0.43, &lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt;&amp;lt;0.0001) and 8 mg (&lt;em&gt;ß&lt;/em&gt; = 0.39, &lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt;&amp;lt;0.0001) doses compared to placebo. Lucid dreams on an active dose of galantamine did not differ from lucid dreams on the placebo dose for any content dimension (all &lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt;&amp;gt;0.05).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;figure&quot; data-doi=&quot;10.1371/journal.pone.0201246.g003&quot; readability=&quot;8.5371428571429&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-box&quot;&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;Click for larger image&quot; href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/figure/image?size=medium&amp;amp;id=info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0201246.g003&quot; data-doi=&quot;info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0201246&quot; data-uri=&quot;info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0201246.g003&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/figure/image?size=inline&amp;amp;id=info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0201246.g003&quot; alt=&quot;thumbnail&quot; class=&quot;thumbnail&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Fig 3.&lt;/span&gt; Responses to dimensions of consciousness (DIMs) questionnaire separated by lucid and non-lucid dreams and galantamine dose (G0 = 0 mg; G4 = 4 mg; G8 = 8 mg).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Points and error bars show the mean and standard error of the mean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption_object&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0201246.g003&quot;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0201246.g003&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;




&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;section6&quot; class=&quot;section toc-section&quot; readability=&quot;18.653758542141&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Prediction/Classification of lucid dreams&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In half 1 of the dataset, we first used binary logistic regression to predict lucidity from content dimensions of dreams. As shown in &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.s003&quot;&gt;S1 Table&lt;/a&gt;, the variables with the highest predictive values (regression coefficients) were positive emotion, cognitive clarity, sensory vividness and control (all &lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt;&amp;lt;0.005). Next, in half 2 of the dataset, we evaluated whether we could classify dreams as lucid or non-lucid using Bayesian combination of these variables (see Methods: &lt;em&gt;Bayesian classification&lt;/em&gt;). Control as a single indicator yielded 73% Bayesian classification accuracy of lucidity; combining control and positive emotion yielded 86.1% accuracy; combining control, positive emotion and cognitive clarity yielded 92.5% accuracy; combining control, positive emotion, cognitive clarity and sensory vividness yielded 95.5% accuracy (&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.s004&quot;&gt;S2 Table&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;section7&quot; class=&quot;section toc-section&quot; readability=&quot;12.758445945946&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Adverse effects&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Galantamine was generally well-tolerated with a total of 14 participants (12%) reporting mild side effects on an active dose: 12 (10%) and 11 (9%) with the 8 mg and 4 mg doses respectively (note that most participants who reported side effects reported them on both doses), compared to 4 (3%) with placebo. Side effects were more commonly reported for both the 4 mg dose (&lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; = 0.039) and 8 mg dose (&lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; = 0.057) compared to placebo, and did not significantly differ between doses (&lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; = 1). Reports included mild gastrointestinal upset, insomnia and next-day fatigue (&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.s002&quot;&gt;S2 Appendix&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;section4&quot; class=&quot;section toc-section&quot; readability=&quot;197.20725680325&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Discussion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Together our results show that galantamine substantially and significantly increases the frequency of lucid dreaming. The double blind and placebo-controlled design of this study provides strong evidence that cholinergic enhancement with galantamine causally increases the frequency of lucid dreams in a dose-related manner. Increased incidence of lucid dreaming was observed for both 4 mg (27%) and 8 mg (42%) doses compared to 14% for the active placebo, with an increased incidence of lucid dreams in the 8 mg dose compared to 4 mg dose. In addition to assessing galantamine’s influence on lucid dreams, our study tested an integrated protocol for inducing lucid dreams, which combined some of the most effective existing methods of lucid dream induction reported in previous studies (including sleep interruption [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.ref018&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;18&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.ref032&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;32&lt;/a&gt;] and the Mnemonic Induction of Lucid Dreams (MILD) technique [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.ref007&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;]) together with cholinergic enhancement. This combined protocol resulted in a total of 69 out of 121 participants (57%) successfully having a lucid dream on at least one out of two nights on an active dose of galantamine. This protocol is one of the most effective methods for inducing lucid dreams known to-date, and holds promise for making lucid dreaming available to a wider population.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mechanism by which AChE inhibition results in lucid dreams is not understood at this time. Acetylcholinesterase inhibitors (AChEls) inhibit the normal metabolic inactivation of acetylcholine (ACh) by inhibiting the enzyme, acetylcholinesterase (AChE), leading to accumulation of ACh. It is known that ACh and its agonists as well as AChE and its inhibitors/antagonists are involved with REM sleep [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.ref022&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;22&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.ref023&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;23&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.ref033&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;33&lt;/a&gt;]. Specifically, evidence suggests that REM sleep is modulated by acetylcholine and controlled by cholinergic neurons in the brainstem [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.ref024&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;24&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.ref034&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;34&lt;/a&gt;]. For example, microinjection of the ACh agonist carbachol in the pons elicits extended periods of REM sleep, and many of the neurons critical to REM sleep are responsive to ACh [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.ref024&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;24&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.ref033&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;33&lt;/a&gt;]. Furthermore, galantamine in particular has been associated with shortened REM latency and increased phasic activity, including REM density [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.ref025&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;25&lt;/a&gt;]. Notably, AChEls are also commonly used to enhance memory in patients suffering from Alzheimer's disease, and have shown promise in managing the symptoms of mild cognitive impairment [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.ref035&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;35&lt;/a&gt;]. Galantamine belongs to a class of drugs that includes donepezil (Aricept®) and rivastigmine (Exelon®), which are frequently associated with the reported side effect of an increase in the vividness or intensity of dreams [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.ref036&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;36&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.ref037&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;37&lt;/a&gt;].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In general, therefore, the increased prevalence of lucid dreams caused by galantamine is likely to be related to its effects on cholinergic receptor activity during REM sleep, which could include one or several different mechanisms, including the reduction in REM sleep latency, or more likely, increased phasic activity, which our previous research has shown to be strongly associated with lucid dreaming [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.ref021&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;21&lt;/a&gt;]. The improvements in memory associated with galantamine may also contribute to increased propensity for lucid dreams, for example by increasing one’s ability to remember to recognize one is dreaming, which is a prospective memory task. Cholinergic modulation has also been shown to bias attention and behavior toward top-down goal directed responses, and away from bottom-up, habitual, and otherwise pre-potent responses [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.ref038&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;38&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.ref039&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;39&lt;/a&gt;]. In the context of dreaming, the bottom-up, habitual responses to dream content will likely be the notoriously nonlucid responses of ordinary dreaming. That means taking experienced content at face value, as if real, and engaged or ignored, as it appears relevant or not, to the goal-related activity one supposes one is pursuing within the given situation. However, experienced content need not be taken at face value, and instead can be recognized as &lt;em&gt;dream&lt;/em&gt; content. If the dreamer is sleeping with the mental set of becoming lucid by recognizing dream content predictive of dreaming [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.ref004&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;], cholinergic modulation should favor attaining this goal via the top-down facilitation effect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, as AChEls also influence systemic norepinephrine, dopamine and serotonin [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.ref040&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;40&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.ref041&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;41&lt;/a&gt;], another possible explanation is that the impact of AChEI on lucidity could be entirely, or partially, indirect, and lucid dreaming could be causally linked to the aminergic modulation that occurs as a corollary to the cholinergic modulation brought on by AChEl [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.ref042&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;42&lt;/a&gt;]. For instance, there is evidence that galantamine in particular enhances dopaminergic neurotransmission [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.ref043&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;43&lt;/a&gt;] and dopamine has been shown to enhance metacognition and conscious self-monitoring [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.ref044&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;44&lt;/a&gt;], which could potentially increase lucid dreaming. Future research will be needed for a better understanding of how the neuromodulatory changes brought on by AChEIs precisely facilitate the emergence of the higher-order consciousness and cognitive skills associated with lucid dreaming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to its effect on lucidity, galantamine was associated with increased recall, sensory vividness, bizarreness and complexity of dreams. We expected that galantamine would have a positive effect on memory given that, as noted above, AChEIs are used to treat memory deficits associated with Alzheimer's disease and mild cognitive impairment. As discussed above, evidence suggests that REM sleep is modulated by acetylcholine and that galantamine results in increased phasic activity during REM sleep [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.ref025&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;25&lt;/a&gt;]. The increased sensory vividness, bizarreness and complexity of dreams on galantamine are therefore consistent with the general intensification of REM sleep (and associated dreaming) triggered by the cholinergic enhancement [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.ref025&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;25&lt;/a&gt;].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lucid dreams overall were associated with significantly higher levels of recall, cognitive clarity, control, positive emotion, sensory vividness and self-reflection on one’s thoughts and feelings compared to non-lucid dreams. This finding replicates the largest previous study of lucid dream phenomenology [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.ref045&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;45&lt;/a&gt;], which analyzed self-rated content scales from 699 reports provided by 52 relatively experienced lucid dreamers and found that lucid dreams had significantly higher levels of control, positive emotions, visual vividness and clarity of thinking. Our findings are also broadly consistent with a recent study comparing lucid and non-lucid dream phenomenology by Voss et al. [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.ref046&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;46&lt;/a&gt;], which found that lucid dreams had greater amounts of control, self-reflective thought, memory, and positive emotion. Our results suggest that, aside from the state-consciousness that defines being lucid (the explicit awareness of being in a dream), lucid dreams are best characterized by increased control, cognitive clarity, positive emotion and sensory vividness. Bayesian combination of these four dimensions allowed us to classify lucid dreams with greater than 95% accuracy, indicating that dreams that are scored high on all of these features are very likely to be lucid. Nevertheless, we would like to emphasize that increased self-ratings on these (or other) dream features is not sufficient to establish whether an individual was lucid. Indeed, it is possible that some dreams could be high on all of these features but still be non-lucid, which is consistent with the fact that our classification was less than 100%. It is beyond the scope of the current analysis to undertake a more detailed investigation of differences in lucid and non-lucid dream phenomenology. However, there are currently very few systematic studies of content differences between lucid and non-lucid dreams, and future research on this question would be welcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two recent studies have attempted to induce lucid dreams with electrical stimulation of the brain and it might be asked how these techniques compare with the current approach. In one study, Stumbrys et al. [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.ref012&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;12&lt;/a&gt;] applied either tDCS or sham stimulation (counterbalanced across nights) to the frontal cortex during REM sleep. 7 out of 109 dreams were classified as having a clear indication of lucidity by a judge: 3 from sham stimulation and 4 from tDCS stimulation. As the difference of only 1 lucid dream between stimulation and sham conditions is well within any reasonable estimate of noise, overall tDCS as tested in this study appears to be ineffective for inducing lucid dreams. In another study, Voss et al. [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.ref013&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;13&lt;/a&gt;] reported that by applying transcranial alternating current stimulation (tACS) in the gamma frequency range over the frontal cortex, lucid dreams could be induced with a success rate of 58% under 25 Hz and 77% under 40 Hz stimulation. However, trials were arbitrarily classified as lucid solely on “elevated ratings (&amp;gt;mean + 2 s.e.) on either or both of the LuCiD scale factors insight and dissociation”. Voss et al. neither reported content analyses of the dream reports nor did they verify lucid dreaming through volitional eye-movement signaling. Dissociation in the sense of adopting a 3&lt;sup&gt;rd&lt;/sup&gt; person perspective has never been considered a defining feature of lucid dreams in the literature on the topic [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.ref004&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.ref005&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.ref047&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;47&lt;/a&gt;–&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.ref049&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;49&lt;/a&gt;], and it is therefore highly controversial to classify dreams as lucid based solely on higher ratings of dissociation. Moreover, Voss et al. did not report how many dreams met their criteria for dissociation only. While the insight subscale corresponds more closely to what other researchers as well as the public refer to as lucid dreaming, it is unfortunately not possible to determine unambiguously from scores on any of the questionnaire items whether an individual was lucid. Perhaps the largest issue with the inference that the stimulation resulted in lucid dreams was related to how the scale anchors ranged from 0 (strongly disagree) to 5 (strongly agree), yet mean response scores in the 25 and 40 Hz stimulation conditions ranged from ~0.5–1.0, meaning that on average participants reported that they &lt;em&gt;disagreed&lt;/em&gt; that their dream content contained insight and dissociation. Overall, the study did not show that tACS induced lucid dreams and it is too early to tell how effective tACS will be for lucid dream induction. Despite these considerations, we believe that follow-up studies using various methods of brain stimulation could be a fruitful direction for future research if properly combined with training in the mental set for induction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Individuals with high levels of dream recall, avid interest in lucid dreaming, and motivation to have lucid dreams are the kind of participants we expect to give similar results following the protocol for lucid dream induction evaluated here. It is again worth emphasizing that all of the statements regarding the effectiveness of galantamine in stimulating lucid dreams are in the specific context of a lucid dreaming training program in Hawaii, which teaches participants to cultivate effective mental sets for lucid dream induction. That is not to say that this protocol could not facilitate high rates of lucid dreaming in other motivated groups. Indeed, there are several factors that suggest that this protocol could be useful to a wide population. First, our study sample was comprised of individuals from diverse backgrounds who came from all over the world to attend the workshops, and included a wide age range (19–75 years). Our data suggest that galantamine is effective for inducing lucid dreams for adults of all ages and both sexes when combined with sleep interruption and MILD. Furthermore, while individuals who had a lucid dream on an active dose of galantamine reported higher baseline rates of lucid dreaming, the data show that previous experience with lucid dreaming is not necessary. Indeed, of the ten individuals who reported never experiencing a lucid dream before the study, 40% were able to have their first lucid dream ever in a single nap with galantamine (8 mg), a success rate that was not different from the rest of the sample.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As noted, a primary aim of this study was to develop a protocol for inducing lucid dreams by combining the most effective methods known for lucid dream induction together with cholinergic enhancement. However, because these methods were not tested here in isolation from each other, the precise quantitative effect of MILD and sleep interruption in this study remains unclear. Future studies might consider comparing, for example, MILD alone to MILD plus sleep interruption to MILD plus galantamine to MILD plus sleep interruption plus galantamine in order to address this question. Likewise there were several additional aspects of the training program likely to contribute in some degree to increased lucid dream frequency, from group discussion of lucid dreams to being in a unique environment, which together might be termed “set and setting”. The combined effect of these factors can be estimated by comparing lucid dream frequency on the placebo dose (14%) to the 4% estimated baseline rate. However, any influence of these factors does not impact the dose-related effect of galantamine on lucidity established by comparison to the placebo control condition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because the experiment was not conducted in a sleep laboratory, we therefore do not have physiological recordings of lucid dreams or polysomnographic validation of participants’ sleep stage. However, several aspects of our methodology lend weight to the authenticity of participants’ reports of lucid dreams. First, participants developed a thorough conceptual understanding of the meaning of lucid dreaming through lectures and discussion sections in the pre-experiment workshop, limiting any errors in self-reports due to misunderstandings of what constitutes a lucid dream. Second, as discussed above, participants explicitly reported whether they had a lucid dream (and if so what type), in contrast to other studies that have inferred lucidity based on measures of dream content (i.e., [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246#pone.0201246.ref013&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;13&lt;/a&gt;]). Finally, full written and oral reports of lucid dreams were collected, which had to include a clear indication of lucidity including explicit mention of knowing the current state was a dream. Together these factors provide confidence in the reliability of participants’ reports of lucid dreams in this study.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to the fact that sleep cycles could not be objectively assessed with a sleep hypnogram, the timing of the sleep interruption period had to be approximated rather than timed to specific REM cycles. Future research might test whether the impact of galantamine and sleep interruption can be further optimized by comparing protocols administered after specific sleep cycles, at specific placement with respect to sleep cycles, as well as the optimal activity to engage in during the sleep interruption period. The adverse effects reported in the study were difficulty falling back to sleep (N = 5) and mild gastrointestinal symptoms, including nausea (N = 5). While these side effects were mild and their incidence low in our sample, future studies might further reduce the incidence of adverse reactions by testing and screening for cholinergic sensitivity or use of anti-nausea medication. Future studies might also test whether a higher dose of galantamine (e.g., 10 or 12 mg) would further increase lucid dream frequency without increasing side effects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Altogether the current results show that galantamine substantially increases the frequency of lucid dreams with a minimal side effect profile, suggesting it is well-placed as a method for inducing lucid dreams, and has the potential to make lucid dreaming available to a wider population. While more studies documenting the safety profile of this substance are needed, the potential of making lucid dreaming widely accessible also has implications for scientific research. As one of the challenges for conducting scientific research on lucid dreaming is its relative infrequency, making the state more accessible would increase the efficiency of the collection of larger datasets, which would greatly facilitate research in this field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;section5&quot; class=&quot;section toc-section&quot; readability=&quot;5.2288732394366&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Supporting information&lt;/h2&gt;





&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section toc-section&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Acknowledgments&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We thank Patricia Keelin for assistance in conducting the study, including data collection and administration of the experiment. Finally, we thank all the individuals who participated in the Dreaming and Awakening programs who volunteered their time to participate in the study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;toc-section&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;references&quot;&gt;&lt;li id=&quot;ref1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;1.&lt;/span&gt; LaBerge S. Lucid dreaming: Paradoxes of dreaming consciousness. In: Cardeña E, Lynn SJ, Krippner S, editors. Varieties of anomalous experience: Examining the scientific evidence (2nd ed). Washington, DC: American Psychological Association; 2014. p. 145–73.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;2.&lt;/span&gt; LaBerge S. Lucid dreaming: Metaconsciousness during paradoxical sleep. In: Glucksman MKM, editor. Dream research: Contributions to clinical practice. New York, NY: Routledge; 2015. p. 198–214.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref3&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;3.&lt;/span&gt; LaBerge SP, Nagel LE, Dement WC, Zarcone VP. Lucid dreaming verified by volitional communication during REM sleep. Percept Mot Skills. 1981; 52: 727–32. pmid:24171230
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref4&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;4.&lt;/span&gt; LaBerge S, Rheingold H. Exploring the world of lucid dreaming. New York, NY: Ballantine Books; 1990.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref5&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;5.&lt;/span&gt; LaBerge S. Lucid dreaming: Psychophysiological studies of consciousness during REM sleep. In: Bootzin RR, Kihlstrom JF, Schacter DL, editors. Sleep and Cognition. Washington DC: American Psychological Association; 1990. pp. 109–26.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref6&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;6.&lt;/span&gt; Saunders DT, Roe CA, Smith G, Clegg H. Lucid dreaming incidence: a quality effects meta-analysis of 50years of research. Conscious Cogn. 2016;43:197–215. pmid:27337287
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref7&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;7.&lt;/span&gt; LaBerge S. Lucid dreaming as a learnable skill: A case study. Percept Mot Skills. 1980;51(3):1039–42.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref8&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;8.&lt;/span&gt; LaBerge S, Levitan L. Validity established of DreamLight cues for eliciting lucid dreaming. Dreaming. 1995;5(3):159–168.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref9&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;9.&lt;/span&gt; Price RF, Cohen DB. Lucid dream induction: An empirical evaluation. In: Gackenbach J, LaBerge S, editors. Conscious mind, sleeping brain. New York: Plenum Press; 1988. pp. 105–154.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref10&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;10.&lt;/span&gt; LaBerge S, Levitan L, Rich R, Dement WC. Induction of lucid dreaming by light stimulation during REM sleep. Sleep Research. 1988;17:104.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref11&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;11.&lt;/span&gt; LaBerge S, Owens J, Nagel L, Dement WC. This is a dream: Induction of lucid dreams by verbal suggestion during REM sleep. Sleep Research. 1981;10:150.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref12&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;12.&lt;/span&gt; Stumbrys T, Erlacher D, Schredl M. Testing the involvement of the prefrontal cortex in lucid dreaming: a tDCS study. Conscious Cogn. 2013;22(4):1214–22. pmid:24021850
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref13&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;13.&lt;/span&gt; Voss U, Holzmann R, Hobson A, Paulus W, Koppehele-Gossel J, Klimke A, et al. Induction of self awareness in dreams through frontal low current stimulation of gamma activity. Nat Neurosci. 2014;17(6):810–2. pmid:24816141
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref14&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;14.&lt;/span&gt; LaBerge S. Lucid dreaming: An exploratory study of consciousness during sleep [Doctoral Dissertation]: Stanford University; 1980.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref15&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;15.&lt;/span&gt; Stumbrys T, Erlacher D, Schädlich M, Schredl M. Induction of lucid dreams: A systematic review of evidence. Conscious Cogn. 2012;21(3):1456–75. pmid:22841958
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref16&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;16.&lt;/span&gt; Sparrow GS. Lucid dreaming: Dawning of the clear light. Virginia Beach, VA: ARE Press; 1987.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref17&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;17.&lt;/span&gt; Garfield P. Psychological concomitants of the lucid dream state. Sleep Research. 1975;4:184.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref18&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;18.&lt;/span&gt; LaBerge S, Phillips L, Levitan L. An hour of wakefulness before morning naps makes lucidity more likely. NightLight. 1994;6(3):1–4.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref19&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;19.&lt;/span&gt; Aspy DJ, Delfabbro P, Proeve M, Mohr P. Reality testing and the Mnemonic Induction of Lucid Dreams: Findings from the national Australian lucid dream induction study. Dreaming. 2017;27(3):206–31.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref20&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;20.&lt;/span&gt; LaBerge S, Levitan L, Dement WC. Lucid dreaming: Physiological correlates of consciousness during REM sleep. Journal of Mind and Behavior. 1986;7(2–3);251–58.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref21&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;21.&lt;/span&gt; LaBerge S, Nagel L, Taylor W, Dement W, Zarcone V Jr. Psychophysiological correlates of the initiation of lucid dreaming. Sleep Research. 1981;10:149.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref22&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;22.&lt;/span&gt; Gillin JC, Sitaram N, Janowsky D, Risch C, Huey L, Storch FI. Cholinergic mechanisms in REM sleep. In: Wauquier A, Gaillard JM, Monti JM, Radulovacki M, editors. Sleep: Neurotransmitters and neuromodulators. New York, NY: Raven Press; 1985. pp. 29–42.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref23&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;23.&lt;/span&gt; Velazquez-Moctezuma J, Shalauta M, Gillin JC, Shiromani PJ. Cholinergic antagonists and REM sleep generation. Brain Res. 1991;543(1):175–9. pmid:2054672
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref24&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;24.&lt;/span&gt; Baghdoyan HA. Cholinergic mechanisms regulating REM sleep. In: Schwartz WJ, editor. Sleep Science: Integrating Basic Research and Clinical Practice. Basel: Karger; 1997.pp. 88–116.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref25&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;25.&lt;/span&gt; Riemann D, Gann H, Dressing H, Müller WE, Aldenhoff JB. Influence of the cholinesterase inhibitor galanthamine hydrobromide on normal sleep. Psychiatry Res. 1994;51(3):253–67. pmid:8208872
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref26&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;26.&lt;/span&gt; LaBerge S. The paradox and promise of lucid dreaming: Research update: Cholinergic stimulation of lucid dreaming; voluntary control of auditory perception during REM lucid dreams. 2001; Berkeley, CA: International Association for the Study of Dreams.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref27&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;27.&lt;/span&gt; LaBerge S. To sleep, perchance to read. NightLight. 1996;3(2):17–21.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref28&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;28.&lt;/span&gt; LaBerge S, DeGracia D, Zimbardo P. Prolonging lucid dreams. NightLight. 1995;7(3–4):22–7.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref29&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;29.&lt;/span&gt; Huang F, Fu Y. A review of clinical pharmacokinetics and pharmacodynamics of galantamine, a reversible acetylcholinesterase inhibitor for the treatment of Alzheimer's disease, in healthy subjects and patients. Current clinical pharmacology. 2010;5(2):115–24. pmid:20156150
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref30&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;30.&lt;/span&gt; Bates D, Mächler M, Bolker B, Walker S. Fitting linear mixed-effects models using lme4. arXiv preprint arXiv:14065823. 2014.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref31&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;31.&lt;/span&gt; Allen JJ, Iacono WG, Danielson KD. The identification of concealed memories using the event‐related potential and implicit behavioral measures: A methodology for prediction in the face of individual differences. Psychophysiology. 1992;29(5):504–22. pmid:1410180
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref32&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;32.&lt;/span&gt; Levitan L, LaBerge S, Dole J. Morning naps are better than afternoon naps for lucid dreaming. NightLight. 1992;4(4):9–10.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref33&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;33.&lt;/span&gt; Amatruda TT, Black DA, McKenna TM, McCarley RW, Hobson JA. Sleep cycle control and cholinergic mechanisms: differential effects of carbachol injections at pontine brain stem sites. Brain Res. 1975;98(3):501–15. pmid:1182534
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref34&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;34.&lt;/span&gt; Hernandez-Peon R, Chavez-Ibarra G, Morgane P, Timo-Iaria C. Limbic cholinergic pathways involved in sleep and emotional behavior. Experimental Neurology. 1963;8(2):93–111.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref35&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;35.&lt;/span&gt; Koontz J, Baskys A. Effects of galantamine on working memory and global functioning in patients with mild cognitive impairment: a double-blind placebo-controlled study. American Journal of Alzheimer's Disease &amp;amp; Other Dementias. 2005;20(5):295–302.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref36&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;36.&lt;/span&gt; Yorston G, Gray R. Hypnopompic hallucinations with donepezil. Journal of Psychopharmacology. 2000;14(3):303–4. pmid:11106313
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref37&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;37.&lt;/span&gt; Ross JS, Shua‐Haim JR. Aricept-induced nightmares in alzheimer's disease: 2 case reports. Journal of the American Geriatrics Society. 1998;46(1):119–20. pmid:9434681
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref38&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;38.&lt;/span&gt; Hasselmo ME, Sarter M. Modes and models of forebrain cholinergic neuromodulation of cognition. Neuropsychopharmacology. 2011;36(1):52–73. pmid:20668433
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref39&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;39.&lt;/span&gt; Sarter M, Hasselmo ME, Bruno JP, Givens B. Unraveling the attentional functions of cortical cholinergic inputs: interactions between signal-driven and cognitive modulation of signal detection. Brain Research Reviews. 2005;48(1):98–111. pmid:15708630
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref40&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;40.&lt;/span&gt; Cuadra G, Summers K, Giacobini E. Cholinesterase inhibitor effects on neurotransmitters in rat cortex in vivo. Journal of Pharmacology and Experimental Therapeutics. 1994;270(1):277–84. pmid:7913496
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref41&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;41.&lt;/span&gt; Giacobini E, Zhu X-D, Williams E, Sherman K. The effect of the selective reversible acetylcholinesterase inhibitor E2020 on extracellular acetylcholine and biogenic amine levels in rat cortex. Neuropharmacology. 1996;35(2):205–11. pmid:8734490
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref42&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;42.&lt;/span&gt; Hobson JA. REM sleep and dreaming: towards a theory of protoconsciousness. Nature Reviews Neuroscience. 2009;10(11):803–13. pmid:19794431
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref43&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;43.&lt;/span&gt; Schilström B, Ivanov VB, Wiker C, Svensson TH. Galantamine enhances dopaminergic neurotransmission in vivo via allosteric potentiation of nicotinic acetylcholine receptors. Neuropsychopharmacology. 2007;32(1):43. pmid:16641937
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref44&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;44.&lt;/span&gt; Joensson M, Thomsen KR, Andersen LM, Gross J, Mouridsen K, Sandberg K, et al. Making sense: dopamine activates conscious self‐monitoring through medial prefrontal cortex. Hum Brain Mapp. 2015;36(5):1866–77. pmid:25627861
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref45&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;45.&lt;/span&gt; Levitan L, LaBerge S. Day life, night life: How waking and dreaming experiences relate. NightLight. 1993;6(3):1–5.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref46&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;46.&lt;/span&gt; Voss U, Schermelleh-Engel K, Windt J, Frenzel C, Hobson A. Measuring consciousness in dreams: The lucidity and consciousness in dreams scale. Conscious Cogn. 2013;22(1):8–21. pmid:23220345
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref47&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;47.&lt;/span&gt; Gackenbach J, LaBerge S. Conscious mind, sleeping brain: Perspectives on lucid dreaming. New York: Plenum Press; 1988.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref48&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;48.&lt;/span&gt; Green C. Lucid dreams. London: Hamilton; 1968.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref49&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;49.&lt;/span&gt; DeGracia DJ, LaBerge S. Varieties of lucid dreaming experience. In: Kunzendorf RG, Wallace B, editors. Individual differences in conscious experience. Amsterdam: John Benjamins; 2000. pp. 269–307.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 13:31:24 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>rbanffy</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246</og:url>
<og:title>Pre-sleep treatment with galantamine stimulates lucid dreaming: A double-blind, placebo-controlled, crossover study</og:title>
<og:description>Lucid dreaming is a remarkable state of consciousness in which one is aware of the fact that one is dreaming while continuing to dream. Based on the strong relationship between physiological activation during rapid eye-movement sleep and lucid dreaming, our pilot research investigated whether enhancing cortical activation via acetylcholinesterease inhibition (AChEI) would increase the frequency of lucid dreams and found AChEI to be a promising method for lucid dream induction. In the current study we sought to quantify the size and reliability of the effect of AChEI on lucid dreaming, dream recall and dream content as well as to test the effectiveness of an integrated lucid dream induction protocol which combined cholinergic stimulation with other methods for lucid dream induction. Participants (N = 121) with high dream recall and an interest in lucid dreaming were randomly assigned counterbalanced orders of 3 doses of galantamine (0, 4 and 8 mg). On 3 consecutive nights, they awoke approximately 4.5 hours after lights out, recalled a dream, ingested the capsules and stayed out of bed for at least 30 minutes. Participants then returned to bed and practiced the Mnemonic Induction of Lucid Dreams technique while returning to sleep. The percentage of participants who reported a lucid dream was significantly increased for both 4 mg (27%, odds ratio = 2.29) and 8 mg doses (42%, odds ratio = 4.46) compared to the active placebo procedure (14%). Galantamine also significantly increased dream recall, sensory vividness and complexity (p&lt;0.05). Dream recall, cognitive clarity, control, positive emotion, vividness and self-reflection were increased during lucid compared to non-lucid dreams (p&lt;0.0001). These results show that galantamine increases the frequency of lucid dreams in a dose-related manner. Furthermore, the integrated method of taking galantamine in the last third of the night with at least 30 minutes of sleep interruption and with an appropriately focused mental set is one of the most effective methods for inducing lucid dreams available today.</og:description>
<og:image>http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/figure/image?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246.g003&amp;size=inline</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0201246</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Show HN: git-bug – Distributed bug tracker embedded in git</title>
<link>https://github.com/MichaelMure/git-bug</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/MichaelMure/git-bug</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;Box-body p-6&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;markdown-body entry-content&quot; itemprop=&quot;text&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://travis-ci.org/MichaelMure/git-bug&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/6636985588446b4098a990e96255152c8b967e98/68747470733a2f2f7472617669732d63692e6f72672f4d69636861656c4d7572652f6769742d6275672e7376673f6272616e63683d6d6173746572&quot; alt=&quot;Build Status&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://travis-ci.org/MichaelMure/git-bug.svg?branch=master&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gnu.org/licenses/gpl-3.0&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/e2337d525a3dc6880ffff8cc1c7d7a4792dfbdd3/68747470733a2f2f696d672e736869656c64732e696f2f62616467652f4c6963656e73652d47504c76332b2d626c75652e737667&quot; alt=&quot;License: GPL v3&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/License-GPLv3+-blue.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://godoc.org/github.com/MichaelMure/git-bug&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/8f29e35dbf3149112058f72e261497549e6d8884/68747470733a2f2f676f646f632e6f72672f6769746875622e636f6d2f4d69636861656c4d7572652f6769742d6275673f7374617475732e737667&quot; alt=&quot;GoDoc&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://godoc.org/github.com/MichaelMure/git-bug?status.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://goreportcard.com/report/github.com/MichaelMure/git-bug&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/65388f1f38d0db9f2b8f5d4a7fb7bb61153adeae/68747470733a2f2f676f7265706f7274636172642e636f6d2f62616467652f6769746875622e636f6d2f4d69636861656c4d7572652f6769742d627567&quot; alt=&quot;Go Report Card&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://goreportcard.com/badge/github.com/MichaelMure/git-bug&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Distributed bug tracker embedded in Git&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Would it be nice to not have to rely on a web service somewhere to deal with bugs ?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Would it be nice to be able to browse and edit bug reports offline?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;git-bug&lt;/code&gt; is a distributed bug tracker embedded in &lt;code&gt;git&lt;/code&gt;. It uses git's internal storage so &lt;strong&gt;no files are added in your project&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you would do with commits and branches, you can push your bugs to the same git remote you are already using to collaborate with other people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🚧 This is for now a proof of concept. Expect dragons and unfinished business. 🚧&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Install&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Go get&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
go get github.com/MichaelMure/git-bug
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If it's not done already, add golang binary directory in your PATH:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;export&lt;/span&gt; PATH=&lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;$PATH&lt;/span&gt;:&lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;$GOROOT&lt;/span&gt;/bin:&lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;$GOPATH&lt;/span&gt;/bin
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Pre-compiled binaries&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Go to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/MichaelMure/git-bug/releases/latest&quot;&gt;release page&lt;/a&gt; and download the appropriate binary for your system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copy the binary anywhere in your PATH&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rename the binary to &lt;code&gt;git-bug&lt;/code&gt; (or &lt;code&gt;git-bug.exe&lt;/code&gt; on windows)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;That's all !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;CLI usage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create a new bug:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;git bug new
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your favorite editor will open to write a title and a message.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can push your new entry to a remote:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;git bug push [&amp;lt;remote&amp;gt;]
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And pull for updates:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;git bug pull [&amp;lt;remote&amp;gt;]
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;List existing bugs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;git bug ls
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can now use commands like &lt;code&gt;show&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;comment&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;open&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;close&lt;/code&gt; to display and modify bugs. For more details about each command, you can run &lt;code&gt;git bug &amp;lt;command&amp;gt; --help&lt;/code&gt; or read the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/MichaelMure/git-bug/blob/master/doc/md/git-bug.md&quot;&gt;command's documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Interactive terminal UI&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An interactive terminal UI is available using the command &lt;code&gt;git bug termui&lt;/code&gt; to browse and edit bugs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/6547137e6c84d00045007c195ad0859d334caeef/68747470733a2f2f63646e2e7261776769742e636f6d2f4d69636861656c4d7572652f6769742d6275672f35356162393633312f646f632f7465726d75695f7265636f7264696e672e737667&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/6547137e6c84d00045007c195ad0859d334caeef/68747470733a2f2f63646e2e7261776769742e636f6d2f4d69636861656c4d7572652f6769742d6275672f35356162393633312f646f632f7465726d75695f7265636f7264696e672e737667&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://cdn.rawgit.com/MichaelMure/git-bug/55ab9631/doc/termui_recording.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Web UI (status: WIP)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can launch a rich Web UI with &lt;code&gt;git bug webui&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/MichaelMure/git-bug/blob/master/doc/webui1.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/MichaelMure/git-bug/raw/master/doc/webui1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Web UI screenshot 1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/MichaelMure/git-bug/blob/master/doc/webui2.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/MichaelMure/git-bug/raw/master/doc/webui2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Web UI screenshot 2&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This web UI is entirely packed inside the same go binary and serve static content through a localhost http server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The web UI interact with the backend through a GraphQL API. The schema is available &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/MichaelMure/git-bug/blob/master/graphql/schema.graphql&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Internals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interested by how it works ? Have a look at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/MichaelMure/git-bug/blob/master/doc/model.md&quot;&gt;data model&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Misc&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Planned features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;media embedding&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;import/export of github issue&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;extendable data model to support arbitrary bug tracker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;inflatable raptor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Contribute&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PRs accepted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GPLv3 or later © Michael Muré&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 12:02:43 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>michaelmure</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars3.githubusercontent.com/u/294669?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>MichaelMure/git-bug</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/MichaelMure/git-bug</og:url>
<og:description>git-bug - Distributed bug tracker embedded in Git</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/MichaelMure/git-bug</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>24-core CPU and I can’t type an email</title>
<link>https://randomascii.wordpress.com/2018/08/16/24-core-cpu-and-i-cant-type-an-email-part-one/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://randomascii.wordpress.com/2018/08/16/24-core-cpu-and-i-cant-type-an-email-part-one/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I wasn’t looking for trouble. I wasn’t trying to build Chrome a &lt;a href=&quot;https://randomascii.wordpress.com/2017/07/09/24-core-cpu-and-i-cant-move-my-mouse/&quot;&gt;thousand times in a weekend&lt;/a&gt;, I was just engaging in that most mundane of 21st century tasks, writing an email at 10:30 am. And suddenly gmail hung. I kept typing but for several seconds but no characters were appearing on screen. Then, suddenly gmail caught up and I resumed my &lt;em&gt;very important&lt;/em&gt; email. Then it happened again, only this time gmail went unresponsive for even longer. Well &lt;a href=&quot;https://quoteinvestigator.com/2015/03/02/eureka-funny/&quot;&gt;that’s funny&lt;/a&gt;…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have trouble resisting a good performance mystery but in this case the draw was particularly strong. I work at Google, making Chrome, for Windows, focused on performance. Investigating this hang was actually my &lt;em&gt;job&lt;/em&gt;. And after a lot of false starts and some hard work I figured out how Chrome, gmail, Windows, and our IT department were working together to prevent me from typing an email, and in the process I found a way to save a significant amount of memory for some web pages in Chrome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This investigation had so many rabbit holes that I’m going to save some of the digressions for a follow-on post, but this one will entirely explain the hangs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As usual I had &lt;a href=&quot;https://randomascii.wordpress.com/2015/09/01/xperf-basics-recording-a-trace-the-ultimate-easy-way/&quot;&gt;UIforETW&lt;/a&gt; running in the background, tracing to circular buffers, so I just had to type Ctrl+Win+R and the buffers, representing the last thirty seconds or so of system activity, were saved to disk. I loaded it into &lt;a href=&quot;https://randomascii.wordpress.com/2012/06/19/wpaxperf-trace-analysis-reimagined/&quot;&gt;Windows Performance Analyzer&lt;/a&gt; (WPA), but I couldn’t definitively find the hang.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a Windows program stops pumping messages there will be ETW events emitted to indicate &lt;a href=&quot;https://randomascii.wordpress.com/2012/05/05/xperf-wait-analysisfinding-idle-time/&quot;&gt;exactly where this happened&lt;/a&gt;, so those types of hangs are trivial to find. But apparently Chrome kept on pumping messages. I looked for a time when one of Chrome’s crucial threads either went into a busy loop or went completely idle, but I couldn’t find anything conclusive. There were some spots where Chrome went &lt;em&gt;mostly&lt;/em&gt; idle, but even then all of the key threads kept chugging along, so I couldn’t be sure where the hang was – Chrome might have been going idle because nothing was happening:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://randomascii.files.wordpress.com/2018/08/image.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img title=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;https://randomascii.files.wordpress.com/2018/08/image_thumb.png?w=624&amp;amp;h=182&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; width=&quot;624&quot; height=&quot;182&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://randomascii.files.wordpress.com/2018/08/image1.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img title=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;https://randomascii.files.wordpress.com/2018/08/image_thumb1.png?w=163&amp;amp;h=202&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; width=&quot;163&quot; height=&quot;202&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;UIforETW has a built-in key logger which is often useful when identifying key points in a trace. However, for obvious security reasons it defaults to anonymizing the keystrokes, treating every number typed as a ‘1’ and every letter as an ‘A’. This was making it hard to find the exact moment of the hang so I turned the input tracing from “Private” to “Full” and waited for the hang. At around 10:30 the next morning the hang happened again. I saved the trace buffers, and put these notes into UIforETW’s trace information field:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Was typing “defer to those with more scuba experience” and gmail hung around the end of “those” and then resumed partway through “experience”. gmail tab was PID 27368.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clearly just a normal work-related discussion of &lt;a href=&quot;https://randomascii.wordpress.com/2017/05/01/commute-challenge-2017/&quot;&gt;commute methods&lt;/a&gt;, but the important thing is that now I had a way of locating the hang in the ETW trace. I loaded the trace, looked at the keyboard data in the Generic Events field (the events are emitted by UIforETW itself, each one is a purple diamond in the screen shot below) and suddenly I could see exactly where the hang was, and clearly the dip in CPU usage was 100% correlated:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://randomascii.files.wordpress.com/2018/08/image2.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img title=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;https://randomascii.files.wordpress.com/2018/08/image_thumb2.png?w=635&amp;amp;h=460&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; width=&quot;635&quot; height=&quot;460&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, but why is Chrome stopping? Here’s some foreshadowing: not shown in these screenshots is that &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/desktop/wmisdk/wmi-start-page&quot;&gt;WmiPrvSE.exe&lt;/a&gt; was consuming an entire CPU hyperthread whenever this happened. But that shouldn’t matter. I have a 24-core/48-thread machine so consuming one hyperthread means my machine is still about 98% idle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I then zoomed in to the clearly-significant period where Chrome was idle and looked in particular at CrRendererMain in chrome.exe (27368), the gmail tab process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aside: I just want to say thank you to &lt;a href=&quot;https://randomascii.wordpress.com/2015/10/26/thread-naming-in-windows-time-for-something-better/&quot;&gt;2015 me&lt;/a&gt; for asking Microsoft to improve their thread naming mechanisms, and thank you to Microsoft for doing everything I suggested – thread names in WPA are &lt;em&gt;great&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem suddenly became clearer. During the 2.81 s hang this thread was scheduled and ran 440 separate times. Normally running every 6 ms is enough to make a program responsive, but for some reason it wasn’t making any progress. I noticed that every time it woke up it was on the same stack. Simplified down it was:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;chrome_child.dll (stack base)&lt;br/&gt;KernelBase.dll!VirtualAlloc&lt;br/&gt;ntoskrnl.exe!MiCommitVadCfgBits&lt;br/&gt;ntoskrnl.exe!MiPopulateCfgBitMap&lt;br/&gt;ntoskrnl.exe!ExAcquirePushLockExclusiveEx&lt;br/&gt;ntoskrnl.exe!KeWaitForSingleObject (stack leaf)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chrome is calling VirtualAlloc, which tries to update some “CfgBits” and needs to acquire a lock. At first I assumed that Chrome was calling VirtualAlloc 440 times, which seemed like a weird thing to do, but the reality was perhaps weirder. Chrome called VirtualAlloc once and a lock needed to be acquired. Chrome was signaled when that lock was available but – for 439 times in a row – when Chrome woke up and tried to acquire the lock it was unavailable. The lock had been reacquired by the process that had just released it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is because Windows locks are, by design, &lt;a href=&quot;http://joeduffyblog.com/2006/12/14/anticonvoy-locks-in-windows-server-2003-sp1-and-windows-vista/&quot;&gt;not fair&lt;/a&gt; and if a thread releases a lock and then tries to reacquire it immediately then it can, in cases like this, reacquire it every single time. Starvation. More on this next time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Readying Process – the one that signaled Chrome to go grab the lock – in &lt;em&gt;every&lt;/em&gt; case was WmiPrvSE.exe, releasing the lock on this stack:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ntoskrnl.exe!KiSystemServiceCopyEnd (stack base)&lt;br/&gt;ntoskrnl.exe!NtQueryVirtualMemory&lt;br/&gt;ntoskrnl.exe!MmQueryVirtualMemory&lt;br/&gt;ntoskrnl.exe!MiUnlockAndDereferenceVad&lt;br/&gt;ntoskrnl.exe!ExfTryToWakePushLock (stack leaf)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got distracted by WMI for a while (more on that next time) but eventually I wrote a program to recreate WMI’s behavior. I had CPU sampling data that showed me where WmiPrvSE.exe was spending its time (some edits and simplifications made):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WmiPerfClass.dll!EnumSelectCounterObjects (stack base)&lt;br/&gt;WmiPerfClass.dll!ConvertCounterPath&lt;br/&gt;pdh.dll!PdhiTranslateCounter&lt;br/&gt;pdh.dll!GetSystemPerfData&lt;br/&gt;KernelBase.dll!blah-blah-blah&lt;br/&gt;advapi32.dll!blah-blah-blah&lt;br/&gt;perfproc.dll!blah-blah-blah&lt;br/&gt;perfproc.dll!GetProcessVaData&lt;br/&gt;ntdll.dll!NtQueryVirtualMemory&lt;br/&gt;ntoskrnl.exe!NtQueryVirtualMemory&lt;br/&gt;ntoskrnl.exe!MmQueryVirtualMemory&lt;br/&gt;ntoskrnl.exe!MiQueryAddressSpan&lt;br/&gt;ntoskrnl.exe!MiQueryAddressState&lt;br/&gt;ntoskrnl.exe!MiGetNextPageTable (stack leaf)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It turns out that reproducing the slow scanning from the sampling data was quite easy. The interesting part of the call stack above is &lt;em&gt;NtQueryVirtualMemory&lt;/em&gt;, which is used to scan process memory, and is called by the suggestively named &lt;em&gt;GetProcessVaData&lt;/em&gt;, where &lt;em&gt;Va&lt;/em&gt; probably stands for &lt;em&gt;Virtual Address&lt;/em&gt;. My VirtualScan program just called &lt;em&gt;NtQueryVirtualMemory&lt;/em&gt; in the obvious loop to scan the address space of a specified process, the code worked, it took a really long time to scan the gmail process (10-15 seconds), and it triggered the hang. But why?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The advantage of writing the scanning loop myself was that I could start generating statistics. &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-hardware/drivers/ddi/content/ntifs/nf-ntifs-ntqueryvirtualmemory&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;NtQueryVirtualMemory&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; returns data on each contiguous range of address space that has matching attributes. That might mean all reserved, all committed with particular protection settings, etc. The gmail process had about 26,000 of these blocks but I found another process (&lt;a href=&quot;https://randomascii.wordpress.com/2012/06/19/wpaxperf-trace-analysis-reimagined/&quot;&gt;WPA&lt;/a&gt;, as it turns out) that had 16,000 memory blocks but could be scanned very quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At some point I looked at the gmail process with &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/sysinternals/downloads/vmmap&quot;&gt;vmmap&lt;/a&gt; and noticed that the gmail process had a fair amount of memory (361,836 KiB) and a lot of separate blocks (49,719) coming from a single reservation in the Shareable category – a reservation with a size of 2,147,483,648 KiB, aka 2 TiB. Wot?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://randomascii.files.wordpress.com/2018/08/image4.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img title=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;https://randomascii.files.wordpress.com/2018/08/image_thumb4.png?w=585&amp;amp;h=225&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; width=&quot;585&quot; height=&quot;225&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I happened to know that the 2 TiB reservation is used for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alex-ionescu.com/?p=246&quot;&gt;Control Flow Guard&lt;/a&gt; (CFG), and I remembered that “CFG” showed up on the call stacks where the gmail Chrome process was waiting – &lt;em&gt;MiCommitVadCfgBits&lt;/em&gt; was on the stack. Maybe the large number of blocks in the CFG region were the problem!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Control Flow Guard (CFG) is used to try to stop exploits. Its 2 TiB reservation is a sparse bitmap which indicates which addresses (across 128 TiB of user-mode address space) are valid indirect branch targets. So I modified my virtual memory scanner to count how many blocks were in the CFG region (just look for the 2 TiB reservation) and how many blocks were tagged as executable. Since CFG memory is used to &lt;em&gt;describe&lt;/em&gt; executable memory I expected to see one block of CFG memory for each block of executable memory in the process. Instead I saw 98 blocks of executable memory and &lt;em&gt;24,866&lt;/em&gt; blocks of committed CFG memory. A significant discrepancy:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;     Scan time,  Committed, page tables, committed blocks&lt;br/&gt;Total: 41.763s, 1457.7 MiB,    67.7 MiB,  32112, 98 code blocks&lt;br/&gt;CFG: 41.759s,  353.3 MiB,    59.2 MiB,  24866&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;vmmap shows reservations and commited memory as blocks and my scanning tool only counts committed blocks – that’s why vmmap shows 49,684 blocks where my scanning tool reports 24,866&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In hindsight it is obvious, but what if the CFG bitmap never gets cleaned up? What if memory gets allocated in the CFG bitmap when you allocate executable memory, but it doesn’t get freed when you free the executable memory. That would explain this behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;End-to-end repro&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next step was to write a VAllocStress program that allocates and then frees thousands of blocks of executable memory at random addresses. This executable needs to have CFG enabled and needs to be 64-bit and I hit some road blocks because I didn’t really know what I was trying to do but it worked. After allocating and freeing this many blocks of executable memory this program should sit in a loop where it occasionally try to allocate/free more executable memory, and note when this is slow. Here is my basic algorithm for VAllocStress:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Spin in a loop a lot of times:
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Allocate some executable memory with VirtualAlloc at a random address&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Free the memory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Then, spin in an infinite loop:
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Sleep for 500 ms (don’t want to be a CPU hog)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allocate some executable memory with VirtualAlloc at a fixed location&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Print a message if the VirtualAlloc call takes more than ~500 ms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Free the memory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;That’s it. It’s super simple. And it was so satisfying when it worked. I ran it and then got my VirtualScan program to scan my VAllocStress process. I quickly got confirmation that the CFG block was horribly fragmented, and the scanning took a &lt;em&gt;long&lt;/em&gt; time. And my VAllocStress program hung for the duration of the scan!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point I had simulated the CFG fragmentation, the long scanning times, and the hang. Huzzah!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Root-cause&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It turns out that v8 (Chrome’s JavaScript engine) has CodeRange objects for managing code-gen, and each CodeRange object is constrained to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://cs.chromium.org/chromium/src/v8/src/globals.h?q=kMaximalCodeRangeSize&amp;amp;dr=CSs&amp;amp;l=182&quot;&gt;128 MiB address range&lt;/a&gt;. This should be small enough to avoid the rampant CFG allocation I was seeing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what if you have multiple CodeRange objects, and what if those get allocated at random addresses and then freed? I instrumented the CodeRange constructor, left gmail running, and found the smoking gun. Every couple of minutes another CodeRange object was created (and destroyed). Being in the debugger made it easy to find that WorkerThread::Start was allocating these objects, and suddenly everything makes sense:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;gmail uses &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/web/fundamentals/codelabs/offline/&quot;&gt;service workers&lt;/a&gt;, probably for implementing offline mode&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;These appear and disappear every few minutes because that’s how service workers behave&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Each worker thread gets a temporary CodeRange object which allocates some executable pages for JITted JavaScript code from a random location in the 47-bit process address space&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The 2 TB CFG memory reservation gets some entries every time new code pages are allocated&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The CFG allocations are never freed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NtQueryVirtualMemory is &lt;em&gt;painfully&lt;/em&gt; slow when scanning CFG memory (about 1 ms per block) for reasons that I don’t understand&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;The slow scanning of CFG memory is actually fixed in Windows 10 RS4 (April 2018 Update), which briefly had me wondering if all of this investigation was pointless. But it’s not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Memory&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CFG reservation starts out as just an address reservation – no memory is actually committed. As executable pages are allocated however parts of the CFG reservation are turned into committed memory, using real memory pages. And those pages never get freed. If you keep allocating and freeing randomly located blocks of executable memory then the CFG region will grow arbitrarily large! Well, that’s not quite true. The CFG memory block is best thought of a cache with bounded size. However that is little consolation when the bounded size is &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/BruceDawson0xB/status/1029433717670871040&quot;&gt;2 TiB, per-process&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The worst I’ve seen so far is when my gmail tab had been running for eight days and had accumulated 353.3 MiB of CFG memory, and 59.2 MiB of page-tables to map that memory, for a total waste of about 400 MiB. For some reason most people see either no symptoms or much milder symptoms than I do.&lt;span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Resolution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The v8 (Chrome’s JavaScript engine) team has updated their code so that it &lt;a href=&quot;https://chromium-review.googlesource.com/c/v8/v8/+/1174837&quot;&gt;reuses addresses for CodeRange objects&lt;/a&gt;, which will squish this bug quite nicely. Microsoft already fixed their CFG memory scanning performance problems. Maybe some day Microsoft will free CFG regions when executable memory is freed, at least in the easy cases where large address ranges are freed. And a vmmap bug was reported.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of my coworkers and our customers never noticed this problem. I only noticed it because:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;I had gmail’s offline mode enabled&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I was running on an old version of Windows 10&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Our IT department was running regular WMI scans of our computers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I was paying attention&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I got lucky&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;It seems highly improbably that, as one of the most qualified people to diagnose this bug, I was the first to notice it. If any of the factors above had not been true then I would not have experienced this hang and the associated memory waste might never have been found.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the way, the reason that the hangs kept happening at 10:30 am is just because that’s when our IT team ran their inventory scans. If you want to trigger a scan manually, you can go to Control Panel | Configuration Manager | Actions | Select ‘Hardware Inventory Cycle’ and then Run Now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://randomascii.files.wordpress.com/2018/08/clip_image002.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img title=&quot;clip_image002&quot; src=&quot;https://randomascii.files.wordpress.com/2018/08/clip_image002_thumb.png?w=546&amp;amp;h=331&quot; alt=&quot;clip_image002&quot; width=&quot;546&quot; height=&quot;331&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Source code&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to play along at home you can grab the source-code to VAllocStress and VirtualScan from github, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/randomascii/blogstuff/tree/master/cfg&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Rabbit holes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This investigation included a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of rabbit holes. Some were important (page tables), some were instructive (locks), and some were purely a waste of time (WMI details). I’ll talk more about these, and a vmmap bug, in a follow-up post. If you want more gory details – some of which ended up being wrong or irrelevant – you can follow the whole investigation at &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugs.chromium.org/p/chromium/issues/detail?id=870054&quot;&gt;crbug.com/870054&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hacker news discussion is &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17780127&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reddit discussion is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/programming/comments/97zy08/24core_cpu_and_i_cant_type_an_email_part_one/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wpcnt&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wpa wpmrec&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;wpa-about&quot;&gt;Advertisements&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;jp-post-flair&quot; class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-like-enabled sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;robots-nocontent sd-block sd-social sd-social-icon-text sd-sharing&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Share this:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-block sd-like jetpack-likes-widget-wrapper jetpack-likes-widget-unloaded&quot; id=&quot;like-post-wrapper-18565082-2858-5b7761939ac14&quot; data-src=&quot;//widgets.wp.com/likes/index.html?ver=20180319#blog_id=18565082&amp;amp;post_id=2858&amp;amp;origin=randomascii.wordpress.com&amp;amp;obj_id=18565082-2858-5b7761939ac14&quot; data-name=&quot;like-post-frame-18565082-2858-5b7761939ac14&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Like this:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;likes-widget-placeholder post-likes-widget-placeholder&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;button&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Like&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;loading&quot;&gt;Loading...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 03:39:17 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ghuntley</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>24-core CPU and I can’t type an email (part one)</og:title>
<og:url>https://randomascii.wordpress.com/2018/08/16/24-core-cpu-and-i-cant-type-an-email-part-one/</og:url>
<og:description>I wasn’t looking for trouble. I wasn’t trying to build Chrome a thousand times in a weekend, I was just engaging in that most mundane of 21st century tasks, writing an email at 10:30 am. And sudden…</og:description>
<og:image>https://randomascii.files.wordpress.com/2018/08/clip_image002_thumb.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://randomascii.wordpress.com/2018/08/16/24-core-cpu-and-i-cant-type-an-email-part-one/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Elon Musk Confronts a Fateful Tweet and an ‘Excruciating’ Year</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/08/16/business/elon-musk-interview-tesla.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2018/08/16/business/elon-musk-interview-tesla.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Another possibility under consideration is that SpaceX, Mr. Musk’s rocket company, would help bankroll the Tesla privatization and would take an ownership stake in the carmaker, according to people familiar with the matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Mr. Musk’s tweet kicked off a chain reaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;An hour and 20 minutes after the tweet, with Tesla’s shares up 7 percent, the Nasdaq stock exchange halted trading, and Tesla published a letter to employees from Mr. Musk explaining the rationale for possibly taking the company private. When the shares resumed trading, they continued their climb, ending the day with an 11 percent gain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The next day, investigators in the San Francisco office of the Securities and Exchange Commission asked Tesla for explanations. Ordinarily, such material information about a public company’s plans is laid out in detail after extensive internal preparation and issued through official channels. Board members, blindsided by the chief executive’s market-moving statement, were angry that they had not been briefed, two people familiar with the matter said. They scrambled to cobble together a public statement trying to defuse a mounting uproar over the seemingly haphazard communication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Mr. Musk said in the interview that board members had not complained to him about his tweet. “I don’t recall getting any communications from the board at all,” he said. “I definitely did not get calls from irate directors.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;But shortly after the Times published its interview with Mr. Musk, he added through a Tesla spokeswoman that Antonio Gracias, Tesla’s lead independent director, had indeed contacted him to discuss the Aug. 7 Twitter post, and that he had agreed not to tweet again about the possible privatization deal unless he had discussed it with the board.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;In the interview, Mr. Musk added that he did not regret his Twitter post — “Why would I?” — and said he had no plans to stop using the social media platform. Some board members, however, have recently told Mr. Musk that he should lay off Twitter and focus on making cars and launching rockets, according to people familiar with the matter.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 03:30:28 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>tysone</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/08/16/business/elon-musk-interview-tesla.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Elon Musk Details ‘Excruciating’ Personal Toll of Tesla Turmoil</og:title>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/08/17/business/17MUSK1/17MU-facebookJumbo.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>After setting off a furor that unsettled the markets and his own board, the Tesla chief talks about the pressure he is under and his struggle to cope.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/08/16/business/elon-musk-interview-tesla.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Traveling the World on a Third World Passport</title>
<link>https://www.bucketlistly.blog/posts/how-to-travel-third-world-passport-thai</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bucketlistly.blog/posts/how-to-travel-third-world-passport-thai</guid>
<description>&lt;div itemprop=&quot;text&quot; readability=&quot;281.07475150725&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many things in life that we can choose to be but one thing we can't choose is where we are born. The location of our birth can determine the opportunity we will get, the privilege we will receive, and it can predefine how our lives will play out. I truly believe that traveling the world is a rite of passage every human being in this world should take, but unfortunately, the access to this privilege is predetermined by which country we are born in and the passport we were given.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been traveling the world since 2012 and every time I mentioned to the first-world passport holders, the things I have to go through in order to go to a place like Europe, they were shocked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am a Thai citizen through and through and my Thai passport is ranked &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.passportindex.org/byRank.php&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow external&quot;&gt;54 on the Passport Index&lt;/a&gt; with 39 countries visa-free, 41 visa-on-arrival and 116 countries visa required. In comparison to European passports which ranked 2 - 10 on the Passport Index with over 119 visa-free, 36 visa-on-arrival and only 43 countries visa required, you can see the difference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every time I hear first-world passport holders complain about doing a visa run or having to apply for an electronic visa online, I cringe a little. For us third-world passport holders, we have to go through much worst to get to places they can simply hop on a plane and be there in no time. How much worst? Well, let me explain the things we have to go through just to get to Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What is it like?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;lightbox-full&quot; href=&quot;https://du1frgvkr39c.cloudfront.net/sites/5adf778b6eabcc00190b75b1/content_entry5b155bed5711a8176e9f9783/5b1650f2d584e80016b7efde/files/166738817516-original-image.jpg?1529633552&quot; rel=&quot;post&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://du1frgvkr39c.cloudfront.net/sites/5adf778b6eabcc00190b75b1/content_entry5b155bed5711a8176e9f9783/5b1650f2d584e80016b7efde/files/166738817516-original-image.jpg?1529633552&quot; data-srcset=&quot;https://du1frgvkr39c.cloudfront.net/sites/5adf778b6eabcc00190b75b1/content_entry5b155bed5711a8176e9f9783/5b1650f2d584e80016b7efde/files/166738817516-original-image.jpg?1529633552 500w, https://du1frgvkr39c.cloudfront.net/sites/5adf778b6eabcc00190b75b1/content_entry5b155bed5711a8176e9f9783/5b1650f2d584e80016b7efde/files/166738817516-original-image.jpg?1529633552 1200w&quot; data-original=&quot;https://du1frgvkr39c.cloudfront.net/sites/5adf778b6eabcc00190b75b1/content_entry5b155bed5711a8176e9f9783/5b1650f2d584e80016b7efde/files/166738817516-original-image.jpg?1529633552&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 1200px&quot; width=&quot;1200&quot; class=&quot;lazy&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Europe does not make it easy for us to travel to their continent, in contrary to them coming to us. The entire process takes at least 2 weeks to a month from us calling to book for a time slot which can be fully booked up to 2 weeks, to us picking the passport up which can be 3 days to a month from the day we apply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Planning a Trip&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Planning for a trip for people with a first world passport can simply be just buying a plane ticket and show up on time, but for us, it requires extensive planning weeks in advance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Europe, first we would have to find the embassy to apply, read up their document requirements and followed the list to a tee. Documents involved are usually a valid return flight ticket, all the accommodation booking details for the entire stay, an itinerary of the entire trip, a 3 months bank statement with cash movement (to prove that it is your money), a letter from work proving that you have something to return to, non-refundable fee from 50 - 200 USD and many more. If anything is missing from the documents, we would get rejected outright and we would have to make an appointment again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see, going somewhere with a third world passport requires extensive research and careful planning that hinder us from exploring the world as freely as other types of passport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Traveling on a Whim&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People often wonder why we, third-world passport holders, don't travel on a whim. The answer is simple, we can't. Our passport just doesn't allow the type of backpacking trip that goes on for months and months around the world without a return ticket. Even with countries that are visa-free to us, we sometimes get rejected if we do not have a return or onward ticket.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depending on the countries we are going, we are also forced to be bound to our home country because some visa applications require us to be in our home country to be able to apply. For example, I can not go traveling in Turkey for a few months and apply for a European visa in Istanbul to continue my journey to Europe. I have to come back to Thailand to get the visa and fly back to Europe which doubled the cost for us, and since we are not from a very rich country, we can only afford to do this so many time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;What do we get?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For most first-world passport holders, when you get a visa or exempted from one, you are often given a maximum fixed period of time you can stay in a country, say 90 days in Europe, or Thailand together with multi-entries. For us, on the other hand, is not as simple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a third-world passport, often times, the duration we get is considerably less than our first-world counterpart. Europe is the worst at this because they will only give us the duration and the entry that is shown on our submitted itinerary. If we apply for a Schengen visa with a 10 days itinerary involving countries in the Schengen zone, instead of getting the 90 days maximum period like other passport holders, they would only give us 11 days single entry visa, which leave us no room for flexibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine if we want to backpack through Europe for 3 months, we would have to book 90 days of accommodation, printed them all out and submitted to the embassy every time. Even with that, we wouldn't be able to go out of the Schengen zone, say for a small spontaneous trip to Croatia and get back into the Schengen area, because that will be considered multi-entry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see, it is not all flowers and sunshine even after we got the visa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;How I Travel the World With a Third World Passport&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;lightbox-full&quot; href=&quot;https://du1frgvkr39c.cloudfront.net/sites/5adf778b6eabcc00190b75b1/assets/5b39e90f58d39907e58893d4/how-to-travel-third-world-passport-thai-image-2.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;post&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://du1frgvkr39c.cloudfront.net/sites/5adf778b6eabcc00190b75b1/assets/5b39e91258d39907e58893d5/how-to-travel-third-world-passport-thai-image-2-placeholder.jpg&quot; data-size=&quot;1280x859&quot; data-srcset=&quot;https://du1frgvkr39c.cloudfront.net/sites/5adf778b6eabcc00190b75b1/assets/5b39e91458d39907e58893d6/how-to-travel-third-world-passport-thai-image-2-500.jpg 500w, https://du1frgvkr39c.cloudfront.net/sites/5adf778b6eabcc00190b75b1/assets/5b39e90f58d39907e58893d4/how-to-travel-third-world-passport-thai-image-2.jpg 1200w&quot; data-original=&quot;https://du1frgvkr39c.cloudfront.net/sites/5adf778b6eabcc00190b75b1/assets/5b39e90f58d39907e58893d4/how-to-travel-third-world-passport-thai-image-2.jpg&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 1200px&quot; width=&quot;1200&quot; class=&quot;lazy&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though that sounds grim, I can confidently say that it is not impossible for us to travel the world like a first-world passport holder if we know our way around our passport weaknesses. There are many world travelers out there with a third world passport (&lt;a href=&quot;https://iamaileen.com/how-to-travel-the-world-third-world-passport/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Aileen from IAmAileen.com&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lovedandwanderlust.com/third-world-passport/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Melai from LovedandWanderlust.com&lt;/a&gt;) that are constantly pushing the limit of what is possible for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Research and Preparation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It all comes down to doing your homework before a trip. First I would see which countries have my passport exempted and I would try to stick to that area first and if I came across a country that requires me to get a visa prior to the trip, then I would go into their website and look at the visa application requirement one by one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key is to do enough research that you have an itinerary you can base your trip on. You don't have to follow the itinerary to a tee but it is good to know which country you can go and cannot go without a visa in order to prevent disappointment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, when I first planned my trip to the middle east, I wanted to go to Egypt, Jordan, and Turkey for 3 months. I found out early on that I would need a visa for Egypt prior to traveling and none needed for the other 2 so I went and got my Egypt visa beforehand. I was also looking at neighboring countries like Georgia and Armenia in case I have spare time which I did and I was prepared for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see, you can travel the world with a third world passport with the flexibility like a first world passport if you do enough research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Paperwork for Visa&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;lightbox-full&quot; href=&quot;https://du1frgvkr39c.cloudfront.net/sites/5adf778b6eabcc00190b75b1/assets/5b39e91758d39907e58893d7/how-to-travel-third-world-passport-thai-image-3.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;post&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://du1frgvkr39c.cloudfront.net/sites/5adf778b6eabcc00190b75b1/assets/5b39e91d58d39907e58893d8/how-to-travel-third-world-passport-thai-image-3-placeholder.jpg&quot; data-size=&quot;1280x853&quot; data-srcset=&quot;https://du1frgvkr39c.cloudfront.net/sites/5adf778b6eabcc00190b75b1/assets/5b39e91f58d39907e58893d9/how-to-travel-third-world-passport-thai-image-3-500.jpg 500w, https://du1frgvkr39c.cloudfront.net/sites/5adf778b6eabcc00190b75b1/assets/5b39e91758d39907e58893d7/how-to-travel-third-world-passport-thai-image-3.jpg 1200w&quot; data-original=&quot;https://du1frgvkr39c.cloudfront.net/sites/5adf778b6eabcc00190b75b1/assets/5b39e91758d39907e58893d7/how-to-travel-third-world-passport-thai-image-3.jpg&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 1200px&quot; width=&quot;1200&quot; class=&quot;lazy&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After you have done your homework, it's time to do the boring part, the paperwork. The key here is to prove to the embassy that you have the mean to come back to your home country. They put this rule in the first place to prevent us from going to their countries and work illegally and we will have to prove that that is not the case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More often than not, the embassy will require you to provide several documents about your itineraries such as flights, accommodation, and day-to-day itinerary. Here is a list of things you are often asked to prepare:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Filled-in Application Form&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A Copy of Passport&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 x photos with specific requirements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A confirmed return flight ticket&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Proof of booked accommodation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Travel Health Insurance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A day-to-day itinerary&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 months bank statement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Proof of employment or a letter explaning what you do and how you earn money&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;application form&lt;/strong&gt; is often found on the embassy website where you can fill in online, print it out and attach with a copy of your passport, 2 photos and all the other documents listed above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I often &lt;strong&gt;book a flight&lt;/strong&gt; in advanced that would give me enough time for the visa process (a month prior) and often time I'd buy at full price so that I could get a full refund if need be. Be sure to look at the airline's refund policy so that you can choose the right type of ticket.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a &lt;strong&gt;day-to-day itinerary&lt;/strong&gt;, I would often come up with a plan that I would stick to loosely and write them in the format shown below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Arrival Date] – [Departure Date]: Travel to [City], [Country] via [Bus or Train or Airline] and [a brief activity]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is an example of the itinerary I wrote for my Europe trip:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jan 22, 2018: Flight from Bangkok to Warsaw, Poland via Qatar Airline&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jan 22, 2018 – Feb 12, 2018: Warsaw, Poland and travel around the city..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the &lt;strong&gt;accommodation&lt;/strong&gt;, I often go on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.booking.com/index.html?aid=905356&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Booking.com&lt;/a&gt; to book the accommodation for the entire time I planned to be traveling based on the day-to-day itinerary I came up with, printed the email confirmation, and make sure that the date on the booking confirmation emails add up to the exact amount of time I want to be there for. Booking.com is great for this because they allow you to cancel the booking for free if need be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the &lt;strong&gt;travel insurance&lt;/strong&gt;, I often buy mine from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.worldnomads.com/Turnstile/AffiliateLink?partnerCode=blbe9200&amp;amp;utm_source=blbe9200&amp;amp;source=link&amp;amp;utm_content=link&amp;amp;path=https://www.worldnomads.com/travel-insurance/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;World Nomads&lt;/a&gt; which has all the tools I need to get the right travel insurance for the right country I am going to and covers the entire time I would be there for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the &lt;strong&gt;proof of employment&lt;/strong&gt;, you can ask your employer to provide an employment letter with your job title, the date you started and a signature of an authorized personnel in your company. If you are like me who do not have an employer, you will have to write your own letter explaining in detail what you do, who is your client, and how much money you are making per month. If you have any business website to show, capture a screenshot and print them out too. The good thing is once you have written one freelance letter for an application, you can reuse that forever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last but not least, the &lt;strong&gt;bank statement&lt;/strong&gt;. This is by far one of the most important documents you will have to carefully prepare. One of the criteria they used to approve or reject people is the amount of money you have. You must have enough money in your bank account to cover the entire trip and the bank statement will have to show an active bank account with money coming in and out regularly in the last 3 months which is to prevent people from asking others to temporary transfer the money to the account just for the visa process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From my experience, if you have around 2,000 USD in your account for a 3 months trip in Europe, that should be enough to prove that you can cover all the cost but the value varies considerably depending on your duration, the embassy you are applying to and how expensive that country is, so prepare accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Apply Process&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;lightbox-full&quot; href=&quot;https://du1frgvkr39c.cloudfront.net/sites/5adf778b6eabcc00190b75b1/assets/5b39e92058d39907e58893da/how-to-travel-third-world-passport-thai-image-4.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;post&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://du1frgvkr39c.cloudfront.net/sites/5adf778b6eabcc00190b75b1/assets/5b39e92358d39907e58893db/how-to-travel-third-world-passport-thai-image-4-placeholder.jpg&quot; data-size=&quot;1280x853&quot; data-srcset=&quot;https://du1frgvkr39c.cloudfront.net/sites/5adf778b6eabcc00190b75b1/assets/5b39e92558d39907e58893dc/how-to-travel-third-world-passport-thai-image-4-500.jpg 500w, https://du1frgvkr39c.cloudfront.net/sites/5adf778b6eabcc00190b75b1/assets/5b39e92058d39907e58893da/how-to-travel-third-world-passport-thai-image-4.jpg 1200w&quot; data-original=&quot;https://du1frgvkr39c.cloudfront.net/sites/5adf778b6eabcc00190b75b1/assets/5b39e92058d39907e58893da/how-to-travel-third-world-passport-thai-image-4.jpg&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 1200px&quot; width=&quot;1200&quot; class=&quot;lazy&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The process of applying for a visa varies depending on the embassy but for the most part, you will have to make an appointment with the embassy in your home country, prepare all your documents according to their requirements on their website, and organized them in the order they recommended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If there is no embassy in your home country, then you can apply it in any country that has it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once all the documents are ready, you will have to go to the embassy at the time slot you were assigned to and give them all your documents. They may ask you a few questions about your trip, so answer them truthfully and the process should go smoothly. They will usually tell you when you will get the result so all you have to do now is wait until they call you and they will tell you when you can come and pick up the result. You won't know the result until you pick it up so don't bother asking the person who called you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Getting Rejected&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting rejected is a common occurrence for us. I was lucky enough to only got rejected once, but many people often do and all we can do is observe what went wrong and try again. There are many factors that could affect the outcome of a visa process and more often than not, it boils down to either we did not give enough proof of our return or the bank statement did not pass their requirements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key is to never give up and keep trying. You just need to know what the embassy is looking for in your application and try to prepare enough documents to reinforce it. When it comes to applying for a visa, &lt;strong&gt;it is always better to be over prepared than under prepared&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope this guide helps shed light on how lucky it is to be a first-world passport holder, the situation us, third-world passport holders have to deal with and how we can overcome the limits of our passport and travel the world freely. If you have any question, please do not hesitate to ask me in the comments below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Looking for more inspirational articles? Check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bucketlistly.blog/inspiration&quot;&gt;The Solo Traveler’s Inspiration&lt;/a&gt; section where we will discuss topics related to the nomadic and traveling lifestyle and shower-thoughts that will invoke wanderlust in all of us.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bucketlistly.blog/resources&quot;&gt;The Solo Traveler’s Resources&lt;/a&gt; is a series of posts by Bucketlistly where we will explore the ways of life of nomads including how we work, travel, and what we carry in our backpack.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 20:16:55 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>cirrus-clouds</dc:creator>
<og:title>Traveling the World on a Third World Passport - What is it like and how to overcome it</og:title>
<og:description>There are many things in life that we can choose to be but one thing we can't choose is where we are born. The location of our birth can determine the opportunity we will get, the privilege we will receive, and it can predefine how our lives will play out....</og:description>
<og:image>https://du1frgvkr39c.cloudfront.net/sites/5adf778b6eabcc00190b75b1/content_entry5adf77af6eabcc00190b75b6/5b39e92c58d39907e58893de/files/how-to-travel-third-world-passport-thai-main-image-op.jpg?1533014686</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.bucketlistly.blog/posts/how-to-travel-third-world-passport-thai</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bucketlistly.blog/posts/how-to-travel-third-world-passport-thai</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>How to Hire</title>
<link>https://hbr.org/2018/01/how-to-hire</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://hbr.org/2018/01/how-to-hire</guid>
<description>&lt;h4 class=&quot;ideainbrief-title&quot;&gt;In Brief&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ideainbrief-contents&quot; readability=&quot;39&quot;&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;The Problem&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most companies approach hiring with faulty assumptions and poor practices. They believe talent is fixed rather than contextual. They fail to create real partnerships between recruiters and hiring managers. And they rely too much on salary surveys and rigid compensation formulas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;The Solution&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dig beneath the résumé. Ensure that recruiters deeply understand the business and are not viewed as support staff. Don’t obsess over “culture fit”; assess whether candidates can drive growth and address pressing challenges. Calculate the real value they can bring to the company and the comp package required to get them to sign on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really dislike the term “A player.” It implies a grading system that can determine who will be best for a position. HR people always ask how Netflix, where I served as chief talent officer from 1998 to 2012, managed to hire only A players. I say, “There’s an island populated exclusively by A players, but only some of us know where it is.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In truth, one company’s A player may be a B player for another firm. There is no formula for what makes people successful. Many of the people we let go from Netflix because they were not excelling at what we were doing went on to excel in other jobs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finding the right people is also not a matter of “culture fit.” What most people really mean when they say someone is a good fit culturally is that he or she is someone they’d like to have a beer with. But people with all sorts of personalities can be great at the job you need done. This misguided hiring strategy can also contribute to a company’s lack of diversity, since very often the people we enjoy hanging out with have backgrounds much like our own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making great hires is about recognizing great matches—and often they’re not what you’d expect. Take Anthony Park. On paper he wasn’t a slam dunk for a Silicon Valley company. He was working at an Arizona bank, where he was a “programmer,” not a “software developer.” And he was a pretty buttoned up guy. We called Anthony because in his spare time he’d created a Netflix-enhancing app, which he had posted on his website. He came in for a day of interviews, and everyone loved him. When he got to me, late in the day, I told him he would be getting an offer. He seemed overwhelmed, so I asked if he was all right. He said, “You’re going to pay me a lot of money to do what I love!” I did wonder how he’d fit in with the high-powered team he was joining; I hoped it wouldn’t burn him out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few months later I sat in on a meeting of his team. Everyone was arguing until Anthony suddenly said, “Can I speak now?” The room went silent, because Anthony didn’t say much, but when he did speak, it was something really smart—something that would make us all wonder, &lt;em&gt;Damn it, why didn’t I think of that?&lt;/em&gt; Now Anthony is a vice president. He’s proof that organizations can adapt to many people’s styles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article I’ll describe what I’ve learned about making great hires during my 14 years at Netflix and in subsequent consulting on culture and leadership. The process requires probing beneath the surface of people and their résumés; engaging managers in every aspect of hiring; treating your in-house recruiters as true business partners; adopting a mindset in which you’re always recruiting; and coming up with compensation that suits the performance you need and the future you aspire to. My observations may be especially relevant to fast-growing tech-based firms, whose rapid innovation means a continual need for new talent. But organizations of all types can benefit from taking a fresh look at their hiring and compensation practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Probe Beneath the Surface&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Netflix we had to be creative about where we searched for talent, because we often needed people with rarefied technical skills. When we began looking for big data experts, for example, no one even really knew what “big” meant. We couldn’t just search résumés and do keyword matching. We had to think about all the different kinds of companies—many were insurance or credit card companies—that handled masses of data. What’s more, our recruiting team lacked the in-depth knowledge to assess people’s technical skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our best recruiter of technical people was Bethany Brodsky. She knew virtually nothing about technology before coming to Netflix, but she was great at understanding our business and the root problems we had to solve. She also understood that a candidate’s approach to problem solving was more important than previous experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of Bethany’s best interviews was with someone working at Lawrence Livermore—a government research center focused on nuclear science. This was when Netflix was beginning to stream on Xbox, Roku, and TiVo. When interviewing candidates, Bethany would tell them we had signed up a million subscribers in just 30 days on one of those devices and ask which one they thought it was. TiVo was taking off then, so most people said, “TiVo, for sure.” But this candidate asked whether any conditions were attached to getting a Netflix subscription on any of the devices. She told him that Xbox subscribers needed a gold membership. He reasoned that it must be Xbox, because its users were already willing to pay a premium. He was right, and she knew he was our guy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;article-callout&quot; readability=&quot;31&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;callout-contents&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;callout&quot;&gt;Making great hires is about recognizing great matches.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had a similar “aha” moment when I interviewed Christian Kaiser, who was managing a group of 25 programmers at AOL. I had tried to hire quite a few people from his group, because they were doing the kind of technical work we needed. But they all wanted to stay at AOL. Netflix was a much sexier place to work, so I was perplexed. When I asked them about it, they would say, “I have the most amazing boss! He’s the best communicator I’ve ever known. I can’t bear the thought of leaving him.” I told my recruiters, “Go get that guy.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Christian wasn’t what I’d expected. He had a thick German accent, and he stuttered. This was the great communicator? On top of that, he was clearly nervous. Our conversation was painful for him and for me. But when I asked him to explain, in simple terms, the technical work he was doing, he was transformed. He still stuttered, but he gave me a riveting explanation, and I realized, &lt;em&gt;That’s it! He’s great at making really complicated things understandable.&lt;/em&gt; We hired him, and he’s been an amazing team builder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We always tried to be creative about probing people and their résumés. Bethany once decided to analyze the résumés of our best data-science people for common features. She found that those people shared an avid interest in music. From then on she and her team looked for that quality. She recalls, “We’d get really excited and call out, ‘Hey, I found a guy who plays piano!’” She concluded that such people can easily toggle between their left and right brains—a great skill for data analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Engage Managers Fully&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many companies rely on outside recruiters. Netflix was growing so quickly that we opted for a different strategy: We formed an internal team of experienced recruiters. The sad truth is that most companies treat recruitment as a separate, nonbusiness, even non-HR function, and many young companies outsource it. Building a talented team of internal recruiters was a substantial investment, but I could make an irrefutable business case for doing so: I could clearly show what the return would be from eliminating headhunter fees. We saved bundles of money over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The technical nature of our business meant that managers needed to be highly engaged in the hiring process. But that should be required at all companies. Every hiring manager should understand the company’s approach to hiring and how to execute on it, down to the smallest detail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;article-callout&quot; readability=&quot;31&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;callout-contents&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;callout&quot;&gt;Your HR chief should understand the details of your business.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our recruiters’ job involved coaching our hiring managers. The recruiters created a slide deck to use with each manager, one-on-one. They would ask, “What does your interview process look like? What does your interview team look like? What is your process for having candidates come in?” People don’t have to approach interviewing or recruiting in the same way, but we insisted that they have a plan and not just improvise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end, the manager would make the hiring decision. Team members provided input, and my team and I also weighed in. But the ultimate responsibility was the manager’s, as was the performance of the team he or she was building.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All this should be modeled from the top. Bethany once worked with our CEO, Reed Hastings, to fill a director-level position. They met on a Thursday morning to discuss what type of candidate they needed. Friday afternoon Reed e-mailed her to say he had sent messages to 20 prospects he’d found on LinkedIn and had gotten three responses. He’d interviewed one via Skype, really liked him, and wanted him to come in on Monday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When hiring managers are as engaged as Reed was, recruiters up their game even more. After getting Reed’s e-mail, Bethany was determined to find someone even better. (We ended up hiring Reed’s guy, and Reed gloated about it for years.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Treat Recruiters as Business Partners&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the approach I’m describing to work, recruiters must be considered vital contributors to building the business. They need to deeply understand the needs of the business, and hiring managers need to treat them as business partners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting the two groups to work together optimally may require holding hiring managers’ feet to the fire. One day I heard one of my best recruiters complain about a new executive: “He doesn’t return my calls or e-mails. I send him résumés, but he doesn’t respond. I’m frustrated, because we really need to build him a great team.” I walked up to her and said, “I think you need to work with someone else. I’ll take care of this.” Then I sent him an e-mail saying I had reassigned his recruiter: “I’ve put her on another project, because you appear to have a methodology for hiring and don’t seem to need her help. Let us know when we can step in and assist. Love, Patty.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within minutes he was at my desk, fuming. “What the hell?” he demanded. I asked him, “Is it true that she set up two meetings with you and you canceled?” He snapped, “I’m a busy guy. I’m doing the work of 10 people.” I asked, “Is it true that she sent you a number of qualified candidates and you didn’t respond? It’s your job to build the team, not hers. By the way, there are three people who are delighted that she’s not spending time on you. She’s a great partner; she could really make this work for you. But if you don’t need her, that’s cool.” Realizing that he did need the recruiter to help grow his team, he changed his tune and began treating her with respect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It infuriates me when hiring managers dismiss the value of good HR people. Usually when I asked managers why they weren’t engaging more with recruiters, they’d say, “Well, they’re not that smart, and they don’t really understand what’s going on in my business or how the technology works.” My response would be “Then start expecting—and demanding—that they do!” If you hire smart people; insist that they be businesspeople; and include them in running the business, they’ll act like businesspeople.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On occasion I even advise companies to hire a businessperson, not an HR specialist, to run HR. Just like any other department or division head, your HR chief should understand the details of your business, how you earn your revenue, who your customers are, and your strategy for the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Always Be Recruiting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Netflix we had a saying: “Always be recruiting!” Candidates came from everywhere—from professional conferences, from the sidelines of a kids’ soccer game, from conversations on airplanes. But certain fundamentals were strictly enforced. The interview and hiring process gives a powerful first impression about how your company operates, for good or bad. So I had an ironclad rule that if people saw a stranger sitting alone at headquarters waiting for an interview, they should stop and say, “Hi, I’m ____. Are you here for an interview? Let’s look at your schedule, and I’ll help you find the next person.” If I was late coming to meet with a candidate and said, “Sorry—I hope someone talked to you,” he or she would say, “Six people talked to me.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recruiting was so important that interviews trumped any meeting a hiring manager was scheduled for, and they were the only reason people could miss our executive staff meetings. Candidates are evaluating you, just as you’re evaluating them. People forget that. Our goal was to have every person who came for an interview walk away wanting the job. Even if we hated candidates, we wanted them to think, &lt;em&gt;Wow, that was an incredible experience. It was efficient, it was effective, it was on time, the questions were relevant, everyone was smart, and I was treated with dignity.&lt;/em&gt; I would tell people, “Even if this person isn’t the right fit, we might love his next-door neighbor.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We acted as quickly as possible once the decision was made: no running the hire by two levels of management, the compensation department, and HR. My team worked directly with hiring managers to determine compensation, title, and other details. Recruiters laid the groundwork; managers made the offers. Speed and efficiency often meant we could land candidates who were interviewing with other great companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Set Compensation That Makes Sense For You&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Competitive salaries are obviously needed to lure top talent. Every business would like to mark its salaries to the market, but that can be challenging. There are amazingly sophisticated resources to tap for salary information; industry surveys cover every domain and give elaborate breakdowns by level. But jobs are not widgets, and neither are people. Roles are specialized in ways that survey descriptions cannot account for, and a candidate may have skills, such as good judgment and collaborative prowess, that can’t be measured by surveys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Say you need a software engineer. Do you want a senior programmer fluent in the best new techniques in search engine development? And this person will be managing a staff of five? Oh, and this person also needs to understand online advertising systems well enough to work with marketing on an online advertising strategy? A survey is not going to tell you how much such a person is paid currently—or should be paid &lt;em&gt;by you.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compensation departments spend gobs of time comparing descriptions and adjusting for other factors. However, that process gives you only a baseline understanding of the market landscape. How many people with those qualifications are available? To get the person you want, you often need to throw your calculations away and respond to actual market demand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But market demand may not in itself be an adequate guide, because it reflects the present moment, and hiring should be about the future. The prevailing compensation system is often behind the times; it’s based on the historical value of what employees have produced rather than on their potential to add value in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine that your recruiter manages to find a software engineer with all the credentials you need, and your team loves her, but she has an offer from your main competitor that’s $35,000 more than what you were prepared to pay. In determining what to offer, consider the difference it might make to the future of your business if you bring her in rather than settle for your second choice—who may be a distant second, and whom it will take three months to hire because you’ll keep looking for someone with the skills and talent of your first choice. How much added revenue might that great first choice produce? Might she ensure that you beat your competitor on the launch of a fabulous new search system—especially if she gets started now rather than three months down the road? How much ad revenue might she bring in by improving your targeting? What about the value of her management experience—might a key member of her team who gets an offer from another firm decide to stay because she’s a great leader? And what about the value to you of her not working for your competitor, particularly if your domain is undergoing rapid innovation?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Current market demand and salary surveys can’t help you calculate these future gains. I’m not saying there’s &lt;em&gt;no&lt;/em&gt; value to benchmarking, but I advise forgoing elaborate calculations based on what other companies are paying right now; that’s comparing apples and oranges. It’s better to focus on what you can afford to pay for the performance you want and the future you’re heading toward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;article-callout&quot; readability=&quot;31&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;callout-contents&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;callout&quot;&gt;A candidate may have skills that can’t be measured by salary surveys.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve made an offer and hired someone, you need to keep assessing compensation. I learned this during a period when Netflix was losing people because of exorbitant offers from our competitors. One day I heard that Google had offered one of our folks almost twice his current pay, and I hit the roof. He was a really important guy, so his manager wanted to counter. I got into a heated e-mail exchange with his manager and a couple of VPs. I wrote, “Google shouldn’t decide the salaries for everybody just because they have more money than God!” We bickered for days. They kept telling me, “You don’t understand how good he is!” I was having none of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I woke up one morning and thought, &lt;em&gt;Oh, of course! No wonder Google wants him. They’re right!&lt;/em&gt; He had been working on some incredibly valuable personalization technology, and very few people in the world had his expertise. I realized that his work with us had given him a whole new market value. I fired off another e-mail: “I was wrong, and by the way, I went through the P&amp;amp;L, and we can double the salaries of everybody on this team.” That experience changed how we thought about compensation. We realized that for some jobs we were creating expertise and scarcity, and rigidly adhering to internal salary ranges could harm our best contributors, who could make more elsewhere. We decided we didn’t want a system in which people had to leave to be paid what they were worth. We also encouraged our employees to interview elsewhere regularly. That was the most reliable and efficient way to learn how competitive our pay was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People often tell me, “We can’t pay top dollar. That was great for Netflix, because the company was booming. But we’re not growing that way, and we don’t have the margin.” Fair enough. Maybe it’s not possible to pay top of market for every position. In that case I suggest identifying the positions with the greatest potential to boost your performance and paying top dollar to fill them with the very best people you can get. Think about it this way: What if by paying top of market you could bring in one supremely talented person who could do the job of two people or add even more value than that? Consider the 80/20 rule about sales teams: that 20% of your salespeople will generate 80% of your revenue. It may apply to other employees. I’ve seen a similar effect on team after team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another objection I often hear to hiring star performers at top pay is that their salaries will be much higher than those of their teammates. Managers at Netflix used to complain about that. Say we wanted to bring in someone whose salary would be twice that of everybody else on the team. Department heads would sometimes ask, “Does that mean I’m paying people half of what they’re worth?” I’d say, “Well, is this new person going to be able to move us faster, maybe even twice as fast? And when we hire him, who on your team could take his place at his former company?” The answers were usually “Yeah, we’ll be able to move much faster” and “None of them could replace him, because they don’t have his experience.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This focus on the value-add of an individual star is especially important when a company is scaling up. I recently got a call from a CEO whose company employs 150 people. He said it would be growing to 300 and asked my advice on getting there. I said, “That’s a precise number of people. What’s it based on?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He said his company would need to do twice as much work. I asked would the new people be doing the same kinds of work as the current staff, or would there be new things? Would the company be launching a product line? And if teams were getting bigger, might he need more-experienced managers? Did twice as much work mean reaching twice as many customers? If so, he would have to ramp up customer service. But that might not mean hiring twice as many reps; maybe outsourcing would be better. Then I asked the question I’ve found to be the most thought-provoking in these consultations: “Instead of 150 new people, are you sure you don’t want 75 people whom you pay twice as much because they have twice as much experience and can be higher performers?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve found that if you focus intently on hiring the best people you can find and pay them top dollar, chances are your business growth will more than make up for what you spend on compensation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;mvm description-text hbrgray, line-height-tight&quot; readability=&quot;25.428571428571&quot;&gt;A version of this article appeared in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://hbr.org/archive-toc/BR1801&quot;&gt;January–February 2018&lt;/a&gt; issue (pp.90–97) of &lt;em&gt;Harvard Business Review&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 19:26:12 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>devy</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:image>https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2017/12/R1801F_AFONSO.jpg</og:image>
<og:url>https://hbr.org/2018/01/how-to-hire</og:url>
<og:description>And other things you’re doing wrong, according to Patty McCord.</og:description>
<og:title>Stop Hiring for Culture Fit</og:title>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://hbr.org/2018/01/how-to-hire</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Hacker News Habit</title>
<link>https://hackernewslater.com/posts/the-hacker-news-habit/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://hackernewslater.com/posts/the-hacker-news-habit/</guid>
<description>&lt;header class=&quot;mt4 w-100&quot;&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;f6 b helvetica tracked&quot;&gt;POSTS&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;time class=&quot;f6 mv4 dib tracked&quot; datetime=&quot;2018-08-13T23:25:01-07:00&quot;&gt;August 13, 2018&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/header&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have an addiction.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;More accurately it’s a pesky bad habit I uncovered during a period of self-examination while on sabbatical – I love, excessively, the consumption of bite-sized posts, which I justify reading as it relates to my profession; I rationalize the act as a productive use of my time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is what I call the Hacker News habit, and if you’re here, you may have it as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those without any semblance of this affliction, &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/&quot;&gt;Hacker News&lt;/a&gt; is a no-frills news aggregator with a submission guideline for items that can be distilled to a single sentence, “anything that gratifies one’s intellectual curiosity.” The site is a de facto blog of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ycombinator.com/&quot;&gt;Y-Combinator&lt;/a&gt;, an American seed accelerator that provides startups a bit of funding for a bit of stake. Although I will not list them here, you may recognize some of the startups they’ve nurtured since 2005 if I rattled them off in conversation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hacker News has been described by some as a platform that funnels talent into their network by connecting people on projects and encouraging people to apply to the accelerator. On the top of the website is a link to the jobs post, and on the bottom is a link to apply to YC. The site is without traditional ads and loads faster than 90% of the pages on the internet. It really is a special place on the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://hackernewslater.com/images/hn.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Screenshot of Hacker News&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whenever &lt;a href=&quot;https://xkcd.com/303/&quot;&gt;Gradle builds&lt;/a&gt;, or when I finally discover a root of a bug, my routine with Hacker News involves refreshing it, queuing stories I’m interested in by opening tabs and working my way down the front page. Some titles are provocative, while others can do the contents more justice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The subject matter of the articles range and they’re often exciting. Though software topics and startup news often dominate the site, it’s not uncommon to read about computer science, philosophy, music, art, literature, and sociology, or, a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thedailybeast.com/how-an-ex-cop-rigged-mcdonalds-monopoly-game-and-stole-millions&quot;&gt;Jeff Maysh longform about elaborate stings and long cons&lt;/a&gt;. Anyone who loves knowledge would think this is amazing, but there is something wrong about the way I’m reading the items.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While on the site, within a span of five minutes, I typically attempt to skim everything I’ve marked with interest. Afterward, I return to my work not feeling like I’ve read anything substantive, and by the end of the day, I forget about the links I’ve opened up, including the ones I meant to revisit. In other words, I’ve attempted to binge on texts that was &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; meant to be consumed in seconds, unlike Twitter tweets. (As an aside, the only way I was able to kick the Twitter habit was to forget my password, and remain much too lazy to reset it.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unfocused Reading is a Terrible Thing to Do&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I began doing on my sabbatical is set aside about an hour a day to study and read, under the assumption that understanding and proficiency of a topic takes consistency and focus, with the expectation that progress will be slow and not necessarily incremental. I did this with Spanish, and topics in Computer Science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although I could not report leaps and bounds on fluency, I improved overall and felt less stressed about not reading or studying enough. Any novels I read were physical books - no screens. This worked well, but I kept opening tabs on sites like Hacker News throughout the day, committing the act of &lt;em&gt;unfocused reading&lt;/em&gt;. This was when I surrendered to the fact that I had an issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What Solutions Can I Devise?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like many other Hacker News readers, I threw code at the problem. I decided to write an Android app that queues the Hacker News items I marked with interest, then have it send an email to me with my saved links at a time I specify. As a result, I can schedule what I want to read in advance, integrating the items with whatever else I want to read. This was a good opportunity to work on a personal project for Android and work on a platform I know nothing about, &lt;a href=&quot;https://spring.io/&quot;&gt;Spring&lt;/a&gt;, for the backend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to go &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/AndroidFirst?src=hash&quot;&gt;#AndroidFirst&lt;/a&gt; because I wanted to try something new, and move further away from working on iOS. I chose Java on Spring, because in the world of fast and loose JavaScript, it’s easy to forget that Java is the OG high-level language that still powers many of the web applications today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wrote the Android app in &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kotlin_(programming_language)&quot;&gt;Kotlin&lt;/a&gt; - a statically typed language that runs on the JVM. There were no real surprises here, as I was around iOS when Swift was introduced to transition away from Objective-C: Kotlin and Swift are surprisingly similar; here is a &lt;a href=&quot;http://nilhcem.com/swift-is-like-kotlin/&quot;&gt;site&lt;/a&gt; that compares the two. A big improvement over using Java is the null safety; being able to treat objects as potentially null thereby greatly reducing the odds of contributing to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tony_Hoare#Apologies_and_retractions&quot;&gt;Billion Dollar Mistake&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To note, I did use &lt;a href=&quot;https://kotlinlang.org/docs/reference/coroutines.html&quot;&gt;coroutines&lt;/a&gt;, which as of Kotlin 1.1 is still an experimental feature. Coroutines allow you to run tasks on a different thread to prevent lockups on the UI for example. As a result, there is not a single AsyncTask on this app. It was as simple as the following.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-kotlin&quot;&gt;launch(CommonPool) {
  superLongRunningUIBlockingFunction() { data -&amp;gt;
    launch(UI) {
        updateUIWithData(data)
    }
  }
}
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, I experimented with using &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/topic/libraries/architecture/&quot;&gt;Android Architecture Components&lt;/a&gt;. With it, it is now easier to handle lifecycles, as the components are self -aware of the cycle. LiveData allows the UI to update pursuant to database changes, and Room makes writing boilerplate code to work with SQLite a thing of the past. I did not fumble around with Cursors when accessing the database - whether this is a curse or a godsend, you can decide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Midway through development, while wondering if this is an app that anyone would use, I found this &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17637835&quot;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; on one of my many HN breaks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://hackernewslater.com/images/email_later_hn_post.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Oh Hacker News, you did it again!&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems that other people experience the same issue!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Result&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The result of my work above is &lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=hackernewslater.williamha.com.hackernewslater&quot;&gt;Hacker News Later&lt;/a&gt;, currently live on the Google Play store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://hackernewslater.com/images/hacker_news_later_screen_shot.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Hacker News Later&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A user can save the items they want based on the title, to be emailed to him or her later. At the moment, a user can’t read the items on the app unless they penalize themselves by buying credits (processing through Stripe). Although the app is about breaking the bad habit of reading the items immediately, I’m still reconsidering this feature, and perhaps replacing it with a snippet preview and option to read immediately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally, I’m going to shift all Hacker News focused reading through this app sent via email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see below, I was curious about &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17763011&quot;&gt;Katie’s New Face&lt;/a&gt;, and the legitimacy of the claim that &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17767789&quot;&gt;Indian food can be made in five minutes&lt;/a&gt; via a subscription box service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://hackernewslater.com/images/inbox_screen_shot.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;h4&gt;The Email&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hacker News Later, The Digest&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In making this app, the thought of doing a digest of Hacker News may be a worthwhile pursuit, so this is what I hope the blog may become – a place for me to curate and write about news items I find interesting on a weekly basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading! If you’ve enjoyed this post, or even downloaded the app, I’m certainly open for comments and suggestions. If something does not work, I intend to fix it, so please let me know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, my sabbatical is loosely coming to an end and I will be looking for interesting projects to work on. If you know of anything, please feel free to message me &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/burritofanatic&quot;&gt;@burritofanatic&lt;/a&gt; on Twitter; my direct messages are open.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;aside class=&quot;w-30-l mt6-l&quot;/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 18:48:10 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>burritofanatic</dc:creator>
<og:title>The Hacker News Habit</og:title>
<og:description>I have an addiction. More accurately it’s a pesky bad habit I uncovered during a period of self-examination while on sabbatical – I love, excessively, the consumption of bite-sized posts, which I justify reading as it relates to my profession; I rationalize the act as a productive use of my time. This is what I call the Hacker News habit, and if you’re here, you may have it as well.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>/posts/the-hacker-news-habit/</og:url>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://hackernewslater.com/posts/the-hacker-news-habit/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Who Left Open The Cookie Jar?</title>
<link>https://wholeftopenthecookiejar.eu</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://wholeftopenthecookiejar.eu</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Cookies have become an important aspect of the modern-day web. By default, browsers automatically attach cookies to all HTTP requests. This allows users to keep track which items they have added to their online shopping basket, or simply to log in to their favorite websites. However, cookies may also be exploited for more nefarious goals: users' online activies are tracked at large-scale by various advertising companies, or so-called cross-site attacks can be used to take over the account of an unwitting user. As a response to this increasing threat surface, a variety of defense mechanisms have been developed: either as anti-tracking or ad-blocking browser extensions, or as built-in browser features such as the Tracking Protection in Firefox, or SameSite cookies, which can be highly effective at thwarting cross-site attacks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An important prerequisite for these privacy- and security-enhancing features to function properly, is that &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; requests need to comply with the imposed cookie policies. As browsers have become enormously complex, certain edge-cases may have been overlooked or the interplay of specific features may have unwanted side-effects. In our research, we created a framework to verify whether all imposed cookie- and request-policies are correctly applied (will be made available soon). Worryingly, we found that most mechanisms could be circumvented: for instance for all ad-blocking and anti-tracking browser extensions we discovered at least one technique that could bypass the policies. For the technical details of these findings, we invite you to read our &lt;a href=&quot;https://wholeftopenthecookiejar.eu/static/tpc-paper.pdf&quot;&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt;, which was presented at USENIX Security ’18.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have been working with browser vendors and extension developers to mitigate the discovered issues. To verify whether you are affected by our detected bypasses, feel free to explore the data on this website (please note that we are still working to have the most up-to-date information available).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 17:54:41 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>pmoriarty</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://wholeftopenthecookiejar.eu/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>