<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>With teen mental health deteriorating over five years, there’s a likely culprit</title>
<link>https://theconversation.com/with-teen-mental-health-deteriorating-over-five-years-theres-a-likely-culprit-86996</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://theconversation.com/with-teen-mental-health-deteriorating-over-five-years-theres-a-likely-culprit-86996</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Around 2012, something started going wrong in the lives of teens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In just the five years between 2010 and 2015, the number of U.S. teens who felt useless and joyless – &lt;a href=&quot;https://adaa.org/understanding-anxiety/depression/symptoms&quot;&gt;classic symptoms of depression&lt;/a&gt; – surged 33 percent in large national surveys. Teen suicide attempts increased 23 percent. Even more troubling, the number of 13- to 18-year-olds who committed suicide jumped 31 percent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/full/10.1177/2167702617723376&quot;&gt;In a new paper&lt;/a&gt; published in Clinical Psychological Science, my colleagues and I found that the increases in depression, suicide attempts and suicide appeared among teens from every background – more privileged and less privileged, across all races and ethnicities and in every region of the country. All told, our analysis found that the generation of teens I call “&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.simonandschuster.com/books/iGen/Jean-M-Twenge/9781501151989&quot;&gt;iGen&lt;/a&gt;” – those born after 1995 – is much more likely to experience mental health issues than their millennial predecessors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What happened so that so many more teens, in such a short period of time, would feel depressed, attempt suicide and commit suicide? After scouring several large surveys of teens for clues, I found that all of the possibilities traced back to a major change in teens’ lives: the sudden ascendance of the smartphone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;All signs point to the screen&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because the years between 2010 to 2015 were a period of steady economic growth and &lt;a href=&quot;https://data.bls.gov/timeseries/LNS14000000&quot;&gt;falling unemployment&lt;/a&gt;, it’s unlikely that economic malaise was a factor. Income inequality was (and still is) an issue, but it didn’t suddenly appear in the early 2010s: This gap between the rich and poor had been &lt;a href=&quot;https://fred.stlouisfed.org/series/SIPOVGINIUSA&quot;&gt;widening for decades&lt;/a&gt;. We found that the time teens spent on homework barely budged between 2010 and 2015, effectively ruling out academic pressure as a cause.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, according to the Pew Research Center, smartphone ownership &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pewresearch.org/fact-tank/2017/01/12/evolution-of-technology/&quot;&gt;crossed the 50 percent threshold&lt;/a&gt; in late 2012 – right when teen depression and suicide began to increase. By 2015, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pewinternet.org/2015/04/09/teens-social-media-technology-2015/pi_2015-04-09_teensandtech_06/&quot;&gt;73 percent&lt;/a&gt; of teens had access to a smartphone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only did smartphone use and depression increase in tandem, but time spent online was linked to mental health issues across two different data sets. We found that teens who spent five or more hours a day online were 71 percent more likely than those who spent less than an hour a day to have at least one suicide risk factor (depression, thinking about suicide, making a suicide plan or attempting suicide). Overall, suicide risk factors rose significantly after two or more hours a day of time online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, it’s possible that instead of time online causing depression, depression causes more time online. But three other studies show that is unlikely (at least, when viewed through social media use).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two followed people over time, with &lt;a href=&quot;https://hbr.org/2017/04/a-new-more-rigorous-study-confirms-the-more-you-use-facebook-the-worse-you-feel&quot;&gt;both&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0069841&quot;&gt;studies&lt;/a&gt; finding that spending more time on social media led to unhappiness, while unhappiness did not lead to more social media use. &lt;a href=&quot;http://online.liebertpub.com/doi/abs/10.1089/cyber.2016.0259?journalCode=cyber&quot;&gt;A third&lt;/a&gt; randomly assigned participants to give up Facebook for a week versus continuing their usual use. Those who avoided Facebook reported feeling less depressed at the end of the week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The argument that depression might cause people to spend more time online doesn’t also explain why depression increased so suddenly after 2012. Under that scenario, more teens became depressed for an unknown reason and then started buying smartphones, which doesn’t seem too logical.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What’s lost when we’re plugged in&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if online time doesn’t directly harm mental health, it could still adversely affect it in indirect ways, especially if time online crowds out time for other activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, while conducting research for my book on iGen, I found that teens now spend much less time interacting with their friends in person. Interacting with people face to face &lt;a href=&quot;http://ronaldvoorn.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/1995-The-Need-to-Belong-Desire-for-Interpersonal-Attachments-as-a-Fundamental-Human-Motivation.pdf&quot;&gt;is one of the deepest wellsprings of human happiness&lt;/a&gt;; without it, our moods start to suffer and depression often follows. Feeling socially isolated is also &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apa.org/science/about/psa/2009/06/sci-brief.aspx&quot;&gt;one of the major risk factors for suicide&lt;/a&gt;. We found that teens who spent more time than average online and less time than average with friends in person were the most likely to be depressed. Since 2012, that’s what has occurred en masse: Teens have spent less time on activities known to benefit mental health (in-person social interaction) and more time on activities that may harm it (time online).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teens are also sleeping less, and teens who spend more time on their phones &lt;a href=&quot;https://theconversation.com/teens-are-sleeping-less-but-theres-a-surprisingly-easy-fix-85157&quot;&gt;are more likely to not be getting enough sleep&lt;/a&gt;. Not sleeping enough is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0165178108004113&quot;&gt;a major risk factor&lt;/a&gt; for depression, so if smartphones are causing less sleep, that alone could explain why depression and suicide increased so suddenly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depression and suicide have many causes: Genetic predisposition, family environments, bullying and trauma can all play a role. Some teens would experience mental health problems no matter what era they lived in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But some vulnerable teens who would otherwise not have had mental health issues may have slipped into depression due to too much screen time, not enough face-to-face social interaction, inadequate sleep or a combination of all three.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It might be argued that it’s too soon to recommend less screen time, given that &lt;a href=&quot;http://eprints.lse.ac.uk/66927/1/Policy%20Brief%2017-%20Families%20%20Screen%20Time.pdf&quot;&gt;the research isn’t completely definitive&lt;/a&gt;. However, the downside to limiting screen time – say, to two hours a day or less – is minimal. In contrast, the downside to doing nothing – given the possible consequences of depression and suicide – seems, to me, quite high.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not too early to think about limiting screen time; let’s hope it’s not too late.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2018 19:28:59 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>prostoalex</dc:creator>
<og:title>With teen mental health deteriorating over five years, there's a likely culprit</og:title>
<og:description>According to a new analysis, the number of US teens who felt &quot;useless&quot; and &quot;joyless&quot; grew 33 percent between 2010 and 2015, and there was a 23 percent increase in suicide attempts.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:image>https://images.theconversation.com/files/194386/original/file-20171113-27576-a1s7xf.jpg?ixlib=rb-1.1.0&amp;rect=19%2C0%2C3268%2C1631&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=1356&amp;h=668&amp;fit=crop</og:image>
<og:url>http://theconversation.com/with-teen-mental-health-deteriorating-over-five-years-theres-a-likely-culprit-86996</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://theconversation.com/with-teen-mental-health-deteriorating-over-five-years-theres-a-likely-culprit-86996</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Intel Warned Chinese Companies of Chip Flaws Before U.S. Government</title>
<link>https://www.wsj.com/articles/intel-warned-chinese-companies-of-chip-flaws-before-u-s-government-1517157430</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.wsj.com/articles/intel-warned-chinese-companies-of-chip-flaws-before-u-s-government-1517157430</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;In initial disclosures about critical security flaws discovered in its processors, Intel Corp. notified a small group of customers, including Chinese technology companies, but left out the U.S. government, according to people familiar with the matter and some of the companies involved.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The decision raises concerns, security researchers said, as it potentially could have allowed information about the chip flaws, dubbed Spectre and Meltdown, to fall into the hands of the Chinese government before being publicly divulged. There...
  &lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2018 18:07:42 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>propman</dc:creator>
<og:title>Intel Warned Chinese Companies of Chip Flaws Before U.S. Government </og:title>
<og:description>In initial disclosures about critical security flaws discovered in its processors, Intel notified a small group of customers, including Chinese technology companies, but left out the U.S. government, according to people familiar with the matter and some of the companies involved.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.wsj.com/articles/intel-warned-chinese-companies-of-chip-flaws-before-u-s-government-1517157430</og:url>
<og:image>https://images.wsj.net/im-1591/social</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.wsj.com/articles/intel-warned-chinese-companies-of-chip-flaws-before-u-s-government-1517157430</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>After Surgery in Germany, I Wanted Vicodin, Not Herbal Tea</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/01/27/opinion/sunday/surgery-germany-vicodin.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2018/01/27/opinion/sunday/surgery-germany-vicodin.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;80&quot; data-total-count=&quot;1441&quot; id=&quot;story-continues-3&quot;&gt;With mounting panic, I decided to speak to the anesthesiologist, my last resort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;457&quot; data-total-count=&quot;1898&quot;&gt;This time, I used a different tactic. I told him how appalled I had been when my teenager was given 30 Vicodin pills after she had her wisdom teeth removed in the United States. “I am not looking for that,” I said, “but I am concerned about pain management. I won’t be able to sleep. I know I can have ibuprofen, but can I have two or three pills with codeine for the first few nights? Let me remind you that I am getting an entire organ removed.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;712&quot; data-total-count=&quot;2610&quot;&gt;The anesthesiologist explained that during surgery and recovery I would be given strong painkillers, but once I got home the pain would not require narcotics. To paraphrase him, he said: “Pain is a part of life. We cannot eliminate it nor do we want to. The pain will guide you. You will know when to rest more; you will know when you are healing. If I give you Vicodin, you will no longer feel the pain, yes, but you will no longer know what your body is telling you. You might overexert yourself because you are no longer feeling the pain signals. All you need is rest. And please be careful with ibuprofen. It’s not good for your kidneys. Only take it if you must. Your body will heal itself with rest.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;276&quot; data-total-count=&quot;2886&quot;&gt;I didn’t mention that I use ibuprofen like candy. Why else do they come in such jumbo sizes at American warehouse stores? Instead, I thought about his poetic explanation of pain as my guide, although his mention of “just resting” was disturbing. What exactly is resting?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;313&quot; data-total-count=&quot;3199&quot;&gt;I know how to sleep but resting is an in-between space I do not inhabit. It’s like an ambiguous place that can be reached only by walking into a magic closet and emerging on the other side to find a dense forest and a talking lion, a lion who can guide me toward the owl who supplies the forest with pain pills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;180&quot; data-total-count=&quot;3379&quot;&gt;“I do have another question,” I said. “Stool softeners — certainly, you prescribe those? That’s pretty standard with anesthesia throughout the modern world, I believe.”&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;264&quot; data-total-count=&quot;3643&quot;&gt;“You won’t need those,” he answered in his calm voice. “Your body will function just fine. Just give it a day or two. Drink a cup of coffee, slowly. And whatever you do, do not get it in a to-go cup. You must sit in one place and enjoy this cup, slowly.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;423&quot; data-total-count=&quot;4066&quot;&gt;His gentle suggestion to trust my body almost brought me to tears. It reminded me of the poster in my doctor’s waiting room, the one informing us that herbal tea is the first remedy to try when we have a cold. The first remedy I try is the decongestants I bring with me from the United States. I can’t find those in Germany, nor can I find the children’s cough medicine that makes my child drowsy. I also import that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;206&quot; data-total-count=&quot;4272&quot;&gt;Come to think of it, I bring a lot of medicine with me from the United States, all over the counter, all intended to take away discomfort. The German doctors were telling me that being uncomfortable is O.K.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;story-ad-2&quot; class=&quot;story-ad ad ad-placeholder nocontent robots-nocontent&quot;&gt;

&lt;a class=&quot;visually-hidden skip-to-text-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/01/27/opinion/sunday/surgery-germany-vicodin.html#story-continues-4&quot;&gt;Continue reading the main story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;201&quot; data-total-count=&quot;4473&quot; id=&quot;story-continues-4&quot;&gt;My first night home after surgery, I didn’t sleep well because of the pain from the carbon dioxide pumped into my body for the laparoscopy. Had I had something to knock me out, I would have taken it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;174&quot; data-total-count=&quot;4647&quot;&gt;In the morning, my husband propped me up in bed and brought me a pot of tea. I was tired and uncomfortable, and I was bored. An entire day lay ahead of me. I was dreading it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;435&quot; data-total-count=&quot;5082&quot;&gt;I took two ibuprofens that first day. In hindsight, I didn’t need them, but I felt like I should take something. What I really needed was patience pills, and a few distractions. The hardest part of my recovery was lingering in bed, or on the sofa, feeling the discomfort and boredom as time ticked by slowly. I didn’t feel like reading or doing much of anything. I watched a few movies and many episodes of “Antiques Roadshow.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;214&quot; data-total-count=&quot;5296&quot;&gt;Every day, my body felt a little better. I drank mint tea. I drank fennel tea. I drank homemade chai with ginger, cardamom and pepper. I drank coffee slowly, enjoying every sip. I lingered in that in-between space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;311&quot; data-total-count=&quot;5607&quot;&gt;After a week, I took the tram to the doctor’s office to have my stitches removed. My doctor, with her usual cup of chamomile tea in hand, remarked on my progress. “I rested,” I told her. Normally, I would have said, “I did nothing,” but I didn’t say that. I had been healing, and that’s something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;222&quot; data-total-count=&quot;5829&quot;&gt;I did say that this story is not about the benefits of universal health care, but for the sake of accuracy, let me add that this hysterectomy was not without cost. After my surgery, I had to pay $25 for the taxi ride home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;visually-hidden skip-to-text-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/01/27/opinion/sunday/surgery-germany-vicodin.html#whats-next&quot;&gt;Continue reading the main story&lt;/a&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2018 18:03:51 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mpweiher</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/01/27/opinion/sunday/surgery-germany-vicodin.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Opinion | After Surgery in Germany, I Wanted Vicodin, Not Herbal Tea</og:title>
<og:description>My doctor told me that feeling pain during recovery from surgery is normal. Why was I so resistant?</og:description>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/01/28/opinion/sunday/28dumas/28dumas-facebookJumbo.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/01/27/opinion/sunday/surgery-germany-vicodin.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ikea founder Ingvar Kamprad has died</title>
<link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-42851668</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-42851668</guid>
<description>&lt;figure class=&quot;media-with-caption&quot; readability=&quot;-24&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;player-with-placeholder&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img class=&quot;media-placeholder player-with-placeholder__image lead-video-placeholder&quot; src=&quot;https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/images/ic/720x405/p05wcs8q.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Media playback is unsupported on your device&lt;/p&gt;
      
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;figcaption class=&quot;media-with-caption__caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Media caption&lt;/span&gt;WATCH: 5 things to know about Ingvar Kamprad, founder of Ikea&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;story-body__introduction&quot;&gt;The Swedish founder of the Ikea furniture chain, Ingvar Kamprad, has died at the age of 91, the company has announced.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mr Kamprad - who pioneered flat-pack furniture - died at his home in Småland, Ikea confirmed in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The company said that Mr Kamprad was &quot;one of the greatest entrepreneurs of the 20th century&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The billionaire, who was born in 1926 in Småland, founded Ikea at the age of 17.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He used some money his father had given him as a gift for performing well at school despite his dyslexia.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the later years of his life, Mr Kamprad faced questions over his past links to fascist groups - something he admitted, but said was a &quot;mistake&quot;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul class=&quot;story-body__unordered-list&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-42851008&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link&quot;&gt;World reacts to Ikea founder's death&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape has-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
                 &lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image copyright&lt;/span&gt;
                 &lt;span class=&quot;story-image-copyright&quot;&gt;Ikea / Paul Barendregt&lt;/span&gt;
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
            &lt;figcaption class=&quot;media-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image caption&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;media-caption__text&quot;&gt;
                    Ingvar Kamprad said there were &quot;many reasons&quot; why he loved his business
                &lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a statement on Sunday, Ikea said that Mr Kamprad had &quot;peacefully passed away at his home&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;He worked until the very end of his life, staying true to his own motto that most things remain to be done,&quot; it added. Mr Kamprad eventually stepped down from the company's board in 2013, at the age of 87. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Ingvar Kamprad was a great entrepreneur of the typical southern Swedish kind - hardworking and stubborn, with a lot of warmth and a playful twinkle in his eye,&quot; the company said. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;His company's designs became popular in part because of their simplicity and value. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mr Kamprad is reported to have come up with the idea of flat-pack furniture after watching an employee remove the legs from a table in order to fit it into a customer's car.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul class=&quot;story-body__unordered-list&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-41634546&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link&quot;&gt;Is Ikea the Marmite of retailers?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-38747485&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link&quot;&gt;How Ikea's Billy took over the world &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Furniture designer Jeff Banks said that Mr Kamprad's creations radically changed how people made and designed products for the home.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;People have tried to reproduce and copy that, but unsuccessfully,&quot; he said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mr Banks added that the designs produced and sold through the retailer made good use of recyclable products, adding that Mr Kamprad was &quot;head and shoulders above the rest&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape has-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
            &lt;figcaption class=&quot;media-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image caption&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;media-caption__text&quot;&gt;
                    Ikea has expanded to operate all around the world, including in China
                &lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mr Kamprad was renowned for his devotion to frugality, reportedly driving an old Volvo and travelling by economy class.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a 2016 interview with Swedish television channel TV4, Mr Kamprad said that it was &quot;in the nature of Småland to be thrifty&quot;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;If you look at me now, I don't think I'm wearing anything that wasn't bought at a flea market,&quot; he said. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He told the channel that he built his business on a &quot;local ethos&quot;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;We have Småland in the blood, and we know what a krona is - even though it is not as much as it was when we bought candy and went to elementary school,&quot; he said, referring to the Swedish currency. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;People took to social media on Sunday to pay their respects to the &quot;greatest Swedish entrepreneur to have ever lived&quot;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Swedish Foreign Minister Margot Wallstrom tweeted her condolences, saying that Mr Kamprad had &quot;put Sweden on the world map&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr class=&quot;story-body__line&quot;/&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;story-body__crosshead&quot;&gt;Ikea: Key facts&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul class=&quot;story-body__unordered-list&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;Ikea started in 1943 and now has 389 stores worldwide&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;The name comes from Mr Kamprad's initials (IK), together with the name of the farm he grew up on - Elmtaryd (E) - and the nearby village Agunnaryd (A)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;The company's retail sales totalled 36.4bn euros ($43bn, £30bn) in 2016&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;Its flat-pack furniture became iconic both for its affordability and for its picture-based assembly instructions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;hr class=&quot;story-body__line&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ikea has remained privately-owned under a Dutch trust operated by the Kamprad family. Its complex business structure has drawn controversy and the European Commission said last year that it had launched an investigation into Ikea's tax arrangements.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The European Green Party said that the arrangement had allowed the company to avoid paying some €1bn in tax between 2009 and 2014.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A spokesman for Dutch-based Inter Ikea, one of the company's two divisions, said that the company had been taxed &quot;in accordance with EU rules&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul class=&quot;story-body__unordered-list&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-42798506&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link&quot;&gt;Ikea boss says it pays fair share of tax&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-38390497&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link&quot;&gt;Ikea's fight against teen sleepovers &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;In an interview in the 1980s, Mr Kamprad said that his vision for Ikea was that it would be a company that would make life easier for its customers. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In more recent years, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-14661582&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link&quot;&gt;Mr Kamprad had faced scrutiny over his past links to Nazi groups&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The tycoon revealed some elements of his past in a book in 1988, admitting that he was a close friend of the Swedish fascist activist Per Engdahl, and a member of his New Swedish Movement between 1942 and 1945.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He said that his involvement was youthful &quot;stupidity&quot; and the &quot;greatest mistake&quot; of his life. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But a 2011 book by Elisabeth Asbrink alleged details beyond what Mr Kamprad had previously admitted. She wrote that he was an active recruiter for a Swedish Nazi group, and stayed close to sympathisers well after World War Two.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the time a spokesman for Mr Kamprad said he had long admitted flirting with fascism, but that there were now &quot;no Nazi-sympathising thoughts in Ingvar's head whatsoever&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
    </description>
<pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2018 11:06:51 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>severine</dc:creator>
<og:title>Ikea founder Kamprad dies at 91</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>The billionaire Swede Ingvar Kamprad founded the pioneering furniture retailer at the age of 17.</og:description>
<og:url>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-42851668</og:url>
<og:image>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/images/ic/1024x576/p05wcs8q.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-GB</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-42851668</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>I think I found a Mac kernel bug?</title>
<link>https://jvns.ca/blog/2018/01/28/mac-freeze/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://jvns.ca/blog/2018/01/28/mac-freeze/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been working on Mac support for &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rbspy/rbspy&quot;&gt;rbspy&lt;/a&gt;, and I accidentally found something that looks like a Mac kernel bug! Basically I managed to write a very short (17 line) C program that reliably causes &lt;code&gt;ps&lt;/code&gt; to stop working. Without allocating any memory or anything like that!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This seems to be a kernel bug on High Sierra, but not Sierra – someone &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/capileigh/status/957709200385191936&quot;&gt;tried to reproduce on Sierra&lt;/a&gt; and couldn’t. So looks like it’s a new bug.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;mysterious-freezes-on-mac&quot;&gt;mysterious freezes on mac&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This past week I’ve been building Mac support for rbspy (my Ruby profiler). I put a Mac support branch on github yesterday. Some amazing early adopters tried out the branch and reported that it froze their computer (Activity Monitor stopped working, they couldn’t open new terminals, etc). This was extremely surprising – how could that happen?!? There’s a very detailed report at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rbspy/rbspy/issues/70&quot;&gt;https://github.com/rbspy/rbspy/issues/70&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was really mystified by this – how could a program &lt;em&gt;not running as root&lt;/em&gt; freeze someone’s computer? Somebody suggested that maybe the program was allocating a lot of memory, but I didn’t &lt;strong&gt;think&lt;/strong&gt; it was. And it turns out that memory allocations weren’t the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-17-line-c-program-that-freezes-parts-of-my-mac&quot;&gt;A 17-line C program that freezes (parts of) my Mac&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;@parkr was incredibly helpful and managed to narrow down the problem to right before calling the &lt;code&gt;task_for_pid&lt;/code&gt; Mach function. Since &lt;code&gt;task_for_pid&lt;/code&gt; seemed to be the issue, I worked on reproducing the issue in a small C program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s the program that shows the bug. It runs in a loop because it’s a bit race-y and sometimes it needs to try 10 times before it’ll freeze.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;#include &amp;lt;mach/mach_init.h&amp;gt;
#include &amp;lt;mach/port.h&amp;gt;
#include &amp;lt;sys/wait.h&amp;gt;
#include &amp;lt;unistd.h&amp;gt;
#include &amp;lt;stdio.h&amp;gt;

int main() {
    for (;;) {
        pid_t pid = fork();
        if (pid == 0) execv(&quot;/usr/bin/true&quot;, NULL); 
        mach_port_name_t task = MACH_PORT_NULL;
        task_for_pid(mach_task_self(), pid, &amp;amp;task);
        printf(&quot;Ran task_for_pid\n&quot;);
        int wait_status;
        wait(&amp;amp;wait_status);
    }
}
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s the behaviour I see:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;./freeze-mac&lt;/code&gt;. (the example program, above) It hangs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;ps&lt;/code&gt; in another tab. ps hangs, and doesn’t display any output. also trying to &lt;code&gt;Ctrl+C&lt;/code&gt; to stop &lt;code&gt;ps&lt;/code&gt; doesn’t work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;This happens on the Mac I’ve been developing on (running High Sierra, 10.13.2).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The core issue seems to be – if I &lt;code&gt;exec&lt;/code&gt; a new program (like &lt;code&gt;/usr/bin/true&lt;/code&gt;), and then immediately run &lt;code&gt;task_for_pid&lt;/code&gt; on that program, then the process I ran &lt;code&gt;task_for_pid&lt;/code&gt; from will hang and &lt;code&gt;ps&lt;/code&gt; will stop working (though I can terminate it with Ctrl+C and then things seem to go back to normal).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to try it out on your Mac, you can run the program yourself! (at your own risk – for me it freezes some things but everything goes back to normal if I press ctrl+c, I don’t know what will happen if you run it :) )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;wget https://gist.githubusercontent.com/jvns/16c1ea69352a81658d6d8e9c5a289f2a/raw/ea11fa0a16bfcd4fd019666b790c6c8fe624f9f0/freeze-mac.c
cc -o freeze-mac freeze-mac.c
./freeze-mac
# try running `ps` / starting Activity Monitor, they don't work!
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;this-bug-is-affecting-htop-too&quot;&gt;this bug is affecting htop too&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somebody on twitter pointed me to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/hishamhm/htop/issues/682&quot;&gt;this github issue on htop for mac&lt;/a&gt; where people are reporting that &lt;code&gt;htop&lt;/code&gt; sometimes sporadically freezes their computer in the same way (terminals don’t start, Activity Monitor doesn’t work). &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/hishamhm/htop/issues/682#issuecomment-355759162&quot;&gt;In the comments&lt;/a&gt; @grrrrrrrrr says this is a race condition in &lt;code&gt;task_for_pid&lt;/code&gt; and they have what looks to be a POC that’s similar to what I have here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;i-have-a-workaround&quot;&gt;I have a workaround!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is weird and I don’t really understand the underlying kernel issue. Anyway, I have a workaround for this – don’t run &lt;code&gt;task_for_pid&lt;/code&gt; on processes immediately after exec’ing them, instead sleep for a few milliseconds first. So hopefully with this new knowledge I can get rbspy to work on Mac without freezing any users’ computers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Systems programming is weird and exciting though!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;if you have thoughts or questions, here’s the &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/b0rk/status/957498366606368768&quot;&gt;twitter thread for this post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2018 10:17:50 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ingve</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://jvns.ca/blog/2018/01/28/mac-freeze/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Strava heatmap can be used to locate military bases</title>
<link>https://twitter.com/tobiaschneider/status/957317886112124928</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://twitter.com/tobiaschneider/status/957317886112124928</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/tobiaschneider/status/957317886112124928&quot;&gt;https://twitter.com/tobiaschneider/status/957317886112124928&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16249955&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16249955&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Points: 617&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 228&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2018 05:16:37 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>domoritz</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://mobile.twitter.com/tobiaschneider/status/957317886112124928</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>‘Jackpotting’ Attacks Hit U.S. ATMs</title>
<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2018/01/first-jackpotting-attacks-hit-u-s-atms/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://krebsonsecurity.com/2018/01/first-jackpotting-attacks-hit-u-s-atms/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;ATM “&lt;strong&gt;jackpotting&lt;/strong&gt;” — a sophisticated crime in which thieves install malicious software and/or hardware at ATMs that forces the machines to spit out huge volumes of cash on demand — has long been a threat for banks in Europe and Asia, yet these attacks somehow have eluded U.S. ATM operators. But all that changed this week after the &lt;strong&gt;U.S. Secret Service&lt;/strong&gt; quietly began warning financial institutions that jackpotting attacks have now been spotted targeting cash machines here in the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To carry out a jackpotting attack, thieves first must gain physical access to the cash machine. From there they can use malware or specialized electronics — often a combination of both — to control the operations of the ATM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_42367&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot; wp-image-42367&quot; src=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/ploutus-d.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;598&quot; height=&quot;332&quot; /&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;A keyboard attached to the ATM port. Image: FireEye&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Jan. 21, 2018, KrebsOnSecurity began hearing rumblings about jackpotting attacks, also known as “logical attacks,” hitting U.S. ATM operators. I quickly reached out to ATM giant &lt;strong&gt;NCR Corp.&lt;/strong&gt; to see if they’d heard anything. NCR said at the time it had received unconfirmed reports, but nothing solid yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Jan. 26, NCR sent an advisory to its customers saying it had received reports from the Secret Service and other sources about jackpotting attacks against ATMs in the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“While at present these appear focused on non-NCR ATMs, logical attacks are an industry-wide issue,” the NCR alert reads. “This represents the first confirmed cases of losses due to logical attacks in the US. This should be treated as a call to action to take appropriate steps to protect their ATMs against these forms of attack and mitigate any consequences.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The NCR memo does not mention the type of jackpotting malware used against U.S. ATMs. But a source close to the matter said the Secret Service is warning that organized criminal gangs have been attacking stand-alone ATMs in the United States using “&lt;strong&gt;Ploutus.D&lt;/strong&gt;,” an advanced strain of jackpotting malware &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fireeye.com/blog/threat-research/2017/01/new_ploutus_variant.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;first spotted in 2013&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to that source — who asked to remain anonymous because he was not authorized to speak on the record — the Secret Service has received credible information that crooks are activating so-called “cash out crews” to attack front-loading ATMs manufactured by ATM vendor &lt;strong&gt;Diebold Nixdorf&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The source said the Secret Service is warning that thieves appear to be targeting &lt;strong&gt;Opteva 500 and 700&lt;/strong&gt; series Dielbold ATMs using the Ploutus.D malware in a series of coordinated attacks over the past 10 days, and that there is evidence that further attacks are being planned across the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The targeted stand-alone ATMs are routinely located in pharmacies, big box retailers, and drive-thru ATMs,” reads a confidential Secret Service alert sent to multiple financial institutions and obtained by KrebsOnSecurity. “During previous attacks, &lt;span class=&quot;pullquote pqleft&quot;&gt;fraudsters dressed as ATM technicians and attached a laptop computer with a mirror image of the ATMs operating system along with a mobile device to the targeted ATM.&lt;/span&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reached for comment, Diebold shared an alert it sent to customers Friday warning of potential jackpotting attacks in the United States. Diebold’s alert confirms the attacks so far appear to be targeting front-loaded Opteva cash machines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“As in Mexico last year, the attack mode involves a series of different steps to overcome security mechanism and the authorization process for setting the communication with the [cash] dispenser,” the Diebold security alert reads. A copy of the entire Diebold alert, complete with advice on how to mitigate these attacks, is available &lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/20180126-GLOBAL-SECURITY-ALERT-018-04-0005-Potential-Jackpotting-US-Update-on-017-34-0002-smaller.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; (PDF).&lt;span id=&quot;more-42364&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Secret Service alert explains that the attackers typically use an &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Endoscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;endoscope&lt;/a&gt; — a slender, flexible instrument traditionally used in medicine to give physicians a look inside the human body — to locate the internal portion of the cash machine where they can attach a cord that allows them to sync their laptop with the ATM’s computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_42369&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot; wp-image-42369&quot; src=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/endoscope.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;597&quot; height=&quot;521&quot; /&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;An endoscope made to work in tandem with a mobile device. Source: gadgetsforgeeks.com.au&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Once this is complete, the ATM is controlled by the fraudsters and the ATM will appear Out of Service to potential customers,” reads the confidential Secret Service alert.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, the crook(s) installing the malware will contact co-conspirators who can remotely control the ATMs and force the machines to dispense cash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“In previous Ploutus.D attacks, the ATM continuously dispensed at a rate of 40 bills every 23 seconds,” the alert continues. Once the dispense cycle starts, the only way to stop it is to press cancel on the keypad. Otherwise, the machine is completely emptied of cash, according to the alert.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An 2017 analysis of Ploutus.D by security firm &lt;strong&gt;FireEye&lt;/strong&gt; called it “one of the most advanced ATM malware families we’ve seen in the last few years.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Discovered for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.symantec.com/connect/blogs/criminals-hit-atm-jackpot&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; data-ss1517067919=&quot;1&quot;&gt;first time in Mexico &lt;/a&gt;back in 2013, Ploutus enabled criminals to empty ATMs using either an external keyboard attached to the machine or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.symantec.com/connect/blogs/texting-atms-cash-shows-cybercriminals-increasing-sophistication&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; data-ss1517067919=&quot;1&quot;&gt;via SMS message&lt;/a&gt;, a technique that had never been seen before,” FireEye’s &lt;strong&gt;Daniel Regalado&lt;/strong&gt; wrote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to FireEye, the Ploutus attacks seen so far require thieves to somehow gain physical access to an ATM — either by picking its locks, using a stolen master key or otherwise removing or destroying part of the machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regalado says the crime gangs typically responsible for these attacks deploy “money mules” to conduct the attacks and siphon cash from ATMs. The term refers to low-level operators within a criminal organization who are assigned high-risk jobs, such as installing ATM skimmers and otherwise physically tampering with cash machines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“From there, the attackers can attach a physical keyboard to connect to the machine, and [use] an activation code provided by the boss in charge of the operation in order to dispense money from the ATM,” he wrote. “Once deployed to an ATM, Ploutus makes it possible for criminals to obtain thousands of dollars in minutes. While there are some risks of the money mule being caught by cameras, the speed in which the operation is carried out minimizes the mule’s risk.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, the Secret Service memo shared by my source says the cash out crew/money mules typically take the dispensed cash and place it in a large bag. After the cash is taken from the ATM and the mule leaves, the phony technician(s) return to the site and remove their equipment from the compromised ATM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The last thing the fraudsters do before leaving the site is to plug the Ethernet cable back in,” the alert notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FireEye said all of the samples of Ploutus.D it examined targeted Diebold ATMs, but it warned that small changes to the malware’s code could enable it to be used against &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kal.com/en/video/multi-vendor&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; data-ss1517067919=&quot;1&quot;&gt;40 different ATM vendors in 80 countries&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Secret Service alert says ATMs still running on &lt;strong&gt;Windows XP&lt;/strong&gt; are particularly vulnerable, and it urged ATM operators to update to a version of &lt;strong&gt;Windows 7&lt;/strong&gt; to defeat this specific type of attack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a quickly developing story and may be updated multiple times over the next few days as more information becomes available.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p class=&quot;small&quot;&gt;Tags: &lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/tag/atm-jackpotting/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;atm jackpotting&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/tag/atm-logical-attacks/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;atm logical attacks&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/tag/daniel-regalado/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;Daniel Regalado&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/tag/diebold-nixdorf/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;Diebold Nixdorf&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/tag/diebold-opteva/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;Diebold Opteva&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/tag/endoscope/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;endoscope&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/tag/fireeye/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;FireEye&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/tag/ncr-corp/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;NCR Corp&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/tag/ploutus-d/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;Ploutus.D&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/tag/u-s-secret-service/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;U.S. Secret Service&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/tag/windows-7/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;Windows 7&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/tag/windows-xp/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;Windows XP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;postmetadata alt&quot;&gt;&lt;small&gt;This entry was posted on Saturday, January 27th, 2018 at 1:45 pm and is filed under &lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/category/all-about-skimmers/&quot; rel=&quot;category tag&quot;&gt;All About Skimmers&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/category/latest-warnings/&quot; rel=&quot;category tag&quot;&gt;Latest Warnings&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/category/comingstorm/&quot; rel=&quot;category tag&quot;&gt;The Coming Storm&lt;/a&gt;. You can follow any comments to this entry through the &lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/2018/01/first-jackpotting-attacks-hit-u-s-atms/feed/&quot;&gt;RSS 2.0&lt;/a&gt; feed. You can skip to the end and leave a comment. Pinging is currently not allowed.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2018 03:38:12 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>larrymcp</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2018/01/first-jackpotting-attacks-hit-u-s-atms/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Craftsmanship – The alternative to the four-hour work week mindset</title>
<link>https://hackernoon.com/craftsmanship-the-alternative-to-the-four-hour-work-week-mindset-e464a2dd34f4</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://hackernoon.com/craftsmanship-the-alternative-to-the-four-hour-work-week-mindset-e464a2dd34f4</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*nDSBP2BjaSk4KaheAnyPfQ.jpeg&quot; data-width=&quot;1280&quot; data-height=&quot;853&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*nDSBP2BjaSk4KaheAnyPfQ.jpeg&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*nDSBP2BjaSk4KaheAnyPfQ.jpeg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;59ae&quot; id=&quot;59ae&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;Often times when I attend a conference or a networking event I am surprised how many people operate at the periphery of the tech industry. Social media gurus, SEO ‘ninjas’, bloggers, etc. It’s a coterie of tech ‘club promoters.’ The hype men of the industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;89a9&quot; id=&quot;89a9&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf--startsWithSingleQuote graf-after--p&quot;&gt;‘Hack your way to success.’ ‘Meet the right people.’ ‘Become a business superstar.’ They’ve found their silver bullet. They boast of building a passive income from a web business, all while traveling the world as the rest of us mortals are slaving away at our 9–5 jobs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;5eed&quot; id=&quot;5eed&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;In a world where we are searching for silver bullets, these people seem to have amassed an arsenal of them. Moreover they’ve found audiences to sell their silver bullets to en masse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;f080&quot; id=&quot;f080&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;The most blatant example of this are some of the disciples of the 4 Hour Work Week, by Tim Ferriss. The book itself is not really the issue. Ferriss indeed outlines some interesting tips on managing resources to get the highest ROI on your work. What is objectionable, however, is the hack-your-way-to-success mentality it has spawned in entrepreneurial circles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;0ab2&quot; id=&quot;0ab2&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;It’s a mindset that is antithetical to everything I know about entrepreneurship. A mindset that I see when I hear people talk about having an amazing idea that they want to farm out to a young college student who can code or outsourcing development of a product to a cheap dev house. It’s a mindset that assumes entrepreneurship is a series of networking events and fundraising meetings, or even some silver-bullet business connection they have in lieu of a real distribution strategy. &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;It’s taking a passive approach to a very difficult undertaking.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;d1ef&quot; id=&quot;d1ef&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;What is missed in all of this is the mindset of craftsmanship; that one’s expertise and deliberate focus on one’s craft is actually the primary driver for success and not some crapshoot of a series of hacks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;e110&quot; id=&quot;e110&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;What happens on the periphery — whether it be the towel slapping we see on Twitter from tech celebrities or headline gossip out of TechCrunch — is not actually meaningful as a foundation of a business or a profession. Neither are the number of coffee meetings you have scheduled or the amount of networking meetings you attend. These things are tertiary at best, and at worst, just plain old distractions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;1992&quot; id=&quot;1992&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;To be successful over the course of a career requires the application and accumulation of expertise. This assumes that for any given undertaking you either provide expertise or you are just a bystander. It’s the experts that are the drivers—an expertise that is gained from a curiosity, and a mindset of treating one’s craft very seriously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;dd3c&quot; id=&quot;dd3c&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;A startup is by nature a crash course in developing expertise. What makes startups unique is the sheer dearth of resources. This dearth of resources forces founders to rapidly adapt their skills to meet the demands of the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;d91c&quot; id=&quot;d91c&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf--startsWithSingleQuote graf-after--p&quot;&gt;‘I didn’t know how to do x, so I just had to figure it out.’ This is what I regularly hear from successful founders, whereas ‘I couldn’t find someone to do X, so I had to reconsider whether to pursue it at all’ is a common refrain from unsuccessful founders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;760a&quot; id=&quot;760a&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;If you step up to the challenge, you’ll realize that the startup is nothing more than a teacher. It in fact is a great teacher for no other reason than it demands the accumulation of knowledge quickly for the startup to survive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;f4f4&quot; id=&quot;f4f4&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;A technical founder, whose experience may relegate her or him to a specialist role in a large company, for example, has to adapt and take on more expertise in adjacent technical areas. There simply aren’t the human resources to hand off these tasks to another specialist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;6f6d&quot; id=&quot;6f6d&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;This is true for taking on tasks in other domains, whether that be sales, finance, marketing, management or design. You have to take an interest in these domains because there is no one else to fill these roles in your early stage company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;0420&quot; id=&quot;0420&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;It’s in exploring these unknown territories and facing the headwind of startup challenges that it becomes clear that the startup is merely a force of catalytic professional and character growth. With actual success of any given venture subject to the whim of outside forces, this growth is the non-monetary dividend that makes the experience priceless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;9b28&quot; id=&quot;9b28&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;That is why the passive, 4-Hour Mindset is so self defeating. To lounge on a beach or travel the world and not actively engage in building your arsenal of expertise is professional malpractice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;4540&quot; id=&quot;4540&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;It’s also not practical. No serious company has been created passively—the passive mindset that leads people to say “I’ve got a great idea. I’ll hire a team to build it out” or “I have this great connection who will drive sales,” while I play armchair visionary. Startup graveyards are full of visionaries without expertise or the proper skills to execute, for no other reason than ideas are not self executing, but are rather made into being by intense engagement by skilled operators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;ea0e&quot; id=&quot;ea0e&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Most importantly, to think of a business as a series of hacks and transactional relationships, you’ll never amass the expertise that your future self and future businesses need to succeed. Startups fail withstanding founder expertise, of course. It is certainly not sufficient to be an expert. However, expertise does make it possible to traverse the struggles of creating businesses over the course of a career. You’re not simply working on the idea in front of you, you’re building the knowledge to succeed at your next projects as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;f6b9&quot; id=&quot;f6b9&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;It is the expertise and the mindset of craftsmanship that allows someone like Elon Musk to jump from project to project and sector to sector with the knowledge of how to execute on the highest level problems. It’s not simply his ability to find interesting ideas. It’s his command of the domains of the business that allow him to execute the way he does. He is the epitome of interdisciplinary student of his businesses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;bc46&quot; id=&quot;bc46&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p graf--trailing&quot;&gt;If you are to optimize for anything, optimize for the long term. Use the challenges of your business today to build mastery in your craft. There is no guarantee that any one venture will succeed, but that mastery will bend luck in your favor over the long course of your career.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2018 23:54:25 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>rpkoven</dc:creator>
<og:title>Craftsmanship—The Alternative to the Four Hour Work Week Mindset</og:title>
<og:url>https://hackernoon.com/craftsmanship-the-alternative-to-the-four-hour-work-week-mindset-e464a2dd34f4</og:url>
<og:image>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*nDSBP2BjaSk4KaheAnyPfQ.jpeg</og:image>
<og:description>Often times when I attend a conference or a networking event I am surprised how many people operate at the periphery of the tech industry…</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://hackernoon.com/craftsmanship-the-alternative-to-the-four-hour-work-week-mindset-e464a2dd34f4?gi=b296f6a5dff5</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Kaggle Learn review: there is a deep learning track and it is worth your time</title>
<link>https://techandmortals.wordpress.com/2018/01/27/kaggle-learn-review-there-is-a-deep-learning-track-and-it-is-worth-your-time/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techandmortals.wordpress.com/2018/01/27/kaggle-learn-review-there-is-a-deep-learning-track-and-it-is-worth-your-time/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Right from my undergrad days when I was starting out with machine learning to this date, my admiration for &lt;a href=&quot;http://kaggle.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Kaggle&lt;/a&gt; continues to grow. In addition to being synonymous with and popularizing data science competitions, the platform has served as a launching pad and breeding ground for countless data science and machine learning practitioners around the world, including yours truly. In fact, skills I’d picked up from the platform are part of the reason that I recently got to join &lt;a href=&quot;https://socialcops.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;SocialCops&lt;/a&gt;, a company I’d admired for years. However, I hadn’t been on the platform in 2017 as much as I would have liked. So when I saw &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kaggle.com/benhamner&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Ben Hamner&lt;/a&gt;‘s tweet launching &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kaggle.com/learn&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Kaggle Learn&lt;/a&gt;, a set of interactive data science tutorials, I made up my mind to give it a shot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Zeroing in on deep learning&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn currently hosts tutorials about 4 topics – introductory machine learning, R programming, data visualisation and deep learning. I’d stumbled across machine learning for the first time in the form of neural networks (NN) more than 3 years back. Since then, I’d studied the theoretical details of NN at various points of time but somewhat ironically, I’d never got into practical deep learning except for a few tutorials. Hence, I decided to get started with the deep learning track.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The reason I mentioned my past experience with ML and NN was to point out the fact that I was not a complete beginner when I had gotten started with this track and if you are, start with the machine learning track instead.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Getting started&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are unfamiliar with neural networks or haven’t come across them recently, it would be a good idea to get some theoretical foundation before starting with hands-on tutorials. There are a number of introductory resources out there, both text and video. I used an excellent video by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCYO_jab_esuFRV4b17AJtAw/featured&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;3Blue1Brown&lt;/a&gt;, a YouTube channel, as a refresher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;jetpack-video-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;embed-youtube&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe class=&quot;youtube-player&quot; type=&quot;text/html&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height=&quot;435&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/aircAruvnKk?version=3&amp;amp;rel=1&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;autohide=2&amp;amp;showsearch=0&amp;amp;showinfo=1&amp;amp;iv_load_policy=1&amp;amp;wmode=transparent&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Choice of framework&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The track uses the high-level &lt;a href=&quot;https://keras.io/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Keras&lt;/a&gt; API and a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tensorflow.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Tensorflow&lt;/a&gt; backend. Even with numerous frameworks out there, this combination seems to find favor as a beginner-friendly choice among a large portion of the deep learning community. Personally, I admire Keras for being well-designed, user-friendly and playing a big role in democratizing access to deep learning methods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The track&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The deep learning track is currently comprised of six sections. They are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intro to Deep Learning and Computer Vision&lt;/strong&gt;: Starting off with a computer vision example is a great way to get acquainted with machine learning. This is the application which had put deep learning in the limelight and the data (images) is something most of us deal with on an everyday basis. The accompanying exercise allows you to play around with basic &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Convolution&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;convolutions&lt;/a&gt; and images.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Building Models from Convolutions&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Convolutional_neural_network&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Convolutional neural networks&lt;/a&gt; (ConvNet) have received wide praise and coverage for being extremely successful with image recognition tasks. The basics of ConvNets are discussed and the stage is set up for their implementation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Programming in Tensorflow and Keras&lt;/strong&gt;: You get to see TF+Keras in action for the first time and you’ll be amazed at the ease with which you can get up and running. There’s a lot of hand-holding here so getting the code to work alone won’t be very useful. Try to understand the code, including helper functions, as much as possible.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Related – &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fast.ai/2017/01/03/keras/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Big deep learning news: Tensorflow chooses Keras&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Transfer Learning&lt;/strong&gt;: It was a great decision by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kaggle.com/dansbecker&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Dan Becker&lt;/a&gt; to include this, and it is my favorite part of the tutorial. Prior to this, my perception of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Transfer_learning&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;transfer learning&lt;/a&gt; was as an advanced topic which would require a decent amount of know-how to even get started. I am delighted to tell you that that I couldn’t have been more wrong. Even if all you know are the very basics of NN, the idea of transfer learning itself is fascinating and I’ve decided to spend some time in near future to research about the topic. Prior to starting this section, I’d gone through the following video by the one and only Andrew Ng.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;jetpack-video-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;embed-youtube&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe class=&quot;youtube-player&quot; type=&quot;text/html&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height=&quot;435&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/yofjFQddwHE?version=3&amp;amp;rel=1&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;autohide=2&amp;amp;showsearch=0&amp;amp;showinfo=1&amp;amp;iv_load_policy=1&amp;amp;wmode=transparent&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion and additional resources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When learning a new topic, I’ve always found it best to start with a high-level overview. That’s precisely what this track aims to offer and for most part, delivers. For a considerable amount of time, setting up deep learning frameworks used to be a roadblock to getting started with the topic. To that end, Kaggle leverages its platform’s capabilities to host the code and while doing so, showcases its potential for being useful for collaboration. All that being said, this topic only scratches the surface, even if in a better manner than most tutorials out there. You can plan out your path from here on. If it helps, below are some of the resources I plan to dive into or explore over the next few weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If there’s any other useful resource you can think of, feel free to mention it in the comments below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you read and liked the article, sharing it would be a good next step.&lt;br/&gt;Additionally, you can check out some of my open source projects on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/analyticalmonk&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br/&gt;Drop me a &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:akashtndn.acm@gmail.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;mail&lt;/a&gt;, or hit me up on &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/AkashTandon&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/akashtandon/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt; in case you want to get in touch.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;wpcnt&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wpa wpmrec&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;wpa-about&quot;&gt;Advertisements&lt;/span&gt;



&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;jp-post-flair&quot; class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-like-enabled sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;robots-nocontent sd-block sd-social sd-social-icon-text sd-sharing&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Share this:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-block sd-like jetpack-likes-widget-wrapper jetpack-likes-widget-unloaded&quot; id=&quot;like-post-wrapper-91879015-1692-5a6ed4ddc727d&quot; data-src=&quot;//widgets.wp.com/likes/#blog_id=91879015&amp;amp;post_id=1692&amp;amp;origin=techandmortals.wordpress.com&amp;amp;obj_id=91879015-1692-5a6ed4ddc727d&quot; data-name=&quot;like-post-frame-91879015-1692-5a6ed4ddc727d&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Like this:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;likes-widget-placeholder post-likes-widget-placeholder&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;button&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Like&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;loading&quot;&gt;Loading...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2018 17:48:41 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>akashtndn</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Kaggle Learn review: there is a deep learning track and it is worth your time</og:title>
<og:url>https://techandmortals.wordpress.com/2018/01/27/kaggle-learn-review-there-is-a-deep-learning-track-and-it-is-worth-your-time/</og:url>
<og:description>Right from my undergrad days when I was starting out with machine learning to this date, my admiration for Kaggle continues to grow. In addition to being synonymous with and popularizing data scien…</og:description>
<og:image>http://img.youtube.com/vi/aircAruvnKk/0.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techandmortals.wordpress.com/2018/01/27/kaggle-learn-review-there-is-a-deep-learning-track-and-it-is-worth-your-time/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Follower Factory</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2018/01/27/technology/social-media-bots.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2018/01/27/technology/social-media-bots.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;g-lead-in&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;T&lt;/span&gt;he real Jessica Rychly&lt;/span&gt; is a Minnesota teenager with a broad smile and wavy hair. She likes reading and the rapper Post Malone. When she goes on Facebook or Twitter, she sometimes muses about being bored or trades jokes with friends. Occasionally, like many teenagers, she posts a duck-face selfie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;But on Twitter, there is a version of Jessica that none of her friends or family would recognize. While the two Jessicas share a name, photograph and whimsical bio — “I have issues” — the other Jessica promoted accounts hawking Canadian real estate investments, cryptocurrency and a radio station in Ghana. The fake Jessica followed or retweeted accounts using Arabic and Indonesian, languages the real Jessica does not speak. While she was a 17-year-old high school senior, her fake counterpart frequently promoted graphic pornography, retweeting accounts called Squirtamania and Porno Dan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;All these accounts belong to customers of an obscure American company named Devumi that has collected millions of dollars in a shadowy global marketplace for social media fraud. Devumi sells Twitter followers and retweets to celebrities, businesses and anyone who wants to appear more popular or exert influence online. Drawing on an estimated stock of at least 3.5 million automated accounts, each sold many times over, the company has provided customers with more than 200 million Twitter followers, a New York Times investigation found.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;The accounts that most resemble real people, like Ms. Rychly, reveal a kind of large-scale social identity theft. At least 55,000 of the accounts use the names, profile pictures, hometowns and other personal details of real Twitter users, including minors, according to a Times data analysis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;“I don’t want my picture connected to the account, nor my name,” Ms. Rychly, now 19, said. “I can’t believe that someone would even pay for it. It is just horrible.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;These accounts are counterfeit coins in the booming economy of online influence, reaching into virtually any industry where a mass audience — or the illusion of it — can be monetized. Fake accounts, deployed by governments, criminals and entrepreneurs, now infest social media networks. By &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/2017/03/10/nearly-48-million-twitter-accounts-could-be-bots-says-study.html&quot;&gt;some calculations&lt;/a&gt;, as many as 48 million of Twitter’s reported active users — nearly 15 percent — are automated accounts designed to simulate real people, though the company claims that number is far lower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;In November, Facebook disclosed to investors that it had at least twice as many fake users as it previously estimated, indicating that up to 60 million automated accounts may roam the world’s largest social media platform. These fake accounts, known as bots, can help sway advertising audiences and reshape political debates. They can defraud businesses and ruin reputations. Yet their creation and sale fall into a legal gray zone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;“The continued viability of fraudulent accounts and interactions on social media platforms — and the professionalization of these fraudulent services — is an indication that there’s still much work to do,” said Senator Mark Warner, the Virginia Democrat and ranking member of the Senate Intelligence Committee, which has been investigating the spread of fake accounts on Facebook, Twitter and other platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;Despite rising criticism of social media companies and growing scrutiny by elected officials, the trade in fake followers has remained largely opaque. While Twitter and other platforms prohibit buying followers, Devumi and dozens of other sites openly sell them. And social media companies, whose market value is closely tied to the number of people using their services, make their own rules about detecting and eliminating fake accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;Devumi’s founder, German Calas, denied that his company sold fake followers and said he knew nothing about social identities stolen from real users. “The allegations are false, and we do not have knowledge of any such activity,” Mr. Calas said in an email exchange in November.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;The Times reviewed business and court records showing that Devumi has more than 200,000 customers, including reality television stars, professional athletes, comedians, TED speakers, pastors and models. In most cases, the records show, they purchased their own followers. In others, their employees, agents, public relations companies, family members or friends did the buying. For just pennies each — sometimes even less — Devumi offers Twitter followers, views on YouTube, plays on SoundCloud, the music-hosting site, and endorsements on LinkedIn, the professional-networking site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;The actor John Leguizamo has Devumi followers. So do Michael Dell, the computer billionaire, and Ray Lewis, the football commentator and former Ravens linebacker. Kathy Ireland, the onetime swimsuit model who today presides over a half-billion-dollar licensing empire, has hundreds of thousands of fake Devumi followers, as does Akbar Gbajabiamila, the host of the show “American Ninja Warrior.” Even a Twitter board member, Martha Lane Fox, has some.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;At a time when Facebook, Twitter and Google are grappling with an epidemic of political manipulation and fake news, Devumi’s fake followers also serve as phantom foot soldiers in political battles online. Devumi’s customers include both avid supporters and fervent critics of President Trump, and both liberal cable pundits and a reporter at the alt-right bastion Breitbart. Randy Bryce, an ironworker seeking to unseat Representative Paul Ryan of Wisconsin, purchased Devumi followers in 2015, when he was a blogger and labor activist. Louise Linton, the wife of the Treasury secretary, Steven Mnuchin, bought followers when she was trying to gain traction as an actress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;Devumi’s products serve politicians and governments overseas, too. An editor at China’s state-run news agency, Xinhua, paid Devumi for hundreds of thousands of followers and retweets on Twitter, which the country’s government has banned but sees as a forum for issuing propaganda abroad. An adviser to Ecuador’s president, Lenín Moreno, bought tens of thousands of followers and retweets for Mr. Moreno’s campaign accounts during last year’s elections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;Kristin Binns, a Twitter spokeswoman, said the company did not typically suspend users suspected of buying bots, in part because it is difficult for the business to know who is responsible for any given purchase. Twitter would not say whether a sample of fake accounts provided by The Times — each based on a real user — violated the company’s policies against impersonation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;“We continue to fight hard to tackle any malicious automation on our platform as well as false or spam accounts,” Ms. Binns said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;Unlike some social media companies, Twitter does not require accounts to be associated with a real person. It also permits more automated access to its platform than other companies, making it easier to set up and control large numbers of accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;g-interactive jumbo&quot; id=&quot;interactive-00bots-code&quot; data-id=&quot;100000005581503&quot; data-slug=&quot;00bots-code&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;g-interactive-wrapper&quot; readability=&quot;13&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;interactive-headline&quot;&gt;Three Types of Twitter Bots&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;interactive-summary&quot;&gt;Tweets from a Twitter bot look just like those of a normal user, but a bot’s tweets are generated by a computer program, rather than a person. Below are three examples of common bot types you might encounter on Twitter and an approximation of the code controls them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;By Richard Harris and Danny DeBelius&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;“Social media is a virtual world that is filled with half bots, half real people,” said Rami Essaid, the founder of Distil Networks, a cybersecurity company that specializes in eradicating bot networks. “You can’t take any tweet at face value. And not everything is what it seems.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;Including, it turns out, Devumi itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;Last year, three billion people logged on to social media networks like Facebook, WhatsApp and China’s Sina Weibo. The world’s collective yearning for connection has not only reshaped the Fortune 500 and upended the advertising industry but also created a new status marker: the number of people who follow, like or “friend” you. For some entertainers and entrepreneurs, this virtual status is a real-world currency. Follower counts on social networks help determine who will hire them, how much they are paid for bookings or endorsements, even how potential customers evaluate their businesses or products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;High follower counts are also critical for so-called influencers, a budding market of amateur tastemakers and YouTube stars where advertisers now lavish billions of dollars a year on sponsorship deals. The more people influencers reach, the more money they make. According to data collected by Captiv8, a company that connects influencers to brands, an influencer with 100,000 followers might earn an average of $2,000 for a promotional tweet, while an influencer with a million followers might earn $20,000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;Genuine fame often translates into genuine social media influence, as fans follow and like their favorite movie stars, celebrity chefs and models. But shortcuts are also available: On sites like Social Envy and DIYLikes.com, it takes little more than a credit-card number to buy a huge following on almost any social media platform. Most of these sites offer what they describe as “active” or “organic” followers, never quite stating whether real people are behind them. Once purchased, the followers can be a powerful tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;“You see a higher follower count, or a higher retweet count, and you assume this person is important, or this tweet was well received,” said Rand Fishkin, the founder of Moz, a company that makes search engine optimization software. “As a result, you might be more likely to amplify it, to share it or to follow that person.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;Twitter and Facebook can be similarly influenced. “Social platforms are trying to recommend stuff — and they say, ‘Is the stuff we are recommending popular?’” said Julian Tempelsman, the co-founder of Smyte, a security firm that helps companies combat online abuse, bots and fraud. “Follower counts are one of the factors social media platforms use.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;Search on Google for how to buy more followers, and Devumi often turns up among the first results. Visitors are greeted by a polished website listing a Manhattan address, displaying testimonials from customers and a money-back guarantee. Best of all, Devumi claims, the company’s products are blessed by the platform for which they are selling followers. “We only use promotion techniques that are Twitter approved so your account is never at risk of getting suspended or penalized,” Devumi’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://devumi.com/twitter-followers/&quot;&gt;website promises&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;To better understand Devumi’s business, we became a customer. In April, The Times set up a test account on Twitter and paid Devumi $225 for 25,000 followers, or about a penny each. As advertised, the first 10,000 or so looked like real people. They had pictures and full names, hometowns and often authentic-seeming biographies. One account looked like that of Ms. Rychly, the young Minnesota woman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;But on closer inspection, some of the details seemed off. The account names had extra letters or underscores, or easy-to-miss substitutions, like a lowercase “L” in place of an uppercase “I.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;g-interactive jumbo&quot; id=&quot;interactive-00bots-bizarro&quot; data-id=&quot;100000005581502&quot; data-slug=&quot;00bots-bizarro&quot; readability=&quot;8.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;g-interactive-wrapper&quot; readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;interactive-headline&quot;&gt;How to Spot a Devumi Bot&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;interactive-summary&quot;&gt;Devumi claims to use its own “private network of hand-picked real and active Twitter users and influencers”. In reality, it sells bots with stolen profiles. Here are the details that give them away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;By Richard Harris and Danny DeBelius&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;The next 15,000 followers from Devumi were more obviously suspect: no profile pictures, and jumbles of letters, numbers and word fragments instead of names.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;In August, a Times reporter emailed Mr. Calas, asking if he would answer questions about Devumi. Mr. Calas did not respond. Twitter &lt;a href=&quot;https://help.twitter.com/en/safety-and-security/fake-twitter-followers-and-interactions&quot;&gt;forbids&lt;/a&gt; selling or buying followers or retweets, and Devumi promises customers absolute discretion. “Your info is always kept confidential,” the company’s website reads. “Our followers look like any other followers and are always delivered naturally. The only way anyone will know is if you tell them.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;But company records reviewed by The Times revealed much of what Devumi and its customers prefer to conceal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;Most of Devumi’s best-known buyers are selling products, services or themselves on social media. In interviews, their explanations varied. They bought followers because they were curious about how it worked, or felt pressure to generate high follower counts for themselves or their customers. “Everyone does it,” said the actress Deirdre Lovejoy, a Devumi customer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;While some said they believed Devumi was supplying real potential fans or customers, others acknowledged that they knew or suspected they were getting fake accounts. Several said they regretted their purchases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;“It’s fraud,” said James Cracknell, a British rower and Olympic gold medalist who bought 50,000 followers from Devumi. “People who judge by how many likes or how many followers, it’s not a healthy thing.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;Ms. Ireland has over a million followers on Twitter, which she often uses to promote companies with whom she has endorsement deals. The Wisconsin-based American Family Insurance, for example, said that the former model was one of its most influential Twitter “brand ambassadors,” celebrities who are paid to help promote products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;But in January last year, Ms. Ireland had only about 160,000 followers. The next month, an employee at the branding agency she owns, Sterling/Winters, spent about $2,000 for 300,000 more followers, according to Devumi records. The employee later made more purchases, he acknowledged in an interview. Much of Ms. Ireland’s Twitter following appears to consist of bots, a Times analysis found.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;A spokeswoman said that the employee had acted without Ms. Ireland’s authorization and had been suspended after The Times asked about the purchases. “I’m sure he thought he was fulfilling his duties, but it’s not something he should have done,” said the spokeswoman, Rona Menashe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;Similarly, Ms. Lane Fox, a British e-commerce pioneer, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.parliament.uk/biographies/lords/baroness-lane-fox-of-soho/4275&quot;&gt;member of Parliament&lt;/a&gt; and Twitter board member, blamed a “rogue employee” for a series of follower purchases spanning more than a year. She declined to name the person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;Several Devumi customers or their representatives contacted by The Times declined to comment, among them Mr. Leguizamo, whose followers were bought by an associate. Many more did not respond to repeated efforts to contact them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;A few denied making Devumi purchases. They include Ashley Knight, Mr. Lewis’s personal assistant, whose email address was listed on an order for 250,000 followers, and Eric Kaplan, a friend to Mr. Trump and motivational speaker whose personal email address was associated with eight orders. A Twitter account belonging to Paul Hollywood, the celebrity baker, was deleted after The Times emailed him with questions. Mr. Hollywood then sent a reply: “Account does not exist.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;g-interactive jumbo&quot; id=&quot;interactive-00bots-clients&quot; data-id=&quot;100000005599227&quot; data-slug=&quot;00bots-clients&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;g-interactive-wrapper&quot; readability=&quot;17&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;interactive-headline&quot;&gt;Devumi’s Web&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;interactive-summary&quot;&gt;Many of these celebrities, business leaders, sports stars and other Twitter users bought their own followers, records show. In other cases, the purchases were made by their employees, agents, family members or other associates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;By Richard Harris and Danny DeBelius&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;Over two years, the Democratic public relations consultant and CNN contributor Hilary Rosen bought more than a half-million fake followers from Devumi. Ms. Rosen previously spent more than a decade as head of the Recording Industry Association of America. In an interview, she described the purchases as “an experiment I did several years ago to see how it worked.” She made more than a dozen purchases of followers from 2015 to 2017, according to company records.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;Other buyers said they had faced pressure from employers to generate social media followers. Marcus Holmlund, a young freelance writer, was at first thrilled when Wilhelmina, the international modeling agency, hired him to manage its social media efforts. But when Wilhelmina’s Twitter following didn’t grow fast enough, Mr. Holmlund said, a supervisor told him to buy followers or find another job. In 2015, despite misgivings, he began making monthly Devumi purchases out of his own pocket.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;“I felt stuck with the threat of being fired, or worse, never working in fashion again,” said Mr. Holmlund, who left in late 2015. “Since then, I tell anyone and everyone who ever asks that it’s a total scam — it won’t boost their engagement.” (A Wilhelmina spokeswoman declined to comment.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;Several Devumi customers acknowledged that they bought bots because their careers had come to depend, in part, on the appearance of social media influence. “No one will take you seriously if you don’t have a noteworthy presence,” said Jason Schenker, an economist who specializes in economic forecasting and has purchased at least 260,000 followers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;Not surprisingly, Devumi has sold millions of followers and retweets to entertainers on the lower and middle rungs of Hollywood, such as the actor Ryan Hurst, a star of the television series “Sons of Anarchy.” In 2016 and 2017, he bought a total of 750,000 followers, about three-quarters of his current count. It cost less than $4,000, according to company records. Mr. Hurst did not respond to multiple requests for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;Devumi also sells bots to reality television stars, who can parlay fame into endorsement and appearance fees. Sonja Morgan, a cast member on the Bravo show “The Real Housewives of New York City,” uses her Devumi-boosted Twitter feed to promote her fashion line, a shopping app and a website that sells personalized “video shout-outs.” One former “American Idol” contestant, Clay Aiken, even paid Devumi to spread a grievance: his &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/clayaiken/status/631273740991635460&quot;&gt;customer service complaint against Volvo&lt;/a&gt;. Devumi bots retweeted his complaint 5,000 times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;Mr. Aiken and Ms. Morgan did not respond to requests for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;More than a hundred self-described influencers — whose market value is even more directly linked to their follower counts on social media — have purchased Twitter followers from Devumi. Justin Blau, a popular Las Vegas-based D.J. who performs as 3LAU, acquired 50,000 followers and thousands of retweets. In an email, Mr. Blau said a former member of his management team bought them without his approval.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;At least five Devumi influencer customers are also contractors for HelloSociety, an influencer agency owned by The New York Times Company. (A Times spokeswoman said the company sought to verify that the audience of each contractor was legitimate and would not do business with anyone who violated that standard.) Lucas Peterson, a freelance journalist who writes a travel column for The Times, also bought followers from Devumi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;Influencers need not be well known to rake in endorsement money. According to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thesun.co.uk/fabulous/5030582/aspiring-child-youtubers-callum-ryan-erin-bradley-arabella-daho/&quot;&gt;recent profile&lt;/a&gt; in the British tabloid The Sun, two young siblings, Arabella and Jaadin Daho, earn a combined $100,000 a year as influencers, working with brands such as Amazon, Disney, Louis Vuitton and Nintendo. Arabella, who is 14, tweets under the name Amazing Arabella.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;But her Twitter account — and her brother’s — are boosted by thousands of retweets purchased by their mother and manager, Shadia Daho, according to Devumi records. Ms. Daho did not respond to repeated attempts to reach her by email and through a public relations firm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;While Devumi sells millions of followers directly to celebrities and influencers, its customers also include marketing and public relations agencies, which buy followers for their own customers. Phil Pallen, a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/philpallen&quot;&gt;brand strategist&lt;/a&gt; based in Los Angeles, &lt;a href=&quot;https://philpallen.co/branding/&quot;&gt;offers customers&lt;/a&gt; “growth &amp;amp; ad campaigns” on social media. At least a dozen times, company records show, Mr. Pallen has paid Devumi to deliver those results. Beginning in 2014, for example, he purchased tens of thousands of followers for Lori Greiner, the inventor and “Shark Tank” co-host.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;Mr. Pallen at first denied buying those followers. After The Times contacted Ms. Greiner, Mr. Pallen said he had “experimented” with the company but “stopped using it long ago.” A lawyer for Ms. Greiner said she had asked him to stop after learning of the first purchases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;Still, records show, Mr. Pallen bought Ms. Greiner more Devumi followers in 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;Marketing consultants sometimes buy followers for themselves, too, in effect purchasing the evidence of their supposed expertise. In 2015, Jeetendr Sehdev, a former adjunct professor at the University of Southern California who calls himself “the world’s leading celebrity branding authority,” began buying hundreds of thousands of fake followers from Devumi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;He did not respond to requests for comment. But in his recent best-selling book, “The Kim Kardashian Principle: Why Shameless Sells,” he had a different explanation for his rising follower count. “My social media following exploded,” Mr. Sehdev claimed, because he had discovered the true secret to celebrity influence: “Authenticity is the key.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;Among the followers delivered to Mr. Sehdev was Ms. Rychly — or at least, a copy of her. The fake Rychly account, created in 2014, was included in the purchase orders of hundreds of Devumi customers. It was retweeted by Mr. Schenker, the economist, and Arabella Daho, the teenage influencer. Clive Standen, star of the show “Taken,” ended up with Ms. Rychly’s stolen social identity. So did the television baker Mr. Hollywood, the French entertainer DJ Snake and Ms. Ireland. (DJ Snake’s followers were purchased by a former manager, and Mr. Standen did not respond to requests for comment.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;The fake Ms. Rychly also retweeted at least five accounts linked to a prolific American pornographer named Dan Leal, who is based in Hungary and tweets as @PornoDan. Mr. Leal, who has bought at least 150,000 followers from Devumi in recent years, is one of at least dozens of customers who work in the adult film industry or as escorts, according to a review of Devumi records.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;In an email, Mr. Leal said that buying followers for his business generated more than enough new revenue to pay for the expense. He was not worried about being penalized by Twitter, Mr. Leal said. “Countless public figures, companies, music acts, etc. purchase followers,” he wrote. “If Twitter was to purge everyone who did so there would be hardly any of them on it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;Devumi has sold at least tens of thousands of similar high-quality bots, a Times analysis found. In some cases, a single real Twitter user was transformed into hundreds of different bots, each a minute variation on the original.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;g-interactive jumbo&quot; id=&quot;interactive-00bots-flocks&quot; data-id=&quot;100000005589853&quot; data-slug=&quot;00bots-flocks&quot; readability=&quot;8.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;g-interactive-wrapper&quot; readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;interactive-headline&quot;&gt;Families of bots&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;interactive-summary&quot;&gt;Individually, fake accounts are hard to detect. Study their group behaviour, and incriminating patterns begin to emerge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;By Richard Harris and Mark Hansen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;These fake accounts borrowed social identities from Twitter users in every American state and dozens of countries, from adults and minors alike, from highly active users and those who hadn’t logged in to their accounts for months or years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;Sam Dodd, a college student &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCJh7aKCdVmwSZ31ZAC6ZYRA?view_as=subscriber&quot;&gt;and aspiring filmmaker&lt;/a&gt;, set up his Twitter account as a high school sophomore in Maryland. Before he even graduated, his Twitter details were copied onto a bot account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;The fake account remained dormant until last year, when it suddenly began retweeting Devumi customers continuously. This summer, the fake Mr. Dodd promoted various pornographic accounts, including Mr. Leal’s Immoral Productions, as well as a link to a gambling website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;“I don’t know why they’d take my identity — I’m a 20-year-old college student,” Mr. Dodd said. “I’m not well known.” But even unknown, Mr. Dodd’s social identity has value in the influence economy. At prices posted in December, Devumi was selling high-quality followers for under two cents each. Sold to about 2,000 customers — the rough number that many Devumi bot accounts follow — his social identity could bring Devumi around $30.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;The stolen social identities of Twitter users like Mr. Dodd are critical to Devumi’s brand. The high-quality bots are usually delivered to customers first, followed by millions of cheaper, low-quality bots, like sawdust mixed in with grated Parmesan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;Some of Devumi’s high-quality bots, in effect, replace an idle Twitter account — belonging to someone who stopped using the service — with a fake one. Whitney Wolfe, an executive assistant who lives in Florida, opened a Twitter account in 2008, when she was a wedding planner. By the time she stopped using it regularly in 2014, a fake account copying her personal information had been created. In recent months, it has retweeted adult film actresses, several influencers and an escort turned memoirist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;“The content — pictures of women in thongs, pictures of women’s chests — it’s not anything I want to be represented with my faith, my name, where I live,” said Ms. Wolfe, who is active in her local Southern Baptist congregation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;Other victims were still active on Twitter when Devumi-sold bots began impersonating them. Salle Ingle, a 40-year-old engineer who lives in Colorado, said she worried that a potential employer would come across the fake version of her while vetting her social media accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;“I’ve been applying for new jobs, and I’m really grateful that no one saw this account and thought it was me,” Ms. Ingle said. Once contacted by The Times, Ms. Ingle reported the account to Twitter, which deactivated it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;After emailing Mr. Calas last year, a Times reporter visited Devumi’s Manhattan address, listed on its website. The building has dozens of tenants, including a medical clinic and a labor union. But Devumi and its parent company, Bytion, do not appear to be among them. A spokesman for the building’s owner said neither Devumi nor Bytion had ever rented space there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;Like the followers Devumi sold, the office was an illusion.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;In real life, Devumi is based in a small office suite above a Mexican restaurant in West Palm Beach, Fla., overlooking an alley crowded with Dumpsters and parked cars. Mr. Calas lives a short commute away, in a penthouse apartment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;On &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/german-calas-bb181926/&quot;&gt;his LinkedIn profile&lt;/a&gt;, Mr. Calas is described as a “serial entrepreneur,” with a long record in the tech business and an advanced degree from the Massachusetts Institute of Technology. But Mr. Calas’s persona, too, is a mixture of fact and fantasy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;Mr. Calas, who is 27, grew up in South Florida, where as a teenager he learned web design and built sites for local businesses, according to earlier versions of his personal web page available on the Internet Archive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;Eventually he taught himself techniques for search engine optimization — the art of pushing a web page higher in search results. While in high school, he began taking classes at Palm Beach State College, where he earned an associate degree in 2012, according to a school spokeswoman. Within a few years, Mr. Calas was claiming to have built dozens of online businesses serving 10 million customers, now under the Bytion umbrella.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;“I started this company with a thousand dollars in the bank, without investors, and only the burning passion for success,” Mr. Calas wrote last year on the job-listing site Glassdoor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;As Mr. Calas’s ambitions grew, so did his embroidery. &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20140221071512/http://gcalas.com:80/#/resume&quot;&gt;A copy of his résumé&lt;/a&gt; posted online in 2014 claimed that he earned a physics degree from Princeton University in 2000, when he would have been about 10 years old, and a Ph.D. in computer science from M.I.T. Representatives for both schools said they had no record of Mr. Calas’s attending their institution. His current LinkedIn page says that he has a master’s degree in “international business” from M.I.T., a degree it does not offer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;According to former employees interviewed by The Times, turnover was high at Devumi, and Mr. Calas kept his operation tightly compartmentalized. Employees sometimes had little idea what their colleagues were doing, even if they were working on the same project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;The ex-employees asked for anonymity for fear of lawsuits or because they were subject to nondisclosure agreements with Mr. Calas’s companies. But their comments are echoed in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.glassdoor.com/Reviews/Bytion-Reviews-E1356490.htm&quot;&gt;reviews on Glassdoor&lt;/a&gt;, where some former employees said that Mr. Calas was uncommunicative and demanded that they install monitoring software on their personal devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;Dozens of Devumi’s customer service and order fulfillment personnel are based in the Philippines, according to company records. Employing overseas contractors may have helped Mr. Calas hold down costs. But it also appears to have left him vulnerable to a kind of social identity theft himself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;Last August, Mr. Calas sued Ronwaldo Boado, a Filipino contractor who previously worked for Devumi as an assistant customer support manager. After being fired for squabbling with other members of his team, Mr. Boado took control of a Devumi email account listing more than 170,000 customer orders, Mr. Calas alleged in court papers. Then Mr. Boado created a fake Devumi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;His copycat company used a similar name — DevumiBoost — and copied the design of Devumi’s website, Mr. Calas alleged. (Mr. Boado did not respond to emails seeking a response to Mr. Calas’s claims.) The fake Devumi even listed the same phantom Manhattan address. Over a stretch of days last July, Mr. Boado, posing as a Devumi employee, emailed hundreds of Devumi customers to inform them that their orders needed to be reprocessed on DevumiBoost. Then he impersonated the customers, too, emailing Devumi under different aliases to ask that Devumi cancel the original orders. Mr. Boado, according to Mr. Calas, was trying to steal his customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;Mr. Calas’s lawsuit also revealed something else: Devumi doesn’t appear to make its own bots. Instead, the company buys them wholesale — from a thriving global market of fake social media accounts.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;Scattered around the web is an array of obscure websites where anonymous bot makers around the world connect with retailers like Devumi. While individual customers can buy from some of these bare-boned sites — Peakerr, CheapPanel and YTbot, among others — they are less user-friendly. Some, for example, do not accept credit cards, only cryptocurrencies like Bitcoin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;But each site sells followers, likes and shares in bulk, for a variety of social media platforms and in different languages. The accounts they sell may change hands repeatedly. The same account may even be available from more than one seller.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;Devumi, according to one former employee, sourced bots from different bot makers depending on price, quality and reliability. On Peakerr, for example, 1,000 high-quality, English-language bots with photos costs a little more than a dollar. Devumi charges $17 for the same quantity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;The price difference has allowed Mr. Calas to build a small fortune, according to company records. In just a few years, Devumi sold about 200 million Twitter followers to at least 39,000 customers, accounting for a third of more than $6 million in sales during that period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;Last month, Mr. Calas asked for examples of bots The Times found that copied real users. After receiving the names of 10 accounts, Mr. Calas, who had agreed to an interview, asked for more time to analyze them. Then he stopped responding to emails.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;Ms. Binns, the Twitter spokeswoman, said the company did not proactively review accounts to see if they were impersonating other users. Instead, the company’s efforts are focused on identifying and suspending accounts that violate Twitter’s spam policies. In December, for example, the company identified an average of 6.4 million suspicious accounts each week, she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;All of the sample accounts provided by The Times violated Twitter’s anti-spam policies and were shut down, Ms. Binns said. “We take the action of suspending an account from the platform very seriously,” she said. “At the same time, we want to aggressively fight spam on the platform.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;The company also suspended Devumi’s account on Saturday after the Times article was published online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;Yet Twitter has not imposed seemingly simple safeguards that would help throttle bot manufacturers, such as requiring anyone signing up for a new account to pass an anti-spam test, as many commercial sites do. As a result, Twitter now hosts vast swaths of unused accounts, including what are probably dormant accounts controlled by bot makers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;Former employees said the company’s security team for many years was more focused on abuse by real users, including racist and sexist content and orchestrated harassment campaigns. Only recently, they said, after revelations that Russia-aligned hackers had deployed networks of Twitter bots to spread divisive content and junk news, has Twitter turned more attention to weeding out fake accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;Leslie Miley, an engineer who worked on security and user safety at Twitter before leaving in late 2015, said, “Twitter as a social network was designed with almost no accountability.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;Some critics believe Twitter has a business incentive against weeding out bots too aggressively. Over the past two years, the company has struggled to generate the user growth seen by rivals like Facebook and Snapchat. And outside researchers have disputed the company’s estimates for how many of its active users are actually bots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;g-interactive jumbo&quot; id=&quot;interactive-00bots-twitter&quot; data-id=&quot;100000005581504&quot; data-slug=&quot;00bots-twitter&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;g-interactive-wrapper&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;interactive-headline&quot;&gt;The Evolution of Twitter’s Timeline&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;interactive-summary&quot;&gt;Small design changes over a number of years has placed an increasingly greater focus on user engagement with replies, retweets and likes in Twitter’s timeline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;By Richard Harris and Danny DeBelius&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;“We’re working with completely unregulated, closed ecosystems that aren’t reporting on these things. They have a perverse incentive to let it happen,” said Mr. Essaid, the cybersecurity expert. “They want to police it to the extent it doesn’t seem obvious, but they make money off it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;In January, after almost two years of promoting hundreds of Devumi customers, the fake Jessica Rychly account was finally flagged by Twitter’s security algorithms. It was recently suspended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;But the real Ms. Rychly may soon leave Twitter for good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;“I am probably just going to delete my Twitter account,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2018 16:34:09 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>gregkerzhner</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2018/01/27/technology/social-media-bots.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>The Follower Factory</og:title>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/01/28/technology/28bots-promo/28bots-promo-facebookJumbo-v2.png</og:image>
<og:description>Everyone wants to be popular online. Some even pay for it. Inside social media’s black market.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2018/01/27/technology/social-media-bots.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>