<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Infinite procedurally-generated city with the Wave Function Collapse algorithm</title>
<link>https://marian42.itch.io/wfc</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://marian42.itch.io/wfc</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;An infinite, procedurally generated city, assembled out of blocks using the Wave Function Collapse algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, there is no gameplay, you can only walk around and look at the scenery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Controls: WASD for walking, Shift to run, Ctrl to jetpack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Xbox controller: Left Stick for walking, right stick for looking around, A to jump, LB to run, RB to jetpack&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flight mode: Use M to toggle between flight mode and normal mode. In flight mode, you fly across the world, without any controls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mxgmn/WaveFunctionCollapse&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;Read more about the WFC algorithm here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Source code: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/marian42/wavefunctioncollapse&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://github.com/marian42/wavefunctioncollapse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 18:21:46 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>guessmyname</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://img.itch.zone/aW1nLzE1OTQwMTIucG5n/original/JccxLG.png</og:image>
<og:description>Walk through an infinite, procedurally generated city</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://marian42.itch.io/wfc</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Amazon’s HQ2 Spectacle Should Be Illegal</title>
<link>https://www.theatlantic.com/article/575539/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.theatlantic.com/article/575539/</guid>
<description>&lt;section class=&quot;l-article__section s-cms-content&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot; id=&quot;article-section-0&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Amazon HQ2 saga had all the hallmarks of the gaudiest reality TV. It was an absurd spectacle, concluding with a plot twist, which revealed a deep and dark truth about the modern world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fourteen months ago, Amazon announced a national beauty contest, in which North American cities could apply to win the honor of landing the retailer’s second headquarters. The prize: 50,000 employees and the glory of housing an international tech giant. The cost? Just several billion dollars in tax incentives and a potential face-lift to the host city. Then last week, in a classic late-episode shock, several news outlets reported that Amazon would split its second headquarters between Crystal City, a suburban neighborhood near Washington, D.C., and Long Island City, in Queens, New York.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rumored announcement has emboldened Amazon’s army of critics. Did the world’s smartest company really need 13 months, and applications from &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://jacobinmag.com/2018/02/amazon-corporate-headquarters-tax-breaks&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'0',r'None'&quot;&gt;238 cities&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, to reach the striking conclusion that it should invest in New York and D.C.?  The former is America’s heart of capital, and the latter is America’s literal capital, where Jeff Bezos, chief executive of Amazon, already owns a house and a newspaper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;c-recirculation-link&quot; data-id=&quot;injected-recirculation-link&quot; id=&quot;injected-recirculation-link-0&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2018/11/amazon-washington-new-york-headquarters/575281/&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'1',r'None'&quot;&gt;Annie Lowrey: Amazon was never going to choose Detroit.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section class=&quot;l-article__section s-cms-content&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot; id=&quot;article-section-1&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Was this national auction nothing more than a scripted drama to raise the value of the inevitable winning bid? And did the retailer miss an opportunity to revitalize a midwestern city by choosing to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2018/11/amazon-washington-new-york-headquarters/575281/&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'2',r'None'&quot;&gt;enrich the already-rich East Coast&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All good questions. But here’s the big one: Why the hell are U.S. cities spending tens of billions of dollars to steal jobs from one another in the first place?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;c-section-divider&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every year, American cities and states spend &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.brookings.edu/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/report_examining-the-local-value-of-economic-development-incentives_brookings-metro_march-2018.pdf&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'3',r'None'&quot;&gt;up to $90 billion&lt;/a&gt; in tax breaks and cash grants to urge companies to move among states. That’s more than the federal government spends on housing, education, or infrastructure. And since cities and states can’t print money or run steep deficits, these deals take scarce resources from everything local governments would otherwise pay for, such as schools, roads, police, and prisons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/wonk/wp/2014/09/15/should-we-ban-states-and-cities-from-offering-big-tax-breaks-for-jobs/?utm_term=.6346c2b91f55&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'4',r'None'&quot;&gt;past 10 years&lt;/a&gt;, Boeing, Nike, Intel, Royal Dutch Shell, Tesla, Nissan, Ford, and General Motors have each received subsidy packages worth more than $1 billion to either move their corporate headquarters within the U.S. or, quite often, to keep their headquarters right where they are. New Jersey and Maryland reportedly offered $7 billion for HQ2, which would be &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/amazon-headquarters-hq2-new-jersey-economic-incentive-2017-10&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'5',r'None'&quot;&gt;the biggest corporate giveaway in American history&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might think, &lt;em&gt;Don’t blame the companies&lt;/em&gt;. These businesses have a fiduciary obligation to make money, and it’s negligent to leave cash piles on the table while their competitors are raking it in. And you might even think, &lt;em&gt;Don’t blame the local governments&lt;/em&gt;. Not bidding on an exciting new project feels akin to unilateral disarmament in a war for talent and business. Sometimes a big new firm can revitalize a downtown area and become a magnet for new firms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-recirculation-link&quot; data-id=&quot;injected-recirculation-link&quot; id=&quot;injected-recirculation-link-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2018/06/amazon-flex-workers/563444/&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'6',r'None'&quot;&gt;Read: I delivered packages for Amazon and it was a nightmare.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there are three major problems with America’s system of corporate giveaways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, they’re redundant. One recent &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.natemjensen.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/Kansas-Working-Paper-7-23-15.pdf&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'7',r'None'&quot;&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; by Nathan Jensen, then an economist at George Washington University, found that these incentives “have no discernible impact on firm expansion, measured by job creation.” Companies often decide where they want to go and then find ways to get their dream city, or hometown, to pay them to do what they were going to do anyway. For example, Amazon is a multinational company with large media and advertising divisions. The drama of the past 13 months probably wasn’t crucial to its (probable) decision to expand to New York City, the unambiguous capital of media and advertising.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, companies don’t always hold up their end of the deal. Consider the saga of Wisconsin and the Chinese manufacturing giant Foxconn. Several years ago, Wisconsin Governor Scott Walker lured Foxconn with a subsidy plan totaling more than $3 billion. (For the same amount, you could give every household in Wisconsin &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2018/10/29/18027032/foxconn-wisconsin-plant-jobs-deal-subsidy-governor-scott-walker&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'8',r'None'&quot;&gt;about $1,700&lt;/a&gt;.) Foxconn said it would build a large manufacturing plant that would create about 13,000  jobs near Racine. Now it seems the company is building a much smaller factory with just one quarter of its initial promised investment, and much of the assembly work may be done by robots. Meanwhile, the expected value of Wisconsin’s subsidy has grown to more than $4 billion. Thus a state &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/answer-sheet/wp/2018/07/03/a-new-public-education-movement-is-emerging-in-wisconsin-a-rebuke-to-gov-walkers-war-on-labor-and-school-privatization/?utm_term=.5de93532b373&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'9',r'None'&quot;&gt;with declining wages for many public-school teachers&lt;/a&gt; could wind up paying more than $500,000 per net new Foxconn job—about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.americanprogressaction.org/issues/economy/reports/2017/11/15/169146/attacks-public-sector-unions-harm-states-act-10-affected-education-wisconsin/&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'10',r'None'&quot;&gt;10 times the average salary&lt;/a&gt; of a Wisconsin teacher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section class=&quot;l-article__section s-cms-content&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot; id=&quot;article-section-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Third, even when the incentives aren’t redundant, and even when companies do hold up their end of the bargain, it’s still ludicrous for Americans to collectively pay tens of billions of dollars for huge corporations to relocate &lt;em&gt;within the United States&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No story illuminates this absurdity more than the so-called Border War, in which the Kansas and Missouri sides of Kansas City have spent zillions of dollars dragging companies back and forth across state lines, within the same metro area. Several years ago, Kansas lured AMC Entertainment with tens of millions of dollars in incentives. Then Missouri responded by stealing Applebee’s headquarters from Kansas with another incentive package. Back and forth they went, until both states had spent half a billion dollars creating no net new jobs but changing the commutes of 10,000 Kansas City workers who got caught up in an interstate duel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;c-section-divider&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We need a national truce, both within states and between states,” said Amy Liu, the director of the Metropolitan Policy Program at the Brookings Institution. “There should be no more poaching of private companies with public funds.” But how would the United States ban states and local governments from poaching jobs from one another, or from giving tax dollars to private corporations?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, Congress could pass a national law banning this sort of corporate bribery. Mark Funkhouser, a former mayor of Kansas City, Missouri, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/wonk/wp/2014/09/15/should-we-ban-states-and-cities-from-offering-big-tax-breaks-for-jobs/?utm_term=.6346c2b91f55&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'11',r'None'&quot;&gt;envisions&lt;/a&gt; the law as the domestic version of the Foreign Corrupt Practices Act, which makes it illegal for Americans to bribe foreign officials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-recirculation-link&quot; data-id=&quot;injected-recirculation-link&quot; id=&quot;injected-recirculation-link-2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/business/archive/2017/09/sears-predicts-amazon/540888/&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'12',r'None'&quot;&gt;Read: The history of Sears predicts nearly everything Amazon is doing.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not entirely clear whether that would pass constitutional muster. The Supreme Court hasn’t ruled decisively on whether the Commerce Clause gives Washington the authority to ban interstate bidding wars. In the 2006 Supreme Court case &lt;em&gt;DaimlerChrysler Corp. v. Cuno&lt;/em&gt;, Ohio taxpayers sued the state after it paid the automaker DaimlerChrysler about $280 million in tax exemptions and tax credits. The Sixth Circuit Court sided with the taxpayers, striking down Ohio’s subsidy as a violation of the Commerce Clause. But the Supreme Court avoided a final judgment on the matter by finding unanimously that the plaintiffs &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oyez.org/cases/2005/04-1704&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'13',r'None'&quot;&gt;did not have standing to bring the suit&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, Congress could make corporate subsidies less valuable by threatening to tax state or local incentives as a special kind of income. “Congress should institute a federal tax of 100 percent” on corporate subsidies, Jack Markell, a former governor of Delaware, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/09/21/opinion/incentives-businesses-corporations-giveaways.html&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'14',r'None'&quot;&gt;wrote&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;. “This would not include investments in public infrastructure, work force development or other investments that can attract employers while also providing a significant long-term benefit to taxpayers.” Taxing subsidies would hopefully &lt;a href=&quot;https://hbr.org/2018/07/landing-amazon-hq2-isnt-the-right-way-for-a-city-to-create-jobs-heres-what-works-instead&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'15',r'None'&quot;&gt;force cities to change their economic-development strategies, from importing other states’ companies&lt;/a&gt; to building their own—through investing in research universities, building more housing, and welcoming immigrants, since foreign-born Americans &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apnews.com/ab44ff583d194070a5eae431231c4450&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'16',r'None'&quot;&gt;have the highest rates of entrepreneurship&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section class=&quot;l-article__section s-cms-content&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot; id=&quot;article-section-3&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally, the federal government could actively discourage the culture of corporate subsidies by yelling, screaming, and penny-pinching. As Meagan Day &lt;a href=&quot;https://jacobinmag.com/2018/02/amazon-corporate-headquarters-tax-breaks&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'17',r'None'&quot;&gt;wrote&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;Jacobin&lt;/em&gt;, “The federal government could withhold funds from governors and mayors who threaten to poach jobs from other states, or who won’t disclose their incentive packages.” Washington tends to look on quietly when cash-strapped states break the bank to welcome glitzy tech firms. But an attitude change at the top could trickle down to the local level. Donald Trump, or another president, could have made a national address after the HQ2 announcement slamming Amazon for soliciting taxpayer funds in a silent auction. He could have called a summit to encourage the nation’s mayors and governors to offer the same tax subsidy for HQ2—zero dollars and zero cents. Even a tweet could suffice: “7 BILLION FOR BEZOS?? Trillion-dollar companies in America don’t need our welfare! Bad!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But no one is yelling and screaming. Instead, in a starkly divided country, corporate pandering is the last bastion of bipartisanship, an activity enjoyed by both Democrats and Republicans at every level of government. New Jersey and Maryland, both blue states, insisted that Amazon take $7 billion in tax savings just months after congressional Republicans passed a corporate income-tax cut that some analysts project will save Amazon nearly $1 billion over the next decade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Corporate America is getting all the help it doesn’t need. You and I may not like it. But executives such as Jeff Bezos have no reason to care. They are winning by the rules of a broken game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;c-letters-cta&quot;&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;c-letters-cta__text&quot;&gt;We want to hear what you think about this article. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/contact/letters/&quot; class=&quot;c-letters-cta__link&quot;&gt;Submit a letter&lt;/a&gt; to the editor or write to letters@theatlantic.com.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;address id=&quot;article-writer-0&quot; class=&quot;c-article-writer lazyload&quot; data-author-id=&quot;1608&quot; data-include=&quot;css:https://cdn.theatlantic.com/assets/static/b/frontend/dist/theatlantic/css/components/article-writer.38f8b806e515.css&quot; itemprop=&quot;author&quot; itemtype=&quot;https://schema.org/Person&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot;/&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;c-article-writer__image&quot; itemprop=&quot;image&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/ImageObject&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot;&gt;


&lt;a class=&quot;o-media__object&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/author/derek-thompson/&quot; title=&quot;Derek Thompson's writer page&quot;&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;c-article-writer__img o-media__img&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn.theatlantic.com/assets/media/None/Derek_Thompson_grey/200.png?mod=1522336427&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; itemprop=&quot;contentUrl&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;c-article-writer__img o-media__img lazyload&quot; data-src=&quot;https://cdn.theatlantic.com/assets/media/None/Derek_Thompson_grey/200.png?mod=1522336427&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;c-article-writer__content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;c-article-writer__bio&quot; itemprop=&quot;description&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/author/derek-thompson/&quot; class=&quot;author-link&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;inherit&quot;&gt;Derek Thompson&lt;/a&gt; is a staff writer at &lt;em&gt;The Atlantic,&lt;/em&gt; where he writes about economics, labor markets, and the media. He is the author of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Hit-Makers-Science-Popularity-Distraction/dp/110198032X/ref=tmm_hrd_swatch_0?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=&amp;amp;sr=&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hit Makers&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 18:15:13 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>tysone</dc:creator>
<og:title>Amazon’s HQ2 Spectacle Isn’t Just Shameful—It Should Be Illegal</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2018/11/amazons-hq2-spectacle-should-be-illegal/575539/</og:url>
<og:image>https://cdn.theatlantic.com/assets/media/img/mt/2018/11/RTX6HE2A/facebook.jpg?1541802126</og:image>
<og:description>Each year, local governments spend nearly $100 billion to move headquarters and factories between states. It’s a wasteful exercise that requires a national solution.</og:description>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2018/11/amazons-hq2-spectacle-should-be-illegal/575539/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Redox – A Unix-Like Operating System Written in Rust</title>
<link>https://www.redox-os.org/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.redox-os.org/</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.redox-os.org/&quot;&gt;https://www.redox-os.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=18442390&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=18442390&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 258&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 118&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 16:46:15 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>wtetzner</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.redox-os.org/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>How to Keep Your Job as Your Company Grows</title>
<link>https://steveblank.com/2018/11/13/its-not-change-you-fear-its-loss/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://steveblank.com/2018/11/13/its-not-change-you-fear-its-loss/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wEBlaMOmKV4&quot;&gt;I know a change is going to come&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re an early employee at a startup, one day you will wake up to find that what you worked on 24/7 for the last year is no longer the most important thing – you’re no longer the most important employee, and process, meetings, paperwork and managers and bosses have shown up. Most painfully, you’ll learn that &lt;a href=&quot;https://steveblank.com/2015/02/12/what-do-i-do-now/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;your role in the company has to change&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/mad-employee-s.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;24877&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://steveblank.com/2018/11/13/its-not-change-you-fear-its-loss/mad-employee-s/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/mad-employee-s.jpg&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;720,509&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Mad employee s&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/mad-employee-s.jpg?w=300&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/mad-employee-s.jpg?w=468&quot; class=&quot;alignright size-thumbnail wp-image-24877&quot; src=&quot;https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/mad-employee-s.jpg?w=150&amp;amp;h=106&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; height=&quot;106&quot; srcset=&quot;https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/mad-employee-s.jpg?w=150&amp;amp;h=106 150w, https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/mad-employee-s.jpg?w=300&amp;amp;h=212 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;I’ve seen these transitions as an investor, board member and CEO. At times they are painful to watch and difficult to manage. Early in my career I lived it as an employee, and I handled it in the worst possible way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s what I wish I had known.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;I had joined MIPS Computers, my second semiconductor company&lt;strong&gt;,&lt;/strong&gt; as the VP of marketing and also took on the role of the acting VP of Sales. During the first year of the company’s life, I was a fireball – relentless in creating and pursuing opportunities – getting on an airplane at the drop of a hat to fly anywhere, anytime, to get a design win. I worked with engineering to try to find product/market fit (&lt;a href=&quot;https://steveblank.com/2009/11/30/customer-development-is-not-a-focus-group/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;big endian or little endian&lt;/a&gt;?) and get the chip designed into companies building engineering workstations – powerful personal computers, all while trying to refine how to find the right markets, customers, and sales process. I didn’t get much sleep, but I was having the time of my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And after a year there was good news. Our rent-a-CEO was being replaced by a permanent one. Our chip was nearing completion, and I had convinced early &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.alchemistaccelerator.com/lighthouse-customers-four-best-practices&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;lighthouse customers&lt;/a&gt; to design it into their computers. I had done amazing things with almost no resources and got the company on the radar of every tech publication and into deals we had no right to be in. I was feeling 10 feet tall. Everything was great… until the new CEO called me in for a chat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t remember much about the details, but I do remember hearing him tell me how impressed he was with what I had accomplished so far, then immediately the visceral feeling of shock and surprise when his next words were that now the company needed to scale, and I wasn’t the right person to do that… Wait! What??&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a minute I couldn’t breathe. I felt like I had been punched in the gut. How could that be?  What do you mean I’m not the right person??? Hadn’t he just listed all the great work I had done? He acknowledged it was a lot of progress but offered that it was a flurry of disconnected tactics without a coherent strategy. No one knew what I was doing, and I couldn’t explain why I was doing it when asked. “You’re just throwing stuff against the wall. That doesn’t scale.” I was speechless. Wasn’t that what the first year of a startup was supposed to be like?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scrambling to save my job, I regained the power of speech, and asked him if I could be the person to take the company to the next level. And to his credit (which I only appreciated years later) he agreed that while he was going to start a search, I could be a candidate for the job. And to top it off he got me a coach to help me understand what taking it to the next level meant. In preparation I remember buying all the management books I could find and reading what little literature there was at the time about how small company management transitioned into a larger one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And herein lies the tale….&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;I vaguely remember going to lunch with my coach, a nice white-haired “old guy” who was trying to help me learn the skills to grow into the new job. The problem was I had shut down. Even as we were meeting, I was obsessively thinking about the change in my role, my title and my status. “I don’t get it, I did all this work, and everything was great. &lt;em&gt;Why does anything have to change&lt;/em&gt;?”  But I never shared any of how I felt with my coach. To do this day I am really embarrassed to admit that I have no idea what my coach tried to teach me over multiple lunches and weeks. As we went to lunch, all I could think about was me and how I was being screwed. I literally paid zero attention. In my righteous anger I was unreachable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I shouldn’t have been surprised, but yet again I was, when a month later the CEO said, that the report from the coach said, “I had a long way to go”. The company was going to hire a VP of Marketing. I was devastated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I quit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It’s Not About Change – It’s About Loss&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;If you had asked me a decade later what had been going on in my head and why I handled this so badly, I would have simply said, that: 1) I was resistant to change, and that 2) I had made this all about me and never once considered that our new CEO was right&lt;em&gt;. &lt;/em&gt;All true – to a point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It took me another decade to realize if I had been really honest with myself &lt;em&gt;it wasn’t about fighting change at all&lt;/em&gt;. Heck every day something new was happening at our startup. I was agile enough to keep up with innumerable changes and I was changing lots of things myself. It was actually about something much more personal I wouldn’t admit to myself – it was that &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.strategy-business.com/article/09306?gko=5df7f&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;these changes made me fear what I was losing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;I felt a &lt;em&gt;l&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;oss of status and identity &lt;/em&gt;– I had been judged inadequate to continue in my role and my stature and the value of my skills and abilities had dropped.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I felt a &lt;em&gt;loss of certainty &lt;/em&gt;– I was now competing to hold a job I thought was mine forever in the company. At least that’s what I thought my business card said. Now I was adrift and didn’t know what the future held.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I felt a loss of &lt;em&gt;autonomy –&lt;/em&gt; Up until now I used my best judgment of what was needed and I was doing what I wanted, when I wanted it. I was fine making up a strategy on the fly from disconnected tactics. Now we were going to have plans and a strategy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I felt a &lt;em&gt;loss of community &lt;/em&gt;– we had been a small tight team who had bonded together under extreme pressure and accomplished amazing things. Now new people who knew none of that and appreciated little of it were coming in. They had little trust and empathy with us.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I felt &lt;em&gt;the process lacked fairness –&lt;/em&gt; no one had warned/told me that the job I was doing needed to change over time, and no one told me what those new skills were.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What was going on?&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Researchers have found there’s a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.strategy-business.com/article/09306?gko=5df7f&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;link between social connection and physical discomfort&lt;/a&gt; within the brain. “Being hungry and being ostracized activate similar neural responses because &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.strategy-business.com/article/09306?gko=5df7f&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;being socially connected is necessary for survival&lt;/a&gt;. Although a job is often regarded as a purely economic transaction, &lt;em&gt;the brain experiences the workplace first and foremost as a social system&lt;/em&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking back over the decades it’s clear that the new CEO was right. Even though these losses triggered something primal, I did need to learn discipline, pattern recognition, time management, separating the trivial from the important and the difference between tactics and strategy. I needed to learn to grow from being a great individual contributor to being a manager and then a leader. Instead I walked away from learning any of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I probably added five unneeded years to my career.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What should I have done?&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Today it’s understood that all startups &lt;a href=&quot;https://steveblank.com/2015/02/12/what-do-i-do-now/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;go through a metamorphosis as they become larger companies&lt;/a&gt;. They go from organizations struggling for survival as they search for product/market fit, to building a repeatable and scalable business model, and then growing to profitability. And we are all &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dunbar's_number&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;hard-wired for a set number&lt;/a&gt; of social relationships. This mental wiring defines boundaries in growing an organization – get bigger than a certain size, and you need a different management system. The skills needed from employees differ at each stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/search-build-grow1.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;24903&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://steveblank.com/2018/11/13/its-not-change-you-fear-its-loss/search-build-grow-4/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/search-build-grow1.jpg&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1385,310&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;search build grow&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/search-build-grow1.jpg?w=300&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/search-build-grow1.jpg?w=400&amp;amp;h=90&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-24903&quot; src=&quot;https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/search-build-grow1.jpg?w=400&amp;amp;h=90&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;90&quot; srcset=&quot;https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/search-build-grow1.jpg?w=400&amp;amp;h=90 400w, https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/search-build-grow1.jpg?w=800&amp;amp;h=180 800w, https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/search-build-grow1.jpg?w=150&amp;amp;h=34 150w, https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/search-build-grow1.jpg?w=300&amp;amp;h=67 300w, https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/search-build-grow1.jpg?w=768&amp;amp;h=172 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 400px) 100vw, 400px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;What I wish I knew was that if you’re an early company employee, &lt;em&gt;it’s not likely that the skills you have on day one are the skills needed as the company scales to the next level&lt;/em&gt;. This sentence is worth reading multiple times as no one – not the person who hired you, the VC’s or your peers -is going to tell you when you’re hired &lt;span&gt;that the company will likely outgrow you.&lt;/span&gt; Some (like your peers or even the founders) don’t understand it, and others (the VCs) realize it’s not in their interest to let you know. The painful reality is that products change, strategies change, people change…things have to change for your company to stay in business and grow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What should my CEO have done?&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;When my CEO was explaining to me how the company needed to change to grow, he was explaining facts while I was processing deeply held feelings. The &lt;em&gt;changes in the organization and my role represented what I was about to lose&lt;/em&gt;. And when people feel they’re going to lose something deeply important, it triggers an emotional response because change feels like a threat. It’s not an excuse for my counterproductive behavior, but explains why I acted out like I did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Startup CEOs need to &lt;u&gt;think about these transitions from day one &lt;/u&gt;and consider &lt;em&gt;how to address the real sense of loss these transitions mean to early employees&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Loss of status&lt;/em&gt;? It’s almost impossible to take away a title from someone, give it to someone else and still retain that employee. Think hard about whether titles need to be formal (VP of Engineering, VP of Marketing, VP of Sales, etc.) before the company finds product/market fit and/or tens of people – as you can almost guarantee that these people won’t have those roles and titles when you scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Loss of Certainty?&lt;/em&gt; Startups and VC’s have historically operated on the “I’ll deal with this later” principle in letting early employees know what happens as the company scales. The common wisdom is that no one would want to work like crazy knowing that they might not be the ones to lead as the company grows. I call this the Moses-problem – you work for years to get the tribe to the promised land – but you’re not allowed to cross over. The company needs to give formal recognition for those individuals who brought the tribe to the promised land.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Loss of Autonomy? &lt;/em&gt;This is the time you and your employees get to have a discussion about the next steps in their career. Do they want to be an individual contributor? Manager of people and process? Special projects? These shouldn’t be random assignments but instead, offer a roadmap of possible choices and directions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Loss of Community?&lt;/em&gt; Your original hires embody the company culture. Unless you have them capture the unique aspects of the culture, it will become diluted and disappear among the new hires. Declare them &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mastersofscale.com/#/aneel-bhusri-the-elusive-formula-for-great-hiring/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;cultural co-founders&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/em&gt;Help them understand the community is growing and they’re the ambassadors. Have them formalize it as part of a now needed on-boarding process as the company grows. And most importantly, make sure that they are celebrated as the team that got the company to where it is now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Loss of Fairness?&lt;/em&gt; Just telling employees “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wEBlaMOmKV4&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;a change is going to come&lt;/a&gt;” it is not sufficient. What are the new skills needed when you scale from Search to Build to Grow – from tens to hundreds and then thousands of people? How can your existing employees gain those new skills?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lessons Learned&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;VC’s, Founders and CEOs now recognize that startups grow through different stages: &lt;a href=&quot;https://steveblank.com/2015/02/12/what-do-i-do-now/&quot;&gt;Search, Build and Grow&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;They recognize that employees need different skills at each stage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And that some of the original employees won’t grow into the next stage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;But while these changes make rational sense to the CEO and the board, to early employees these changes feel like a real and tangible personal &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.strategy-business.com/article/09306?gko=5df7f&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;loss&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Loss of Status and Identity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Loss of Community&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Loss of Autonomy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Loss of Certainty&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Loss of Fairness&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CEOs need to put processes in places to acknowledge and deal with the real sense of loss
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;These will keep early employees motivated – and retained&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And build a stronger company&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For employees, how you handle change will affect the trajectory of your career and possibly your net worth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post appeared in &lt;a href=&quot;https://angel.co/blog/steve-blank-how-to-keep-your-job-as-your-startup-grows&quot;&gt;AngelList&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://angel.co/blog/steve-blank-how-to-keep-your-job-as-your-startup-grows&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;24934&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://steveblank.com/2018/11/13/its-not-change-you-fear-its-loss/angellist-2/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/angellist1.jpg&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1458,277&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Angellist&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/angellist1.jpg?w=300&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/angellist1.jpg?w=468&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-24934 size-thumbnail aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/angellist1.jpg?w=150&amp;amp;h=28&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; height=&quot;28&quot; srcset=&quot;https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/angellist1.jpg?w=150&amp;amp;h=28 150w, https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/angellist1.jpg?w=295&amp;amp;h=56 295w, https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/angellist1.jpg?w=300&amp;amp;h=57 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;jp-post-flair&quot; class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-like-enabled sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;robots-nocontent sd-block sd-social sd-social-official sd-sharing&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Share this:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-block sd-like jetpack-likes-widget-wrapper jetpack-likes-widget-unloaded&quot; id=&quot;like-post-wrapper-6599589-24863-5beb64c2d7bbe&quot; data-src=&quot;//widgets.wp.com/likes/index.html?ver=20180319#blog_id=6599589&amp;amp;post_id=24863&amp;amp;origin=steveblank.wordpress.com&amp;amp;obj_id=6599589-24863-5beb64c2d7bbe&quot; data-name=&quot;like-post-frame-6599589-24863-5beb64c2d7bbe&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Like this:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;button&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Like&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;loading&quot;&gt;Loading...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;postinfo&quot;&gt;Filed under: &lt;a href=&quot;https://steveblank.com/category/familycareerculture/&quot; rel=&quot;category tag&quot;&gt;Family/Career/Culture&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://steveblank.com/category/mips-computers/&quot; rel=&quot;category tag&quot;&gt;MIPS Computers&lt;/a&gt; |&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 15:46:39 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Raj7k</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Steve Blank How to Keep Your Job As Your Company Grows</og:title>
<og:url>https://steveblank.com/2018/11/13/its-not-change-you-fear-its-loss/</og:url>
<og:description>I know a change is going to come If you’re an early employee at a startup, one day you will wake up to find that what you worked on 24/7 for the last year is no longer the most important thing &amp;#82…</og:description>
<og:image>https://steveblank.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/mad-employee-s.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://steveblank.com/2018/11/13/its-not-change-you-fear-its-loss/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>GitLab Made $10.5M in Revenue with Every Employee Working from Home</title>
<link>https://www.inc.com/cameron-albert-deitch/2018-inc5000-gitlab.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.inc.com/cameron-albert-deitch/2018-inc5000-gitlab.html</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.inc.com/cameron-albert-deitch/2018-inc5000-gitlab.html&quot;&gt;https://www.inc.com/cameron-albert-deitch/2018-inc5000-gitlab.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=18441768&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=18441768&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 598&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 334&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 15:42:05 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>janvdberg</dc:creator>
<dc:identifier>https://www.inc.com/cameron-albert-deitch/2018-inc5000-gitlab.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Amazon Selects New York City and Northern Virginia for New Headquarters</title>
<link>https://blog.aboutamazon.com/company-news/amazon-selects-new-york-city-and-northern-virginia-for-new-headquarters</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.aboutamazon.com/company-news/amazon-selects-new-york-city-and-northern-virginia-for-new-headquarters</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;RichTextArticleBody mood-color&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;RichTextArticleBody-body&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazon today announced that we have selected New York City and Arlington, Virginia, as the locations for our new headquarters. Amazon will invest $5 billion and create more than 50,000 jobs across the two new headquarters locations, with more than 25,000 employees each in New York City and Arlington. The new locations will join Seattle as the company’s three headquarters in North America. In addition, Amazon announced that it has selected Nashville for a new Center of Excellence for its Operations business, which is responsible for the company’s customer fulfillment, transportation, supply chain, and other similar activities. The Operations Center of Excellence in Nashville will create more than 5,000 jobs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new Washington, D.C. metro headquarters in Arlington will be located in National Landing, and the New York City headquarters will be located in the Long Island City neighborhood in Queens. Amazon’s investments in each new headquarters will spur the creation of tens of thousands of additional jobs in the surrounding communities. Hiring at both the new headquarters will begin in 2019. The Operations Center of Excellence will be located in downtown Nashville as part of a new development site just north of the Gulch, and hiring will also begin in 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We are excited to build new headquarters in New York City and Northern Virginia,” said Jeff Bezos, founder and CEO of Amazon. “These two locations will allow us to attract world-class talent that will help us to continue inventing for customers for years to come. The team did a great job selecting these sites, and we look forward to becoming an even bigger part of these communities.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;cms-headings-h2&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amazon in Long Island City in New York City&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Located just across the East River from Midtown Manhattan and the Upper East Side, Long Island City is a mixed-use community where arts and industry intersect. It is a diverse community with a unique blend of cultural institutions, arts organizations, new and converted housing, restaurants, bars, breweries, waterfront parks, hotels, academic institutions, and small and large tech sector and industrial businesses. Long Island City has some of the best transit access in New York City, with 8 subway lines, 13 bus lines, commuter rail, a bike-sharing service, and ferries serving the area, and LaGuardia and JFK airports are in close proximity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;As part of Amazon’s new headquarters, New York and Long Island City will benefit from more than 25,000 full-time high-paying jobs; approximately $2.5 billion in Amazon investment; 4 million square feet of energy-efficient office space with an opportunity to expand to 8 million square feet; and an estimated incremental tax revenue of more than $10 billion over the next 20 years as a result of Amazon’s investment and job creation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Amazon will receive performance-based direct incentives of $1.525 billion based on the company creating 25,000 jobs in Long Island City. This includes a refundable tax credit through New York State’s Excelsior Program of up to $1.2 billion calculated as a percentage of the salaries Amazon expects to pay employees over the next 10 years, which equates to $48,000 per job for 25,000 jobs with an average wage of over $150,000; and a cash grant from Empire State Development of $325 million based on the square footage of buildings occupied in the next 10 years. Amazon will receive these incentives over the next decade based on the incremental jobs it creates each year and as it reaches building occupancy targets. The company will separately apply for as-of-right incentives including New York City’s Industrial &amp;amp; Commercial Abatement Program (ICAP) and New York City’s Relocation and Employment Assistance Program (REAP).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The community will benefit from New York City providing funding through a Payment In Lieu Of Tax (PILOT) program based on Amazon’s property taxes on a portion of the development site to fund community infrastructure improvements developed through input from residents during the planning process. Amazon has agreed to donate space on its campus for a tech startup incubator and for use by artists and industrial businesses, and Amazon will donate a site for a new primary or intermediary public school. The company will also invest in infrastructure improvements and new green spaces.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;“When I took office, I said we would build a &lt;em&gt;new&lt;/em&gt; New York State – one that is fiscally responsible and fosters a business climate that is attractive to growing companies and the industries of tomorrow. We’ve delivered on those promises and more, and today, with Amazon committing to expand its headquarters in Long Island City, New York can proudly say that we have attracted one of the largest, most competitive economic development investments in U.S. history,” said Governor Andrew M. Cuomo of New York. “With an average salary of $150,000 per year for the tens of thousands of new jobs Amazon is creating in Queens, economic opportunity and investment will flourish for the entire region. Amazon understands that New York has everything the company needs to continue its growth. The State’s more than $100 billion transportation infrastructure program – the most ambitious in our history – combined with our education initiatives like K-12 tech education and the first-in-the-nation Excelsior Scholarship program, will help ensure long-term success and an unrivaled talent pool for Amazon.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This is a giant step on our path to building an economy in New York City that leaves no one behind. We are thrilled that Amazon has selected New York City for its new headquarters,” said Mayor Bill de Blasio of New York City. “New Yorkers will get tens of thousands of new, good-paying jobs, and Amazon will get the best talent anywhere in the world. We’re going to use this opportunity to open up good careers in tech to thousands of people looking for their foothold in the new economy, including those in City colleges and public housing. The City and State are working closely together to make sure Amazon’s expansion is planned smartly, and to ensure this fast growing neighborhood has the transportation, schools, and infrastructure it needs.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;cms-headings-h2&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amazon in National Landing in Arlington, Virginia&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;National Landing is an urban community in Northern Virginia located less than 3 miles from downtown Washington, D.C. The area is served by 3 Metro stations, commuter rail access, and Reagan National Airport – all within walking distance. The community has a variety of hotels, restaurants, high-rise apartment buildings, retail, and commercial offices. National Landing has abundant parks and open space with sports and cultural events for residents of all ages throughout the year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;As part of Amazon’s new headquarters, Virginia and Arlington will benefit from more than 25,000 full-time high-paying jobs; approximately $2.5 billion in Amazon investment; 4 million square feet of energy-efficient office space with the opportunity to expand to 8 million square feet; and an estimated incremental tax revenue of $3.2 billion over the next 20 years as a result of Amazon’s investment and job creation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Amazon will receive performance-based direct incentives of $573 million based on the company creating 25,000 jobs with an average wage of over $150,000 in Arlington. This includes a workforce cash grant from the Commonwealth of Virginia of up to $550 million based on $22,000 for each job created over the next 12 years. Amazon will only receive this incentive if it creates the forecasted high-paying jobs. The company will also receive a cash grant from Arlington of $23 million over 15 years based on the incremental growth of the existing local Transient Occupancy Tax, a tax on hotel rooms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The community and Amazon employees will benefit from the Commonwealth investing $195 million in infrastructure in the neighborhood, including improvements to the Crystal City and the Potomac Yard Metro stations; a pedestrian bridge connecting National Landing and Reagan National Airport; and work to improve safety, accessibility, and the pedestrian experience crossing Route 1 over the next 10 years. Arlington will also dedicate an estimated $28 million based on 12% of future property tax revenues earned from an existing Tax Increment Financing (TIF) district for on-site infrastructure and open space in National Landing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;“This is a big win for Virginia – I’m proud Amazon recognizes the tremendous assets the Commonwealth has to offer and plans to deepen its roots here,” said Governor Ralph Northam of Virginia. “Virginia put together a proposal for Amazon that we believe represents a new model of economic development for the 21st century, and I’m excited to say that our innovative approach was successful. The majority of Virginia’s partnership proposal consists of investments in our education and transportation infrastructure that will bolster the features that make Virginia so attractive: a strong and talented workforce, a stable and competitive business climate, and a world-class higher education system.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We are proud that Amazon has selected National Landing for a major new headquarters. This is, above all, a validation of our community’s commitment to sustainability, transit-oriented development, affordable housing, and diversity,” said Arlington County Board Chair Katie Cristol. “The strength of our workforce coupled with our proximity to the nation’s capital makes us an attractive business location. But Arlington’s real strength is the decades of planning that have produced one of the most vibrant, civically engaged communities in the world. Those plans have paved the way for this investment, and we look forward to engaging the Arlington community about Amazon’s plans and how we can grow together.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;cms-headings-h2&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amazon’s new Operations Center of Excellence in Nashville&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Downtown Nashville, along the Cumberland River, is the heart of the city just north of the Gulch and is home to urban living, retail, restaurants, entertainment venues, hospitality, open green spaces, and offices. The area is served by commuter rail, more than a dozen bus routes, and is a 15-minute drive to Nashville International Airport.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;As part of Amazon’s investment, Tennessee, Davidson County and the city of Nashville will benefit from 5,000 full-time, high-paying jobs; over $230 million in investment; 1 million square feet of energy-efficient office space; and an estimated incremental tax revenue of more than $1 billion over the next 10 years as a result of Amazon’s investment and job creation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Amazon will receive performance-based direct incentives of up to $102 million based on the company creating 5,000 jobs with an average wage of over $150,000 in Nashville. This includes a cash grant for capital expenditures from the state of Tennessee of $65 million based on the company creating 5,000 jobs over the next 7 years, which is equivalent to $13,000 per job; a cash grant from the city of Nashville of up to $15 million based on $500 for each job created over the next 7 years; and a job tax credit to offset franchise and excise taxes from the state of Tennessee of $21.7 million based on $4,500 per new job over the next 7 years.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We want to thank Amazon for its continued investment in the state of Tennessee and are excited about the additional 5,000 corporate jobs they will be creating in Nashville,” said Governor Bill Haslam of Tennessee. “It has never been clearer that Tennessee is a great place to do business, and we continue to attract a wide variety of global companies that provide high-paying, quality jobs for our residents.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Amazon’s decision to expand its presence in Nashville is a direct result of the talented workforce and strong community we’ve built here,” said Mayor David Briley of Nashville. “These are quality, high-paying jobs that will boost our economy, provide our workers with new opportunities, and show the rest of the world that Nashville is a premiere location for business investment. We thank Amazon for investing in Nashville, and we look forward to welcoming them to this community.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With more than 610,000 employees worldwide, including over 250,000 in North America, Amazon ranks #1 on American Customer Satisfaction Index, #2 on Fortune’s World’s Most Admired Companies, #1 on The Harris Poll’s Corporate Reputation survey, and #1 on LinkedIn’s U.S. Top Companies, a ranking recognizing the most desirable workplaces in the country. Amazon was also recently included in the Military Times’ Best for Vets list of companies committed to providing opportunities for military veterans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All economic impact and incentive figures are best estimates calculated by relevant entities in each of the selected communities based on current information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;cms-headings-h2&quot; id=&quot;faq&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FAQ&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Why did Amazon pick more than one location for its new headquarters?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;We can recruit more top talent by being in two locations. These are fantastic cities that attract a lot of great talent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. What differentiates the two new headquarters locations from the corporate offices and development centers Amazon has across the U.S. and around the world?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Amazon’s biggest office outside of Seattle in the U.S. has 3,100 employees – we are planning to grow both these new headquarters to over 25,000. These headquarters locations will have far more employees, senior leaders, and we will do more cross-company meetings and events at these headquarters, including company-wide All Hands meetings, Shareholder Meetings, Board of Directors meetings, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. How did you pick New York City and Northern Virginia as headquarters?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;We were looking for a location with strong local and regional talent—particularly in software development and related fields—to continue hiring and innovating on behalf of our customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Where will the headquarters be located in New York City and Arlington?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Amazon in Northern Virginia is in National Landing in Arlington&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Enhancement&quot; data-align-center=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Enhancement-item&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d39w7f4ix9f5s9.cloudfront.net/dims4/default/6f2d76e/2147483647/strip/true/crop/808x627+96+0/resize/812x630!/quality/90/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fd39w7f4ix9f5s9.cloudfront.net%2Fe0%2Fe5%2F06c5a387413792757b62d70786d5%2Famzn-arlington-v2.2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Map of the Arlington area with a pin placed to illustrate the location of a new Amazon headquarters. &quot; srcset=&quot;https://d39w7f4ix9f5s9.cloudfront.net/dims4/default/6f2d76e/2147483647/strip/true/crop/808x627+96+0/resize/812x630!/quality/90/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fd39w7f4ix9f5s9.cloudfront.net%2Fe0%2Fe5%2F06c5a387413792757b62d70786d5%2Famzn-arlington-v2.2.jpg 1x,https://d39w7f4ix9f5s9.cloudfront.net/dims4/default/18555ae/2147483647/strip/true/crop/808x627+96+0/resize/1624x1260!/quality/90/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fd39w7f4ix9f5s9.cloudfront.net%2Fe0%2Fe5%2F06c5a387413792757b62d70786d5%2Famzn-arlington-v2.2.jpg 2x&quot; width=&quot;812&quot; height=&quot;630&quot;/&gt;&lt;hr class=&quot;mood-bgcolor&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/2z8rZWx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-cms-ai=&quot;0&quot;&gt;Download the map here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazon in New York City is in the Long Island City neighborhood in Queens&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Enhancement&quot; data-align-center=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Enhancement-item&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d39w7f4ix9f5s9.cloudfront.net/dims4/default/462e147/2147483647/strip/true/crop/808x627+96+0/resize/812x630!/quality/90/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fd39w7f4ix9f5s9.cloudfront.net%2F77%2Fe5%2Fd28b3fdc4cbd9ec1f1029a6558ad%2Famzn-nyc-v2.2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Map of the New York City area with a pin placed to illustrate the location of a new Amazon headquarters. &quot; srcset=&quot;https://d39w7f4ix9f5s9.cloudfront.net/dims4/default/462e147/2147483647/strip/true/crop/808x627+96+0/resize/812x630!/quality/90/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fd39w7f4ix9f5s9.cloudfront.net%2F77%2Fe5%2Fd28b3fdc4cbd9ec1f1029a6558ad%2Famzn-nyc-v2.2.jpg 1x,https://d39w7f4ix9f5s9.cloudfront.net/dims4/default/5cb8f05/2147483647/strip/true/crop/808x627+96+0/resize/1624x1260!/quality/90/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fd39w7f4ix9f5s9.cloudfront.net%2F77%2Fe5%2Fd28b3fdc4cbd9ec1f1029a6558ad%2Famzn-nyc-v2.2.jpg 2x&quot; width=&quot;812&quot; height=&quot;630&quot;/&gt;&lt;hr class=&quot;mood-bgcolor&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/2QDx93D&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-cms-ai=&quot;0&quot;&gt;Download the map here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. What is the Operations Center of Excellence and where will it be located in Nashville?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Our Retail Operations division handles customer fulfillment, customer service, transportation, and supply chain, amongst others. The Operations Center of Excellence will be the Eastern U.S. regional hub for the tech and management functions of this division. It will be located in downtown Nashville just north of The Gulch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazon Operations Center of Excellence is north of the Gulch in downtown Nashville&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Enhancement&quot; data-align-center=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Enhancement-item&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d39w7f4ix9f5s9.cloudfront.net/dims4/default/0d50e8a/2147483647/strip/true/crop/808x627+96+0/resize/812x630!/quality/90/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fd39w7f4ix9f5s9.cloudfront.net%2F4a%2F74%2F7a0760434eed825dada968c3c9e3%2Famzn-nashville-v2.2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Map of the Nashville area with a pin placed to illustrate the location of a new Amazon Operations Center of Excellence. &quot; srcset=&quot;https://d39w7f4ix9f5s9.cloudfront.net/dims4/default/0d50e8a/2147483647/strip/true/crop/808x627+96+0/resize/812x630!/quality/90/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fd39w7f4ix9f5s9.cloudfront.net%2F4a%2F74%2F7a0760434eed825dada968c3c9e3%2Famzn-nashville-v2.2.jpg 1x,https://d39w7f4ix9f5s9.cloudfront.net/dims4/default/7f33b70/2147483647/strip/true/crop/808x627+96+0/resize/1624x1260!/quality/90/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fd39w7f4ix9f5s9.cloudfront.net%2F4a%2F74%2F7a0760434eed825dada968c3c9e3%2Famzn-nashville-v2.2.jpg 2x&quot; width=&quot;812&quot; height=&quot;630&quot;/&gt;&lt;hr class=&quot;mood-bgcolor&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/2Pqqhdy&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-cms-ai=&quot;0&quot;&gt;Download the map here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. What role did economic incentives play in Amazon picking these locations and what incentives have been agreed?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Economic incentives were one factor in our decision—but attracting top talent was the leading driver. Our agreements with each location may be downloaded:&lt;br/&gt;New York City, New York &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/2TbfCBC&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-cms-ai=&quot;0&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Arlington, Virginia &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/2z9qnMg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-cms-ai=&quot;0&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/2B46dEQ&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-cms-ai=&quot;0&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Nashville, Tennessee &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/2z8sdx8&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-cms-ai=&quot;0&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/2OG8nOD&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-cms-ai=&quot;0&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Are you continuing to hire in the Seattle area?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Yes. We currently have more than 8,000 positions open and over 45,000 Amazonians in the Seattle area.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 15:26:27 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>appwiz</dc:creator>
<og:title>Amazon selects New York City and Northern Virginia for new headquarters</og:title>
<og:url>https://blog.aboutamazon.com/company-news/amazon-selects-new-york-city-and-northern-virginia-for-new-headquarters</og:url>
<og:image>https://d39w7f4ix9f5s9.cloudfront.net/dims4/default/90456df/2147483647/strip/true/crop/899x471+2+0/resize/1200x628!/quality/90/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fd39w7f4ix9f5s9.cloudfront.net%2F58%2Fe5%2F4501be6b4829961d701cae8ed249%2Fblog-social-final-2.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>Amazon to invest $5 billion and create more than 50,000 jobs across the two new headquarters, and announces Nashville as new Operations Center of Excellence with more than 5,000 jobs.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.aboutamazon.com/company-news/amazon-selects-new-york-city-and-northern-virginia-for-new-headquarters</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>My App Is Dead in the Water</title>
<link>https://medium.com/@mds6058/my-app-is-dead-in-the-water-93a97a137eff</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://medium.com/@mds6058/my-app-is-dead-in-the-water-93a97a137eff</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*yomgHKj-LJisepcsXEWnRA.jpeg&quot; data-width=&quot;1280&quot; data-height=&quot;720&quot; data-is-featured=&quot;true&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*yomgHKj-LJisepcsXEWnRA.jpeg&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*yomgHKj-LJisepcsXEWnRA.jpeg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;f005&quot; id=&quot;f005&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;About 5 years ago, I decided to write an iOS app. I wasn’t satisfied with the features of the Hacker News clients I had downloaded from the app store, so I decided to write my own. It was called Hacker News Zero (&lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/hacker-news-zero/id764890985?mt=8&quot; data-href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/hacker-news-zero/id764890985?mt=8&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/hacker-news-zero/id764890985?mt=8&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*9-AvNGGVp2uvyZyIJsaWlA.png&quot; data-width=&quot;1242&quot; data-height=&quot;2208&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*9-AvNGGVp2uvyZyIJsaWlA.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*9-AvNGGVp2uvyZyIJsaWlA.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Screenshot of the current app
&lt;p name=&quot;c558&quot; id=&quot;c558&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;It’s a pretty basic Hacker News app. You can only read comments (currently the API doesn’t support it), and you can view each of the other “sections” of the site like Ask HN, Jobs, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;9003&quot; id=&quot;9003&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;After it was released, it developed a (very) modest following, and it actually ended up helping me get my first job as an iOS developer. I took the time to maintain the app in my spare time, adding things like iPad support and dark mode. I even re-wrote it in Swift this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;7e31&quot; id=&quot;7e31&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;But then one day, after submitting a small bug fix update, I got an email from Apple. My app had been rejected. The following is their first letter:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;cc01&quot; id=&quot;cc01&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--p&quot; readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guideline 5.2.2 — Legal&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;c56c&quot; id=&quot;c56c&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--blockquote&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your app contains content or features that may infringe upon rights owned by news and media outlets such as Harper’s Magazine, Ars Technica, and TechCrunch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;f4d6&quot; id=&quot;f4d6&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--blockquote&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your app and its contents should not infringe upon the rights of another party. In the event your app infringes another party’s rights, you are responsible for any liability to Apple because of a claim.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;9932&quot; id=&quot;9932&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--blockquote&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next Steps&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;7e2a&quot; id=&quot;7e2a&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--blockquote&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To resolve this issue, please attach documentary evidence in the App Review Information section in App Store Connect. In accordance with section 3.2(f) of the Apple Developer Program License Agreement, you acknowledge that submitting falsified or fraudulent documentation can result in the termination of your Apple Developer Program account and the removal of your apps from the App Store. Once Legal has reviewed your documentation and confirms its validity, we will proceed with the review of your app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;8611&quot; id=&quot;8611&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--blockquote&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alternatively, please make the necessary changes to your app so that it does not infringe upon the rights of a third party. For example, before accessing the news articles:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;c041&quot; id=&quot;c041&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--blockquote&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Include links to third-party news articles that launch in a web browser outside of the app.&lt;br/&gt;or&lt;br/&gt;- Require the user to configure third-party RSS feeds/sources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;f1d2&quot; id=&quot;f1d2&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--blockquote&quot;&gt;Showing articles from random third party sources is pretty much THE feature of a Hacker News client app. There is no way anyone anywhere can get “documentary evidence” for every domain on the internet. As for their alternatives, kicking the user out to Safari would significantly reduce the usability of the app. And I don’t think configuring a “feed” really works for this kind of app: am I supposed to force the user to configure a feed that includes every site on the internet?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;7371&quot; id=&quot;7371&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;So I thought that maybe they missed the fact that there is a “Show in Safari” button in a toolbar below every article. So I sent a reply back informing them of this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;3fbe&quot; id=&quot;3fbe&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;I got a prompt reply back from them:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;9f33&quot; id=&quot;9f33&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--p&quot; readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We continue to find that your app displays full articles from multiple news sources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;f326&quot; id=&quot;f326&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--blockquote&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To resolve this issue you can do any of the following:&lt;br/&gt;- Attach documentary evidence in the App Review Information section in App Store Connect granting you permission to use these sources&lt;br/&gt;- Require users to customize their news sources upon launching your app&lt;br/&gt;- Only show a portion of the article within your app and link out to Safari for the rest&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;935a&quot; id=&quot;935a&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--blockquote&quot;&gt;Ok, they’ve made themselves clear. Apps can’t show any third party links within the app itself. But wait, aren’t there hundreds of Hacker News client apps out there that do exactly that? Not to mention clients for other similar services like Reddit, Twitter, etc. This must be a mistake. They are mistaking my app for some sort of RSS feed aggregator or something, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;d8b5&quot; id=&quot;d8b5&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Over the next couple of weeks, I sent several replies back and forth the app reviewer, but it was wholly unproductive. Questions like, “How is my app different than all the other Hacker News apps out there?” were ignored. It felt like I was arguing with a robot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;6ebe&quot; id=&quot;6ebe&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;So I decided to send an official appeal to the App Review board. However, after a couple of days, it was rejected. Guideline 5.2.2 was cited back to me in their short response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;d71a&quot; id=&quot;d71a&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Guideline 5.2.2, for the record, is pretty broad. Here it is from Apple’s site:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;b298&quot; id=&quot;b298&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--p&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5.2.2 Third Party Sites/Services: If your app uses, accesses, monetizes access to, or displays content from a third party service, ensure that you are specifically permitted to do so under the service’s terms of use. Authorization must be provided upon request.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;c3e3&quot; id=&quot;c3e3&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--blockquote&quot;&gt;It makes you wonder: if this rule is supposed to be enforced by app review, how does ANY Hacker News client make it through app review? Showing content from a third party service is what a Hacker News client DOES. My best guess is this rule is kind of a CYA guideline put in to protect themselves from lawsuits, and I am one of the unlucky ones they decided to exercise it on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;e0f1&quot; id=&quot;e0f1&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;The lesson here is: be wary if your iOS app relies on third party services, or even links to third-party domains. Also, the app reviewer’s word is final, and you must do what they say if your app gets rejected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;7f39&quot; id=&quot;7f39&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p graf--trailing&quot;&gt;Nothing I do, short of dramatically reducing the usability of the app, will let me make any more updates to it. It is very frustrating, seeing as I maintain it for free and in my own spare time. Perhaps there’s an avenue I haven’t thought of, but for now, it seems my app is dead in the water.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 14:32:31 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>stan503</dc:creator>
<og:title>My App Is Dead in the Water – Matt Stanford – Medium</og:title>
<og:url>https://medium.com/@mds6058/my-app-is-dead-in-the-water-93a97a137eff</og:url>
<og:image>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*yomgHKj-LJisepcsXEWnRA.jpeg</og:image>
<og:description>About 5 years ago, I decided to write an iOS app. I wasn’t satisfied with the features of the Hacker News clients I had downloaded from…</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://medium.com/@mds6058/my-app-is-dead-in-the-water-93a97a137eff</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Medium is a poor choice for blogging</title>
<link>https://medium.com/@nikitonsky/medium-is-a-poor-choice-for-blogging-bb0048d19133</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://medium.com/@nikitonsky/medium-is-a-poor-choice-for-blogging-bb0048d19133</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;section-inner sectionLayout--insetColumn&quot; readability=&quot;20&quot;&gt;

&lt;p name=&quot;afc0&quot; id=&quot;afc0&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;Many people choose Medium lately as their go-to platform to blog. Kind of like Blogger a while back, it just seems what everybody has been doing (unless you are really nit-picky and care enough to host your own thing).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;8904&quot; id=&quot;8904&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;And kind of like Blogger, Medium is a terrible thing for publishing. If you think about publishing an article, starting a blog or even just sharing a short rant on Medium, please consider what you’ll be putting your readers through.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;641f&quot; id=&quot;641f&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Every Medium article will greet &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;each&lt;/em&gt; person who opens your link with a huge full-page banner &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;every time&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section-inner sectionLayout--outsetColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*6Mu_U4dUXP5uzebamoUYaw.png&quot; data-width=&quot;2560&quot; data-height=&quot;1554&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*6Mu_U4dUXP5uzebamoUYaw.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/1*6Mu_U4dUXP5uzebamoUYaw.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section-inner sectionLayout--insetColumn&quot; readability=&quot;19&quot;&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;6aca&quot; id=&quot;6aca&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;If they open your link on a phone, Medium will really, really, really insist on installing an app. I guess reading text from a webpage is too old-school:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*YydCukQpUYFjrbGw1sW0BQ@2x.png&quot; data-width=&quot;750&quot; data-height=&quot;1334&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*YydCukQpUYFjrbGw1sW0BQ@2x.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*YydCukQpUYFjrbGw1sW0BQ@2x.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;fe89&quot; id=&quot;fe89&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;Medium is advertising itself as a reader-oriented experience. At the same time, most of Medium articles look and read &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;worse&lt;/em&gt; than just plaintext HTML. If you get through banners and set down to read anything, you will be surrounded by HUGE sticky header, sticky footer and sticky social media controls:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section-inner sectionLayout--outsetColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*PEEiieiArEeemd4IY-9F6A.png&quot; data-width=&quot;2318&quot; data-height=&quot;1300&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*PEEiieiArEeemd4IY-9F6A.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/1*PEEiieiArEeemd4IY-9F6A.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section-inner sectionLayout--insetColumn&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;c9bf&quot; id=&quot;c9bf&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;No, those do not go away as you scroll. They literally (yes, literally) take up 25% of your vertical space (and vertical space is very valuable, especially for text columns and horizontal screens):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section-inner sectionLayout--outsetColumn&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*s-ov4Rl0RfrPRnpzE6n3Tw.png&quot; data-width=&quot;1159&quot; data-height=&quot;650&quot; data-is-featured=&quot;true&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*s-ov4Rl0RfrPRnpzE6n3Tw.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/1*s-ov4Rl0RfrPRnpzE6n3Tw.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Are you sure I have to look at this 2-storey 100px header ALL THE TIME?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section-inner sectionLayout--insetColumn&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;c526&quot; id=&quot;c526&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;For contrast, this is how it could’ve look like without Medium styling: nice and pleasant to read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section-inner sectionLayout--outsetColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*M6lZhKNYvdAoaDDOcqGUlw.png&quot; data-width=&quot;2314&quot; data-height=&quot;1304&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*M6lZhKNYvdAoaDDOcqGUlw.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/1*M6lZhKNYvdAoaDDOcqGUlw.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section-inner sectionLayout--insetColumn&quot; readability=&quot;39&quot;&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;cdd6&quot; id=&quot;cdd6&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;I mean, you don’t have to do &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;anything&lt;/em&gt; special with text, it was designed to look fine by default. You had one job: don’t mess it up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;6212&quot; id=&quot;6212&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Every time you select text an annoying popup shows up. And if you accidentally click it (which is really easy to do because it pops up right under your cursor) you’ll be redirected to the login page (and lose your reading position) because God forbids unauthenticated users would try to do &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;anything&lt;/em&gt; with their &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;platform&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*LC5yoqj1ZGHKxSE0th8cyQ.png&quot; data-width=&quot;261&quot; data-height=&quot;140&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*LC5yoqj1ZGHKxSE0th8cyQ.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;ccee&quot; id=&quot;ccee&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;So scroll, but do not touch. In spite of the fact that it’s a plain freaking text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;69fc&quot; id=&quot;69fc&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;But maybe that popup is useful? I don’t know. Take me, for example. I’m perfectly capable of posting links and quotes on Twitter without any popup menus (and without converting them into an image first). In fact, popup menu makes it &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;harder&lt;/em&gt; for me because I can’t safely select text and adjust selection anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*i7jmGKpx7rb_YBlyg7Z_6A@2x.png&quot; data-width=&quot;800&quot; data-height=&quot;442&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*i7jmGKpx7rb_YBlyg7Z_6A@2x.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*i7jmGKpx7rb_YBlyg7Z_6A@2x.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;9785&quot; id=&quot;9785&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;And yes, it does attach an image of you selecting a text on Medium instead of just quoting the text. What a mess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*B2kMLAaHHEoqRinAPSeF4Q.png&quot; data-width=&quot;1196&quot; data-height=&quot;821&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*B2kMLAaHHEoqRinAPSeF4Q.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*B2kMLAaHHEoqRinAPSeF4Q.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
This is an image attached here, not a text quote
&lt;p name=&quot;cad2&quot; id=&quot;cad2&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;But the misadventures do not end here. If anyone decides to blog on Medium regularly, there’s no way to follow them through RSS. I mean Medium does serve RSS, but they serve it with replies and it turns the whole idea into a non-usable mess. You just get random phrases with no context in your feed instead of articles:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section-inner sectionLayout--outsetColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*PurGFcNPJIiHObKGnwZ2Hg.png&quot; data-width=&quot;1976&quot; data-height=&quot;676&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*PurGFcNPJIiHObKGnwZ2Hg.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/1*PurGFcNPJIiHObKGnwZ2Hg.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section-inner sectionLayout--insetColumn&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;6e42&quot; id=&quot;6e42&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;You can always follow people on Medium, you would say. Sort of, but Medium does not have a non-algorithmic (linear, that is) feed. Look at this mess:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section-inner sectionLayout--outsetColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*d0Vw7y0UwE2uS4S6phng3A.png&quot; data-width=&quot;2562&quot; data-height=&quot;1556&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*d0Vw7y0UwE2uS4S6phng3A.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/1*d0Vw7y0UwE2uS4S6phng3A.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section-inner sectionLayout--insetColumn&quot; readability=&quot;13&quot;&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;635d&quot; id=&quot;635d&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;Look how dates are all over the place. What happened here? And I only get to access the 15 latest publications? At least I hope they are latest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;8227&quot; id=&quot;8227&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Another interesting point is that they are really eager to block embeds that do not respect Do Not Track header but do not respect DNT themselves. Yes, Medium will collect your profile even if you are not a registered user and explicitly ask them not to do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section-inner sectionLayout--outsetColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*_P71qxrtmdnc_4kJVj1wDw.png&quot; data-width=&quot;2316&quot; data-height=&quot;1306&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*_P71qxrtmdnc_4kJVj1wDw.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/1*_P71qxrtmdnc_4kJVj1wDw.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section-inner sectionLayout--insetColumn&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;96c1&quot; id=&quot;96c1&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;Putting letters on a webpage is “impossible” without collecting your profile. Or so they say. Static HTML is not disruptive enough, I guess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section-inner sectionLayout--outsetColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*pW4p1Fh6LLtsFAXXFyRiBg.png&quot; data-width=&quot;2258&quot; data-height=&quot;222&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*pW4p1Fh6LLtsFAXXFyRiBg.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/1*pW4p1Fh6LLtsFAXXFyRiBg.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section-inner sectionLayout--insetColumn&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;1fba&quot; id=&quot;1fba&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;And it has been a common theme with them. Instead of becoming nice citizens and do what other websites do, they turned themselves into a closed silo that’s either all or nothing. No RSS. Bad reading experience, and I want to highlight it: it’s bad. &lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;Bad&lt;/strong&gt;. Really bad. It’s not good, for &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; meaning of good you can imagine. There’s no person on Earth who could honestly call it at even partially good. Banners all over the place. Aggressive tracking and profiling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;e22f&quot; id=&quot;e22f&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;UPD: Cookie banner. Really slow UI for replies/discussions. Other people highlights that interrupt your reading flow.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*X61uNUvOdFcBATOrZZWdTA.png&quot; data-width=&quot;2560&quot; data-height=&quot;1554&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*X61uNUvOdFcBATOrZZWdTA.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*X61uNUvOdFcBATOrZZWdTA.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Hey Medium! My one-line comments are in no sense “Published Stories”
&lt;p name=&quot;babd&quot; id=&quot;babd&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;Each one of your readers&lt;/em&gt; will have to go through &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;ALL&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;THAT&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;EACH&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;TIME&lt;/em&gt; just to occasionally read a couple of paragraphs of text. It’s fascinating, really, how they managed to make plain text so complicated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;547d&quot; id=&quot;547d&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Sure, Medium editor is nice. Typography is good (for English, other languages are not supported). Publishing is free. So the ones who pay for all that are your readers. Basically, you’re selling readers to aggressive Medium self-advertising so that Medium could make laughably small money from a miserable fraction of them. And annoy the hell out of everyone else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section-inner sectionLayout--outsetColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*Tj3mtf12OrwzelbTIwV_bQ.png&quot; data-width=&quot;2560&quot; data-height=&quot;1554&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*Tj3mtf12OrwzelbTIwV_bQ.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/1*Tj3mtf12OrwzelbTIwV_bQ.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
hear, hear&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section-inner sectionLayout--insetColumn&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;2ba8&quot; id=&quot;2ba8&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure graf--trailing&quot;&gt;Next time you think of publishing anything on the web, please, please, PLEASE consider something else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 13:30:20 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>rlv-dan</dc:creator>
<og:title>Medium is a poor choice for blogging – Nikitonsky – Medium</og:title>
<og:url>https://medium.com/@nikitonsky/medium-is-a-poor-choice-for-blogging-bb0048d19133</og:url>
<og:image>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*s-ov4Rl0RfrPRnpzE6n3Tw.png</og:image>
<og:description>Many people choose Medium lately as their go-to platform to blog. Kind of like Blogger a while back, it just seems what everybody has been…</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://medium.com/@nikitonsky/medium-is-a-poor-choice-for-blogging-bb0048d19133</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Internet Vulnerability Takes Down Google</title>
<link>https://blog.thousandeyes.com/internet-vulnerability-takes-down-google/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.thousandeyes.com/internet-vulnerability-takes-down-google/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;On November 12th, 2018, between 1:00 PM and 2:23 PM PST, ThousandEyes noticed issues connecting to G Suite, a critical application for our organization. Reviewing ThousandEyes Endpoint Agent stats, we noticed this was impacting all users at the ThousandEyes office. The outage not only affected G Suite, but also Google Search as well as Google Analytics. What caught our attention was that traffic to Google was getting dropped at China Telecom. Why would traffic from a San Francisco office traversing to Google go all the way to China? We also noticed a Russian ISP in the traffic path, which definitely sparked some concerns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.thousandeyes.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Figure-1-Endpoint-agent-path-visualization-China.png&quot; alt=&quot;Figure 1: Traffic from ThousandEyes users in San Francisco getting dropped in China.&quot; title=&quot;Figure 1: Traffic from ThousandEyes users in San Francisco getting dropped in China.&quot; width=&quot;1058&quot; height=&quot;850&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-5015&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Figure 1: Traffic from ThousandEyes users in San Francisco getting dropped in China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon further investigation, we saw that several ThousandEyes vantage points around the globe were reporting similar unusual traffic routing, all terminating at China Telecom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.thousandeyes.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Figure-2-Google-path-visualization-blackholed.png&quot; alt=&quot;Figure 2: Traffic from multiple locations to Google getting black-holed at China Telecom.&quot; title=&quot;Figure 2: Traffic from multiple locations to Google getting black-holed at China Telecom.&quot; width=&quot;1035&quot; height=&quot;741&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-5016&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Figure 2: Traffic from multiple locations to Google getting black-holed at China Telecom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThousandEyes BGP Route Visualization painted an interesting picture. Traffic from Paris to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Google&quot;&gt;www.google.com&lt;/a&gt; resolved to 216.58.204.132. While Google announces many /24 prefixes to cover its IP address range, this address was not covered by a /24 prefix. Instead, it was covered by a /19 prefix. We saw a suspicious announcement for 216.58.192.0/19 appear after about 12:45 pm PST with a convoluted AS path that included TransTelecom (AS 20485) in Russia, China Telecom (AS 4809) in China and MainOne (AS 37282), a small ISP in Nigeria.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.thousandeyes.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Figure-3-BGP-route-visualization-best-path-to-Google-via-Russia-China-Nigeria.png&quot; alt=&quot;Figure 3: Suspicious announcement for 216.58.192.0/19.&quot; title=&quot;Figure 3: Suspicious announcement for 216.58.192.0/19 showing the best path to Google via Russia, China and Nigeria.&quot; width=&quot;969&quot; height=&quot;504&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-5014&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Figure 3: Suspicious announcement for 216.58.192.0/19 showing the best path to Google via Russia, China and Nigeria.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The traffic paths we saw mirrored the BGP AS Path, except all the traffic slammed into the &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.thousandeyes.com/deconstructing-great-firewall-china/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Deconstructing the Great Firewall of China&quot;&gt;great firewall&lt;/a&gt;, terminating at China Telecom edge router. For a detailed look, at this incident, follow this ThousandEyes &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwoyqhbkr.share.thousandeyes.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Google - ThousandEyes Snapshot&quot;&gt;snapshot share link&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This incident at a minimum caused a massive denial of service to G Suite and Google Search. However, this also put valuable Google traffic in the hands of ISPs in countries with a long history of Internet surveillance. Overall ThousandEyes detected over 180 prefixes affected by this route leak, which covers a vast scope of Google services. Our analysis indicates that the origin of this leak was the BGP peering relationship between MainOne, the Nigerian provider, and China Telecom. MainOne has a peering relationship with Google via IXPN in Lagos and has direct routes to Google, which leaked into China Telecom. These leaked routes propagated from China Telecom, via TransTelecom to NTT and other transit ISPs. We also noticed that this leak was primarily propagated by business-grade transit providers and did not impact consumer ISP networks as much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On November 13, MainOne tweeted out that the root cause of the problem was in fact due to a configuration error.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.thousandeyes.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Figure-4-MainOne-tweet-BGP-upgrade-filters-error.png&quot; alt=&quot;Figure 4: MainOne owns up to the configuration error that brought Google services down.&quot; title=&quot;Figure 4: MainOne owns up to the configuration error that brought Google services down.&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;192&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-5033&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Figure 4: MainOne owns up to the configuration error that brought Google services down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This incident further underscores one of the fundamental weaknesses in the fabric of the Internet. BGP was designed to be a chain of trust between well-meaning ISPs and universities that blindly believe the information they receive. It hasn’t evolved to reflect the complex commercial and geopolitical relationships that exist between ISPs and nations today. While verification methods like ROA exist, few ISPs use them. Even corporations like Google with massive resources at their disposal are not immune from this sort of BGP leak or malicious hijacks. MainOne took 74 minutes to either notice or be notified of the issue and fix it, and it took about three quarters of an hour more for services to come back up. Most enterprises who don’t have Google’s reach and resources may not be able to resolve the issue as quickly, which can significantly impact business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BGP-related incidents have been on the rise. In April 2018 we saw a brazen &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.thousandeyes.com/amazon-route-53-dns-and-bgp-hijack/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Anatomy of a BGP Hijack on Amazon's Route 53 DNS Service&quot;&gt;cryptocurrency heist&lt;/a&gt; involving the hijack of an entire DNS provider (Route 53). Just a year before that, in April 2017, we saw the &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.thousandeyes.com/rostelecom-route-leak-targets-ecommerce-services/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Rostelecom Route Leak Targets E-Commerce Services&quot;&gt;Rostelecom BGP route leak&lt;/a&gt; which affected a large number of e-commerce and financial services websites. While the ISP community recognizes the scope of the problem, and solutions such as ROA and IRR filtering exist, none of them are silver bullets and implementing them risks breaking the Internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the absence of guarantees, enterprises need to continuously monitor their BGP routes and detect such incidents quickly in order to mitigate any service impacts to their business. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thousandeyes.com/resources/detecting-hijacks-and-leaks-webinar&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Detecting Hijacks and Leaks&quot;&gt;Learn more&lt;/a&gt; about how you can use ThousandEyes to detect BGP hijacks and leaks. &lt;a class=&quot;inline-subscribe-textlink&quot; title=&quot;Subscribe&quot; data-subscribe-modal=&quot;on&quot;&gt;Subscribe&lt;/a&gt; to the ThousandEyes blog to stay up to date on outage analyses like these and best practices on delivering a reliable Internet experience.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 10:10:54 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>doener</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Internet Vulnerability Takes Down Google</og:title>
<og:description>BGP route leak interrupts access to Google’s services throughout the world. Traffic rerouted via Russia and China and slammed into the great firewall.</og:description>
<og:url>https://blog.thousandeyes.com/internet-vulnerability-takes-down-google/</og:url>
<og:image>https://blog.thousandeyes.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Internet-Vulnerability-Takes-Down-Google-1200x630.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.thousandeyes.com/internet-vulnerability-takes-down-google/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Cadbury ‘pushing orangutans towards extinction by wrecking habitat for palm oil’</title>
<link>https://www.independent.co.uk/environment/orangutans-palm-oil-habitat-rainforest-cadbury-mondelez-oreos-indonesia-greenpeace-a8630801.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.independent.co.uk/environment/orangutans-palm-oil-habitat-rainforest-cadbury-mondelez-oreos-indonesia-greenpeace-a8630801.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The maker of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.independent.co.uk/topic/cadbury&quot;&gt;Cadbury&lt;/a&gt; chocolate bars, Oreo biscuits and Ritz crackers is accused of destroying tens of thousands of hectares of orangutan habitat in just two years for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.independent.co.uk/topic/palm-oil&quot;&gt;palm oil&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suppliers to food giant &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.independent.co.uk/topic/mondelez&quot;&gt;Mondelez&lt;/a&gt; have destroyed 70,000 hectares since 2016, analysis by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.independent.co.uk/topic/Greenpeace&quot;&gt;Greenpeace&lt;/a&gt; International claims, pushing the primate further towards extinction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The areas razed to the ground include 25,000 hectares of habitations in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.independent.co.uk/topic/Indonesia&quot;&gt;Indonesia&lt;/a&gt; that are home to the critically endangered orangutan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;aside class=&quot;inline-block inline-related align-left item-count-4&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;box-title&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mondelez, which is one of the world’s biggest buyers of palm oil, uses it in many of its most popular products, including Cadbury and Roses chocolates, Oreos and Ritz crackers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new investigation, carried out through mapping Indonesia, discovered that between 2015 and 2017, 22 of the company’s palm oil suppliers cleared at least 70,000 hectares of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.independent.co.uk/topic/Rainforest&quot;&gt;rainforest&lt;/a&gt; – an area bigger than the City of Chicago, where Mondelez is based.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a 31-page report detailing the supply chains of the main brands the charity says are responsible for destruction, Greenpeace points the finger largely at the producer of some of Britain’s favourite chocolates and snacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The report says that although Mondelez claims to have been purchasing entirely responsible palm oil since 2013, “in practice almost 95 per cent of the palm oil it buys is covered by ‘book-and-claim’ certificates – by far the weakest of the certification models offered by the main palm oil industry body, the Roundtable on Sustainable Palm Oil (RSPO)”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Orangutans are literally dying for a biscuit&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Greenpeace’s Kiki Taufik
&lt;p&gt;“This means that the plantations and producer groups from which the overwhelming majority of the palm oil that Mondelez purchases is sourced are not governed by any sustainability initiatives,” the study claims.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greenpeace’s campaign against destructive palm oil hit the headlines over the weekend when a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.independent.co.uk/news/uk/home-news/iceland-christmas-advert-2018-deforestation-palm-oil-greenpeace-emma-thompson-political-a8625381.html&quot;&gt;video that Iceland repurposed for a Christmas advert&lt;/a&gt; was banned from television for being “political”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Campaigners have warned “it’s now or never” for Indonesia’s critically endangered orangutans, which are being killed at a rate of 25 a day as natural vegetation is bulldozed to make way for palm plantations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rang-tan: Iceland’s banned TV Christmas advert protests palm oil industry&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In September this year Greenpeace International published Final Countdown, a report that showed Mondelez was sourcing palm oil from 22 of 25 destructive producer groups. “Alarmingly, these are just the cases that Greenpeace was able to identify – Mondelez sources from hundreds of palm oil companies and this destruction is likely just the tip of the iceberg,” it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Orangutans are critically endangered (&lt;span class=&quot;scayt-misspell-word&quot; data-scayt-word=&quot;istock&quot; data-wsc-lang=&quot;en_GB&quot;&gt;istock&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kiki Taufik, head of Greenpeace Southeast Asia’s Indonesia forests campaign, said: “It’s outrageous that despite promising to clean up its palm oil almost 10 years ago, Mondelez is still trading with forest destroyers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Palm oil can be made without destroying forests, yet our investigation discovered that Mondelez suppliers are still trashing forests and wrecking orangutan habitat, pushing these beautiful and intelligent creatures to the brink of extinction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“They’re literally dying for a biscuit.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bornean &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.independent.co.uk/topic/orangutans&quot;&gt;orangutan&lt;/a&gt; numbers have halved in 16 years, studies show, and both the Sumatran and newly discovered Tapanuli orangutan lost more than half their habitat between 1985 and 2007.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All three species are classified by the International Union for Conservation of Nature as critically endangered, along with the Sumatran tiger and Sumatran rhino.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A spokeswoman for Mondelez International told &lt;em&gt;The Independent&lt;/em&gt; the company was committed to eradicating deforestation in the palm oil supply and it was actively working with suppliers to ensure palm oil was fully traceable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We’re calling on our suppliers to further map and monitor the plantations where oil is grown so we can drive further traceability. We’re excluding 12 upstream suppliers from our supply chain who have not met our standards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“For many years we have been calling for 100 per cent sustainable and we’re making good progress on our palm oil action plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-preview-wrapper&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;icon-chevron dir-left&quot; role=&quot;button&quot; tabindex=&quot;&quot; on=&quot;tap:gallery-lightbox-3443241&quot;&gt; Created with Sketch.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;icon-chevron dir-right&quot; role=&quot;button&quot; tabindex=&quot;&quot; on=&quot;tap:gallery-lightbox-3443241&quot;&gt; Created with Sketch.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-contents&quot;&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;1/3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greenpeace&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;2/3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greenpeace&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;3/3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getty Images&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;1/3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greenpeace&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;2/3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greenpeace&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;count&quot;&gt;3/3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getty Images&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This includes actionable steps to ensure the palm oil we buy is produced on legally held land, does not lead to deforestation or loss of peat land, respects human rights and does not use forced or child labour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“At the end of 2017, 96 per cent of our palm oil was traceable back to mill and 99 per cent was from suppliers with policies aligned to ours.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She added that Mondelez was calling on suppliers to improve practices and to engage third-party suppliers to ensure production was fully sustainable and traceable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We will continue to prioritise suppliers that meet our principles, and exclude those that don’t,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 07:37:48 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>dsr12</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.independent.co.uk/environment/orangutans-palm-oil-habitat-rainforest-cadbury-mondelez-oreos-indonesia-greenpeace-a8630801.html</og:url>
<og:title>Chocolate giant Cadbury ‘still pushing orangutans towards extinction'</og:title>
<og:description>Destruction likely to be just the tip of the iceberg, campaigners warn</og:description>
<og:image>https://static.independent.co.uk/s3fs-public/thumbnails/image/2018/11/13/00/orangutan.jpg</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.independent.co.uk/environment/orangutans-palm-oil-habitat-rainforest-cadbury-mondelez-oreos-indonesia-greenpeace-a8630801.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>