<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Rethinking GPS: Engineering Next-Gen Location at Uber</title>
<link>https://ubere.ng/2qLlaFH</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://ubere.ng/2qLlaFH</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Location and navigation using&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Global_Positioning_System&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;global positioning systems&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;(GPS) is deeply embedded in our daily lives, and is particularly crucial to Uber’s services. To orchestrate quick, efficient pickups, our GPS technologies need to know the locations of matched riders and drivers, as well as provide navigation guidance from a driver’s current location to where the rider needs to be picked up, and then, to the rider’s chosen destination. For this process to work seamlessly, the location estimates for riders and drivers need to be as precise as possible.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Since&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Global_Positioning_System&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;the (literal!) launch of GPS in 1973&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, we have advanced our understanding of the world, experienced exponential growth in the computational power available to us, and developed powerful algorithms to model uncertainty from fields like robotics. While our lives have become increasingly dependent on GPS, the fundamentals of how GPS works have not changed that much, which leads to significant performance limitations. In our opinion, it is time to rethink some of the starting assumptions that were true in 1973 regarding where and how we use GPS, as well as the computational power and additional information we can bring to bear to improve it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;While GPS works well under clear skies, its location estimates can be wildly inaccurate (with a margin of error of 50 meters or more) when we need it the most: in densely populated and highly built-up urban areas, where many of our users are located. To overcome this challenge, we developed a software upgrade to GPS for Android which substantially improves location accuracy in urban environments via a client-server architecture that utilizes 3D maps and performs sophisticated probabilistic computations on GPS data available through&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/guide/topics/sensors/gnss.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Android’s GNSS APIs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;In this article, we discuss why GPS can perform poorly in urban environments and outline how we fix it using advanced signal processing algorithms deployed at scale on our server infrastructure.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_1324&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; readability=&quot;35&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/image3.gif&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-1324 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/image3.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1416&quot; height=&quot;980&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Figure 1: The above GIF offers a comparison of standard GPS (red) against our improved location estimate (blue) for a pickup from Uber HQ in San Francisco. Our estimated location closely follows the true path taken by the rider, while GPS shows very large excursions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span&gt;A bit of background on GPS/GNSS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Before discussing our approach in detail, let us do a quick recap of how GPS works in order to understand why it can be inaccurate in high-rise urban environments.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;GPS is a network of more than 30 satellites operated by the U.S. government, orbiting the earth at an altitude of about 20,000 kilometers. (Most cell phones these days can pick up similar Russian “&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/GLONASS&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;GLONASS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;” satellites too.)  These satellites send out radio frequency signals that GPS receivers, such as those found in cell phones, can lock onto. Importantly, these satellites advertise the time at which they launch their signals.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;For each satellite whose signal the receiver processes, the difference between reception time and launch time (time-of-flight), multiplied by the speed of light, is called the&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pseudorange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;pseudorange&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;If the satellite and receiver’s clocks are synchronized, and the signal travels along the straight line-of-sight path, then this would equal the actual distance to the satellite. However, the clocks are not synchronized, so the receiver needs to solve for four unknowns, its own 3D coordinates on the globe, and its clock bias. Thus, we need a minimum of four satellites (four equations) to solve for these four unknowns.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;If we ignore clock bias, we can intuitively interpret the location estimate performed by the GPS receiver by intersecting spheres centered at the satellites with the radius of each sphere given by the pseudorange. In practice, a GPS receiver processes signals from a significantly larger number of satellites (up to 20 GPS and GLONASS satellites are visible in an open field), and having more than the minimum number of equations provides extra robustness to noise, blockages, etc. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;In addition to GPS and GLONASS, some new/future receivers can/will process signals from other satellite systems.  Other navigation satellite systems coming online are&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Galileo_(satellite_navigation)&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Galileo&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, operated by the European Union,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;IRNSS&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;in India, and&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BeiDou_Navigation_Satellite_System&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;BeiDou&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, operated by China. The more general term&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Satellite_navigation&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;GNSS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;(global navigation satellite systems) encompasses these systems. (We will use this term in the remainder of the article.)  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_1325&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; readability=&quot;34&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-1325&quot; src=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/image1-4-968x1024.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;635&quot; srcset=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/image1-4-968x1024.png 968w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/image1-4-284x300.png 284w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/image1-4-768x812.png 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Figure 2: In this simplified interpretation of GPS receiver computation, spheres intersect at the center of known satellite locations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span&gt;Why GNSS location is inaccurate in urban environments&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;A major assumption behind GNSS-based positioning is that the receiver has a direct line-of-sight to each satellite whose pseudorange it is computing. This works seamlessly in open terrain but really breaks down in urban environments, as shown in Figure 3, below:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_3071&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/image9.jpg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-3071&quot; src=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/image9.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;338&quot; srcset=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/image9.jpg 1920w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/image9-300x169.jpg 300w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/image9-768x432.jpg 768w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/image9-1024x576.jpg 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Figure 3: Line-of-sight blockage and strong reflections can cause large GPS errors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Buildings often block the lines of sight to satellites, so the receiver frequently processes signals corresponding to strong reflections off of other buildings. The significant inaccuracy (positive offsets) in pseudoranges resulting from this phenomenon can lead to errors in position estimates that can be 50 meters or more in urban canyons. Most of us who have wandered,  driven around, or requested an Uber in big cities have experienced these problems first hand.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span&gt;Satellite signal strengths to the rescue&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Our approach to improving location accuracy makes a feature out of the very blockage of GNSS signals that causes trouble for standard receivers.  How? For Android phones, the LocationManager API provides not just the phone’s position estimate, but also the signal-to-noise ratio (SNR) for each GNSS satellite in view. If we put this “signal strength” information together with 3D maps, then we can obtain very valuable location information. Figure 4, below, shows a simplified version of how satellite SNRs and 3D maps can be used to infer which side of the street we are on:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_3072&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; readability=&quot;35&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/image8.jpg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-3072&quot; src=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/image8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;338&quot; srcset=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/image8.jpg 1920w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/image8-300x169.jpg 300w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/image8-768x432.jpg 768w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/image8-1024x576.jpg 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Figure 4: Satellite signal strengths, when combined with 3D maps, provide valuable location information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Zooming into the details, our approach relies on putting the following intuition in a mathematical framework: if the SNR for a satellite is low, then the line-of-sight path is probably blocked or shadowed; if the SNR is high, then the LOS is probably clear. The qualifier “probably” is crucial here: even when the receiver is in a shadowed area, strong reflected signals can still reach it, and even if it is in a clear area, the received signal can be weak (because of destructive interference between LOS and reflected paths, a phenomenon referred to as&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.radio-electronics.com/info/propagation/multipath/multipath-fading.php&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;multipath fading&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;).  Also, in general, the 3D map is not entirely accurate, and certainly does not capture random blockages by large moving objects not in the map, like trucks. This adds additional uncertainty to the process.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span&gt;Probabilistic shadow matching using ray tracing&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;While the intuition on satellite signal strengths carrying useful location information is sound, it must be fleshed out within a probabilistic framework. For any possible location for the receiver, we can check whether the ray joining the location to the satellite is blocked using our 3D map. Now, using a model for the probability distribution of the SNR under LOS and shadowed conditions, we determine the likelihood of the SNR measured for that satellite. For example, if the location is shadowed, then the likelihood of a high SNR is low. The overall likelihood of a given location, based on the satellite SNRs, is the product of the likelihoods corresponding to the different satellites. By doing this over a grid of possible locations, we obtain a likelihood surface—or heat map—of possible receiver locations, based on satellite signal strengths alone. We call this procedure&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.insidegnss.com/node/4628&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;probabilistic shadow matching&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_1328&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; readability=&quot;33&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-1328&quot; src=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/image8-2-1024x622.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;364&quot; srcset=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/image8-2-1024x622.png 1024w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/image8-2-300x182.png 300w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/image8-2-768x467.png 768w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/image8-2.png 1508w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Figure 5: Ray tracing from one possible location to each satellite for probabilistic shadow matching. This is done for thousands of hypothesized locations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The likelihood surface, or heat map, from probabilistic shadow matching summarizes the information from satellite SNR measurements. However, as we see from Figure 6 below, this heat map can be pretty complicated. It can have many distinct, widely separated hotpots (local maxima) often corresponding to a given side of the street, but sometimes still in the wrong location (i.e., phantoms).  In order to narrow down our location estimate and to avoid locking onto the phantoms, we must now fuse this information with even more information.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_1329&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; readability=&quot;38&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-1329&quot; src=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/image9-2-1024x530.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;310&quot; srcset=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/image9-2-1024x530.png 1024w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/image9-2-300x155.png 300w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/image9-2-768x397.png 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Figure 6. A location heat map computed based on satellite signal strengths can have many hotspots. In the above example, our improved location estimate (blue path, black uncertainty ellipse) follows ground truth (yellow path), whereas standard GPS (red path, gray uncertainty ellipse) is inaccurate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;span&gt;Information fusion via particle filter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;For Android phones, the information we use in addition to satellite signal strengths is usually just the standard GNSS position fix, but can also be Android Fused locations, which may include WiFi-based positioning. Since this location can be very inaccurate, single time instant (one-shot) fusion of GNSS fix with shadow matching likelihoods typically leads to poor performance.  In order to take advantage of the information from satellite signal strengths, we trust GPS less in built-up areas (the gray GPS uncertainty ellipse in Figure 6 is a typical model that we use, while the black uncertainty ellipse for improved GPS is an output of our algorithm). We therefore use past measurements and constrain the location evolution over time using a motion model adapted to the application (e.g., pedestrian vs. vehicular motion). This is accomplished by using a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Particle_filter&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;particle filter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, which approximates the probability distribution of the receiver’s location at any given time by a set of weighted particles. In other words, we estimate where the phone is using thousands of hypothesized locations (i.e., particles).  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Over time, the probability weights and particle locations evolve based on the measurements and the motion model. Since the heat map from probabilistic shadow matching has so many local maxima and because the GNSS fix can have such large outliers, we cannot use standard techniques such as the&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kalman_filter&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Kalman filter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;or the&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Extended_Kalman_filter&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;extended Kalman filter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, which rely on the tracked probability distribution being well approximated by a bell-shaped&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Normal_distribution&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Gaussian distribution&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;. The particle filter allows us to approximate arbitrary distributions, at the expense of higher complexity, and this is where our server infrastructure comes in.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_1330&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; readability=&quot;36&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-1330&quot; src=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/image5-3-1024x493.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;289&quot; srcset=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/image5-3-1024x493.png 1024w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/image5-3-300x145.png 300w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/image5-3-768x370.png 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Figure 7: The location estimate obtained as the weighted centroid of the hotspot provided by the particle filter often corrects very large GPS errors. The uncertainty radius (white circle) for improved GPS is based on the spread of the particle set, and is often a more realistic measure than the small uncertainty radius (black circle) typically reported for raw GPS even when the actual position errors are large.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span&gt;From signal processing to software at scale&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The combination of particle filtering and ray tracing introduces complexity to the back-end server ecosystem, making for a very stateful service.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_1331&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; readability=&quot;39&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-1331&quot; src=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/image2-2-1024x707.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;415&quot; srcset=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/image2-2-1024x707.png 1024w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/image2-2-300x207.png 300w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/image2-2-768x531.png 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Figure 8: Uber’s GPS improvement system is composed of a particle filter service, 3D map tile management service, a manager service, Uber HTTP API, and cloud storage, and integrates with other Uber services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;There are two kinds of state at play: per-user particle filter state and per-region 3D maps used for ray tracing. The use of particle filters necessitates a level of server affinity. Each new request to our service must be routed to the same back-end server for processing in order to update the correct particle filter. Additionally, due to the large size of 3D maps, each back-end server can only hold a few small sections of the 3D world in RAM.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Since each server can only hold a few square kilometers of map data, not all servers are capable of serving all users. Essentially, implementing the back-end systems for our solution necessitated the creation of a sticky session routing layer that takes server 3D map state into account. In addition to internal tests and performance evaluations, we also run spot checks on our own Android devices using an internal version of the Uber rider app, as illustrated in Figure 9, below:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-3074&quot; src=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/image4-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; srcset=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/image4-1.png 778w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/image4-1-300x110.png 300w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/image4-1-768x280.png 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_3073&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; readability=&quot;33&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/image7.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-3073&quot; src=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/image7.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;711&quot; srcset=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/image7.png 1080w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/image7-169x300.png 169w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/image7-768x1365.png 768w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/image7-576x1024.png 576w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 400px) 100vw, 400px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Figure 9: Red dot/blue dot comparison on our internal version of the rider app allows Uber employees to spot check our solution anywhere in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span&gt;Moving forward&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Accurate estimation of rider and driver location is a crucial requirement for fulfilling Uber’s mission of providing transportation as reliable as running water, everywhere, for everyone.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;To meet our mission, the Sensing, Intelligence, and Research team is working on a variety of approaches for improving location with creative use of sensors and computation on mobile devices, coupled with the computational power of our server infrastructure. The combination of advanced signal processing, machine learning algorithms, and software at scale has huge potential, and we are always looking for talented and highly motivated individuals (&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.uber.com/careers/list/14345/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;software and algorithms engineers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.uber.com/careers/list/13203/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;data visualization engineers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, and &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.uber.com/careers/list/37852/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;machine learning engineers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;) to join us to help realize this potential.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Danny Iland, Andrew Irish, Upamanyu Madhow, &amp;amp; Brian Sandler are members of Uber’s Sensing, Inference and Research team. Danny, Andrew, and Upamanyu were part of the original group that led this research at the University of California, Santa Barbara. After spinning this work into a startup, they demonstrated server-based particle filtering for location improvement in San Francisco using a 3D map constructed from publicly available aerial LiDAR data. They joined Uber in July 2016.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;div id=&quot;sexy-author-bio&quot; class=&quot;danny-iland&quot; readability=&quot;8.0480769230769&quot;&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;sab-social-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;sab-sablinkedin&quot; href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/daniel-iland-33b252b/&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;&lt;img id=&quot;sig-sablinkedin&quot; alt=&quot;Danny Iland on Linkedin&quot; src=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/plugins/sexy-author-bio/public/assets/images/flat-circle/sablinkedin.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;sab-gravatar&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/author/danny-iland/&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Danny Iland&quot; src=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/up_8f7223e3-b7a5-432b-b56f-ff7197ba05bf-1.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Danny Iland is a senior software engineer on Uber’s Sensing, Inference, and Research team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;sexy-author-bio&quot; class=&quot;andrew-irish&quot; readability=&quot;7.9811320754717&quot;&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;sab-social-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;sab-sablinkedin&quot; href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/andrew-irish-565b6324/&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;&lt;img id=&quot;sig-sablinkedin&quot; alt=&quot;Andrew Irish on Linkedin&quot; src=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/plugins/sexy-author-bio/public/assets/images/flat-circle/sablinkedin.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;sab-gravatar&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/author/andrew-irish/&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Andrew Irish&quot; src=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/up_aea689ce-7016-4311-b4ce-edd8ca585f9c.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andrew Irish is a senior software engineer on Uber’s Sensing, Inference, and Research team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;sexy-author-bio&quot; class=&quot;upamanyu-madhow&quot; readability=&quot;8.1455696202532&quot;&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;sab-social-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;sab-sablinkedin&quot; href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/upamanyu-madhow-7a124512/&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;&lt;img id=&quot;sig-sablinkedin&quot; alt=&quot;Upamanyu Madhow on Linkedin&quot; src=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/plugins/sexy-author-bio/public/assets/images/flat-circle/sablinkedin.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;sab-gravatar&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/author/upamanyu-madhow/&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Upamanyu Madhow&quot; src=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/bg_919763ee-15a3-45ca-a907-6ea7c99faab9-mpI9EDSTIR.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upamanyu Madhow is a researcher at Uber and a professor of Electrical and Computer Engineering at the University of California, Santa Barbara.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;sexy-author-bio&quot; class=&quot;brian-sandler&quot; readability=&quot;9.2168674698795&quot;&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;sab-social-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;sab-sablinkedin&quot; href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/sandlerbrian/&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;&lt;img id=&quot;sig-sablinkedin&quot; alt=&quot;Brian Sandler on Linkedin&quot; src=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/plugins/sexy-author-bio/public/assets/images/flat-circle/sablinkedin.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;sab-gravatar&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/author/brian-sandler/&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Brian Sandler&quot; src=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/0.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brian Sandler was a summer intern on Uber’s Sensing, Inference, and Research team and is currently a Ph.D student with the University of Pennsylvania.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;post-meta&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Categories: &lt;a href=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/category/general-engineering/&quot; rel=&quot;category tag&quot;&gt;General Engineering&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;muted&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tags: &lt;a href=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/tag/3d-mapping/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;3D mapping&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/tag/android/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/tag/beidou/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;BeiDou&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/tag/galileo/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;Galileo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/tag/global-positioning-system/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;Global Positioning System&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/tag/glonass/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;GLONASS&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/tag/gps/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;GPS&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/tag/inference/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;Inference&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/tag/maps/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;maps&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/tag/particle-filter/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;Particle Filter&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/tag/probabilistic-shadow-matching/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;Probabilistic Shadow Matching&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/tag/ray-tracing/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;Ray Tracing&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/tag/research/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;Research&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/tag/sensing/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;Sensing&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/tag/signal-processing/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;Signal Processing&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/tag/uber-engineering/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;Uber Engineering&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/tag/uber-maps/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;Uber Maps&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/tag/ucsb/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;UCSB&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 18:27:40 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mkvorwerck</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Rethinking GPS: Engineering Next-Gen Location at Uber</og:title>
<og:description>Uber’s Sensing, Inference, and Research team released a software upgrade for GPS on Android phones that significantly improves location accuracy in urban environments.</og:description>
<og:url>https://eng.uber.com/rethinking-gps/</og:url>
<og:image>http://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/Facebook.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://eng.uber.com/rethinking-gps/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Wells Fargo Hit with $1B in Fines</title>
<link>https://www.npr.org/sections/thetwo-way/2018/04/20/604279604/wells-fargo-hit-with-1-billion-in-fines-over-consumer-abuses</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.npr.org/sections/thetwo-way/2018/04/20/604279604/wells-fargo-hit-with-1-billion-in-fines-over-consumer-abuses</guid>
<description>&lt;div id=&quot;res604304922&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap image large&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;imagewrap&quot; data-crop-type=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2018/04/20/gettyimages-861003112_slide-bd3ac74af19e8183d9efdf1642d6f283f55431fb-s1100-c15.jpg&quot; data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2018/04/20/gettyimages-861003112_slide-bd3ac74af19e8183d9efdf1642d6f283f55431fb-s1100.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img lazyOnLoad&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;credit-caption&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-wrap&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image caption&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Consumer Financial Protection Bureau is levying a $1 billion fine against Wells Fargo as punishment for the banking giant's actions in its mortgage and auto loan businesses. &lt;strong class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Spencer Platt/Getty Images&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong class=&quot;hide-caption&quot;&gt;hide caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;strong class=&quot;toggle-caption&quot;&gt;toggle caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Spencer Platt/Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;enlarge_measure&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img_wrap&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2018/04/20/gettyimages-861003112_slide-bd3ac74af19e8183d9efdf1642d6f283f55431fb-s1200.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;enlarge_html&quot; readability=&quot;6.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image_data&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;The Consumer Financial Protection Bureau is levying a $1 billion fine against Wells Fargo as punishment for the banking giant's actions in its mortgage and auto loan businesses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Spencer Platt/Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Consumer Financial Protection Bureau is levying a $1 billion fine against Wells Fargo — a record for the agency — as punishment for the banking giant's actions in its mortgage and auto loan businesses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wells Fargo's &quot;conduct caused and was likely to cause substantial injury to consumers,&quot; the agency said in its filings about the bank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wells Fargo broke the law by charging some consumers too much over mortgage interest rate-lock extensions and by running a mandatory insurance program that added insurance costs and fees into some borrowers' auto loans, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.consumerfinance.gov/about-us/newsroom/bureau-consumer-financial-protection-announces-settlement-wells-fargo-auto-loan-administration-and-mortgage-practices/&quot;&gt;the CFPB said&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;res604308916&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap internallink insettwocolumn inset2col&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bucket img&quot;&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;featuredStackSquareImage583014020&quot; href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/sections/thetwo-way/2018/02/03/583014020/fed-slaps-unusual-penalty-on-wells-fargo-following-widespread-consumer-abuses&quot; data-metrics=&quot;{&amp;quot;category&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Story to Story&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;action&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Click Internal Link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;label&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https:\/\/www.npr.org\/sections\/thetwo-way\/2018\/02\/03\/583014020\/fed-slaps-unusual-penalty-on-wells-fargo-following-widespread-consumer-abuses&amp;quot;}&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2018/02/03/ap_1205060105615_sq-b7476b9f811b18e99d7e86854601fcc344acb491-s100-c15.jpg&quot; data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2018/02/03/ap_1205060105615_sq-b7476b9f811b18e99d7e86854601fcc344acb491-s100.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img lazyOnLoad&quot; alt=&quot;Fed Slaps Unusual Penalty On Wells Fargo Following 'Widespread Consumer Abuses'&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CFPB said Friday that the penalty is part of a settlement with Wells Fargo, which has pledged to repair the financial harm to consumers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because of the penalties, Wells Fargo says, it is adjusting its preliminary financial results for the first quarter of 2018, shifting $800 million in its balance sheet — and dropping its net income for the quarter to $4.7 billion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new federal action against the bank comes less than two years after &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/sections/thetwo-way/2016/09/08/493130449/wells-fargo-to-pay-around-190-million-over-fake-accounts-that-sparked-bonuses&quot;&gt;Wells Fargo was fined $185 million&lt;/a&gt; over what the CFPB called &quot;the widespread illegal practice of secretly opening unauthorized deposit and credit card accounts.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those earlier penalties included a $100 million fine by the CFPB — a record at the time. The new punishment stems from the agency's findings that Wells Fargo abused its relationship with home and auto loan borrowers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wells Fargo was also punished by the U.S. Office of the Comptroller of the Currency over its risk management practices, with the agency collecting a $500 million penalty as part of the fines announced Friday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id=&quot;ad-backstage-wrap&quot; aria-label=&quot;advertisement&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;res604315593&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap internallink insettwocolumn inset2col&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bucket img&quot;&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;featuredStackSquareImage604236275&quot; href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/sections/thetwo-way/2018/04/20/604236275/national-teachers-union-cuts-ties-with-wells-fargo-over-banks-ties-to-nra-guns&quot; data-metrics=&quot;{&amp;quot;category&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Story to Story&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;action&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Click Internal Link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;label&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https:\/\/www.npr.org\/sections\/thetwo-way\/2018\/04\/20\/604236275\/national-teachers-union-cuts-ties-with-wells-fargo-over-banks-ties-to-nra-guns&amp;quot;}&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2018/04/20/ap_17305670835737_sq-bab6ab2418fe429653ba75315877775e5e6ba365-s100-c15.jpg&quot; data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2018/04/20/ap_17305670835737_sq-bab6ab2418fe429653ba75315877775e5e6ba365-s100.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img lazyOnLoad&quot; alt=&quot;National Teachers Union Cuts Ties With Wells Fargo Over Bank's Ties To NRA, Guns&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along with treating its customers unfairly, the OCC said, Wells Fargo had failed to maintain a compliance risk management program that was appropriate for a bank of its size and complexity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That failure, the OCC said, led Wells Fargo to &quot;engage in reckless unsafe or unsound practices and violations of law.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Auto loans, insurance and fees&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Problems in the way the Wells Fargo auto loan unit handled consumers' accounts exposed people to hundreds or thousands of dollars in premiums and fees. The issues were also found to have possibly contributed to thousands of cars being repossessed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CFPB said problems with the auto loan unit persisted for more than 10 years, from October 2005 to September 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lenders can require borrowers to maintain insurance on their vehicles — and if a borrower doesn't do that, there is a process that allows lenders to arrange for what is called force-placed insurance and add that cost to the loan. But Wells Fargo acknowledged that of the roughly 2 million car loans that it put into that program, it &quot;forcibly placed duplicative or unnecessary insurance on hundreds of thousands of those borrowers' vehicles.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For some borrowers, the bank also improperly maintained those force-placed policies on their accounts even after they secured adequate insurance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the CFPB, &quot;if borrowers failed to pay the amounts [Wells Fargo] charged them for the Force-Placed Insurance, they faced additional fees and, in some instances, experienced delinquency, loan default, and even repossession.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In one five-year period from 2011 to 2016, Wells Fargo acknowledged in the settlement, the extra costs of force-placed insurance may have played a role in at least 27,000 customers having their vehicles repossessed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Home loan rate locks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wells Fargo failed to follow its own policies in how it charged fees over locking in mortgage interest rates beyond the standard guaranteed window, the CFPB said, adding that the bank charged customers for the rate extension — even in cases in which the bank itself was the reason for delays in closing on a home loan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problems persisted for several years after the bank's internal audit identified the risk of harming consumers, according to the government's filing about the settlement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wells Fargo unfairly and inconsistently applied its policy on rate-extension fees from September 2013 through February 2017, the agency said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In February, Wells Fargo also faced a government reprimand in February, when the Federal Reserve took the rare step of &quot;restricting Wells Fargo's growth and demanding the replacement of four board members in response to 'widespread consumer abuses and compliance breakdowns' at the bank,&quot; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/sections/thetwo-way/2018/02/03/583014020/fed-slaps-unusual-penalty-on-wells-fargo-following-widespread-consumer-abuses&quot;&gt;as NPR reported&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the time, the Fed faulted Wells Fargo for maintaining a business strategy that prioritizes its own growth at the expense of risk management.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 16:43:47 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>smaili</dc:creator>
<og:title>Wells Fargo Hit With $1 Billion In Fines Over Home And Auto Loan Abuses</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.npr.org/sections/thetwo-way/2018/04/20/604279604/wells-fargo-hit-with-1-billion-in-fines-over-consumer-abuses</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>Some consumers were charged too much to extend the lock on their mortgage interest rates, and the bank's mandatory insurance program added unneeded costs and fees to borrowers' auto loans.</og:description>
<og:image>https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2018/04/20/gettyimages-861003112_wide-1d7e110f7ec152de8452cf597d4f09bfbe2ca3c4.jpg?s=1400</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.npr.org/sections/thetwo-way/2018/04/20/604279604/wells-fargo-hit-with-1-billion-in-fines-over-consumer-abuses</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Facebook has auto-enrolled users into a facial recognition test in Europe</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2018/04/20/just-say-no/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2018/04/20/just-say-no/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Facebook users in Europe are reporting that the company has started giving them the option to turn on its controversial facial recognition technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jimmy Nsubuga, a journalist at &lt;a href=&quot;http://metro.co.uk/2018/03/09/facebook-begins-test-banned-facial-recognition-system-uk-europe-7374305/&quot;&gt;Metro&lt;/a&gt;, is among several European Facebook users who have reporting getting notifications asking if they want to turn on face recognition technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook has previously said an opt-in option would be pushed out to all European users, and also globally, as part of changes to its T&amp;amp;Cs and consent flow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Europe the company is hoping to convince users to voluntarily allow it to deploy the privacy-hostile tech — which was turned off in the bloc after regulatory pressure, back in &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2012/09/21/facebook-turns-off-facial-recognition-in-the-eu-gets-the-all-clear-from-irelands-data-protection-commissioner-on-its-review/&quot;&gt;2012&lt;/a&gt;, when Facebook began using facial recognition to offer features such as automatically tagging users in photo uploads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But under &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/04/17/facebook-gdpr-changes/&quot;&gt;impending changes to its T&amp;amp;Cs&lt;/a&gt; — ostensibly to comply with the EU’s incoming GDPR data protection standard — the company has crafted a manipulative consent flow that tries to sell people on giving it their data; including filling in its own facial recognition blanks by convincing Europeans to agree to it grabbing and using their biometric data after all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users who choose not to switch on facial recognition still have to click through a ‘continue’ screen before they get to the off switch. On this screen Facebook attempts to convince them to turn it on — using manipulative examples of how the tech can “protect” them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As another Facebook user who has also already received the notifications — journalist, Jennifer Baker — points out, what it’s doing here is incredibly disingenuous — because it’s using fear to try to manipulate people’s choices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the EU’s incoming data protection framework Facebook cannot automatically opt users into facial recognition — it has to convince people to switch the tech on themselves. So it is emphasizing that users can choose whether or not to enable the technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But data protection experts we spoke to &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/04/18/data-experts-on-facebooks-gdpr-changes-expect-lawsuits/&quot;&gt;earlier this week&lt;/a&gt; do not believe Facebook’s approach to consent will be legal under GDPR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Essentially, this is big data-powered manipulation of human decision-making — until the ‘right’ answer (for Facebook’s business) is ‘selected’ by the user. In other words, not freely given, informed consent at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Legal challenges are certain at this point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Facebook spokeswoman confirmed to TechCrunch that any European users who are being asked about the tech now, ahead of the May 25 GDPR deadline, are part of its rollout of platform changes intended to comply with the incoming standard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The flow is not a test, it is part of a rollout we are doing across the EU,” she said. “We are asking people for opt-in consent for three things — third party data for ads, facial recognition and the permission to process their sensitive data.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She also confirmed that Facebook did run a test of “a very similar version of this flow to a small percentage of users in the EU back in March”, adding: “The flow + wording was broadly the same. At all times it was opt-in.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem is, given Facebook controls the entire consent flow, and can rely on big data insights gleaned from its own platform (of 2BN+ users), this is not even remotely a fair fight. Manipulated acceptance is not consent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But legal challenges take time. And in the meanwhile Facebook users are being &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/04/17/facebook-gdpr-changes/&quot;&gt;socially engineered&lt;/a&gt;, with selective examples and friction, into agreeing with things that align with the company’s data-harvesting business interests — handing over sensitive personal data without understanding the full implications of doing so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not clear exactly how many Facebook users were part of the earlier flow test. It’s likely the company used the aforementioned variations in wording to determine — via an A/B testing process — which consent screens were most successful at convincing people to accept the &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/02/08/chinese-police-are-getting-smart-glasses/&quot;&gt;highly privacy-hostile technology&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last month — when Facebook &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.siliconrepublic.com/enterprise/gdpr-facebook-facial-recognition&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; it would be rolling out “a limited test of some of the additional choices we’ll ask people to make as part of GDPR” — it also said it would start “by asking only a small percentage of people so that we can be sure everything is working properly”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly it did not put a number on how many people were involved in that test. And Facebook’s spokeswoman did not provide an answer when we asked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company was likely hoping the test would not attract too much attention — given how much GDPR news is flowing through its PR channels, and how much attention the topic is generally sucking up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But depending on how successful those tests prove to be at convincing Europeans to let it have and use their facial biometric data, millions of additional Facebook users could soon be providing the company with fresh streams of sensitive data — and having their fundamental rights trampled on, yet again, thanks to a very manipulative consent flow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article was updated with a series of corrections after Facebook confirmed the notifications are in fact the rollout of its new consent flow, not part of the earlier tests. It has also told us categorically that no users were auto-enrolled in facial recognition tech in Europe — even in the test. So we’ve updated this article accordingly. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 14:35:01 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Ours90</dc:creator>
<og:title>Facebook starts its facial recognition push to Europeans</og:title>
<og:description>Facebook users in Europe are reporting that the company has started giving them the option to turn on its controversial facial recognition technology. Jimmy Nsubuga, a journalist at Metro, is among several European Facebook users who have reporting getting notifications asking if they want to turn …</og:description>
<og:image>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/shutterstock_113956645.jpg?w=584</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2018/04/20/just-say-no/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2018/04/20/just-say-no/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Towards Scala 3</title>
<link>http://www.scala-lang.org/blog/2018/04/19/scala-3.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.scala-lang.org/blog/2018/04/19/scala-3.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;blog-detail-head&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thursday 19 April 2018&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Martin Odersky&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that Scala 2.13 is only a few months away, it’s time to consider the roadmap beyond it. It’s been no secret that the work on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/lampepfl/dotty&quot;&gt;Dotty&lt;/a&gt; over the last 5 years was intended to explore what a new Scala could look like. We are now at a stage where we can commit: Dotty will become Scala 3.0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, this statement invites many follow-up questions. Here are some answers we can already give today. We expect there will be more questions and answers as things shape up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;when-will-it-come-out&quot;&gt;When will it come out?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The intent is to publish the final Scala 3.0 soon after Scala 2.14. At the current release schedule (which might still change), that means early 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-scala-214-for&quot;&gt;What is Scala 2.14 for?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scala 2.14’s main focus will be on smoothing the migration to Scala 3. It will do this by defining migration tools, shim libraries, and targeted deprecations, among others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;whats-new-in-scala-3&quot;&gt;What’s new in Scala 3?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scala has pioneered the fusion of object-oriented and functional programming in a typed setting. Scala 3 will be a big step towards realizing the full potential of these ideas. Its main objectives are to&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;become more opinionated by promoting programming idioms we found to work well,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;simplify where possible,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;eliminate inconsistencies and surprising behavior,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;build on strong foundations to ensure the design hangs well together,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;consolidate language constructs to improve the language’s consistency, safety, ergonomics, and performance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The main language changes, either implemented or projected, are listed in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://dotty.epfl.ch/docs/reference/overview.html&quot;&gt;Reference section on the Dotty website&lt;/a&gt;. Many of the new features will be submitted to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.scala-lang.org/sips&quot;&gt;SIP&lt;/a&gt; process, subject to approval.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s worth emphasizing that Scala 2 and Scala 3 are fundamentally the same language. The compiler is new, but nearly everything Scala programmers already know about Scala 2 applies to Scala 3 as well, and most ordinary Scala 2 code will also work on Scala 3 with only minor changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-about-migration&quot;&gt;What about migration?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with previous Scala upgrades, Scala 3 is not binary compatible with Scala 2. They are mostly source compatible, but differences exist. However:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Scala 3 code can use Scala 2 artifacts because the Scala 3 compiler understands the classfile format for sources compiled with Scala 2.12 and upwards.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scala 3 and Scala 2 share the same standard library.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With some small tweaks it is possible to cross-build code for both Scala 2 and 3. We will provide a guide defining the shared language subset that can be compiled under both versions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Scala 3 compiler has a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;-language:Scala2&lt;/code&gt; option that lets it compile most Scala 2 code and at the same time highlights necessary rewritings as migration warnings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The compiler can perform many of the rewritings automatically using a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;-rewrite&lt;/code&gt; option.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Migration through automatic rewriting will also be offered through the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scalacenter/scalafix&quot;&gt;scalafix&lt;/a&gt; tool, which can convert sources to the cross-buildable language subset without requiring Scala 3 to be installed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;whats-the-expected-state-of-tool-support&quot;&gt;What’s the expected state of tool support?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Compiler: The Scala 3 compiler &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;dotc&lt;/code&gt; has been used to compile itself and a growing set of libraries for a number of years now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IDEs: IDE support is provided by having &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;dotc&lt;/code&gt; implement LSP, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://langserver.org&quot;&gt;Language Server Protocol&lt;/a&gt;, including standard operations such as completion and hyperlinking and more advanced ones such as find references or rename. There’s a &lt;a href=&quot;http://dotty.epfl.ch/docs/usage/ide-support.html&quot;&gt;VS Code plugin&lt;/a&gt; incorporating these operations. JetBrains has also released a first version of Scala 3 support in their &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.jetbrains.com/scala/2017/03/23/scala-plugin-for-intellij-idea-2017-1-cleaner-ui-sbt-shell-repl-worksheet-akka-support-and-more&quot;&gt;Scala IntelliJ plugin&lt;/a&gt;, and we intend to work with them on further improvements.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;REPL: A friendly REPL is supported by the compiler&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Docs: A revamped Scaladoc tool generates docs for viewing in a browser and (in the future) also in the IDE..&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build tools: There is a Dotty/Scala 3 plugin for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scala-sbt.org&quot;&gt;sbt&lt;/a&gt;, and we will also work on Scala 3 integration in other build tools.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-about-stability&quot;&gt;What about stability?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;A &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/lampepfl/dotty-community-build&quot;&gt;community build&lt;/a&gt; contains some &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/lampepfl/dotty-community-build/blob/master/src/test/scala/dotty/communitybuild/CommunityBuildTest.scala&quot;&gt;initial open source projects&lt;/a&gt; that are compiled nightly using Scala 3. We plan to add a lot more projects to the build between now and the final release.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We plan to use the period of developer previews to ensure that core projects are published for Scala 3.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We have incorporated most of the Scala 2 regression tests in the Scala 3 test suite and will keep including new tests.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the near future we plan to build all Scala 3 tools using a previous version of the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;dotc&lt;/code&gt; compiler itself. So far all tools are built first with the current Scala compiler and then again with &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;dotc&lt;/code&gt;. Basing the build exclusively on Scala 3 has the advantage that it lets us “eat our own dog food” and try out the usability of Scala 3’s new language feature on a larger scale.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;when-can-i-try-it-out&quot;&gt;When can I try it out?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can start working with Dotty now. See the &lt;a href=&quot;http://dotty.epfl.ch/docs/contributing/getting-started.html&quot;&gt;getting started&lt;/a&gt; guide. Dotty releases are published every 6 weeks. We expect to be in feature-freeze and to release developer previews for Scala 3.0 in the first half of 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-about-macros&quot;&gt;What about macros?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned! We are about to release another blog post specifically about that issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-can-i-help&quot;&gt;How can I help?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scala 3 is developed completely in the open at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/lampepfl/dotty&quot;&gt;https://github.com/lampepfl/dotty&lt;/a&gt;. Get involved there, by fixing and opening issues, making pull requests, and participating in the discussions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 12:07:04 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>kushti</dc:creator>
<og:title>Towards Scala 3</og:title>
<og:url>/blog/2018/04/19/scala-3.html</og:url>
<og:image>/resources/img/scala-spiral-3d-2-toned-down.png</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.scala-lang.org/blog/2018/04/19/scala-3.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Be likeable or get fired</title>
<link>https://sites.google.com/a/athaydes.com/renato-athaydes/posts/belikeableorgetfired</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://sites.google.com/a/athaydes.com/renato-athaydes/posts/belikeableorgetfired</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I have just been let go by my employer after only 5 months on the job. As usual in my country, the contract I signed included a probation period of 6 months within which any party (employee or employer) could terminate the contract, basically without advance notice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was shocked... not because I thought everything was perfect... I had been quite unhappy myself for some time, and I knew some of my co-workers also didn't like me too much... the shock was because just a few weeks earlier, I had a &quot;performance review&quot; in which half-a-dozen of my peers mostly congratulated me for the great job I was doing, with just one guy being a bit disgruntled with me and, after giving me quite nice compliments, as all the others had done, went on a lengthy rampage listing items which he believed I needed to improve on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I get to that list, let me tell the story from the beginning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div readability=&quot;23.847926267281&quot;&gt;I was hired with pretty good salary and benefits (no great title though - I was simply &lt;em&gt;Backend Developer&lt;/em&gt; - which I asked to be changed to &lt;em&gt;Software Developer&lt;/em&gt; to reflect how I see myself, not tied to only one part of the stack) after impressing the CTO with my &lt;a href=&quot;https://bitbucket.org/renatoathaydes/izettle-auth&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;take-home assignment&lt;/a&gt; and an incredible feat of luck: just the week he interviewed me, knowing I had Kotlin experience, he asked my opinion on Kotlin and as we discussed that (my opinion is that Kotlin is an excellent language, by the way), he mentioned he had just read &lt;a href=&quot;https://sites.google.com/a/athaydes.com/renato-athaydes/posts/fastercommandlinetoolswithkotlin&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;an article&lt;/a&gt; showing how Kotlin performance was really competitive... and as it turned out, I was the author of the article!&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div readability=&quot;10.571428571429&quot;&gt;That seemed like a great start, so I decided to leave my comfortable job at &lt;a href=&quot;https://curity.io/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Curity&lt;/a&gt; (the up-and-coming OAuth/Identity server), and join a payments company.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My intention was to get exposed to new technologies used in high-traffic, scalable systems... things like Cassandra, Amazon ECS and Kubernetes. I had been working in product companies for several years, which on one hand is great as you get to develop a great understanding of the code-base and, in the case of Curity, lots of greenfield development as it was a relatively new product. But on the other hand, you're stuck with one technology stack, in my case, JVM stuff: Java, the language, Kotlin, Groovy, Jetty and so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my first week, I was assigned to a temporary team which had been assembled to fix a security issue with a high level of urgency. Right from the first contact with my new colleagues, I noticed that there was something strange: even though the fix we had to make was extremely simple compared to the kind of thing I had been doing in my previous jobs, the other developers seemed quite stressed about the situation and declared that we would need months to sort things out. In my head, the fix was a matter of days!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being new in the company, chances were I was just ignorant of some details that they were not making very clear to me, but in any case, the matter was urgent and management requested that we tried to fix it within 2 weeks (not a hard deadline, as I understood it).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, once we started the work, it was clear there was no complications I had failed to see: it was pretty trivial, actually, and within one week we were mostly done - even after spending lots of time discussing possible alternative solutions. Having expertise in the area, I took the lead in implementing the solution and wrote most of the code (unfortunately, the project is not open-source so I cant' verify it, but I probably wrote more than 70% of the code). The second week was spent mostly testing everything and communicating our solution to the other teams involved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was some more concern about deploying the code to production... clearly, the guys didn't trust the testing systems to pick up all issues before they hit production. That was a second red-flag for me - I've always worked extremely hard to establish a staging environment which reliably reproduces the production environment, so that great confidence could be had that if the released code passed the unit tests, system tests and some final manual tests in the staging environment, that it would be very unlikely that serious/obvious issues would only happen in production. And when it did, it was always a failure of the tests to cover some obscure edge case, not something much more basic like differences in setup between production and staging.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In any case, once we deployed the fix to production, it was a big triumph for us - specially for me, as this was only my first couple of weeks on the job and I had already been able to take a large role in fixing a serious issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But from this initial experience, I had learned that things were far from perfect and decided to start pointing out things we needed to improve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div readability=&quot;23.215453194651&quot;&gt;I noticed that the tech-lead was quite upset every time I criticized something, as clearly he had been involved personally in most of the things I was criticizing: code of poor quality with no validation of inputs, lots of partially finished modifications (see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lava_flow_(programming)&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;lava flow anti-pattern&lt;/a&gt;), lack of unit tests, obvious differences between production and staging environments, developers releasing from their own machines rather than the CI server... things that, in my opinion, would be irresponsible to ignore. The answer was always the same: they had had to compromise due to time constraints, or lack of resources... the familiar, valid (even if unsatisfactory), excuses.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I don't like to criticize without showing a better way, so I decided to immediately start fixing the most glaring issues that I had observed during my initial contact with the micro-service I had been working on. That involved quite extensive changes and writing lots of unit-tests. I broke up the work in separate pull requests and hoped for some help from the guys to make sure the assumptions the tests were making were valid.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That's when my relationship with the team started to degrade. My pull requests were left mostly unattended for several days. I kept nagging people to please review my changes, but apparently I had made too many changes, even considering I had broken up the changes in separate PRs, so no one wanted to review. This situation would remain for the whole time I was there and probably was the root cause of our problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started noticing that it was not only me.. having PRs left open for several days or even months seemed to be common: I found PRs in other projects that were almost celebrating their first anniversaries and still had no reviews.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I have a lingering PR, what I normally do is fork a new branch from the PR branch, and continue work from there - until I am ready to submit another PR, which may result in a stack of PRs if the PRs are not reviewed fast enough. Notice that we're talking days here, not hours!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I brought that up with the team lead who responded that they could not spend their whole time just reviewing my code! I felt like I had been just reprehended for working too fast!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another guy in the team started criticizing me for being messy with my PRs. Someone even complained when I offered to help another team perform some task which for me would be easy (and would definitely not affect our sprint negatively) - as if they had control over what I was allowed to do. So, everyone was clearly unhappy about me actually doing what I was paid to do. I actually heard from more than one people that I should slow down as there was no rush.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried to set an example by quickly reviewing PRs the other team members submitted, at which point someone complained I was reviewing his PR before it was ready for review (it had WIP in the title)... but I'd always thought that you just don't make a PR before you want someone to have a look at it!! Why would you do that?!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, I think the atmosphere was already too heavy to recover from... everything I did was criticized by someone (except the code, which is what I actually wanted to get critic on) so I started becoming more and more defensive, which further deteriorated the situation! I thought of just going back to my previous job (the guys made it clear I was welcome to go back) but I was afraid it would make my Resume look like I am too much of a job-hopper. Also, it's in my veins to never give up when something is not going too well until I've put every effort to fix it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A month or two passed... and we were now working on a Cassandra database migration which required changes both in the code and in the data, including the schema itself. This kind of thing might be simple with SQL databases like Postgres, but with Cassandra, this is basically uncharted territory from what we could gather.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One person who was held as an expert in Cassandra had already started writing some code to start the migration... but apparently hit a wall when error would occur every time he tried to run a migration with a larger volume of data. He was claiming the DB driver was &quot;blowing up&quot; because there was too much data in memory (or something on these lines)... looking into it, I immediately noticed the error had nothing to do with that, it was just a conflict in the Java classpath which caused a certain path in the code to throw a &lt;code&gt;NoSuchMethodError&lt;/code&gt;. I tried to explain that to the guy, but he seemed lost at what I was saying - his knowledge of the Java runtime was clearly very limited. This lowered my confidence in his general expertise significantly. Later technical arguments with him were very difficult as I knew I couldn't trust his judgement (many other similarly bogus technical claims were made by the same person several times later) and when I started responding like &lt;em&gt;&quot;This is just not true&quot;&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;&quot;I don't believe you&quot;&lt;/em&gt; (which are the only responses I could master when someone claimed, for example, that &lt;em&gt;&quot;you can't iterate over all rows in Cassandra&quot;&lt;/em&gt;), others may have felt like I was the one being irrational.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, after I sorted out the correct library versions we needed, the code obviously started working... but he started arguing that with Cassandra, you can't do things the way I was doing. He suggested that I should go read a book about Cassandra as I didn't know what I was doing - even as I made clear progress and got things working that he couldn't. I might not have known Cassandra well, but I had experience with CouchDB, MongoDB, MySQL, Postgres... and I could not imagine a database that does not provide such basic functionality as paginating over the whole data in a table!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Needless to say that it did work. Tests showed all data was being correctly iterated over as expected. But the damage was done: out of this situation, I became the ignorant guy who knows nothing about Cassandra, he the guy who tried giving expert advice and was not being listened to (if he was so expert, maybe he should be writing the code - but he was too busy playing with Terraform to try to automatically deploy new database clusters, something we had clearly said earlier would not be necessary). Even more so when another guy in the team pointed out how stupid I was that I was inserting the data in the new tables via BATCH statements (that from someone who did not write a single line of code to help us in the effort)!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thing is: the Cassandra book actually warns against using BATCH statements in &quot;buckloading&quot; scenarios as that affects the stability of the nodes. So that other guy was right... but I was not using BATCH statements directly, but via the Java-equivalent, whose documentation I had read and said nothing about this problem. In any case, now my credibility was lower than ever as I had made the huge mistake of using &lt;strong&gt;BATCH&lt;/strong&gt; statements for &lt;strong&gt;batch&lt;/strong&gt; processing :).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn't like that situation at all and decided to verify the claims with data... so I measured how much load the nodes experienced using BATCH VS individual statements. I just couldn't get my head around the fact that you're supposed to send million of individual statements to be executed by the DB, rather than BATCHing them together like any civilized database client would. All measurements I did, which were quite comprehensive, showed that the load both within the JVM and on the OS metrics was significantly lower using BATCH, contradicting the advice in the book. As it turns out, BATCH probably becomes too expensive only when you have a large amount of nodes... but we had just a couple! So this problem didn't really affect us. I made a slide presentation to the whole team showing my findings.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did anyone recognize my efforts and agreed to use BATCH?? Nope! Instead, I was accused of being stubborn and never changing my mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, I AM actually stubborn!! But if the metrics had shown that BATCH was worse, I would absolutely be the first to change my mind. This accusation lead to another confrontation where I became aggressive (the guy attacked me personally), which probably was the last drop for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We ended up not using BATCH. Instead, they asked me to throttle the migration, which to me was pretty absurd and showed a lack of technical knowledge: I applied back-pressure to avoid flooding the database with INSERTs... the &quot;producer&quot; only sent a group of requests (no longer a batch) then waited for all of them to be completed before sending more. Throttling via sleeps between &quot;batches&quot; in this scenario seems rather unnecessary - specially when the &quot;consumer&quot; was Cassandra, a database specifically written to handle high-throughput without just dying - and the metrics I had collected showed 0 impact on end users (which I verified by running realistic load tests on the server as the job was running). But anyway, arguing my case by now was completely hopeless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, the migration was a success. It took much longer than it should, but it did finish with only minor, fixable hiccups that did not affect production in any way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CTO suggested we celebrate with cake, which was common in such circumstances. But we got no cake. After a few days, I got escorted out of the building.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was successful in every task during my 5 months at this company, but I was not successful in what is, in many ways, the most important: &lt;strong&gt;likeability&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my previous jobs, I am pretty certain I'd been liked by most people (I got asked to stay by several people), and even in this job, I had some great relationships. But small clashes due to unclear process and technical arguments, with differences in expectations lead to a situation where I became disliked enough within my team for them to ask for my removal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has taught me a lot, and I hope that this post helps myself and others understand how small things on our day-to-day can quickly escalate, causing unnecessary harm.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div readability=&quot;21&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The list of things I was told I should improve on included listening more to other people and accepting their opinions, being less defensive, less aggressive... basically, be more agreeable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I know I made many mistakes, I believe I was not the only one who did... but I was the one on probation... so... so long and thanks for all the fish.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;em&gt;To the people involved: if you believe I have misrepresented anything you did or said, even though I took utmost care to only make accurate claims, feel free to contact me and I will redact the story to reflect both sides of the story.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 11:28:56 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>gnulinux</dc:creator>
<og:title>Be likeable or get fired! - Renato Athaydes</og:title>
<og:description>Renato Athaydes' Personal Website. Computer Science, programming and all that stuff.</og:description>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://sites.google.com/a/athaydes.com/renato-athaydes/posts/belikeableorgetfired</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Mathematics I Use (2012)</title>
<link>http://pub.gajendra.net/2012/10/mathematics_i_use</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://pub.gajendra.net/2012/10/mathematics_i_use</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, on an online forum, a question was posed: How much, and what kind, of mathematics does a working programmer actually use? Here is my answer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;First, I and almost all programmers use a lot of &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boolean_algebra&quot;&gt;boolean logic&lt;/a&gt;, from evaluating boolean expressions for conditionals and loop exit criteria, to rearranging the terms of such expressions according to, e.g., &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/De_Morgan%27s_laws&quot;&gt;De Morgan's laws&lt;/a&gt;. Much of our work borders on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/First-order_logic&quot;&gt;first-order predicate calculus&lt;/a&gt; and other &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Predicate_logic&quot;&gt;predicate logics&lt;/a&gt; in the guise of analysis of preconditions, invariants, etc (though it may not always be presented as such).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, I do a lot of performance analysis. The kind of data sets we process these days are massive. In 2010, &lt;span itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/Person&quot;&gt;&lt;a itemprop=&quot;url&quot; href=&quot;https://plus.google.com/104233435224873922474/posts&quot;&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;name&quot;&gt;Eric Schmidt&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; made a comment at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://techonomy.com&quot;&gt;Techonomy&lt;/a&gt; conference that we (humans) produce as much data in &lt;em&gt;two days&lt;/em&gt; as &lt;em&gt;ever existed&lt;/em&gt; world-wide in 2003. I want to be able to process large chunks of that and infer things from it, and understanding the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Analysis_of_algorithms&quot;&gt;space and time complexity&lt;/a&gt; of the operations we apply to the data is critical to determining whether the computations are even feasible. Further, unlike in much traditional &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Big_O_notation&quot;&gt;big-O&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://mathworld.wolfram.com/Big-ThetaNotation.html&quot;&gt;theta&lt;/a&gt; analysis, the constant factors matter very much at that kind of scale: a factor of 2 will not change the asymptotic time complexity of an algorithm, but if it means the difference between running it over 10,000 or 20,000 processors, now we are talking about real resources. The calculations tend to be much more intricate as a result. Examples: can I take some linear computation and reduce it in strength to a logarithmic computation? Can I reduce memory usage by a factor of three? Etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Often times, I want to compute the worst-case or upper bound of, say, the size of some data set. The calculations can be nontrivial for many of these. Or, I may want to analyze some &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Recurrence_relation&quot;&gt;recurrence relation&lt;/a&gt; to see how it varies as I increase the recursion depth. To do that, I need, among other things, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Master_theorem&quot;&gt;Master Theorem&lt;/a&gt; and a good understanding of how to analyze &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Series_(mathematics)&quot;&gt;series&lt;/a&gt;. Believe it or not, this sometimes means I need to evaluate an &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Integral&quot;&gt;integral&lt;/a&gt; (though mostly of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Riemann_integral&quot;&gt;Riemann&lt;/a&gt; variety). Or can I just solve the recurrence and get a &lt;a href=&quot;http://mathworld.wolfram.com/Closed-FormSolution.html&quot;&gt;closed-form solution&lt;/a&gt;? Do I have to resort to &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linear_algebra&quot;&gt;linear algebra&lt;/a&gt;? This gets into things like &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Generating_function&quot;&gt;generating functions&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stirling_number&quot;&gt;Stirling numbers&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;span itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/Book&quot; itemid=&quot;urn:isbn:9780801854149&quot;&gt;&lt;a itemprop=&quot;url&quot; href=&quot;http://www.cs.cornell.edu/cv/books/gvl/index.htm&quot;&gt;matrix computations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, etc. If you are curious what goes into “fundamental” mathematical concepts necessary to understand computer science, have a look at volume 1 of, &lt;span itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/Book&quot; itemid=&quot;urn:isbn:9780201896831&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;The Art of Computer Programming&lt;/cite&gt;, by &lt;span itemprop=&quot;author&quot;&gt;&lt;span itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.orb/Person&quot; id=&quot;knuth&quot;&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;name&quot;&gt;Donald Knuth&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, or &lt;span itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/Book&quot; itemid=&quot;urn:isbn:9780201558029&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Concrete Mathematics&lt;/cite&gt;, by &lt;span itemprop=&quot;author&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemref=&quot;knuth&quot;&gt;Knuth&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span itemprop=&quot;author&quot;&gt;&lt;span itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/Person&quot;&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;name&quot;&gt;Ronald L. Graham&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span itemprop=&quot;author&quot;&gt;&lt;span itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/Person&quot;&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;name&quot;&gt;Oren Patashnik&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do a lot of straight-up computation in terms of aggregating, combining and transforming data; lots of &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Combinatorics&quot;&gt;combinatorics&lt;/a&gt; (e.g., counting things, looking for symmetries across different dimensions, etc). Examples are obvious, I think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do a lot of &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Discrete_mathematics&quot;&gt;discrete mathematics&lt;/a&gt;: looking for &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Algebraic_structure&quot;&gt;algebraic structures&lt;/a&gt; across operations on extremely large sets. Is there some kind of structure latent in whatever I am doing that can be preserved across &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Homomorphism&quot;&gt;homomorphism&lt;/a&gt; to some &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Group_(mathematics)&quot;&gt;group&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ring_(mathematics)&quot;&gt;ring&lt;/a&gt; that I understand better? Is there a looser constraint? Can I apply &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Group_action&quot;&gt;group actions&lt;/a&gt; to some set in order to build a mental model for some transformation that makes it easier to reason about? Can I define some &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Topology&quot;&gt;topology&lt;/a&gt; towards analyzing the data? You would be surprised how many things fall into the category of &lt;a href=&quot;http://mathworld.wolfram.com/DiscreteTopology.html&quot;&gt;discrete topologies&lt;/a&gt;. For that matter, you would be surprised how many places the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Triangle_inequality&quot;&gt;triangle inequality&lt;/a&gt; shows up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do a lot of &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Graph_theory&quot;&gt;graph theory&lt;/a&gt;. “Designing a web site” is not just about where to put the cute cat graphic on the page, it is also about inserting nodes into the global &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hyperlink&quot;&gt;hyperlink&lt;/a&gt; graph; a single page potentially adds many edges to the graph and that can have subtle effects on performance, analysis, search engine rankings, etc. Understanding the consequences of that can yield interesting insights: how does the graph grow? As it turns out, it &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencemag.org/content/287/5461/2115.full&quot;&gt;looks an awful lot&lt;/a&gt; like it obeys a &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Power_law&quot;&gt;power law&lt;/a&gt;: the web is a &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scale-free_network&quot;&gt;scale-free network&lt;/a&gt;. What is the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shortest_path_problem&quot;&gt;shortest distance between two nodes in that graph&lt;/a&gt;? What would it mean for the web graph to be &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Planar_graph&quot;&gt;planar&lt;/a&gt;? &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bipartite_graph&quot;&gt;Bipartite&lt;/a&gt;? When, if ever, do these properties hold? What if the graph isn't the web, but entire road network for North America, Europe or Asia?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This implies something else. Something people often do not realize about “modern” web pages is that they are not just &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.w3.org/html/&quot;&gt;HTML&lt;/a&gt; documents with links to images and other resources, but they are really &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tree_structure&quot;&gt;tree structures&lt;/a&gt; of data that are linked together in a &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Graph_(mathematics)&quot;&gt;graph&lt;/a&gt;. Those trees are often walked over, reprocessed and updated dynamically by interactions between the user's web browser and some server (this is what “&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ajax_(programming)&quot;&gt;AJAX&lt;/a&gt;” is all about). For a clever and relevant example of this, see: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mathjax.org&quot;&gt;MathJax&lt;/a&gt;. Or &lt;a href=&quot;https://mail.google.com&quot;&gt;GMail&lt;/a&gt;. Understanding how to do that means having some understanding of &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Symbolic_computation&quot;&gt;symbolic computation&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Semantic_analysis_(compilers)&quot;&gt;semantic analysis&lt;/a&gt; of the elements of a page. For MathJax, the authors must write a program that can walk a tree generated from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Document_Object_Model&quot;&gt;Document Object Model&lt;/a&gt; (or DOM), look for mathematical elements, &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parsing&quot;&gt;parse&lt;/a&gt; them, and dynamically replace them with new rendered elements representing the underlying expression. It may not seem like much to most users, for whom it “just works”, but it is actually some heady stuff under the hood. I do not do things like that necessarily (I am not a front-end person), but I do do similar things in &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lisp_(programming_language)&quot;&gt;Lisp&lt;/a&gt; all the time. Note that Lisp was originally defined as a mathematical notation for symbolic processing: Lisp macros are all about manipulation of symbolic expressions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do a lot of &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Time_series&quot;&gt;time-series analysis&lt;/a&gt;. How is traffic or resource consumption changing? What are the trends? Is a spike in request latency or memory use &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Seasonality&quot;&gt;seasonal&lt;/a&gt;? How does the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rate_of_change&quot;&gt;rate of change&lt;/a&gt; of something vary as input changes in different dimensions? Is it &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Correlation_and_dependence&quot;&gt;correlated&lt;/a&gt; with some external event?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do a lot of &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statistics&quot;&gt;statistical&lt;/a&gt; analysis of data, not just to understand its performance characteristics but also to understand the data itself. In addition to looking at the aforementioned DOM tree for semantic metadata (e.g., &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.w3.org/TR/2011/WD-microdata-20110525/&quot;&gt;microdata&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://microformats.org&quot;&gt;microformats&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.w3.org/TR/rdfa-core/&quot;&gt;RDFa&lt;/a&gt;, other &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.w3.org/XML/&quot;&gt;XML&lt;/a&gt; data with some explicit &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Schema&quot;&gt;schema&lt;/a&gt;, etc) also trying to make sense of &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unstructured_data&quot;&gt;unstructured data&lt;/a&gt;. What is the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Probability&quot;&gt;probability&lt;/a&gt; that this text is a street address? &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Geographic_coordinate_system&quot;&gt;Geographical coordinates&lt;/a&gt;? What context does it appear in? Is it &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spam_(electronic)&quot;&gt;spam&lt;/a&gt;? Does it make sense? Does it look like the output of a &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Markov_chain&quot;&gt;Markov chain&lt;/a&gt; generator? Is it a series of exact quotes from some well-known work of literature? Or is it some discussion about literature? Is it a discussion about spam that includes literature? I still chuckle when I think about the piece of spam I got for pharmaceuticals wrapped inside a section of &lt;span itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/Book&quot; itemid=&quot;urn:isbn:9780141180144&quot;&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;author&quot;&gt;&lt;span itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/Person&quot;&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;name&quot;&gt;Mikhail Bulgakov&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;'s &lt;cite&gt;The Master and Margarita&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Category_theory&quot;&gt;Category theory&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Type_theory&quot;&gt;Types&lt;/a&gt; in computer programming languages roughly correspond to categories, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Monad_(category_theory)&quot;&gt;monads&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Functor&quot;&gt;functors&lt;/a&gt; can be brought to bear to greatly simplify some constructs in surprisingly elegant ways. For instance, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Functional_programming&quot;&gt;functional programming&lt;/a&gt; language &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Haskell_(programming_language)&quot;&gt;Haskell&lt;/a&gt; uses &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Monad_(functional_programming)&quot;&gt;monads&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Input/output&quot;&gt;input and output&lt;/a&gt;, and for modeling &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/State_(computer_science)&quot;&gt;state&lt;/a&gt;. Simplified programs are easier to get right, easier to reason about, understand, modify, etc. Types can often be inferred; this brings in things like &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unification_(computer_science)&quot;&gt;unification&lt;/a&gt; (which can also be used in general problems of inference). Consider using &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Inference&quot;&gt;inference&lt;/a&gt; to apply &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Prolog&quot;&gt;prolog&lt;/a&gt;-style predicates as an approach to &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Operational_transformation&quot;&gt;transforming graphs&lt;/a&gt; in a &lt;a href=&quot;http://pdos.csail.mit.edu/6.824/&quot;&gt;distributed system&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Distributed systems bring us back to graph theory: at scale, in the real world, systems fail, backhoes cut fiber, there are earthquakes, volcanoes, and fishing trawlers that disturb Marine cables. One needs to understand the graph characteristics of the network to understand the effects of these things and how best to respond. Routing algorithms and network analysis is intimately tied to things like how to find the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shortest_path_problem&quot;&gt;shortest path between nodes&lt;/a&gt; in the network graph; &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dijkstra's_algorithm&quot;&gt;Dijkstra's algorithm&lt;/a&gt; anyone?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, how does one distribute a large computation across globally distributed data centers? You have to understand some physics to do this well: at Internet scale, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Speed_of_light&quot;&gt;speed of light&lt;/a&gt; starts to be a bottleneck. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thermal_management_of_electronic_devices_and_systems&quot;&gt;Heat dissipation&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Current_density&quot;&gt;density of electrical current&lt;/a&gt; draw per unit area, etc, are all real world considerations that go into what programmers do. Should I put a data center in Iceland? Cheap cooling and geothermal energy sound appealing, but what is the minimum latency to some place where user's care abut the data living on those servers in Iceland? That is the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Great_circle&quot;&gt;great-circle&lt;/a&gt; distance between, say, Iceland and London? Berlin? Amsterdam? These are fairly simple things to figure out, but I need to have enough mathematical chops to do them. Can I run fiber from Iceland to some hub location? What is the average latency? What is the probability of a fiber break in a marine cable under the North Sea over a 12 month period? 48 months?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Theory_of_computation&quot;&gt;theory of computation&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Automata_theory&quot;&gt;automata&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parsing&quot;&gt;parsing&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Formal_grammar&quot;&gt;grammars&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Regular_language&quot;&gt;regular languages&lt;/a&gt;, etc, all enter into what programmers' work. I do a lot of parsing and &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pattern_matching&quot;&gt;pattern matching&lt;/a&gt;. At even moderate size, real-world data sets contain items that can trigger &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pathological_(mathematics)&quot;&gt;pathologically bad behavior&lt;/a&gt; when using, for instance, &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Backtracking&quot;&gt;backtracking&lt;/a&gt; techniques. If I use &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Regular_expression&quot;&gt;regular expressions&lt;/a&gt; to match data, I must be careful to make sure that the expressions &lt;a href=&quot;http://swtch.com/~rsc/regexp/&quot;&gt;really are regular&lt;/a&gt;. If I am using a &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pushdown_automaton&quot;&gt;push-down automaton&lt;/a&gt; to parse a &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Context-free_grammar&quot;&gt;context-free grammar&lt;/a&gt; (which happens every time you send a request to an &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ietf.org/rfc/rfc2616.txt&quot;&gt;HTTP&lt;/a&gt; server, by the way), I have to make sure I limit the depth of recursion to avoid things like processor &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Call_stack&quot;&gt;procedure call stack&lt;/a&gt; exhaustion, which requires understanding the underlying principles of the computation and the mathematics they are based on. If I have to actually write a &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Recursive_descent_parser&quot;&gt;recursive descent parser&lt;/a&gt; for some funky grammar that is not &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/LALR_parser&quot;&gt;LALR(1)&lt;/a&gt; (so I can't just use &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yacc&quot;&gt;yacc&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gnu.org/software/bison/&quot;&gt;bison&lt;/a&gt;), I have to be careful or maintain the state stack separately from procedural recursion. That this is also something I need to understand if I am walking a DOM tree (or any recursively defined data structure). &lt;a href=&quot;http://golang.org/&quot;&gt;Some programming languages&lt;/a&gt; recognize this as a hassle for the programmer and work around it by using &lt;a href=&quot;http://golang.org/doc/go_faq.html#stack_or_heap&quot;&gt;segmented stacks&lt;/a&gt;. Of course, it would be nice if I could define my “compilation” of some parsable resource as a &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Function_(mathematics)&quot;&gt;function&lt;/a&gt; (in the mathematical sense). Wouldn't it be nice if this was all just some &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linear_programming&quot;&gt;linear programming&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_optimization&quot;&gt;optimization&lt;/a&gt; problem?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that none of this is esoterica; it is all based on real-world experience with real-world data sets and problems. Of course, I do not do &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; of this every day, but I have done all of it at one time or another and most of it regularly. Probably a lot more is based on observation, experience and &lt;a hef=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Heuristic&quot;&gt;heuristics&lt;/a&gt; than should be (the heuristic models are often incomplete and inaccurate). Do I know enough math to calculate the average &lt;a href=&quot;http://mathworld.wolfram.com/ErrorPropagation.html&quot;&gt;error&lt;/a&gt; between reality and my heuristic model?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is what computer science really is, and how it interacts with programming and the realities of modern computing. Being the “IT expert” somewhere is not the same thing as being a computer scientist, and as many correctly note, being a computer scientist is a lot closer to being an applied mathematician than a tradesman. This is not to downplay the importance of trade professions, which are both useful and highly respectable, but to point out that computer science is different. I am very fortunate that I was able to serve in the Marines with a number of folks who work in trades; we as a society should show them a lot more respect than we do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(For the record, I am not a computer scientist. I was trained as a [pure] mathematician, and what I do professionally is a lot closer to engineering.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 11:23:40 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>pmarin</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>application/xhtml+xml</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://pub.gajendra.net/2012/10/mathematics_i_use</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Susan Kare designed the suite of icons that made the Macintosh revolutionary</title>
<link>https://www.newyorker.com/culture/cultural-comment/the-woman-who-gave-the-macintosh-a-smile</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.newyorker.com/culture/cultural-comment/the-woman-who-gave-the-macintosh-a-smile</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Every fifteen minutes or so, as I wrote this story, I moved my cursor northward to click on the disk in the Microsoft Word toolbar that indicates “Save.” This is a superstitious move, as my computer automatically saves my work every ten minutes. But I learned to use a computer in the era before AutoSave, in the dark ages when remembering to save to a disk often stood between you and term-paper disaster. The persistence of that disk icon into the age of flash drives and cloud storage is a sign of its power. A disk means “Save.” Susan Kare designed a version of that disk, as part of the suite of icons that made the Macintosh revolutionary—a computer that you could communicate with in pictures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paola Antonelli, the senior curator of architecture and design at the Museum of Modern Art, was the first to physically show Kare’s original icon sketches, in the 2015 exhibit “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.moma.org/calendar/exhibitions/1501&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;ArticleBody__link___1FS03&quot;&gt;This is for Everyone&lt;/a&gt;.” “If the Mac turned out to be such a revolutionary object––a pet instead of a home appliance, a spark for the imagination instead of a mere work tool––it is thanks to Susan’s fonts and icons, which gave it voice, personality, style, and even a sense of humor. Cherry bomb, anyone?” she joked, referring to the icon which greeted crashes in the original operating system. After working for Apple, Kare designed icons for Microsoft, Facebook, and, now, Pinterest, where she is a creative director. The mainstream presence of Pinterest, Instagram, Snapchat, emoji, and &lt;em class=&quot;small&quot;&gt;GIFS&lt;/em&gt; is a sign that the visual revolutionaries have won: online, we all communicate visually, piecing together sentences from tiny-icon languages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kare, who is sixty-four, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aiga.org/medalist-susan-kare&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;ArticleBody__link___1FS03&quot;&gt;will be honored for her work&lt;/a&gt; on April 20th, by her fellow designers, with the prestigious AIGA medal. In 1982, she was a sculptor and sometime curator when her high-school friend Andy Hertzfeld asked her to create graphics for a new computer that he was working on in California. Kare brought &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.moma.org/collection/works/188382?artist_id=38483&amp;amp;locale=en&amp;amp;page=1&amp;amp;sov_referrer=artist&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;ArticleBody__link___1FS03&quot;&gt;a Grid notebook&lt;/a&gt; to her job interview at Apple Computer. On its pages, she had sketched, in pink marker, a series of icons to represent the commands that Hertzfeld’s software would execute. Each square represented a pixel. A pointing finger meant “Paste.” A paintbrush symbolized “MacPaint.” Scissors said “Cut.” Kare told me about this origin moment: “As soon as I started work, Andy Hertzfeld wrote an icon editor and font editor so I could design images and letterforms using the Mac, not paper,” she said. “But I loved the puzzle-like nature of working in sixteen-by-sixteen and thirty-two-by-thirty-twopixel icon grids, and the marriage of craft and metaphor.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Callout__feature-xsmall___3cfPv&quot; data-type=&quot;callout&quot; data-callout=&quot;feature-xsmall&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ImageEmbed__container___1S6AV&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Lightbox__lightbox___2lLZl Lightbox__white___jj_9p&quot; role=&quot;button&quot; tabindex=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;placeholder&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;placeholder-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Image__image___1PhYl Figure__image___1hDvt ImageEmbed__image___VwXNk&quot; role=&quot;button&quot; tabindex=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/5ad8c2239b71e2027502654c/master/w_727,c_limit/Lange-Susan-Kare-vector-icons.jpg&quot; title=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;button class=&quot;Button__button___2vDCa Button__seeMore___czyKz ImageEmbed__button___1EF1B&quot;&gt;

&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;small class=&quot;ImageCaption__credit___rg3mC&quot;&gt;Icons provided by kareprints.com&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What Kare lacked in computer experience she made up for in visual knowledge. “Bitmap graphics are like mosaics and needlepoint and other pseudo-digital art forms, all of which I had practiced before going to Apple,” she &lt;a href=&quot;http://web.stanford.edu/dept/SUL/library/mac/primary/interviews/kare/trans.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;ArticleBody__link___1FS03&quot;&gt;told an interviewer&lt;/a&gt;, in 2000. The command icon, still right there to the left of your space bar, was based on a Swedish campground sign meaning “interesting feature,” pulled from a book of historical symbols. Kare looked to cross-stitch, to mosaics, to hobo signs for inspiration when she got stuck. “Some icons, like the piece of paper, are no problem; but others defy the visual, like ‘Undo.’ ” At one point, there was to be an icon of a copy machine for making a copy of a file, and users would drag and drop a file onto it to copy it, but it was difficult to render a copier at that scale. Kare also tried a cat in a mirror, for copycat. Neither made the cut. She also designed a number of the original Mac fonts, including Geneva, Chicago, and the picture-heavy Cairo, using only a nine-by-seven grid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her notebooks are part of the permanent collections of the New York and San Francisco modern-art museums, and one was included in the recent London Design Museum exhibit “&lt;a href=&quot;https://designmuseum.org/exhibitions/california-designing-freedom&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;ArticleBody__link___1FS03&quot;&gt;California: Designing Freedom&lt;/a&gt;.” Justin McGuirk, the co-curator of that exhibition, said, “The Xerox Star initiated the metaphor of the ‘desktop’ as an icon-based method of interacting with computers, but it was the Apple Mac that popularized it.” While the Macintosh once made you wait with a tiny watch designed by Kare, Pinterest offers you a spinning button when you refresh, also designed by Kare. Last fall, the small home-design brand &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.areaware.com/collections/susan-kare&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;ArticleBody__link___1FS03&quot;&gt;Areaware&lt;/a&gt; débuted Kare-designed placemats, coasters, and napkins with bitmap raindrops, waves, and diagonals; I bought them for the whole family for Christmas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s fun to read that, before there was social media, countless people spent hours with Microsoft Windows Solitaire using the cards I designed,” she said. In 2008, Kare created virtual “gifts” for Facebook that you could buy and send to a friend, with new offerings daily, based on a sixty-four-by-sixty-four-pixel grid. The best-sellers played to the crowd: hearts, penguins, and kisses, like a digital box of chocolates. A sixty-four-pixel palette would seem like a big step up, but Kare doesn’t think detail necessarily makes better icons. “Simple images can be more inclusive,” she said. Look at traffic signs: “There’s a reason the silhouettes of kids in a school crossing sign don’t have plaid lunchboxes and superhero backpacks, even though it’s not because of technology limitations,” she said. “Those would be extraneous details.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kare’s personal style is distinctly unfussy. She was bemused last year when her son and colleagues at Pinterest alerted her that a 1984 portrait of her by Norman Seeff, taken for &lt;em&gt;Rolling Stone&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/OldSchoolCool/comments/7pj0wk/susan_kare_famous_apple_artist_who_designed_many/?st=jfhiksff&amp;amp;sh=fcd1af24&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;ArticleBody__link___1FS03&quot;&gt;had turned up on Reddit&lt;/a&gt; in the subreddit of “old school cool.” In the photo, Kare lounges horizontally in her ergonomic chair, wearing jeans and a gray sweatshirt, with one gray-and-burgundy New Balance shoe propped on her desk. “Just a regular 1984 work outfit—nothing special—but seems ‘pre-normcore’ in retrospect,” she said. “I lived in New Balance and Reebok ankle-high workout shoes. Colleagues brought me toy robot souvenirs from work trips to Japan, and I see postcards of favorite images from the Metropolitan Museum.” The toys, the art, and the sneakers embody the rigor and the humor that Kare has always brought to the task of making icons, which resonate across the decades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A redditor helpfully identified the robots—Monster from Macross (1983), MR-11 Bulldozer Robo/Dozer (1982), and, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/evilmallelis/status/952796525041664000?lang=en&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;ArticleBody__link___1FS03&quot;&gt;on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, Daniel Mallory Ortberg made a proposal:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;embed twitter-embed-component twitter-tweet&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot; data-type=&quot;twitter&quot; data-url=&quot;https://twitter.com/evilmallelis/status/952796525041664000?lang=en&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/evilmallelis/status/952796525041664000?lang=en&quot;&gt;https://twitter.com/evilmallelis/status/952796525041664000?lang=en&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;http://web.stanford.edu/dept/SUL/library/mac/primary/interviews/kare/trans.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;ArticleBody__link___1FS03&quot;&gt;a 2000 interview&lt;/a&gt; with Alex Soojung-Kim Pang, now a researcher at Institute for the Future, Kare brings the history of American graphic design full circle. It was she who brought the legendary Paul Rand (the AIGA Medal winner in 1966 and a designer of I.B.M.) to the attention of Steve Jobs when the latter founded NeXT, in 1985, and needed a logo as iconic as the Apple. Rand’s solution, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.logodesignlove.com/next-logo-paul-rand&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;ArticleBody__link___1FS03&quot;&gt;presented in a hundred-page booklet&lt;/a&gt;, for which he was paid a hundred thousand dollars, was a black box poised on one corner, mimicking the distinctive &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fastcodesign.com/3056684/remembering-the-design-legacy-of-steve-jobss-other-great-computer-company&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;ArticleBody__link___1FS03&quot;&gt;and problematic&lt;/a&gt; appearance of the computers themselves. Letters are easier to fit into a perfect cube than motherboards. “Don’t get scared, this is not the design,” Rand quips in a video of the presentation, taking out the book. Kare stands next to Rand in a star-spangled sweater. “Steve and I both learned a lot from him,” she said. “He was very unequivocal. I remember him almost pounding the table, saying, ‘I’ve been doing this for fifty-five years, and I know what you should do!’ It must be great to have that much confidence in such an inexact science.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I asked Kare if there were other AIGA medalists, besides Rand, whom she saw as influences, and she lists a series of pre-digital greats whose work is known for broad appeal, infectious warmth, and a sometimes cartoony hand: Charles and Ray Eames (1977), Milton Glaser (1972), and the &lt;em&gt;New Yorker&lt;/em&gt; contributor and cartoonist Saul Steinberg (1963). Through their work, and now hers, one can see a legacy of personal touch that one hopes will continue into our digital future on a deeper level than fingerprint readers. She gave the Mac a smile—where’s the smile now?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 10:29:42 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>matt4077</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://media.newyorker.com/photos/5ad8c22380befa7611f8659a/16:9/w_1200,h_630,c_limit/Lange-Susan-Kare.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>The Woman Who Gave the Macintosh a Smile</og:title>
<og:description>Susan Kare designed the suite of icons that made the Macintosh revolutionary—a computer that you could communicate with in pictures.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.newyorker.com/culture/cultural-comment/the-woman-who-gave-the-macintosh-a-smile</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.newyorker.com/culture/cultural-comment/the-woman-who-gave-the-macintosh-a-smile</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>In India, high-pressure exams are creating a student suicide crisis</title>
<link>http://www.wired.co.uk/article/india-kota-student-suicide-exams-institutes-of-technology</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.wired.co.uk/article/india-kota-student-suicide-exams-institutes-of-technology</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;bb-figure__wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.wired.co.uk/static/img/tiny.gif&quot; data-src=&quot;https://wi-images.condecdn.net/image/KwLrDp70prp/crop/405/f/gettyimages-691465282.jpg&quot; data-srcset=&quot;https://wi-images.condecdn.net/image/KwLrDp70prp/crop/405/f/gettyimages-691465282.jpg 405w, https://wi-images.condecdn.net/image/KwLrDp70prp/crop/810/f/gettyimages-691465282.jpg 810w, https://wi-images.condecdn.net/image/KwLrDp70prp/crop/1020/f/gettyimages-691465282.jpg 1020w, https://wi-images.condecdn.net/image/KwLrDp70prp/crop/1440/f/gettyimages-691465282.jpg 1440w, https://wi-images.condecdn.net/image/KwLrDp70prp/crop/1620/f/gettyimages-691465282.jpg 1620w&quot; data-sizes=&quot;auto&quot; class=&quot;global__image img-lazyload&quot;/&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://wi-images.condecdn.net/image/KwLrDp70prp/crop/405/f/gettyimages-691465282.jpg&quot; class=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;With only 23 prestigious Institutes of Technology and thousands of hopeful applicants, competition amongst India’s brightest minds is intense&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pradeep Gaur/Mint via Getty Images&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;bb-dropcap bb-dropcap--letter&quot;&gt;F&lt;/span&gt;or Indian teenagers, the pressure to excel in a country of 1.3 billion people is immense. And at no other time do these pressures metastasise more than in the month of April: exam season.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;This is when the nation’s brightest minds sit the examinations that will determine whether they secure entrance to one of India’s prestigious Institutes of Technology (IITs), medical institutes, or business schools. They dream of becoming engineers, dentists, or doctors. But with only 23 IITs in one of the most densely populated nations on Earth, and vastly over-subscribed dental and medical colleges, competition is intense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;ad__main is-hidden ad--article ad--article-rail ad--article-rail-top stick-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;ad__block stick-element&quot;&gt;
&lt;h5 class=&quot;ad__title&quot;&gt;Advertisement&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;To prepare, students from across India travel to the historic northern city of Kota, spending months or even years away from their family and home. Whether the children of manual labourers or business tycoons, all have travelled to Kota for one reason: academic glory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;Kota is the epicentre of India’s private coaching industry. Here, students enrol at one of the many for-profit residential institutes that prepare teenagers for their university entrance exams. For months, even years, teens who’ve barely left their parental homes before live alone, in austere hostel rooms, cramming morning, noon, and night in the hope of a secure, financially lucrative future. They leave their hostel rooms early in the morning to avoid the midday heat and walk down cracked pavements to stuffy classrooms, where they crouch over desks. At lunchtime they wolf chutney-filled dosas before returning to their desks to cram some more. The most studious return to their hostel rooms and study alone, well into the night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;But most of the teenagers who come to Kota, this effort proves futile. And for some, the threat of failure can prove psychologically overwhelming – and even fatal. In recent years, Kota has earned a more unfortunate reputation for a spate of suicides.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bb-figure__wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.wired.co.uk/static/img/tiny.gif&quot; data-src=&quot;https://wi-images.condecdn.net/image/jvPorOyBned/crop/405/f/gettyimages-691484302.jpg&quot; data-srcset=&quot;https://wi-images.condecdn.net/image/jvPorOyBned/crop/405/f/gettyimages-691484302.jpg 405w, https://wi-images.condecdn.net/image/jvPorOyBned/crop/810/f/gettyimages-691484302.jpg 810w, https://wi-images.condecdn.net/image/jvPorOyBned/crop/1020/f/gettyimages-691484302.jpg 1020w, https://wi-images.condecdn.net/image/jvPorOyBned/crop/1440/f/gettyimages-691484302.jpg 1440w, https://wi-images.condecdn.net/image/jvPorOyBned/crop/1620/f/gettyimages-691484302.jpg 1620w&quot; data-sizes=&quot;auto&quot; class=&quot;global__image img-lazyload&quot;/&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://wi-images.condecdn.net/image/jvPorOyBned/crop/405/f/gettyimages-691484302.jpg&quot; class=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;Kota is the epicentre of India’s private coaching industry. From the start of 2014 to November 2017, 45 students in the city committed suicide&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pradeep Gaur/Mint via Getty Images&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;From the start of 2014 to November 2017, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/student-suicides-in-rajasthan-s-kota-drops-by-70/story-2Msn5Kwn8EFHqzZ8zIDS8L.html&quot; class=&quot;bb-a&quot;&gt;45 Kota students committed suicide&lt;/a&gt;. So far, at least three people &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hindustantimes.com/jaipur/neet-aspirant-commits-suicide-in-kota-third-death-this-year/story-I4VApW1LTvHYUtb8p3x49H.html&quot; class=&quot;bb-a&quot;&gt;have taken their lives in 2018&lt;/a&gt;. Many of these deaths were the result of hanging by ceiling fan. Like 17-year-old Amandeep Singh, from the Raigarh district in Maharashtra, who committed suicide in 2017. Or 18-year-old Niharika Devangan, who died in January this year after three years in Kota, preparing for medical entrance exams. But this particular suicide method isn’t limited to Kota alone. According to 2015 figures from the National Crime Record Bureau, hanging accounts for 45.6 percent of all suicides in India.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;ad__main is-hidden ad--article ad--article-inline&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;ad__block&quot;&gt;
&lt;h5 class=&quot;ad__title&quot;&gt;Advertisement&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;There is no easy solution. But engineer Sharad Ashani believes that he might have one answer to India’s teen suicide problem — and it’s a simple bit of kit. But as with many deceptively simple offerings to complicated social problems, not everything is as easy as it might appear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;His offering? The world’s first anti-suicide fan (or as Ashani’s latterly rebranded it, the Smart Fan – as the manufacturers thought that the old name wasn’t auspicious.) Ashani was inspired to create the Smart Fan after the death of Indian model Nafisa Joseph in 2004. “It struck me that people used fans in this way,” Ashani says. “So I invented an anti-suicide fan pipe.” The inner pipe consists of a joint with a mechanism. When a weight greater than 20 kilograms is attached to the fan, the spring unlatches, lowering the individual to the ground safely. (Ashani, an exuberant presence, is fond of demoing the ceiling fan by attempting to hang himself on Indian TV.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;Ashani is candid about his struggles to get his Smart Fan into wider circulation. “I was expecting a huge demand for the product, but so far it’s not coming through,” he explains. “Unfortunately, safety in India is always everyone’s last priority.” Whilst Ashani has succeeded in getting the Kota Hostel Association, which consists of 2,000 hostels across the city, to pledge to install the devices, not everyone is on board: he provides a list of hostels that have refused to instal the fan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;“I’ve been producing the fan for eight months, and I was expecting the production would shoot like anything, but I’ve sold only about 1,000 fans so far,” Ashani says, blaming institutional apathy for the Smart Fan’s limited success. “Hangings happen, and people think, ‘Oh, we must see what we can do’. Then people forget, and another hanging happens,” he says. “People make inquiries but when it comes to collecting the orders, they back out.” Right now, Ashani is looking for an NGO to help sponsor a wider roll-out. Despite his enthusiasm, there is little evidence to suggest that novel inventions such as Ashani’s have any impact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;ad__main is-hidden ad--article ad--article-inline&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;ad__block&quot;&gt;
&lt;h5 class=&quot;ad__title&quot;&gt;Advertisement&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;bb-figure__wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.wired.co.uk/static/img/tiny.gif&quot; data-src=&quot;https://wi-images.condecdn.net/image/0nAO8x4bgPO/crop/405/f/fan-with-smart-fan-rod.jpg&quot; data-srcset=&quot;https://wi-images.condecdn.net/image/0nAO8x4bgPO/crop/405/f/fan-with-smart-fan-rod.jpg 405w, https://wi-images.condecdn.net/image/0nAO8x4bgPO/crop/810/f/fan-with-smart-fan-rod.jpg 810w, https://wi-images.condecdn.net/image/0nAO8x4bgPO/crop/1020/f/fan-with-smart-fan-rod.jpg 1020w, https://wi-images.condecdn.net/image/0nAO8x4bgPO/crop/1440/f/fan-with-smart-fan-rod.jpg 1440w, https://wi-images.condecdn.net/image/0nAO8x4bgPO/crop/1620/f/fan-with-smart-fan-rod.jpg 1620w&quot; data-sizes=&quot;auto&quot; class=&quot;global__image img-lazyload&quot;/&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://wi-images.condecdn.net/image/0nAO8x4bgPO/crop/405/f/fan-with-smart-fan-rod.jpg&quot; class=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;Engineer Sharad Ashani is fond of demoing his anti-suicide ceiling fan by attempting to hang himself on Indian TV&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sharad Ashani&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;Institutional apathy aside, suicide prevention technologies are a novel (and media-friendly) approach to a complex social issue, albeit one with limited effectiveness. Often targeting specific suicide hotspots can be useful as a short-term solution. At Niagara Falls, authorities have set up a suicide hotline to deter would-be jumpers, whilst in Japan’s Aokigahara forest, dedicated volunteers prowl the woodland in the hope of preventing people from taking their lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;The evidence is that these measures can help. Crisis hotlines in particular do work: Distress and Crisis Ontario, which administers suicide prevention services around Niagara Falls, reports that in 2017 92 per cent of callers ringing their hotline &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dcontario.org/PDF/DCO-Annual-Report-2017.pdf&quot; class=&quot;bb-a&quot;&gt;were de-escalated from suicidal behavior&lt;/a&gt; without involving emergency services. And a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC5654733/&quot; class=&quot;bb-a&quot;&gt;2017 evidence review of suicide prevention apps&lt;/a&gt; concluded that “apps are an essential tool that can help us to prevent suicide”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;Fans aren’t the only technology being used in an attempt to save lives. Largely in response to widespread media scrutiny of Kota’s teen suicides, authorities and regulators have been struggling for a response. Biometric scanners have been installed in many hostels, and a helpline for anxious teens to call has been set up. “Around 500 to 600 hostels have installed biometric attendance machines,” says Manish Jain of the Kota Hostel Association. “When students enter and leave their hostels, a message is sent to their parents telling them whether they’re arrived or left. It’s much better for students and parents. Parents are less stressed.” But suicide prevention expert Vikram Patel of Harvard University’s department of global health and social medicine isn’t convinced by biometric scanners. “I don’t think we have sufficient evidence to suggest the utility of biometric technologies at this time,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;Whether fans, biometric scanners, or hotlines, these stop-gap solutions are, just that: they stop immediate loss of life, but don’t address the underlying issue. Unless emergency initiatives are complemented by a full suite of mental health interventions and large-scale government initiatives, they have limited effectiveness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;And the vast majority of students who visit Kota have no need for biometric technologies or special ceiling fans. “The atmosphere is good here, honestly,” says Rudra Nadalia, an 18-year-old student resident of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.beinghome.co.in/&quot; class=&quot;bb-a&quot;&gt;Being Home&lt;/a&gt; hostel. He thinks that Kota’s suicide problem is overplayed by the media, and hasn’t encountered any suicidal students during his eight-month stay in the city. That said, he’s not immune to the pressures of exam season. With his IIT JEE a month away, Nadalia’s putting in 15-hour daily study stints, but even that may not be enough. “It’s gruesome!” he says, before reeling off statistics: only 10,000 applicants out of a pool of over a million students will score highly enough for entrance to an IIT. “The competition is fierce.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bb-figure__wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.wired.co.uk/static/img/tiny.gif&quot; data-src=&quot;https://wi-images.condecdn.net/image/zlzPe2w7qok/crop/405/f/gettyimages-691469476.jpg&quot; data-srcset=&quot;https://wi-images.condecdn.net/image/zlzPe2w7qok/crop/405/f/gettyimages-691469476.jpg 405w, https://wi-images.condecdn.net/image/zlzPe2w7qok/crop/810/f/gettyimages-691469476.jpg 810w, https://wi-images.condecdn.net/image/zlzPe2w7qok/crop/1020/f/gettyimages-691469476.jpg 1020w, https://wi-images.condecdn.net/image/zlzPe2w7qok/crop/1440/f/gettyimages-691469476.jpg 1440w, https://wi-images.condecdn.net/image/zlzPe2w7qok/crop/1620/f/gettyimages-691469476.jpg 1620w&quot; data-sizes=&quot;auto&quot; class=&quot;global__image img-lazyload&quot;/&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://wi-images.condecdn.net/image/zlzPe2w7qok/crop/405/f/gettyimages-691469476.jpg&quot; class=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;For months, even years, teens who’ve barely left their parental homes before live alone, in austere hostel rooms in the hope of securing a place at one of India's top academic institutions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pradeep Gaur/Mint via Getty Images&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;Nadalia is remarkably well-adjusted given the pressures he is under. But, as he explains, his parents are affluent and thus able to afford the not-inconsiderable cost of months of residential private tuition in the city. Not everyone is as fortunate. “There are some students here whose parents are labourers,” he explains, “and the amount they spend over here means a lot for them. Suicides are probably because of that – because of the financial pressures and competition they’re under.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;But Kota’s suicide problem is likely a simulacrum of India’s growing mental health crisis. The nation as a whole has one of the world’s highest youth suicide rates. According to a 2012 &lt;em class=&quot;bb-em&quot;&gt;Lancet&lt;/em&gt; report, suicide is the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-india-18546215&quot; class=&quot;bb-a&quot;&gt;second-leading cause of death&lt;/a&gt; amongst young Indians aged 15-29. Despite these figures, India only spends 0.06 per cent of its health budget on mental healthcare, compared to the four per cent or more typically spent by developed nations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;“We need to promote an open conversation about mental health,” says Patel. He argues that policy makers should respond to India’s suicide epidemic not with gimmicks like fans or fingerprint scanners, but with evidence based policy approaches. “We need a significant financial commitment to ensure the actual implementation of progressive ideas and values in national mental health policy, and the government must commit to an evidence-based approach to mental health care.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;ad__main is-hidden ad--article ad--article-rail stick-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;ad__block stick-element&quot;&gt;
&lt;h5 class=&quot;ad__title&quot;&gt;Advertisement&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;For now, ceiling fans — whilst a well-intentioned response to a real problem — will only have limited impact on India’s suicide crisis. The real solution? Sustained investment in mental health initiatives from an early age, and cultural change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;Nadalia sits his exam in days: he’s sanguine about his prospects. “If I don’t get in, it’s okay,” he shrugs. “Life will go on.” Meanwhile, Ashani will continue trying to sell his fans, one at a time if necessary. “My mission is to save lives,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;bb-p&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;bb-em&quot;&gt;Need help? Contact the Samaritans anytime on 116 123 in the UK and Ireland. For a list of international numbers, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_suicide_crisis_lines&quot; class=&quot;bb-a&quot;&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 07:28:48 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>AnatMl2</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://www.wired.co.uk/article/india-kota-student-suicide-exams-institutes-of-technology</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>In India, high-pressure exams are creating a student suicide crisis</og:title>
<og:image>https://wi-images.condecdn.net/image/KwLrDp70prp/crop/1440/0.523560209424/f/gettyimages-691465282.jpg</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.wired.co.uk/article/india-kota-student-suicide-exams-institutes-of-technology</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>How to build a house alone [video]</title>
<link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-3MDhLC7Prc</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-3MDhLC7Prc</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-3MDhLC7Prc&quot;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-3MDhLC7Prc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16882674&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16882674&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Points: 408&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 269&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 06:52:50 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>tomcam</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-3MDhLC7Prc</og:url>
<og:title>How to build a house alone part 1</og:title>
<og:image>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/-3MDhLC7Prc/maxresdefault.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>How to build a house alone</og:description>
<og:type>video.other</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-3MDhLC7Prc</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Google changes its messaging strategy again: Goodbye to Allo, double down on RCS</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2018/04/19/google-changes-its-messaging-strategy-again-goodbye-to-allo-double-down-on-rcs/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2018/04/19/google-changes-its-messaging-strategy-again-goodbye-to-allo-double-down-on-rcs/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/google/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;google&quot;&gt;Google’s&lt;/a&gt; long-and-winding road to figuring out messaging is taking yet another change of direction after the company called time on Allo, its newest chat app launch, in order to double down on its vision to enable an enhanced version of SMS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/platform/amp/2018/4/19/17252486/google-android-messages-chat-rcs-anil-sabharwal-imessage-texting&quot;&gt;The company told The Verge&lt;/a&gt; that it is “pausing” work on Allo, &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2016/09/20/allo-brings-googles-smarts-to-messaging/&quot;&gt;which was only launched as recently as September 2016&lt;/a&gt;, in order to put its resources into the adoption of RCS (Rich Communication Services), a messaging standard that has the potential to tie together SMS and other chat apps. RCS isn’t new, and Google has been pushing it for some time, but now the company is rebranding it as “Chat” and putting all its efforts into getting operators on board.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new strategy will see almost the entire Allo team switch to Android Messages, according to The Verge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In case you didn’t hear about it before, RCS is essentially a technology that allows basic “SMS” messaging to be standardized across devices. In the same way that iMessage lets Apple device owners chat for free using data instead of paid-for SMS, RCS could allow free chats across different networks on Android or other devices. RCS can be integrated into chat apps, which is something Google has already done with Android Messages, but the tipping point is working with others, and that means operators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike Apple, RCS is designed to work with carriers who can develop their own messaging apps that work with the protocol and connect to other apps, which could include chat apps. Essentially, it gives them a chance to take part in the messaging boom, rather than be cut out as WhatsApp, Messenger, iMessage and others take over. They don’t make money from consumers, but they do get to keep their brand and they can look to get revenue from business services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;But this approach requires operators themselves to implement the technology. That’s no easy thing as carriers don’t exactly trust tech companies — WhatsApp alone has massively eaten into its SMS and call revenues — and they don’t like working with each other, too.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google said &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gsma.com/futurenetworks/rcs/universal-profile/&quot;&gt;more than 55 operators worldwide&lt;/a&gt; have been recruited to support Chat, but it isn’t clear exactly when they might roll it out. Microsoft is among the OEM supporters, which raises the possibility it could bring support to Windows 10, but the company was non-committal when The Verge pressed it on that possibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google has tried many things on messaging, but it has largely failed because it doesn’t have a ramp to users. WhatsApp benefited from being a first mover — all the other early leaders in Western markets are nowhere to be seen today — and Facebook Messenger is built on top of the world’s most popular social network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both of those services have more than one billion active users, Allo never got to 50 million. Google search doesn’t have that contact, and the company’s previous efforts didn’t capture market share. (Hangouts was promising but it has pivoted into a tool for enterprises.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That left Google with two options: take on carriers directly with an iMessage-style service that’s built into Android, or work with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It chose the second option. It is far messier with so many different parties involved, but it is also apparently a principled approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We can’t do it without these [carrier and OEM] partners. We don’t believe in taking the approach that Apple does. We are fundamentally an open ecosystem. We believe in working with partners. We believe in working with our OEMs to be able to deliver a great experience,” Anil Sabharwal, the Google executive leading Chat, told The Verge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sabharwal refused to be drawn on a timeframe for operators rolling out Chat apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“By the end of this year, we’ll be in a really great state, and by mid-next year, we’ll be in a place where a large percentage of users [will have] this experience,” he said, explaining that uptake could be quicker in Europe or Latin America than the U.S. “This is not a three-to-five-year play. Our goal is to get this level of quality messaging to our users on Android within the next couple of years.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We shall see. But at least there won’t be yet more Google messaging apps launching, so there’s that.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 06:19:22 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Garbage</dc:creator>
<og:title>Google changes its messaging strategy again: Goodbye to Allo, double down on RCS</og:title>
<og:description>Google’s long-and-winding road to figuring out messaging is taking yet another change of direction after the company called time on Allo, its newest chat app launch, in order to double down on its vision to enable an enhanced version of SMS. The company told The Verge that it is “pausin…</og:description>
<og:image>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/gettyimages-913011976.jpg?w=602</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2018/04/19/google-changes-its-messaging-strategy-again-goodbye-to-allo-double-down-on-rcs/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2018/04/19/google-changes-its-messaging-strategy-again-goodbye-to-allo-double-down-on-rcs/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>