<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>“Lifefaker.com makes faking perfection easy”</title>
<link>http://lifefaker.com/?=HackerNews</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://lifefaker.com/?=HackerNews</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;http://lifefaker.com/?=HackerNews&quot;&gt;http://lifefaker.com/?=HackerNews&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16953005&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16953005&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Points: 250&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 93&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 29 Apr 2018 17:42:54 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>olifrost</dc:creator>
<og:title>Lifefaker.com makes faking perfection easy</og:title>
<og:description>Lifefaker.com is a new tech startup with a mission: to help you fake a perfect social profile, whoever you are. Life isn't perfect, your profile should be.</og:description>
<og:image>http://lifefaker.com/socialpreview-2.jpg</og:image>
<og:url>http://lifefaker.com/</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://lifefaker.com/?=HackerNews</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Competitive Programmer&amp;#039;s Handbook (2017) [pdf]</title>
<link>https://cses.fi/book.pdf</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://cses.fi/book.pdf</guid>
<description>&lt;a href=&quot;https://cses.fi/book.pdf&quot;&gt;Download PDF&lt;/a&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 29 Apr 2018 14:45:25 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>linouk23</dc:creator>
<og:title>Lifefaker.com makes faking perfection easy</og:title>
<og:description>Lifefaker.com is a new tech startup with a mission: to help you fake a perfect social profile, whoever you are. Life isn't perfect, your profile should be.</og:description>
<og:image>http://lifefaker.com/socialpreview-2.jpg</og:image>
<og:url>http://lifefaker.com/</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://cses.fi/book.pdf</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>France seizes france.com from man who&amp;#039;s had it since 1994</title>
<link>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2018/04/france-seizes-france-com-from-man-whos-had-it-since-94-so-he-sues/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2018/04/france-seizes-france-com-from-man-whos-had-it-since-94-so-he-sues/</guid>
<description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/GettyImages-565297243-800x535.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;aside id=&quot;social-left&quot;&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;88 posters participating&quot; class=&quot;comment-count icon-comment-bubble-down&quot; href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2018/04/france-seizes-france-com-from-man-whos-had-it-since-94-so-he-sues/?comments=1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;comment-count-before&quot;&gt;reader comments&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;comment-count-number&quot;&gt;138&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;share-links&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Share this story&lt;/span&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;aside class=&quot;pullbox sidebar story-sidebar right&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;
A French-born American has now &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/4446066-1-Complaint.html&quot;&gt;sued&lt;/a&gt; his home country because, he claims, the Ministry of Foreign Affairs has illegally seized a domain that he’s owned since 1994: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.france.com&quot;&gt;France.com&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;p&gt;In the mid-1990s, Jean-Noël Frydman bought France.com from Web.com and set up a website to serve as a &quot;digital kiosk&quot; for Francophiles and Francophones in the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gauliath.wpengine.com/&quot;&gt;For over 20 years&lt;/a&gt;, Frydman built up a business (also known as France.com), often collaborating with numerous official French agencies, including the Consulate General in Los Angeles and the Ministry of Foreign Affairs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, sometime around 2015, that very same ministry initiated a lawsuit in France in an attempt to wrest control of the France.com domain away from Frydman. Web.com locked the domain, and Frydman even &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/4446836-France-Com-202016-04-15-20-Letter-20to-20-Web-Com.html&quot;&gt;roped&lt;/a&gt; in the Berkman Klein Center at Harvard Law School to intervene on his behalf.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By September 2017, the Paris Court of Appeals &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/4446106-Copy-20of-20the-20-Translation-20-Jugement-20of.html&quot;&gt;ruled&lt;/a&gt; that France.com was violating French trademark law. Armed with this ruling, lawyers representing the French state wrote to Web.com &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/4446110-Notification-20letter-20domain-20name-20-France.html&quot;&gt;demanding&lt;/a&gt; that the domain be handed over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, on March 12, 2018, Web.com abruptly transferred ownership of the domain to the French Ministry of Foreign Affairs. The company did so without any formal notification to Frydman and no compensation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;I'm probably [one of Web.com's] oldest customers,&quot; Frydman told Ars. &quot;I've been with them for 24 years... There's never been any cases against France.com, and they just did that without any notice. I've never been treated like that by any company anywhere in the world. If it happened to me, it can happen to anyone.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gallery shortcode-gallery gallery-wide&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li data-thumb=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/2018-150x150.jpeg&quot; data-src=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/2018.jpeg&quot; data-responsive=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/2018-980x825.jpeg 1080, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/2018.jpeg 2560&quot; data-sub-html=&quot;#caption-1300479&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;France.com as seen in 2018, since being taken over by the French government.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;France.com&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li data-thumb=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/2016-150x150.jpeg&quot; data-src=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/2016.jpeg&quot; data-responsive=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/2016-980x931.jpeg 1080, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/2016.jpeg 2560&quot; data-sub-html=&quot;#caption-1300483&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;France.com as seen in 2016.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;France.com&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li data-thumb=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/2012-150x150.jpeg&quot; data-src=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/2012.jpeg&quot; data-responsive=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/2012.jpeg 1080, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/2012.jpeg 2560&quot; data-sub-html=&quot;#caption-1300485&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;France.com as seen in 2012.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;France.com&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li data-thumb=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/2005-150x150.jpeg&quot; data-src=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/2005.jpeg&quot; data-responsive=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/2005-980x518.jpeg 1080, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/2005-1440x761.jpeg 2560&quot; data-sub-html=&quot;#caption-1300487&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;France.com as seen in 2005.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;France.com&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li data-thumb=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/2001-150x150.jpeg&quot; data-src=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/2001.jpeg&quot; data-responsive=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/2001-980x595.jpeg 1080, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/2001-1440x874.jpeg 2560&quot; data-sub-html=&quot;#caption-1300489&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;France.com as seen in 2001.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;France.com&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li data-thumb=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/99-150x150.jpeg&quot; data-src=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/99.jpeg&quot; data-responsive=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/99-980x698.jpeg 1080, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/99-1440x1025.jpeg 2560&quot; data-sub-html=&quot;#caption-1300491&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;France.com as seen in 1999.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;France.com&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li data-thumb=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/97-150x150.jpeg&quot; data-src=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/97.jpeg&quot; data-responsive=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/97-980x708.jpeg 1080, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/97-1440x1040.jpeg 2560&quot; data-sub-html=&quot;#caption-1300493&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;France.com as seen in 1997.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;France.com&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On April 19, Frydman filed a federal lawsuit in Virginia in an attempt to get his domain name back. The suit names the French Republic, Atout France (a government tourism agency), the Ministry of Foreign Affairs, the minister himself (Jean-Yves Le Drian), and VeriSign as defendants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None of the defendants has yet made a formal appearance in the Alexandria, Virginia, courtroom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Web.com, the original registrar, is not a party to the lawsuit. However, the company seems to have taken it upon itself to heed the French legal ruling and give up the France.com domain name without a fight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Frydman's civil complaint &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/4446066-1-Complaint.html#document/p4/a420695&quot;&gt;states&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prior to the incidents complained of in this lawsuit, Defendants did not object to nor challenge Plaintiff's ownership or use of &amp;lt;France.com&amp;gt;. To the contrary, and as previously demonstrated in Exhibit A, Defendants publicly recognized Plaintiff as a leader in the tourism industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2015, Defendants began expressing an interest in owning the &amp;lt;France.com&amp;gt; domain name and exploiting it for Defendants' own use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Defendants did not approach Plaintiff to purchase or license the domain, the trademark, or Plaintiff's underlying business and goodwill. Instead, in 2015, Defendants misused the French judicial system to seize the domain from Plaintiff without compensation, under the erroneous theory that Defendants were inherently entitled to take the domain because it included the word &quot;France.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Defendants knew that they did not, and do not, have a right to the word &quot;France,&quot; as evidenced by Defendant Atout France's US Trademark Registration No. 4027580, filed in 2009, in which Defendant expressly disclaimed the exclusive right to the word &quot;France.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lawsuit accuses France of cybersquatting France.com and &quot;reverse domain-name hijacking,&quot; among other allegations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Web.com's chief legal officer, Matt McClure, did not respond to Ars' request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;They claim to be a company that's good for small businesses,&quot; Frydman said. &quot;What a joke. They've been absolutely horrible, not even answering our emails.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 29 Apr 2018 14:38:10 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>coobird</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2018/04/france-seizes-france-com-from-man-whos-had-it-since-94-so-he-sues/</og:url>
<og:title>France seizes France.com from man who’s had it since ‘94, so he sues</og:title>
<og:image>https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/GettyImages-565297243-760x380.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>Jean-Noël Frydman: &quot;If it happened to me, it can happen to anyone.&quot;</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2018/04/france-seizes-france-com-from-man-whos-had-it-since-94-so-he-sues/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>&amp;#039;Demonically Clever&amp;#039; Backdoor Hides Inside Computer Chip</title>
<link>https://www.wired.com/2016/06/demonically-clever-backdoor-hides-inside-computer-chip/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.wired.com/2016/06/demonically-clever-backdoor-hides-inside-computer-chip/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Security flaws in software can be tough to find. Purposefully planted ones—hidden backdoors created by spies or saboteurs—are often even stealthier. Now imagine a backdoor planted not in an application, or deep in an operating system, but even deeper, in the hardware of the processor that runs a computer. And now imagine that silicon backdoor is invisible not only to the computer’s software, but even to the chip’s designer, who has no idea that it was added by the chip’s manufacturer, likely in some farflung Chinese factory. And that it’s a single component hidden among hundreds of millions or billions. And that each one of those components is less than a thousandth of the width of a human hair.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In fact, researchers at the University of Michigan haven’t just imagined that computer security nightmare; they’ve built and proved it works. In a &lt;a href=&quot;http://static1.1.sqspcdn.com/static/f/543048/26931843/1464016046717/A2_SP_2016.pdf?token=N4pJSSoqL4kE4V4JXpTwx7qDRX4%3D&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; that won the “best paper” award at last week’s IEEE Symposium on Privacy and Security, they detailed the creation of an insidious, microscopic hardware backdoor proof-of-concept. And they showed that by running a series of seemingly innocuous commands on their minutely sabotaged processor, a hacker could reliably trigger a feature of the chip that gives them full access to the operating system. Most disturbingly, they write, that microscopic hardware backdoor wouldn’t be caught by practically any modern method of hardware security analysis, and could be planted by a single employee of a chip factory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Detecting this with current techniques would be very, very challenging if not impossible,” says Todd Austin, one of the computer science professors at the University of Michigan who led the research. “It’s a needle in a mountain-sized haystack.” Or as Google engineer Yonatan Zunger &lt;a href=&quot;https://plus.google.com/+YonatanZunger/posts/ayXVWrFpQus&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;wrote&lt;/a&gt; after reading the paper: “This is the most demonically clever computer security attack I’ve seen in years.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Analog Attack&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The “demonically clever” feature of the Michigan researchers’ backdoor isn’t just its size, or that it’s hidden in hardware rather than software. It’s that it violates the security industry’s most basic assumptions about a chip’s digital functions and how they might be sabotaged. Instead of a mere change to the “digital” properties of a chip—a tweak to the chip’s logical computing functions—the researchers describe their backdoor as an “analog” one: a &lt;em&gt;physical&lt;/em&gt; hack that takes advantage of how the actual electricity flowing through the chip’s transistors can be hijacked to trigger an unexpected outcome. Hence the backdoor’s name: A2, which stands for both Ann Arbor, the city where the University of Michigan is based, and “Analog Attack.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s how that analog hack works: After the chip is fully designed and ready to be fabricated, a saboteur adds a single component to its “mask,” the blueprint that governs its layout. That single component or “cell”—of which there are hundreds of millions or even billions on a modern chip—is made out of the same basic building blocks as the rest of the processor: wires and transistors that act as the on-or-off switches that govern the chip’s logical functions. But this cell is secretly designed to act as a capacitor, a component that temporarily stores electric charge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/Screen-Shot-2016-05-31-at-8.43.32-AM.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-2037847 size-text-column-width&quot; src=&quot;https://www.wired.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/Screen-Shot-2016-05-31-at-8.43.32-AM-482x265.png&quot; alt=&quot;This diagram shows the size of the processor created by the researchers compared with the size of malicious cell that triggers its backdoor function.&quot; width=&quot;482&quot; height=&quot;265&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;This diagram shows the size of the processor created by the researchers compared with the size of malicious cell that triggers its backdoor function.&lt;span class=&quot;credit link-underline-sm&quot;&gt;University of Michigan&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every time a malicious program—say, a script on a website you visit—runs a certain, obscure command, that capacitor cell “steals” a tiny amount of electric charge and stores it in the cell’s wires without otherwise affecting the chip’s functions. With every repetition of that command, the capacitor gains a little more charge. Only after the “trigger” command is sent many thousands of times does that charge hit a threshold where the cell switches on a logical function in the processor to give a malicious program the full operating system access it wasn’t intended to have. “It takes an attacker doing these strange, infrequent events in high frequency for a duration of time,” says Austin. “And then finally the system shifts into a privileged state that lets the attacker do whatever they want.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That capacitor-based trigger design means it’s nearly impossible for anyone testing the chip’s security to stumble on the long, obscure series of commands to “open” the backdoor. And over time, the capacitor also leaks out its charge again, closing the backdoor so that it’s even harder for any auditor to find the vulnerability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;New Rules&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Processor-level backdoors &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usenix.org/legacy/event/leet08/tech/full_papers/king/king_html/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;have been proposed before&lt;/a&gt;. But by building a backdoor that exploits the unintended physical properties of a chip’s components—their ability to “accidentally” accumulate and leak small amounts of charge—rather than their intended logical function, the researchers say their backdoor component can be a thousandth the size of previous attempts. And it would be far harder to detect with existing techniques like visual analysis of a chip or measuring its power use to spot anomalies. “We take advantage of these rules ‘outside of the Matrix’ to perform a trick that would [otherwise] be very expensive and obvious,” says Matthew Hicks, another of the University of Michigan researchers. “By following that different set of rules, we implement a much more stealthy attack.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Michigan researchers went so far as to build their A2 backdoor into a simple open-source OR1200 processor to test out their attack. Since the backdoor mechanism depends on the physical characteristics of the chip’s wiring, they even tried their “trigger” sequence after heating or cooling the chip to a range of temperatures, from negative 13 degrees to 212 degrees Fahrenheit, and found that it still worked in every case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/Screen-Shot-2016-05-31-at-8.43.56-AM.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-default-top-art wp-image-2037848&quot; src=&quot;https://www.wired.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/Screen-Shot-2016-05-31-at-8.43.56-AM-582x288.png&quot; alt=&quot;The experimental setup the researchers used to test their backdoored processor at different temperatures.&quot; width=&quot;582&quot; height=&quot;288&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Here you can see the experimental setup the researchers used to test their backdoored processor at different temperatures.&lt;span class=&quot;credit link-underline-sm&quot;&gt;University of Michigan&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As dangerous as their invention sounds for the future of computer security, the Michigan researchers insist that their intention is to prevent such undetectable hardware backdoors, not to enable them. They say it’s very possible, in fact, that governments around the world may have already thought of their analog attack method. “By publishing this paper we can say it’s a real, imminent threat,” says Hicks. “Now we need to find a defense.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But given that current defenses against detecting processor-level backdoors wouldn’t spot their A2 attack, they argue that a new method is required: Specifically, they say that modern chips need to have a trusted component that constantly checks that programs haven’t been granted inappropriate operating-system-level privileges. Ensuring the security of that component, perhaps by building it in secure facilities or making sure the design isn’t tampered with before fabrication, would be far easier than ensuring the same level of trust for the entire chip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They admit that implementing their fix could take time and money. But without it, their proof-of-concept is intended to show how deeply and undetectably a computer’s security could be corrupted before it’s ever sold. “I want this paper to start a dialogue between designers and fabricators about how we establish trust in our manufactured hardware,” says Austin. “We need to establish trust in our manufacturing, or something very bad will happen.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s the Michigan researchers’ full paper:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;a class=&quot;visually-hidden skip-to-text-link focusable bg-white&quot; href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/2016/06/demonically-clever-backdoor-hides-inside-computer-chip/#start-of-content&quot;&gt;Go Back to Top. Skip To: Start of Article.&lt;/a&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 29 Apr 2018 08:53:35 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Digit-Al</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>This ‘Demonically Clever’ Backdoor Hides In a Tiny Slice of a Computer Chip</og:title>
<og:image>https://www.wired.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/GettyImages-467833575-1200x630.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>Researchers have built a proof-of-concept processor that uses secretly stored electrical charge to trigger an ultra-stealthy backdoor.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.wired.com/2016/06/demonically-clever-backdoor-hides-inside-computer-chip/</og:url>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.wired.com/2016/06/demonically-clever-backdoor-hides-inside-computer-chip/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>What happened, Gmail?</title>
<link>https://uxplanet.org/what-happened-gmail-e5f35e423b1b</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://uxplanet.org/what-happened-gmail-e5f35e423b1b</guid>
<description>&lt;p name=&quot;3c01&quot; id=&quot;3c01&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf--leading&quot;&gt;From a business perspective I understand that there are more people using Gmail than Calendar, Keep or the new Tasks, but the way Google has attempted to bring people into the fold and have them use add-ons and the rest of their products is just crazy. It’s a designer’s nightmare and it transports me back to the 90s when only developers were building web apps. Why do I mention the 90s? Well, it’s because it happens to look very similar to Outlook, AOL, and Yahoo, all from this era. All of these services still work amazingly well, but it’s not accurate to call what Google has done new. It’s the same thing in a new box, with the same problems and over complexity. It comes as no surprise that companies like Slack succeed by solving these problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*aYkRcVr6msMgwMFXKrJvFw.png&quot; data-width=&quot;1490&quot; data-height=&quot;864&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*aYkRcVr6msMgwMFXKrJvFw.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*aYkRcVr6msMgwMFXKrJvFw.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Starting to look a lot like this — which gets even worse on mobile
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;2b5f&quot; id=&quot;2b5f&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf--startsWithDoubleQuote graf-after--figure&quot; readability=&quot;8.3684210526316&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Google has &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/2018/02/01/google-cloud-revenue-passes-1-billion-per-quarter.html&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/2018/02/01/google-cloud-revenue-passes-1-billion-per-quarter.html&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--blockquote-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;4 million people&lt;/a&gt; paying for G Suite right now, compared to 120 million Office 365 commercial users….1.4 billion people are using Gmail, compared to 400 million on Microsoft’s Outlook.com service.” (The Verge)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;301c&quot; id=&quot;301c&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--blockquote&quot;&gt;There is more functionality and design here than on an airplane dashboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 name=&quot;54a6&quot; id=&quot;54a6&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Innovation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;d7ca&quot; id=&quot;d7ca&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;Cross-selling, merging, and doing a Frankenstein is not innovation. Moving features from one service to another is also not innovation. Even though it’s impossible to innovate every year, I would hope that within one of the core products at Google there is a willingness to innovate. When I hear of a redesign I’m always excited, and I’m still excited about the fact that something has changed with Gmail, even if it’s not enough to get me to go back to using it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*zB5W2nPicWBpXzwUnaP3ag.jpeg&quot; data-width=&quot;1500&quot; data-height=&quot;750&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*zB5W2nPicWBpXzwUnaP3ag.jpeg&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*zB5W2nPicWBpXzwUnaP3ag.jpeg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;581b&quot; id=&quot;581b&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;Here are a few of the innovations that are needed:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;postList&quot;&gt;&lt;li name=&quot;47cb&quot; id=&quot;47cb&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--p&quot;&gt;A good method for telling users what’s important to read and what can wait for later.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p name=&quot;8162&quot; id=&quot;8162&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--li&quot;&gt;• A way to help users handle the amount of emails they get.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;28b9&quot; id=&quot;28b9&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;• An efficient way to categorize, filter and search content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;0534&quot; id=&quot;0534&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;• New ways of passing information (from media types, to supported files for preview).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;c9f4&quot; id=&quot;c9f4&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;• A tool to help users fix mistakes they’ve made, such as sending someone the wrong email, or spelling something incorrectly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;289c&quot; id=&quot;289c&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;• Providing an efficient way of sending big files (Drive works to some extent, but it’s cumbersome in many cases).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;d3bb&quot; id=&quot;d3bb&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;• Allowing users to handle their business better through Gmail (e.g. sign documents, approve things, review things).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;ed8b&quot; id=&quot;ed8b&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;• Allowing users to design their emails in a better way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;b335&quot; id=&quot;b335&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;• Letting users know if someone read their presentation and what parts interested them (DocSend).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;f79c&quot; id=&quot;f79c&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p graf--trailing&quot;&gt;All of these are focused on the core usage of Gmail: communicating with information. Ideally, you don’t need emails to schedule a meeting because emailing is slow, complicated and sometimes requires too much coordination. That’s why you have tools like X.AI (Amy), Calendarly and Doodle. Tasks are also way better informed by chatter rather than an email.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 29 Apr 2018 08:43:41 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>xoxoavi</dc:creator>
<og:title>What happened Gmail? – UX Planet</og:title>
<og:url>https://uxplanet.org/what-happened-gmail-e5f35e423b1b</og:url>
<og:image>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*KOB2-XoR74y3LFPbH3b3hA.jpeg</og:image>
<og:description>I’m a Google Inbox user, and since Inbox for iOS hasn’t been updated to match the screen size of iPhone X (which seems quite a trivial…</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://uxplanet.org/what-happened-gmail-e5f35e423b1b?gi=1539ca79857f</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The NetHack dev team is happy to announce the release of NetHack 3.6.1</title>
<link>https://groups.google.com/forum/m/#!topic/rec.games.roguelike.nethack/XhcIrLlNzpA</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://groups.google.com/forum/m/#!topic/rec.games.roguelike.nethack/XhcIrLlNzpA</guid>
<description>The NetHack DevTeam is happy to announce the release of NetHack 3.6.1.&lt;p&gt;3.6.1 is a general patch release.  It includes a large number of fixes&lt;br /&gt;to the 3.6.0 version, all of which have been incrementally published on&lt;br /&gt;the public Git repository for the game.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The DevTeam has decided that 3.6.1 will be the final &quot;official&quot; 3.6.x&lt;br /&gt;version, barring some sort of major issue that requires a new release.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After this release, 3.6 will continue to be maintained in our Git repositories,&lt;br /&gt;however the team will focus on a new major release. Another 3.6.x release&lt;br /&gt;and packaged set of binaries, is not anticipated.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here's a synopsis of some of the changes we've made in the past two years&lt;br /&gt;(approximately) since the release of 3.6.0 in December 2015:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;1. Personnel changes&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We've added some additional members to the team since the 3.6.0 release:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Alex Smith and Patric Mueller joined the team in July 2016.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Alex created the AceHack and NetHack 4 variants and is an expert on the&lt;br /&gt;inner workings of the game and the ways in which they can be exploited.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Patric is probably best known as the creator of the UnNetHack variant.&lt;br /&gt;He also created NetHack-De (a German translation of NetHack) and has&lt;br /&gt;considerable involvement in the Junethack tournament.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;2. Gameplay changes&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are fewer gameplay changes in 3.6.1 than in 3.6.0,  but still over&lt;br /&gt;500 items.  Here are a few, though not necessarily the most important,&lt;br /&gt;examples:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;General New Features&lt;br /&gt;--------------------&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    Naming Sting or Orcrist now breaks illiterate conduct&lt;br /&gt;    Poison breath leaves a trail of poison gas&lt;br /&gt;    Allow knife and stiletto as possible tin opening tools&lt;br /&gt;    New status line conditions Stone Strngl Deaf Lev Fly Ride&lt;br /&gt;    Swallowers can't re-engulf hero immediately after spitting him/her out&lt;br /&gt;    Allow taming monkeys and apes with bananas&lt;br /&gt;    Ray bounceback chance depends on the wall type&lt;br /&gt;    Undead #turning takes less time at higher experience level&lt;br /&gt;    Peacefuls may react when you attack other peacefuls&lt;br /&gt;    Prevent diagonal jumping through open doorways&lt;br /&gt;    Give feedback just before timed levitation runs out&lt;br /&gt;    Blinded hero or monster who eats a nurse corpse will have blindness cured&lt;br /&gt;    Wielding *bane have additional effects&lt;br /&gt;    &quot;Elbereth&quot; must now be the only engraved text on a square to function&lt;br /&gt;    &quot;Elbereth&quot; now erodes based on attacks by the player, not monsters scared&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;NetHack Community Patches (or Variations) Included&lt;br /&gt;-------------------------------------------------&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    Malcolm Ryan's improved tin opener&lt;br /&gt;    Ray Chason's keyboard may stop responding after locking or unlocking a door&lt;br /&gt;        when using altkeyhandler=nhraykey.dll&lt;br /&gt;    Ray Chason's fix: window interfaces that support transparency may give away&lt;br /&gt;        unseen parts of the map&lt;br /&gt;    Ray Chason's xprname should honor iflags.menu_tab_sep&lt;br /&gt;    Ray Chason's punctuation for &quot;That foo is really a mimic.&quot;&lt;br /&gt;    Ray Chason's proper background tiles for lava and water&lt;br /&gt;    Ray Chason's MS-DOS port restored to functionality with credit to Reddit user&lt;br /&gt;        b_helyer for the fix to sys/share/pcmain.c&lt;br /&gt;    Ray Chason's MSDOS port support for some VESA modes&lt;br /&gt;    Ray Chason's Qt4 windowport&lt;br /&gt;    Darshan Shaligram's pet ranged attack&lt;br /&gt;    Jason Dorje Short's key rebinding&lt;br /&gt;    Maxime Bacoux's new DUMPLOG: compile-time option to enable logging of&lt;br /&gt;         end-of-game information into a text file&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For a complete, very granular, but not necessarily clear list of the&lt;br /&gt;changes incorporated in this release, please take a look at the file&lt;br /&gt;doc/fixes36.1 in the source distribution.  This file has a full list of all&lt;br /&gt;changes to the game.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The text in this file is populated automatically for the development team's&lt;br /&gt;own use and is provided &quot;as is&quot;, so please do not ask us to further explain&lt;br /&gt;the entries in that file. Some entries may also be &quot;spoilers&quot;, particularly&lt;br /&gt;in the &quot;new features&quot; sections, so read at your own risk.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;3. Deprecations announced post NetHack 3.6.1&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;3.6.1 is essentially a maintenance release and as such doesn't change much&lt;br /&gt;in terms of what is or is not supported.  However there will be some&lt;br /&gt;significant changes to support in the next major release.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following ports will be dropped from the next major release unless&lt;br /&gt;someone comes forward to maintain them:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    * Amiga&lt;br /&gt;    * Atari&lt;br /&gt;    * Macintosh Classic&lt;br /&gt;    * BeOS&lt;br /&gt;    * OS/2&lt;br /&gt;    * 16-bit MS-DOS&lt;br /&gt;    * Floppy disk support for all platforms&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Starting with the next major release, we will be dropping support for most&lt;br /&gt;K&amp;amp;R and pre-ANSI C features, including:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;    * The Bitfield macro&lt;br /&gt;    * K&amp;amp;R function definitions&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Starting with the next major release, we will start using ANSI C features;&lt;br /&gt;which ones have yet to be determined.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;If you are actively running NetHack on a system that cannot handle full&lt;br /&gt;ANSI C, please let us know some details and we _might_ be able to&lt;br /&gt;accommodate you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;4. Save File Portability:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Save files should be portable between version 3.6.0 and 3.6.1.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We did, however, identify a bug early in the 3.6.0 release that may affect&lt;br /&gt;some score files.For full instructions on how to deal with this bug, please&lt;br /&gt;go to:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://nethack.org/v360/bugmore/fixrecord.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://nethack.org/v360/bugmore/fixrecord.html&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://nethack.org/v360/bugmore/fixrecord.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://nethack.org/v360/bugmore/fixrecord.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yes, this is in the 3.6.0 tree as it is a 3.6.0 bug.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As with all releases of the game, we appreciate your feedback. Please submit&lt;br /&gt;any bugs using the problem report form at:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nethack.org/common/contact.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.nethack.org/common/contact.html&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also, please check the &quot;known bugs&quot; list at:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nethack.org/v361/bugs.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.nethack.org/v361/bugs.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;before you log a problem - somebody else may have already found it, after all.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Happy NetHacking!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the DevTeam...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mike Stephenson&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 29 Apr 2018 00:49:32 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>hapnin</dc:creator>
<og:title>The NetHack DevTeam is happy to announce the release of NetHack 3.6.1.</og:title>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>https://groups.google.com/forum/#!topic/rec.games.roguelike.nethack/XhcIrLlNzpA</og:url>
<og:image>http://www.google.com/images/icons/product/groups-128.png</og:image>
<og:description>Posted 4/27/18 6:59 PM, 13 messages</og:description>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://groups.google.com/forum/m/?_escaped_fragment_=topic/rec.games.roguelike.nethack/XhcIrLlNzpA</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ask HN: My startup has basically failed. What now?</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16949209</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16949209</guid>
<description>&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.55737704918033&quot;&gt;&lt;td bgcolor=&quot;#FF6600&quot;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;9.3552546744036&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table class=&quot;fatitem&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;6.5486782720825&quot;&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing&quot; id=&quot;16949209&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;right&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;title&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16949209&quot; class=&quot;storylink&quot;&gt;Ask HN: My startup has basically failed. What now?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.75&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;subtext&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;score&quot; id=&quot;score_16949209&quot;&gt;369 points&lt;/span&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/user?id=mlevental&quot; class=&quot;hnuser&quot;&gt;mlevental&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;age&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16949209&quot;&gt;1 day ago&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span id=&quot;unv_16949209&quot;/&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/hide?id=16949209&amp;amp;goto=item%3Fid%3D16949209&quot;&gt;hide&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://hn.algolia.com/?query=Ask%20HN%3A%20My%20startup%20has%20basically%20failed.%20What%20now%3F&amp;amp;sort=byDate&amp;amp;dateRange=all&amp;amp;type=story&amp;amp;storyText=false&amp;amp;prefix&amp;amp;page=0&quot; class=&quot;hnpast&quot;&gt;past&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=Ask%20HN%3A%20My%20startup%20has%20basically%20failed.%20What%20now%3F&quot;&gt;web&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/fave?id=16949209&amp;amp;auth=142362e6190de4a1ec2d44e86cfde29e3ba46d62&quot;&gt;favorite&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16949209&quot;&gt;193 comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;14&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;I've been working on a startup for ~9 months (as the technical cofounder) in the event tech space (B2B tradeshows) and I'm pretty sure we've failed to do anything productive (find product/market fit, find a problem/solution fit, learn anything valuable, etc.). We still have ~100k left but the main investors/advisors (from the 220k friends/family/fools round) pretty much feel like it's time to pull the plug. My personal opinion is that that's the most responsible thing to do (return money pro-rata) but there are simultaneous voices (paradoxically same investors) pushing to keep going (continue running pilots, building out the team [we just finally found a bd cofounder], crafting a pitch for a seed round). I don't know what to do since in my understanding we've failed at the most important thing: finding product/market fit. others on the team (advisors) believe that that's not the case and we can keep raising based on negative results.
&lt;p&gt;re pilots: we got 5 pilots (some paying some not) by basically being persistent and doing really really high touch sales. two of them ran this week and they were miserable failures (for every reason from poor marketing/education to last minute catastrophic product failures). absolutely all of the metrics skew heavily towards 0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i realize i'm being vague and maybe there's not enough detail in the post to give substantive advice but regardless any would be appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td&gt;

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;yclinks&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/newsguidelines.html&quot;&gt;Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/newsfaq.html&quot;&gt;FAQ&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:hn@ycombinator.com&quot;&gt;Support&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/HackerNews/API&quot;&gt;API&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/security.html&quot;&gt;Security&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/lists&quot;&gt;Lists&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/bookmarklet.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Bookmarklet&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ycombinator.com/legal/&quot;&gt;Legal&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ycombinator.com/apply/&quot;&gt;Apply to YC&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:hn@ycombinator.com&quot;&gt;Contact&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2018 20:08:10 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mlevental</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16949209</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Seattle vacates hundreds of marijuana charges going back 30 years</title>
<link>https://www.theroot.com/seattle-vacates-hundreds-of-marijuana-possession-charge-1825622917</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.theroot.com/seattle-vacates-hundreds-of-marijuana-possession-charge-1825622917</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;img-wrapper lazy-image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-permalink-sub-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;js_lightbox-wrapper lightbox-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.kinja-img.com/gawker-media/image/upload/s--a6euO8cB--/c_scale,f_auto,fl_progressive,q_80,w_800/dr9eoxskr5ohfci78lol.jpg&quot; class=&quot;lazyload ls-lazy-image-tag&quot; data-sizes=&quot;auto&quot; data-width=&quot;2119&quot; data-chomp-id=&quot;dr9eoxskr5ohfci78lol&quot; data-format=&quot;jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Photo: iStock&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The City of Seattle on Friday filed a motion asking the court to vacate hundreds of marijuana possession convictions going back three decades and adversely impacting people of color.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;City Attorney Pete Holmes acknowledged the racial disparity in marijuana convictions, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/4448762-Marijuana-Vacation-Motion.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; onclick=&quot;window.ga('send', 'event', 'Embedded Url', 'External link', 'https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/4448762-Marijuana-Vacation-Motion.html', {metric25:1})&quot;&gt;citing an ACLU report showing that African Americans are more than three times more likely to be arrested for pot possession than whites&lt;/a&gt;, despite the facts that blacks and whites use at the same rates.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;js_ad-mobile-dynamic js_ad-dynamic ad-mobile-dynamic&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ad-unit js_ad-unit hide-contents ad-mobile js_ad-mobile&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ad-mobile-inner&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ad-label proxima&quot;&gt;&lt;small class=&quot;proxima&quot;&gt;Advertisement&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“As we see marijuana sold in retail storefronts today, people who simply had a joint in their pocket a decade ago still have a red mark on their records,” &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thestranger.com/slog/2018/04/27/26107159/city-files-motion-to-vacate-misdemeanor-pot-convictions&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; onclick=&quot;window.ga('send', 'event', 'Embedded Url', 'External link', 'https://www.thestranger.com/slog/2018/04/27/26107159/city-files-motion-to-vacate-misdemeanor-pot-convictions', {metric25:1})&quot;&gt;Holmes said in a statement&lt;/a&gt;. “It’s long past time we remedy the drug policies of yesteryear, and this is one small step to right the injustices of a drug war that has primarily targeted people of color. I’m hopeful the court will choose to clear these charges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marijuana is now legal in the state of Washington; voters approved its recreational use in 2012. A 2017 report forecasts &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thenewstribune.com/news/local/marijuana/article130464479.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; onclick=&quot;window.ga('send', 'event', 'Embedded Url', 'External link', 'http://www.thenewstribune.com/news/local/marijuana/article130464479.html', {metric25:1})&quot;&gt;the state to take in about $730 million from sales of legalized marijuana over the next two years&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In February, Seattle Mayor Jenny Durkan announced the proposed reversals in a press release, saying the move would affect 542 people who have weed convictions on their records.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;js_ad-mobile-dynamic js_ad-dynamic ad-mobile-dynamic&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ad-unit js_ad-unit hide-contents ad-mobile js_ad-mobile&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ad-mobile-inner&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ad-label proxima&quot;&gt;&lt;small class=&quot;proxima&quot;&gt;Advertisement&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Vacating charges for misdemeanor marijuana possession is a necessary step to correct the injustices of what was a failed war on drugs, which disproportionately affected communities of color in Seattle,” the Democratic mayor said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The war on drugs in large part became a war on people who needed opportunity and treatment,” she added.” While we cannot reverse all the harm that was done, we must do our part to give Seattle residents — including immigrants and refugees — a clean slate.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thehill.com/homenews/state-watch/385248-seattle-officials-file-motion-to-vacate-marijuana-convictions&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; onclick=&quot;window.ga('send', 'event', 'Embedded Url', 'External link', 'http://thehill.com/homenews/state-watch/385248-seattle-officials-file-motion-to-vacate-marijuana-convictions', {metric25:1})&quot;&gt;The Hill reports&lt;/a&gt; that Seattle is following in the footsteps of Philadelphia District Attorney Larry Krasner, who in February dropped more than 50 criminal charges against residents for marijuana possession, in a radical new policy shift that he says should free up “[police] resources to solve homicides.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;js_ad-mobile-dynamic js_ad-dynamic ad-mobile-dynamic&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ad-unit js_ad-unit hide-contents ad-mobile js_ad-mobile&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ad-mobile-inner&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ad-label proxima&quot;&gt;&lt;small class=&quot;proxima&quot;&gt;Advertisement&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;inset--story js_inset branded-item branded-item--kinja&quot; onclick=&quot;window.ga('send', 'event', 'Embedded Url', 'External inset', 'https:\/\/www.nbcphiladelphia.com\/news\/local\/Marijuana-Criminal-Cases-Dropped-En-Masse-by-Philadelphia-District-Attorney-Larry-Krasner-474228023.html', {metric25:1})&quot; readability=&quot;15.54469273743&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nbcphiladelphia.com/news/local/Marijuana-Criminal-Cases-Dropped-En-Masse-by-Philadelphia-District-Attorney-Larry-Krasner-474228023.html&quot; class=&quot;inset--story__thumb&quot; onclick=&quot;window.ga('send', 'event', 'Permalink page click', 'Permalink page click - inset photo');&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazyload&quot; data-sizes=&quot;auto&quot; src=&quot;https://i.kinja-img.com/gawker-media/image/upload/s--gaMHaVC3--/c_fill,fl_progressive,g_north,h_77,q_80,w_137/xof24f5545zyhqjmswhk.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Article preview thumbnail&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;inset--story__content&quot; readability=&quot;19.357541899441&quot;&gt;
&lt;h6 class=&quot;inset--story__headline&quot; onclick=&quot;window.ga('send', 'event', 'Permalink page click', 'Permalink page click - inset headline');&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nbcphiladelphia.com/news/local/Marijuana-Criminal-Cases-Dropped-En-Masse-by-Philadelphia-District-Attorney-Larry-Krasner-474228023.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Marijuana Cases Dropped En Masse by Philly District Attorney&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Philadelphia District Attorney said criminal charges for marijuana possession against 51 people …&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nbcphiladelphia.com/news/local/Marijuana-Criminal-Cases-Dropped-En-Masse-by-Philadelphia-District-Attorney-Larry-Krasner-474228023.html&quot; class=&quot;js_readmore inset--story__readmore&quot; onclick=&quot;window.ga('send', 'event', 'Permalink page click', 'Permalink page click - inset read more link');&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Read more &lt;span class=&quot;js_external-text hide&quot;&gt;Read&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;As is now accepted fact, the so-called war on drugs laws has decimated the African American community, with marijuana criminalization oftentimes becoming the first contact many have with a grinding criminal justice system that won’t let them go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The arrests can stay on their records for years, and impact their prospects for jobs, loans, housing and benefits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;js_ad-mobile-dynamic js_ad-dynamic ad-mobile-dynamic&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ad-unit js_ad-unit hide-contents ad-mobile js_ad-mobile&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ad-mobile-inner&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ad-label proxima&quot;&gt;&lt;small class=&quot;proxima&quot;&gt;Advertisement&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This video put out by the Drug Policy Alliance and narrated by Jay-Z, runs down some of the disturbing stats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The question now becomes is 1,000 or even 10,000 vacated convictions enough to turn the tide of the adverse effects of mass incarceration?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2018 19:49:07 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>MilnerRoute</dc:creator>
<og:title>Seattle Vacates Hundreds of Marijuana Charges Going Back 30 Years</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:image>https://i.kinja-img.com/gawker-media/image/upload/s--bmml10Ck--/c_fill,fl_progressive,g_center,h_900,q_80,w_1600/dr9eoxskr5ohfci78lol.jpg</og:image>
<og:url>https://www.theroot.com/seattle-vacates-hundreds-of-marijuana-possession-charge-1825622917</og:url>
<og:description>The City of Seattle on Friday filed a motion asking the court to vacate hundreds of marijuana possession convictions going back three decades and adversely impacting people of color.</og:description>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.theroot.com/seattle-vacates-hundreds-of-marijuana-possession-charge-1825622917</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>It’s Impossible to Prove Your Laptop Hasn’t Been Hacked</title>
<link>https://theintercept.com/2018/04/28/computer-malware-tampering/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://theintercept.com/2018/04/28/computer-malware-tampering/</guid>
<description>&lt;div data-reactid=&quot;185&quot; readability=&quot;77&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How safe is it to leave your laptop in your hotel room while you’re attending sessions at a conference? If you come back to find your laptop in a different position than where you thought you left it, can you still trust it? Did someone tamper with it, did a hotel housekeeper simply straighten up the items you left on your desk, or did you misremember where you left it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These questions typically can’t be answered with total confidence because clever tampering can be so hard to detect. But I hoped I could get a sense of the risks with a carefully controlled experiment. For the last two years, I have carried a “honeypot” laptop with me every time I’ve traveled; this computer was intended to attract (and then detect) tampering. If any hackers, state-sponsored or otherwise, wanted to hack me by physically messing with my computer, I wanted to not only catch them in the act, but also gather technical evidence that I could use to learn how their attack worked and, hopefully, who the attacker was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While traveling by air, I checked this laptop in my luggage to make it easily accessible to border agents, both domestic and foreign, to tamper with if they chose to. When staying in hotels, I left the laptop sitting on the desk in my room while I was away during the day, to make sure that any malicious housekeepers with permission to enter my room, or anyone else who broke into my room, was free to tamper with it if they chose to. I also put a bunch of hacker stickers all over it, hoping that this would make it a more enticing target.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-wrap align-right width-fixed&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2018/04/IMG_1651-1524597624.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignright size-article-medium wp-image-184827&quot; src=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2018/04/IMG_1651-1524597624.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&amp;amp;w=540&amp;amp;h=1023&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_1651-1524597624&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;A “notice of baggage inspection” from TSA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption source&quot;&gt;Photo: Micah Lee&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Over the duration of this experiment, I traveled to Europe three times and domestically in the United States five times (including once to Puerto Rico). I found eight different notices from the Transportation Security Administration informing me that my baggage had been searched. I have no way of knowing how many times it had been searched by other authorities who weren’t kind enough to leave me a note.
&lt;p&gt;I never caught anyone tampering with this laptop. But the absence of any evidence of tampering — and my obsessive thoughts about the various ways an attacker could have evaded by detection — serve to underline how fraught the process of computer forensics can be. If someone who makes their living securing computers thinks they could have missed a computer infection, what hope is there for the average computer user?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of my experiment, I thought through all of the things that could have gone wrong. Perhaps someone did tamper with my honeypot laptop, and my methodology for detecting this wasn’t thorough enough to notice. Or maybe potential attackers noticed that the laptop I carried with me and used at the conferences I was attending was different than the one I left in my room, and decided against tampering with it in case it was a trap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the most likely reason I didn’t catch any attackers is that no one tried to tamper with my laptop. Hacking a target’s laptop by physically tampering with it while they’re traveling probably happens only rarely because it’s so expensive – it may require travel, physical surveillance, breaking and entering, and the risk of getting caught or breaking the laptop is high. Compare this to cheap forms of hacking like email phishing: You can target thousands of people at once from the comfort of your office, and the risk of getting caught is much lower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, I believe actively checking devices for tampering is worthwhile. You’ll never catch an attacker in the act if you never look for evidence of their attacks. And just looking for evidence, even if you don’t find any, increases costs for attackers: If they want to be sure you won’t notice, they’re going to have to get more creative. I believe it’s useful to explain the technology and the methodology I came up with to detect tampering and share what I learned from the experience. Doing so gives a taste of just how many ways there are to tamper with a laptop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div data-reactid=&quot;196&quot; readability=&quot;373.8149608125&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Evil Maid Attacks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you don’t &lt;a href=&quot;https://theintercept.com/2015/04/27/encrypting-laptop-like-mean/&quot;&gt;use full disk encryption&lt;/a&gt; on your laptop, anyone who gains physical access to it, even for just a few minutes, can access all of your data and even implant malware on your computer to spy on you in the future. It doesn’t matter how good your password is because without encryption, the attacker can simply unscrew the case on your laptop, remove your hard disk, and access it from another computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disk encryption does a great job of protecting your data in case you lose your laptop or someone steals it from you. When this person tries accessing your data, they should be completely locked out, so long as the passphrase you use to unlock your laptop is &lt;a href=&quot;https://theintercept.com/2015/03/26/passphrases-can-memorize-attackers-cant-guess/&quot;&gt;strong enough&lt;/a&gt; that they can’t guess it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there is a sneaky class of attack, called “evil maid” attacks, that disk encryption alone cannot protect against. Evil maid attacks work like this: An attacker (such as a malicious hotel housekeeper, for example) gains temporary access to your encrypted laptop. Although they can’t decrypt your data, they can spend a few minutes tampering with your laptop and then leave it exactly where they found it. When you come back and type in your credentials, &lt;em&gt;now&lt;/em&gt; you have been hacked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exactly how an evil maid attack would work against your laptop depends on many factors: the type of computer you use, what operating system you use, which disk encryption software you use, and the configuration of firmware used to boot your computer, firmware which I’ll call “BIOS,” although it can also go by acronyms like EFI and UEFI. Some computers have considerably better technology to prevent evil maid attacks than others – for example, attackers have to do more advanced tampering to hack a Windows laptop encrypted with BitLocker than they do to hack a Mac laptop encrypted with FileVault (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twocanoes.com/secureboot-imac-pro/&quot;&gt;as of now&lt;/a&gt;, anyway) or a Linux laptop encrypted with LUKS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-wrap align-center width-fixed&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2018/04/IMG_0538-1524597859.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-184829&quot; src=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2018/04/IMG_0538-1524597859.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&amp;amp;w=1024&amp;amp;h=698&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;The honeypot laptop I used, with red boxes around the hard disk and the SPI flash chip that stores the BIOS firmware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption source&quot;&gt;Photo: Micah Lee&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;Here are the main ways that an attacker could physically tamper with your laptop:
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;An attacker could modify data on your hard disk.&lt;/strong&gt; “Full disk encryption,” the term used to refer generically to systems like FileVault, really ought to be called “nearly full disk encryption” because, except in a few specific circumstances, there’s always a small part of a computer’s disk that isn’t encrypted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you power on your laptop, before your disk has been unlocked, your computer loads a program from this unencrypted part of your disk; it then runs the program, and the program asks you to enter your passphrase. The program converts your passphrase into an encryption key and tries to use it to unlock the disk. If you typed the correct passphrase, the disk unlocks, and the rest of the operating system (which is stored in the encrypted part of the disk) boots up. If you don’t know the right passphrase, there is no way to unlock the disk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But since the program that asks for your passphrase isn’t encrypted, it’s possible for an attacker that physically has your laptop to replace it with a malicious version that looks exactly the same to the user, but that takes extra steps. For example, after you successfully unlock your disk, it might copy malware onto it that, after the computer finishes booting up, automatically runs in the background, spying on what you’re doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Computers that support “secure boot” or “verified boot,” such as Chromebooks and Windows laptops with BitLocker, aren’t vulnerable to this. The BIOS can detect if the unencrypted part of your disk has been tampered with, and if it has, it will refuse to boot. MacBooks and laptops that run Linux could potentially be attacked in this way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;An attacker could replace your BIOS firmware with malicious firmware.&lt;/strong&gt; When you power on your computer, the very first program that your computer runs is your BIOS firmware. The job of this program is to initialize all of your hardware – your memory, disks, Wi-Fi adapter, video card, USB ports, and everything else – and then ultimately boot an operating system, typically the one stored on your hard disk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you format your disk and install a new operating system on your computer, your BIOS firmware doesn’t change. This is because this program isn’t stored on your hard disk at all. Instead, it’s stored in a small chip on your computer’s motherboard called an SPI flash chip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is why BIOS malware is so stealthy – you can’t get rid of it by formatting your hard disk, and it can spy on you across operating systems, such as if you boot to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://tails.boum.org/&quot;&gt;Tails&lt;/a&gt; USB stick.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SPI flash chips have eight pins, including one for providing the chip with power, one for reading data, and one for writing data to the chip. This means that it’s possible for an attacker to power off your laptop, open up the case, and attach their own wires to the SPI flash chip pins in order to power it on, and then read and write data to it (the chip itself has no way of telling the difference between this, or just being part of the normal computer). Using this technique, an attacker with physical access to your laptop can replace your BIOS firmware with whatever malware they want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Italian spyware firm Hacking Team was caught &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.trendmicro.com/trendlabs-security-intelligence/hacking-team-uses-uefi-bios-rootkit-to-keep-rcs-9-agent-in-target-systems/&quot;&gt;selling such BIOS malware&lt;/a&gt; to its customers (the company’s clients include &lt;a href=&quot;https://theintercept.com/2015/07/07/leaked-documents-confirm-hacking-team-sells-spyware-repressive-countries/&quot;&gt;foreign governments with troubling human rights records&lt;/a&gt;). This specific firmware made sure that Windows was always infected with malware. If you’re a target of a Hacking Team customer, even formatting your disk and re-installing Windows would not remove the malware. As soon as you reboot, the malicious BIOS firmware would re-infect the freshly installed Windows with the same malware again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-wrap align-center width-fixed&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2018/04/honeypot_bios_flash-1524598249.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-184830&quot; src=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2018/04/honeypot_bios_flash-1524598249.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&amp;amp;w=1024&amp;amp;h=768&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Trying to dump BIOS firmware directly from the SPI flash chip by wiring it to a BeagleBone Black, a small and cheap external computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption source&quot;&gt;Photo: Micah Lee&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;An attacker could do other things to your hardware.&lt;/strong&gt; Tampering with unencrypted data on your hard disk, or replacing your BIOS firmware with malware, are the most straightforward types of evil maid attacks, but the list of other potential attacks is only limited by the attacker’s creativity and budget.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are a few examples:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;An attacker could potentially figure out a way of spying on your computer use by replacing firmware on other components of your computer besides your BIOS, like your processor, video card, network card, or hard disk.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An attacker could install a hardware keylogger (they would plug your internal keyboard into the keylogger, then plug the keylogger into the motherboard) with the intention of stealing your laptop later, but with a record of your disk passphrase and your other keystrokes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An attacker could completely replace your laptop with a different laptop of the same model – they could even put your real laptop case with all your stickers and scratches on the fake laptop, so that it looks exactly the same. When you type your passphrase into this one though, it could send that passphrase over the internet to the attacker, who could then use it to unlock your real disk.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I decided to start this honeypot laptop project, I realized early on that I couldn’t possibly detect every form of tampering. Because tampering with the data on the hard disk or the BIOS firmware are the simplest and cheapest types of evil maid attacks to conduct, and because attackers have limited resources and prefer low-hanging fruit when it’s available, I decided to limit my detection to these two components. But who knows? It’s possible that my honeypot laptop has a malicious component in it that I never checked for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-wrap align-bleed full-bleed width-auto&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2018/04/IMG_1651-1-1524775041.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-185481&quot; src=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2018/04/IMG_1651-1-1524775041.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_1651-1-1524775041&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption overlayed&quot;&gt;Re-assembling the computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption source pullright&quot;&gt;Photo: Micah Lee&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Methodology&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In February 2016, shortly before I was planning to fly to Spain for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://internetfreedomfestival.org/&quot;&gt;Internet Freedom Festival&lt;/a&gt;, I bought a Lenovo IdeaPad S210 Touch for about $700 to use as my honeypot laptop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here was the plan. Before each trip, I would:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Update all of the software on my honeypot laptop. (I wanted potential attackers to see that I’m using up-to-date bootloader software stored on the small unencrypted part of my disk, to believe that I actively use this computer.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Power off the laptop, and don’t power it on again until the trip was over. (Just by powering on the computer, I risk slightly modifying data in my BIOS and hard disk.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove the hard disk from the laptop, attach it to an external USB enclosure, and plug it into another computer, taking care not to modify any data on it. From there, I could make a record of the state of the disk.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Attach a &lt;a href=&quot;https://beagleboard.org/black&quot;&gt;BeagleBone Black&lt;/a&gt;, or BBB, a tiny $50 computer that’s great for hardware hacking, to the SPI flash chip on the motherboard and use it to dump the BIOS firmware, saving an exact copy of the data stored on the chip.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Re-assemble the computer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then, during the trip, I would:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Put the honeypot laptop in my checked luggage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Leave the honeypot laptop unattended in my hotel room.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once I returned home from a trip, I would:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Remove the hard disk from the laptop, plug it into another computer, and record the state of the disk again. If even a single bit of data on the disk has changed, I could detect it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Attach the BBB to the SPI flash chip and dump the BIOS firmware again. I could then compare the firmware image I took from before my trip with the image I took after it, to detect if it was tampered with.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Along the way, I planned to document everything: I’d take photos of my laptop in my luggage, in hotels, and of the cards that TSA leaves informing me that they searched my luggage; I’d keep a log of the state of my hard disk and BIOS before and after each trip; and I’d keep a journal that includes all technical hurdles I ran into.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is &lt;em&gt;mostly&lt;/em&gt; how it went down, but I did run into a few snags. Bear with me, in the following sections I venture much deeper into the technical weeds than I already have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Checking the Hard Disk for Tampering&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I proceed, there a few concepts I need to explain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Computer drives, whether disk- or flash- based, are organized into separate “partitions.” For example, if you install Linux with disk encryption, your drive will likely have two partitions: a small (often less than 1 gigabyte) unencrypted partition called “/boot” – this is where the program that asks for your encryption passphrase is stored, and where evil maids might put their malware – and the rest of the disk will contain a large encrypted partition. After you unlock the encrypted partition with the right passphrase, it will likely contain two other partitions inside, a “/” or “root” partition that holds the rest of the files on the computer, and a “swap” partition that’s only used when the computer is running low on memory. (I refer to both flash- and disk- based storage drives as “disks” and “hard disks.”)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is a small amount of disk space at the beginning of every hard disk (which I call the disk header) that’s reserved for a bootloader program. When you power on a computer and boot from your hard disk, you run this program. In Linux, this program simply starts running another program called “grub” that’s stored in your unencrypted “/boot” partition. Grub is responsible for actually booting your operating system. In order to detect evil maid attacks, it’s important to make sure the disk header was not tampered with.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In cryptography, a “hash function” is a one-way function that takes an input of any size and outputs a fixed-size result called a “hash” or “checksum.” For example, with SHA256, the hash function I use in this project, whether your input is 5 bytes long (the size of the word “hello”) or 512 gigabytes long (the size of a hard disk), the output will always be 32 bytes long. The same input will always lead to the same output, but if you change the input in &lt;em&gt;any way&lt;/em&gt;, even if only a single byte is different, the content of the output will be entirely different (although the length will be the same). You can use checksums to detect tampering.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I started this project, I decided to dual-boot Windows 10 and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.debian.org/&quot;&gt;Debian&lt;/a&gt;, a popular Linux distribution, on my honeypot laptop – that is, I installed both operating systems in different partitions on the same disk, and when I powered on the computer, I got to choose which to boot to. But due to various time-consuming and annoying issues related to Windows updates, I eventually chose to abandon Windows altogether and just run Debian on my honeypot laptop, which made my job of detecting hard disk tampering simpler.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before each trip, I removed the disk from the honeypot laptop, plugged it into a USB enclosure, and then plugged the USB disk enclosure into a different computer. The first snag I ran into was that when I plugged in the USB disk, my computer automatically tried to mount the partitions. This isn’t good – just by mounting the partitions, I risked modifying the data. So I changed the settings on my computer (which was running Linux) to disable automatically mounting external drives by following &lt;a href=&quot;https://access.redhat.com/solutions/20107&quot;&gt;these instructions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-wrap align-center width-fixed&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2018/04/IMG_0545-1524598450.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-184832&quot; src=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2018/04/IMG_0545-1524598450.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&amp;amp;w=1024&amp;amp;h=768&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Hard disk from the honeypot laptop, removed and plugged into a cheap external USB enclosure that can be plugged into a separate computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption source&quot;&gt;Photo: Micah Lee&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Once the USB disk enclosure was attached to a computer other than the honeypot, I could generate checksums of all of the disk’s partitions, as well as the disk header, using a tool called &lt;a href=&quot;https://help.ubuntu.com/community/HowToSHA256SUM&quot;&gt;sha256sum&lt;/a&gt;. In order to take a checksum of just the disk header, I used a tool called &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dd_(Unix)&quot;&gt;dd&lt;/a&gt; to copy the disk header into a file, and then used sha256sum to take a checksum of that file.
&lt;p&gt;When I returned home from my trip, I repeated the same process to generate a new set of checksums. Finally, I compared the checksums from before my trip with the checksums from after my trip. If the checksums were not the same, then the data on the disk must have changed – this would be evidence of tampering. If I discovered this, I could then start looking into exactly what data had changed to discover how the tampering worked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, in March 2017, before flying to Amsterdam to attend a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.torproject.org/&quot;&gt;Tor Project&lt;/a&gt; meeting with developers, volunteers, and advocates for the open-source anonymity network, these were the checksums I generated:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
4040239f4f0a2090c3ca15216b6e42522c4c3cd291f2c78f3c9e815f25be8295 disk_header
ed6e8a3438e55d2aeae4ae691823c4005f7b5df0b62d856bd72d54fa00d886bb /dev/xvdi1
db3d92ed1cfa8621e5673da32100d9117a3835c06a613cf9ac0f2f90de404d17 extended_header
cbeb585b6fa39a8425f57fa095ac17353a583bccd93532d65d9274da628a4c72 luks_header
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ten days later, after I had returned from my trip, I generated another set of checksums. They all turned out to be exactly the same, which allowed me to confirm that the data on my hard disk had not changed at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Checking the BIOS for Tampering&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I started this project, I intended to dump BIOS firmware images externally using a BeagleBone Black (explained previously) and a software tool called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flashrom.org/Flashrom&quot;&gt;flashrom&lt;/a&gt;, which is used for reading and writing data that’s stored on physical chips on circuit boards, roughly following the &lt;a href=&quot;https://libreboot.org/docs/install/bbb_setup.html&quot;&gt;instructions outlined here&lt;/a&gt;. But I quickly hit a snag, one that I didn’t have the tools or knowledge of electronics to easily resolve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The SPI flash chip that holds my honeypot laptop’s BIOS firmware has a pin for power and another pin for ground. With the laptop powered off, I connected the power and ground pins to my BBB, and then powered on the BBB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had hoped that the BBB would provide power to the SPI flash chip, allowing me to read and write directly to that chip. But instead the BBB immediately powered off. It turns out that, the way this specific laptop was wired, the power for the SPI chip was not isolated from the rest of the system. In order to provide power to that chip, I also needed to provide power to rest of the components of the motherboard, and that takes more watts than my BBB was able to handle. This was annoying because one of the reasons I chose a Lenovo computer as my honeypot laptop is because I have had success doing this exact process on other Lenovo computers in the past, dumping the BIOS firmware by connecting a BBB to the SPI flash chip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I decided to change strategies. Instead of dumping the BIOS firmware by connecting wires directly from the SPI flash chip, I would instead use a piece of software called &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/chipsec/chipsec&quot;&gt;chipsec&lt;/a&gt;, running on the honeypot laptop itself, to dump the firmware. However, this strategy has a few downsides compared to directly connecting to the chip:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;In order to run chipsec, I needed to first power on the honeypot laptop and boot to an operating system. It turns out that this process, booting up the computer, slightly modifies the data stored in the BIOS firmware, which makes it more difficult to check for tampering.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It’s impossible to get a complete BIOS dump from within an operating system, but you can get most of it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When I dump BIOS firmware using chipsec, it may be possible for sophisticated BIOS malware to lie to chipsec, which could be used to prevent detection. (I have never heard of BIOS malware that actually does this, though.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;In order to use chipsec, I set up a USB stick with the operating system &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ubuntu.com/desktop&quot;&gt;Ubuntu&lt;/a&gt; (another popular Linux distribution). With the hard disk removed from the honeypot laptop, I plugged in my Ubuntu USB stick, powered on the laptop, and booted to Ubuntu. I put a copy of chipsec on an SD memory card, which I also plugged into the laptop. From there, I was able to run a specific chipsec command to dump the BIOS firmware and save it to the SD card, which I could then inspect on my other computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-wrap align-bleed large-bleed width-auto&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2018/04/honeypot_chipsec-1524598486.png?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-184833&quot; src=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2018/04/honeypot_chipsec-1524598486.png?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&amp;amp;w=1024&amp;amp;h=576&quot; alt=&quot;honeypot_chipsec-1524598486&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption overlayed&quot;&gt;Dumping the BIOS firmware using chipsec.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Here is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.virustotal.com/en/file/2e3263fa904729c3c4d416b7ee8d7cec21500a4c50f33a348140003aeef988e7/analysis/1456336870/&quot;&gt;VirusTotal report&lt;/a&gt; from the first BIOS firmware image that I dumped using chipsec from my honeypot laptop.
&lt;p&gt;Once I successfully managed to dump the BIOS firmware, I came up with this plan:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Before each trip, I would remove the hard disk from the laptop, boot to the Ubuntu USB stick, and dump the BIOS firmware, making sure to save a copy of it on my other computer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After I return from the trip, I would repeat the process, dumping a fresh BIOS firmware image.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Then I would generate checksums of the BIOS firmware images from before and after my trip. If the checksums were exactly the same, I could confirm that my BIOS was not tampered with.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Of course, it wasn’t this simple. It turns out, &lt;em&gt;every time&lt;/em&gt; I booted my honeypot laptop to an Ubuntu live USB stick and dumped the BIOS firmware, that firmware image had a different checksum than the previous one. In order to investigate what was going on, I used a program called &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/LongSoft/UEFITool&quot;&gt;UEFITool&lt;/a&gt;. This is a graphical program that lets you load BIOS images, view and edit what data is stored inside, and extract data into separate files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-wrap align-center width-fixed&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2018/04/honeypot_uefitool-1524598511.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-article-large wp-image-184834&quot; src=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2018/04/honeypot_uefitool-1524598511.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&amp;amp;w=1000&amp;amp;h=796&quot; alt=&quot;honeypot_uefitool-1524598511&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Inspecting BIOS firmware using UEFITool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
For this specific laptop, each BIOS firmware image is exactly 4 megabytes. Some of that space is used to store the actual programs that make up the BIOS (an evil maid attacker would replace these programs with malicious versions), and some of it is used to store other data, such as saved BIOS settings.
&lt;p&gt;Looking at two BIOS firmware images that had different checksums, I was able to use UEFITool to extract the same components from both, and then generate new checksums for those individual components to see if they matched. I discovered that there was only one small part of the firmware images that differed, and that part did not include any programs. It turns out, each time I powered on the honeypot laptop and opened the boot menu to tell it to boot from my Ubuntu USB stick, it saved information related to booting to a USB stick in that section of the firmware, and this information was slightly different each time, which caused the firmware images to always have different checksums.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I amended my plan for detecting tampering in the BIOS firmware. To compare firmware images from before and after my trip, I would have to open each image in UEFITool, extract all of the components except for the one that I knew changed, generate checksums for those components, and then compare &lt;em&gt;those&lt;/em&gt; checksums to make sure they matched.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What I Learned&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traveling with a honeypot laptop was a lot of work. It required spending a few hours both before and after each trip if I hoped to actually catch an evil maid attacker in the act. So after two years without catching anyone, I have decided to retire the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A tool exists today, that didn’t exist when I started the project, that makes it possible to catch evil maid attackers in the act in a different way. &lt;a href=&quot;https://theintercept.com/2017/12/22/snowdens-new-app-uses-your-smartphone-to-physically-guard-your-laptop/&quot;&gt;Haven&lt;/a&gt; is an Android app, designed to run on a spare phone that you leave in your hotel room while you’re away, perhaps sitting on top of your laptop. It uses all of its sensors – microphone, motion detector, light detector, and cameras – to monitor the room for changes, logs everything it notices, and can send Signal notifications to the phone you carry with you when it detects a change. Haven isn’t perfect – there are plenty of false positives – but it gets better all the time and is still likely to catch anyone attempting to tamper with the laptop that’s sitting under the phone Haven is running on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was able to do this entire project with 100% free and open source software, thanks to projects like Debian and Ubuntu and tools like dd, sha256sum, flashrom, chipsec, and UEFITool. Other than the honeypot laptop itself, you can buy all of the hardware tools I used, like screwdrivers, a USB enclosure, and a BeagleBone Black, for less than $100.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Top photo: Honeypot laptop in the luggage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2018 17:28:52 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>wglb</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://theintercept.com/2018/04/28/computer-malware-tampering/</og:url>
<og:description>I spent two years trying to get someone to tamper with my laptop, so I could then detect it. Somewhere along the way, I realized this might never happen.</og:description>
<og:image>https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2018/04/honeypot-feature-1524597271.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;q=90&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=1200&amp;h=800</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>It’s Impossible to Prove Your Laptop Hasn’t Been Hacked. I Spent Two Years Finding Out.</og:title>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://theintercept.com/2018/04/28/computer-malware-tampering/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Lessons learned from a failing local mall</title>
<link>https://www.strongtowns.org/journal/2018/4/23/bon-ton-gone</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.strongtowns.org/journal/2018/4/23/bon-ton-gone</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-layout sqs-grid-12 columns-12&quot; data-layout-label=&quot;Post Body&quot; data-type=&quot;item&quot; data-updated-on=&quot;1524461381256&quot; id=&quot;item-5add6c14352f538288118dec&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row sqs-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col sqs-col-12 span-12&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block html-block sqs-block-html&quot; data-block-type=&quot;2&quot; id=&quot;block-85b60e10fb9262c66e8d&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In high school, when I took my girlfriend (now my wife) to the Christmas Ball, I bought my clothes at the nicer of the two clothiers in town: Herberger's. The other — JC Penny — is where I bought most of my regular school clothes. That was life in a small town in the early 1990's. Still is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At least until the last year. It was thirteen months ago that we found out that &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.brainerddispatch.com/news/4236361-update-jc-penney-shutter-baxter-store&quot;&gt;the JC Penney was going to close&lt;/a&gt;. It had moved from its old location in the East Brainerd Mall (where it had moved from its original location in downtown Brainerd) to the Highway 371 bypass strip — &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.strongtowns.org/journal/2015/1/18/the-classic-case&quot;&gt;the &quot;classic case&quot; of transportation investment success&lt;/a&gt;, according to one of our most respected policy advocates — but even that wasn't enough to save it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week we found out we were going to lose our other big store. With &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/2018/04/18/heres-a-map-of-all-of-bon-tons-stores.html&quot;&gt;the forced liquidation of Bon-Ton&lt;/a&gt;, parent company of Herberger's, the last major retailer in my hometown is gone. Here's &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.brainerddispatch.com/business/4434952-biz-buzz-changing-business-landscape&quot;&gt;how the local paper&lt;/a&gt; described it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Just this week, the lakes area learned it is losing its second major department store with Herberger's leaving and J.C. Penney already gone. It represents the last large department store in Brainerd and highlights a real and major shift in the American consumer. Something that wouldn't have been considered not that long ago when passing the Herberger's cosmetics counter or browsing through row after row of merchandise.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Forced Liquidation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven't studied the books at Bon-Ton because I have no intention of owning anything in the American retail space at the moment, but I did take a few minutes to look over some of their recent financials. It's ugly. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They have nearly a billion dollars in debt, the interest of which overwhelms the profit they are generating off their operations. This is true even at today's ridiculously low interest rates. In a normal interest rate environment, this debt hog would have been slain quite a while ago. As it sits, enough was done to help it limp along, despite having every indication that it would never be able to claw its way out of this. &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.thestreet.com/story/14365572/1/bon-ton-gets-a-tiny-boost-from-lenders-ahead-of-holiday-season.html&quot;&gt;A debt rollover at the end of last year&lt;/a&gt; was probably a chance for creditors to buy time to unload the debt onto some pension fund or foreign sucker, er... investor. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of 2016, the company had $35 million in equity securing $1.5 billion in liabilities, a leverage ratio of 1:43. Ha! And that got worse by the end of last year, when total liabilities exceeded equity and the company was forced into bankruptcy. Despite the fact that the company would operate profitably if the debt were wiped out, the creditors are going to secure what they can and sell off the parts that have some value. Getting out of the lease they have with my little town mall will be a simple formality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Efficient, but Fragile&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember when Herberger's opened. In fact, I remember when the mall itself opened. It was a big deal. Sure, there was whining about the destruction of the downtown but, come on, those places really weren't that competitive in today's market. Herberger's and national retailers like them were able to operate much more efficiently and, as the story goes, pass those savings on to consumers. The message to the community was simple: better selection, better prices and everything would be shiny and new. We embraced it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block image-block sqs-block-image sqs-col-6 span-6 float float-right&quot; data-block-type=&quot;5&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1524461387017_48181&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-outer-wrapper layout-caption-below design-layout-inline&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;intrinsic&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-wrapper has-aspect-ratio&quot; data-description=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static1.squarespace.com/static/53dd6676e4b0fedfbc26ea91/t/5add800e6d2a739567bfc2dd/1524465693349/FB+herbergers.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;FB herbergers.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;thumb-image&quot; alt=&quot;FB herbergers.jpg&quot; data-src=&quot;https://static1.squarespace.com/static/53dd6676e4b0fedfbc26ea91/t/5add800e6d2a739567bfc2dd/1524465693349/FB+herbergers.jpg&quot; data-image=&quot;https://static1.squarespace.com/static/53dd6676e4b0fedfbc26ea91/t/5add800e6d2a739567bfc2dd/1524465693349/FB+herbergers.jpg&quot; data-image-dimensions=&quot;503x422&quot; data-image-focal-point=&quot;0.5,0.5&quot; data-load=&quot;false&quot; data-image-id=&quot;5add800e6d2a739567bfc2dd&quot; data-type=&quot;image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block html-block sqs-block-html&quot; data-block-type=&quot;2&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1524461387017_48449&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a thought experiment, I asked a local Facebook page dedicated to sharing Brainerd history to help me put together a list of the clothiers that operated in the downtown before the opening of Herberger's, a.k.a. those inefficient businesses that &quot;the market&quot; killed off through &quot;competition&quot; (albeit competition with a ton of government subsidy, but hey, who's counting). Here's an abbreviated list of the responses:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Opal Ann's, John Bye's Clothiers, Cunningham's, Georgia's Dress Shop, Brekken's Men's Store, Carlson's, Rosalin Style Shop, JC Penny, O'Brien's, Murphy's, Montgomery Ward, Sear's, Ehler's, Fieldman's Army Navy Store, Mezner's Children's Shop, Paul's Shoes, Sampson's Shoes, Sylvester's, Dottie's Hats, Woolworth's, Winkleman's Furs, Karin's Shop and the Frances Shop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My grandmother worked at that last one. I remember going to visit her with my mom, a trip where I was bribed with a promised visit to the pet and hobby store across the street. That's quite an ecosystem of clothiers and it makes me kinda sick to my stomach to think about them all gone. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the pursuit of the shiny and new, the efficient and the low-priced, we turned our backs on decades of small business wealth creation. We walked away from all of these stores — all these families and their local bank deposits, local newspaper ads, local insurance brokers, local accountants, softball team sponsorships, Fourth of July floats, Crazy Day sales and after school jobs — and, as the old saying goes, put all our eggs into one basket.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm sure Herberger's had a greater shoe selection, cheaper clothes and a shinier location with a mall Santa at Christmas. They also had a fragile business model, one that was far too responsive to investors far beyond our little city limits. All the profits from the sales here went to provide the basis for greater and greater leverage (along with bonuses, dividends and the like—almost none of which stayed in Brainerd). We're still willing to give them our money — to spirit our wealth out of here as quickly as possible — but they are too bloated to take it anymore. So now we have an empty store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What was the payoff?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So we gutted our downtown, devaluing our core neighborhoods in the process. But we must have gotten something worthwhile in the process, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block image-block sqs-block-image sqs-col-6 span-6 float float-left&quot; data-block-type=&quot;5&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1524461387017_29406&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-outer-wrapper layout-caption-below design-layout-inline&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;intrinsic&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-wrapper has-aspect-ratio&quot; data-description=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static1.squarespace.com/static/53dd6676e4b0fedfbc26ea91/t/5add84ff0e2e7220202c4b19/1524466951958/mall+dt.png&quot; alt=&quot;mall dt.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;thumb-image&quot; alt=&quot;mall dt.png&quot; data-src=&quot;https://static1.squarespace.com/static/53dd6676e4b0fedfbc26ea91/t/5add84ff0e2e7220202c4b19/1524466951958/mall+dt.png&quot; data-image=&quot;https://static1.squarespace.com/static/53dd6676e4b0fedfbc26ea91/t/5add84ff0e2e7220202c4b19/1524466951958/mall+dt.png&quot; data-image-dimensions=&quot;904x800&quot; data-image-focal-point=&quot;0.5,0.5&quot; data-load=&quot;false&quot; data-image-id=&quot;5add84ff0e2e7220202c4b19&quot; data-type=&quot;image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block html-block sqs-block-html&quot; data-block-type=&quot;2&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1524461387017_71786&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the most tragic part of the story.  Today, the mall that once represented sophistication and progress is failing, just like similar malls in similar towns all around the country. The K-Mart anchor is gone and, while they've been able to replace it with a pair of lesser retailers, the shops in between the ends underwhelm. Herberger's had taken over nearly a third of the mall, and now they're gone too. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that downtown with all those historic clothiers now long departed? It's also a shell of its old self. While some life is starting to creep back in now, to my eyes, it's been through a lifetime of decline. Brainerd's downtown has fallen far from its high water mark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet look at the wealth. Even in its current (kinda sad) state, the nine blocks of the core downtown still produce 287% more property tax than the entire mall property. And that's before the Herberger's goes away, before there is a big hole in a building with no obvious way to fill it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine the wealth we would have if we &lt;em&gt;hadn't&lt;/em&gt; destroyed our downtown — if we hadn't walked away from the wealth our ancestors had built and disinvested from our core, if we hadn't been seduced by the shiny and new...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We ran sewer, water, storm sewer, commercial roads and sidewalks out to and around that failing mall location. Where is the money going to come from to fix and maintain all of that stuff now? We invested tens of millions in an approach that made us poorer. And now we don't even have a place to buy clothes, except the big box store strip — Walmart, Target, or maybe we could buy some coveralls at Mills Fleet Farm. Of course, all of these stores are in the neighboring city. It's a tragedy I struggle to fully comprehend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is how you bleed a small town white.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What Comes Next?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's pretty easy to predict what comes next. The rah-rah crowd — the ones who generally make their money or gain the little power there is to be wielded in such a place off these kind of &quot;growth&quot; transactions — will push to fill the space. Failure is not an option, regardless of the amount (or length) of subsidy required. There'll be talk of jobs and growth and restoring our economy. There'll be job training (a.k.a. debt acquisition potential for teacher salaries) for the dislocated and anything else needed to help those of us who are gainfully employed not have to fret too much about our neighbors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll embrace anyone big enough to fill that space, and in doing so, we'll continue to discount not only our history but the hard math of who is actually paying the freight in this community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block image-block sqs-block-image sqs-col-8 span-8 float float-right&quot; data-block-type=&quot;5&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1524461387017_64757&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-outer-wrapper layout-caption-below design-layout-inline&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;intrinsic&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-wrapper has-aspect-ratio&quot; data-description=&quot;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;In this map showing tax value per acre, the historic downtown and surrounding neighborhoods are the most financially productive land in the entire region. (Source: Urban3)&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&quot;&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static1.squarespace.com/static/53dd6676e4b0fedfbc26ea91/t/5add85396d2a739567c02b39/1524467008004/brainerd+wealth.jpg&quot; alt=&quot; In this map showing tax value per acre, the historic downtown and surrounding neighborhoods are the most financially productive land in the entire region. (Source: Urban3) &quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;thumb-image&quot; alt=&quot; In this map showing tax value per acre, the historic downtown and surrounding neighborhoods are the most financially productive land in the entire region. (Source: Urban3) &quot; data-src=&quot;https://static1.squarespace.com/static/53dd6676e4b0fedfbc26ea91/t/5add85396d2a739567c02b39/1524467008004/brainerd+wealth.jpg&quot; data-image=&quot;https://static1.squarespace.com/static/53dd6676e4b0fedfbc26ea91/t/5add85396d2a739567c02b39/1524467008004/brainerd+wealth.jpg&quot; data-image-dimensions=&quot;1027x599&quot; data-image-focal-point=&quot;0.5,0.5&quot; data-load=&quot;false&quot; data-image-id=&quot;5add85396d2a739567c02b39&quot; data-type=&quot;image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-caption-wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this map showing tax value per acre, the historic downtown and surrounding neighborhoods are the most financially productive land in the entire region. (Source: Urban3)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block html-block sqs-block-html&quot; data-block-type=&quot;2&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1524461387017_65025&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What we &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; do is recognize the fragile condition that we're in; our dependence on forces beyond our control not only threatens our ability to shop for clothes. It threatens everything. We rely on national retailers and their high debt / low equity business models for almost everything we buy. This should create a sense of urgency for us and an obsession with becoming more resilient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And we should also recognize where our wealth really comes from. It comes from our downtown and our core neighborhoods (those within walking distance of the downtown). It certainly doesn't come from people driving through those places. It doesn't come from people commuting in. It doesn't come from tourists or developers or the potential of land development out on the edge. Our wealth — the wealth built slowly over generations — is slowly seeping away in our downtown and its surrounding neighborhoods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Put these things together — the need to build resilience and the historic wealth that still remains in our core — and the strategy becomes too obvious to ignore: We need to piece our economic ecosystem back together. We shouldn't spend a penny on the mall — we should be willing to let it fall apart and collapse if the market can't support it. But we &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; support those investments in the core that are already paying our bills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here's the really sweet thing: the downtown doesn't need millions of dollars of investment. There are some trying to force that down the city's throat, but we don't need it. It's already the most successful area in the region. We just need to start reconnecting things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are thousands of people — thousands of &lt;em&gt;customers&lt;/em&gt; — living a short walk from downtown. There are hundreds at the courthouse each day. Hundreds at the high school as well. All these places are two to six blocks away from where we need them — a short and very easy walk — yet walking these paths is so dangerous and nasty that few people do it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fixing this should be our obsession. And let me clarify: starting to fix this on the &lt;em&gt;cheap&lt;/em&gt; — with paint, some construction cones and a modest landscaping budget — should be our obsession. If the closing of Herberger's does anything to us, it should turn us into obsessive fanatics about making our downtown as amazing a place as it once was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we do that, we'll find we spend less money, grow wealthier, become more resilient and gain greater control of our destiny. All that will happen, &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; the city will become a better place to live. That's the essence of a Strong Towns approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block summary-v2-block sqs-block-summary-v2&quot; data-block-json=&quot;{&amp;quot;hSize&amp;quot;:null,&amp;quot;floatDir&amp;quot;:null,&amp;quot;collectionId&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;54b6c509e4b062126976d942&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;design&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;carousel&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;headerText&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Related Stories&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;textSize&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;medium&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;pageSize&amp;quot;:3,&amp;quot;imageAspectRatio&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;columnWidth&amp;quot;:270,&amp;quot;gutter&amp;quot;:60,&amp;quot;listImageSize&amp;quot;:30,&amp;quot;listImageAlignment&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;left&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;slidesPerRow&amp;quot;:3,&amp;quot;textAlignment&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;left&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;showTitle&amp;quot;:true,&amp;quot;showThumbnail&amp;quot;:true,&amp;quot;showExcerpt&amp;quot;:true,&amp;quot;showReadMoreLink&amp;quot;:false,&amp;quot;showPrice&amp;quot;:true,&amp;quot;productQuickViewEnabled&amp;quot;:false,&amp;quot;showPastOrUpcomingEvents&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;upcoming&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;metadataPosition&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;below-content&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;primaryMetadata&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;date&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;secondaryMetadata&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;author&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;filter&amp;quot;:{&amp;quot;category&amp;quot;:null,&amp;quot;featured&amp;quot;:true,&amp;quot;tag&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;suburban experiment&amp;quot;},&amp;quot;autoCrop&amp;quot;:true,&amp;quot;lightbox&amp;quot;:false,&amp;quot;mixedContent&amp;quot;:true,&amp;quot;blockId&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;8dda2d167bac76a12470&amp;quot;}&quot; data-block-type=&quot;55&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1524487301507_12258&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot; summary-block-wrapper summary-block-collection-type-blog summary-block-setting-text-size-medium summary-block-setting-text-align-left summary-block-setting-design-carousel summary-block-setting-design-list-thumbnail-left summary-block-setting-metadata-position-below-content summary-block-setting-primary-metadata-date summary-block-setting-secondary-metadata-author summary-block-setting-show-thumbnail summary-block-setting-show-title summary-block-setting-show-price summary-block-setting-show-excerpt sqs-gallery-design-carousel&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;summary-item-list-container sqs-gallery-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;header class=&quot;summary-block-header&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;summary-heading&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;summary-header-text&quot;&gt;Related Stories&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/header&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;summary-item-list sqs-gallery&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot; summary-item summary-item-record-type-text sqs-gallery-design-carousel-slide summary-item-has-thumbnail summary-item-has-excerpt summary-item-has-cats summary-item-has-tags summary-item-has-author summary-item-has-comments-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;summary-thumbnail-outer-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;summary-thumbnail img-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-src=&quot;https://static1.squarespace.com/static/53dd6676e4b0fedfbc26ea91/54b6c509e4b062126976d942/5ad43a52562fa7176246425f/1524230223044/IMG_20180328_125045.jpg&quot; data-image=&quot;https://static1.squarespace.com/static/53dd6676e4b0fedfbc26ea91/54b6c509e4b062126976d942/5ad43a52562fa7176246425f/1524230223044/IMG_20180328_125045.jpg&quot; data-image-dimensions=&quot;2500x1875&quot; data-image-focal-point=&quot;0.5,0.5&quot; alt=&quot;Where did all the money go?&quot; data-load=&quot;false&quot; class=&quot;summary-thumbnail-image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;summary-content sqs-gallery-meta-container&quot;&gt;



&lt;div class=&quot;summary-excerpt&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no way to sustain a city over time without building wealth within it. That is why a Strong Towns approach is critical.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot; summary-item summary-item-record-type-text sqs-gallery-design-carousel-slide summary-item-has-thumbnail summary-item-has-excerpt summary-item-has-cats summary-item-has-tags summary-item-has-author summary-item-has-comments-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;summary-thumbnail-outer-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;summary-thumbnail img-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-src=&quot;https://static1.squarespace.com/static/53dd6676e4b0fedfbc26ea91/54b6c509e4b062126976d942/5a58ec8cc830254ae7beda88/1523040191104/Screen+Shot+2018-01-12+at+12.14.33+PM-min.png&quot; data-image=&quot;https://static1.squarespace.com/static/53dd6676e4b0fedfbc26ea91/54b6c509e4b062126976d942/5a58ec8cc830254ae7beda88/1523040191104/Screen+Shot+2018-01-12+at+12.14.33+PM-min.png&quot; data-image-dimensions=&quot;1365x468&quot; data-image-focal-point=&quot;0.5,0.5&quot; alt=&quot;Today is Yesterday’s Tomorrow&quot; data-load=&quot;false&quot; class=&quot;summary-thumbnail-image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;summary-content sqs-gallery-meta-container&quot;&gt;



&lt;div class=&quot;summary-excerpt&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the last 70 years, our cities and towns have spread out in a way that our forebears never dreamed of, and that future generations will never be able to pay for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot; summary-item summary-item-record-type-text sqs-gallery-design-carousel-slide summary-item-has-thumbnail summary-item-has-excerpt summary-item-has-cats summary-item-has-tags summary-item-has-author summary-item-has-comments-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;summary-thumbnail-outer-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;summary-thumbnail img-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-src=&quot;https://static1.squarespace.com/static/53dd6676e4b0fedfbc26ea91/54b6c509e4b062126976d942/59fc9f1fe31d1952e7182e73/1511907809544/Screen+Shot+2017-11-03+at+10.26.27+AM.png&quot; data-image=&quot;https://static1.squarespace.com/static/53dd6676e4b0fedfbc26ea91/54b6c509e4b062126976d942/59fc9f1fe31d1952e7182e73/1511907809544/Screen+Shot+2017-11-03+at+10.26.27+AM.png&quot; data-image-dimensions=&quot;1348x756&quot; data-image-focal-point=&quot;0.5,0.5&quot; alt=&quot;Big box stores are costing our cities far more than we ever imagined.&quot; data-load=&quot;false&quot; class=&quot;summary-thumbnail-image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;summary-content sqs-gallery-meta-container&quot;&gt;



&lt;div class=&quot;summary-excerpt&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Big box developments are &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; paying their fair share.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block summary-v2-block sqs-block-summary-v2&quot; data-block-json=&quot;{&amp;quot;hSize&amp;quot;:null,&amp;quot;floatDir&amp;quot;:null,&amp;quot;collectionId&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;54b6c50ae4b062126976ea98&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;design&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;list&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;headerText&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Featured&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;textSize&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;medium&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;pageSize&amp;quot;:1,&amp;quot;imageAspectRatio&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1.5&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;columnWidth&amp;quot;:270,&amp;quot;gutter&amp;quot;:60,&amp;quot;listImageSize&amp;quot;:30,&amp;quot;listImageAlignment&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;left&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;slidesPerRow&amp;quot;:3,&amp;quot;textAlignment&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;left&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;showTitle&amp;quot;:true,&amp;quot;showThumbnail&amp;quot;:true,&amp;quot;showExcerpt&amp;quot;:true,&amp;quot;showReadMoreLink&amp;quot;:false,&amp;quot;showPrice&amp;quot;:true,&amp;quot;productQuickViewEnabled&amp;quot;:false,&amp;quot;showPastOrUpcomingEvents&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;upcoming&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;metadataPosition&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;below-content&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;primaryMetadata&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;date&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;secondaryMetadata&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;none&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;filter&amp;quot;:{&amp;quot;category&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Marohn&amp;quot;},&amp;quot;autoCrop&amp;quot;:true,&amp;quot;lightbox&amp;quot;:false,&amp;quot;mixedContent&amp;quot;:true,&amp;quot;blockId&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0dcff36a62b126b106f4&amp;quot;}&quot; data-block-type=&quot;55&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1524461387017_76443&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot; summary-block-wrapper summary-block-collection-type-blog summary-block-setting-text-size-medium summary-block-setting-text-align-left summary-block-setting-design-list summary-block-setting-design-list-thumbnail-left summary-block-setting-metadata-position-below-content summary-block-setting-primary-metadata-date summary-block-setting-secondary-metadata-none summary-block-setting-show-thumbnail summary-block-setting-show-title summary-block-setting-show-price summary-block-setting-show-excerpt sqs-gallery-design-list&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;summary-item-list-container sqs-gallery-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;header class=&quot;summary-block-header&quot;&gt;

&lt;/header&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;summary-item-list sqs-gallery&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot; summary-item summary-item-record-type-text sqs-gallery-design-list-slide summary-item-has-thumbnail summary-item-has-excerpt summary-item-has-cats summary-item-has-tags summary-item-has-author summary-item-has-comments-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;summary-thumbnail-outer-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;summary-thumbnail img-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-src=&quot;https://static1.squarespace.com/static/53dd6676e4b0fedfbc26ea91/54b6c50ae4b062126976ea98/55fae021e4b02aa4358e5329/1524238003207/i-qxmJc8w-X3.jpg&quot; data-image=&quot;https://static1.squarespace.com/static/53dd6676e4b0fedfbc26ea91/54b6c50ae4b062126976ea98/55fae021e4b02aa4358e5329/1524238003207/i-qxmJc8w-X3.jpg&quot; data-image-dimensions=&quot;1600x1067&quot; data-image-focal-point=&quot;0.6679862060546875,0.23265971109538736&quot; alt=&quot;Charles Marohn&quot; data-load=&quot;false&quot; class=&quot;summary-thumbnail-image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;summary-content sqs-gallery-meta-container&quot;&gt;



&lt;div class=&quot;summary-excerpt&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Charles Marohn is the &lt;strong&gt;Founder and President of Strong Towns&lt;/strong&gt;. He's a Professional Engineer (PE) licensed in the State of Minnesota and a member of the American Institute of Certified Planners (AICP). Marohn has a bachelor's degree in Civil Engineering from the University of Minnesota's Institute of Technology and a Master of Urban and Regional Planning degree from the University of Minnesota's Humphrey Institute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marohn is the lead author of &lt;em&gt;Thoughts on Building Strong Towns — &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Thoughts-Building-Strong-Towns-1/dp/1478319275/ref=pd_bxgy_14_2?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;pd_rd_i=1478319275&amp;amp;pd_rd_r=J1YVNP9VVDEF4SWDXC16&amp;amp;pd_rd_w=hZGKR&amp;amp;pd_rd_wg=dM7Xn&amp;amp;psc=1&amp;amp;refRID=J1YVNP9VVDEF4SWDXC16&quot;&gt;Volume 1&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Thoughts-Building-Strong-Towns-II/dp/1533018553/ref=tmm_pap_swatch_0&quot;&gt;Volume 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;  and &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Thoughts-Building-Strong-Towns-III/dp/1979930139/ref=sr_1_2?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1514608731&amp;amp;sr=8-2&amp;amp;keywords=thoughts+on+building+strong+towns&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Volume 3&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; — as well as the author of &lt;em&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/World-Class-Transportation-System-Finance-ebook/dp/B00NDAB65W&quot;&gt;A World Class Transportation System&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. He hosts the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.strongtowns.org/podcast/&quot;&gt;Strong Towns Podcast&lt;/a&gt; and is a primary writer for Strong Towns’ web content. He has presented Strong Towns concepts in hundreds of cities and towns across North America and in 2017 was named one of the &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.planetizen.com/features/95189-100-most-influential-urbanists&quot;&gt;10 Most Influential Urbanists of all time&lt;/a&gt; by Planetizen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2018 14:23:38 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>oftenwrong</dc:creator>
<og:title>The Real Reason Your Local Mall is Failing</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.strongtowns.org/journal/2018/4/23/bon-ton-gone</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>The closing of the mall’s anchor store exposes how fragile the community’s business model is, providing an opening to shift approach.</og:description>
<og:image>http://static1.squarespace.com/static/53dd6676e4b0fedfbc26ea91/54b6c509e4b062126976d942/5add6c14352f538288118dec/1524836612568/herbergers.jpg?format=1000w</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.strongtowns.org/journal/2018/4/23/bon-ton-gone</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>