<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>The Multiworse Is Coming</title>
<link>http://backreaction.blogspot.com/2018/03/the-multiworse-is-coming.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://backreaction.blogspot.com/2018/03/the-multiworse-is-coming.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-XHuj9rg_r4o/WqfEFFm9dNI/AAAAAAAAD5w/0ChaC3HocfQON1wRxE2Y-hhBxKRPKI_WgCLcBGAs/s1600/mycat.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1200&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1600&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-XHuj9rg_r4o/WqfEFFm9dNI/AAAAAAAAD5w/0ChaC3HocfQON1wRxE2Y-hhBxKRPKI_WgCLcBGAs/s200/mycat.jpg&quot; width=&quot;200&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
You haven’t seen headlines recently about the Large Hadron Collider, have you? That’s because even the most skilled science writers can’t find much to write about.&lt;p&gt;There are loads of data for sure, and nuclear physicists are giddy with joy because the LHC has delivered &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1709.04922&quot;&gt;a wealth of new information about the structure of protons and heavy ions&lt;/a&gt;. But the good old proton has never been the media’s darling. And the fancy new things that many particle physicists expected – the supersymmetric particles, dark matter, extra dimensions, black holes, and so on – have shunned CERN.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s a PR disaster that particle physics won’t be able to shake off easily. Before the LHC’s launch in 2008, many theorists expressed themselves confident the collider would produce new particles besides the Higgs boson. That hasn’t happened. And the public isn’t remotely as dumb as many academics wish. They’ll remember next time we come ask for money.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The big proclamations came almost exclusively from theoretical physicists; CERN didn’t promise anything they didn’t deliver. That is an important distinction, but I am afraid in the public perception the subtler differences won’t matter. It’s “physicists said.” And what physicists said was wrong. Like hair, trust is hard to split. And like hair, trust is easier to lose than to grow.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What the particle physicists got wrong was an argument based on a mathematical criterion called “naturalness”. If the laws of nature were “natural” according to this definition, then the LHC should have seen something besides the Higgs. The data analysis isn’t yet completed, but at this point it seems unlikely something more than statistical anomalies will show up.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I must have sat through hundreds of seminars in which naturalness arguments were repeated. Let me just flash you a representative slide from a 2007 talk by Michelangelo L. Mangano (&lt;a href=&quot;https://indico.cern.ch/event/14815/contributions/180725/attachments/145317/205966/Mangano-IFAE07-web.pdf&quot;&gt;full pdf here&lt;/a&gt;), so you get the idea. The punchline is at the very top: “new particles must appear” in an energy range of about a TeV (ie accessible at the LHC) “to avoid finetuning.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-D_IIrhwcVBM/Wqe78JmSQoI/AAAAAAAAD5M/dHYNszblh8g8yHxN_QhHRtFg0EPg4hpNACLcBGAs/s1600/michelangelo.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;879&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1194&quot; height=&quot;235&quot; src=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-D_IIrhwcVBM/Wqe78JmSQoI/AAAAAAAAD5M/dHYNszblh8g8yHxN_QhHRtFg0EPg4hpNACLcBGAs/s320/michelangelo.jpg&quot; width=&quot;320&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;I don’t mean to pick on Mangano in particular; his slides are just the first example that Google brought up. This was the argument why the LHC should see something new: To avoid finetuning and to preserve naturalness.&lt;p&gt;I explained &lt;a href=&quot;http://backreaction.blogspot.de/2009/12/what-is-natural.html&quot;&gt;many&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://backreaction.blogspot.de/2013/12/the-finetuned-cube.html&quot;&gt;times&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://backreaction.blogspot.de/2016/07/why-lhc-is-such-disappointment-delusion.html&quot;&gt;previously&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://backreaction.blogspot.de/2017/11/naturalness-is-dead-long-live.html&quot;&gt;why&lt;/a&gt; the conclusions based on naturalness were not predictions, but merely pleas for the laws of nature to be pretty. Luckily I no longer have to repeat these warnings, because the data agree that naturalness isn’t a good argument.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The LHC hasn’t seen anything new besides the Higgs. This means the laws of nature aren’t “natural” in the way that particle physicists would have wanted them to be. The consequence is not only that there are no new particles at the LHC. The consequence is also that we have no reason to think there will be new particles at the next higher energies – not until you go up a full 15 orders of magnitude, far beyond what even futuristic technologies may reach.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So what now? What if there are no more new particles? What if we’ve caught them all and that’s it, game over? What will happen to particle physics or, more to the point, to particle physicists?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;http://inference-review.com/article/higgs-on-the-moon&quot;&gt;an essay some months ago&lt;/a&gt;, Adam Falkowski expressed it this way:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“[P]article physics is currently experiencing the most serious crisis in its storied history. The feeling in the field is at best one of confusion and at worst depression”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
At present, the best reason to build another particle collider, one with energies above the LHC’s, is to measure the properties of the Higgs-boson, specifically its self-interaction. But it’s difficult to spin a sexy story around such a technical detail. My guess is that particle physicists will try to make it sound important by arguing the measurement would probe whether our vacuum is stable. Because, depending on the exact value of a constant, the vacuum may or may not eventually decay in a catastrophic event that rips apart everything in the universe.*&lt;p&gt;Such a vacuum decay, however, wouldn’t take place until long after all stars have burned out and the universe has become inhospitable to life anyway. And seeing that most people don’t care what might happen to our planet in a hundred years, they probably won’t care much what might happen to our universe in 10&lt;sup&gt;&lt;span&gt;100&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; billion years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Personally I don’t think we need a specific reason to build a larger particle collider. A particle collider is essentially a large microscope. It doesn’t use light, it uses fast particles, and it doesn’t probe a target plate, it probes other particles, but the idea is the same: It lets us look at matter very closely. A larger collider would let us look closer than we have so far, and that’s the most obvious way to learn more about the structure of matter.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Compared to astrophysical processes which might reach similar energies, particle colliders have the advantage that they operate in a reasonably clean and well-controlled environment. Not to mention nearby, as opposed to some billion light-years away.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That we have no particular reason to expect the next larger collider will produce so-far unknown particles is in my opinion entirely tangential. If we stop here, the history of particle physics will be that of a protagonist who left town and, after the last street sign, sat down and died, the end. Some protagonist.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But I have been told by several people who speak to politicians more frequently than I that the “just do it” argument doesn’t fly. To justify substantial investments, I am told, an experiment needs a clear goal and at least a promise of breakthrough discoveries.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Knowing this, it’s not hard to extrapolate what particle physicists will do next. We merely have to look at what they’ve done in the past.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first step is to backpedal from their earlier claims. This has already happened. Originally we were told that if supersymmetric particles are there, we would see them right away.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Discovering gluinos and squarks in the expected mass range […] seems straightforward, since the rates are large and the signals are easy to separate from Standard Model backgrounds.”&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/hep-ph/9801254&quot;&gt;Frank Paige (1998)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“The Large Hadron Collider will either make a spectacular discovery or rule out supersymmetry entirely.”&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://physicstoday.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/1.2825069?journalCode=pto&quot;&gt;Michael Dine (2007)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Now they claim no one ever said it would be easy. By 2012, it was &lt;em&gt;“&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1203.5539&quot;&gt;Natural SUSY is difficult to see at LHC&lt;/a&gt;”&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/science/life-and-physics/2013/mar/14/supersymmetry-spell&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;“&quot;Natural supersymmetry&quot; may be hard to find.” &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Step two is arguing that the presently largest collider will just barely fail to see the new particles but that the next larger collider will be up to the task.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the presently most popular proposals for the next collider is the International Linear Collider (ILC), which would be a lepton collider. Lepton colliders have the benefit of doing away with structure functions and fragmentation functions that you need when you collide composite particles like the proton.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/the-collider-that-could-save-physics/&quot;&gt;a 2016 essay for &lt;em&gt;Scientific American&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Howard Baer, Vernon D. Barger, and Jenny List kicked off the lobbying campaign:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Recent theoretical research suggests that Higgsinos might actually be showing up at the LHC—scientists just cannot find them in the mess of particles generated by the LHC's proton-antiproton collisions […] Theory predicts that the ILC should create abundant Higgsinos, sleptons (partners of leptons) and other superpartners. If it does, the ILC would confirm supersymmetry.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
The “recent theoretical research” they are referring to happens to be &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1611.02846&quot;&gt;that of the authors themselves&lt;/a&gt;, vividly demonstrating that the quality standard of this field is currently so miserable that particle physicists can come up with predictions for anything they want. The phrase “theory predicts” has become entirely meaningless.&lt;p&gt;The website of the ILC itself is also charming. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linearcollider.org/from-design-to-reality/&quot;&gt;There we can read&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“A linear collider would be best suited for producing the lighter superpartners… Designed with great accuracy and precision, the ILC becomes the perfect machine to conduct the search for dark matter particles with unprecedented precision; we have good reasons to anticipate other exciting discoveries along the way.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
They don’t tell you what those “good reasons” are because there are none. At least not so far. This brings us to step three.&lt;p&gt;Step three is the fabrication of reasons why the next larger collider should see something. The leading proposal is presently &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1204.6626&quot;&gt;that of Michael Douglas&lt;/a&gt;, who is advocating a different version of naturalness, that is naturalness in theory space. And the theory space he is referring to is, drums please, the string theory landscape.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Naturalness, of course, has always been a criterion in theory-space, which is exactly why I keep saying it’s nonsense: You need a probability distribution to define it and since we only ever observe one point in this theory space, we have no way to ever get empirical evidence about this distribution. So far, however, the theory space was that of quantum field theory.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When it comes to the landscape at least the problem of finding a probability distribution is known (called “the measure problem”), but it’s still unsolvable because we never observe laws of nature other than our own. “Solving” the problem comes down to guessing a probability distribution and then drowning your guess in lots of math. Let us see what predictions Douglas arrives at:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table align=&quot;center&quot; cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;tr-caption-container&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-EPrJr1LKwkk/Wqe_IMY9B9I/AAAAAAAAD5Y/yB37jAwAyYg5mCGtAOrT2Z-zuZ1hkpDjgCLcBGAs/s1600/douglas.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;925&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1246&quot; height=&quot;237&quot; src=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-EPrJr1LKwkk/Wqe_IMY9B9I/AAAAAAAAD5Y/yB37jAwAyYg5mCGtAOrT2Z-zuZ1hkpDjgCLcBGAs/s320/douglas.jpg&quot; width=&quot;320&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tr-caption&quot;&gt;Slide from Michael Douglas. &lt;a href=&quot;http://workshops.ift.uam-csic.es/WMH126/douglas.pdf&quot;&gt;PDF here&lt;/a&gt;. Emphasis mine.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;Supersymmetry might be just barely out of reach of the LHC, but a somewhat larger collider would find it. Who’d have thought.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You see what is happening here. Conjecturing a multiverse of any type (string landscape or eternal inflation or what have you) is useless. It doesn’t explain anything and you can’t calculate anything with it. But once you add a probability distribution on that multiverse, you can make calculations. Those calculations are math you can publish. And those publications you can later refer to in proposals read by people who can’t decipher the math. Mission accomplished.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The reason this cycle of empty predictions continues is that everyone involved only stands to benefit. From the particle physicists who write the papers to those who review the papers to those who cite the papers, everyone wants more funding for particle physics, so everyone plays along.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I too would like to see a next larger particle collider, but not if it takes lies to trick taxpayers into giving us money. More is at stake here than the employment of some thousand particle physicists. If we tolerate fabricated arguments in the scientific literature just because the conclusions suit us, we demonstrate how easy it is for scientists to cheat.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fact is, we presently have no evidence –  neither experimental nor theoretical evidence –  that a next larger collider would find new particles. The absolutely last thing particle physicists need right now is to weaken their standards even more and appeal to multiversal math magic that can explain everything and anything. But that seems to be exactly where we are headed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;* I know that’s not correct. I merely said that’s likely how the story will be spun.&lt;/span&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2018 09:50:29 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>franzb</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://backreaction.blogspot.com/2018/03/the-multiworse-is-coming.html</og:url>
<og:title>The Multiworse Is Coming</og:title>
<og:description>You haven’t seen headlines recently about the Large Hadron Collider, have you? That’s because even the most skilled science writers can’...</og:description>
<og:image>https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-XHuj9rg_r4o/WqfEFFm9dNI/AAAAAAAAD5w/0ChaC3HocfQON1wRxE2Y-hhBxKRPKI_WgCLcBGAs/w1200-h630-p-k-no-nu/mycat.jpg</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://backreaction.blogspot.com/2018/03/the-multiworse-is-coming.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>What America looked like before the EPA, in photos</title>
<link>https://kottke.org/18/03/what-america-looked-like-before-the-epa-in-photos</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://kottke.org/18/03/what-america-looked-like-before-the-epa-in-photos</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Popular Science has a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.popsci.com/america-before-epa-photos?src=SOC&amp;amp;dom=tw&quot;&gt;series of photos taken by EPA staff in the early years of the agency&lt;/a&gt; after it was formed in the 1970s, that have since been digitized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s pretty grim stuff: abandoned cars in Jamaica Bay, broken candy-glass unreturnable bottles everywhere, and one mill after another belching out smoke and dumping refuse in the rivers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://kottke.org/plus/misc/images/marc_st_gil_the_atlas_chemical_company_belches_smoke_across_pasture_land_in_foreground._061972_0.jpg&quot; width=&quot;655&quot; height=&quot;439&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;marc_st_gil_the_atlas_chemical_company_belches_smoke_across_pasture_land_in_foreground._061972_0.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;small&gt;The Atlas Chemical Company, by Marc St. Gil&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://kottke.org/plus/misc/images/charles_steinhacker_-_outflow_pipe_6_of_the_oxford_paper_company_will_at_rumford_._061973.jpg&quot; width=&quot;655&quot; height=&quot;965&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;charles_steinhacker_-_outflow_pipe_6_of_the_oxford_paper_company_will_at_rumford_._061973.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;small&gt;Oxford Paper Company, by Charles Steinhacker&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://kottke.org/plus/misc/images/william_strode_-_burning_barge_on_the_ohio_river_may_1972.jpg&quot; width=&quot;655&quot; height=&quot;443&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;william_strode_-_burning_barge_on_the_ohio_river_may_1972.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;small&gt;Burning barge on the Ohio River, by William Strode&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://kottke.org/plus/misc/images/erik_calonius_-_mary_workman_holds_a_jar_of_undrinkable_water_that_comes_from_her_well_and_has_filed_a_damage_suit_against_the_hanna_coal_company_._101973.jpg&quot; width=&quot;655&quot; height=&quot;441&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;erik_calonius_-_mary_workman_holds_a_jar_of_undrinkable_water_that_comes_from_her_well_and_has_filed_a_damage_suit_against_the_hanna_coal_company_._101973.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;small&gt;Mary Workman holds a jar of undrinkable water from her well, and has filed suit against the Hanna Coal Company - by Erik Calonius&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Given that there’s been a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.popsci.com/pruitt-EPA-confirmation&quot;&gt;renewed, serious push this year to dismantle or undermine the EPA&lt;/a&gt;, it’s worth revisiting just why we needed an agency to protect the environment to begin with.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2018 08:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>AJRF</dc:creator>
<og:title>What America looked like before the EPA, in photos</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://kottke.org/18/03/what-america-looked-like-before-the-epa-in-photos</og:url>
<og:image>https://kottke.org/plus/misc/images/marc_st_gil_the_atlas_chemical_company_belches_smoke_across_pasture_land_in_foreground._061972_0.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>Popular Science has a series of photos taken by EPA staff in the early years of the agency after it was formed in the 1970s, that</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://kottke.org/18/03/what-america-looked-like-before-the-epa-in-photos</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Interactive map of Linux kernel</title>
<link>http://www.makelinux.net/kernel_map/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.makelinux.net/kernel_map/</guid>
<description>
&lt;center&gt;&lt;nobr&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;xxcap&quot;&gt;Navigation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/nobr&gt;&lt;table cellspacing=&quot;2&quot; cellpadding=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;button onclick=&quot;move(30,30)&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.makelinux.net/kernel_map/lu.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;button onclick=&quot;move(0,30)&quot; title=&quot;pan up&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.makelinux.net/kernel_map/u.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;button onclick=&quot;move(-30,30)&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.makelinux.net/kernel_map/ru.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;button onclick=&quot;move(30,0)&quot; title=&quot;pan left&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.makelinux.net/kernel_map/l.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;button onclick=&quot;map_home()&quot; title=&quot;HOME&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.makelinux.net/kernel_map/c.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;button onclick=&quot;move(-30,0)&quot; title=&quot;pan right&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.makelinux.net/kernel_map/r.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;button onclick=&quot;move(30,-30)&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.makelinux.net/kernel_map/ld.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;button onclick=&quot;move(0,-30)&quot; title=&quot;pan down&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.makelinux.net/kernel_map/d.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;button onclick=&quot;move(-30,-30)&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.makelinux.net/kernel_map/rd.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;button onclick=&quot;mousePos={x:wnd.x/2,y:wnd.y/2};zoom(-1);&quot; title=&quot;zoom out&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.makelinux.net/kernel_map/zo.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;button onclick=&quot;mousePos={x:wnd.x/2,y:wnd.y/2};zoom(1)&quot; title=&quot;zoom in&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.makelinux.net/kernel_map/zi.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;button onclick=&quot;mousePos=null;map_macro()&quot; title=&quot;macro zoom&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.makelinux.net/kernel_map/zm.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;nobr readability=&quot;1.5&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;small&quot; readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;Mouse:&lt;br/&gt;Drag - pan&lt;br/&gt;Wheel,&lt;br/&gt;Dbl Click - zoom&lt;br/&gt;Items - links&lt;p&gt;Keyboard:&lt;br/&gt;PgDn, PgUp - zoom&lt;br/&gt;arrows - pan&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/nobr&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;hide&quot;&gt;NEW!&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;
New book:
&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/143026196X/ref=as_li_ss_il?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=143026196X&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=makelinux-20&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://www.makelinux.net/kernel_map/linux_kernel_networking.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Linux Kernel Networking&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=makelinux-20&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;a=143026196X&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;_hide&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apress.com/9781430261964&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;hide&quot; src=&quot;http://www.makelinux.net/kernel_map/linux_kernel_networking.png&quot; alt=&quot;Linux Kernel Networking&quot;/&gt;on Apress&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;
Purchase and&lt;br/&gt;download instantly&lt;br/&gt;unlimited resolution&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PDF&lt;/strong&gt; of the map:
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;form action=&quot;https://www.paypal.com/cgi-bin/webscr&quot; method=&quot;post&quot;&gt;

&lt;/form&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;form action=&quot;https://www.paypal.com/cgi-bin/webscr&quot; method=&quot;post&quot;&gt;

&lt;/form&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;small&quot; href=&quot;mailto:const@makelinux.net?subject=Linux%20map%20PDF&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; width=&quot;10&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://www.makelinux.net/style/letter.png&quot;/&gt; e-mail&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;hide&quot;&gt;Recommended&lt;blink&gt;:&lt;/blink&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;small&quot; href=&quot;http://www.makelinux.net/android/internals/&quot;&gt;• Android internals&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a id=&quot;poster2&quot; class=&quot;poster2&quot; href=&quot;http://www.makelinux.net/kernel_map/poster&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;• Wall poster&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;small&quot; href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0672329468?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=makelinux-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0672329468&quot;&gt;• Linux Kernel&lt;br/&gt;Development&lt;br/&gt;3rd edition, 2010&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;small&quot; href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1593272200?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=makelinux-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=1593272200&quot;&gt;• The Linux&lt;br/&gt;Programming&lt;br/&gt;Interface, 2010&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=makelinux-20&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;a=1593272200&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;small&quot; href=&quot;http://www.makelinux.net/man/&quot;&gt;• Linux man pages&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;   </description>
<pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2018 03:24:39 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mayankkaizen</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.makelinux.net/kernel_map/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Sierra Leone just ran the first blockchain-based election</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2018/03/14/sierra-leone-just-ran-the-first-blockchain-based-election/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2018/03/14/sierra-leone-just-ran-the-first-blockchain-based-election/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The citizens of Sierra Leone went to the polls on March 7 but this time something was different: the country recorded votes at 70% of the polling to the &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/blockchain-info/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;blockchain-info&quot;&gt;blockchain&lt;/a&gt; using a technology that is the first of its kind in actual practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tech, created by Leonardo Gammar of &lt;a href=&quot;https://agora.vote&quot;&gt;Agora&lt;/a&gt;, anonymously stored votes in an immutable ledger, thereby offering instant access to the election results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Anonymized votes/ballots are being recorded on Agora’s blockchain, which will be publicly available for any interested party to review, count and validate,” said Gammar. “This is the first time a government election is using blockchain technology.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Sierra Leone wishes to create an environment of trust with the voters in a contentious election, especially looking at how the election will be publicly viewed post-election. By using blockchain as a means to immutably record ballots and results, the country hopes to create legitimacy around the election and reduce fall-out from opposition parties,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is this interesting? While this is little more than a proof of concept – it is not a complete voting record but instead captured a seemingly acceptable plurality of votes – it’s fascinating to see the technology be implemented in Sierra Leone, a country of about 7.4 million people. The goal ultimately is to reduce voting costs by cutting out paper ballots as well as reducing corruption in the voting process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gammar, for his part, sees the value of a decentralizes system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We’re the only company in the world that has built a fully-functional blockchain voting platform. Other electronic voting machines are ‘block boxes’ that have been increasingly shown to be vulnerable to security attacks. For that reason, many US states and foreign nations have been moving back to paper,” he said. “If you believe that most countries will use some form of digital voting 50 years from now, then blockchain is the only technology that has been created which can provide an end-to-end verifiable and fully-transparent voting solution for this future.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One election in one country isn’t a movement – yet. However, Gammar and his team plan on expanding their product to other African countries and, eventually, to the rest of the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the election it is still unclear who won and there will be a run-off election on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnn.com/2018/03/14/africa/sierra-leone-election-run-off/index.html&quot;&gt;March 27&lt;/a&gt;. The winner will succeed President Ernest Bai Koroma who has run the country for a full decade.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2018 02:49:23 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>grdeken</dc:creator>
<og:title>Sierra Leone just ran the first blockchain-based election</og:title>
<og:description>The citizens of Sierra Leone went to the polls on March 7 but this time something was different: the country recorded votes at 70% of the polling to the blockchain using a technology that is the first of its kind in actual practice. The tech, created by Leonardo Gammar of Agora, anonymously stored …</og:description>
<og:image>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/gettyimages-463655687.jpg?w=734</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2018/03/14/sierra-leone-just-ran-the-first-blockchain-based-election/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2018/03/14/sierra-leone-just-ran-the-first-blockchain-based-election/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Stock trade app Robinhood raising at $5B+, up 4X in a year</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2018/03/15/robinhood-quintacorn/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2018/03/15/robinhood-quintacorn/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;By adding a cryptocurrency exchange, a web version and stock option trading, &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/analyst/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;analyst&quot;&gt;Robinhood&lt;/a&gt; has managed to quadruple its valuation in a year, according to a source familiar with a new round the startup is raising. Robinhood is closing in on around $350 million in Series D funding led by Russian firm DST Global, the source says. That’s just 11 months after Robinhood confirmed TechCrunch’s scoop that the zero-fee stock trading app had raised a &lt;a href=&quot;https://beta.techcrunch.com/2017/04/26/robincorn&quot;&gt;$110 million Series C&lt;/a&gt; at a $1.3 billion valuation. The new raise would bring Robinhood to $526 million in funding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Details of the Series D were first reported by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/robinhoods-valuation-soars-above-5-billion-1521141033&quot;&gt;The Wall Street Journal&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The astronomical value growth shows that investors see Robinhood as a core part of the mobile finance tools upon which the next generation will rely. The startup also just proved its ability to nimbly adapt to trends by &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/02/22/free-crypto-trading/&quot;&gt;building its cryptocurrency trading feature&lt;/a&gt; in less than two months to make sure it wouldn’t miss the next big economic shift. One million users waitlisted for access in just the five days after &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/01/25/free-cryptocurrency-trading-app/&quot;&gt;Robinhood Crypto was announced&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-1606474&quot; src=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/robinhood-crypto.png?w=680&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;680&quot; height=&quot;356&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The launch completed a trio of product debuts. The mobile app finally launched a &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2017/11/01/robinhood-for-web/&quot;&gt;website version&lt;/a&gt; for tracking and trading stocks without a commission in November. In December it &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.robinhood.com/news/2017/12/12/introducing-options-trading&quot;&gt;opened options trading&lt;/a&gt;, making it a more robust alternative to brokers like E*Trade and Scottrade. They often charge $7 or more per stock trade compared to zero with Robinhood, but also give away features that are reserved for &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2016/09/29/robinhood-premium/&quot;&gt;Robinhood’s premium Gold subscription tier&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robinhood won’t say how many people have signed up for its $6 to $200 per month Gold service that lets people trade on margin, with higher prices netting them more borrowing power. That and earning interest on money stored in Robinhood accounts are the startup’s primary revenue sources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-1481765&quot; src=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/robinhood-gold.png?w=680&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;680&quot; height=&quot;238&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rapid product iteration and skyrocketing value surely helped recruit &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/03/14/robinhood-hires-josh-elman-as-vp-of-product-wholl-stay-at-greylock/&quot;&gt;Josh Elman, who Robinhood announced yesterday has joined as VP of product&lt;/a&gt; as he transitions to a part-time roll at Greylock Partners. He could help the company build a platform business as a backbone for other fintech apps, they way he helped Facebook build its identity platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In effect, Robinhood has figured out how to make stock trading freemium. Rather than charge per trade with bonus features included, Robinhood gives away the bare-bones trades and charges for everything else. That could give it a steady, scalable business model akin to Dropbox, which grew by offering small amounts of free storage and then charging for extras and enterprise accounts. From a start with free trades, Robinhood could blossom into a hub for your mobile finance life.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2018 00:10:48 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>wgyn</dc:creator>
<og:title>Stock trade app Robinhood raising at $5B+, up 4X in a year</og:title>
<og:description>By adding a cryptocurrency exchange, a web version and stock option trading, Robinhood has managed to quadruple its valuation in a year, according to a source familiar with a new round the startup is raising. Robinhood is closing in on around $350 million in Series D funding led by Russian firm DST…</og:description>
<og:image>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/robinhood-co-founders.jpg?w=751</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2018/03/15/robinhood-quintacorn/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2018/03/15/robinhood-quintacorn/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>ProtonMail blocked by Vodafone Turkey</title>
<link>https://protonmail.com/blog/turkey-online-censorship-bypass/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://protonmail.com/blog/turkey-online-censorship-bypass/</guid>
<description>&lt;h2&gt;We have confirmed that Internet service providers in Turkey have been blocking ProtonMail this week. Here’s what we know so far, and some ways to bypass the block.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our support team first became aware of connectivity problems for Turkish ProtonMail users starting on Tuesday. After further investigation, we determined that protonmail.com was unreachable for both Vodafone Turkey mobile and fixed line users. Since then, we have also received some sporadic reports from users of other Turkish ISPs. At one point, the issue was prevalent in every single major city in Turkey. After investigating the issue along with members of the ProtonMail community in Turkey, &lt;strong&gt;we have confirmed this is a government-ordered block rather than a technical glitch&lt;/strong&gt;. Internet censorship in Turkey tends to be fluid so the situation is constantly evolving. &lt;strong&gt;Sometimes ProtonMail is accessible, and sometimes it is unreachable.&lt;/strong&gt; For the first time ever though, we have confirmed that ProtonMail was subject to a block, and could face further issues in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://protonmail.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/VDF-Turkey-PM-block-2-IM2.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-3687&quot; src=&quot;https://protonmail.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/VDF-Turkey-PM-block-2-IM2-1024x379.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;379&quot; srcset=&quot;https://protonmail.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/VDF-Turkey-PM-block-2-IM2-1024x379.jpg 1024w, https://protonmail.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/VDF-Turkey-PM-block-2-IM2-300x111.jpg 300w, https://protonmail.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/VDF-Turkey-PM-block-2-IM2-768x285.jpg 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;What Vodafone Turkey users saw when they tried to access ProtonMail on Wednesday, March 14th, 2018.
&lt;p&gt;With the assistance of ProtonMail users within Turkey, we were able to do a deeper, technical analysis of the issue from within Turkey. First, we discovered that Proton IPs were in fact still reachable, and traceroutes were succeeding. Instead, it appears that ISP DNS servers have simply stopped resolving protonmail.com, or were in other cases returning incorrect results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;a href=&quot;https://protonmail.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/VDF-Turkey-PM-block.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-3670 size-large&quot; src=&quot;https://protonmail.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/VDF-Turkey-PM-block-1024x512.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;512&quot; srcset=&quot;https://protonmail.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/VDF-Turkey-PM-block-1024x512.jpg 1024w, https://protonmail.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/VDF-Turkey-PM-block-300x150.jpg 300w, https://protonmail.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/VDF-Turkey-PM-block-768x384.jpg 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Traceroutes from Turkey to our IP addresses were succeeding, but protonmail.com could not be resolved by carrier DNS servers.
&lt;p&gt;This is consistent with how internet censorship is typically performed in Turkey. As part of ProtonMail’s anti-censorship efforts (and as part of the work we do at &lt;a href=&quot;https://protonvpn.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;ProtonVPN&lt;/a&gt;, our free VPN service), we actively perform research on the censorship techniques used by different regimes. In Turkey, DNS blocking is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2016/07/15/circumvent-social-media-block/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;predominant method of blocking&lt;/a&gt;. Turkish ISPs have even gone as far as to conduct &lt;a href=&quot;https://dyn.com/blog/turkish-internet-censorship/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;local DNS poisoning&lt;/a&gt;, and to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.silicon.co.uk/workspace/google-dns-censorship-turkey-142726&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;intercept requests&lt;/a&gt; going to well-known DNS servers, such as Google’s public DNS server. &lt;strong&gt;The type of DNS blocking that has been performed against ProtonMail very much fits the modus operandi of the Turkish government’s online censorship efforts.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have contacted both Vodafone Group (the UK-based parent company) and Vodafone Turkey, but so far neither has commented on the incident. However, &lt;strong&gt;ProtonMail users are everywhere in Turkey&lt;/strong&gt; — some even work for Vodafone Turkey or the Turkish government — and &lt;strong&gt;we are working to escalate this behind the scenes to get approval for ProtonMail to be unblocked.&lt;/strong&gt; These same sources were also able to disclose that ProtonMail was swept up in a concerted action launched on March 12th, 2018 against a number of services, not just ProtonMail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If this is indeed a case of government-ordered censorship, it would not be the first time this has happened in Turkey. In recent years, the Turkish government has ordered ISPs to block &lt;a href=&quot;https://freedomhouse.org/report/freedom-net/2017/turkey&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;tens of thousands of websites&lt;/a&gt;, from news outlets to atheist sites and even Wikipedia, for content that contradicts government propaganda. Sometimes these blocks are temporary, such as its throttling of Facebook and Twitter, while others are long-lasting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-width=&quot;550&quot; data-dnt=&quot;true&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;I can’t access my emails &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/VodafoneTR?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@VodafoneTR&lt;/a&gt; Can you tell me why are you blocking &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ProtonMail?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@ProtonMail&lt;/a&gt; ? Just give me one sane reason please!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Bülent Köstem (@BulentKostem) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/BulentKostem/status/973892534018756608?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;March 14, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-width=&quot;550&quot; data-dnt=&quot;true&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;I can confirm that &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ProtonMail?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@ProtonMail&lt;/a&gt; website, as well as &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ProtonVPN?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@ProtonVPN&lt;/a&gt; website and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ProtonMail?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@ProtonMail&lt;/a&gt; ios app is blocked from Turkey: &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/gVyaJYzahG&quot;&gt;https://t.co/gVyaJYzahG&lt;/a&gt; Please note that several other VPN providers are also currently blocked from Turkey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Yaman Akdeniz (@cyberrights) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/cyberrights/status/974575038119768065?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;March 16, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has come as part of a broader government clampdown on politicians, journalists, and human rights activists. More &lt;a href=&quot;https://cpj.org/reports/2017/12/journalists-prison-jail-record-number-turkey-china-egypt.php&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;journalists are imprisoned in Turkey&lt;/a&gt; than any other country, including much larger China. News media have been &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.com/news/world-europe-35729114&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;shut down&lt;/a&gt; and reopened under government control. In one noteworthy case, the director of Amnesty International Turkey was arrested last summer along with other activists and is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hrw.org/news/2018/02/01/turkey-amnesty-chair-detained-again&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;still being held in pre-trial detention&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ProtonMail, of course, is widely known for being an obstacle for governments that wish to violate the privacy rights of their citizens. As the &lt;a href=&quot;https://protonmail.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;world’s largest encrypted email provider&lt;/a&gt;, ProtonMail’s mission is to protect the universal right to privacy that all citizens are entitled to. In this way, we also protect freedom of speech, which is essential for democracy to survive and thrive. &lt;strong&gt;One of the most effective ways to suppress freedom is to remove access to services such as ProtonMail.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, Vodafone Turkey controls &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.btk.gov.tr/File/?path=ROOT%2F1%2FDocuments%2FPages%2FMarket_Data%2F2017_Q1_Eng.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;31.2% of the mobile internet market in Turkey&lt;/a&gt; and is a leading fixed-line ISP operating in 81 cities. The company is owned by Vodafone Group, a British multinational that provides telecommunications services in countries around the world. Unfortunately, Vodafone has a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rawstory.com/2011/01/vodafone-confirms-role-egypts-cellular-internet-blackout/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;history of complying with the demands from authoritarian governments&lt;/a&gt; to shut down or block internet access. &lt;strong&gt;While for Vodafone this is merely a business decision, the consequences are far reaching.&lt;/strong&gt; In this case, it is denying millions of people their right to online privacy, and helping to perpetuate the same system that made this possible in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Bypassing government censorship of ProtonMail&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because of ProtonMail’s unique mission to protect online freedom and ensure freedom of speech in the digital age, we have long anticipated that certain governments who act contrary to these values will be interested in denying access to ProtonMail and ProtonVPN. We view this as a serious threat, and we focus a lot of development effort on technologies to circumvent such blocks. &lt;strong&gt;Below is a list of techniques to circumvent online censorship if ProtonMail is blocked.&lt;/strong&gt; Because the situation is constantly changing, some of these recommendations could stop working at any time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Use a VPN service like ProtonVPN&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VPNs remain one of the best ways to bypass censorship, and ProtonMail provides ProtonVPN for free in order to ensure people around the world can have access to an uncensored internet. When you use a VPN, all your internet traffic, including DNS requests, is routed through an encrypted tunnel to a VPN server, meaning that ISP IP and DNS blocks can be bypassed. You can get ProtonVPN for free &lt;a href=&quot;https://protonvpn.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, VPNs are not always effective and can be blocked. If ProtonVPN becomes blocked, we suggest trying the public servers at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vpngate.net/en/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;VPNGate&lt;/a&gt;. It is possible however, to block all VPN services (and Turkey is currently attempting to ban all VPN services), in which case, there are a few other circumvention techniques.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Switch DNS servers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ProtonMail is currently being blocked at the DNS level, which means the block can be circumvented by using different DNS servers instead of the ones provided by default by Vodafone. &lt;strong&gt;A list of free alternative DNS servers can be found&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;online &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lifewire.com/free-and-public-dns-servers-2626062&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using any of those should allow the DNS block to be bypassed. Guides for setting a custom DNS for your operating system can be found below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lifewire.com/how-to-change-dns-servers-in-windows-2626242&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Windows&lt;/a&gt;   ||   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.howtogeek.com/howto/38793/how-to-switch-mac-os-x-to-use-opendns-or-google-dns/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;MacOS&lt;/a&gt;   ||   &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.opendns.com/hc/en-us/articles/228009007-Android-Configuration-instructions-for-OpenDNS&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt;   ||   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.howtogeek.com/261701/how-to-change-the-dns-server-on-your-ios-device/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;iOS&lt;/a&gt;   ||   &lt;a href=&quot;https://pchelp.ricmedia.com/set-custom-dns-servers-linux-network-manager-resolv-conf/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Linux&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Use Tor&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tor is an invaluable tool for bypassing online censorship and staying anonymous online. The Turkish government has also been trying to ban Tor, but using Tor Bridges has so far still been an effective method of circumventing online censorship. Guides for using Tor Bridge can be found online &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ibtimes.co.uk/tor-blocked-turkey-heres-how-circumvent-tor-ban-using-bridges-1597217&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.deepdotweb.com/2016/12/21/pluggable-transports-tor-dodging-censorship/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ProtonMail has long been a supporter of the Tor project, and we are &lt;a href=&quot;https://protonmail.com/blog/tor-encrypted-email/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;one of the only Tor email services in the world&lt;/a&gt;, with a fully functioning Tor hidden service at &lt;strong&gt;protonirockerxow.onion&lt;/strong&gt;. More information about how to connect to our Tor hidden service can be found &lt;a href=&quot;https://protonmail.com/tor&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ProtonMail will continue to fight censorship on all fronts, and our commitment to this cause is the reason why we operate ProtonVPN, the only completely free VPN service that has no bandwidth limitations and does not sell or exploit user data. Despite the costs, &lt;strong&gt;we firmly believe that providing services like ProtonMail and ProtonVPN for free is essential for building a better future&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We, as individuals, are also not powerless against the forces that may seek to limit freedom and democracy. Through our choices (and our wallets), we can hold companies like Vodafone, and even governments, accountable for acting in the best interests of the people they serve. Slowly but surely, the global Proton user community is already doing that, and while challenges like this are bound to arise, the fact that we are being targeted also means that we are on the right track. &lt;strong&gt;To our users in Turkey, thank you for your continued support and understanding as we work on getting the block lifted.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Best Regards,&lt;br/&gt;The ProtonMail Team&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 20:15:05 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>stockmania</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>ProtonMail is being blocked in Turkey. Here’s how to bypass Turkey’s online censorship. - ProtonMail Blog</og:title>
<og:description>We have confirmed that Internet service providers in Turkey have been blocking ProtonMail this week. Here’s what we know so far, and some ways to bypass the block. Our support team first became aware of connectivity problems for Turkish ProtonMail users starting on Tuesday. After further investigation, we determined that protonmail.com was unreachable for both …</og:description>
<og:url>https://protonmail.com/blog/turkey-online-censorship-bypass/</og:url>
<og:image>https://protonmail.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/ProtonMail-bypass-Turkey-online-censorship..jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://protonmail.com/blog/turkey-online-censorship-bypass/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Private Internet Access Goes Open Source</title>
<link>https://www.privateinternetaccess.com/blog/2018/03/private-internet-access-goes-open-source/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.privateinternetaccess.com/blog/2018/03/private-internet-access-goes-open-source/</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;apss-social-share apss-theme-1 clearfix&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;apss-facebook apss-single-icon&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;apss-social-text&quot;&gt;Share on Facebook&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;apss-share&quot;&gt;Share&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;apss-twitter apss-single-icon&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;apss-social-text&quot;&gt;Share on Twitter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;apss-share&quot;&gt;Tweet&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;apss-google-plus apss-single-icon&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;apss-social-text&quot;&gt;Share on Google Plus&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;apss-share&quot;&gt;Plus&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://www.privateinternetaccess.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/PIA-Chrome-extension-Chromium-02.png&quot; class=&quot;attachment-large size-large wp-post-image&quot; alt=&quot;PIA Open Source Chrome Browser Extension&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.privateinternetaccess.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/PIA-Chrome-extension-Chromium-02.png 400w, https://www.privateinternetaccess.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/PIA-Chrome-extension-Chromium-02-150x150.png 150w, https://www.privateinternetaccess.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/PIA-Chrome-extension-Chromium-02-300x300.png 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 400px) 85vw, 400px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Today marks the start of an exciting shift over here at Private Internet Access. As long-time supporters of the Free and Open Source Software community, we have started the process of open sourcing our software, and over the next six months we will be releasing the source code for all our client-side applications, as well as libraries and extensions.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;We are extremely grateful to the Free and Open Source Software community for creating the foundations of the Internet as we know it. And while we may be late to the party, we are looking forward to furthering our work with a movement that aligns with our own passions, on both a personal and professional level.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;We believe that the shift to open source is the right move for a privacy-focused business, and recognise that code transparency is key. We appreciate that our code may not be perfect, and we hope that the wider FOSS community will get involved, provide feedback, feature requests, bug fixes and generally help provide a greater service to the wider privacy movement.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Today, we are opening up the first of many repositories, the chrome extension, that allows users to access our network of proxies from their web browser. The chrome extension also boasts additional privacy and security features such as disabling the microphone and camera, blocking flash and ip discovery through WebRTC, and can also automatically block ads and tracking through PIA MACE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;sup&gt;TM&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;. Please note that the extension will protect traffic from the browser only and will NOT offer any protection when using other applications.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Let’s continue to fight the good fight. Freedom is an earned right, and we must continue to re-earn it everyday. As the world continues to fight, Private Internet Access will be there. In crypto we trust.” — Andrew Lee, Private Internet Access Founder, and long-term FOSS contributor.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Head over to &lt;a href=&quot;https://pia-foss.github.io/&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;, check out the repo and get involved! You can find us in #privateinternetaccess on chat.freenode.net if you have questions, comments or simply want to find out more about what we are up to.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Our longer term goal is to release all our code into the open, and we hope that you will join us on our journey. We have some exciting things planned, and would love to hear from you if you want to get involved … and don’t forget to keep an eye on our blog and/or social media as we will be throwing some exciting launch events further down the line.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;It should come as no surprise that we think that open source is awesome, and as long-term consumers of open source we are really happy to now be in a position where we can contribute back.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions or comments, please do drop us a line to opensource@privateinternetaccess.com, we look forward to speaking with you and hope that our transparency will ensure that you have some peace of mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chrome is a trademark of Google Inc. Use of this trademark is subject to Google Permissions. The Chromium logo has been used in accordance with &lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.5/&quot;&gt;CC By 2.5&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wp-biographia-container-around&quot; readability=&quot;8.0909090909091&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wp-biographia-pic&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/ad4d1091456e78f0a05e87fecf024a20?s=70&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&quot; srcset=&quot;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/ad4d1091456e78f0a05e87fecf024a20?s=140&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&quot; class=&quot;wp-biographia-avatar avatar-70 photo&quot; height=&quot;70&quot; width=&quot;70&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wp-biographia-text&quot; readability=&quot;34.161616161616&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;About &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.privateinternetaccess.com/blog/author/christel-dahlskjaer/&quot; title=&quot;Christel Dahlskjaer&quot;&gt;Christel Dahlskjaer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Christel is the Director of Sponsorships, Events and Community Outreach at Private Internet Access. She is a privacy and digital rights advocate, a firm believer in software freedom and a bit of an all-round activist. She enjoys real ale, decent scotch and good conversation. She does not enjoy internet shutdowns and believes we must #KeepItOn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.privateinternetaccess.com/pages/buy-vpn/piablog-10000?utm_source=PIA-Blog&amp;amp;utm_medium=Banner&amp;amp;utm_campaign=singlepostbottom&quot; title=&quot;Buy VPN&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.privateinternetaccess.com/blog/wp-content/themes/privacynews/images/banner-ad.png&quot; alt=&quot;VPN Service&quot; title=&quot;VPN Service&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 19:45:15 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>iamd3vil</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Private Internet Access goes Open Source | Private Internet Access Blog</og:title>
<og:description>Today marks the start of an exciting shift over here at Private Internet Access. As long-time supporters of the Free and Open Source Software community, we have started the process of open sourcing our software, and over the next six months we will be releasing the source code for all our client-side applications, as well … Continue reading &quot;Private Internet Access goes Open Source&quot;</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.privateinternetaccess.com/blog/2018/03/private-internet-access-goes-open-source/</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.privateinternetaccess.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/PIA-Chrome-extension-Chromium-02.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.privateinternetaccess.com/blog/2018/03/private-internet-access-goes-open-source/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Airtable gets $52M in funding</title>
<link>http://www.businessinsider.com/airtable-ceo-howie-liu-interview-on-52-million-in-funding-2018-3?op=1</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.businessinsider.com/airtable-ceo-howie-liu-interview-on-52-million-in-funding-2018-3?op=1</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-source-caption&quot;&gt;Howie Liu, the CEO of Airtable. &lt;span class=&quot;image-source&quot; data-e2e-name=&quot;image-source&quot;&gt;Airtable&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Airtable has raised $52 million in Series B funding led by Caffeinated Capital and CRV.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Airtable is an app that creates spreadsheets, like Google Sheets and Microsoft Excel. But the cells can fit much more than just numbers, including photos and lists.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Airtable has become a sleeper hit in Silicon Valley, earning love from users and companies like Tesla, WeWork, Airbnb, and Time magazine.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;An initial public offering is the plan — Liu sold his last company to Salesforce and doesn't want to go that route again.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Airtable, a spreadsheet app that has become one of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.businessinsider.com/zapier-35-million-annualized-run-rate-software-trends-report-2018-1&quot;&gt;Silicon Valley's sleeper hits&lt;/a&gt;, has raised $52 million in new funding in a round led by Caffeinated Capital and CRV to bring its total to $62.6 million.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it was founded in 2012, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.airtable.com&quot;&gt;Airtable&lt;/a&gt; was a small, business-focused spreadsheet program. It has since found new audiences, as companies like Tesla, Airbnb, and WeWork — as well as smaller teams and individual users — have come to rely on Airtable to organize their data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The secret to Airtable's success, according to its CEO, Howie Liu, is that it makes it easy to make a custom app. Every cell of an Airtable spreadsheet can store anything, including photos and lists. Adding an interface on top can turn it into a simple but powerful app — without coding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;We think we can be what Windows was for personal computing,&quot; he said. &quot;We're confident we can be the Apple or Microsoft of the low-end-app space.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, Tesla uses Airtable to store information and keep track of every car that leaves its factory in Fremont, California. The video and photo teams at Time magazine and Fortune use Airtable to manage their entire production schedule too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;It really allows people with little or no technical knowledge to build high-level workflow systems,&quot; Liu said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-source-caption&quot;&gt;Airtable lets you build basic apps without coding. &lt;span class=&quot;image-source&quot; data-e2e-name=&quot;image-source&quot;&gt;Airtable&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The state of Airtable's business&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liu's first company, Etacts, was acquired by Salesforce in 2010, when he was 21. A year later, after realizing how limiting Google Sheets and Microsoft Excel were, Liu quit to start Airtable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ashton Kutcher, who had invested in Liu's first company, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.businessinsider.com/airtable-ceo-howie-liu-interview-2015-4&quot;&gt;also invested in Airtable&lt;/a&gt; after Liu pitched him in his trailer on the set of the show &quot;Two and a Half Men.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It worked out, and Airtable is growing fast. Though Liu didn't disclose specifics, he said revenue was up 500% from the year-ago period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The app has millions of users and &quot;thousands&quot; of sign-ups every day, Liu says. And Tesla has become one of Airtable's biggest clients, with a six-figure deal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liu said all the interest caught him a little by surprise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;If you asked me on the day we launched if a few years later we would be signing six-figure enterprise clients, I would have said no,&quot; he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-source-caption&quot;&gt;Airtable's mapping block. &lt;span class=&quot;image-source&quot; data-e2e-name=&quot;image-source&quot;&gt;Airtable&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liu also says he's had good advice along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bill Macaitis, the former chief marketing officer of Slack, is an adviser to Airtable, as is Amanda Kleha, formerly the head of marketing at Zendesk — both help assist with Airtable's enterprise-marketing push. Dylan Smith, the CFO of Box who's a college friend of Liu's, has also acted as an adviser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Airtable isn't yet profitable, Liu says, but could be &quot;cash flow positive at a moment's notice.&quot; And an initial public offering is the goal; Liu doesn't want to sell his company again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liu said the funding would go toward hiring, product development, and opening an office in New York.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Airtable is also launching a new product called Blocks, designed to allow users to build more-involved apps for businesses — but still without coding. For example, a mapping block could let a film studio track its shoots around the globe in real time, including the status of equipment rentals and the production itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liu attributes Airtable's growth to a change in marketing strategy. Recently, he and his team shifted their focus to going after larger enterprise customers rather than smaller businesses and startups. Once they made that decision — and started blanketing San Francisco in billboards — word began to spread.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;It's crazy how Airtable kind of blew up,&quot; Patrick Perini, the vice president of product at Mira, another startup based in San Francisco, told Business Insider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perini says he's considering moving all of Mira's operations to Airtable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;All of my developer friends are pretty excited about it,&quot; Perini said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 17:21:29 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>prostoalex</dc:creator>
<og:title>This Silicon Valley sleeper hit app just got $52 million to do for spreadsheets what Microsoft did for computers</og:title>
<og:description>Airtable, whose product uses a simple spreadsheet interface to make it easier to build apps and databases, raised $52 million in its latest funding round.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>http://www.businessinsider.com/airtable-ceo-howie-liu-interview-on-52-million-in-funding-2018-3</og:url>
<og:image>https://amp.businessinsider.com/images/5aa9b43f3be59f20008b471d-750-375.jpg</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.businessinsider.com/airtable-ceo-howie-liu-interview-on-52-million-in-funding-2018-3?op=1</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>A billion reasons never to buy IBM services</title>
<link>https://foliovision.com/2018/03/why-not-buy-ibm</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://foliovision.com/2018/03/why-not-buy-ibm</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;nc_socialPanel swp_flatFresh swp_d_customColor swp_i_customColor swp_o_customColor scale-70 scale-left&quot; data-position=&quot;above&quot; data-float=&quot;floatNone&quot; data-count=&quot;5&quot; data-floatcolor=&quot;#ffffff&quot; data-emphasize=&quot;0&quot;&gt;




&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;swp_count&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;swp_label&quot;&gt;Shares&lt;/span&gt; 204&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apparently IBM has made USD $780 million building a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.itprotoday.com/hybrid-cloud/canada-scrap-ibm-payroll-plan-gone-awry-costing-c1-billion&quot;&gt;payroll system for the Canadian Government&lt;/a&gt; which does not work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Potential Savings on Payroll&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea was to save money by eliminating jobs. Canada has about 260,000 public servants. Over 1200 people were working on payroll (accountants, bookkeepers and managers mainly with some IT guys thrown in to make it work). This is about half of one percent on payroll. Payroll is about one third the cost of accounting in our company. I'm unable to bring our accounting costs much below 3% of turnover on a sub-million dollar turnover despite strong efforts and automated software like Freshbooks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;more-64290&quot;/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm using headcount as a symbol of dollar figures for the Canadian government as in a service business like government or a software/IT company salary makes up over 70% of costs. It's not exact, but it provides pretty good reference numbers. Projecting these ratios onto Canada's federal government this would mean it's about twice as efficient as we've been able to become as a small business paying attention (we'd be at 1%). This is a ludicrously high on this kind of economy of scale. So the idea to reduce the head count was a good one. The target was 500 staff instead of 1200.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mistake which was made was to try to stuff all the very diverse payment systems into a single system. It would have made more sense to categorise the type of payment systems and put like together with like. There would be a master reporting system on top of all the modules to deliver combined reports. The reporting system would be relatively easy to write if the ten or fifteen payment systems were well and simply made and storing data in an accessible way. You'd start by categorising the kinds of payroll, choosing one category, building one good payment system and then clone it out to the others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IBM instead sold the Canadian government someone else's software (Oracle's Peoplesoft) on a sweetheart contract which did not require delivery of a working solution. Then IBM failed to successfully implement while taking payment all the way along.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;A History of Public Contract Fraud&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like a military contractor in the United States who is paying kickbacks (campaign contributions above board, foreign bank accounts below board) to the congressmen and women and senators who vote on their programs, IBM &lt;strong&gt;gets paid more&lt;/strong&gt; for their failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's not an accident or a one-off. IBM did something &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.itprotoday.com/hybrid-cloud/canada-scrap-ibm-payroll-plan-gone-awry-costing-c1-billion&quot;&gt;similar to Australia&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Australian state of Queensland scrapped a similar project after an initial contract went off the rails and ended up costing the government around A$1 billion ($772 million) to fix. A public inquiry mostly blamed government officials, but determined IBM shouldn’t have been chosen for the job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It shouldn't be this difficult for governments to resolve failed contracts. There is no reason for private enterprise to profit from failed public projects or inadequate estimates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In cases like this in the past, the Canadian Government would just be able to tell IBM to deliver the goods as promised or IBM would be banned from doing business in Canada - effectively frozen. Under NAFTA and similar trade pacts, governments have lost all leverage and these sweetheart deals continue to be pushed through.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why should the Canadian taxpayer foot the bills for corrupt contracts with devious suppliers? The answer is we should not. Companies should know that when they contract to provide public services they will be held accountable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Some more history of IBM at home and abroad&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IBM is a hollow shell of what it once was. IBM treated its own workers horribly, when they off-shored what was the best software and services team. One of IBM's major destinations after blowing up their US workforce was Bratislava. Some of IBM's business has moved on from Bratislava now as the environment is not sufficiently low cost any more. From insiders here, I had the chance to learn how IBM's service business really works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.glassdoor.at/Gehalt/IBM-Bratislava-Geh%C3%A4lter-EI_IE354.0,3_IL.4,14_IM1661.htm?countryRedirect=true&quot;&gt;IBM team in Bratislava&lt;/a&gt; is an account manager who is an a group of ten with an account director above them. I.e. there are only two people with whom you would have contact. Slovaks are very talented at mid-level service jobs: responsible and polite if not particularly fast-moving. The general level of foreign language learning is high as as in addition to reasonable natural talent, Slovaks are forced to communicate with the outside world in any other language except their own. So far, so good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tech credentials of these software &quot;experts&quot; were pretty low. Language skills was the bigger issue along with basic computer literacy (ability to send emails and manage a CRM). An HR recruiter who worked for IBM and I had a running joke about what it took to get &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.profesia.sk/praca/bratislava/?company_id=24143&quot;&gt;hired at IBM Slovakia&lt;/a&gt;. It was just three yeses to the following questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&quot;Can you speak English?&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&quot;Can you sit at a desk?&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&quot;Can you turn on a computer?&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yet if these people or their friends were the only ones who had contact with your data, no issues at all. Slovaks, particularly in the service industry, are astonishingly honest.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://foliovision.com/2018/03/why-not-buy-ibm#fn1-15712&quot; id=&quot;fnr1-15712&quot; title=&quot;see footnote&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Who really implements software at IBM&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The technical work was not kept within Slovakia at all. It was sent out to boiler rooms in India with extremely low skilled specialists and very high turnover. Your little service job might have to be done three or four times before it passed quality control and your &quot;team leader&quot; reported back to you. The teams were always rotating and there was no continuity on the work on any given project. If I were an IBM customer, I'd be very worried about my data transferred between so many jurisdictions and experts. It only takes one weak in the chain for your private business data to leak into the wrong hands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In exchange, companies were paying premium development rates - hundreds of dollars an hour. IBM were effectively selling you &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.glassdoor.at/Gehalt/IBM-India-Geh%C3%A4lter-EI_IE354.0,3_IL.4,9_IN115.htm?countryRedirect=true&quot;&gt;$4/hour developers&lt;/a&gt; at premium prices. A company could hire software customisation engineers on hourly remuneration with ten times the soft skills and five times the hard skills for one third the hourly rate IBM charges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;colorbox&quot; href=&quot;https://cdn.foliovision.com/images/2018/03/IBM-Bangalore-Where-Software-is-Made-square.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODdhAQABAPAAAP///wAAACwAAAAAAQABAEACAkQBADs=&quot; data-lazy-src=&quot;https://foliovision.com/images/2018/03/IBM-Bangalore-Where-Software-is-Made-square-640x634.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;634&quot; size-large=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://foliovision.com/images/2018/03/IBM-Bangalore-Where-Software-is-Made-square-640x634.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;634&quot; size-large=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;IBM Bangalore, where software is made © CC/Amol Gaitonde&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now Canada is paying for IBM's irresponsibility as an employer, a supplier and a corporate citizen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;IBM vs Local Developers or Local Experts &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Canada would have done far better to hire Canadian Mike McDerment to build their payroll system from scratch. Mike has built two accounting systems which work more or less flawlessly: Freshbooks One (what we use) and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.freshbooks.com/new-freshbooks&quot;&gt;Freshbooks Two&lt;/a&gt; (what Freshbooks are selling now). Freshbooks practices accountability. Once when Freshbooks servers went down for about eight hours, Mike gave everyone affected (about half their customers) a free month of service. I thought that was crazy over-compensation (and that's from someone who refunded $6000 to a single client for a project which didn't go according to plan).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My only recommendation to someone thinking of buying the IBM brand. Just don't. IBM doesn't produce what they are selling, offer low quality services at high prices and seek to sign customers up to dishonest contracts. In addition, IBM treats its employees very poorly (as contractors where possible), has hollowed out its home economies (North America). As coup de grace, IBM has stolen nearly a billion dollars from both Canada and Australia on failed payroll projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If this is how IBM treats its staff and governments, &lt;em&gt;why would IBM treat your small business any differently&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;fv-testimonials-shortcode classic&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fvt_item&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fvtestimonial fvt-article-bio&quot; readability=&quot;31.383673469388&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fvt-thumb&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODdhAQABAPAAAP///wAAACwAAAAAAQABAEACAkQBADs=&quot; data-lazy-src=&quot;https://cdn.foliovision.com/images/2017/02/Alec-Kinnear-balcony.jpg&quot; width=&quot;250&quot; height=&quot;333&quot; alt=&quot;Alec Kinnear&quot;/&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.foliovision.com/images/2017/02/Alec-Kinnear-balcony.jpg&quot; width=&quot;250&quot; height=&quot;333&quot; alt=&quot;Alec Kinnear&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fvt-content&quot; readability=&quot;34.236734693878&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;fvt-author-name&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://foliovision.com/author/alec&quot;&gt;Alec Kinnear&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alec has been helping businesses succeed online since 2000. Alec is an SEM expert with a background in advertising, as a former Head of Television for Grey Moscow and Senior Television Producer for Bates, Saatchi and Saatchi Russia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 17:21:09 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>shelkie</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>A billion reasons never to buy IBM Services</og:title>
<og:description>IBM has made USD $780 million building a payroll system for the Canadian Government which does not work.</og:description>
<og:image>https://foliovision.com/images/2018/03/canada-ibm.png</og:image>
<og:url>https://foliovision.com/2018/03/why-not-buy-ibm</og:url>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://foliovision.com/2018/03/why-not-buy-ibm</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Learning Rust</title>
<link>https://learning-rust.github.io</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://learning-rust.github.io</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://learning-rust.github.io&quot;&gt;https://learning-rust.github.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16594547&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16594547&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Points: 210&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 62&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 17:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>dumindunuwan</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://learning-rust.github.io/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>