<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>The Italian Covid contact-tracing app is now developed in open source</title>
<link>https://github.com/immuni-app/immuni-documentation</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/immuni-app/immuni-documentation</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Immuni is the Italian Government’s exposure notification solution, realized by the Special Commissioner for the COVID-19 emergency (Presidency of the Council of Ministers), in collaboration with the Ministry of Health and the Ministry for Technological Innovation and Digitalization. It only uses public infrastructures located within the national borders. It is exclusively managed by the public company Sogei S.p.A. The source code has been developed for the Presidency of the Council of Ministers by Bending Spoons S.p.A., and it is released under a GNU Affero General Public License version 3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Table of contents&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Executive summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Immuni is a technological solution that centres on &lt;strong&gt;an iOS and Android smartphone app.&lt;/strong&gt; It helps us to fight the COVID-19 epidemic by notifying users at risk of carrying the virus as early as possible—&lt;strong&gt;even when they are asymptomatic.&lt;/strong&gt; These users can then isolate themselves to avoid infecting others, and seek medical advice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Immuni’s design and development are based on six main principles: &lt;strong&gt;utility, accessibility, accuracy, privacy, scalability,&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;transparency.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It features an &lt;strong&gt;exposure notification&lt;/strong&gt; system that leverages &lt;strong&gt;Bluetooth Low Energy:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;When two users come sufficiently close to each other for long enough, their devices record each other’s &lt;em&gt;rolling proximity identifier&lt;/em&gt; in local memory. Rolling proximity identifiers are generated from &lt;em&gt;temporary exposure keys&lt;/em&gt; and change multiple times each hour. Temporary exposure keys are &lt;strong&gt;generated randomly&lt;/strong&gt; and change once per day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When a user tests positive for SARS-CoV-2, the virus causing COVID-19, they have the option to upload to a server their recent temporary exposure keys. This operation can only happen with the validation of a &lt;strong&gt;healthcare operator.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The app periodically downloads the new temporary exposure keys and uses them to derive the infected users’ rolling proximity identifiers for the recent past. It then matches the identifiers against those stored in the device’s memory and &lt;strong&gt;notifies the user&lt;/strong&gt; if a risky exposure has occurred.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The system uses &lt;strong&gt;no geolocation data&lt;/strong&gt; whatsoever, including GPS data. So, the app cannot tell where the contact with a potentially contagious user took place, nor the identities of those involved.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To implement its contact tracing functionality, Immuni leverages &lt;strong&gt;the Apple and Google Exposure Notification framework.&lt;/strong&gt; This allows Immuni to be more reliable than otherwise would be possible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Besides the temporary exposure keys, the Immuni app also sends to the server some analytics data. These include &lt;strong&gt;epidemiological and operational information,&lt;/strong&gt; and are sent for the purpose of helping the National Healthcare Service (Servizio Sanitario Nazionale) to provide effective assistance to users.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Immuni is being developed while paying a lot of attention to user privacy and a number of measures have been taken to protect it. For example, the app collects &lt;strong&gt;no personal data that would disclose the user’s identity,&lt;/strong&gt; such as the user’s name, age, address, email, or phone number.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The whole world is united by a determination to stop the spread of COVID-19, the disease caused by SARS-CoV-2. The pandemic is threatening people’s health and severely damaging economies on a global scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many experts agree that, in the future, new pandemics are a distinct possibility. Some may become even more dangerous to humanity than the one we are currently battling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this challenging context, the contribution of technological innovation can be decisive. Immuni is one of a number of tools deployed and initiatives taken by the Italian government to help slow down the spread of the disease and accelerate the return to everyday life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This document provides a high-level description of Immuni—it is a good idea to read it first. More detailed information can be found in the following documents:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have open-sourced Immuni’s software under the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/licenses/agpl-3.0.en.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;GNU Affero General Public License version 3&lt;/a&gt;. Finally, penetration tests are taking place and we will share the resulting reports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Vision and goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Immuni is a technological solution that centres on a smartphone app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It helps us to fight epidemics—starting with COVID-19:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The app aims to notify users at risk of carrying the virus as early as possible—even when they are asymptomatic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;These users can then isolate themselves to avoid infecting others. This minimises the spread of the virus while speeding up a return to normal life for most people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By being notified early, they can also seek medical advice and lower the risk of serious health consequences.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Immuni is designed to address the current crisis, but the vision behind it is for the tools that are being developed to make us all better prepared in addressing similar threats that may arise in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Principles&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main principles that guide the design and development of Immuni follow:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Utility.&lt;/strong&gt; The app needs to be useful in fulfilling the project's vision and goals, as outlined above. The key here is to be able to notify as high a percentage of the people who are substantially at risk as possible, and to do so as early as is practical. This is the most important principle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Accessibility.&lt;/strong&gt; For fairness and to facilitate the widest adoption, Immuni should be accessible to the maximum possible number of people who may want to use it. This principle impacts decision-making across the board, including in user experience, design, localisation, and technology.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Accuracy.&lt;/strong&gt; Immuni aims to notify only those users who have a substantial risk of having contracted the virus. This is important because of the psychological toll that goes with being notified about a potential transmission of the disease, and because too high a rate of false positives would result in users losing trust in the app—and stopping their use of it. Also, the more accurate the app is, the more efficiently the National Healthcare Service (&lt;em&gt;Servizio Sanitario Nazionale&lt;/em&gt;) will be able to take care of users, making sure to attend to higher-risk ones first.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Privacy.&lt;/strong&gt; Immuni must protect user privacy while remaining effective. Earning and maintaining user trust is critical—failing to do so reduces the likelihood of widespread adoption.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scalability.&lt;/strong&gt; Immuni needs to be widely adopted throughout the country. This requires the system to scale well technologically and the operational burden it places on the National Healthcare Service to be manageable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Transparency.&lt;/strong&gt; Everyone should be provided with access to documentation describing Immuni in all its parts and the rationale behind the most important design decisions. Also, the app will be open source. This allows the users to verify that the app works as documented and the expert community to help improve it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Product&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Immuni is a technological solution that centres on a smartphone app available for Android and iOS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It features an exposure notification system to help alert potentially SARS-CoV-2-positive users at an early stage. This system keeps track of contact between Immuni users, even when they are total strangers. When a user tests positive for SARS-CoV-2, the app uses this system to notify other at-risk users. The system is based on Bluetooth Low Energy and does not use any geolocation data whatsoever, including GPS data. So, while the app knows that the contact with an infected user took place, how long it lasted, and can estimate the distance that separated the two users, it cannot tell where the contact took place, nor the identities of those involved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The app then recommends to at-risk users what to do. Recommendations may include self-isolation (which helps minimise the spread of the disease) and contacting their general practitioner (so that the user can receive the most appropriate care and reduce the likelihood of developing severe complications).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As stated, Immuni’s exposure notification system leverages Bluetooth Low Energy. This has some advantages compared to a solution based on location tracking:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The system is more accurate.&lt;/strong&gt; Geolocalisation, in many contexts, has an accuracy in the order of tens of metres. Meanwhile, Bluetooth Low Energy signals allow for capturing contact occurring within a radius of a few metres of the user. These are the cases of contact relevant to the transmission of SARS-CoV-2.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The battery is used more efficiently.&lt;/strong&gt; Bluetooth Low Energy excels when it comes to energy efficiency. This is important because it is reasonable to expect that the app’s uninstall rate will be correlated with battery consumption.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No geolocation data are required.&lt;/strong&gt; Thanks to Bluetooth Low Energy, contact is traced without tracking the users’ location. This may result in the app being more welcomed by the public and could facilitate wider adoption, increasing Immuni’s utility.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;To implement its contact tracing functionality, Immuni leverages the Apple and Google Exposure Notification framework (see &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/covid19/contacttracing&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Apple’s documentation&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/covid19/exposurenotifications/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Google’s documentation&lt;/a&gt;). This allows Immuni to overcome certain technical limitations, thus being more reliable than otherwise would be possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;How it works&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below, a high-level, simplified description of the system is provided. For more details, please study the rest of the Immuni documentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once installed and set up on a device (&lt;em&gt;device_A&lt;/em&gt;), the app generates a &lt;em&gt;temporary exposure key.&lt;/em&gt; This key is generated randomly and changes daily. The app also starts transmitting a Bluetooth Low Energy signal. The signal contains a &lt;em&gt;rolling proximity identifier&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;em&gt;ID_A1,&lt;/em&gt; assumed fixed in this example, for simplicity). This is generated from the current temporary exposure key. When another device (&lt;em&gt;device_B&lt;/em&gt;) running the app receives this signal, it records &lt;em&gt;ID_A1&lt;/em&gt; locally, in its memory. At the same time, &lt;em&gt;device_A&lt;/em&gt; records &lt;em&gt;device_B&lt;/em&gt;’s identifier (&lt;em&gt;ID_B1,&lt;/em&gt; also assumed fixed in this example).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the user of &lt;em&gt;device_A&lt;/em&gt; later tests positive for SARS-CoV-2, following the protocol defined by the National Healthcare Service, they have the option to upload to the Immuni server the temporary exposure keys from which the Immuni app can derive the rolling proximity identifiers recently broadcast by &lt;em&gt;device_A&lt;/em&gt; (including &lt;em&gt;ID_A1&lt;/em&gt;). Periodically, &lt;em&gt;device_B&lt;/em&gt; checks the new keys uploaded to the server against its local list of identifiers. &lt;em&gt;ID_A1&lt;/em&gt; will be a match. The app notifies the user of &lt;em&gt;device_B&lt;/em&gt; that they may be at risk and provides advice on what to do next (for example, isolating themselves and calling their general practitioner).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In practice, when it comes to determining whether the user of &lt;em&gt;device_B&lt;/em&gt; is at risk, finding that they had been in the proximity of the user of &lt;em&gt;device_A&lt;/em&gt; is not enough. Immuni assesses this risk based on the duration of the exposure and the distance between the two devices. This is estimated from the attenuation of the Bluetooth Low Energy signal as received by &lt;em&gt;device_B.&lt;/em&gt; The longer the exposure and the closer the contact, the higher the risk that a transmission of the virus occurred. Contact lasting only a couple of minutes and happening at several metres of distance will generally be considered to be low risk. The risk model may evolve with time as more information about SARS-CoV-2 becomes available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It should be noted that the estimation of distance is error-prone. In fact, the attenuation of a Bluetooth Low Energy signal depends on factors such as the orientation of the two devices relative to each other and the obstacles (including human bodies) that lie in between. While leveraging this information is likely useful in increasing the accuracy of Immuni’s assessments of the risk of contagion, wrong assessments will happen with some frequency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rolling proximity identifier that is broadcast by the app is generated from random temporary exposure keys and does not contain any information about the device, let alone the user. Moreover, it is &lt;em&gt;rolling,&lt;/em&gt; meaning that it changes multiple times each hour, further protecting the privacy of Immuni’s users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To ensure that only users who actually tested positive for SARS-CoV-2 upload their keys to the server, the upload procedure can only be performed with the cooperation of an authenticated healthcare operator. The operator asks the user to provide a code generated by the app and inputs it into a back-office tool. The upload can succeed only if the code used by the app to authenticate the data corresponds to that entered in the system by the healthcare operator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Analytics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides the temporary exposure keys, some additional information is sent to the server and analysed to ensure the proper functioning of the system:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Epidemiological information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Operational information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;These data are important for the National Healthcare Service’s effective management of the system, including maximising the effectiveness of the exposure notifications and providing optimal healthcare assistance to users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The optimisations enabled by the epidemiological and operational information may be most effective if carried out at the local level. The various Italian regions differ in healthcare policies, resources, and capabilities. Moreover, the epidemic might be at different stages in different locations. Therefore, when sending these data to the server, the app attaches the user’s province of domicile as provided by the user during the onboarding process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Epidemiological information&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only epidemiological data Immuni collects relate to the user’s exposure to infected users. The data include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The day the exposure occurred&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The duration of the exposure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Signal attenuation information used for estimating the distance between the two users’ devices during the exposure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Information on how contagious the infected user was likely to be when the exposure occurred, based on the day of symptom onset, if any (this information may be attached to each temporary exposure key the infected user has uploaded with the assistance of a health operator)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The app may send epidemiological information to the server only upon uploading temporary exposure keys. When a healthcare operator communicates to the user their positivity to a SARS-CoV-2 test, any available epidemiological information from the previous 14 days will be uploaded too. The data upload needs to be initiated by the user and approved by the healthcare operator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To protect the user’s privacy, the data uploaded relating to their exposure to potentially contagious users have certain limitations. For example, the duration of the exposure is measured in five-minute increments and capped at 30 minutes for the sum of all contact with an infected user on any given day. Moreover, Immuni has no way to determine that exposures occurring on different days may have involved the same infected user. The app also performs periodic dummy uploads to mitigate the risk of someone gaining sensitive information about the user through traffic analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Collecting these data helps the National Healthcare Service to optimise the app’s risk model. By learning how the epidemiological information (e.g., the duration of the user's exposure) correlates with the user ultimately testing positive for SARS-CoV-2, it may be possible to improve the app's risk model and therefore increase its accuracy, thereby increasing the effectiveness of the exposure notification system. Note that the assessment of risk always happens on the user's device, while the latest model can be fetched from the server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Operational information&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the above, some data on device activity and exposure notifications may be collected and uploaded. These data include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Whether permission to leverage the Apple and Google Exposure Notification framework is granted&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Whether the device’s Bluetooth is enabled&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Whether permission to send local notifications is granted&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Whether the user was notified of a risky exposure after the last exposure detection (i.e., after the app has downloaded new temporary exposure keys from the server and detected if the user has been exposed to SARS-CoV-2-positive users)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The date on which the last risky exposure took place, if any&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The upload may take place after an exposure detection has been completed. The operational information is uploaded automatically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To protect user privacy, the data are uploaded without leveraging a user identifier or device identifier, and without requiring the user to authenticate in any way (e.g., no phone number or email verification). Moreover, traffic analysis is obstructed by dummy uploads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to these data, it is possible to estimate the level of the app’s adoption across the country, not just measured by number of downloads—a largely meaningless metric—but by devices that are actually working properly. This information is very helpful, as we know that the utility of Immuni depends heavily on its uptake within the population. Supported by these data, the National Healthcare Service can make better decisions in a number of areas critical to maximising the effectiveness of exposure notifications and providing optimal patient care. Such areas include product development, engineering, and communications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data would also help with optimising the allocation of resources. By notifying at-risk users, the app will increase the volume of interactions with the National Healthcare Service. Therefore, estimating the number of users that the system will notify may help the National Healthcare Service to allocate its resources accordingly and thus efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Privacy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Immuni has been and continues to be designed and developed while paying a lot of attention to user privacy. It is a fundamental right that we must do everything we can to protect. We also think that outstanding privacy protection is critical to making the app acceptable to the greatest number of people, thereby maximising Immuni’s utility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below, we provide a list of some of the measures by which Immuni protects the user’s privacy:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The app does not collect any personal data that would disclose the user’s identity. For example, it does not collect the user’s name, date of birth, address, email, or phone number.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The app does not collect any geolocation data, including GPS data. The user’s movements are not tracked in any shape or form.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The rolling proximity identifier that is broadcast by the app is generated from random temporary exposure keys and does not contain any information about the device, let alone the user. Moreover, it changes multiple times each hour.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The epidemiological information uploaded about the user’s exposure to potentially contagious users has certain limitations. For example, the duration of the exposure is measured in five-minute increments and capped at 30 minutes for the sum of all contact with an infected user on any given day. Moreover, Immuni has no way to determine that exposures occurring on different days may have involved the same infected user.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The operational information is uploaded without leveraging a user identifier or device identifier, and without requiring the user to authenticate in any way (including verifying a phone number or email).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The app performs periodic dummy uploads to mitigate the risk of someone gaining sensitive information about the user through traffic analysis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The data stored on the device are encrypted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All connections between the device and the server are encrypted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All data, whether stored on the device or on the server, are deleted when no longer needed, and in any case no later than December 31, 2020.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Ministry of Health will be the data controller. The data will be used solely with the aim of containing the COVID-19 epidemic or for scientific research.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The data will be stored on servers located in Italy and managed by publicly controlled entities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Open points&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are some of the most pressing points on which we are working:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dummy traffic.&lt;/strong&gt; We would like to minimise the information that an attacker could gain by analysing network traffic. We are finalising the development of dummy uploads.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Analytics integrity.&lt;/strong&gt; We are trying to collect the necessary operational information while preserving user privacy to the maximum possible extent. However, performing such collection without asking the user to authenticate (e.g., by verifying a phone number or email address) and without using any user identifier or device identifier makes it harder to prevent attackers from polluting the data with fake uploads. We devised a promising solution that we expect to work for a significant portion of devices. Documentation and development are underway.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 21:26:20 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>giovannibajo1</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://repository-images.githubusercontent.com/257338092/e43dad80-9632-11ea-947d-70ddd2437fc4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>immuni-app/immuni-documentation</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/immuni-app/immuni-documentation</og:url>
<og:description>Repo for Immuni's documentation. Contribute to immuni-app/immuni-documentation development by creating an account on GitHub.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/immuni-app/immuni-documentation</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>P2P Matrix</title>
<link>https://matrix.org/blog/2020/06/02/introducing-p-2-p-matrix</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://matrix.org/blog/2020/06/02/introducing-p-2-p-matrix</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;TL;DR: we shipped a major update (v0.1.1) to &lt;a href=&quot;https://p2p.riot.im&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;https://p2p.riot.im&lt;/a&gt; - fire up a desktop Chrome or Firefox in not-private-browsing mode and give it a go!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi folks,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As many know by now, a few of us have been working away since mid-December on experimenting with running Matrix in a peer-to-peer architecture - one where every user has absolute total autonomy and ownership of their conversations, because the only place their conversations exist is on the devices they own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In some ways this is the logical end goal of Matrix: our aim has always been to empower users to have full control over their communication rather than being beholden to any given service provider, and in a P2P world we completely return power over secure communication to the people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-p2p&quot;&gt;Why P2P?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;P2P Matrix is about more than just letting users store their own conversations: it can also avoid dependencies on the Internet itself by working over local networks, mesh networks, or situations where the Internet has been cut off. Even more interestingly, without homeservers, there is nowhere for metadata to accumulate about who is talking to who, and when - which is a legitimate complaint about today’s Matrix network, given the homeservers of all users in a given conversation necessarily have to store that conversation’s metadata. P2P also lets us radically simplify signup for new users if they don’t have to pick a server to get going - and we avoid the unintentional centralisation of users piling onto public servers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;P2P also forces us to solve many of the hardest remaining problems in Matrix: e.g multi-homed accounts, given multi-device P2P requires your account to exist in multiple places. This in turn unlocks high availability and geo-redundancy for accounts on today’s Matrix network (imagine having a primary and backup homeserver that magically did the right thing!), as well as account portability, and thus also vhosting and load-balancing accounts between servers, and even improved GDPR compliance (for if your user IDs are ephemeral they are no longer personally identifying information baked into your Matrix rooms). We’ll also need better safety mechanisms to avoid folks exploiting the anonymous nature of the network for abuse, accelerating the work we’re already doing for today’s Matrix network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The way we’ve been approaching P2P is the “&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Lucid00/status/1263974339294175232&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;hamfisted but genius&lt;/a&gt;” approach of taking homeservers and running them on the client, alongside or within your Matrix client - meaning that there are literally &lt;strong&gt;no&lt;/strong&gt; changes required for any Matrix client to talk P2P Matrix, and so P2P Matrix can instantly benefit from all the work which has gone into Riot and other apps. As a result, P2P is also a huge motivator towards developing much smaller homeservers which can run efficiently clientside (e.g. Dendrite!) - which is of course great news for Matrix as a whole. It also forces us to develop more scalable routing algorithms (as you don’t want your client to have to talk to every other device in a room every time it sends a message!) and also spurs development of low bandwidth Matrix transports (as you don’t want the additional chatter of talking to multiple peers to consume all your bandwidth). Finally, it forces us to really ruggedize federation, given nodes are constantly appearing and disappearing, giving the federation much more of a stress test than we see with today’s relatively static homeservers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;p2p-in-practice&quot;&gt;P2P in Practice&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, P2P has been acting as fuel for a lot of our longer term Matrix work over the last few months. There have been three main experiments so far: at &lt;a href=&quot;https://fosdem.org/2020/schedule/event/dip_p2p_matrix/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;FOSDEM&lt;/a&gt; we showed off running our next-gen Dendrite homeserver running clientside using HTTP over &lt;a href=&quot;https://libp2p.io/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;libp2p&lt;/a&gt; as the transport. We also highlighted Timothée Floure’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epfl.ch/labs/dedis/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/presentation-2019-2-Timothee-Floure-Experimenting-with-Matrix-federation-over-Yggdrasil.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;project at EPFL&lt;/a&gt; experimenting with Synapse talking P2P CoAP over yggdrasil as the transport via a proxy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most recently, however, we’ve been experimenting with compiling Dendrite down to Web Assembly and running it embedded in Riot Web as a Service Worker, using HTTP over libp2p’s websocket transport (coordinated via a websocket rendezvous server). Architecturally, it looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://matrix.org/blog/img/p2p-diag.png&quot; alt=&quot;P2P Architecture Diagram&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, we’re shipping a major new alpha (v0.1.1) of this P2P demo up at &lt;a href=&quot;https://p2p.riot.im&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;https://p2p.riot.im&lt;/a&gt; (requires desktop Chrome or Firefox in non-private-browsing mode) - which hopefully should give a really usable and concrete taste of the shape of things to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main features are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Your conversations are now persisted in your browser storage (via IndexedDB), meaning that as long as all the browsers participating in a given conversation don’t clear their local storage, rooms on the P2P network are here to stay!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your room directory lists all the aliases for all the rooms published by active nodes on the network. Moreover, we now automatically publish a local room alias whenever you join a public room, so that others will be able to discover that room via you, even if the server who originally created the alias has disappeared.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lots and lots of federation improvements between the nodes - for instance, when a node comes online, others should now automatically detect and send scrollback to it. Invites should work, and there should no longer be any unexpectedly redacted messages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Needless to say, all the code for this is open source under the Apache license, and if you’re feeling particularly adventurous you can embed your very own P2P Dendrite into Riot Web by using the Dockerfile at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/matrix-org/dendrite/blob/master/build/docker/DendriteJS.Dockerfile&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;https://github.com/matrix-org/dendrite/blob/master/build/docker/DendriteJS.Dockerfile&lt;/a&gt; or following the instructions at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/matrix-org/dendrite/blob/master/docs/p2p.md&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;https://github.com/matrix-org/dendrite/blob/master/docs/p2p.md&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please report bugs to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/matrix-org/dendrite/issues&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;https://github.com/matrix-org/dendrite/issues&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, please understand that the demo is very likely &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; what the final version of P2P Matrix will look like - this is just one step in a series of experiments as we investigate the best paths forward :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;whats-next&quot;&gt;What’s next?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the current demo, there’s still lots of stuff remaining, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;More federation debugging (and hooking in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/matrix-org/tardis&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;tardis&lt;/a&gt; and writing up everything we’ve learned about implementing federation in Dendrite!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Making the content repository work in-browser (gotta fill up those IndexedDBs with some GIFs!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hooking up E2E Encryption APIs in Dendrite (not that it buys us much in a pure P2P world)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WebRTC transports. Turns out that service workers aren’t allowed to speak WebRTC, so we’ll have to shim through to Riot to speak true peer-to-peer WebRTC data channels rather than relaying all the traffic through the websocket rendezvous server.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Decentralised accounts for multidevice support - reviewing &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/matrix-org/matrix-doc/blob/rav/proposal/remove_mxids_from_events/proposals/1228-removing-mxids-from-events.md&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;MSC1228&lt;/a&gt; and getting Dendrite supporting multihoming accounts!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finishing all of Dendrite’s other remaining APIs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Beyond this, there are some bigger picture questions left to be answered in future experiments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly: we do not yet have a solution for “store and forward” nodes which can relay messages on behalf of a room if all the participating devices are offline. A first cut will be to run a P2P-capable homeserver server-side for this, but then metadata will start to accumulate server-side for the conversations it hosts. A more interesting approach would be to use a store and forward system which obfuscates who is talking to who, such as a mixnet, and could even provide resistance to network traffic pattern analysis. This is very much an open area of research, but one we are getting into :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly: we want to experiment more with other transports, and find out which works best for Matrix. Libp2p has some really exciting new stuff in the form of &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.ipfs.io/2020-05-20-gossipsub-v1.1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Gossipsub v1.1&lt;/a&gt; - a much smarter routing algorithm for pubsub traffic in libp2p, which David Dias gave us a &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/APVp-20ATLk?t=3598&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;VIP tour&lt;/a&gt; of at the first Open Tech Will Save Us meetup. So we’ll need to restructure our libp2p transport as pubsub to see how it works in practice. Separately, we also want to play with hooking up &lt;a href=&quot;https://yggdrasil-network.github.io/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Yggdrasil&lt;/a&gt; (the encrypted overlay network) as a transport as a totally different approach - Yggdrasil will easily let us span different underlying network transports, but comes with different tradeoffs (e.g. no browser support yet). We also want to take a look at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://dat.foundation/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;DAT&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/hypercore-protocol/hypercore&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;hypercore&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/hyperswarm/hyperswarm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;hyperswarm&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href=&quot;https://cabal.chat/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Cabal&lt;/a&gt; ecosystem to see if there’s a match :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thirdly and finally: we obviously want to unify the new P2P Matrix network with today’s federated one. The ideal outcome here would be to have a hybrid model, where teams who want their users to have a dedicated homeserver (for availability, IT policies, etc) can continue to have one as they do today - but newbies who have just installed Riot would float around on P2P unless they decided to consciously put down roots on a server or two. Best of all, it would let us turn off the matrix.org homeserver: the best public homeserver is one you run yourself on your own phone ;) The approach we take for linking P2P and today’s Matrix will depend very much on the transport we select for P2P in the long run, but the likelihood is that today’s homeservers will sprout P2P gateways to link the networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, there you have it. P2P Matrix exists, and is developing at an alarming speed - and pushing Dendrite development along with it. Most excitingly, there have been no changes yet to the Matrix spec for P2P at all; we’ve just swapped https for http-over-libp2p as the transport. So &lt;strong&gt;all&lt;/strong&gt; of the work we’ve been doing making Dendrite work in a P2P world has directly translated into making Dendrite work on today’s Matrix too You can now stand up a Dendrite and have it federate pretty reliably with the wider Matrix network, although we’re still rushing through implementing APIs (we’re up to 35% passing &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/matrix-org/sytest&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;sytest&lt;/a&gt; coverage - although that 35% does contain most of the important tests :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, in case you’re worried about why the Matrix core team is off chasing P2P dreams rather than improving Riot’s UX, or implementing Communities, or Extensible Profiles, or working through the MSC backlog etc... in practice only two people (ignoring Matthew) have been working on P2P - Neil Alexander (author of the original FOSDEM demo, Dendrite wrangler and Yggdrasil co-maintainer) and Kegan Dougal (of the original Matrix dev team, one of the original authors of Dendrite, and now wrangling the WASM P2P work too). Huge thanks to Kegan &amp;amp; Neil for pushing P2P forwards - and huge thanks to everyone else on the core team and the wider community for keeping today’s Matrix advancing too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope this has given a tempting glimpse of the shape of things to come. Honestly we never thought we’d get as far as P2P when we started Matrix back in 2014, but it’s really fun to be finally catching up with the future :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-- Matthew&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;P.S. You can read more about this from Neil Alexander’s point of view &lt;a href=&quot;https://neilalexander.dev/2020/06/02/thoughts-p2p-matrix.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;over at his blog&lt;/a&gt; (including more thoughts on the potential Yggdrasil demo!)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 17:58:53 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Arathorn</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://matrix.org/blog/2020/06/02/introducing-p-2-p-matrix</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Introducing P2P Matrix | Matrix.org</og:title>
<og:image>https://matrix.org/blog/img/matrix-logo.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://matrix.org/blog/2020/06/02/introducing-p-2-p-matrix/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Police attacks against journalists across the U.S. since May 28</title>
<link>https://www.niemanlab.org/2020/06/well-try-to-help-you-follow-the-police-attacks-on-journalists-across-the-country</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.niemanlab.org/2020/06/well-try-to-help-you-follow-the-police-attacks-on-journalists-across-the-country</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;As Black Lives Matter protests spread across the country one week after a white police officer &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Death_of_George_Floyd&quot;&gt;allegedly murdered a black man, George Floyd&lt;/a&gt;, it’s becoming clear that attacks by police on journalists are becoming a widespread pattern, not one-off incidents. While violence against press-credentialed reporters covering the protests may still be dwarfed by violence against the American citizens who are protesting, incidents are piling up — and are getting more attention in part because the journalists being attacked include those from large mainstream news organizations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A number of efforts are underway to try to track the attacks on journalists, which are often first documented on Twitter. Bellingcat senior investigator &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/N_Waters89&quot;&gt;Nick Waters&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/N_Waters89/status/1267433966967103488&quot;&gt;had documented 124 incidents by 3:30 PM ET on Tuesday afternoon.&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/N_Waters89/status/1267604692059684866&quot;&gt;#101 occurred outside the White House&lt;/a&gt;, when federal law enforcement &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/salvadorhernandez/trump-white-house-protesters-police&quot;&gt;attacked a group of protestors and journalists with tear gas&lt;/a&gt;, allowing the president a clear path to walk to a photo opportunity in which he &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/dc-md-va/2020/06/01/dc-protest-george-floyd-white-house/#link-6X27RW6V5JELFNMC7VDBVI3ERI&quot;&gt;held a Bible in front of St. John’s Church&lt;/a&gt;.) A story on Bellingcat’s site, “U.S. Law Enforcement Are Deliberately Targeting Journalists During George Floyd Protests,” &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bellingcat.com/news/americas/2020/05/31/us-law-enforcement-are-deliberately-targeting-journalists-during-george-floyd-protests/&quot;&gt;provides more insight into some of the incidents&lt;/a&gt;, and notes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although in some incidents it is possible the journalists were hit or affected accidentally, in the majority of the cases we have recorded the journalists are clearly identifiable as press, and it is clear that they are being deliberately targeted. This pattern of violence against journalists is replicated in several cities, but appears most intense in Minneapolis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://pressfreedomtracker.us/&quot;&gt;U.S. Press Freedom Tracker&lt;/a&gt; counts 192 total press freedom violations, which it categorizes like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; readability=&quot;10.622950819672&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;You can see our spreadsheet tracking this data below. Please note these are preliminary numbers, so please let us know if anything is accidentally mischaracterized! (Also, some journalists were assaulted multiple ways.) &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/73e9qJ0uLp&quot;&gt;https://t.co/73e9qJ0uLp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— U.S. Press Freedom Tracker (@uspresstracker) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/uspresstracker/status/1267878379216396291?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;June 2, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; readability=&quot;11.8125&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;If you're a journalist who's been arrested, gassed, or shot — get in touch with us at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/uspresstracker?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@USPressTracker&lt;/a&gt; so we can document your case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our team is investigating literally dozens of press freedom violations across the country as we speak. &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/nJcVsWAqLQ&quot;&gt;https://t.co/nJcVsWAqLQ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Freedom of the Press (@FreedomofPress) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/FreedomofPress/status/1266937125901082624?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;May 31, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; readability=&quot;11.560975609756&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Police forces have regularly attacked and arrested journalists at protests in this country. But often it has been unfamous journalists from non-corporate outlets, so no one paid attention to it. Now, the police are deliberately &amp;amp; consistently attacking corporate journalists too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— jeremy scahill (@jeremyscahill) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jeremyscahill/status/1267097377879572480?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;May 31, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; readability=&quot;8.8782051282051&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;I’ve never seen so many incidents with police and reporters simultaneously in different cities. Tension between cops and reporters is nothing new. Aggression on reporters in multiple locations nationally at same time is something different. &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/SA5s1Wy3DP&quot;&gt;https://t.co/SA5s1Wy3DP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Maggie Haberman (@maggieNYT) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/maggieNYT/status/1267293015321739265?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;June 1, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; readability=&quot;10.56862745098&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;I researched countless protests for my first book. I’ve written about many since. I think it’s safe to say that we’ve never seen the widespread, deliberate targeting of journalists by police that we’ve seen over the last few days. Something has changed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Radley Balko (@radleybalko) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/radleybalko/status/1267421847957704704?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;June 1, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; readability=&quot;9.4759825327511&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;I'll continue to track and file FOIA requests for journalists arrested in Minneapolis. I filed requests for the CNN crew this morning. If you hear about something new, please let me know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Runa Sandvik (@runasand) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/runasand/status/1266368199307563008?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;May 29, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; readability=&quot;10.695652173913&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;This is the thing, to me, that feels different. This is the action where the police are crossing a line in terms of press freedom that they hadn’t routinely cross before at 2014-2019 protests. Your “new” and “increasing” narratives are now accurate &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/MNq3sCrvvl&quot;&gt;https://t.co/MNq3sCrvvl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Wesley (@WesleyLowery) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/WesleyLowery/status/1267281688482242560?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;June 1, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post was last updated on Tuesday, June 2 at 3:30 PM ET.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 17:57:06 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>laurex</dc:creator>
<og:title>U.S. police have attacked journalists more than 120 times since May 28</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:image>https://www.niemanlab.org/images/police-julia-walshere-700x467.jpeg</og:image>
<og:url>https://www.niemanlab.org/2020/06/well-try-to-help-you-follow-the-police-attacks-on-journalists-across-the-country/</og:url>
<og:description>&quot;Although in some incidents it is possible the journalists were hit or affected accidentally, in the majority of the cases we have recorded the journalists are clearly identifiable as press, and it is clear that they are being deliberately targeted.&quot;</og:description>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.niemanlab.org/2020/06/well-try-to-help-you-follow-the-police-attacks-on-journalists-across-the-country</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Tor Browser 9.5</title>
<link>https://blog.torproject.org/new-release-tor-browser-95</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.torproject.org/new-release-tor-browser-95</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Tor Browser 9.5 is now available from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.torproject.org/download/&quot;&gt;Tor Browser download page&lt;/a&gt; and also from our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.torproject.org/dist/torbrowser/9.5/&quot;&gt;distribution directory&lt;/a&gt;. The Android version is also available from Google Play and should be available from F-Droid within the next day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This release includes important &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/security/advisories/mfsa2020-21/&quot;&gt;security updates&lt;/a&gt; to Firefox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This new Tor Browser release is focused on helping users understand onion services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tor's onion routing remains the best way to achieve end-to-end anonymous communication on the Internet. With onion services (.onion addresses), website administrators can provide their users with anonymous connections that are metadata-free or that hide metadata from any third party. Onion services are also one of the few censorship circumvention technologies that allow users to route around censorship while simultaneously protecting their privacy and identity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the first time, Tor Browser users on desktop will be able to opt-in for using onion sites automatically whenever the website makes them available. For years, some websites have invisibly used onion services with &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.cloudflare.com/cloudflare-onion-service/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;alternative services (alt-svc)&lt;/a&gt;, and this continues to be an excellent choice. Now, there is also an opt-in mechanism available for websites that want their users to know about their onion service that invites them to upgrade their connection via the .onion address.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What is new?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Onion Location&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Website publishers now can advertise their onion service to Tor users by adding an HTTP header. When &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.torproject.org&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;visiting a website&lt;/a&gt; that has both an &lt;a href=&quot;http://4bflp2c4tnynnbes.onion&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;.onion address&lt;/a&gt; and Onion Location enabled via Tor Browser, users will be prompted about the onion service version of the site and will be asked to opt-in to upgrade to the onion service on their first use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Onion Location Propublica&quot; data-entity-type=&quot;file&quot; data-entity-uuid=&quot;3b987597-aa20-4b94-b8a6-93d6bd9fddf8&quot; src=&quot;https://blog.torproject.org/sites/default/files/inline-images/onion-location-propublica%402x.png&quot; class=&quot;align-center&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Onion Authentication&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onion services administrators who want to add an extra layer of security to their website can now set a pair of keys for access control and authentication. Tor Browser users can save keys and manage them via &lt;a href=&quot;about:preferences#privacy&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;about:preferences#privacy&lt;/a&gt; in the Onion Services Authentication section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Onion Authentication&quot; data-entity-type=&quot;file&quot; data-entity-uuid=&quot;d66f4680-faf7-490a-aaa4-1865a0d55202&quot; src=&quot;https://blog.torproject.org/sites/default/files/inline-images/onion-auth%402x.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Improved URL Bar Security Indicators&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Browsers traditionally rendered sites delivered via a secure transport protocol with a green lock icon. But in mid-2019, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.mozilla.org/security/2019/10/15/improved-security-and-privacy-indicators-in-firefox-70/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;formerly green lock icon became gray&lt;/a&gt;, intending to de-emphasize the default (safe) connection state and, instead, putting more emphasis on broken or insecure connections. Major browsers as Mozilla Firefox and Google Chrome understood that it is a benefit for the entire user base if they deploy familiar experiences for both users. We are following Firefox on this decision, and we have updated Tor Browser security indicators to make it easier for users to understand when they are visiting a non-secure website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Tor Browser 9.5 URL Bar Update&quot; data-entity-type=&quot;file&quot; data-entity-uuid=&quot;0226a879-0418-4711-88fc-db0540fdb463&quot; src=&quot;https://blog.torproject.org/sites/default/files/inline-images/onion-url-bar-update%402x_1.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Error Pages for Onion Services&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes users have a hard time reaching onion sites. In previous versions of Tor Browser, when there was an error connecting to an onion service, users received a standard Firefox error message, with no information about why they were unable to connect to the onion site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this release, we have improved the way Tor Browser communicates with users about service-, client-, and network-side errors that might happen when they are trying to visit an onion service. Tor Browser now displays a simplified diagram of the connection and shows where the error occurred. We want these messages to be clear and informative without being overwhelming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Error Page for Onion Pages&quot; data-entity-type=&quot;file&quot; data-entity-uuid=&quot;d1bb8668-5464-4b28-8067-19559bfaf9db&quot; src=&quot;https://blog.torproject.org/sites/default/files/inline-images/onion-error%402x.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Onion Names&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because of cryptographic protections, onion service URLs are not easy for humans to remember (ie, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.torproject.org&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://torproject.org&lt;/a&gt; vs. &lt;a href=&quot;http://expyuzz4wqqyqhjn.onion&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://expyuzz4wqqyqhjn.onion/&lt;/a&gt;). This makes it hard for users to discover or return to an onion site. We found that organically, developers have approached this problem in different ways, mostly with solutions tailored for their service. Given that there is no solution that works perfectly for all our user groups, we also approached this problem from a broad angle. For this release, we partnered with &lt;a href=&quot;https://freedom.press&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Freedom of the Press Foundation&lt;/a&gt; (FPF) and the Electronic Frontier Foundation's &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/https-everywhere&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;HTTPS Everywhere&lt;/a&gt; to develop the first proof-of-concept human-memorable names for SecureDrop onion services addresses:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The Intercept:
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lucy Parsons Labs:
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Freedom of the Press Foundation has reached out to a small number of additional media organizations for participation, and Tor and FPF will jointly consider next steps based on feedback on this initial proof-of-concept.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Onion Names&quot; data-entity-type=&quot;file&quot; data-entity-uuid=&quot;1adc8ce1-ddc2-413a-b8d8-8f5b063bbc51&quot; src=&quot;https://blog.torproject.org/sites/default/files/inline-images/onion-names%402x.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Known Issues&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tor Browser 9.5 comes with a number of &lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/query?status=accepted&amp;amp;status=assigned&amp;amp;status=merge_ready&amp;amp;status=needs_information&amp;amp;status=needs_review&amp;amp;status=needs_revision&amp;amp;status=new&amp;amp;status=reopened&amp;amp;keywords=~tbb-9.5-issues&amp;amp;col=id&amp;amp;col=summary&amp;amp;col=keywords&amp;amp;col=status&amp;amp;col=owner&amp;amp;col=priority&amp;amp;col=component&amp;amp;col=severity&amp;amp;col=time&amp;amp;col=changetime&amp;amp;col=reporter&amp;amp;order=id&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;known issues&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Give Feedback&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you find a bug or have a suggestion for how we could improve this release, please let us know. Thanks to all of the teams across Tor, and the many volunteers, who contributed to this release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Full Changelog&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The full &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitweb.torproject.org/builders/tor-browser-build.git/plain/projects/tor-browser/Bundle-Data/Docs/ChangeLog.txt?h=maint-9.5&quot;&gt;changelog&lt;/a&gt; since Tor Browser 9.0.10 is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;All Platforms
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Bump NoScript to 11.0.26&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update Firefox to 68.9.0esr&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update HTTPS-Everywhere to 2020.5.20&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update NoScript to 11.0.26&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update Tor to 0.4.3.5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Translations update&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/21549&quot;&gt;Bug 21549&lt;/a&gt;: Disable wasm for now until it is properly audited&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/27268&quot;&gt;Bug 27268&lt;/a&gt;: Preferences clean-up in Torbutton code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/28745&quot;&gt;Bug 28745&lt;/a&gt;: Remove torbutton.js unused code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/28746&quot;&gt;Bug 28746&lt;/a&gt;: Remove torbutton isolation and fp prefs sync&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/30237&quot;&gt;Bug 30237&lt;/a&gt;: Control port module improvements for v3 client authentication&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/30786&quot;&gt;Bug 30786&lt;/a&gt;: Add th locale&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/30787&quot;&gt;Bug 30787&lt;/a&gt;: Add lt locale&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/30788&quot;&gt;Bug 30788&lt;/a&gt;: Add ms locale&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/30851&quot;&gt;Bug 30851&lt;/a&gt;: Move default preferences to 000-tor-browser.js&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/30888&quot;&gt;Bug 30888&lt;/a&gt;: move torbutton_util.js to modules/utils.js&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/31134&quot;&gt;Bug 31134&lt;/a&gt;: Govern graphite again by security settings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/31395&quot;&gt;Bug 31395&lt;/a&gt;: Remove inline script in aboutTor.xhtml&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/31499&quot;&gt;Bug 31499&lt;/a&gt;: Update libevent to 2.1.11-stable
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/33877&quot;&gt;Bug 33877&lt;/a&gt;: Disable Samples and Regression tests For Libevent Build&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/31573&quot;&gt;Bug 31573&lt;/a&gt;: Catch SessionStore.jsm exception&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/32318&quot;&gt;Bug 32318&lt;/a&gt;: Backport Mozilla's fix for bug 1534339&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/32414&quot;&gt;Bug 32414&lt;/a&gt;: Make Services.search.addEngine obey FPI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/32493&quot;&gt;Bug 32493&lt;/a&gt;: Disable MOZ_SERVICES_HEALTHREPORT&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/32618&quot;&gt;Bug 32618&lt;/a&gt;: Backport fixes from Mozilla bugs 1467970 and 1590526&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/33342&quot;&gt;Bug 33342&lt;/a&gt;: Avoid disconnect search addon error after removal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/33726&quot;&gt;Bug 33726&lt;/a&gt;: Fix patch for #23247: Communicating security expectations for .onion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/34157&quot;&gt;Bug 34157&lt;/a&gt;: Backport fix for Mozilla Bug 1511941&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Windows + OS X + Linux
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Update Tor Launcher to 0.2.21.8
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/19251&quot;&gt;Bug 19251&lt;/a&gt;: Show improved error pages for onion service errors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/19757&quot;&gt;Bug 19757&lt;/a&gt;: Support on-disk storage of v3 client auth keys&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/21952&quot;&gt;Bug 21952&lt;/a&gt;: Implement Onion-Location&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/27604&quot;&gt;Bug 27604&lt;/a&gt;: Fix broken Tor Browser after moving it to a different directory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/28005&quot;&gt;Bug 28005&lt;/a&gt;: Implement .onion alias urlbar rewrites&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/30237&quot;&gt;Bug 30237&lt;/a&gt;: Improve TBB UI of hidden service client authorization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/32076&quot;&gt;Bug 32076&lt;/a&gt;: Upgrade to goptlib v1.1.0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/32220&quot;&gt;Bug 32220&lt;/a&gt;: Improve the letterboxing experience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/32418&quot;&gt;Bug 32418&lt;/a&gt;: Allow updates to be disabled via an enterprise policy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/32470&quot;&gt;Bug 32470&lt;/a&gt;: Backport fix for bug 1590538&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/32645&quot;&gt;Bug 32645&lt;/a&gt;: Update URL bar onion indicators&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/32658&quot;&gt;Bug 32658&lt;/a&gt;: Create a new MAR signing key&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/32674&quot;&gt;Bug 32674&lt;/a&gt;: Point the about:tor &quot;Get involved&quot; link to the community portal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/32767&quot;&gt;Bug 32767&lt;/a&gt;: Remove Disconnect search&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/33698&quot;&gt;Bug 33698&lt;/a&gt;: Update &quot;About Tor Browser&quot; links in Tor Browser&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/33707&quot;&gt;Bug 33707&lt;/a&gt;: Swap out onion icon in circuit display with new one&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/34032&quot;&gt;Bug 34032&lt;/a&gt;: Use Securedrop's Official https-everywhere ruleset&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/34196&quot;&gt;Bug 34196&lt;/a&gt;: Update site info URL with the onion name&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/34321&quot;&gt;Bug 34321&lt;/a&gt;: Add Learn More onboarding item&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Windows
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/22919&quot;&gt;Bug 22919&lt;/a&gt;: Improve the random number generator for the boundaries in multipart/form-data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/29614&quot;&gt;Bug 29614&lt;/a&gt;: Use SHA-256 algorithm for Windows timestamping&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/33113&quot;&gt;Bug 33113&lt;/a&gt;: Bump NSIS version to 3.05&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OS X
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/32505&quot;&gt;Bug 32505&lt;/a&gt;: Tighten our rules in our entitlements file for macOS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linux
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/27903&quot;&gt;Bug 27903&lt;/a&gt;: Tor Browser 8 does not respect gtk3 settings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/34315&quot;&gt;Bug 34315&lt;/a&gt;: Avoid reading policies from /etc/firefox on Linux&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Android
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/26529&quot;&gt;Bug 26529&lt;/a&gt;: Notify user about possible proxy-bypass before opening external app&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/30767&quot;&gt;Bug 30767&lt;/a&gt;: Custom obfs4 bridge does not work on Tor Browser for Android&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/32303&quot;&gt;Bug 32303&lt;/a&gt;: Obfs4 is broken on Android Q&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/33359&quot;&gt;Bug 33359&lt;/a&gt;: Use latest Version of TOPL and Remove Patches&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/33931&quot;&gt;Bug 33931&lt;/a&gt;: obfs4 bridges are used instead of meek if meek is selected in Tor Browser for Android alpha&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build System
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;All Platforms
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Go to 1.13.11&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/33380&quot;&gt;Bug 33380&lt;/a&gt;: Add *.json to sha256sums-unsigned-build.txt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Windows
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/33802&quot;&gt;Bug 33802&lt;/a&gt;: --enable-secure-api is not supported anymore in mingw-w64&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linux
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Android
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/28765&quot;&gt;Bug 28765&lt;/a&gt;: LibEvent Build for Android&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/28766&quot;&gt;Bug 28766&lt;/a&gt;: Tor Build for Android&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/28803&quot;&gt;Bug 28803&lt;/a&gt;: Integrate building Pluggable Transports for Android&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/30461&quot;&gt;Bug 30461&lt;/a&gt;: Clean up tor-android-service project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/32993&quot;&gt;Bug 32993&lt;/a&gt;: Package Tor With Tor Android Service Project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/33685&quot;&gt;Bug 33685&lt;/a&gt;: Add Support for Building zlib for Android&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 16:25:31 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ASVVVAD</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.torproject.org/new-release-tor-browser-95</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Microsoft Defender SmartScreen is hurting independent developers</title>
<link>https://getimageview.net/2020/06/02/microsoft-defender-smartscreen-is-hurting-independent-developers/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://getimageview.net/2020/06/02/microsoft-defender-smartscreen-is-hurting-independent-developers/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Let us say you are an independent developer and it is time to publish your app to the world. To make it easier, you build an installer and start distributing it. A courageous early adopter downloads and runs it, only to be greeted by this strongly worded warning:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://getimageview.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/smart_screen_windows_protected_your_pc.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-87&quot; srcset=&quot;https://getimageview.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/smart_screen_windows_protected_your_pc.png 534w, https://getimageview.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/smart_screen_windows_protected_your_pc-300x281.png 300w, https://getimageview.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/smart_screen_windows_protected_your_pc-320x300.png 320w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 534px) 100vw, 534px&quot;/&gt;Windows SmartScreen blocking an executable from running&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, in today’s Windows environment, Microsoft actively blocks binaries from running; thanks to “SmartScreen”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;But what is SmartScreen?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SmartScreen collects installation data from all Windows users in order to establish “reputation”. If the program does not have an established good reputation, you get this big warning message. By this time most users have deleted the .exe already thinking it is a malware, but SmartScreen can be bypassed by clicking on “More info” then “Run anyway”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The digital signature racket&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But how do you build reputation? First of all, Microsoft needs to be able to gather information on who has published the app, and this is done by a code signing certificate. The most obvious implication is that unsigned apps will always trigger SmartScreen. The more insidious implication is that acquiring a code signing certificate is a big expense for an individual developer. There is currently no “Let’s Encrypt” equivalent to code signing certificates; so you have to purchase it from trusted authorities. The price range is wide but a certificate only valid for a year will typically go for about $100.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://getimageview.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/code-sgining-cert-ssl-com-1024x866.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-88&quot; srcset=&quot;https://getimageview.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/code-sgining-cert-ssl-com-1024x866.png 1024w, https://getimageview.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/code-sgining-cert-ssl-com-300x254.png 300w, https://getimageview.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/code-sgining-cert-ssl-com-768x649.png 768w, https://getimageview.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/code-sgining-cert-ssl-com-355x300.png 355w, https://getimageview.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/code-sgining-cert-ssl-com.png 1134w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot;/&gt;SSL.com offer one of the “cheapest” code signing certs on the market, at $129 a year.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But let’s say you bite the bullet, you buy yourself an overpriced piece of prime numbers generated by a computer, sign your code and re-publish your application. You can now start getting users to install your app right? Wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Building reputation is a catch 22&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even with your newly digitally signed application, SmartScreen will still trigger. After all you are an unknown new publisher, and the “building up reputation” part of SmartScreen is a complete blackbox. So here’s the catch 22: to build up reputation, you need people to install your software so that Microsoft collects data. To get users to install your software, they need not be greeted by a message that strongly suggests your piece of code will harm their computers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It gets worse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you try to publish your piece of software with WinGet (in a nutshell: what will probably replace the Windows Store once it gets out of beta), you will get this message from Microsoft:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://getimageview.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/winget_smartscreen_error-1024x305.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-91&quot; srcset=&quot;https://getimageview.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/winget_smartscreen_error-1024x305.png 1024w, https://getimageview.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/winget_smartscreen_error-300x89.png 300w, https://getimageview.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/winget_smartscreen_error-768x229.png 768w, https://getimageview.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/winget_smartscreen_error-590x176.png 590w, https://getimageview.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/winget_smartscreen_error.png 1115w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot;/&gt;Microsoft WinGet considers triggering SmartScreen is an “error” and your software is classified as “malware”
&lt;p&gt;In the words of Microsoft, your application is considered a malware if it triggers SmartScreen. They link to a potential solution in the form of submitting your file for review through a dedicated link. If you follow all this process, this is the response you will get:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;wp-block-quote&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve reviewed your submission and we’ve confirmed that the submitted files are clean. Windows Defender Antivirus doesn’t report them as malware.&lt;br/&gt;The message you observed is a notification from Windows Defender SmartScreen indicating that the application does not have known reputation in our system.&lt;br/&gt;Application reputation warnings are meant to inform end users when applications do not have known positive reputation. This doesn’t mean that the application is malicious, only that it is “unknown”. Please note that users can still proceed to download and run the application.&lt;br/&gt;In most cases, a digitally signed application will establish reputation organically, unless something has happened to denigrate existing reputation such as being used to sign malware. We will investigate this issue further and contact you if we need additional information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In essence: your app is clean but we won’t do anything about the SmartScreen error. Our cloud bots overlords will decide when it is fine for you to be trusted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it still gets worse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s say you finally get accepted by the algorithms that be as a trusted publisher. Your certificate is about to expire and you renew it. Simple “business as usual” in the world of the Internet. In the world of Windows software though, that means that your reputation is reset back to nothing. Certificate renewal is not recognized by SmartScreen, it considers yourself as a new publisher again you have to go through this painful process yet another time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This can be mitigated by purchasing a certificate with a longer validity period, but at this point the cost simply becomes an insurmountable barrier for most independent developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;EV Code Signing Certificates&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For independent developers, this is the end of the road. For publishers, there is another solution: Extended Validation Code Signing Certificate. Signing code with one of these will automatically bypass SmartScreen. It is reserved for corporations only and as the name suggests it is subject to additional background checks done by certificate authorities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Digicert.com, a popular CA for code signing certificates, sells them for a whopping $699 a year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an independent developer, a solution would be to go through the troubles of incorporating a sole proprietary company and fork out the outrageous prices that these certificates command. Of course, that isn’t a realistic endeavor for most.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;“Developers, developers, developers!”&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://getimageview.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/ballmer-developers.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-100&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Developers, developers, developers!” was a cry from Steve Ballmer and one of the speeches that defined him as CEO of Microsoft. These infamous words were uttered back in 2006. Fourteen years later, under Satya Nadella, Microsoft is being praised for becoming more open than ever. Ironically, it seems that Microsoft made its Windows environment extremely hostile towards their beloved developers. A change in SmartScreen or on the way certificates work is needed to turn around this dire situation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 15:54:33 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>illuminated</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://getimageview.net/2020/06/02/microsoft-defender-smartscreen-is-hurting-independent-developers/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Lawmakers begin bipartisan push to cut off police access to military-style gear</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2020/06/01/us/politics/police-military-gear.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2020/06/01/us/politics/police-military-gear.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-158dogj evys1bk0&quot;&gt;WASHINGTON — Republicans and Democrats in Congress have begun a new push to shut down a Pentagon program that transfers military weaponry to local law enforcement departments, as bipartisan urgency builds to address the excessive use of force and the killings of unarmed black Americans by the police.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-158dogj evys1bk0&quot;&gt;With &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/news-event/george-floyd-protests-minneapolis-new-york-los-angeles&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;protests turning violent&lt;/a&gt; across the country, lawmakers are scrutinizing the Defense Department initiative — curtailed by former President Barack Obama but revived by President Trump — that furnishes police departments with equipment such as bayonets and grenade launchers. The move comes after several nights when officers wearing riot gear have been documented using pepper spray and rubber bullets on protesters, bystanders and journalists, &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2020/05/31/us/police-tactics-floyd-protests.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;often without warning or seemingly unprovoked.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-158dogj evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The push stands in stark contrast to the reaction of Mr. Trump, who has often encouraged rough tactics by law enforcement and spent Monday &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2020/06/01/us/politics/trump-governors.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;complaining privately to governors&lt;/a&gt; that they were not handling protesters aggressively enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-158dogj evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“Mayors and governors must establish an overwhelming presence until the violence is quelled,” Mr. Trump said in remarks from the Rose Garden on Monday evening. “If a city or state refuses to take the actions necessary to defend the life and property of their residents, then I will &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2020/06/02/us/politics/military-national-guard-trump-protests.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;deploy the United States military&lt;/a&gt; and quickly solve the problem for them.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-ew4tgv&quot; aria-label=&quot;companion column&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-158dogj evys1bk0&quot;&gt;On Capitol Hill, however, where Republicans often take their cues from the president, most lawmakers had a different message as they focused on the immediate catalyst for the protests: George Floyd, a black man in Minneapolis who was &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2020/05/31/us/george-floyd-investigation.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;killed after a police officer knelt on his neck&lt;/a&gt; for a prolonged period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-158dogj evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“In no world whatsoever should arresting a man for an alleged minor infraction involve a police officer putting his knee on the man’s neck for nine minutes while he cries out ‘I can’t breathe’ and then goes silent,” Senator Mitch McConnell, Republican of Kentucky and the majority leader, said on Monday. “Our nation cannot deafen itself to the anger, the pain and the frustration of black Americans. Our nation needs to hear this.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-158dogj evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Top lawmakers in both parties and on both sides of the Capitol moved quickly last week to &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2020/05/29/us/politics/congress-hearings-racial-violence-police-force.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;announce their intention to hold hearings&lt;/a&gt; on the use of excessive force by law enforcement and racial violence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;NYT_MAIN_CONTENT_1_REGION&quot; class=&quot;css-9tf9ac&quot;&gt;
&lt;section id=&quot;styln-nfldraft-updates-block&quot; class=&quot;css-l08pwh interactive-content interactive-size-medium&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;css-17ih8de interactive-body&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;styln-briefing-block&quot;&gt;



&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-158dogj evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Senator Brian Schatz, Democrat of Hawaii, who has long &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.paul.senate.gov/news/sens-rand-paul-and-brian-schatz-introduce-stop-militarizing-our-law-enforcement-act&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;pressed to limit the transfer of military-grade equipment&lt;/a&gt; to police departments, announced that he would move to include an amendment in the must-pass annual defense policy bill to shut down the program entirely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-158dogj evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“It is clear that many police departments are being outfitted as if they are going to war, and it is not working in terms of maintaining the peace,” Mr. Schatz said in an interview. “This is not the only thing we need to do, but as our country sees these images on television that remind us of some countries far, far away, it’s time to recalibrate this program. Just because the Department of Defense has excess weaponry doesn’t mean it will be put to good use.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-ew4tgv&quot; aria-label=&quot;companion column&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-158dogj evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Doug Stafford, Senator Rand Paul’s chief strategist, responded on Sunday night to Mr. Schatz’s idea: “We’ve being doing this one for years. Happy to help,” he wrote &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/dougstafford/status/1267260564834865152?s=20&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;. Mr. Paul has also been a longtime proponent of the demilitarization of local police and has previously teamed with Mr. Schatz to reform the Pentagon program, known as 1033.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-158dogj evys1bk0&quot;&gt;It is unclear how much support Mr. Schatz’s measure could receive in the Republican-controlled Senate. But in the House, Representative Ruben Gallego, Democrat of Arizona and a former Marine, &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/RepRubenGallego/status/1267552986642944001&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;said on Monday&lt;/a&gt; that he would introduce similar legislation, opening up the possibility that the measure could find additional traction in making its way into the final defense bill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-158dogj evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“As a combat veteran and proud Marine, very little of my equipment or training was relevant to policing Phoenix or other American communities,” Mr. Gallego said. “Our neighborhoods aren’t war zones.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-158dogj evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The program was created in the 1990s in an effort to offload surplus military equipment and aid police departments during the war on drugs. It expanded in the wake of the Sept. 11, 2001, attacks but came under heavy scrutiny in the aftermath of a string of high-profile deaths of black men at the hands of the police, including the shooting of Michael Brown, an unarmed 18-year-old, by a white police officer in Ferguson, Mo., in 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-158dogj evys1bk0&quot;&gt;In response to stark images of heavily armed police confronting unarmed protesters in armored vehicles in Ferguson, Mr. Obama &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://obamawhitehouse.archives.gov/sites/default/files/docs/federal_support_for_local_law_enforcement_equipment_acquisition.pdf&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;placed limits on that program in 2015&lt;/a&gt;, restricting the transfer of weapons, including battering rams and explosives, from the Pentagon to local police. The Pentagon &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/08/28/us/politics/trump-police-military-surplus-equipment.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;reported in 2017&lt;/a&gt; that 126 tracked armored vehicles, 138 grenade launchers and 1,623 bayonets had been returned since Mr. Obama prohibited their transfer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-158dogj evys1bk0&quot;&gt;But Mr. Trump rescinded those restrictions in 2017, opening the flow of equipment to police departments. He argued the gear was necessary for officers to protect themselves and their communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-158dogj evys1bk0&quot;&gt;On his call with governors on Monday, the president appeared to applaud the National Guard’s handling of the riots in Minneapolis, pointedly remarking on their use of tear gas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-ew4tgv&quot; aria-label=&quot;companion column&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-158dogj evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“They just walked right down the street, knocking them out with tear gas, tear gas,” Mr. Trump said. “These guys, they were running.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-158dogj evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Secretary of Defense Mark T. Esper used military language on the same call with governors, telling them, “we need to dominate the battle space,” and that they would have his full support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-158dogj evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Senator Cory Booker, Democrat of New Jersey, on Monday laid out a framework for a series of reforms he said he hoped the Senate would take up. It included creating a national police misconduct registry, incentivizing states to adopt policies banning the use of chokeholds and reforming a legal doctrine known as qualified immunity that shields police officers from being held legally liable for damages sought by citizens whose constitutional rights were violated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-158dogj evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“Cities are literally on fire with the pain and anguish wrought by the violence visited upon black and brown bodies,” Mr. Booker said. “There’s no one singular policy change that will fix this issue tomorrow. We need an entire set of holistic reforms to improve police training and practices, and ensure greater accountability and transparency.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-158dogj evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Representative Justin Amash, Independent of Michigan, said he would introduce a similar measure to strike down qualified immunity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-158dogj evys1bk0&quot;&gt;A pattern of “egregious police misconduct” has continued, Mr. Amash &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/justinamash/status/1267267244029083648&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;said in a letter to colleagues&lt;/a&gt;, “because police are legally, politically and culturally insulated from consequences for violating the rights of the people whom they have sworn to serve. This must change so that these incidents of brutality stop happening.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-ew4tgv&quot; aria-label=&quot;companion column&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 15:53:41 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>miles</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2020/06/01/us/politics/police-military-gear.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Lawmakers Begin Bipartisan Push to Cut Off Police Access to Military-Style Gear</og:title>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2020/06/01/us/politics/01dc-cong/01dc-cong-facebookJumbo-v3.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>The effort to end a program transferring surplus military equipment from the Pentagon to the police reflects a revived bipartisan concern about excessive use of force by law enforcement.</og:description>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2020/06/01/us/politics/police-military-gear.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Dust in the Light</title>
<link>https://stratechery.com/2020/dust-in-the-light/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://stratechery.com/2020/dust-in-the-light/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Everyone in Madison knew to avoid Badger Road.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was 1996, and the city was celebrating being christened the &lt;a href=&quot;https://money.cnn.com/magazines/moneymag/moneymag_archive/1996/07/01/214151/index.htm&quot;&gt;best place to live in America by Money Magazine&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://money.cnn.com/magazines/moneymag/moneymag_archive/1996/07/01/214151/index.htm&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/dust-light-6.png&quot; alt=&quot;Money Magazine declares Madison the best city in America&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;852&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-4993&quot; srcset=&quot;https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/dust-light-6.png 721w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/dust-light-6-225x300.png 225w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/dust-light-6-473x630.png 473w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year, Madison (and the rest of Dane County) earns the No. 1 position among the 300 biggest U.S. metropolitan areas in our 1996 Best Places to Live in America ranking. It snagged the top spot because apparently someone forgot to tell the folks in Madison that life is supposed to be full of trade-offs. The 390,300 residents of Dane County, 80 miles west of Milwaukee in south-central Wisconsin, have a vibrant economy with plentiful jobs, superb health care and a range of cultural activities usually associated with cities twice as big. Yet this mid-size metro area also offers up a low crime rate and palpable friendliness you might assume are available only in, say, Andy Griffith’s Mayberry. The news that the great Dane County is top dog this year probably won’t surprise the region’s residents. More than 90% of Madisonians rated their quality of life good or very good in a recent survey. Since the cosmopolitan Madison area — the city accounts for about half the county’s population — is surrounded by Wisconsin’s everpresent dairy farms, it seems only right to toast 1996’s No. 1 big cheese with a wedge of aged Wisconsin cheddar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, despite the excellent quality of life, most everyone had, at one time or another, been made aware that the neighborhoods around South Park Street were “dangerous”; that wasn’t such a big deal, though, because no one you knew ever went there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Madison’s Crescent&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2016, &lt;a href=&quot;https://fascinationhub.wordpress.com/2016/02/28/the-shocking-racial-gap-of-madison-wi/&quot;&gt;a blogger named Lew Blank&lt;/a&gt; observed that the racial distribution of Madison neighborhoods formed a crescent:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you look at Madison’s Racial Dot Map, you notice a pattern. The bottom and right sides of the map hold the majority of the black and hispanic population. It forms a curve almost – starting in the South Side, crossing along the east side of Lake Monona, and ending at the Northeast Side. I dub this curve-like chain of black and hispanic neighborhoods “The Crescent”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://fascinationhub.wordpress.com/2016/02/28/the-shocking-racial-gap-of-madison-wi/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/dust-light-7.png&quot; alt=&quot;Non-white neighborhoods in Madison form a crescent&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;417&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-4992&quot; srcset=&quot;https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/dust-light-7.png 806w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/dust-light-7-300x195.png 300w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/dust-light-7-768x500.png 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This crescent was also seen in poverty indicators:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shown below is a map of every single school in Madison with above average usage of free/reduced lunch programs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://fascinationhub.wordpress.com/2016/02/28/the-shocking-racial-gap-of-madison-wi/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/dust-light-2-1024x742.png&quot; alt=&quot;Schools with kids in poverty are in the crescent&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;464&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-4997&quot; srcset=&quot;https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/dust-light-2-1024x742.png 1024w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/dust-light-2-300x218.png 300w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/dust-light-2-768x557.png 768w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/dust-light-2-869x630.png 869w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/dust-light-2.png 1182w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s right. 23 out of 23 schools in Madison that have above average usage of free/reduced lunch programs all fall along the Crescent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The deal is, the children who need free/reduced lunch are poor, obviously. So does that mean that the poorest neighborhoods of Madison fall along the Crescent? Unfortunately, that’s exactly what it means.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Madison, a black child is 13 times more likely than a white child to be born into poverty – an insanely high disparity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://fascinationhub.wordpress.com/2016/02/28/the-shocking-racial-gap-of-madison-wi/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/dust-light-1-1024x405.png&quot; alt=&quot;Black children in Madison are much more likely to be born into poverty&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;253&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-4998&quot; srcset=&quot;https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/dust-light-1-1024x405.png 1024w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/dust-light-1-300x119.png 300w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/dust-light-1-768x304.png 768w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/dust-light-1.png 1074w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, Madison’s black and hispanic neighborhoods (the ones on the Crescent) are its poorest neighborhoods, and Madison’s white neighborhoods (the ones not on the Crescent) are its wealthiest neighborhoods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unsurprisingly, the crescent was also seen in educational outcomes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s clear, then, that schools in the Crescent of poor black/hispanic neighborhoods would be expected to have below-average academic success. And unfortunately, the map below of all Madison schools with below-average reading proficiency rates indicates that this is exactly the case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://fascinationhub.wordpress.com/2016/02/28/the-shocking-racial-gap-of-madison-wi/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/dust-light-3-1024x724.png&quot; alt=&quot;Schools in the crescent have worse performance&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;453&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-4996&quot; srcset=&quot;https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/dust-light-3-1024x724.png 1024w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/dust-light-3-300x212.png 300w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/dust-light-3-768x543.png 768w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/dust-light-3-891x630.png 891w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/dust-light-3.png 1248w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Believe it or not, 24 out of 24 schools with below-average reading proficiency rates fall along the Crescent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, of course, crime; I personally added the red box to Blank’s final map to indicate the Badger Road area I mentioned above:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The map below of the addresses of incarcerated Madisonians shows that incarceration in Madison tends to be clustered around the Crescent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://fascinationhub.wordpress.com/2016/02/28/the-shocking-racial-gap-of-madison-wi/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/dust-light-4-1024x940.png&quot; alt=&quot;Incarceration rates in Madison are worse in the crescent&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;588&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-4995&quot; srcset=&quot;https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/dust-light-4-1024x940.png 1024w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/dust-light-4-300x275.png 300w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/dust-light-4-768x705.png 768w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/dust-light-4-686x630.png 686w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/dust-light-4.png 1280w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was one map that Blank was missing though: the notorious Home Owners’ Loan Corporation map. The Home Owners’ Loan Corporation was a federal agency formed as part of President Franklin D. Roosevelt’s New Deal; its purpose was to refinance home mortgages, but as part of the process, the Corporation mapped out U.S. neighborhoods by risk, and by risk, HOLC all-too-frequently meant percentage of non-white people, particularly African Americans. Here was the map of Madison (laid on top of a current map in order to deliver the a north-is-up perspective):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://dsl.richmond.edu/panorama/redlining/#loc=12/43.07/-89.431&amp;amp;city=madison-wi&amp;amp;adview=full&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/dust-light-15-1024x888.png&quot; alt=&quot;The crescent matches Madison red-lining&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;555&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-5001&quot; srcset=&quot;https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/dust-light-15-1024x888.png 1024w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/dust-light-15-300x260.png 300w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/dust-light-15-768x666.png 768w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/dust-light-15-726x630.png 726w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/dust-light-15.png 1280w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you see the crescent, you can’t unsee it. And, relatedly, you can’t escape the impact on Madison. &lt;a href=&quot;https://madison.com/ct/news/local/govt-and-politics/none-of-this-has-changed-madisons-racial-disparities-have-gotten-worse-despite-decades-of-reports/article_0490a398-46f5-54ea-af5c-66ff1a32dfac.html&quot;&gt;In 2018&lt;/a&gt; African Americans made up 7% of the population but 43% of arrests and 46% of Dane County Jail inmates; African American students were 18% of the school district, but received 57% of suspensions; 10 percent of African American students received an “advanced” or “proficient” score on the math portion of &lt;a href=&quot;https://madison.com/ct/news/local/education/disparities-persist-in-madison-school-district-2018-19-test-scores/article_bd914359-5d5c-5487-852c-2926831c26be.html&quot;&gt;Wisconsin’s standardized testing&lt;/a&gt;, while 61% of white students did the same (the proportions were similar for all subjects). Meanwhile the &lt;a href=&quot;https://madison.com/wsj/news/local/govt-and-politics/madisons-average-home-value-tops-300-000/article_bb3095ae-f92d-5028-be3e-28572caef9f0.html&quot;&gt;average house price&lt;/a&gt; in the Burr Oaks neighborhood (which includes Badger Road) is $145,300; the Madison average is $300,967.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pattern is even worse in Milwaukee, Wisconsin’s largest city, and the most segregated city in the country; small wonder that Wisconsin ranks so highly when it comes to the disparity between black and white median household income:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.policymattersohio.org/research-policy/fair-economy/work-wages/race-in-the-heartland#source13&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/dust-light-9.png&quot; alt=&quot;Wisconsin has amongst the worst disparity between black and white median income&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;559&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-4990&quot; srcset=&quot;https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/dust-light-9.png 834w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/dust-light-9-300x262.png 300w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/dust-light-9-768x671.png 768w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/dust-light-9-721x630.png 721w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And poverty rates:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.policymattersohio.org/research-policy/fair-economy/work-wages/race-in-the-heartland#source13&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/dust-light-10-1024x697.png&quot; alt=&quot;Wisconsin has amongst the worst disparity between black and white poverty rates&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;436&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-4989&quot; srcset=&quot;https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/dust-light-10-1024x697.png 1024w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/dust-light-10-300x204.png 300w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/dust-light-10-768x523.png 768w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/dust-light-10-925x630.png 925w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/dust-light-10.png 1253w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.policymattersohio.org/research-policy/fair-economy/work-wages/race-in-the-heartland&quot;&gt;the paper from which these charts are drawn puts it&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Racial disparities in rewards and returns (opportunity, compensation, security) are matched by racial disparities in punishment…Five (WI, IA, MN, IL, NE) of the ten worst-performing states, ranked by the ratio between black and white rates, are in the Midwest. Such disparities, glaring in their own right, also have profound impacts on individuals, families and communities. Incarceration short circuits equal citizenship—the right to vote, educational and employment opportunities, access to housing—in deep and lasting ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.policymattersohio.org/research-policy/fair-economy/work-wages/race-in-the-heartland#source13&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/dust-light-11-1024x688.png&quot; alt=&quot;Wisconsin has amongst the worst disparity and black and white incarceration rates&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;430&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-4988&quot; srcset=&quot;https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/dust-light-11-1024x688.png 1024w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/dust-light-11-300x201.png 300w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/dust-light-11-768x516.png 768w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/dust-light-11-938x630.png 938w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/dust-light-11.png 1178w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The one state competing with Wisconsin for the highest measurements of disparity is the neighbor to the west: Minnesota.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Minneapolis and George Floyd&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While red-lining helped shape segregation in many cities, Minneapolis was pre-emptive about its discrimination; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.minnpost.com/metro/2019/02/with-covenants-racism-was-written-into-minneapolis-housing-the-scars-are-still-visible/&quot;&gt;beginning in the 1910s&lt;/a&gt; Minneapolis real estate deeds started to include “Covenants” that explicitly excluded African Americans. A &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mappingprejudice.org/index.html&quot;&gt;team from the University of Minnesota&lt;/a&gt; has been researching real estate deeds to uncover these covenants, and created this striking time-lapse of their spread:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Racial covenants were ruled unconstitutional by the Supreme Court in 1948, but the effect remains; compare the racial covenant map to the racial dot map Blank referenced above — the blue (which is white people) adheres to the blue of racial covenants:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/dust-light-5-1024x596.png&quot; alt=&quot;A map of racial covenants closely matches a map of Minneapolis' population&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;373&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-4994&quot; srcset=&quot;https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/dust-light-5-1024x596.png 1024w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/dust-light-5-300x175.png 300w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/dust-light-5-768x447.png 768w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/dust-light-5-1082x630.png 1082w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/dust-light-5.png 1280w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That red cross, meanwhile, is the location of the homicide of George Floyd, in the decidedly non-blue portion of the map. “Homicide” was the word used by the &lt;a href=&quot;https://content.govdelivery.com/attachments/MNHENNE/2020/06/01/file_attachments/1464238/2020-3700%20Floyd,%20George%20Perry%20Update%206.1.2020.pdf&quot;&gt;Hennepin County Medical Examiner&lt;/a&gt;, which ruled that Floyd’s cause of death was “Cardiopulmonary arrest complicating law enforcement subdual, restraint, and neck compression”; it is up to prosecutors and a jury to decide if that homicide constitutes murder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rest of the country did not take so long: nearly all have seen &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/video/us/100000007159353/george-floyd-arrest-death-video.html&quot;&gt;the video&lt;/a&gt; of Minneapolis police officer Derek Chauvin with his knee on Floyd’s neck for 8 minutes and 46 seconds, even as Floyd first complains he cannot breath, and then, for the final two minutes and 53 seconds, falls silent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Dust in the Air&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first version of the Hennepin County Medical Examiner’s autopsy, at least the part quoted in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/6933246-Derek-Chauvin-Complaint.html&quot;&gt;the criminal complaint against Chauvin&lt;/a&gt;, read a bit differently:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Hennepin County Medical Examiner (ME) conducted Mr. Floyd’s autopsy on May 26, 2020. The full report of the ME is pending but the ME has made the following preliminary findings. The autopsy revealed no physical findings that support a diagnosis of traumatic asphyxia or strangulation. Mr. Floyd had underlying health conditions including coronary artery disease and hypertensive heart disease. The combined effects of Mr. Floyd being restrained by the police, his underlying health conditions and any potential intoxicants in his system likely contributed to his death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The underlying health conditions and intoxicants are still in the final report; what has changed is their relative prominence in explaining Floyd’s death. One suspects that in a different world — say, the world that was Minneapolis for most of the 20th century — said underlying health conditions and intoxicants would have been held to be the cause of death, not “Other significant conditions.” Perhaps there would be a two paragraph story in the &lt;em&gt;Star Tribune&lt;/em&gt; on page A17, or more likely Floyd’s death would have disappeared into a police filing cabinet, a non-event as far as most of Minneapolis was concerned. At best there would be a murmur to avoid that sketchy Powderhorn neighborhood, a rarely-visited barely-remembered exception to Minneapolis’ status as one of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.travisneighborward.com/travel/best-cities-live-usa-2015/&quot;&gt;the best cities in America&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those who knew Floyd or witnessed his death would know better, of course. They would, as Kareem Abdul-Jabbar wrote in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.latimes.com/opinion/story/2020-05-30/dont-understand-the-protests-what-youre-seeing-is-people-pushed-to-the-edge&quot;&gt;Los Angeles Times&lt;/a&gt;, shout “Not @#$%! again!” Abdul-Jabbar explains:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;African Americans have been living in a burning building for many years, choking on the smoke as the flames burn closer and closer. Racism in America is like dust in the air. It seems invisible — even if you’re choking on it — until you let the sun in. Then you see it’s everywhere. As long as we keep shining that light, we have a chance of cleaning it wherever it lands. But we have to stay vigilant, because it’s always still in the air.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What made the Floyd story different than all of the surely similar examples that went before it is the Internet, specifically the combination of cameras on smartphones and social networks. The former means any incident can be recorded on a whim; the latter means that said recording can be spread worldwide instantly. That is exactly what happened with the Floyd homicide: the initial video was captured on a smartphone and posted on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/darnellareallprettymarie/videos/1425398217661280/&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, triggering a level of attention to the Floyd case that in all likelihood changed the nature of the autopsy and led to the pressing of charges against Chauvin — a chance, in Abdul-Jabbar’s words, of cleaning at least one spec of that omnipresent dust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Trump’s Tweets&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notably, this is not why Facebook is in the news this week; yesterday hundreds of employees staged a virtual walkout to protest the fact that the company committed, in their mind, a sin of omission: not deleting posts from President Trump. Those posts are copies of Trump tweets, three of which Twitter modified in some way last week. The first two were Trump allegations that voting by mail had a high risk of fraud; &lt;a href=&quot;https://stratechery.com/2020/twitter-and-trump-youtube-and-china-facebook-and-polarization/&quot;&gt;Twitter attached&lt;/a&gt; a “Get the facts” label that led to a page disputing Trump’s claim.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The more serious intervention came early Friday morning, when Twitter obscured a Trump tweet because it, in their determination, “violated the Twitter Rules about glorifying violence.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/realDonaldTrump/status/1266231100780744704&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/dust-light-13-1024x324.png&quot; alt=&quot;Twitter obscured a Trump tweet&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;203&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-4986&quot; srcset=&quot;https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/dust-light-13-1024x324.png 1024w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/dust-light-13-300x95.png 300w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/dust-light-13-768x243.png 768w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/dust-light-13.png 1194w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twitter — at least as far as citing its rules is concerned — apparently objected to the phrase “when the looting starts, the shooting starts,” which is associated with a brutal segregationist police chief &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/2020/05/29/864818368/the-history-behind-when-the-looting-starts-the-shooting-starts&quot;&gt;from Miami&lt;/a&gt;; Trump claimed to not know the saying’s history, but honestly, arguing about that phrase feels like a distraction from Trump’s all-capitalization use of the descriptor “thugs”, a word with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/2015/04/30/403362626/the-racially-charged-meaning-behind-the-word-thug&quot;&gt;significant racial undertones&lt;/a&gt;. That certainly seemed to be what the protesting Facebook employees picked up on; from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2020/06/01/technology/facebook-employee-protest-trump.html&quot;&gt;New York Times&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The hateful rhetoric advocating violence against black demonstrators by the US President does not warrant defense under the guise of freedom of expression,” one Facebook employee wrote in an internal message board, according to a copy of the text viewed by The New York Times. The employee added: “Along with Black employees in the company, and all persons with a moral conscience, I am calling for Mark to immediately take down the President’s post advocating violence, murder and imminent threat against Black people.” The Times agreed to withhold the employee’s name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is notable about that New York Times story is that it reproduces the post (and tweet!) that the employees want taken down:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2020/06/01/technology/facebook-employee-protest-trump.html&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/dust-light-12-741x1024.png&quot; alt=&quot;The New York Times published the post and tweets many want banned&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;884&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-4987&quot; srcset=&quot;https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/dust-light-12-741x1024.png 741w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/dust-light-12-217x300.png 217w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/dust-light-12-768x1061.png 768w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/dust-light-12-1112x1536.png 1112w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/dust-light-12-456x630.png 456w, https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/dust-light-12.png 1280w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So did the story I linked to above about that Miami police chief, and countless other publications. Indeed, it seems rather obvious that Twitter’s action — and those objecting to Facebook’s lack of action — ensured that Trump’s tweet would be far more widely read than it might have been otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is not clear that this is a bad thing. Trump’s tweet is abominable, but sadly, of a piece with far too many presidents. &lt;a href=&quot;https://apnews.com/b0fe304f1fad44e19e5ff4490ad1110c&quot;&gt;The Associated Press wrote in 2019&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout American history, presidents have uttered comments, issued decisions and made public and private moves that critics said were racist, either at the time or in later generations. The presidents did so both before taking office and during their time in the White House…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This extends far beyond the founding fathers, most of whom owned slaves, to the 20th century:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Virginia-born Woodrow Wilson worked to keep blacks out of Princeton University while serving as that school’s president…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Democrat Lyndon Johnson assumed the presidency in 1963 after the assassination of John F. Kennedy and sought to push a civil rights bill amid demonstrations by African Americans…But according to tapes of his private conversations, Johnson routinely used racist epithets to describe African Americans and some blacks he appointed to key positions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His successor, Republican Richard Nixon, also regularly used racist epithets while in office in private conversations…As with Johnson, many of Nixon’s remarks were unknown to the general public until tapes of White House conversations were released decades later. Recently the Nixon Presidential Library released an October 1971 phone conversation between Nixon and then California Gov. Ronald Reagan, another future president…Reagan, in venting his frustration with United Nations delegates who voted against the U.S., dropped some racist language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The part about secret tapes is notable: much of this racism — this dust in the air — was in darkened rooms, unseen by the public. Trump, if nothing else, has no need for secret tapes: we have his very public Twitter account, and all indications, particularly in terms of pre-COVID polling, suggest that it &lt;a href=&quot;https://fivethirtyeight.com/features/trump-may-be-even-more-unpopular-than-his-approval-rating-shows/&quot;&gt;massively weakened&lt;/a&gt; his reelection bid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The president’s threats, meanwhile, continue: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/trump-pushes-governors-to-get-tough-on-violent-protesters-11591026977&quot;&gt;yesterday&lt;/a&gt; Trump demanded governors around the country crack down on the looting that has in several cities followed peaceful protests, saying he would call in the military otherwise. That certainly seems to be, in broad strokes, in line with the tweet Twitter hid — does it matter that Trump stated his position on a conference call and in the Rose Garden instead of a tweet?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, that is what is so striking about the demands that Facebook act on this particular post (beyond the extremely problematic prospect of an unaccountable figure like Zuckerberg unilaterally deciding what is and is not acceptable political speech): the preponderance of evidence suggests that these demands have nothing to do with misinformation, but rather reality. The United States really does have a president named Donald Trump who uses extremely problematic terms — in all caps! — for African Americans and quotes segregationist police chiefs, and social media, for better or worse, is ultimately a reflection of humanity. Facebook deleting Trump’s post won’t change that fact, but it will, at least for a moment, turn out the lights, hiding the dust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;A Gargantuan Force&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is hard to be optimistic about anything at this moment in time. My regular refrain from the beginning of the coronavirus crisis is that the most likely outcome will be the acceleration of trends that were already happening. That is particularly scary given what I wrote back when Stratechery started in 2013, in a post called &lt;a href=&quot;https://stratechery.com/2013/friction/&quot;&gt;Friction&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Count me with those who believe the Internet is on par with the industrial revolution, the full impact of which stretched over centuries. And it wasn’t all good. Like today, the industrial revolution included a period of time that saw many lose their jobs and a massive surge in inequality. It also lifted millions of others out of sustenance farming. Then again, it also propagated slavery, particularly in North America. The industrial revolution led to new monetary systems, and it created robber barons. Modern democracies sprouted from the industrial revolution, and so did fascism and communism. The quality of life of millions and millions was unimaginably improved, and millions and millions died in two unimaginably terrible wars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another comparison point is the printing press, which I wrote about &lt;a href=&quot;https://stratechery.com/2019/the-internet-and-the-third-estate/&quot;&gt;last year&lt;/a&gt; in the context of Facebook:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just as important, though, particularly in terms of the impact on society, is the drastic reduction in fixed costs. Not only can existing publishers reach anyone, anyone can become a publisher. Moreover, they don’t even need a publication: social media gives everyone the means to broadcast to the entire world. Read again Zuckerberg’s description of the Fifth Estate:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People having the power to express themselves at scale is a new kind of force in the world — a Fifth Estate alongside the other power structures of society. People no longer have to rely on traditional gatekeepers in politics or media to make their voices heard, and that has important consequences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is difficult to overstate how much of an understatement that is. I just recounted how the printing press effectively overthrew the First Estate, leading to the establishment of nation-states and the creation and empowerment of a new nobility. The implication of overthrowing the Second Estate, via the empowerment of commoners, is almost too radical to imagine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yet, look again at this past week: a century of institutionalized racism in Minneapolis was not necessarily overthrown, but certainly overwhelmed in the case of George Floyd, because of a post on Facebook. Both peaceful protests and wanton destruction and looting were likely organized on social media. Video of both were circulated around the world via ubiquitous smartphone cameras on said social networks. The Internet is an amoral force — it can effect both positive and negative outcomes — but what cannot be underestimated is how gargantuan a force it is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To that end, while there is much to fear, there is room for hope as well. I am grateful that I can no longer unsee Madison’s crescent, thanks to a blog post. I am angered by the video of Floyd’s death, and appalled at the dust in the air that yes, I was privileged enough to avoid without a second thought. And no matter what upheaval lies ahead, I am certain that the light that illuminates that dust so brightly can never be put away. There are no more gatekeepers, oftentimes for worse, but also for better.&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 15:42:51 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>zwieback</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Dust in the Light</og:title>
<og:url>https://stratechery.com/2020/dust-in-the-light/</og:url>
<og:description>The Internet ends gatekeepers and increases transparency, which has world-altering effects — both good and bad.</og:description>
<og:image>https://stratechery.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/dust-light-15.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://stratechery.com/2020/dust-in-the-light/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Papers with Code</title>
<link>https://paperswithcode.com/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://paperswithcode.com/</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;author-section&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;author-name-text&quot;&gt;1 Jun 2020&lt;/span&gt; • &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/deepmind/acme&quot; onclick=&quot;captureOutboundLink('https://github.com/deepmind/acme'); return true;&quot;&gt;deepmind/acme&lt;/a&gt; • &lt;img src=&quot;https://paperswithcode.com/static/frameworks/jax.f5241005b2fb.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;item-strip-abstract&quot;&gt;Ultimately, we show that the design decisions behind Acme lead to agents that can be scaled both up and down and that, for the most part, greater levels of parallelization result in agents with equivalent performance, just faster.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 15:19:39 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>xzvf</dc:creator>
<og:title>Papers with Code - The latest in machine learning</og:title>
<og:description>Papers With Code highlights trending ML research and the code to implement it.</og:description>
<og:image>https://paperswithcode.com/static/index.jpeg</og:image>
<og:url>https://paperswithcode.com/</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://paperswithcode.com/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Lawsuit over online book lending could bankrupt Internet Archive</title>
<link>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2020/06/publishers-sue-internet-archive-over-massive-digital-lending-program/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2020/06/publishers-sue-internet-archive-over-massive-digital-lending-program/</guid>
<description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/GettyImages-1217253028-800x564.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A laminated sign which reads &quot; book=&quot;&quot; drops=&quot;&quot; are=&quot;&quot; adorns=&quot;&quot; a=&quot;&quot; metal=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;caption-text&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/GettyImages-1217253028.jpg&quot; class=&quot;enlarge-link&quot; data-height=&quot;3165&quot; data-width=&quot;4493&quot;&gt;Enlarge&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;sep&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; The book drop outside the Spring Township library in Pennsylvania was closed on April 6, 2020.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;aside id=&quot;social-left&quot; class=&quot;social-left&quot; aria-label=&quot;Read the comments or share this article&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;comment-count-before&quot;&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;104 posters participating&quot; class=&quot;comment-count icon-comment-bubble-down&quot; href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2020/06/publishers-sue-internet-archive-over-massive-digital-lending-program/?comments=1&quot;&gt;reader comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;a title=&quot;104 posters participating&quot; class=&quot;comment-count icon-comment-bubble-down&quot; href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2020/06/publishers-sue-internet-archive-over-massive-digital-lending-program/?comments=1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;comment-count-number&quot;&gt;174&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;visually-hidden&quot;&gt;with 104 posters participating&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;share-links&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Share this story&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;Four of the nation's leading book publishers have sued the Internet Archive, the online library best known for maintaining the Internet Wayback Machine. The Internet Archive makes scanned copies of books—both public domain and under copyright—available to the public on a site called the Open Library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Despite the Open Library moniker, IA's actions grossly exceed legitimate library services, do violence to the Copyright Act, and constitute willful digital piracy on an industrial scale,&quot; write publishers Hachette, HarperCollins, Wiley, and Penguin Random House in their complaint. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.nysd.537900/gov.uscourts.nysd.537900.1.0.pdf&quot;&gt;lawsuit&lt;/a&gt; was filed in New York federal court on Monday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For almost a decade, the Open Library has offered users the ability to &quot;borrow&quot; scans of in-copyright books via the Internet. Until recently, the service was based on a concept called &quot;controlled digital lending&quot; that mimicked the constraints of a conventional library. The library would only &quot;lend&quot; as many digital copies of a book as it had physical copies in its warehouse. If all copies of a book were &quot;checked out&quot; by other patrons, you'd have to join a waiting list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In March, as the coronavirus pandemic was gaining steam, the Internet Archive announced it was &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2020/03/internet-archive-offers-thousands-of-copyrighted-books-for-free-online/&quot;&gt;dispensing&lt;/a&gt; with this waiting-list system. Under a program it called the National Emergency Library, IA began allowing an unlimited number of people to check out the same book at the same time—even if IA only owned one physical copy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before this change, publishers largely looked the other way as IA and a few other libraries experimented with the digital lending concept. Some publishers' groups condemned the practice, but no one filed a lawsuit over it. Perhaps the publishers feared setting an adverse precedent if the courts ruled that CDL was legal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the IA's emergency lending program was harder for publishers to ignore. So this week, as a number of states have been lifting quarantine restrictions, the publishers sued the Internet Archive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an email to Ars Technica, IA founder Brewster Kahle described the lawsuit as &quot;disappointing.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;As a library, the Internet Archive acquires books and lends them, as libraries have always done,&quot; he wrote. &quot;Publishers suing libraries for lending books, in this case, protected digitized versions, and while schools and libraries are closed, is not in anyone's interest.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;“The publishers have a pretty strong case”&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The publishers' legal argument is straightforward: the Internet Archive is making and distributing copies of books without permission from copyright holders. That's generally illegal unless a defendant can show it is authorized by one of copyright law's various exceptions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Legal experts tell Ars that the Internet's Archive's best response is to argue that its program is fair use. That's a flexible legal doctrine that has been used to justify a wide range of copying over the decades—from recording television broadcasts for personal use to quoting a few sentences of a book in a review. Most relevant for our purposes, the courts have &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2013/11/google-books-ruled-legal-in-massive-win-for-fair-use/&quot;&gt;held&lt;/a&gt; that it is a fair use to scan books for limited purposes such as building a book search engine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When considering a fair use claim, courts consider several factors, including the impact of the use on the market for the original work. A book search engine, for example, is not a substitute for reading books but, rather, helps readers find new books they might want to buy. This is one of the reasons the courts found that book scanning for a search engine was legal under fair use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it's harder to come up with compelling arguments that the Internet Archive's open-ended lending program is fair use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;James Grimmelmann, a copyright scholar at Cornell University, told Ars that he is withholding judgment until he sees the Internet Archive's response. However, he said, &quot;it seems like the publishers have a pretty strong case.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;I think there are arguments for fair use, but they're not terribly strong arguments,&quot; he said in a Monday phone interview.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;A pandemic exception?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Internet Archive would have had a stronger argument if it had continued to limit the number of copies that could be lent out. In that scenario, IA could argue that the program's impact on the market was little different from a conventional library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously, a patron who checks out a book from a library is less likely to purchase a copy, undermining the market for the book. On the other hand, libraries themselves buy many books—and the more popular a book is, the more copies libraries must buy. So the overall impact of libraries on demand for books is not clear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But once the IA stopped buying a copy of a book for every copy it lent out, this argument became a lot weaker. An institution like AI can buy a single copy of a book and then &quot;lend&quot; it to dozens, hundreds, or thousands of people at the same time. There's little doubt that this has a negative impact on the market for new books.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, the Internet Archive will likely need to make a more novel argument—that the unique circumstances of a pandemic justifies allowing types of infringement that would be clearly illegal at other times. Grimmelmann wasn't able to identify any other cases where courts have made that kind of leap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also spoke to John Bergmayer, a copyright expert at the copyright reform group Public Knowledge. He said there was a &quot;pretty strong fair use argument&quot; for both the Internet Archive's previous controlled digital lending program and its new approach without waiting lists. Bergmayer pointed to the fact that millions of books are currently locked up in libraries that have been closed due to the pandemic. That, he said, creates a unique situation that could justify digital lending activities that would otherwise be illegal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But like Grimmelmann, Bergmayer couldn't name any specific court decisions that back up IA's aggressive interpretation of copyright law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The stakes are high&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Grimmelmann was fairly bullish on the publishers' legal prospects, he disagreed with one aspect of the industry's argument. The Internet Archive is officially a non-profit, but the publishers' lawsuit portrays the group as effectively a commercial operation profiting from copyright infringement. It points out that IA has earned millions of dollars from contracts to scan books on behalf of partners such as other libraries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Grimmelmann told Ars that this fundamentally misunderstands the motivations of Brewster Kahle, the founder of Internet Archive and still its driving force.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Brewster Kahle is what the Russians might call a holy fool—someone who acts without real regard for himself or for worldly things in the service of a higher calling,&quot; Grimmelmann said. The Internet Archive &quot;is not a commercial venture,&quot; he argued. Grimmelmann believes that Kahle, a 1990s dot-com entrepreneur who has sunk millions of dollars into the Internet Archive, is fundamentally an idealist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Kahle's idealism—or foolishness—might cost him dearly. Copyright law allows statutory damages as high as $150,000 per work for willful infringement. And Grimmelmann tells Ars that if the publishers win the case, they'll have a strong case that the infringement was willful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Internet Archive has scanned more than a million books that are still under copyright, so a loss could easily lead to billions of dollars in damages—far beyond the non-profit's ability to pay. So if the publishers win the lawsuit, they could force the Internet Archive out of business. That would be an incalculable loss given the group's work archiving other types of content, including the early Web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the publishers may not be interested in forcing the Internet Archive out of business. Their goal is to get the Internet Archive to stop scanning their books. If they win the lawsuit, they might force the group to shut down its book scanning operation and promise to not start it up again, then allow it to continue its other, less controversial offerings.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 14:55:02 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>nixass</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2020/06/publishers-sue-internet-archive-over-massive-digital-lending-program/</og:url>
<og:title>Lawsuit over online book lending could bankrupt Internet Archive</og:title>
<og:image>https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/GettyImages-1217253028-760x380.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>Publishers call online library “willful digital piracy on an industrial scale.”</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2020/06/publishers-sue-internet-archive-over-massive-digital-lending-program/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Snakeware – Linux distro with Python userspace inspired by Commodore 64</title>
<link>https://github.com/joshiemoore/snakeware</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/joshiemoore/snakeware</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;snakeware is a free Linux distro with a Python userspace inspired by the Commodore 64. You are booted directly into a Python interpreter, which you can use to do whatever you want with your computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our designated IRC channel is &lt;code&gt;#snakeware&lt;/code&gt; on &lt;code&gt;irc.rizon.net&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=d7zD9zmZvbQ&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Check out our latest demo on YouTube!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/joshiemoore/snakeware/blob/master/screenshot.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/joshiemoore/snakeware/raw/master/screenshot.png&quot; alt=&quot;snakeware/snakewm running in QEMU&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Motivation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea is that a Python OS would be fun to use and very easy to contribute to. Even relative beginners might be able to find ways to meaningfully contribute apps and other code to this distro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our window manager, snakewm, is based on pygame/pygame_gui. We do not use X11; snakewm draws directly to &lt;code&gt;/dev/fb0&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also are not going to be using any other huge and opaque software such as systemd, etc. The goal is to eventually have a usable set of userspace apps and utilities written entirely in Python, because Python is fun and it Just Werks™.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Running&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/joshiemoore/snakeware/releases&quot;&gt;Download the latest release image.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, burn the image file to a flash drive and boot it, or launch it in QEMU. Here is how I start it in QEMU, it works pretty well for me:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;qemu-system-x86_64 -drive format=raw,file=snakeware.img -m 2048 -soundhw hda -audiodev id=pa,driver=pa&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you are booted into the Python environment, launch snakewm with these commands:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; from snakewm.wm import SnakeWM
&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; SnakeWM().run()
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Press the Left WinKey to open the App Menu!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Building&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The snakeware build system is based on buildroot. See the &lt;code&gt;snakeware/&lt;/code&gt; directory in this repo for resources and documentation on how to build your own snakeware distro image.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE:&lt;/strong&gt; If you are only contributing apps or other code to snakewm, you don't need to build a whole snakeware distro image to test your changes. Simply make your changes to snakewm then run &lt;code&gt;sudo python wm.py&lt;/code&gt; in the &lt;code&gt;snakewm/&lt;/code&gt; directory. snakewm will then start drawing itself directly to the framebuffer and you can test out your changes. Press &lt;code&gt;ALT+ESC&lt;/code&gt; to return to your normal desktop. (It would still be good to test your changes in an actual snakeware environment though.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developers of all experience levels are welcome and encouraged to contribute to snakeware. Python enthusiasts that are familiar with pygame and pygame_gui will be able to write their own snakeware apps very easily. See existing apps in &lt;code&gt;snakewm/apps/&lt;/code&gt; for examples of how to get started, and feel free to ask questions if you need help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those with experience building Linux systems are encouraged to contribute to the underlying aspects of the distro, such as the build/package scripts and configuration for the kernel, GRUB, etc. The build system is currently not very streamlined or robust, and I am sure that there are better ways to do a lot of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would also like to eventually stop using Busybox for intialization and find a way to perform all necessary init from the Python environment, so ideas about that are welcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;TODO&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an abridged list of future plans:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Raspberry Pi configs for buildroot and kernel!!!!!!!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix pip module installation - won't work when cross-compiling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many more snakewm apps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;App menu for choosing apps to run&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;Improved/streamlined build system&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved kernel config&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;snake-games - full-screen user games separate from SnakeWM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;Modify partition scheme for faster boot - /usr on its own partition?&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take advantage of pygame_gui's theme functionality&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dynamic/interactive desktop backgrounds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;Sound support&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Networking -&amp;gt; web browser
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;snakechat - chat with everyone else who's using snakeware&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gopher client?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ditch busybox, init via Python somehow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;...&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 14:29:24 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>AnIdiotOnTheNet</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars0.githubusercontent.com/u/36491773?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>joshiemoore/snakeware</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/joshiemoore/snakeware</og:url>
<og:description>A free Linux distro with a fully Python userspace. Contribute to joshiemoore/snakeware development by creating an account on GitHub.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/joshiemoore/snakeware</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>