<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>For back pain, the subtle moves of the Feldenkrais Method can help some people</title>
<link>https://www.washingtonpost.com/national/health-science/a-different-way-to-relieve-years-of-back-pain/2018/09/27/f3e663f4-b505-11e8-a2c5-3187f427e253_story.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.washingtonpost.com/national/health-science/a-different-way-to-relieve-years-of-back-pain/2018/09/27/f3e663f4-b505-11e8-a2c5-3187f427e253_story.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div data-elm-loc=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;inline-content inline-photo inline-photo-normal&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/kQY-UhzZnJRD_FjJSzwCniPHMZQ=/480x0/arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/YAK2QXFULYI6RLSPFQKDTSLNPE.jpg&quot; data-hi-res-src=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/Qx8SgJEqXg6Eu-8LDs4GITDtpvQ=/1484x0/arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/YAK2QXFULYI6RLSPFQKDTSLNPE.jpg&quot; data-low-res-src=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/kQY-UhzZnJRD_FjJSzwCniPHMZQ=/480x0/arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/YAK2QXFULYI6RLSPFQKDTSLNPE.jpg&quot; data-raw-src=&quot;https://arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/YAK2QXFULYI6RLSPFQKDTSLNPE.jpg&quot; data-threshold=&quot;480&quot; class=&quot;unprocessed&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pb-caption&quot;&gt;A student practices Feldenkrais in a class led by Chrish Kresge in her studio in Northwest Washington. The method seeks to retrain the mind and body. It involves slow, sometimes tiny movements of the shoulders, neck, hips, legs and ribs. (Calla Kessler/The Washington Post)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;author-sig-line-wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author-sig-line&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author-byline&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author-wrapper&quot; data-authorname=&quot;Lisa Rein&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;author-hover-card&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author-headshot&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/people/lisa-rein/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/T_NBA8YjVPhu52yT_UvY_WfzjK4=/200x200/s3.amazonaws.com/arc-authors/washpost/866274de-0703-42f2-b1c9-8c69f69ed1de.png&quot; class=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;author-name&quot; href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/people/lisa-rein/&quot;&gt;Lisa Rein&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author-bio&quot;&gt;Reporter covering federal agencies and the management of government in the Trump administration&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;author-timestamp&quot; itemprop=&quot;datePublished&quot; content=&quot;2018-09-27T01:15-500&quot;&gt;September 27&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;1&quot;&gt;In my first Feldenkrais class, we lay on our backs with eyes closed and drifted our eyeballs left to right and back again. We shifted our heads from side to side as our eyes followed in their sockets. Then we changed it up, moving our eyes in the opposite direction from our heads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;2&quot;&gt;This may sound like a simple sequence. It’s deceptively challenging. And it continued for an hour, with sitting variations, eyes alternately open and shut, a brain workout that included tracking our thumbs as our bent arms moved at eye level from left to right and back again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;3&quot;&gt;These eye calisthenics were supposed to relieve my years of back pain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;4&quot;&gt;Yeah, right, I remember thinking that Sunday morning 18 months ago as I felt an odd exhaustion set in. Slow and subtle was harder than I thought. I fidgeted. My eyes grew tired. How was all of this commotion under my lids supposed to stop my right hip from unnecessary rotation when I walked and unfreeze my left shoulder and neck?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;5&quot;&gt;I had tried the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.feldenkrais.com/about-the-feldenkrais-method/&quot;&gt;Feldenkrais Method&lt;/a&gt; under some duress. Although there aren’t a lot of good studies, my friend Jon told me it had reduced his lower back pain from excruciating to manageable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;6&quot;&gt;Too many chiropractors, osteopaths, yoga classes, trainers, acupuncturists and ibuprofen over 30 years of back pain. They had at best given me only temporary relief — or sometimes more pain. Feldenkrais sounded too nuanced, with its slow and subtle movements that were supposed to retrain how I walked, sat or held myself as I typed a story on my computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;7&quot;&gt;I had convinced myself that my diagnosis — osteoarthritis in my neck, a mild scoliosis in my lower back and a genetic weakness inherited from my father, whose severely S-curved spine led to a life of pain — would not be cured by yet another approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;8&quot;&gt;Finally, after a particularly bad stretch and pressure from my husband, who was impatient with my constant complaints, I capitulated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;9&quot;&gt;And at the end of that first class, I was surprised: I felt a little different, lighter. I could turn my neck a bit more to the left. My right hip moved more freely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div data-elm-loc=&quot;10&quot; class=&quot;inline-content inline-photo inline-photo-normal&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/TXJKur-cQ3m4AF9lqk_kkjfemkk=/3x2/www.washingtonpost.com/pb/resources/img/spacer.gif&quot; data-hi-res-src=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/_YJqKM1owsYc4tebZs9kzraKbYg=/1484x0/arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/VCD55RVULYI6RLSPFQKDTSLNPE.jpg&quot; data-low-res-src=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/zlRIp_D-IefdUW-ztfSNBxFa0dc=/480x0/arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/VCD55RVULYI6RLSPFQKDTSLNPE.jpg&quot; data-raw-src=&quot;https://arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/VCD55RVULYI6RLSPFQKDTSLNPE.jpg&quot; data-threshold=&quot;480&quot; class=&quot;unprocessed _3-to-2 placeholder&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pb-caption&quot;&gt;Kresge leads one of her classes. “Undoing patterns often means telling the body to try not to try, to do less so you can feel more,” said Kresge, a musical-theater buff who discovered the method in the 1980s to help free her singing voice. (Calla Kessler/The Washington Post)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div data-elm-loc=&quot;11&quot; class=&quot;inline-content inline-photo inline-photo-double&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;left&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/TXJKur-cQ3m4AF9lqk_kkjfemkk=/3x2/www.washingtonpost.com/pb/resources/img/spacer.gif&quot; data-hi-res-src=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/nuEmP7CmB9B5ih2n21A9DC2Shv8=/742x0/arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/XM5ITTVULYI6RLSPFQKDTSLNPE.jpg&quot; data-low-res-src=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/wLLMevbYPnPd5oHAzQ_49ZCvrFw=/240x0/arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/XM5ITTVULYI6RLSPFQKDTSLNPE.jpg&quot; data-raw-src=&quot;https://arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/XM5ITTVULYI6RLSPFQKDTSLNPE.jpg&quot; data-threshold=&quot;240&quot; class=&quot;unprocessed _3-to-2 placeholder&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pb-caption&quot;&gt;Students recline on mats with their arms outstretched in Kresge’s class. Moshé Feldenkrais, a Russian-born physicist, had developed the technique after World War II. (Calla Kessler/The Washington Post)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;right&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pb-caption&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/TXJKur-cQ3m4AF9lqk_kkjfemkk=/3x2/www.washingtonpost.com/pb/resources/img/spacer.gif&quot; data-hi-res-src=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/hc65JPG7s6-HDEWVYplonZ1wXvA=/742x0/arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/UOOLQCVULYI6RLSPFQKDTSLNPE.jpg&quot; data-low-res-src=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/fs2OEkRO-YDpuXBj0_O9sJIn-K0=/240x0/arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/UOOLQCVULYI6RLSPFQKDTSLNPE.jpg&quot; data-raw-src=&quot;https://arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/UOOLQCVULYI6RLSPFQKDTSLNPE.jpg&quot; data-threshold=&quot;240&quot; class=&quot;unprocessed _3-to-2 placeholder&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pb-caption&quot;&gt;People lift their arms during a class led by Kresge. There are now 1,300 certified Feldenkrais teachers in the United States and about 14,000 in 22 other countries. (Calla Kessler/The Washington Post)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;12&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pb-caption&quot;&gt;Yet this made no sense to me, as the class involved no hip stretching. All of those eye motions, with my lids open and shut, had somehow freed up my body.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;13&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pb-caption&quot;&gt;And that, it turns out, was the point. Eye movements play a vital role in coordinating the body’s musculature, particularly in how the neck muscles contract, one of Feldenkrais’s many counterintuitive approaches to learning to move differently, teacher Chrish Kresge says.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;14&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pb-caption&quot;&gt;Or as Moshé Feldenkrais (1904-1984), the Russian-born physicist, engineer and judo master who developed the technique to deal with his own pain from a debilitating knee injury, writes in his book, “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0062503227?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=washpost-20&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;linkCode=xm2&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0062503227&quot;&gt;Awareness Through Movement&lt;/a&gt;,” “The eyes are not only for seeing.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;15&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pb-caption&quot;&gt;Like shifting the shoulders, ankles, pelvis, spring and limbs in certain ways, exercising your eyes can improve the organization of the entire trunk, he writes, by moving in ways that are not habitual and make you aware of how other parts of your body respond.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pb-caption&quot;&gt;Nearly 65 years after he began teaching it (post-World War II, in his adopted home of Israel), Feldenkrais’s method is finally having its moment. There are now 1,300 certified teachers in the United States and about 14,000 in 22 other countries, including China, Australia, Russia and Germany, where the method is most popular, according to the Feldenkrais Guild of North America. &lt;span&gt;(A major &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.feldenkrais.com/2018-conference/&quot;&gt;gathering&lt;/a&gt; of Feldenkrais practitioners, open to the public at the National 4-H Conference Center in Chevy Chase, Md., ends Sunday.)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;17&quot;&gt;Way before the idea of a mind-body connection became a popular health concept, Feldenkrais promoted his technique’s potential to lead us away from bad physical habits that cause tension and pain and to restore the body’s capacity for efficient, flexible, coordinated movement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;18&quot;&gt;The brain, he maintained, can be retrained to reorganize the way we move our bodies, eliminating unnecessary and harmful patterns. For example, the Feldenkrais road map involves slow, sometimes tiny movements of the shoulders, neck, hips, legs and ribs. These movements help us perceive what feels good and what causes pain, and prod the brain into giving our bodies new feedback, leading to a better division of labor among our muscles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div data-elm-loc=&quot;19&quot; class=&quot;inline-content inline-photo inline-photo-normal&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/TXJKur-cQ3m4AF9lqk_kkjfemkk=/3x2/www.washingtonpost.com/pb/resources/img/spacer.gif&quot; data-hi-res-src=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/MG1q07FU08ogttswSXfX4vbrH3s=/1484x0/arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/TW54XOVULYI6RLSPFQKDTSLNPE.jpg&quot; data-low-res-src=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/zpd3svEkYWcoElObTgnDXeK3vh4=/480x0/arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/TW54XOVULYI6RLSPFQKDTSLNPE.jpg&quot; data-raw-src=&quot;https://arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/TW54XOVULYI6RLSPFQKDTSLNPE.jpg&quot; data-threshold=&quot;480&quot; class=&quot;unprocessed _3-to-2 placeholder&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pb-caption&quot;&gt;People on mats during Kresge’s Feldenkrais Method class. (Calla Kessler/The Washington Post)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;20&quot;&gt;The more than 1,000 lessons Feldenkrais created include such movements as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3Cb3pXCh2jA&quot;&gt;getting up from a sitting position without putting too much pressure on your knees&lt;/a&gt;; by sitting and then rotating the upper body so the rib cage softens to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-VwZvZDOnqU&quot;&gt;improve your posture&lt;/a&gt;; and walking so you engage your pelvis instead of your lower back. But most involve l&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uSSAVc0J7so&quot;&gt;ying on your back and moving the spine and other parts of the body in gentle sequences&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;21&quot;&gt;As with many “alternative” and mind-body therapies, there isn’t a lot of research assessing the effect of the Feldenkrais Method. A 2015 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hindawi.com/journals/ecam/2015/752160/&quot;&gt;analysis&lt;/a&gt; in the Journal of Evidence-Based Complementary and Alternative Medicine found most studies of it were subpar, but it said the method showed “promising evidence” of improved balance and pain relief, particularly for the elderly. They suggested more research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;22&quot;&gt;A 2004 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thieme-connect.de/DOI/DOI?10.1055/s-2004-834763&quot;&gt;review&lt;/a&gt; that looked at clinical trials involving patients with multiple sclerosis, neck/shoulder problems and chronic back pain found methodological weaknesses. The review concluded that “evidence for [Feldenkrais] is encouraging but, due to the paucity and low quality of studies, by no means compelling.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;23&quot;&gt;Doctors who specialize in alternative medicine say there is a reason Feldenkrais works for some people with pain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;24&quot;&gt;“We’ve learned that there is a substantial connection between what’s happening in the low back and the central nervous system,” says Robert Saper, an associate professor of family medicine at Boston University School of Medicine and a National Institutes of Health researcher in non-pharmacologic approaches to chronic back pain. “When we do a practice like this, changes can occur in the brain that modulate the perception of pain in a favorable direction.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;25&quot;&gt;Feldenkrais has not eliminated my chronic neck and back discomfort, but it has helped me manage it. Its biggest benefit is a confidence that I can wriggle myself out of a setback on my own without counting the days until someone can crack my back to realign my vertebrae.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;26&quot;&gt;So every Sunday morning, I join 10 to 20 men and women of all ages on mats in Kresge’s class, where she channels Feldenkrais with mantras such as “Slow gets the brain’s attention” and “Don’t rehearse pain” and “If you’re sensing differences between your left side and your right, you’re already making changes.” She walks around the room with gentle touches that coax our necks or sternums or ribs to let go of the tension blocking them from moving freely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;27&quot;&gt;Her Northwest Washington studio is filled at various times with Type A federal workers, diplomats, athletes and musicians, retirees, special-needs children and adults with neuromotor challenges, including Parkinson’s, and stroke victims with motor issues. (The method has attracted some prominent adherents over the years including basketball player Julius Erving, tennis player Martina Navratilova, cellist Yo-Yo Ma and violinist Yehudi Menuhin.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;28&quot;&gt;All of this minimal effort is harder than it seems — particularly for people like me who tend to thrive on stress, then collapse from it in a continuous loop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;29&quot;&gt;Babies, it turns out, don’t tighten their sternums or their backs, or hold their heads in front of their necks as stressed-out adults do. Feldenkrais tries to get us back to the conditions that babies experience when they learn to move. They haven’t yet stretched or learned to strain. I’ve spent entire classes lying on the floor holding my big toe, gently lifting my head and my foot to rewire the primal movements that have gone askew.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div data-elm-loc=&quot;30&quot; class=&quot;inline-content inline-photo inline-photo-normal&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/TXJKur-cQ3m4AF9lqk_kkjfemkk=/3x2/www.washingtonpost.com/pb/resources/img/spacer.gif&quot; data-hi-res-src=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/vg2csPM9fNJ7gOROYIFfPi4ocMo=/1484x0/arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/YUQZ6NVULYI6RLSPFQKDTSLNPE.jpg&quot; data-low-res-src=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/4bfaaLArdZ9F_7cwXg42T8fN3h8=/480x0/arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/YUQZ6NVULYI6RLSPFQKDTSLNPE.jpg&quot; data-raw-src=&quot;https://arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/YUQZ6NVULYI6RLSPFQKDTSLNPE.jpg&quot; data-threshold=&quot;480&quot; class=&quot;unprocessed _3-to-2 placeholder&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pb-caption&quot;&gt;Lila Asher, 96, practices various movements in Kresge class. Asher says she enjoys the routine because she doesn't feel sore after class. (Calla Kessler/The Washington Post)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div data-elm-loc=&quot;31&quot; class=&quot;inline-content inline-photo inline-photo-double&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;left&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/TXJKur-cQ3m4AF9lqk_kkjfemkk=/3x2/www.washingtonpost.com/pb/resources/img/spacer.gif&quot; data-hi-res-src=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/DrZSUWc86k693eBMYe6u2O28eMg=/742x0/arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/YFOVXTVULYI6RLSPFQKDTSLNPE.jpg&quot; data-low-res-src=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/GlP3LxK_BW3xsxDntFR9n70SO5M=/240x0/arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/YFOVXTVULYI6RLSPFQKDTSLNPE.jpg&quot; data-raw-src=&quot;https://arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/YFOVXTVULYI6RLSPFQKDTSLNPE.jpg&quot; data-threshold=&quot;240&quot; class=&quot;unprocessed _3-to-2 placeholder&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pb-caption&quot;&gt;A group practices Feldenkrais in Northwest Washington. (Calla Kessler/The Washington Post)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;right&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pb-caption&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/TXJKur-cQ3m4AF9lqk_kkjfemkk=/3x2/www.washingtonpost.com/pb/resources/img/spacer.gif&quot; data-hi-res-src=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/-k3rKssNcxTKFmj9KoCECakcR6w=/742x0/arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/VNFKLKFULYI6RLSPFQKDTSLNPE.jpg&quot; data-low-res-src=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/TpdG4p3_ceUIfQLx4lGX8zL9BYo=/240x0/arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/VNFKLKFULYI6RLSPFQKDTSLNPE.jpg&quot; data-raw-src=&quot;https://arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/VNFKLKFULYI6RLSPFQKDTSLNPE.jpg&quot; data-threshold=&quot;240&quot; class=&quot;unprocessed _3-to-2 placeholder&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pb-caption&quot;&gt;Kresge walks around the room, giving instructions and words of encouragement to her students. (Calla Kessler/The Washington Post)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;32&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pb-caption&quot;&gt;My own body routines went haywire back in college, when an accumulation of all-nighters and long hours studying with my neck jutting toward my American history books left both shoulders throbbing with an ache that persisted. Massage was nirvana — for a few minutes. When things kept getting worse in my 20s, a variety of practitioners offered diagnoses ranging from a short right leg to nothing to worry about. (That last verdict came from an orthopedic surgeon who told me that if I wasn’t a candidate for surgery, he couldn’t help.)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;33&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pb-caption&quot;&gt;I’ve had a few memorable disasters. The vertebrae in my lower neck shifted out of alignment on a canoeing trip in Nova Scotia, sending the muscles around them into spasm. My then-boyfriend had to do all the paddling and carry our packs for the rest of the trip.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;34&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pb-caption&quot;&gt;I once left an arch support I convinced myself I could not live without in a rental car, never to find a suitable replacement that makes walking with certain shoes pain-free. My husband, a lifelong backpacker, has searched the Internet for an inflatable sleeping pad that’s comfortable enough for a tent.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;35&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pb-caption&quot;&gt;Why I have pain and others with more crooked backs don’t is still a mystery. The best I have come up with is that a combination of genetics, poor eyesight, wear and tear, and a tendency to carry anxiety in my body contribute. And doctors tell me that people carry their vulnerabilities in different places.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;36&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pb-caption&quot;&gt;“Undoing patterns often means telling the body to try not to try, to do less so you can feel more,” said Kresge, a musical-theater buff who discovered Feldenkrais in the late 1980s to help free her singing voice.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;37&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pb-caption&quot;&gt;I’m still undoing my own patterns.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;38&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pb-caption&quot;&gt;On a vacation in the Pacific Northwest last week, I zoomed down a steep playground slide, my 2-year-old nephew in my lap, and crash-landed on my tailbone. Unable to sit for more than five minutes and with my neck muscles seized up in their familiar pattern, I saw a skilled chiropractor — twice.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;39&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pb-caption&quot;&gt;I felt better, but two days later the pain was back. After flying home, I was back in Feldenkrais class, which was devoted, luckily for me, to freeing the shoulders. We lay on our backs, bent our elbows at right angles and slowly moved our arms back and forward, lifting and lowering our necks and pelvises in different patterns. After class, I walked to my car, took some deep breaths and drove home, my neck in a much better place.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div data-elm-loc=&quot;40&quot; class=&quot;inline-content inline-photo inline-photo-normal&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pb-caption&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/TXJKur-cQ3m4AF9lqk_kkjfemkk=/3x2/www.washingtonpost.com/pb/resources/img/spacer.gif&quot; data-hi-res-src=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/D8_0xBV8Xebn8dZDqHlerVza9qU=/1484x0/arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/XRLIDZVULYI6RLSPFQKDTSLNPE.jpg&quot; data-low-res-src=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/pY-ZiEZ7xe7eqQu0OMwkuyMCRow=/480x0/arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/XRLIDZVULYI6RLSPFQKDTSLNPE.jpg&quot; data-raw-src=&quot;https://arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/XRLIDZVULYI6RLSPFQKDTSLNPE.jpg&quot; data-threshold=&quot;480&quot; class=&quot;unprocessed _3-to-2 placeholder&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pb-caption&quot;&gt;Students bend and lift their knees during Kresge’s class. (Calla Kessler/The Washington Post)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;42&quot; class=&quot;interstitial-link&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read more&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;43&quot; class=&quot;interstitial-link&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/national/health-science/going-to-the-doctor-for-back-pain-can-be-a-slippery-slope/2014/05/23/7679ccf0-d5ec-11e3-95d3-3bcd77cd4e11_story.html?utm_term=.4c1514b9634f&quot;&gt;Going to the doctor for back pain can be a slippery slope&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;44&quot; class=&quot;interstitial-link&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/national/health-science/that-aching-back-is-hard-to-fix-but-here-are-a-few-things-to-try/2018/07/06/4e719048-64e1-11e8-99d2-0d678ec08c2f_story.html?utm_term=.825721e02ab6&quot;&gt;That aching back is hard to fix, but here are a few things to try&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;45&quot; class=&quot;interstitial-link&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/national/health-science/at-night-she-suffered-through-searing-pain-by-morning-it-mysteriously-vanished/2018/05/25/65dea0d4-2799-11e8-b79d-f3d931db7f68_story.html?utm_term=.a076e03b9e88&quot;&gt;Medical Mystery: At night she suffered searing pain, by morning it mysteriously vanished.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2018 18:10:44 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>rutenspitz</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.washingtonpost.com/national/health-science/a-different-way-to-relieve-years-of-back-pain/2018/09/27/f3e663f4-b505-11e8-a2c5-3187f427e253_story.html</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/Qx8SgJEqXg6Eu-8LDs4GITDtpvQ=/1484x0/arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/YAK2QXFULYI6RLSPFQKDTSLNPE.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>A different way to relieve years of back pain</og:title>
<og:description>The slow and subtle movements of the Feldenkrais Method aim to retrain the body and brain.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.washingtonpost.com/national/health-science/a-different-way-to-relieve-years-of-back-pain/2018/09/27/f3e663f4-b505-11e8-a2c5-3187f427e253_story.html?noredirect=on</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Bing has been serving up malicious Google Chrome ads for months</title>
<link>https://www.forbes.com/sites/jasonevangelho/2018/10/27/stop-using-microsoft-edge-to-download-chrome-unless-you-want-malware/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.forbes.com/sites/jasonevangelho/2018/10/27/stop-using-microsoft-edge-to-download-chrome-unless-you-want-malware/</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;speakable-paragraph&quot;&gt;For many people who purchase a new Windows 10 PC, Microsoft's built-in Edge browser has one purpose: to download an alternate browser like Google Chrome. The most common way to do this for people who don't have the URL memorized? Type &quot;download Chrome&quot; in the address bar and click the first result provided by Bing search. Unfortunately those unsuspecting users have a high chance of downloading malware and adware. That's because &lt;span class=&quot;tweet_quote&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.forbes.com%2Fsites%2Fjasonevangelho%2F2018%2F10%2F27%2Fstop-using-microsoft-edge-to-download-chrome-unless-you-want-malware%2F&amp;amp;text=Microsoft%27s%20Bing%20has%20been%20serving%20up%20malicious%20but%20very%20visible%20Google%20Chrome%20ads%20for%20months.&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot; data-ga-track=&quot;ExternalLink:https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.forbes.com%2Fsites%2Fjasonevangelho%2F2018%2F10%2F27%2Fstop-using-microsoft-edge-to-download-chrome-unless-you-want-malware%2F&amp;amp;text=Microsoft%27s%20Bing%20has%20been%20serving%20up%20malicious%20but%20very%20visible%20Google%20Chrome%20ads%20for%20months.&quot;&gt;Bing has been serving up malicious but highly visible Google Chrome ads for months&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_25509&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot;&gt;

&lt;div article-image-caption=&quot;&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-container&quot; ng-class=&quot;caption_state&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Deceptive site ahead. Google and Firefox know this. Bing can't be bothered, apparently&lt;small class=&quot;article-photo-credit&quot;&gt;Jason Evangelho&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This weekend, Twitter user Gabriel Landau enjoyed his first few hours with a Windows 10 laptop by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/GabrielLandau/status/1055300918101598208&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot; data-ga-track=&quot;ExternalLink:https://twitter.com/GabrielLandau/status/1055300918101598208&quot;&gt;doing this exact thing (video in Twitter link)&lt;/a&gt;. The top result for his &quot;download chrome&quot; search via Edge looked ordinary enough. Except that when he clicked it the resulting domain was &quot;GoogleOnline2018.com.&quot; The fake site isn't an exact copy of Google's own Chrome landing page, but looks genuine enough to fool people. The download itself is called &quot;ChromeSetup.exe,&quot; but examining the digital signature reveals &quot;Alpha Criteria Ltd.&quot; That's definitely &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; Google.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; readability=&quot;7.991452991453&quot;&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;Brand new Win10 laptop. Attempt to install Chrome. Almost get owned with my very first action. Why is this still happening in 2018, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/bing?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot; data-ga-track=&quot;ExternalLink:https://twitter.com/bing?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@bing&lt;/a&gt;? Please explain. &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/uYJhu7xa9H&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot; data-ga-track=&quot;ExternalLink:https://t.co/uYJhu7xa9H&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/uYJhu7xa9H&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Gabriel Landau (@GabrielLandau) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/GabrielLandau/status/1055300918101598208?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot; data-ga-track=&quot;ExternalLink:https://twitter.com/GabrielLandau/status/1055300918101598208?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;October 25, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deceptive Site Ahead&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fortunately Landau was observant enough to detect something fishy was happening, but the way these deceptive ads are hijacking Bing is clever enough to fool the average user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;tweet_line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;tweet_quote&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.forbes.com%2Fsites%2Fjasonevangelho%2F2018%2F10%2F27%2Fstop-using-microsoft-edge-to-download-chrome-unless-you-want-malware%2F&amp;amp;text=The%20malicious%20URL%20that%20Bing%20is%20happy%20to%20promote%20can%27t%20fool%20Google%20or%20Firefox.&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot; data-ga-track=&quot;ExternalLink:https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.forbes.com%2Fsites%2Fjasonevangelho%2F2018%2F10%2F27%2Fstop-using-microsoft-edge-to-download-chrome-unless-you-want-malware%2F&amp;amp;text=The%20malicious%20URL%20that%20Bing%20is%20happy%20to%20promote%20can%27t%20fool%20Google%20or%20Firefox.&quot;&gt;The malicious URL that Bing is happy to promote can't fool Google or Firefox.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; When I simply type the above URL into my Firefox browser I'm faced with a bold red page declaring &quot;Deceptive Site Ahead&quot; completely with details and an option to go back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chris Hoffman, EIC of How-To Geek was able to reproduce this error, and several users on Twitter have also complained about it. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.howtogeek.com/fyi/bing-is-pushing-malware-when-you-search-for-chrome/#comments&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot; data-ga-track=&quot;ExternalLink:https://www.howtogeek.com/fyi/bing-is-pushing-malware-when-you-search-for-chrome/#comments&quot;&gt;In his article&lt;/a&gt; he points out that the ad comes into rotation every few page refreshes. Because I can't obtain that result on a fresh Windows 10 install, I suspect it may be targeting users geographically (I live in Europe).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I notified Bing Ads of this issue, and since Landau's tweet went viral overnight, I have confidence the malicious ad will be removed from Bing Search within the next 24 hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the real issue is that &lt;em&gt;it keeps happening&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I searched the web for similar complaints and found an article from Bleeping Computer &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/beware-of-bing-chrome-download-ads-pushing-adware-pup-installers/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot; data-ga-track=&quot;ExternalLink:https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/beware-of-bing-chrome-download-ads-pushing-adware-pup-installers/&quot;&gt;dated April 2018&lt;/a&gt;. The same type of hijack using Bing Ads from Edge, displayed as the top result, leading to a fake Chrome download that serves up  some particularly nasty adware in its installer. The most noticeable difference was the domain name &quot;NewChromeDownload.com.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then &lt;em&gt;again&lt;/em&gt; 21 days ago from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/chrome/comments/9lmqry/chrome_download_link_in_bing_on_edge_redirects_to/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot; data-ga-track=&quot;ExternalLink:https://www.reddit.com/r/chrome/comments/9lmqry/chrome_download_link_in_bing_on_edge_redirects_to/&quot;&gt;this user&lt;/a&gt; on Reddit. You guessed it. Same procedure, same structure, different domain name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then again &lt;a href=&quot;https://i.redd.it/f00etqzot3411.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot; data-ga-track=&quot;ExternalLink:https://i.redd.it/f00etqzot3411.png&quot;&gt;about 4 months ago&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_25504&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot;&gt;

&lt;div article-image-caption=&quot;&quot; readability=&quot;6.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-container&quot; ng-class=&quot;caption_state&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;If you have to use Windows 10, don't use Bing for search. Ever.&lt;small class=&quot;article-photo-credit&quot;&gt;Microsoft&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's a pattern here, and it's a disturbing one. How many people have been affected by these short-lived but recurring hijacks that Microsoft is letting through to millions of people? It's inexcusable that these types of ads aren't vetted properly, especially when the majority of browsers automatically know these sites are unsafe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Isolated issues like this -- one search term in one browser with one search engine -- may not seem significant. But when looking at Windows 10 as a whole, things look considerably darker. Microsoft is letting devastating &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.forbes.com/sites/jasonevangelho/2018/10/05/avoid-windows-10-october-update-until-you-do-one-thing/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot; data-ga-track=&quot;InternalLink:http://www.forbes.com/sites/jasonevangelho/2018/10/05/avoid-windows-10-october-update-until-you-do-one-thing/&quot;&gt;file-deleting bugs&lt;/a&gt; through its Windows 10 updates even &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.forbes.com/sites/jasonevangelho/2018/10/12/how-microsoft-plans-to-avoid-nasty-windows-10-update-bugs-in-the-future/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot; data-ga-track=&quot;InternalLink:http://www.forbes.com/sites/jasonevangelho/2018/10/12/how-microsoft-plans-to-avoid-nasty-windows-10-update-bugs-in-the-future/&quot;&gt;after being warned&lt;/a&gt; by its team of Windows Insider testers. The update process is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.forbes.com/sites/jasonevangelho/2018/09/11/5-ridiculous-windows-10-headlines-that-will-have-you-running-to-linux/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot; data-ga-track=&quot;InternalLink:http://www.forbes.com/sites/jasonevangelho/2018/09/11/5-ridiculous-windows-10-headlines-that-will-have-you-running-to-linux/&quot;&gt;unreliable&lt;/a&gt; and cumbersome &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.forbes.com/sites/jasonevangelho/2018/07/30/ditching-windows-heres-how-ubuntu-updates-your-pc-and-why-its-better/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot; data-ga-track=&quot;InternalLink:http://www.forbes.com/sites/jasonevangelho/2018/07/30/ditching-windows-heres-how-ubuntu-updates-your-pc-and-why-its-better/&quot;&gt;compared to operating systems like Ubuntu&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What You Can Do&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you must use Windows 10, go directly to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chrome.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot; data-ga-track=&quot;ExternalLink:http://www.chrome.com&quot;&gt;Chrome.com&lt;/a&gt; to download Google's browser, or to &lt;a href=&quot;http://mozilla.org&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot; data-ga-track=&quot;ExternalLink:http://mozilla.org&quot;&gt;Mozilla.org&lt;/a&gt; for Firefox. Commit those to memory or just open up Edge and browse directly to google.com. I also highly recommend installing a tracking blocker like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.forbes.com/sites/jasonevangelho/2018/10/03/when-does-googles-convenience-turn-creepy-let-me-duckduckgo-that-for-you/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot; data-ga-track=&quot;InternalLink:http://www.forbes.com/sites/jasonevangelho/2018/10/03/when-does-googles-convenience-turn-creepy-let-me-duckduckgo-that-for-you/&quot;&gt;DuckDuckGo&lt;/a&gt;. If you choose to use the Edge browser, remove Bing as your default search provider by following &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pcworld.com/article/2993839/windows/how-to-remove-bing-from-edge-or-internet-explorer.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot; data-ga-track=&quot;ExternalLink:https://www.pcworld.com/article/2993839/windows/how-to-remove-bing-from-edge-or-internet-explorer.html&quot;&gt;these steps&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the very least, please do not use Bing to search for anything. Ever. You probably won't after &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.howtogeek.com/367878/bing-is-suggesting-the-worst-things-you-can-imagine/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot; data-ga-track=&quot;ExternalLink:https://www.howtogeek.com/367878/bing-is-suggesting-the-worst-things-you-can-imagine/&quot;&gt;reading this&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll update this article with any response from the Bing Ads team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE&lt;/strong&gt;: The Bing Ads &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/BingAds/status/1055972156301967360&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot; data-ga-track=&quot;ExternalLink:https://twitter.com/BingAds/status/1055972156301967360&quot;&gt;Twitter account&lt;/a&gt; has removed the malicious ad and banned the account, saying &quot;Hi Gabriel, protecting customers from malicious content is a top priority and we have removed the ads from Bing and banned the associated account. We encourage users to continue to report this type of content at &lt;a class=&quot;twitter-timeline-link&quot; title=&quot;https://bit.ly/2PZWZ1u&quot; href=&quot;https://t.co/Dh1KuF5O0t&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot; data-ga-track=&quot;ExternalLink:https://t.co/Dh1KuF5O0t&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;invisible&quot; data-ga-track=&quot;ExternalLink:https://t.co/Dh1KuF5O0t&quot;&gt;https://&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;js-display-url&quot; data-ga-track=&quot;ExternalLink:https://t.co/Dh1KuF5O0t&quot;&gt;bit.ly/2PZWZ1u&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;tco-ellipsis&quot; data-ga-track=&quot;ExternalLink:https://t.co/Dh1KuF5O0t&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;invisible&quot; data-ga-track=&quot;ExternalLink:https://t.co/Dh1KuF5O0t&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; so we can take appropriate action.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Is it&lt;/em&gt; a top priority? One can only hope Microsoft will be more vigilant going forward since this is a recurring problem with Bing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2018 16:43:20 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>wglb</dc:creator>
<og:title>Stop Using Microsoft Edge To Download Chrome -- Unless You Want Malware</og:title>
<og:image>https://thumbor.forbes.com/thumbor/600x315/https%3A%2F%2Fblogs-images.forbes.com%2Fjasonevangelho%2Ffiles%2F2018%2F10%2FScreenshot-from-2018-10-27-11-45-23.jpg</og:image>
<og:url>https://www.forbes.com/sites/jasonevangelho/2018/10/27/stop-using-microsoft-edge-to-download-chrome-unless-you-want-malware/</og:url>
<og:description>You had ONE job, Edge.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.forbes.com/sites/jasonevangelho/2018/10/27/stop-using-microsoft-edge-to-download-chrome-unless-you-want-malware/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Hubble is back</title>
<link>https://www.nasa.gov/feature/goddard/2018/update-on-the-hubble-space-telescope-safe-mode</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nasa.gov/feature/goddard/2018/update-on-the-hubble-space-telescope-safe-mode</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nasa.gov/feature/goddard/2018/update-on-the-hubble-space-telescope-safe-mode&quot;&gt;https://www.nasa.gov/feature/goddard/2018/update-on-the-hubble-space-telescope-safe-mode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=18316342&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=18316342&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 600&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 93&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2018 16:09:34 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>perlgeek</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>http://www.nasa.gov/feature/goddard/2018/update-on-the-hubble-space-telescope-safe-mode</og:url>
<og:image>http://www.nasa.gov/sites/default/files/thumbnails/image/s125e012033_1.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>NASA’s Hubble Space Telescope returned to normal operations late Friday, Oct. 26, and completed its first science observations on Saturday, Oct. 27 at 2:10 AM EDT.</og:description>
<og:title>Oct. 27 Gyro Update: NASA’s Hubble Space Telescope Returns to Science</og:title>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nasa.gov/feature/goddard/2018/update-on-the-hubble-space-telescope-safe-mode/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>YouTube marketing horror story</title>
<link>https://www.candyjapan.com/behind-the-scenes/youtube-marketing-horror-story</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.candyjapan.com/behind-the-scenes/youtube-marketing-horror-story</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.candyjapan.com/static/guro-box-logo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;scary halloween candy box&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Happy Halloween. Here are the results from a (not really that horrible) little marketing test: is it worth it asking tiny YouTube channels to make unboxing videos for you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I run a site called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.candyjapan.com/&quot;&gt;Candy Japan&lt;/a&gt;, which ships boxes of Japanese surprise candies to subscribers around the world, twice a month. I've been trying to find an approach to promote the site effectively through YouTube, as it seems great for reaching a lot of people looking for new things to try. Earlier I &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.candyjapan.com/behind-the-scenes/what-i-learned-advertising-on-youtube&quot;&gt;tried YouTube ads&lt;/a&gt;. When that didn't work, many commented that instead of burning money on ads, I should just send YouTubers free samples instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.candyjapan.com/behind-the-scenes/sales-results-from-getting-3-million-views-on-youtube&quot;&gt;already done this before&lt;/a&gt; with some YouTubers. One unboxing video ended up getting millions of views, but didn't result in any sales. I still believed that if I just tried different approaches, eventually something would work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sending samples to a lot of tiny channels&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's what my thinking was for the current experiment. Huge channels may occasionally agree to feature Candy Japan, but it will be a bumpy ride with a small number of videos, some not working out at all. Doubling down on the ones that do work (if they exist) would be hard, as there are only so many big yet relevant YouTube channels out there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand there are probably thousands (hundreds of thousands?) of channels out there in the 1-10k subscriber range. If each just brought in two customers on average, there are so many of them out there that scaling would be straightforward. I would get a stream of sweet sweet data to analyze, enabling me to improve the approach over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Starting with a small-scale test&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;180 channels contacted&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I had no idea if this would work, I wanted to start small, but still big enough to learn something. I decided 180 would be a decent number of channels to contact. I could at the least get a good idea of the response rate, and maybe even run a split test.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to pick a category where I could easily find a lot of related channels, and one that might have an audience interested in Japan. I decided to go for cosplayers. I found websites where cosplayers were uploading their costume photos, and many users linked to their YouTube channels from their profiles. I wrote a quick Python script to find more of them and entered them into a spreadsheet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I manually visited each channel to make sure I knew how to address the YouTuber properly by their name or the name of their team, and also to find out how to contact them. Finding contact information turned out to be quite time-consuming, as someone might only link to Tumblr from their channel, then Tumblr would link to their DeviantArt page, which might then finally have their contact information. At first each channel took me close to 10 minutes to go through, but after doing about a hundred I got good enough at this task that I could do each in 2 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;50 channels agreed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After I had a large list of people to contact, I wasn't sure what to say in my email, so I wrote a bunch of different versions and tested them. To get someone to agree to an unboxing, the most important thing turned out to be not asking for their shipping address up front. Instead first explain the service briefly, then ask if they are interested to do receive a sample for a video. If they say yes, only then ask for the shipping address. Asking for the address in the initial mail seemed to be off-putting and resulted in less people agreeing. I &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.candyjapan.com/behind-the-scenes/ab-testing-contacting-youtubers&quot;&gt;tested other things as well&lt;/a&gt;, but that was the most impactful finding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guessed that around 10% would agree, but in the end 50 channels (28%) out of the 180 contacted agreed to make a video and gave me their shipping address.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;42 samples shipped&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Starting with a small-scale test&quot; src=&quot;https://www.candyjapan.com/static/pile_of_boxes_at_japan_post.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end I did not ship to everyone. Some responded so slowly that I considered the whole experiment over by the time I received their shipping address, for others I made mistakes, such as noticing their Facebook messages too late.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;33 boxes reached destination&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not every box sent actually made it to the YouTuber. I also found that international package tracking often (24% of the time) does not actually work, so it was impossible to be sure exactly how many packages got delivered. I know for sure that 4 got returned back to me, and that at least 33 arrived.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On average it took 2 weeks for an airmailed package to be delivered, ranging from 4 to 42 days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;17 videos made&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the boxes delivered, I waited 2 months before tallying up how many people actually made a video. I also periodically nagged people to ask how their video was coming, and from the responses I felt this helped people to remember to do it. From getting the box, it took on average 20 days for a YouTuber to make a video. The fastest person made theirs in 1 day, slowest after 2 months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLXnSK9EMudUeGONOSeQNZMsSsBpb7n-_K&quot;&gt;see all the videos here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since only a fourth of people actually made a video, to get one video made I need to send 2.5 boxes. That more than doubles the cost of goods and shipping, meaning that the results from these videos would have to be very good for this to be scalable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Results&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Results&quot; src=&quot;https://www.candyjapan.com/static/zero_sales.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The entire process of finding YouTubers to contact, figuring out how to contact them, having back-and-forth discussions with each to discover their shipping address and answering any questions they had, preparing and shipping the boxes, nagging people to make the videos, and finally compiling the results was very time-consuming. Because of delays in messaging, shipping and making the video, this is also a process that dragged on for about 3 months before it finally felt &quot;done&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After videos had been out for about two months, I went to check their view counts. Each only averaged 166 views, for a grand total of 2826 views. This would have been OK if these small channels had such a devoted subscriber base that each would have resulted in a sale or two, but that did not happen. No noticeable change in traffic from YouTube, no uptick in sales, and no-one mentioned buying because of the channels (I ask everyone).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hardest evidence is that not a single new customer claimed any of the 10% off coupons I gave to the YouTubers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Buying all of the goods and shipping all the packages cost about $1000 in total. Buying the same number of YouTube ad views would have cost less than $10. On a CPM basis this was actually ten times more expensive than advertising on prime-time TV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Considering the results, I am becoming pretty reluctant to send out free samples for unboxing videos. I would love to be proven wrong though, so if you run a decent sized channel that you believe could be a good match, do &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:bemmu@candyjapan.com&quot;&gt;drop me a line&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you'd like to try some Japanese candy for yourself, you can &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.candyjapan.com/&quot;&gt;sign up here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2018 13:58:50 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>bemmu</dc:creator>
<og:title>Candy Japan YouTube marketing horror story</og:title>
<og:description>Results from asking 180 YouTubers to make an unboxing video for a subscription box. Includes detailed breakdown of response rate, number of videos made, views and the sales results from them.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.candyjapan.com/behind-the-scenes/youtube-marketing-horror-story</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:image>https://www.candyjapan.com/static/guro-box-logo.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.candyjapan.com/behind-the-scenes/youtube-marketing-horror-story</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Systemd is bad parsing</title>
<link>https://blog.erratasec.com/2018/10/systemd-is-bad-parsing-and-should-feel.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.erratasec.com/2018/10/systemd-is-bad-parsing-and-should-feel.html</guid>
<description>Systemd has a remotely exploitable bug in its DHCPv6 client. That means anybody on the local network can send you a packet and take control of your computer. The flaw is a typical buffer-overflow. Several news stories have pointed out that this client was rewritten from scratch, as if that were the moral failing, instead of reusing existing code. That's not the problem.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div&gt;The problem is that it was rewritten from scratch &lt;em&gt;without taking advantage of the lessons of the past&lt;/em&gt;. It makes the same mistakes all over again.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;In the late 1990s and early 2000s, we learned that parsing input is a problem. The traditional &lt;em&gt;ad hoc&lt;/em&gt; approach you were taught in school is wrong. It's wrong from an abstract theoretical point of view. It's wrong from the practical point of view, error prone and leading to spaghetti code.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;The first thing you need to unlearn is byte-swapping. I know that this was some sort epiphany you had when you learned network programming but byte-swapping is wrong. If you find yourself using a macro to swap bytes, like the &lt;em&gt;be16toh()&lt;/em&gt; macro used in this code, then you are doing it wrong.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;But, you say, the network byte-order is big-endian, while today's Intel and ARM processors are little-endian. So you have to swap bytes, don't you?&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;No. As proof of the matter I point to every other language other than C/C++. They don't don't swap bytes. Their internal integer format is undefined. Indeed, something like JavaScript may be storing numbers as a floating points. You can't muck around with the internal format of their integers even if you wanted to.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;An example of byte swapping in the code is something like this:&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-iC72no7KLwE/W9RKMxBxd1I/AAAAAAAAFaY/9KlFbZgc9TsRC6s-P-3KWOD_gJXEhpp_ACLcBGAs/s1600/Screen%2BShot%2B2018-10-27%2Bat%2B7.20.32%2BAM.png&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;76&quot; data-original-width=&quot;483&quot; src=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-iC72no7KLwE/W9RKMxBxd1I/AAAAAAAAFaY/9KlFbZgc9TsRC6s-P-3KWOD_gJXEhpp_ACLcBGAs/s1600/Screen%2BShot%2B2018-10-27%2Bat%2B7.20.32%2BAM.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;In this code, it's taking a buffer of raw bytes from the DHCPv6 packet and &quot;casting&quot; it as a C internal structure. The packet contains a two-byte big-endian length field, &quot;&lt;em&gt;option-&amp;gt;len&lt;/em&gt;&quot;, which the code must byte-swap in order to use.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;Among the errors here is casting an &lt;em&gt;internal&lt;/em&gt; structure over &lt;em&gt;external&lt;/em&gt; data. From an abstract theory point of view, this is wrong. Internal structures are undefined. Just because you can sort of know the definition in C/C++ doesn't change the fact that they are still undefined.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;From a practical point of view, this leads to confusion, as the programmer is never quite clear as to the boundary between external and internal data. You are supposed to rigorously verify external data, because the hacker controls it. You don't keep double-checking and second-guessing internal data, because that would be stupid. When you blur the lines between internal and external data, then your checks get muddled up.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;Yes you can, in C/C++, cast an internal structure over external data. But just because you can doesn't mean you should. What you should do instead is parse data the same way as if you were writing code in JavaScript. For example, to grab the DHCP6 option length field, you should write something like:&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-58uqUYSOKGs/W9RKhy8bXbI/AAAAAAAAFag/g4nvpKrntT0R4P1prgEbwJCug-yPNf9zwCLcBGAs/s1600/Screen%2BShot%2B2018-10-27%2Bat%2B7.22.21%2BAM.png&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;38&quot; data-original-width=&quot;282&quot; src=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-58uqUYSOKGs/W9RKhy8bXbI/AAAAAAAAFag/g4nvpKrntT0R4P1prgEbwJCug-yPNf9zwCLcBGAs/s1600/Screen%2BShot%2B2018-10-27%2Bat%2B7.22.21%2BAM.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;The thing about this code is that you don't know whether it's JavaScript or C, because it's both, and it does the same thing for both.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;Byte &quot;swapping&quot; isn't happening. We aren't extracting an integer from a packet, then changing it's internal format. Instead, we are extracting two bytes and combining them. This description may seem like needless pedantry, but it's really really important that you grok this. For example, there is no conditional macro here that does one operation for a little-endian CPU, and another operation for a big-endian CPU -- it does the same thing for both CPUs. Whatever words you want to use to describe the difference, it's still profound and important.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;The other thing that you shouldn't do, even though C/C++ allows it, is &lt;em&gt;pointer arithmetic&lt;/em&gt;. Again, it's one of those epiphany things C programmers remember from their early days. It's something they just couldn't grasp until one day they did, and then they fell in love with it. Except it's bad. The reason you struggled to grok it is because it's stupid and you shouldn't be using it. No other language has it, because it's bad.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;I mean, back in the day, it was a useful performance optimization. Iterating through an array can be faster adding to pointer than incrementing an index. But that's virtually never the case today, and it just leads to needless spaghetti code. It leads to convoluted constructions like the following at the heart of this bug where you have to both do arithmetic on the pointer as well as on the length which you are checking against. This nonsense leads to confusion and ultimately, buffer overflows.&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-QTAAZAuyB7w/W9RKwFbLSmI/AAAAAAAAFak/6rRuwKcEUw4kZSLYZjXgqaVaBW_BreuUACLcBGAs/s1600/Screen%2BShot%2B2018-10-27%2Bat%2B7.23.22%2BAM.png&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;58&quot; data-original-width=&quot;355&quot; src=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-QTAAZAuyB7w/W9RKwFbLSmI/AAAAAAAAFak/6rRuwKcEUw4kZSLYZjXgqaVaBW_BreuUACLcBGAs/s1600/Screen%2BShot%2B2018-10-27%2Bat%2B7.23.22%2BAM.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;In a heckofalot of buffer overflows over the years, there's a construct just like this lurking near the bug. If you are going to do a rewrite of code, then this is a construct you need to avoid. Just say no to pointer arithmetic.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;In my code, you see a lot of constructs where it's &lt;em&gt;buf&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;offset&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;length&lt;/em&gt;. The &lt;em&gt;buf&lt;/em&gt; variable points to the start of the buffer and is never incremented. The &lt;em&gt;length&lt;/em&gt; variable is the max length of the buffer and likewise never changes. It's the &lt;em&gt;offset&lt;/em&gt; variable that is incremented throughout.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;Because of simplicity, buffer overflow checks become obvious, as it's always &quot;&lt;em&gt;offset + x &amp;lt; length&lt;/em&gt;&quot;, and easy to verify. In contrast, here is the fix for the DHCPv6 buffer overflow. That this is checking for an external buffer overflow is less obvious:&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-cME4XAUBdqk/W9RK7dg9piI/AAAAAAAAFas/QIEhwvUlTyQzMsqfWU61L_fD6hzvNWuYgCLcBGAs/s1600/Screen%2BShot%2B2018-10-27%2Bat%2B7.24.03%2BAM.png&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;56&quot; data-original-width=&quot;386&quot; src=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-cME4XAUBdqk/W9RK7dg9piI/AAAAAAAAFas/QIEhwvUlTyQzMsqfWU61L_fD6hzvNWuYgCLcBGAs/s1600/Screen%2BShot%2B2018-10-27%2Bat%2B7.24.03%2BAM.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;Now let's look at that error code. That's not what ENOBUFS really means. That's an operating system error code that has specific meaning about kernel buffers. Overloading it for userland code is inappropriate.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;That argument is a bit pedantic I grant you, but that's only the start. The bigger issue is that it's identifying the &lt;em&gt;symptom&lt;/em&gt; not the &lt;em&gt;problem&lt;/em&gt;. The ultimate problem is that the code failed to sanitize the original input, allowing the hacker to drive computation this deep in the system. The error isn't that the buffer is too small to hold the output, the original error is that the input was too big. Imagine if this gets logged and the sysadmin reviewing &lt;em&gt;dmesg&lt;/em&gt; asks themselves how they can allocate bigger buffers to the DHCP6 daemon. That is entirely the wrong idea.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;Again, we go back to lessons of 20 years that this code ignored, the necessity of sanitizing input.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;Now let's look at &lt;em&gt;assert()&lt;/em&gt;. This is a feature in C that we use to double-check things in order to catch programming mistakes early. An example is the code below, which is checking for programming mistakes where the caller of the function may have used NULL-pointers:&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-ZlPslFuA8YA/W9RLJabmsFI/AAAAAAAAFa0/_Bb2AWOH0QcMZMeCHmrl1GNZ1IwlYfaLgCLcBGAs/s1600/Screen%2BShot%2B2018-10-27%2Bat%2B7.25.03%2BAM.png&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;128&quot; data-original-width=&quot;599&quot; src=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-ZlPslFuA8YA/W9RLJabmsFI/AAAAAAAAFa0/_Bb2AWOH0QcMZMeCHmrl1GNZ1IwlYfaLgCLcBGAs/s1600/Screen%2BShot%2B2018-10-27%2Bat%2B7.25.03%2BAM.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;This is pretty normal, but now consider this other use of &lt;em&gt;assert()&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-8CshjiKELtU/W9RLu-TwAWI/AAAAAAAAFbI/9F1a28MEcHAXhXQ9-eM3Y4Md50bmnqLkgCLcBGAs/s1600/Screen%2BShot%2B2018-10-27%2Bat%2B7.27.08%2BAM.png&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;124&quot; data-original-width=&quot;534&quot; src=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-8CshjiKELtU/W9RLu-TwAWI/AAAAAAAAFbI/9F1a28MEcHAXhXQ9-eM3Y4Md50bmnqLkgCLcBGAs/s1600/Screen%2BShot%2B2018-10-27%2Bat%2B7.27.08%2BAM.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;This isn't checking errors by the programmer here, but is instead validating input. That's &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; what you are supposed to use asserts for. This are very different things. It's a coding horror that makes you shriek and run away when you see it. In my fact, that's my Halloween costume this year, using &lt;em&gt;asserts&lt;/em&gt; to validate network input.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;This reflects a naive misunderstanding by programmers who don't understand the difference between out-of-band checks validating the code, and what the code is supposed to be doing validating input. Like the buffer overflow check above, EINVAL because a programmer made a mistake is a vastly different error than EINVAL because a hacker tried to inject bad input. These aren't the same things, they aren't even in the same realm.&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;Rewriting old code is a good thing -- as long as you are fixing the problems of the past and not repeating them. We have 20 years of experience with what goes wrong in network code. We have academic disciplines like &lt;em&gt;langsec&lt;/em&gt; that study the problem. We have lots of good examples of network parsing done well. There is really no excuse for code that is of this low quality.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;This code has no redeeming features. It must be thrown away and rewritten yet again. This time by an experienced programmer who know what error codes mean, how to use asserts properly, and most of all, who has experience at network programming.&lt;/div&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2018 11:43:04 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>fanf2</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://blog.erratasec.com/2018/10/systemd-is-bad-parsing-and-should-feel.html</og:url>
<og:title>Systemd is bad parsing and should feel bad</og:title>
<og:description>Systemd has a remotely exploitable bug in its DHCPv6 client. That means anybody on the local network can send you a packet and take control ...</og:description>
<og:image>https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-iC72no7KLwE/W9RKMxBxd1I/AAAAAAAAFaY/9KlFbZgc9TsRC6s-P-3KWOD_gJXEhpp_ACLcBGAs/w1200-h630-p-k-no-nu/Screen%2BShot%2B2018-10-27%2Bat%2B7.20.32%2BAM.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.erratasec.com/2018/10/systemd-is-bad-parsing-and-should-feel.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Fear, trust and JavaScript: When types and functional programming fail</title>
<link>https://www.reaktor.com/blog/fear-trust-and-javascript/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.reaktor.com/blog/fear-trust-and-javascript/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;As developers, we want to reduce fear of our code failing and increase trust in our code working well. Many developers working with JavaScript borrow useful ideas from functional programming and strongly-typed programming languages to reduce fear by transferring trust from developers to tools and the code. Ideas like optional types, functional transformations, and immutability can all help to write better JavaScript. When pulling these ideas together in JavaScript, however, they come with severe trade-offs, work together poorly, and ultimately fail in the goal of effectively transferring trust from developers to code and tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To illustrate this idea, let’s look at how data is handled in JavaScript from two perspectives: &lt;strong&gt;understanding the shape of data&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;changing data&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Fear and the shape of data&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a dynamic language like JavaScript, it can be hard to know what the shape of your data is. The default approach is to rely on convention. You trust other developers and other systems to give you correct data in agreed upon formats and to follow certain norms within the code base.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone wp-image-101504&quot; src=&quot;https://384ceo111rx2bs5vm3x2ql5z-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/shape_js-1024x452.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;394&quot; height=&quot;174&quot; srcset=&quot;/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/shape_js-1024x452.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/shape_js-300x132.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/shape_js-768x339.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/shape_js.png 1043w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 394px) 100vw, 394px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like to call this the “pretend it’s what you want” approach. In high-trust environments, it can work well enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But then the fear creeps in. The code grows in complexity. You work with code from developers who follow different conventions. You receive data that you cannot control from upstream in erratic formats. You start seeing null pointer errors. Trust in the code breaks down, and questions about the data start to provoke anxiety rather than confidence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;What values does this data actually contain?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can I delete these values without breaking things?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can I pass in this data to this function?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can see the fear in the code base. It looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone wp-image-101507&quot; src=&quot;https://384ceo111rx2bs5vm3x2ql5z-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/shape_validate_manual-300x273.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;365&quot; height=&quot;332&quot; srcset=&quot;/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/shape_validate_manual-300x273.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/shape_validate_manual-768x698.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/shape_validate_manual.png 917w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 365px) 100vw, 365px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is defensive programming. It happens when you can no longer trust your own code to provide the data you expect at the appropriate times. Your beautiful code becomes cluttered with defensive checks, you lose readability, and the code becomes more brittle and harder to change. Fear grows, and it is harder and harder to trust that your code actually works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Optional types: Pretend really hard&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One way to stave off the fear is to introduce optional types via &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typescriptlang.org/&quot;&gt;TypeScript&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://flow.org/&quot;&gt;Flow&lt;/a&gt;. You receive a user and then proclaim joyously that it is of the &lt;code&gt;User&lt;/code&gt; type, and henceforth shall be treated only as a &lt;code&gt;User&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone wp-image-101505&quot; src=&quot;https://384ceo111rx2bs5vm3x2ql5z-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/shape_ts-300x184.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;544&quot; height=&quot;334&quot; srcset=&quot;/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/shape_ts-300x184.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/shape_ts-768x472.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/shape_ts-1024x629.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/shape_ts.png 1482w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 544px) 100vw, 544px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is like pretending really hard. You’ve shifted your trust around. You still trust other systems to give you data in the correct shape. But within your code base, you trust the type that you’ve given to that data and that the compiler will complain if you use that data incorrectly. Instead of trusting developers to know the shape of data and use it appropriately, you’re trusting developers to write and maintain correct types, and you’re trusting the compiler to not lie about those types. More on that later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adding types to our example doesn’t solve the underlying problem. It improves trust within the code base by helping to ensure that data is used consistently, but it says nothing about data received from the outside world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Validation: Trust but validate&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a low trust environment, you may need to introduce data validation at various points.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone wp-image-101546&quot; src=&quot;https://384ceo111rx2bs5vm3x2ql5z-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/shape_validate-1-300x181.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;522&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; srcset=&quot;/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/shape_validate-1-300x181.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/shape_validate-1-768x464.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/shape_validate-1-1024x619.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/shape_validate-1.png 1237w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 522px) 100vw, 522px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You could do this by hand, but the validation would be ad hoc, laborious, and error-prone. Or you could write &lt;a href=&quot;http://json-schema.org/&quot;&gt;JSON schema&lt;/a&gt; definitions and validate with &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/epoberezkin/ajv&quot;&gt;ajv&lt;/a&gt; or the like to verify that the data matches your schema. This is less ad hoc and allows other uses like generating documentation, but is likely no less verbose or error-prone because you have to manually write out schemas like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone wp-image-101508&quot; src=&quot;https://384ceo111rx2bs5vm3x2ql5z-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/shape_validate_schema-224x300.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;361&quot; height=&quot;483&quot; srcset=&quot;/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/shape_validate_schema-224x300.png 224w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/shape_validate_schema-768x1027.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/shape_validate_schema-766x1024.png 766w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/shape_validate_schema.png 895w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 361px) 100vw, 361px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Optional types + validation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or you could introduce both types and validation. Types to stave off fear internally, and validation to be able to trust data from external sources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone wp-image-101547&quot; src=&quot;https://384ceo111rx2bs5vm3x2ql5z-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/shape_validate_ts-1-300x245.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;490&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; srcset=&quot;/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/shape_validate_ts-1-300x245.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/shape_validate_ts-1-768x626.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/shape_validate_ts-1-1024x835.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/shape_validate_ts-1.png 1459w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 490px) 100vw, 490px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To avoid writing essentially the same type definitions for both validation and optional types you can use the TypeScript or Flow compilers directly as libraries, or use another library like &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pelotom/runtypes&quot;&gt;runtypes&lt;/a&gt; (TS), &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/seanhess/runtime-types&quot;&gt;runtime-types&lt;/a&gt; (Flow), or &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/YousefED/typescript-json-schema&quot;&gt;typescript-json-schema&lt;/a&gt; (TS). After going through a few hoops you start feeling more trust in your data. But there are deeper issues here, which I will get to later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Fear and changing data&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What about when the data changes? By default in JavaScript data can change willy-nilly. For example, this function receives a document, and then changes the document to format a field properly and to include a new field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone wp-image-101499&quot; src=&quot;https://384ceo111rx2bs5vm3x2ql5z-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/change_mutate-300x114.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;608&quot; height=&quot;231&quot; srcset=&quot;/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/change_mutate-300x114.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/change_mutate-768x291.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/change_mutate-1024x388.png 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 608px) 100vw, 608px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But in this style, the flow is hard to follow, and fear starts to creep in. What if our data is used elsewhere? What if it was already changed elsewhere? What values do I have in my data at this point? How can I trust that the data I have at this point is the data I want at this point and will stay that way? This is a trivial example, but the problem becomes much worse with a large code base or a highly concurrent system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You turn to optional types, but those types won’t save you. In TypeScript and Flow, both of these functions have the same type:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone wp-image-101501&quot; src=&quot;https://384ceo111rx2bs5vm3x2ql5z-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/change_mutate_ts-300x102.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;608&quot; height=&quot;207&quot; srcset=&quot;/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/change_mutate_ts-300x102.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/change_mutate_ts-768x262.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/change_mutate_ts-1024x349.png 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 608px) 100vw, 608px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone wp-image-101552&quot; src=&quot;https://384ceo111rx2bs5vm3x2ql5z-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/js_format_doc_launch_rocket-300x123.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;610&quot; height=&quot;250&quot; srcset=&quot;/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/js_format_doc_launch_rocket-300x123.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/js_format_doc_launch_rocket-768x314.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/js_format_doc_launch_rocket-1024x419.png 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 610px) 100vw, 610px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of these does what you want; the other burns the city down. As far as these type systems are concerned, these functions do nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Convention: Pretend immutability&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So you write better JavaScript. You agree with your team, explicitly or implicitly, to write in an immutable style.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone wp-image-101551&quot; src=&quot;https://384ceo111rx2bs5vm3x2ql5z-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/js_format_doc_immutable-300x212.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;543&quot; height=&quot;384&quot; srcset=&quot;/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/js_format_doc_immutable-300x212.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/js_format_doc_immutable-768x544.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/js_format_doc_immutable-1024x725.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/js_format_doc_immutable.png 1461w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 543px) 100vw, 543px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You favor &lt;code&gt;const&lt;/code&gt; over &lt;code&gt;var&lt;/code&gt; and duplicating values over mutation. You use &lt;code&gt;let&lt;/code&gt; to indicate value references that change. You rediscover the ternary operator as a functional alternative to &lt;code&gt;if&lt;/code&gt; statements, at least for short lines. You use functions to return new values instead of changing values. You use &lt;code&gt;map&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;filter&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;reduce&lt;/code&gt;, and other functional constructs to create new data structures without changing the underlying data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Immutability by convention is convenient, produces idiomatic JavaScript, and works well within the JavaScript ecosystem. But it relies heavily on both trust and discipline from developers. You trust developers to follow conventions like avoiding mutation or indicating clearly where mutation happens. You might want something stronger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Libraries: Pretend really hard&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can shift the trust partly from other developers to tools by adopting libraries for data transformation and immutable data structures. You might start using a library like &lt;a href=&quot;http://ramdajs.com&quot;&gt;Ramda&lt;/a&gt; pervasively as a functional utility belt, or adopt lenses &lt;em&gt;à la&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/calmm-js/partial.lenses&quot;&gt;partial.lenses&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/gcanti/monocle-ts&quot;&gt;monocle-ts&lt;/a&gt;, or the like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone wp-image-101502&quot; src=&quot;https://384ceo111rx2bs5vm3x2ql5z-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/change_ramda-300x102.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;612&quot; height=&quot;208&quot; srcset=&quot;/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/change_ramda-300x102.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/change_ramda-768x261.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/change_ramda-1024x348.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/change_ramda.png 1503w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 612px) 100vw, 612px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One fundamental idea in these types of libraries is that the underlying data is treated as though it were immutable. It’s not – &lt;a href=&quot;http://ramdajs.com/0.14/docs/#assoc&quot;&gt;even Ramda only does shallow clones&lt;/a&gt; – but if the convention of immutable data is strong enough, then everyone can pretend it is. You may take a slight performance hit from copying data, but you gain some level of trust in the code. This works best if the use of the library and this convention is pervasive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To enforce actual immutability and avoid the performance hit for changing data, you might also introduce immutable data structures via something like &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/facebook/immutable-js&quot;&gt;Immutable.js&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rtfeldman/seamless-immutable&quot;&gt;seamless-immutable&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://swannodette.github.io/mori/&quot;&gt;Mori&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone wp-image-101497&quot; src=&quot;https://384ceo111rx2bs5vm3x2ql5z-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/change_immutablejs-300x117.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;615&quot; height=&quot;240&quot; srcset=&quot;/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/change_immutablejs-300x117.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/change_immutablejs-768x300.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/change_immutablejs-1024x400.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/change_immutablejs.png 1512w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 615px) 100vw, 615px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This makes the data itself actually immutable, in that only immutable ways to touch the data are exposed. But it only applies to data that is expressed within these data structures. As most of JavaScript relies on classic JavaScript data structures, you end up converting back and forth between the two a lot and you lose that trust whenever you have to use standard data structures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both of these approaches have limitations, but most importantly they clash hard with optional types.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Trusting JavaScript&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The previous examples pulled out several tools for writing more effective JavaScript: optional types, functional transformations, and immutable data. But in JavaScript these tools come with some severe limitations, and they are hard to use together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Optional types give a false sense of security&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Optional types for JavaScript are optional by design, which means not everything is typed and you can’t trust that everything has a valid type. Flow is unsound and TypeScript is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typescriptlang.org/docs/handbook/type-compatibility.html&quot;&gt;deliberately unsound&lt;/a&gt;, which means that in various cases the types are wrong and the compiler doesn’t care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And optional types in JavaScript lie for other reasons. Some things in JavaScript are just hard or impossible to type out in TypeScript or Flow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Higher order functions&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dynamic functions&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monkey-patched anything&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highly dynamic data structures&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;To type these out in TypeScript or Flow, you sacrifice on one or more principles:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sacrifice type safety, the whole reason you use types&lt;/strong&gt;: Type them out with &lt;code&gt;any&lt;/code&gt; types, which allow any values and essentially disable the type checker for all values in the “path” of &lt;code&gt;any&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sacrifice usefulness&lt;/strong&gt;: Make the functions less general in order to provide more specific, accurate types.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sacrifice other developers’ time&lt;/strong&gt;: Make the user of the function provide the correct types, as in&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone wp-image-101503&quot; src=&quot;https://384ceo111rx2bs5vm3x2ql5z-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/ramda_pipe-300x18.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;450&quot; height=&quot;27&quot; srcset=&quot;/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/ramda_pipe-300x18.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/ramda_pipe-768x46.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/ramda_pipe-1024x61.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/ramda_pipe.png 1419w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 450px) 100vw, 450px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then you add libraries into the mix, with their own type definitions with mixed levels of accuracy. This transfers some trust not to the developers of libraries, but to the developers of type definitions for libraries. Many of these libraries will contain &lt;code&gt;any&lt;/code&gt; annotations, and calling those functions will quietly render your trust in types invalid. In Flow, type-checking can also be quietly disabled when a file is missing a &lt;code&gt;@flow&lt;/code&gt; annotation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can work around this trust issue by adopting type annotations pervasively, disallowing both implicit and explicit &lt;code&gt;any&lt;/code&gt; types, setting the linter to complain when files are not type-checked, and otherwise tightening up configurations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it’s like plugging holes in a leaky ship. The problem isn’t just that you can’t trust the types in your system, but that you think you can. You rely on the types to tell you when a change breaks something, but because they were quietly disabled by an &lt;code&gt;any&lt;/code&gt; type, or by use of a library, or by a soundness issue, it doesn’t. Types in JavaScript are different from types in most other languages people use: They can’t be trusted in the same way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-101553 aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;https://384ceo111rx2bs5vm3x2ql5z-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/types_and_js2-261x300.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;378&quot; height=&quot;435&quot; srcset=&quot;/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/types_and_js2-261x300.png 261w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/types_and_js2-768x883.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/types_and_js2-890x1024.png 890w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/types_and_js2.png 1100w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 378px) 100vw, 378px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately the strength of your types depends on the knowledge and belief of the team in applying them. If the team has a high level of belief and knowledge of types, they can encode a high level of trust into the system. But this is dependent on the team’s attention and discipline to maintain this level of trust, and fear can creep in and destroy that trust in many subtle ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Functional programming. Types. JavaScript. Pick two&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Optional types and basic functional programming like maps and filters and reduces and so forth work alright together in JavaScript. It’s when you try to go further that you run into problems. Two examples:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/facebook/immutable-js&quot;&gt;Immutable.js&lt;/a&gt; is a persistent, immutable data structure library for JavaScript. It provides common data structures for JavaScript that do not rely on modifying the underlying data in-place. It has built-in type definitions for both &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/facebook/immutable-js/blob/master/type-definitions/Immutable.d.ts&quot;&gt;TypeScript&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/facebook/immutable-js/blob/master/type-definitions/immutable.js.flow&quot;&gt;Flow&lt;/a&gt; – go look at them. There are countless &lt;code&gt;any&lt;/code&gt; annotations, which disable type-checking for those values. Then there are other types which pass the burden on to the user to provide the correct types. Essentially every time you use the library, you are either opting out of optional types or going to extra lengths to make the types work. This discourages functional programming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ramda is a functional utility library for JavaScript. One set of type definitions can be found &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/types/npm-ramda#status&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, along with this comment (emphasis added):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Note: many of the functions in Ramda are still hard to properly type in Ramda, with issues mainly centered around partial application, currying, and composition, especially so in the presence of generics. &lt;strong&gt;And yes, those are probably why you’d be using Ramda in the first place&lt;/strong&gt;, making these issues particularly problematic to type Ramda for TypeScript. A few links to issues at TS can be found below.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the impressive work of people like &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/gcanti&quot;&gt;Giulio Canti&lt;/a&gt;, every time you choose even slightly more advanced functional programming concepts, like immutable data structures, function composition, or currying, you are essentially opting out of the type checker or going to extra lengths to make the types work. This discourages functional programming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Why we can’t have nice things in JavaScript&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Immutability works best when it is pervasive. But the JavaScript language and ecosystem is designed around mutable data, &lt;a href=&quot;http://tagide.com/blog/research/constraints&quot;&gt;you can’t enforce immutability from a library&lt;/a&gt;, and optional types in JavaScript are not expressive enough to handle immutability as a library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Types work best when they are pervasive. But types in JavaScript are optional by design and limit their expressiveness and utility by taking steep trade-offs to maintain compatibility with JavaScript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Types, immutability, and functional programming can all support each other, just like they do in many languages. Types can be used to enforce immutability, even when the underlying data structures are mutable or the types don’t exist at runtime. Types can help developers connect the piping correctly when using functional composition or transforming data using lenses. Functional transformations can be easier to understand and maintain when you see the types. Functional transformations can be more efficient when you know the underlying data is immutable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Learning to code with fear&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So how do you learn to code with the fear? You write better JavaScript. You start with the base assumption that you can trust little in your code, and learn countless tricks to write more functional JavaScript and avoid the wartier parts of the language. You introduce type validation where necessary. You use immutable data, but only where you have a specific need or you enforce it by convention only. You adopt optional types where it makes sense, but abandon types where functional data handling or immutable data provide greater benefits. You use functional composition or lenses while knowingly opting out of type checking guarantees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or you change the game and just use &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.purescript.org&quot;&gt;PureScript&lt;/a&gt;. Or &lt;a href=&quot;https://bucklescript.github.io&quot;&gt;ReasonML&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&quot;http://elm-lang.org&quot;&gt;Elm&lt;/a&gt;, or even &lt;a href=&quot;https://clojurescript.org/&quot;&gt;ClojureScript&lt;/a&gt;. These exist today. Production software runs on them. They work with the JavaScript ecosystem, where necessary. And they provide a higher base level of trust in the code that you write and an environment where immutability, functional programming, and types (where applicable) work well and work together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adopting one of these languages is not going to solve all of your problems. It will introduce its own problems. But it might give you a higher level of basic trust in your code, and better tools to increase or decrease that trust as needed. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reaktor.com/blog/fear-trust-and-purescript&quot;&gt;In my next post, I discuss how these ideas play together in PureScript&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But in JavaScript, the fear is always with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2018 06:40:52 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>fuzzythinker</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Fear, trust and JavaScript: When types and functional programming fail - Reaktor</og:title>
<og:description>As developers, we want to reduce fear of our code failing and increase trust in our code working well. Many developers working with JavaScript borrow</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.reaktor.com/blog/fear-trust-and-javascript/</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.reaktor.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/reaktor-javascript-reaktor-hero-1024x563.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.reaktor.com/blog/fear-trust-and-javascript/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Periodic Table of Data Structures [pdf]</title>
<link>https://stratos.seas.harvard.edu/files/stratos/files/periodictabledatastructures.pdf</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://stratos.seas.harvard.edu/files/stratos/files/periodictabledatastructures.pdf</guid>
<description>&lt;a href=&quot;https://stratos.seas.harvard.edu/files/stratos/files/periodictabledatastructures.pdf&quot;&gt;Download PDF&lt;/a&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2018 06:02:19 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>asplake</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Fear, trust and JavaScript: When types and functional programming fail - Reaktor</og:title>
<og:description>As developers, we want to reduce fear of our code failing and increase trust in our code working well. Many developers working with JavaScript borrow</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.reaktor.com/blog/fear-trust-and-javascript/</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.reaktor.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/reaktor-javascript-reaktor-hero-1024x563.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://stratos.seas.harvard.edu/files/stratos/files/periodictabledatastructures.pdf</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>What the hell happened to Darius Miles?</title>
<link>https://www.theplayerstribune.com/en-us/articles/what-the-hell-happened-to-darius-miles</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.theplayerstribune.com/en-us/articles/what-the-hell-happened-to-darius-miles</guid>
<description>&lt;span class=&quot;tpt-drop-cap&quot;&gt;D&lt;/span&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;udes like me ain’t supposed to talk about this type of stuff. I’m about to tell you some&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;real&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;shit. Things I haven’t told anybody. But first, we gotta go back in time. We gotta go back to when the NBA was still the NBA. Way back when I had the pager with the two-way alert.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;I’m about to tell you the most Y2K story ever.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;I’m about to tell you how I almost died at Alonzo Mourning’s crib in the year 2000 on some&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;dumb&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;shit.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Picture this. I’m 18 years old. I just got drafted by the Clippers. Just got drafted by the Clippers&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;with&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;my boy Q ― that’s Quentin Richardson, my O.G. from way back ― who as a matter of fact is gonna be riding with me on this joint as my special guest editor.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Editor Q’s note: What’s going on, y’all? Lemme keep this man honest.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;We did everything together back in the day, so we might as well do this together, too, right?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Anyway, they messed around and gave us millions of dollars and put us in Los Angeles, of all places. Only Donald Sterling could’ve been wild enough to sign off on that. Right after the draft, I’m on a private plane to L.A. with Q, and we’re just lookin’ at one another like,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Bruh. Bruh. We on a PJ.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;tpt-pullquote offset right&quot;&gt;They messed around and gave us millions of dollars and put us in Los Angeles, of all places.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;I mean, I’m from East St Louis.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Q is from the Wild Hunneds.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;My momma drove a school bus.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Q’s daddy drove the L Train.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Now we’re sitting on the PJ, bro? We&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;made&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;So we land and it’s like straight outta the movies ― dude is standing next to the black town car holding up a sign with our names on it.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Editor’s note: Like he’s about pass the Grey Poupon.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;It was surreal. I’m coming straight outta high school to this. At least Q had a year of college, you know?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;So they take us to the hotel and it’s not just a fancy hotel ― it’s the&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;L’Ermitage in Beverly Hills. Where Ja Rule had&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;just&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;shot the “Livin’ It Up” video with the slip n’ slides and all that. We get to the room, and all the lights are cutting on before we even hit the switch. Automatic. Nowadays, that’s standard. It’s whatever. But this was 2000. This was not normal. I’m looking at Q like,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Bro, this is crazy.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Editor’s note: Yo, weren’t we supposed to be talking about the Zo story?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;I’m setting the scene for these kids, man! They gotta know what it was like back then. Damn.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;article-image-container alignnone size-full wp-image-143977&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.theplayerstribune.com/uploads/a27f66a7-skm_c36818101712440.jpg?width=1000&quot; class=&quot;article-image&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;article-image-info&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;article-image-credit&quot;&gt;Courtesy of Darius Miles&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Anyway, you gotta remember, we’re 18, 19 years old. So we land in L.A. thinking we about to have a superstar girl, and we’re about to be running the city. But then you realize you’re still a teenager and you can’t really get down like that. So mostly we were playing PlayStation and doing dumb stuff. Then about a month later, we finally get our moment. Alonzo Mourning invites us down to Miami for Zo’s Summer Groove.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;For those who don’t know, Zo’s Summer Groove is legendary. Actors, singers, ballplayers. It’s like a whole week of camps for the kids, and cookouts, and parties. Iverson’s gonna be down there. Marbury. Gary Payton. Lenny Kravitz. Tommy from&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Martin&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;We’re like,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;It’s on.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;First day, we’re doing some basketball camps for the kids, and I go to bed that night feeling a little bit sick. Achy, you know? Then I wake up the next morning and I’m dying. I got these&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;spots&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;all over me. So I go see Zo’s doctor, and at first he didn’t even know what it was.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Then he goes, “You ever had chicken pox?”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;I’m like, “&lt;/span&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Chicken&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;pox?”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;He’s like, “Son, you got adult chicken pox.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;I’m like, “&lt;/span&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Adult&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;chicken pox?”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Can you believe this? I come down with adult fucking chicken pox at Zo’s Summer Groove. I mean, honestly.…&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Now, you can laugh all you want, but if you’ve ever had adult chicken pox, you know it ain’t even funny. I was in bad shape. I was calling my momma like, “Momma! Get on a plane! You gotta come take&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;care&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;of me!”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Man, Q is running around South Beach with these boys and I’m sitting in the tub taking oatmeal baths and shit. And the worst part was that he’d come back to check on me and I’d be laid up in bed with a big-ass ice pack on my forehead, and he’d come running in the room like a little kid — like he was having the time of his&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;life&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Like, “Bro! I was just with A.I. and them! We was in the limo! We was at the club with Wyclef, bro! It was&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;crazy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span&gt;!”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;I got the thermometer in my mouth, just looking at him like,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;DAMN&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;I was so heated. But, after a couple days, I got better. I was back on my feet again. So it was cool. We got to hang out at Zo’s house, and Zo is the man. Zo is the best guy on earth. So Zo being Zo, he’s like, “You guys should go out on the WaveRunners!”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;I’m like, “WaveRunners?”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Zo’s like, “WaveRunners. You know, Jet Skis.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;article-image-container custom-size alignleft wp-image-143990&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.theplayerstribune.com/uploads/72def381-skm_c36818101712431.jpg?width=440&quot; class=&quot;article-image&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;article-image-info&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;article-image-credit&quot;&gt;Courtesy of Darius Miles&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;I’m from East Saint. I’ve never been on a Jet Ski in my life. But me and Q are like,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Yo, we’re at&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;Zo’s&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;house. Let’s go on some WaveRunners&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span&gt;. So we get out on the water, and we’re loving it. We’re some 18-year-old millionaires living in a rap video, right? We’re cruising around, laughing, looking for dolphins or whatever. WE LIVIN’ IT UP.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Now, what you gotta know is ― there were all these boats docked in the marina. But one of them was real low in the water, like a speedboat or something. You could barely see it. So there was this little red flag sticking up out of the water. Before we went out, I remember Zo saying something about this little red flag. “Watch out for that little red flag,” and such and such.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;But now we’re out in the water, and the sun is shining, and we’re flying around.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Bro, the last thing I saw was that little red flag.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Then I was in the air.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Editor’s note: You were in The Matrix. Floating.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;I hit the edge of that boat with the Jet Ski and I flipped ― I’m talking&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;flipped&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;that bitch. And now I’m upside down, flying through the air. And I can just see the newspapers flashing in my mind, like, NBA ROOKIE DIES IN DAMN JET SKI ACCIDENT IN SOUTH BEACH.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;So I’m like,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Nah, I did not survive 18 years of my life in East St. Louis to drown in Alonzo Mourning’s damn marina. We’re not going out like that.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;So I do a little tuck-and-roll or whatever, and I hit the water.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Ploosh&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span&gt;. Go under. Now, you might not know this about me, but I can really swim. I’m like the black Michael Phelps. That’s no problem. But the thing about me is, I don’t do ocean water. Too murky, man. If I can’t see underneath me, I’m&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;out&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span&gt;.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;So I pop my head up out the water, and I’m treading, but I’m feeling this seaweed touching my foot. This creepy-ass seaweed. I’m not having that. I’m yelling at Q, like, “Bruh! Come get me! Yo, come&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;get&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;me!”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Editor’s note: This man is like, “Q! HELP ME! This seaweed is touching me, bro! HELP ME!” So I come flying over there to rescue my boy on some&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;Baywatch&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;shit. We get him up out of the water and away from the seaweeds, and we ride out.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Now, imagine this …. two dudes from East Saint and the Wild Hunneds on a WaveRunner in the summer of 2000, going back to Zo’s crib to tell him we crashed his damn Jet Ski into his neighbor’s damn speed boat.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;That was the old NBA. That was before they wised up.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That don’t exist anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;tpt-apostrophe-divider&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;article-image-container custom-size alignright wp-image-143904&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.theplayerstribune.com/uploads/44ae8b94-skm_c36818101712530.jpg?width=401&quot; class=&quot;article-image&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;article-image-info&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;article-image-credit&quot;&gt;Courtesy of Darius Miles&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;When you pop out the womb in East St. Louis, it’s guns, drugs and danger, from start to finish. And I’m not saying that to brag or nothing. It’s just what it is. It’s the murder capital. And the thing about it is that it’s only 89 blocks.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;So no matter who you are, or how much you try to keep your head down … there’s nowhere to hide. You’re&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;in&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;it. There’s no choice. Fact of the matter is, I had a lot of cousins who were street pharmacists. A lot of my people were Streets Disciples. It was what it was. You heard gunshots every night. Routine. You don’t know any different. But that’s the thing ― you might read about those kinds of places, or see them on TV. I don’t think the average person reading this in Montana or whatever understands what it’s like to be a kid in that environment.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;You don’t have any dreams. You’re just thinking about survival.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;I’ll give you a story. I was in sixth grade when those roll-away basketball hoops just started coming out. Before that, you had to nail a backboard to a light pole or whatever. But when the roll-away hoops came out, you could play wherever. So one day, we were playing in the middle of the street. Normal day.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;All of a sudden, this dude comes walking out of one of the houses. And you could just&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;tell&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;by the way he was walking that something was about to happen. You develop a sixth sense for that kind of thing, even when you’re a little-ass kid. You got that PTSD Spidey Sense in your gut, like you’re in war or something. And just the&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;way&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;this dude was walking, I got this feeling like I should run.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;But I didn’t run.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;I mean, I didn’t do nothing wrong. What do I got to worry about?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;He walks straight up to me.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Pulls out his gun. Puts it up to my forehead. And I remember I could see the bullet in that joint.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;He’s saying something about a car.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The funny thing is, I can’t even remember what exactly it was all about. He thought somebody was trying to steal his car, or his car stereo, or his CDs, or whatever. It didn’t matter. In that moment, when you got a gun to your head, details don’t mean anything. Right and wrong don’t mean anything.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;I was the youngest kid out there, but I was the biggest. So he came straight at me, thinking I was the leader. When you’re looking down the barrel of a gun, you got one thing that can save you, and it ain’t reasoning with the man. It’s power.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;tpt-pullquote offset right&quot;&gt;When you’re looking down the barrel of a gun, you got one thing that can save you, and it ain’t reasoning with the man. It’s power.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;So I said, “I’m so-and-so’s son.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;I dropped my dad’s name.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;He said, “What?”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;I said, “I’m&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;so-and-so’s&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;son. I wouldn’t do this.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;My father wasn’t really in my life, but he was a known guy. His name carried weight. That was probably the only thing that saved me. The dude lowered his gun, told us to get the hell up out of there, and he went back inside.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;But that’s not the end of the story. Like I said, this is East St. Louis. This is 89 blocks. There’s nowhere to hide. This dude could still get to me whenever he wanted. So I ran straight home and told my momma what happened, and she went and got&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;her&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;gun. Then she called all my cousins, and they rolled up on the dude’s house and popped the trunk.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;When they pop the trunk on you, they’re coming in like Navy SEALs.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;So they went in and sent the message.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;And the message was, “You do not ever, in a million years, fuck with Ethel’s son again.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Dude got the message, you feel me?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;My momma had my back every single day. If she didn’t, I probably wouldn’t be here. It’s ruthless. You can be minding your own business playing ball with your friends when shots start ringing out. It’s everyday. It’s routine. I’ve been shot at many times. I’ve got homies who are locked up, homies who are dead and gone, homies who got bodies on them like they’ve been in wars, for real.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;I tell people like this: In East St. Louis, nobody’s going to the gun range. I never went to a gun range in my life. When dudes shot their guns for target practice, they did it right in their backyard. I’m talking AR-15s with the 50-round clip. And no police are coming around. The police and the ambulances, they aren’t showing up until it’s all over.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;That’s the environment we came up in. We weren’t dumb enough to have dreams. So it ain’t no surprise that nobody made it out of East St. Louis. We had&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;one&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;guy to look to when I was a kid: LaPhonso Ellis. He made it to the NBA and he never came back.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;I remember when I got to high school, and I started getting letters from colleges, it didn’t even feel real. It felt like another world. That world wasn’t&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;for&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;us, you know? There was one moment that kind of changed my life, though.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;It was the day I met MJ.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;I was in 10th grade, and me and Q got invited to his camp in Chicago. Now, up until that point, I was playing a different kind of basketball. I was playing with grown men in pro-ams, for money. I was 13 years old playing with 30-year-old dudes, and after we’d win the championship, they’d be asking my momma if I could go to celebrate with them at The Pink Slip.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The Pink Slip was a real popular gentlemen’s establishment. That was the kind of ball I was playing, you know what I’m saying?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;But then me and Q got invited to Jordan’s camp, and that was mind-blowing. We had WGN, so we got every single Bulls game. MJ was a hero to every kid, but to us, it was a different level.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;We get to camp the first day, and there’s MJ, in real life.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Editor’s note: MJ is like your pops. As soon as he walks in the room, you straighten up. You’re on your best behavior.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;And when he starts playing with us, nobody wants to guard him. Remember, we’re kids. Who’s trying to go at MJ like that, for real? But me and Q are looking at each other like,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Shoot, we ain’t scared.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;So I went at MJ hard ― and of course he’s MJ, so he got moves. He killed me. But I still went at him hard, and he started showing me respect. After the camp, I got a picture with him and everything, and I took it home and put it on the mantle like MJ was one of my uncles or something.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;And I remember my momma said, “What’s MJ like?”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;And I said, “Momma, it’s so crazy. Michael Jordan was out here cussin’. He talks just like us!”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;That was the first glimmer of hope, like …&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Oh damn, Michael Jordan is like me. He’s a normal dude. Maybe I can make it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;But if I’m being honest, I still didn’t really believe it. Day to day was too intense. You don’t know what might happen. By my junior year, I knew I was one of the best players in the state for sure, and maybe the country, but this was back when stuff was way more word-of-mouth. You didn’t really&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;know&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;like that. I just knew that our games were&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;packed&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span&gt;. It was like the whole city shut down. People used to stop selling drugs for two hours just to come see me play.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;And then one day, we come out for warmups and I see the security guards roping off this section in front of all the students. Literally like a velvet rope. I see these dudes walking into the gym in polo shirts. Only white dudes in the gym. Only white dudes in East St. Louis.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;I knew right then. It’s&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;on&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span&gt;. I’m about to put on a show for these guys.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;It was like that every game. They set up their little VIP section for the dudes in the polos.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Then my senior year, I’ll never forget it. I look over to the Polo Section during warmups and I saw that logo.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;I saw that damn purple dinosaur.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The Toronto Raptors’ scouts came out to watch me.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;And that’s when I knew I was really, really, really about to do it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;I was really about to get out.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;tpt-apostrophe-divider&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Let me try to break it down for you. I don’t think people really understand how crazy it is to go from high school to the NBA. And not just to the NBA, but to the damn Los Angeles&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Clippers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Pre-social media.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;If Twitter had existed back then, it would’ve been a wrap.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Editor’s note: A wrap.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;We used to have Alvin Gentry losing his damn mind. We literally showed up for Day One of training camp with Super Soakers.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Editor’s note: Big dumb-ass Super Soakers with the shoulder strap and everything.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;I remember we busted in and we were terrorizing everybody, and the OG Derek Strong just looked up from his locker, cold as ice, as he goes, “Don’t you be shooting me with no&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;water&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span&gt;.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;We were just kids ― all of us. Me. Q. Lamar Odom. Corey Maggette. Keyon Dooling. We were like a college team. We used to roll everywhere together&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;at least&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;five deep. Imagine in this day and age, five NBA players rolling up to the damn mall together, walking into Macy’s, like&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;What’s Good?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;article-image-container fullbleed alignnone wp-image-143913 size-full&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.theplayerstribune.com/uploads/3f8c0fb6-gettyimages-73812115.jpg?width=1440&quot; class=&quot;article-image&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;article-image-info&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;article-image-credit&quot;&gt;Andy Hayt/NBAE/Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;This was a different time, man. This was the peak of the Sterling era. I mean, we used to literally practice at a damn JUCO. A junior college. In South Central.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Editor’s note: You couldn’t even shower. The showers were those old-school joints with the one big-ass pipe in the middle of the floor with the spouts sticking out every which way. Half of ’em broke. It was ridiculous.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;We had players pulling up to a JUCO parking lot in Inglewood driving Aston Martins and Ferraris. Random dudes were coming out of class, walking across the cut, like “Yooooooooooooooooo!”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;I mean, me and Q, we were used to it. It was nothing. We grew up in that environment.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;But you know, we had Eric Piatkowski coming from South Dakota, and he was just like, “Yoooooooo, what the&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;hell&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;is going on? Get me&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;outta&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;here.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;We didn’t know any better. We’re thinking this is the NBA. But then I remember we went to Dallas for a preseason game, and we rolled up to their locker room and saw what they had going on. And we were like, “Yooooooo!”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;They had flat screens in every locker, heated seats, everything.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;That was the first sign that something was up.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Then we played against Houston, and Moe Taylor had just left the Clippers to go there in the offseason, and this man is looking like he just escaped from a kidnapping or something. He drops like a 30-clip on us, and after every bucket, he’s running past Donald Sterling’s seat, grabbing his damn nuts.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;We’re like,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Bruh. This is not normal.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;That’s when we knew: Something is going on here.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Editor’s note: People ask us about Sterling all the time, looking for crazy stories. But honestly, he wasn’t really around like that. Every once in a while, he would pop into the locker room outta nowhere with all his old-ass friends wearing mink coats and shit. We’d be buck-naked, changing, and he’d say wild-ass stuff, like, “Look at these boys! Look at my beautiful boys!” And we’d just be shooting each other looks like, “Yo! Duh fuuuuuuuuck?”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;We knew that we got stuck with the worst team in the league, and we knew the owner was a weird dude, but we just felt like we had the talent and the energy to change the culture.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Maybe we weren’t gonna win, but we were gonna entertain the hell out of you.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Now, I’ll be honest with you. I wasn’t a shooter. I couldn’t throw a rock in the ocean. But I could dunk on&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;anybody&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span&gt;. Go ahead and check the tapes. I was aggressive. I was a dog.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;It’s funny, I ran into Shawn Kemp after we played Portland, and he was one of my heros. I used to watch all his tapes.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;He said, “Look, I’m not gonna try to tell you anything. But lemme just say this. Every time you dunk, you dunk&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;hard&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span&gt;. If you do that, you know what’s gonna happen?”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;I said, “What, Shawn?”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;He said, “They gonna stop jumpin’. They gonna start wavin’ atcha.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Man, after Shawn Kemp told me that … every time I dunked the ball, I tried to dunk the&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;shit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;outta that motherfucker.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;And he was right.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a while, they was doing this &lt;span class=&quot;article-image-container alignnone size-full wp-image-144118&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.theplayerstribune.com/uploads/1cbc0ac1-waving-hand-sign_1f44b.png?width=1000&quot; class=&quot;article-image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;We had the city electrified, man. If you weren’t alive then, and you just looked up the stats, you might think I’m lying.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;But I ain’t lying.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;article-image-container alignnone size-full wp-image-143988&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.theplayerstribune.com/uploads/0032f73d-gettyimages-52946709.jpg?width=1000&quot; class=&quot;article-image&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;article-image-info&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;article-image-credit&quot;&gt;Fernando Medina/NBAE/Getty Images)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;We only won 31 games that first season, but you would’ve thought we made the Conference Finals. Everybody showed us love.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Editor’s note: Everybody.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;I remember one day I was running late for practice, so I was flying down the 405. All of a sudden, I look in the rearview, and I see the flashing lights. This unmarked police truck is right up on me. Tinted windows. Big heavy-duty truck.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Woop-woop.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;I knew I was speeding. So I pull over, and I roll the window down, and I’m reaching over into the glove compartment to get my papers ….&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;… Then I hear this voice. Big, booming voice.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;“WHERE YOU G’WAN, BOY?”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;I’m like, Damn, they got the sergeant on me or something?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;I turn to look out the window, and I can’t even see this dude’s face he’s so big. All I see is his chest.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;“I SAID WHERE YOU G’WAN BOY?”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Then he bends down and looks in the window.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Big, dumbass grin on his face.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;It’s Shaq.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;I’m like, “Yo! I’m going to practice! You made me late!”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;He don’t miss a beat. He taps side of my truck, turns around and says, “Don’t worry about it. I’ll pay your fine. Just holler at me.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;I’m looking in the rearview mirror, like,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;How the hell&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;…&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Shaq’s got one of those old-school police lights that you put on the hood of your car like you see on&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;C.O.P.S.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;He gets in, laughing his ass off, waving at me.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Editor’s note: Shaq would really be messing with you like that. He was the coolest dude in the world. Remember he invited us over to his house for New Year’s Eve?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;I don’t even really know how to describe what was going on …. We walk in the crib and Shaq’s got this movie on his big screen. Like a DVD. And it’s real professional. It’s a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;real&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;movie. Only it’s Shaq and his boys just messing around, fighting ninjas and shit. I’m talking&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;real&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;extras, throwing ninjas stars and everything. And Shaq’s got this crazy wig on, and he’s doing Kung-Fu flips and flying through windows and whatnot. It was&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;crazy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Editor’s note: I turn around and Mystikal is standing there, eating a potato chip or something, watching this movie, like, “Damn …” I was buggin’ out. I was like, “Yo! Is this real life?”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The respect we got from the legends in the league was something nobody can take away from us. If you were&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;anybody&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;back in 2001, 2002, 2003 and you threw down a dunk on somebody, or you just were walking down the street and you saw somebody&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;real&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span&gt;, you knew what to do.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;You were throwing up them fists.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Two taps to the head.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;article-image-container alignnone size-full wp-image-143983&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.theplayerstribune.com/uploads/27de3b87-2taps.gif?width=1000&quot; class=&quot;article-image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Editor’s note: You want to clear it up for the people? You want to tell them the real story?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Man, we heard everything over the years. Every theory in the book. Some people thought it was a gang sign, some people thought it had something to do with aliens, some people thought it was a sign of disrespect. It was none of that. For whatever reason, we decided early on to keep it between us.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The real story is this.… We were so young that we couldn’t really go to the clubs, so we used drive around L.A. going to high school basketball games. We always used to go to Westchester High games because they had the prettiest girls.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Editor’s note: Yo! I was trying to go to the club. But D used to drag me to these games on his young-boy shit, and he would literally have these high school girls thinking they were about to go to prom with a Clipper.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;I’m 18. I’m in my element, you know? I’ll mess around and go to prom. Why not? Anyway, it wasn’t just about the girls. Westchester had a really good team, so we used to go watch Trevor Ariza and Hassan Adams and Bobby Brown and those boys. I don’t know how it got started, but they’d throw up their fists after they made a three.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;So we’d be hanging with them, and they’d be like, “Come on, when you gonna shout us out? You gotta do it. Show us some love.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;So cut to me dunking the shit out of the ball, or Q hitting a big three-pointer or something, I can’t even remember, and one of us throws it up. Two taps to the head. For them boys from Westchester High.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;We didn’t think anything of it. But then it just took on a life of its own. Everybody started doing it. I was sitting on the couch one day watching football, and Jerry Rice catches a touchdown and&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;he’s&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;doing it. Jerry fucking Rice is throwing it up in the endzone. It was totally unplanned, unexplained, uncut.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;It didn’t mean nothing, but it meant&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;everything&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;It was just … the culture.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Editor’s note: We started a movement, all because D was trying to mess around and go to prom.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;For a minute there, we really were the culture.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Editor’s note: That’s on MJ, too.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;People ask us all the time how we got signed by Jordan Brand so young. We were&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;rookies&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;rocking Jordan Brand. Man, it’s a crazy story. Right after we got drafted, me and Q were at Jordan’s camp in Santa Barbara. This was right after Zo’s Summer Groove. So we’re sitting around after a game, icing our knees or something, and MJ comes walking over to us, looking all concerned.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Or maybe disappointed is the right word.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;You know when your pops is disappointed in you?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;He’s looking down at our feet.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;He says, “What’s all&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;this&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;bullshit?”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Man, that summer, And1 had been sending us all this free stuff. I’m talking&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;crates&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;of shoes, clothes, headbands. That was when And1 was really popping, so we were rocking with it. We don’t know no better! We’re 19, like,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;we winning!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;article-image-container custom-size alignright wp-image-143979&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.theplayerstribune.com/uploads/784c1f5d-gettyimages-104538966.jpg?width=560&quot; class=&quot;article-image&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;article-image-info&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;article-image-credit&quot;&gt;Jean-Paul Aussenard/WireImage&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;MJ is not having it. He’s looking down at our feet, wild disappointed.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;We straighten up, like, “Uh, yo … They sent us … Yo it’s free. We don’t know.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;He’s looking at us, cold. Studying us.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Then he’s like, “But you want to be Nike, right?”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;We’re like, “Yeah, MJ!”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;MJ turns around, super cool, and he just goes, “Alright, I got you.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Like two days later, our agent is calling us up all breathless and whatnot, like “Guys! I just got these contracts faxed over from Jordan Brand! Guys! God&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;damn&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span&gt;!”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;I mean, Mike’s picture was on my mantle in East Saint, you know? That meant more than anything that he showed us respect like that and made us part of his family. We started getting all these boxes of super-rare Js mailed to us before they even came out. And maybe this sounds crazy, but that was the moment that really gave me chills. If you’re not from where we’re from, then maybe you won’t understand what I mean.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;But that was the moment that was like …&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Damn&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span&gt;, look at where we are now.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Mike is sending us Js.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Mike is sending Js. To&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;us&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;We’re talking&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Mike&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Man, I had my whole family rocking Js.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;I had my&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;grandmomma&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;rocking Js.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;I had the whole of East St. Louis rocking Js.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;We were on a mission. We wanted to put our whole swag on it. Everytime we laced ’em up, we wanted to entertain you. We really felt like we were doing it for the culture.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;I’ll never forget, Paul Pierce came up to me after our second year in the league. Now, Paul is a real dude. He’s from Inglewood. He was like, “Man, lemme tell you something. I don’t got&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;nobody’s&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;jersey in the league. I don’t get down like that. But I got your jersey. I like you guys.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;That was the ultimate respect, for us. We got put on the worst team in the league, with the weirdest owner in the world, practicing in a damn JUCO in South Central. But if you were&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;anybody&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;in Los Angeles back then, you want to rock the red, white and blue.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;We were aggressive. We were some dogs. We were The Show.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;We were fucking&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;real&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;And then they blew it all up.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;tpt-apostrophe-divider&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;My OG used to tell me some words of wisdom, and I never wanted to listen.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;He said, “You can stay real. But don’t be&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;too&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;real.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;I used to go back to East St. Louis every summer, even when I was in the league. I bought up damn near the whole block I grew up on. I remember as soon as I started getting some buzz, everybody would say, “Don’t forget about us.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;And I promised I wouldn’t.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;In my mind, I was coming back for the kids, so they could see what kind of car I was driving, and how I was living, and the stories I was telling.… Just to see that it was possible to get up out of there.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;I thought the streets loved me. That was my curse.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The streets don’t love you like that. The streets don’t love nobody.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;When you’re young, you think the money is gonna last forever. I don’t care how street smart you are, or who you got in your corner, when you go from not having anything to making millions of dollars at 18, 19 years old, you’re not going to be prepared for it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;If you read the headlines about me now, it’s all about me going bankrupt. People ask me, “Man, how can you lose all that money?”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;That part is easy to explain. You already heard that story a million times, with a million players. The cliche is that guys go broke buying Ferraris or whatever. Listen, it takes a long time to go broke buying Ferraris. What makes you go broke are shady business deals.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;They’ll make the money disappear quick.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;But if I’m being honest, that’s not really the most interesting part of my story. In the end, when I was at my lowest point, I didn’t even want the money anymore. I didn’t care about anything. I couldn’t even leave the house.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;I was paranoid. I was depressed. I was gonna hurt somebody.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;I was in a dark, dark place, man.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;article-image-container fullbleed alignnone wp-image-144037 size-full&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.theplayerstribune.com/uploads/58a57613-darius-miles.jpg?width=1440&quot; class=&quot;article-image&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;article-image-info&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;article-image-credit&quot;&gt;Jeffery Salter/The Players' Tribune&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;It’s crazy to think about, but six years after we were at the peak with the Young Clippers, I was basically out of the league. I was 27 years old, and I had doctors telling me that my knee was too messed up to play basketball ever again.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;My whole life, I used basketball as an escape. When you grow up how I grew up, I think you’re probably bound to have some kind of PTSD. I ain’t a doctor, but when you grow up running from gunshots all the time, I think there’s something inside you that never leaves. I used to feel this&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;pressure&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;on me — I’m talking like a physical pressure, you know? But I used to be able to go out onto a basketball court and just unleash it. You could let it all out. You could dunk the&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;shit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;outta that motherfucker in front of 100 people or 20,000 people and feel good for a minute.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Basketball got taken away from me at 27, and I was lost. I was just kind of going through the motions. Then a couple years later, my momma got taken away from me, and I pretty much went insane.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;When you’re in the NBA, people think you’re a superhero. Maybe you think you’re a superhero, too. But there’s all kinds of stuff going on under the surface that nobody has any idea about. My momma battled three different cancers while I was in the league ― liver cancer, colon cancer, bone cancer. When I think about all the teams I played for after L.A. ― Cleveland, Portland, Memphis ― what I remember first is the doctors and the hospitals in all those cities.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;I was dealing with all that for most of my career, and I was just … burying it, you know? I prided myself on standing tall through it all and never breaking. I never cried ― not once. My people were dropping like flies when I was in the league ― homies, cousins, my grandmomma ― and I never cried, not one damn time.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;I lost my grandaddy to throat cancer. Lost my grandma to heart disease. Lost my best friend Geracy to the streets. He got stabbed to death in 2004, when we came back home for the summer.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;I’m not saying that for sympathy. Everybody goes through darkness. I’m just saying that I kept my head up through&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;all&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;of that.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;But my mom was a different story.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;I don’t care&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;how&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;hard you are … your momma is your momma.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;article-image-container custom-size alignleft wp-image-144034&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.theplayerstribune.com/uploads/e298a786-skm_c36818101712411-1.jpg?width=440&quot; class=&quot;article-image&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;article-image-info&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;article-image-credit&quot;&gt;Courtesy of Darius Miles&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;I remember when she was near the end, she was doing chemo twice a week, and she couldn’t even put her hand in the refrigerator. She couldn’t even have a cold glass of water. She went to pick the dog up one day, and her arm broke. She was kind of disappearing right in front of me. That’s my momma, you know? When a dude pulled a gun on me, this was the woman who went and got&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;her&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;gun.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;She was the one person who always had my back, no matter what I did.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The last two weeks, she couldn’t talk.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;We didn’t have to say anything, though. She was with me the whole way. The whole damn ride. She&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;knew&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;When she died, I ain’t gonna lie, it broke me.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;After the funeral, I was supposed to clean out her house, and I just couldn’t do it. I didn’t leave her house for an entire year. I never made it past the front yard, for real. I just didn’t have the will to do anything. I went Zero Dark Thirty on everybody. I wasn’t answering anybody’s texts. I wasn’t even answering Qs texts. And it wasn’t like people weren’t trying to help me, but I didn’t want the help. I was just …&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;gone&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;I would sleep in the daytime then stay up all night drinking wine and smoking weed, just to try to get out of my head. I was paranoid. I had my concealed carry permit, so I had a gun on me at all times. The worst part was that I had people who owed me a lot of money, and I just got to a point where I was seeing red, for real. I felt like I was gonna hurt somebody, or I was gonna wind up in jail.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;I know dudes like me aren’t supposed to talk about depression, but I’ll talk about it. If a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;real&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;motherfucker like me can struggle with it, then anybody can struggle with it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;I was stuck in my momma’s house in East St. Louis for like three years. I worked my whole life to get out of there, and I was back. Just … trapped. Carrying my gun with me everywhere. Couldn’t sleep. Couldn’t escape my own head. Couldn’t find any peace.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;tpt-pullquote offset right&quot;&gt;I worked my whole life to get out of there, and I was back. Just … trapped&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Then one night, I just had enough.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;I called up Q.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Q had been living down in Florida for years.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;I said, “Q, it’s nice down there?”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Q said, “Hell yeah.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;I said, “I think I’m gonna come down there.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Q said, “Hell&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;yeah&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span&gt;.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;I packed up a U-Haul, and I drove 14 hours straight through the night. I had to do&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;something&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span&gt;. I had to make a change.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;I hear people talking, like, “What the hell happened to Darius Miles?”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;article-image-container alignnone size-full wp-image-143969&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.theplayerstribune.com/uploads/0f3c15ba-salter_101818_e_452_fnl.jpg?width=1000&quot; class=&quot;article-image&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;article-image-info&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;article-image-credit&quot;&gt;Jeffery Salter/The Players' Tribune&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;They ask about the money, but they don’t ask about my momma.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;They don’t ask me where I came from, and all the things I’ve seen.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;I done it all. I made it and spent it. Went from The Pink Slip to the L’Ermitage. I rode in all them limos. I lived a life, boy.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Now, I live down the street from Q in Florida. I like it down there. For the first time in years, I can sleep at night. I don’t have to carry a gun. I can finally get a little bit of peace. I’m just trying to get better, day by day. Trying to be a better person, day by day.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Me and Q, we don’t got the matching trucks no more. We’re not living that lifestyle. But you know what? You can say whatever you want about us, but you can’t take away a real simple fact.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;It don’t matter who we run into ― MJ, Paul Pierce, Shawn Kemp, some random dude on the street …&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;tpt-pullquote offset right&quot;&gt;I done it all. I made it and spent it. Went from The Pink Slip to the L’Ermitage. I rode in all them limos. I lived a life, boy.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;They&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;know&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span&gt;. They know what we did.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Editor’s note: They know.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Matter fact, I was checking into a hotel just the other day. Bellhop is going about his business. Loading some bags or whatever. Then he looks over at me.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;He’s like, “Is that … are you … yooooo!”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;He don’t have to say anything else. He just looks me dead in the eyes from across the lobby, and he throws it up.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Two taps to the head.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;He&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;knows&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;So,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;What the hell happened to Darius Miles?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;Man, a lot. A lot happened to Darius Miles.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;But it’s 2018 now — and I’ll tell you one thing.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;He alright.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Editor’s note: (Two taps to the head.)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.theplayerstribune.com/products/two-fists&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;article-image-container alignnone wp-image-144210 size-full&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.theplayerstribune.com/uploads/a92389a2-2-fists_black_v2.jpg?width=1000&quot; class=&quot;article-image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.theplayerstribune.com/products/two-fists-ii&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;article-image-container alignnone wp-image-144200 size-full&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.theplayerstribune.com/uploads/6c8321a3-2-fists.jpg?width=1000&quot; class=&quot;article-image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2018 05:56:28 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ribasushi</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.theplayerstribune.com/en-us/articles/what-the-hell-happened-to-darius-miles</og:url>
<og:title>What the Hell Happened to Darius Miles? | By Darius Miles</og:title>
<og:description>Dudes like me ain’t supposed to talk about this type of stuff. I’m about to tell you some real shit. Things I haven’t told anybody.</og:description>
<og:image>https://storage.googleapis.com/www-theplayerstribune-com/uploads/9b012187-darius-milessocial-card.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.theplayerstribune.com/en-us/articles/what-the-hell-happened-to-darius-miles</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Some private equity firms are furious over a paper in a dermatology journal</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/10/26/health/private-equity-dermatology.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2018/10/26/health/private-equity-dermatology.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;css-18sbwfn StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Early this month, a respected medical journal published a research paper on its website that analyzed the effects of a business trend roiling the field of dermatology: the rapid entrance of private equity firms into the specialty by buying and running practices around the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Eight days later, after an outcry from private equity executives and dermatologists associated with private equity firms, the editor of the publication removed the paper from the site. No reason was given.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Furor over the publication and subsequent removal of the article has deepened a rift in the field over what some see as the “corporatization” of dermatology and other areas of medicine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/11/20/health/dermatology-skin-cancer.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;css-8qgvsz euv7paa0&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 ehxkw330&quot;&gt;[The once sleepy field of dermatology is booming these days. Read our story.]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The paper was published on the website of the Journal of the American Academy of Dermatology on Oct. 5, posted along with numerous other articles labeled “In Press Accepted Manuscript.” Most articles with this designation eventually appear in a print edition of the journal; some remain online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;css-18sbwfn StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Dr. Dirk Elston, the journal’s editor, said in an email that he replaced the article with a notice of “temporary removal” after receiving multiple calls and emails “expressing concerns about the accuracy of a few parts” of the article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;On Wednesday, nearly two weeks after removing the article, Dr. Elston told the authors they had a choice: They could correct “factual errors” or retract the paper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The authors maintain that the article does not contain any factual errors and that several of the corrections requested had to do with protecting the reputation of the specialty and the leaders of the American Academy of Dermatology, the association that publishes the journal. Later on Wednesday, they submitted some revisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The article had gone through the standard editorial process of academic journals, undergoing multiple revisions based on feedback from peer-reviewers selected by the journal, before being accepted for publication. It presents data to support a conclusion that private equity firms acquire “outlier” practices — that is, practices that perform an unusually high number of well-reimbursed procedures and bill high amounts to Medicare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“It was interesting when we ran the numbers and we were counting how many practices with billing outliers were being acquired by private equity,” said Dr. Joseph Francis, a dermatologist in Florida who is a co-author on the paper. “With every revision of the paper, that number kept increasing. So it didn’t seem like an anomaly.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-18sbwfn StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;He added, “It wasn’t clear whether these investors realized that the high billing might point to anything irregular. They might have just seen that this was a practice with booming business.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The paper also notes that many practices backed by private equity firms have opened or acquired labs to process pathology specimens, potentially another source of profit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Among those who objected to the article was Dr. George Hruza, the incoming president of the American Academy of Dermatology. Dr. Hruza, whose one-year term as president begins in March, is a dermatologist in Chesterfield, Mo. In 2016 he sold his own dermatology practice to United Skin Specialists, a firm that manages dermatology practices and is backed by private equity. He currently serves on the board of directors of United Skin Specialists, which he said is an unpaid position.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Dr. Hruza is not named in the journal article, but he said he is easily identified by the authors’ reference to his pending presidency of the academy, and to United Skin Specialists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;In an interview, Dr. Hruza said he did not ask that the paper be taken down. He did, however, confirm that he expressed his concerns to Dr. Elston, the editor, after it was posted. Two days later, Dr. Elston removed the paper. A flurry of intense conversations ensued among Dr. Elston; Dr. Hruza; the current academy president, Dr. Suzanne Olbricht; a lawyer for the dermatology academy; and the paper’s authors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1xdhyk6 e1vv25i80&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1afaoz0&quot;&gt;Image&lt;/span&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;css-1m50asq&quot; src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/10/25/science/00DERMATOLOGY2/00DERMATOLOGY2-articleLarge.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;auto=webp&amp;amp;disable=upscale&quot; srcset=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/10/25/science/00DERMATOLOGY2/00DERMATOLOGY2-articleLarge.jpg?quality=90&amp;amp;auto=webp 600w,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/10/25/science/00DERMATOLOGY2/00DERMATOLOGY2-jumbo.jpg?quality=90&amp;amp;auto=webp 1024w,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/10/25/science/00DERMATOLOGY2/00DERMATOLOGY2-superJumbo.jpg?quality=90&amp;amp;auto=webp 2048w&quot; sizes=&quot;((min-width: 600px) and (max-width: 1004px)) 84vw, (min-width: 1005px) 60vw, 100vw&quot; itemprop=&quot;url&quot; itemid=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/10/25/science/00DERMATOLOGY2/00DERMATOLOGY2-articleLarge.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;auto=webp&amp;amp;disable=upscale&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;css-1wp6toh e1olku6u0&quot;&gt;Dr. Sailesh Konda, left, and Dr. Joseph Francis, authors of a paper that has caused a stir in the field of dermatology.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-18sbwfn StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Specifically, Dr. Hruza said, he objected to one of the paper’s conclusions: Influential dermatology leaders are being recruited to work for and promote dermatology practices backed by private-equity firms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-18sbwfn StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“Implying motivation is a stretch,” he said. Dr. Hruza has asked for specific wording changes to that section of the paper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Among the changes the editor of the journal asked the authors to make was the removal of identifiable references to influential dermatologists, including Dr. Hruza.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Interference with a scientific paper from within the ranks of a medical society is highly unusual, say experts in the medical publishing field. The sudden disappearance of the paper has others in the medical publishing world scratching their heads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“The process of science requires that people be allowed to publish their data as long as it has been reviewed by peers who find it accurate in that moment,” said Dr. Mitchell Katz, president and chief executive of NYC Health &amp;amp; Hospitals and Deputy Editor of the journal JAMA Internal Medicine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;As for corrections, Dr. Katz added, “usually you would post a correct copy rather than removing a paper for days on end.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Dr. Elston said others who objected to the article included Dr. Darrell Rigel, a prominent dermatologist in New York who is a former president of the academy and whose practice is now owned by Schweiger Dermatology, a private equity-backed practice. Dr. Rigel did not respond to requests for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Dermatologists account for one percent of physicians in the United States, but &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jamadermatology/article-abstract/2664345&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;15 percent of recent private equity acquisitions of medical practices have involved dermatology practices.&lt;/a&gt; Other specialties that have attracted private equity investment include orthopedics, radiology, cardiology, urgent care, anesthesiology and ophthalmology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-18sbwfn StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;One of the paper’s five supplemental tables lists 32 dermatology practices in the United States that have been formed or acquired by private equity firms. Many are large practices with dozens of physicians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Shortly after the article disappeared from the journal’s website, a copy was posted to a Facebook group composed of some 3,500 dermatologists. Several participants in the Facebook group praised the article for shining a light on the effects of private equity on their specialty, and were outraged that the article had been withdrawn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“If this were an article on psoriasis no one would be questioning it, but this was going to ruffle some feathers,” said Dr. Curtis Asbury, a dermatologist in Selbyville, Del., and an active participant in the Facebook group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The lead author of the paper was Dr. Sailesh Konda, an assistant clinical professor of dermatology at the University of Florida College of Medicine. Dr. Konda, 34, said he first grew interested in the topic when several of his trainees went to work for private equity-backed practices and told him of clinical environments that emphasized profits at the expense of patient care. He said that over the past year he had given 16 talks around the country to medical residents and dermatology societies about private equity. Dr. Francis has joined him for some of the sessions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Dr. Konda said he and his co-authors spent a year working on the paper. After the paper went out for review, he said, “we received constructive feedback.” Most of the comments, he said, were about maintaining a neutral tone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“We strived to not use any polemic words, which could be interpreted as bias,” he said. “We decided to just deal with the facts, which would speak for themselves.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;This week a lawyer for Advanced Dermatology and Cosmetic Surgery, which is backed by private equity and is the largest dermatology practice in the United States, called the general counsel at the University of Florida, where two of the authors are employed, demanding specific changes to the paper. The general counsel for the university declined to comment. Dr. Matt Leavitt, the chief executive of Advanced Dermatology, did not respond to requests for a comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Dr. Konda says he plans to continue his research into private equity. “I am passionate about this topic,” he said. “I realize we live in a capitalist society and money is a driving force behind many decisions regardless of the industry. However, I believe there has to be a balance between profit and patient care.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2018 00:56:09 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ItsMe000001</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/10/26/health/private-equity-dermatology.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Why Private Equity Is Furious Over a Paper in a Dermatology Journal</og:title>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/10/27/business/27DERMATOLOGY1-print/00DERMATOLOGY1-facebookJumbo.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>The sudden, unexplained removal of a research paper on private equity firms buying dermatology practices has raised questions about corporate influence.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/10/26/health/private-equity-dermatology.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Texans say voting machines changing straight-ticket choices</title>
<link>https://apnews.com/a8825810d10441f2ad828e95d6851d55</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://apnews.com/a8825810d10441f2ad828e95d6851d55</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;AUSTIN, Texas (AP) — Some Texas voters are complaining that machines flipped their straight-ticket selections to the other party in key races during early voting, especially the much-watched Senate battle between Republican incumbent Ted Cruz and Democrat Beto O’Rourke.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The secretary of state’s office said Friday that there have been reported issues with Hart eSlate voting machines, which are used in around 30 percent of counties statewide and feature a wheel for selecting candidates and buttons to move from screen to screen. But it says they are caused by voters themselves and often occur when they complete and submit ballots too quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The Hart eSlate machines are not malfunctioning, the problems being reported are a result of user error — usually voters hitting a button or using the selection wheel before the screen is finished rendering,” said Sam Taylor, spokesman for the office of Secretary of State Rolando Pablos, who was appointed by Republican Gov. Greg Abbott.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The machines are used in around 80 counties, including the state’s largest, Harris, which is home to Houston, as well as Travis, which includes Austin, and Tarrant, encompassing Fort Worth. Early voting in Texas began Monday and has featured strong turnout and long lines. It runs through Nov. 2, ahead of Election Day on Nov. 6.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many Hart eSlate machines used in Texas don’t provide receipts or other forms of paper trail to voters, but those casting ballots do see a screen that shows their choices before final submission — and can go back and make changes. Similar machines are used in parts of Indiana, Kentucky, Pennsylvania, Tennessee and Virginia, according to Verified Voting, a nonprofit group focused on ensuring the accuracy of elections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The machine’s manufacturer, Hart InterCivic, attributed the Texas issues to 16-year-old technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The same story has happened in multiple elections,” Steven Sockwell, the company’s vice president of marketing, said Friday. “There was no flipping then and there’s not any now.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, Sockwell said, what typically happens in cases where someone believes his or her vote has been changed is a voter will select a straight-party ticket, then unintentionally change votes in individual races without realizing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, in a statement to supporters, Cruz cited “multiple reports” of race selections changing and added “once you select the Republican party ticket, please be patient and do not select ‘next’ until the ballot has populated all of the selections.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An advisory to county clerks and elections administrators issued earlier this week by Keith Ingram, the secretary of state’s office’s director of elections, said, “We have heard from a number of people voting on Hart eSlate machines that when they voted straight ticket, it appeared to them that the machine had changed one or more of their selections to a candidate from a different party.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Texas Democratic Party called the issue “a malfunction,” said it was causing Democrats to inadvertently vote for Cruz and accused the secretary of state’s office of not doing enough to warn voters of potential issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Party chairman Gilberto Hinojosa said in a statement that “Texas’ Republican government blamed voters and did nothing.” He called for a statewide public service announcement to warn voters, training for poll workers on the issue and removal of “all malfunctioning machines.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taylor said Friday that his office “has already trained election officials across the state” while also instructing “election administrators to post additional signage in multiple languages” and requiring county officials to keep “a detailed, meticulous log of any malfunctioning machines, and remove any machines that are malfunctioning.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taylor also said his office “has no legal authority whatsoever to force any” voting machine vendors “to make upgrades if their voting systems are otherwise in compliance with federal and state law,” and that Hart eSlate’s system was certified in 2009. He said counties are responsible for purchasing their own new voting equipment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We will continue to educate Texas voters using existing resources,” Taylor said, “and urge all Texans casting a ballot to take their time, slow down, and carefully review their ballot before casting one.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Associated Press Writer Frank Bajak contributed to this report from Boston.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 18:59:43 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>threatofrain</dc:creator>
<og:title>Texans say voting machines changing straight-ticket choices</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://apnews.com/a8825810d10441f2ad828e95d6851d55</og:url>
<og:image>https://storage.googleapis.com/afs-prod/media/media:0a29fa8cc01c4cce8ae6a82b940548ad/3000.jpeg</og:image>
<og:description>AUSTIN, Texas (AP) — Some Texas voters are complaining that machines flipped their straight-ticket selections to the other party in key races during early voting, especially the much-watched Senate battle between Republican incumbent Ted Cruz and Democrat Beto O'Rourke. The secretary of state's office said Friday that there have been reported issues with Hart eSlate voting machines, which are used in around 30 percent of counties statewide and feature a wheel for selecting candidates and buttons to move from screen to screen. But it says they are caused by voters themselves and often occur when they complete and submit ballots too quickly.</og:description>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://apnews.com/a8825810d10441f2ad828e95d6851d55</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>