<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>California bans private prisons</title>
<link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2019/sep/12/california-private-prison-ban-immigration-ice</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2019/sep/12/california-private-prison-ban-immigration-ice</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The private prison industry is set to be upended after &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/california&quot; data-link-name=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; data-component=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;California&lt;/a&gt; lawmakers passed a bill on Wednesday banning the facilities from operating in the state. The move will probably also close down four large immigration detention facilities that can hold up to 4,500 people at a time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The legislation is being hailed as a major victory for criminal justice reform because it removes the profit motive from incarceration. It also marks a dramatic departure from California’s past, when private prisons were relied on to reduce crowding in state-run facilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Private prison companies used to view California as one of their fastest-growing markets. As recently as 2016, private prisons locked up approximately 7,000 Californians, about 5% of the state’s total prison population, according to the federal Bureau of Justice Statistics. But in recent years, thousands of inmates have been transferred from private prisons back into state-run facilities. As of June, private prisons held 2,222 of California’s total inmate population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The state’s governor, Gavin Newsom, must still sign &lt;a href=&quot;http://leginfo.legislature.ca.gov/faces/billTextClient.xhtml?bill_id=201920200AB32&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;AB32&lt;/a&gt;, but last year he signaled support for the ban and said during his inaugural speech in January that the state should “end the outrage of private prisons once and for all”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, one company, the Geo Group, operates four private prisons in California under contract with the California department of corrections and rehabilitation. The contracts for these four prisons expire in 2023 and cannot be renewed under AB32, except to comply with a federal court order to reduce crowding in state-run facilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to signaling a major criminal justice reform, AB32 also has become a flashpoint in California’s fight with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/trump-administration&quot; data-link-name=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; data-component=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Trump administration&lt;/a&gt; over the treatment of immigrants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bill’s author, the assemblymember Rob Bonta, originally wrote it only to apply to contracts between the state’s prison authority and private, for-profit prison companies. But in June, Bonta &lt;a href=&quot;https://a18.asmdc.org/press-releases/20190626-bonta-applauds-return-last-ca-inmates-out-state-profit-private-prisons&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;amended&lt;/a&gt; the bill to apply to the Immigration and Customs Enforcement agency’s four major California detention centers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bonta’s amendment, say immigrant rights advocates, appears to have caught Immigrations and Customs Enforcement (Ice) and the private prison companies at a moment when their current contracts are expiring. The result is that instead of slowly phasing out immigration detention centers as their existing contracts expire years down the road, most will face closure next year – unless Ice and its private prison contractors find a workaround.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I think Geo Group is realizing their scheme to circumvent state law is putting them in a place where they could end up being be nailed,” said Hamid Yazdan Panah, an immigration attorney and the regional director for the Northern California Rapid Response &amp;amp; Immigrant Defense Network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;element element-rich-link element--thumbnail element-rich-link--not-upgraded&quot; data-component=&quot;rich-link&quot; data-link-name=&quot;rich-link-1 | 1&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;rich-link&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;rich-link__container&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;rich-link__header&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;rich-link__title&quot;&gt;A US city cut ties with its troubled migrant detention center. That could make things even worse&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;Two of Ice’s largest immigrant detention centers in California are operated by the Geo Group through complicated contracts that use cities as middlemen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The city of Adelanto signed an agreement in 2011 with ICE to hold up to 1,300 immigrant detainees facing deportation. Adelanto then subcontracted the prison operations to Geo Group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“What Ice does is they locate in these very poor and remote areas,” said Lizbeth Abeln, of the Inland Coalition for Immigrant Justice. “The private prison comes in and lobbies and promises jobs, and tax money.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.auditor.ca.gov/reports/2018-117/sections.html&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;According to a report by the California&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.auditor.ca.gov/reports/2018-117/sections.html&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;state&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.auditor.ca.gov/reports/2018-117/sections.html&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;auditor&lt;/a&gt;, this complicated subcontracting model allowed Ice and Adelanto to forgo competitive bidding for the center’s operations subcontract.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A similar process unfolded just north of Bakersfield in McFarland, where in 2015 the city agreed to serve as the middleman for the Geo Group, which operates the 400-bed Mesa Verde detention facility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Geo Group expanded the Adelanto center in 2015 to 1,940 beds, making it the second-largest adult detention center in the country, and with the Trump administration’s crackdown against undocumented immigrants, another 1,000-bed expansion is planned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year, Geo Group &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bakersfield.com/delano-record/owner-the-bakersfield-dome-will-be-demolished-to-allow-expansion/article_95e7d58c-83a3-11e8-8d16-73a00266468d.html&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;reportedly sought to purchase property in Bakersfield&lt;/a&gt; for a major expansion of Mesa Verde.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But these complicated contracts were outlawed last year. Under the state &lt;a href=&quot;http://leginfo.legislature.ca.gov/faces/billNavClient.xhtml?bill_id=201720180SB29&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Dignity Not Detention Act&lt;/a&gt;, cities and counties, including Adelanto and McFarland, were barred from signing new agreements with Ice or amending existing contracts to permit expansion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;u-responsive-ratio&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;gu-image&quot; itemprop=&quot;contentUrl&quot; alt=&quot;An immigrant detainee reads through paperwork in a general population block at the Adelanto detention facility.&quot; src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/69510243da0158fa289be1ad98c406263ca0ed6f/0_0_5760_3456/master/5760.jpg?width=300&amp;amp;quality=85&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;fit=max&amp;amp;s=3259f646001f8f45a67fdb7f4e145ea1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

An immigrant detainee reads through paperwork in a general population block at the Adelanto detention facility. Photograph: John Moore/Getty Images
&lt;p&gt;“To expand their detention center, Geo Group and Ice would have to cut their ties with the city of Adelanto,” said Jose Servin, the communications coordinator of the California Immigrant Youth Justice Alliance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Geo Group asked both cities to break off their Ice contracts and the cities agreed. Ice then provided Geo Group with temporary contracts to operate Adelanto and Mesa Verde. Both agreements expire next March, after AB32 is expected to go into effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“My understanding is AB32 would prevent new contracts for these facilities,” said Panah. “The fact they’re on a one-year bridge, it won’t allow them to move from the one-year contract to a longer-term contract.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ice declined to answer any questions about how AB32 affects its detention center contracts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CoreCivic operates the Otay Mesa detention center in San Diego under a direct contract with Ice and is building a 512-bed expansion to house immigrant detainees, according to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1070985/000156459019004033/cxw-10k_20181231.htm&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Securities and Exchange Commission filings&lt;/a&gt;. But its Ice contract expires in June 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“When California’s prison system capacity was at 200% and conditions were so challenging as to be deemed unconstitutional, companies like ours were one of the solutions the state turned to,” said Brandon Bissel, a CoreCivic spokesperson.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In recent years, contracts with California’s prison authority have amounted to as much as 12% of CoreCivic’s total revenue, more than any other state prison authority in the US, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1070985/000119312517053982/d310578d10k.htm&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;according to SEC filings.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CoreCivic and Geo Group spent $130,000 during the first six months of this year lobbying the legislature and governor against AB32.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On 6 September, AB32 was amended to allow Geo Group, CoreCivic and other for-profit prison companies to continue operating after 2020, but only to help the state comply with a court-ordered prison population cap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Otherwise, the use of private prisons for state inmates is to be fully phased out by 2028.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Immigration advocates still worry that Ice and its contractors could find a way to circumvent the ban.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This legislation is the most powerful we’ve had. It’s a very big step,” said Abeln about AB32. “But we know Geo Group and Ice work in secrecy, and they work to circumvent contract laws, so we’re still monitoring things.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Servin said that while the new law was a significant victory, there was one other thing immigrants rights groups were concerned about. When several sheriffs’ departments canceled their contracts to house Ice detainees last year, instead of freeing the detainees, Ice moved many of them to prisons in Colorado and Hawaii.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We have to worry about all the people who are detained right now,” said Servine. “Where will they end up?”&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 19:02:53 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>anigbrowl</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2019/sep/12/california-private-prison-ban-immigration-ice</og:url>
<og:description>Bill removes profit motive from incarceration and marks latest clash in state’s battle with Trump over treatment of immigrants</og:description>
<og:image>https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/d4cc3178938fd2e4cf4875bae3e80166478b63e3/0_192_5760_3456/master/5760.jpg?width=1200&amp;height=630&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=crop&amp;overlay-align=bottom%2Cleft&amp;overlay-width=100p&amp;overlay-base64=L2ltZy9zdGF0aWMvb3ZlcmxheXMvdGctZGVmYXVsdC5wbmc&amp;enable=upscale&amp;s=87a8ee2998df1e783144a9c8ee47dd54</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>California bans private prisons – including Ice detention centers</og:title>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2019/sep/12/california-private-prison-ban-immigration-ice</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>WebGPU and WSL in Safari</title>
<link>https://webkit.org/blog/9528/webgpu-and-wsl-in-safari/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://webkit.org/blog/9528/webgpu-and-wsl-in-safari/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;WebGPU is a new API &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/gpuweb/gpuweb&quot;&gt;being developed&lt;/a&gt; by Apple and others in the W3C which enables high-performance 3D graphics and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_parallelism&quot;&gt;data-parallel computation&lt;/a&gt; on the Web. This API represents a significant improvement over the existing WebGL API in both performance and ease of use. Starting in &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/safari/technology-preview/&quot;&gt;Safari Technology Preview&lt;/a&gt; release 91, beta support is available for WebGPU API and WSL, our proposal for the WebGPU shading language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few months ago we discussed a &lt;a href=&quot;https://webkit.org/blog/8482/web-high-level-shading-language/&quot;&gt;proposal&lt;/a&gt; for a new shading language called Web High-Level Shading Language, and began implementation as a proof of concept. Since then, we’ve shifted our approach to this new language, which I will discuss a little later in this post. With help from our friends at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.babylonjs.com/&quot;&gt;Babylon.js&lt;/a&gt; we were able to adapt a demo to work with WebGPU and Web Shading Language (WSL):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can &lt;a href=&quot;https://webkit.org/demos/webgpu/babylon/oneHelmetWebGPU.html&quot;&gt;see the demo in action&lt;/a&gt; with Safari Technology Preview 91 or later, and with the WebGPU experimental feature enabled. The demo utilizes many of the best features of WebGPU. Let’s dig in to see what make WebGPU work so well, and why we think WSL is a great choice for WebGPU.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;WebGPU JavaScript API&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just like WebGL, the WebGPU API is accessed through JavaScript because most Web developers are already familiar with working in JavaScript. We expect to create a WebGPU API that is accessed through WebAssembly in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Pipeline State Objects and Bind Groups&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most 3D applications render more than a single object. In WebGL, each of those objects requires a collection of state-changing calls before that object could be rendered. For example, rendering a single object in WebGL might look like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;js&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;gl&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;UseProgram&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;program1&lt;/span&gt;);
&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;gl&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;frontFace&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;gl&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;CW&lt;/span&gt;);
&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;gl&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;cullFace&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;gl&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;FRONT&lt;/span&gt;);
&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;gl&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;blendEquationSeparate&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;gl&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;FUNC_ADD&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;gl&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;FUNC_MIN&lt;/span&gt;);
&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;gl&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;blendFuncSeparate&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;gl&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;SRC_COLOR&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;gl&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;ZERO&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;gl&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;SRC_ALPHA&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;gl&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;ZERO&lt;/span&gt;);
&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;gl&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;colorMask&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;keyword literal&quot;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;keyword literal&quot;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;keyword literal&quot;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;keyword literal&quot;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;);
&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;gl&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;depthMask&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;keyword literal&quot;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;);
&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;gl&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;stencilMask&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;);
&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;gl&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;depthFunc&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;gl&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;GREATER&lt;/span&gt;);
&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;gl&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;drawArrays&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;gl&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;TRIANGLES&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;count&lt;/span&gt;);
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, rendering a single object in WebGPU might look like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;js&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;encoder&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;setPipeline&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;renderPipeline&lt;/span&gt;);
&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;encoder&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;draw&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;count&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;);
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the pieces of state in the WebGL example are wrapped up into a single object in WebGPU, named a “&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/gpuweb/gpuweb/blob/master/spec/index.bs#L664&quot;&gt;pipeline state object&lt;/a&gt;.” Though validating state is expensive, with WebGPU it is done once when the pipeline is created, outside of the core rendering loop. As a result, we can avoid performing expensive state analysis inside the draw call. Also, setting an entire pipeline state is a single function call, reducing the amount of “chatting” between Javascript and WebKit’s C++ browser engine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resources have a similar story. Most rendering algorithms require a set of resources in order to draw a particular material. In WebGL, each resource would be bound one-by-one, leading to code that looks like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;js&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;gl&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;bindBufferRange&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;gl&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;UNIFORM_BUFFER&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;materialBuffer1&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;size1&lt;/span&gt;);
&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;gl&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;bindBufferRange&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;gl&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;UNIFORM_BUFFER&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;materialBuffer2&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;size2&lt;/span&gt;);
&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;gl&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;activeTexture&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;);
&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;gl&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;bindTexture&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;gl&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;TEXTURE_2D&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;materialTexture1&lt;/span&gt;);
&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;gl&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;activeTexture&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;);
&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;gl&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;bindTexture&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;gl&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;TEXTURE_2D&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;materialTexture2&lt;/span&gt;);
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, in WebGPU, resources are batched up into “&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/gpuweb/gpuweb/blob/master/spec/index.bs#L572&quot;&gt;bind groups&lt;/a&gt;.” When using WebGPU, the behavior of the above code is represented as simply:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;js&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;encoder&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;setBindGroup&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;identifier&quot;&gt;bindGroup&lt;/span&gt;);
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In both of these examples, multiple objects are gathered up together and baked into a hardware-dependent format, which is when the browser performs validation. Being able to separate object validation from object use means the application author has more control over when expensive operations occur in the lifecycle of their application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Run-time Performance&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We expect WebGPU to perform faster and handle larger workloads than WebGL. To measure performance, we adopted the test harness from our 2D graphics benchmark &lt;a href=&quot;https://browserbench.org/MotionMark1.1/&quot;&gt;MotionMark&lt;/a&gt; and wrote two versions of a performance test that had a simple yet realistic workload, one in &lt;a href=&quot;https://browserbench.org/MotionMark1.1/developer.html?test-interval=30&amp;amp;display=minimal&amp;amp;tiles=big&amp;amp;controller=ramp&amp;amp;frame-rate=50&amp;amp;kalman-process-error=1&amp;amp;kalman-measurement-error=4&amp;amp;time-measurement=performance&amp;amp;suite-name=3DGraphics&amp;amp;test-name=TrianglesWebGL&quot;&gt;WebGL&lt;/a&gt; and the other in &lt;a href=&quot;https://browserbench.org/MotionMark1.1/developer.html?test-interval=10&amp;amp;display=minimal&amp;amp;tiles=big&amp;amp;controller=ramp&amp;amp;frame-rate=50&amp;amp;kalman-process-error=1&amp;amp;kalman-measurement-error=4&amp;amp;time-measurement=performance&amp;amp;suite-name=3DGraphics&amp;amp;test-name=TrianglesWebGPU&quot;&gt;WebGPU&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The test measures how many triangles with different properties can be drawn while maintaining 60 frames per second. Each triangle renders with a different draw call and bind group; this mimics the way many games render objects (like characters, explosions, bullets, or environment objects) in different draw calls with different resources. Because much of the validation logic in WebGPU is performed during the creation of the bind group instead of inside the draw call, both of these calls execute much faster than the equivalent calls in WebGL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://webkit.org/wp-content/uploads/WSLTrianglesBenchmark.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-9534&quot; srcset=&quot;https://webkit.org/wp-content/uploads/WSLTrianglesBenchmark.png 1210w, https://webkit.org/wp-content/uploads/WSLTrianglesBenchmark-300x125.png 300w, https://webkit.org/wp-content/uploads/WSLTrianglesBenchmark-768x321.png 768w, https://webkit.org/wp-content/uploads/WSLTrianglesBenchmark-1024x428.png 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1210px) 100vw, 1210px&quot;/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Web Shading Language&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The WebGPU community group is actively discussing which shading language or languages should be supported by the specification. Last year, we &lt;a href=&quot;https://webkit.org/blog/8482/web-high-level-shading-language/&quot;&gt;proposed&lt;/a&gt; a new shading language for WebGPU. We are pleased to announce that a beta version of this language is available in Safari Technology Preview 91.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because of community feedback, our approach toward designing the language has evolved. Previously, we designed the language to be source-compatible with HLSL, but we realized this compatibility was not what the community was asking for. Many wanted the shading language to be as simple and as low-level as possible. That would make it an easier compile target for whichever language their development shop uses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many Web developers using GLSL today in WebGL, so a potential browser accepting a different high level language, like HLSL, wouldn’t suit their needs well. In addition, a high-level language such as HLSL can’t be executed faithfully on every platform and graphics API that WebGPU is designed to execute on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, we decided to make the language more simple, low-level, and fast to compile, and renamed the language to Web Shading Language to match this pursuit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The name change reflects a shift in our approach, but the major tenets of WSL have not changed. It’s still a language that is high-performance. It’s still text-based, which integrates well with existing web technologies and culture. WSL’s semantics still bake in safety and portability. It still works great as a compile target. As expected for every web technology, the language is well-defined with a &lt;a href=&quot;https://gpuweb.github.io/WSL/&quot;&gt;robust specification&lt;/a&gt;. And because the WebGPU Community Group owns the language, it matures in concert with the WebGPU API.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an upcoming post, we’ll talk more about the technical details of this language update. Here, let’s discuss further about WSL’s performance characteristics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Wire Size&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Babylon.js demo above demonstrates an area where WSL really shines. The shaders in the demo use complex &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Physically_based_rendering&quot;&gt;physically-based&lt;/a&gt; algorithms to draw with the highest realism possible. Babylon.js creates these complex shading algorithms by stitching together snippets of shader source code at run-time. This way, Babylon’s shaders are tuned at run-time to the specific type of content the application contains. Since WSL is a textual language like GLSL, this kind of workflow can be accomplished simply with string concatenation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building shaders by string concatenation and compiling them directly is a dramatic improvement over languages which cannot do this kind of manipulation easily, like bytecode-based languages. For these other languages, generation of shaders at run-time requires the execution of an additional compiler, written in JavaScript or WebAssembly, to compile the generated source text into the bytecode form.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This extra step slows down performance in two ways. First, the execution of the additional compiler takes time. Second, the compiler source would have to be served with the rest of the web page’s resources, which increases the page size and lengthens the loading time of the web page. On the other hand, since WSL’s format is textual, there’s no additional compile step; you can just write it and run it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a point of comparison, let’s take the Babylon.js demo shown above. Babylon.js renders scenes by joining GLSL shader snippets at runtime. When using WSL, Babylon.js would simply serve the WSL snippets just like they’re serving GLSL snippets today. To do the same with SPIR-V, Babylon.js would serve their shader snippets along with a compiler that compiles these textual snippets down to SPIR-V. Chrome recently &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=K2JzIUIHIhc&quot;&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; their support for WebGPU with SPIR-V using the same demo. Here is a comparison of the gzipped wire sizes for the shaders as WSL, and that of the shaders as GLSL and the SPIR-V compiler:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://webkit.org/wp-content/uploads/WSLGzippedWireSize.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-9535&quot; srcset=&quot;https://webkit.org/wp-content/uploads/WSLGzippedWireSize.png 1132w, https://webkit.org/wp-content/uploads/WSLGzippedWireSize-300x128.png 300w, https://webkit.org/wp-content/uploads/WSLGzippedWireSize-768x328.png 768w, https://webkit.org/wp-content/uploads/WSLGzippedWireSize-1024x438.png 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1132px) 100vw, 1132px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;The top bar shows the wire size if Babylon.js used WSL directly. The middle bar shows the wire size of the GLSL source, plus the compiler that Babylon.js uses to compile their snippets into SPIR-V. The bottom bar shows the wire size if Babylon.js simply served the results of their SPIR-V compilation. Because of the dynamic nature of Babylon.js’s shaders, they assemble their shaders at runtime and compile them dynamically, so they require the SPIR-V compiler. However, other websites’ shaders may be more static, in which case they wouldn’t need the compiler and could serve the SPIR-V directly, like in the bottom bar in the graph above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Compilation Performance&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve heard from developers that shader compilation performance is extremely important. One way the community group addressed this was designing WebGPU to support asynchronous compilation, which avoids blocking successive rendering commands. Asynchronous compilation isn’t a magic bullet, though. If the next rendering command uses a shader currently being compiled, that rendering command must wait for the compilation complete. So, we’ve put significant effort into making WSL compilation times fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The WebGPU community created a compute shader to demonstrate the flocking characteristics of “boids,” and we turned that sample into a &lt;a href=&quot;https://webkit.org/demos/webgpu/compute-boids-compile.html&quot;&gt;compiler performance benchmark&lt;/a&gt;. Here we compare the compilation time of WSL with the run-time of the GLSL compiler to SPIR-V running as a WebAssembly library:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://webkit.org/wp-content/uploads/WSLCompilationTime.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-9536&quot; srcset=&quot;https://webkit.org/wp-content/uploads/WSLCompilationTime.png 1082w, https://webkit.org/wp-content/uploads/WSLCompilationTime-300x131.png 300w, https://webkit.org/wp-content/uploads/WSLCompilationTime-768x335.png 768w, https://webkit.org/wp-content/uploads/WSLCompilationTime-1024x447.png 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1082px) 100vw, 1082px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;As you can see, we’re continuing to optimize compilation performance, and it’s been increasing both throughout and after STP 91’s release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Give WebGPU a try!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re very excited to have implemented a beta version of WebGPU and WSL in the latest version of Safari Technology Preview. Try it out and let us know how well it works for you! We’re interested in feedback so we can evolve the WebGPU and WSL language to better suit everyone’s needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And be sure to check out our &lt;a href=&quot;https://webkit.org/demos/webgpu/&quot;&gt;gallery of WebGPU samples&lt;/a&gt;. We’ll be keeping this page updated with the latest demos. Many thanks to Sebastien Vandenberghe and David Catuhe from Babylon.js for their help with Babylon.js in Safari.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information, you can contact me at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:mmaxfield@apple.com&quot;&gt;mmaxfield@apple.com&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/Litherum&quot;&gt;@Litherum&lt;/a&gt;, or you can contact our evangelist, &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:jond@apple.com&quot;&gt;Jonathan Davis&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://webkit.org/blog/9528/webgpu-and-wsl-in-safari/#footnoteOne&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt; To enable WebGPU beta support, in Develop menu, select Experimental Features &amp;gt; WebGPU.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://webkit.org/blog/9528/webgpu-and-wsl-in-safari/#footnoteTwo&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt; We still pronounce it “whistle”, though.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 17:18:48 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>chmaynard</dc:creator>
<og:title>WebGPU and WSL in Safari</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://webkit.org/blog/9528/webgpu-and-wsl-in-safari/</og:url>
<og:image>https://webkit.org/wp-content/uploads/WSLTrianglesBenchmark.png</og:image>
<og:description>WebGPU is a new API being developed by Apple and others in the W3C which enables high-performance 3D graphics and data-parallel computation on the Web.</og:description>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://webkit.org/blog/9528/webgpu-and-wsl-in-safari/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>A lighter V8</title>
<link>https://v8.dev/blog/v8-lite</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://v8.dev/blog/v8-lite</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;In late 2018 we started a project called V8 Lite, aimed at dramatically reducing V8’s memory usage. Initially this project was envisioned as a separate &lt;em&gt;Lite mode&lt;/em&gt; of V8 specifically aimed at low-memory mobile devices or embedder use-cases that care more about reduced memory usage than throughput execution speed. However, in the process of this work, we realized that many of the memory optimizations we had made for this &lt;em&gt;Lite mode&lt;/em&gt; could be brought over to regular V8 thereby benefiting all users of V8.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this post we highlight some of the key optimizations we developed and the memory savings they provided in real-world workloads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;note&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; If you prefer watching a presentation over reading articles, then enjoy the video below! If not, skip the video and read on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;video video-16:9&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe allow=&quot;picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/56ogP8-eRqA&quot; width=&quot;560&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=56ogP8-eRqA&quot;&gt;“V8 Lite ⁠— slimming down JavaScript memory”&lt;/a&gt; as presented by Ross McIlroy at BlinkOn 10.
&lt;h2 id=&quot;lite-mode&quot;&gt;Lite mode &lt;a href=&quot;https://v8.dev/blog/v8-lite#lite-mode&quot; class=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to optimize V8’s memory usage, we first needed to understand how memory is used by V8 and what object types contribute a large proportion of V8’s heap size. We used V8’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://v8.dev/blog/optimizing-v8-memory#memory-visualization&quot;&gt;memory visualization&lt;/a&gt; tools to trace heap composition across a number of typical web pages.&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;440&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; src=&quot;https://v8.dev/_img/v8-lite/memory-categorization.svg&quot; width=&quot;950&quot;/&gt;Percentage of V8’s heap used by different object types when loading Times of India.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In doing so, we determined that a significant portion of V8’s heap was dedicated to objects that aren’t essential to JavaScript execution, but are used to optimize JavaScript execution and handle exceptional situations. Examples include: optimized code; type feedback used to determine how to optimize the code; redundant metadata for bindings between C++ and JavaScript objects; metadata only required during exceptional circumstances such as stack trace symbolization; and bytecode for functions that are only executed a few times during page loading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result of this, we started work on a &lt;em&gt;Lite mode&lt;/em&gt; of V8 that trades off speed of JavaScript execution against improved memory savings by vastly reducing the allocation of these optional objects.&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;231&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; src=&quot;https://v8.dev/_img/v8-lite/v8-lite.png&quot; width=&quot;149&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A number of the &lt;em&gt;Lite mode&lt;/em&gt; changes could be made by configuring existing V8 settings, for example, disabling V8’s TurboFan optimizing compiler. However, others required more involved changes to V8.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In particular, we decided that since &lt;em&gt;Lite mode&lt;/em&gt; doesn’t optimize code, we could avoid collection of type feedback required by the optimizing compiler. When executing code in the Ignition interpreter, V8 will collect feedback about the types of operands which are passed to various operations (e.g., &lt;code&gt;+&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;o.foo&lt;/code&gt;), in order to tailor later optimization to those types. This information is stored in &lt;em&gt;feedback vectors&lt;/em&gt; which contribute a significant portion of V8’s heap memory usage. &lt;em&gt;Lite mode&lt;/em&gt; could avoid allocating these feedback vectors, however the interpreter and parts of V8’s inline-cache infrastructure expected feedback vectors to be available, and so required considerable refactoring to be able to support this feedback-free execution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lite mode&lt;/em&gt; launched in V8 version 7.3 and provides a 22% reduction in typical web page heap size compared to V8 version 7.1 by disabling code optimization, not allocating feedback vectors and performed aging of seldom executed bytecode (described below). This is a nice result for those applications that explicitly want to trade off performance for better memory usage. However in the process of doing this work we realized that we could achieve most of the memory savings of &lt;em&gt;Lite mode&lt;/em&gt; with none of the performance impact by making V8 lazier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;lazy-feedback-allocation&quot;&gt;Lazy feedback allocation &lt;a href=&quot;https://v8.dev/blog/v8-lite#lazy-feedback-allocation&quot; class=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disabling feedback vector allocation entirely not only prevents optimization of code by V8’s TurboFan compiler, but also prevents V8 from performing &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Inline_caching&quot;&gt;inline-caching&lt;/a&gt; of common operations, such as object property loads in the Ignition interpreter. As such, doing so caused a significant regression to V8’s execution time, reducing page-load-time by 12% and increasing the CPU time used by V8 by 120% on typical interactive web page scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To bring most of these savings to regular V8 without these regressions, we instead moved to an approach where we lazily allocate feedback vectors after the function has executed a certain amount of bytecode (currently 1KB). Since most functions aren’t executed very often, we avoid feedback vector allocation in most cases, but quickly allocate them where needed to avoid performance regressions and still allow code to be optimized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One additional complication with this approach is related to the fact that feedback vectors form a tree, with the feedback vectors for inner functions being held as entries in their outer function’s feedback vector. This is necessary so that newly created function closures receive the same feedback vector array as all other closures created for the same function. With lazy allocation of feedback vectors we can’t form this tree using feedback vectors, since there is no guarantee that an outer function will have allocated its feedback vector by the time an inner function does so. To address this, we created a new &lt;code&gt;ClosureFeedbackCellArray&lt;/code&gt; to maintain this tree, then swap out a function’s &lt;code&gt;ClosureFeedbackCellArray&lt;/code&gt; with a full &lt;code&gt;FeedbackVector&lt;/code&gt; when it becomes hot.&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; src=&quot;https://v8.dev/_img/v8-lite/lazy-feedback.svg&quot; width=&quot;1257&quot;/&gt;Feedback vector trees before and after lazy feedback allocation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our lab experiments and in-the-field telemetry showed no performance regressions for lazy feedback on desktop, and on mobile platforms we actually saw a performance improvement on low-end devices due to a reduction in garbage collection. As such, we have enabled lazy feedback allocation in all builds of V8, including &lt;em&gt;Lite mode&lt;/em&gt; where the slight regression in memory compared to our original no-feedback allocation approach is more than compensated by the improvement in real world performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;lazy-source-positions&quot;&gt;Lazy source positions &lt;a href=&quot;https://v8.dev/blog/v8-lite#lazy-source-positions&quot; class=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When compiling bytecode from JavaScript, source position tables are generated that tie bytecode sequences to character positions within the JavaScript source code. However, this information is only needed when symbolizing exceptions or performing developer tasks such as debugging, and so is rarely used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To avoid this waste, we now compile bytecode without collecting source positions (assuming no debugger or profiler is attached). The source positions are only collected when a stack trace is actually generated, for instance when calling &lt;code&gt;Error.stack&lt;/code&gt; or printing an exception’s stack trace to the console. This does have some cost, as generating source positions requires the function to be reparsed and compiled, however most websites don’t symbolize stack traces in production and therefore don’t see any observable performance impact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One issue we had to address with this work was to require repeatable bytecode generation, which had not previously been guaranteed. If V8 generates different bytecode when collecting source positions compared to the original code, then the source positions will not line up and stack traces could point to the wrong position in the source code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In certain circumstances V8 could generate different bytecode depending on whether a function was &lt;a href=&quot;https://v8.dev/blog/preparser#skipping-inner-functions&quot;&gt;eagerly or lazily compiled&lt;/a&gt;, due to some parser information being lost between the initial eager parse of a function, and later lazy compilation. These mismatches were mostly benign, for example losing track of the fact that a variable is immutable and therefore not being able to optimize it as such. However some of the mismatches uncovered by this work did have the potential to cause incorrect code execution in certain circumstances. As a result, we fixed these mismatches and added checks and a stress mode to ensure that eager and lazy compilation of a function always produce consistent outputs, giving us greater confidence in the correctness and consistency of V8’s parser and preparser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;bytecode-flushing&quot;&gt;Bytecode flushing &lt;a href=&quot;https://v8.dev/blog/v8-lite#bytecode-flushing&quot; class=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bytecode compiled from JavaScript source takes up a significant chunk of V8 heap space, typically around 15%, including related metadata. There are many functions which are only executed during initialization, or rarely used after having been compiled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result, we added support for flushing compiled bytecode from functions during garbage collection if they haven’t been executed recently. In order to do this, we keep track of the &lt;em&gt;age&lt;/em&gt; of a function’s bytecode, incrementing the &lt;em&gt;age&lt;/em&gt; every &lt;a href=&quot;https://v8.dev/blog/trash-talk#major-gc&quot;&gt;major (mark-compact)&lt;/a&gt; garbage collection, and resetting it to zero when the function is executed. Any bytecode which crosses an aging threshold is eligible to be collected by the next garbage collection. If it is collected and then later executed again, it will then be recompiled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were technical challenges to ensure that bytecode is only ever flushed when it is no longer necessary. For instance, if function &lt;code&gt;A&lt;/code&gt; calls another long-running function &lt;code&gt;B&lt;/code&gt;, function &lt;code&gt;A&lt;/code&gt; could be aged while it is still on the stack. We don’t want to flush the bytecode for function &lt;code&gt;A&lt;/code&gt; even if it reaches its aging threshold because we need to return to it when the long-running function &lt;code&gt;B&lt;/code&gt; returns. As such, we treat bytecode as weakly held from a function when it reaches its aging threshold, but strongly held by any references to it on the stack or elsewhere. We only flush the code when there are no strong links remaining.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to flushing bytecode, we also flush feedback vectors associated with these flushed functions. However we can’t flush feedback vectors during the same GC cycle as the bytecode because they aren’t retained by the same object - bytecode is held by a native-context independent &lt;code&gt;SharedFunctionInfo&lt;/code&gt;, whereas the feedback vector is retained by the native-context dependent &lt;code&gt;JSFunction&lt;/code&gt;. As a result we flush feedback vectors on the subsequent GC cycle.&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;492&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; src=&quot;https://v8.dev/_img/v8-lite/bytecode-flushing.svg&quot; width=&quot;1200&quot;/&gt;The object layout for an aged function after two GC cycles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;additional-optimizations&quot;&gt;Additional optimizations &lt;a href=&quot;https://v8.dev/blog/v8-lite#additional-optimizations&quot; class=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to these larger projects, we also uncovered and addressed a couple of inefficiencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first was to reduce the size of &lt;code&gt;FunctionTemplateInfo&lt;/code&gt; objects. These objects store internal metadata about &lt;a href=&quot;https://v8.dev/docs/embed#templates&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;FunctionTemplate&lt;/code&gt;s&lt;/a&gt;, which are used to enable embedders, such as Chrome, to provide C++ callback implementations of functions that can be called by JavaScript code. Chrome introduces a lot of FunctionTemplates in order to implement DOM Web APIs, and therefore &lt;code&gt;FunctionTemplateInfo&lt;/code&gt; objects contributed to V8’s heap size. After analysing the typical usage of FunctionTemplates, we found that of the eleven fields on a &lt;code&gt;FunctionTemplateInfo&lt;/code&gt; object, only three were typically set to a non-default value. We therefore split the &lt;code&gt;FunctionTemplateInfo&lt;/code&gt; object such that the rare fields are stored in a side-table which is only allocated on demand if required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second optimization is related to how we deoptimize from TurboFan optimized code. Since TurboFan performs speculative optimizations, it might need to fall back to the interpreter (deoptimize) if certain conditions no longer hold. Each deopt point has an id which enables the runtime to determine where in the bytecode it should return execution to in the interpreter. Previously this id was calculated by having the optimized code jump to a particular offset within a large jump table, which loaded the correct id into a register and then jumped into the runtime to perform the deoptimization. This had the advantage of requiring only a single jump instruction in the optimized code for each deopt point. However the deoptimize jump table was pre-allocated and had to be large enough to support the whole deoptimization id range. We instead modified TurboFan such that deopt points in optimized code load the deopt id directly before calling into the runtime. This enabled us to remove this large jump table entirely, at the expense of a slight increase in optimized code size.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;results&quot;&gt;Results &lt;a href=&quot;https://v8.dev/blog/v8-lite#results&quot; class=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have released the optimizations described above over the last seven releases of V8. Typically they landed first in &lt;em&gt;Lite mode&lt;/em&gt;, and then were later brought to the default configuration of V8.&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;433&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; src=&quot;https://v8.dev/_img/v8-lite/savings-by-release.svg&quot; width=&quot;700&quot;/&gt;Average V8 heap size for a set of typical web pages on an AndroidGo device.&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;411&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; src=&quot;https://v8.dev/_img/v8-lite/breakdown-by-page.svg&quot; width=&quot;677&quot;/&gt;Per-page breakdown of memory savings of V8 v7.8 (Chrome 78) compared to v7.1 (Chrome 71).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over this time, we have reduced the V8 heap size by an average of 18% across a range of typical websites, which corresponds to an average decrease of 1.5 MB for low-end AndroidGo mobile devices. This has been possible without any significant impact on JavaScript performance either on benchmarks or as measured on real world webpage interactions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lite mode&lt;/em&gt; can provide further memory savings at some cost to JavaScript execution throughput by disabling function optimization. On average &lt;em&gt;Lite mode&lt;/em&gt; provides 22% memory savings, with some pages seeing up to 32% reductions. This corresponds to a 1.8 MB reduction in V8 heap size on an AndroidGo device.&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;411&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; src=&quot;https://v8.dev/_img/v8-lite/breakdown-by-optimization.svg&quot; width=&quot;677&quot;/&gt;Breakdown of memory savings of V8 v7.8 (Chrome 78) compared to v7.1 (Chrome 71).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When split by the impact of each individual optimization, it is clear that different pages derive a different proportion of their benefit from each of these optimizations. Going forward, we will continue to identify potential optimizations which can further reduce V8’s memory usage while still remaining blazingly fast at JavaScript execution.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 14:32:28 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>tosh</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://v8.dev/blog/v8-lite</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ask HN: Are you ok?</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=20951444</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=20951444</guid>
<description>&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.58823529411765&quot;&gt;&lt;td bgcolor=&quot;#FF6600&quot;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr id=&quot;pagespace&quot; title=&quot;Ask HN: Are you ok?&quot;&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.8295081967213&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table class=&quot;fatitem&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.7475409836066&quot;&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing&quot; id=&quot;20951444&quot;&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;right&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;title&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=20951444&quot; class=&quot;storylink&quot;&gt;Ask HN: Are you ok?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.70588235294118&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;subtext&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;score&quot; id=&quot;score_20951444&quot;&gt;712 points&lt;/span&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/user?id=quantumwoke&quot; class=&quot;hnuser&quot;&gt;quantumwoke&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;age&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=20951444&quot;&gt;11 hours ago&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span id=&quot;unv_20951444&quot;/&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/hide?id=20951444&amp;amp;goto=item%3Fid%3D20951444&quot;&gt;hide&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://hn.algolia.com/?query=Ask%20HN%3A%20Are%20you%20ok%3F&amp;amp;sort=byDate&amp;amp;dateRange=all&amp;amp;type=story&amp;amp;storyText=false&amp;amp;prefix&amp;amp;page=0&quot; class=&quot;hnpast&quot;&gt;past&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=Ask%20HN%3A%20Are%20you%20ok%3F&quot;&gt;web&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/fave?id=20951444&amp;amp;auth=ce71d668378851f3cc96d0ca0c527a7187f406a8&quot;&gt;favorite&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=20951444&quot;&gt;722 comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;9.9929577464789&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;9.5171026156942&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ruok.org.au/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.ruok.org.au/&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My Australian friend just linked this to me and I thought it would be good question to ask HN. IME HN and perhaps software development in general contains a lot of at-risk personalities in stressful work environments that don't get asked this question enough. I think you are all interesting, intelligent, hard-working people and mental health is unfortunately still stigmatised in the tech community. Feel free to ask any coworkers today who have been struggling as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td&gt;

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.73972602739726&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ycombinator.com/apply/&quot;&gt;Applications are open for YC Winter 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;yclinks&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/newsguidelines.html&quot;&gt;Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/newsfaq.html&quot;&gt;FAQ&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:hn@ycombinator.com&quot;&gt;Support&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/HackerNews/API&quot;&gt;API&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/security.html&quot;&gt;Security&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/lists&quot;&gt;Lists&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/bookmarklet.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Bookmarklet&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ycombinator.com/legal/&quot;&gt;Legal&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ycombinator.com/apply/&quot;&gt;Apply to YC&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:hn@ycombinator.com&quot;&gt;Contact&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 13:54:06 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>quantumwoke</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=20951444</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Israel accused of planting mysterious spy devices near the White House</title>
<link>https://www.politico.com/story/2019/09/12/israel-white-house-spying-devices-1491351</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.politico.com/story/2019/09/12/israel-white-house-spying-devices-1491351</guid>
<description>&lt;aside class=&quot;story-related cl-l db no-border&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;The U.S. government concluded within the past two years that Israel was most likely behind the placement of cellphone surveillance devices that were found near the White House and other sensitive locations around Washington, according to three former senior U.S. officials with knowledge of the matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But unlike most other occasions when flagrant incidents of foreign spying have been discovered on American soil, the Trump administration did not rebuke the Israeli government, and there were no consequences for Israel’s behavior, one of the former officials said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-continued&quot;&gt;Story Continued Below&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The miniature surveillance devices, colloquially known as “StingRays,” mimic regular cell towers to fool cellphones into giving them their locations and identity information. Formally called international mobile subscriber identity-catchers or IMSI-catchers, they also can capture the contents of calls and data use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The devices were likely intended to spy on President Donald Trump, one of the former officials said, as well as his top aides and closest associates — though it’s not clear whether the Israeli efforts were successful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trump is reputed to be lax in observing White House security protocols. POLITICO &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.politico.com/story/2018/05/21/trump-phone-security-risk-hackers-601903&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt; in May 2018 that the president often used an insufficiently secured cellphone to communicate with friends and confidants. The New York Times subsequently &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/10/24/us/politics/trump-phone-security.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt; in October 2018 that “Chinese spies are often listening” to Trump’s cellphone calls, prompting the president to slam the story as “so incorrect I do not have time here to correct it.” (A former official said Trump has had his cellphone hardened against intrusion.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By then, as part of tests by the federal government, officials at the Department of Homeland Security had already discovered evidence of the surveillance devices around the nation’s capital, but weren’t able to attribute the devices to specific entities. The officials shared their findings with relevant federal agencies, according to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wyden.senate.gov/imo/media/doc/Krebs%20letter%20to%20Wyden%20after%20May%20meeting.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;letter&lt;/a&gt; a top Department of Homeland Security official, Christopher Krebs, wrote in May 2018 to Sen. Ron Wyden (D-Ore.).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;story-related cl-l db&quot;&gt;&lt;aside class=&quot;content-group inline-module-playbook&quot;&gt;&lt;section class=&quot;speedbump layout-bi&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;speedbump-item pos-alpha&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;spotlight spotlight--flex&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;summary link-alt fx1&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;POLITICO Playbook newsletter&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sign up today to receive the #1-rated newsletter in politics&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;speedbump-item pos-beta&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;js-tealium-newsletter&quot; data-subscription-module=&quot;newsletter_inline_standard_Playbook - POLITICO&quot; readability=&quot;6.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;dari-frame dari-frame-loaded&quot; name=&quot;inline-module-playbook-full-0000014f-1646-d88f-a1cf-5f46b7bd0000--0000015a-94d9-d61c-a55a-fedf449a0000&quot; data-insertion-mode=&quot;replace&quot; data-extra-form-data=&quot;_frame.path=5c388a2e37218b65f1db610df3d5c42a&amp;amp;_frame.name=inline-module-playbook-full-0000014f-1646-d88f-a1cf-5f46b7bd0000--0000015a-94d9-d61c-a55a-fedf449a0000&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;legal-disclaimer&quot;&gt;By signing up you agree to receive email newsletters or alerts from POLITICO. You can unsubscribe at any time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;Based on a detailed forensic analysis, the FBI and other agencies working on the case felt confident that Israeli agents had placed the devices, according to the former officials, several of whom served in top intelligence and national security posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That analysis, one of the former officials said, is typically led by the FBI’s counterintelligence division and involves examining the devices so that they “tell you a little about their history, where the parts and pieces come from, how old are they, who had access to them, and that will help get you to what the origins are.” For these types of investigations, the bureau often leans on the National Security Agency and sometimes the CIA (DHS and the Secret Service played a supporting role in this specific investigation).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It was pretty clear that the Israelis were responsible,” said a former senior intelligence official.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An Israeli Embassy spokesperson, Elad Strohmayer, denied that Israel placed the devices and said: “These allegations are absolute nonsense. Israel doesn’t conduct espionage operations in the United States, period.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A senior Trump administration official said the administration doesn’t “comment on matters related to security or intelligence.” The FBI declined to comment, while DHS and the Secret Service didn’t respond to requests for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After this story was published, Trump told reporters that he would find it &quot;hard to believe&quot; that the Israelis had placed the devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;I don't think the Israelis were spying on us,&quot; Trump said. &quot;My relationship with Israel has been great...Anything is possible but I don't believe it.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu also denied after publication that Israel was behind the devices. &quot;We have a directive, I have a directive: No intelligence work in the United States, no spies,&quot; he said in a gaggle with reporters. &quot;And it's vigorously implemented, without any exception. It [the report] is a complete fabrication, a complete fabrication.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But former officials with deep experience dealing with intelligence matters scoff at the Israeli claim — a pro forma denial Israeli officials are also known to make in private to skeptical U.S. counterparts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One former senior intelligence official noted that after the FBI and other agencies concluded that the Israelis were most likely responsible for the devices, the Trump administration took no action to punish or even privately scold the Israeli government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The reaction ... was very different than it would have been in the last administration,” this person said. “With the current administration, there are a different set of calculations in regard to addressing this.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The former senior intelligence official criticized how the administration handled the matter, remarking on the striking difference from past administrations, which likely would have at a very minimum issued a démarche, or formal diplomatic reprimand, to the foreign government condemning its actions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I’m not aware of any accountability at all,” the former official said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond trying to intercept the private conversations of top officials — prized information for any intelligence service — foreign countries often will try to surveil their close associates as well. With the president, the former senior Trump administration official noted, that could include trying to listen in on the devices of the people he regularly communicates with, such as Steve Wynn, Sean Hannity and Rudy Giuliani.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The people in that circle are heavily targeted,” the former Trump official said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another circle of surveillance targets includes people who regularly talk to Trump’s friends and informal advisers. Information obtained from any of these people “would be so valuable in a town that is like three degrees of separation like Kevin Bacon,” the former official added.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s true even for a close U.S. ally like Israel, which often seeks an edge in its diplomatic maneuvering with the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The Israelis are pretty aggressive” in their intelligence gathering operations, said a former senior intelligence official. “They’re all about protecting the security of the Israeli state and they do whatever they feel they have to to achieve that objective.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;story-interrupt pos-alpha format-m&quot;&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;interrupt-item&quot; readability=&quot;1.5&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;story-media&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fig-graphic&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-lazy-img=&quot;https://static.politico.com/ad/3b/0779725a4b549ad517d94caa9fda/190815-netanyahu-trump-gty-773.jpg&quot; src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==&quot; alt=&quot;Benjamin Netanyahu and Donald Trump&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu with President Donald Trump. | Michael Reynolds/Getty Images&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So even though Trump has formed a warm relationship with Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu and made numerous policy moves favorable to the Israeli government — such as moving the U.S. Embassy to Jerusalem, ripping up the Iran nuclear deal and heavily targeting Iran with sanctions — Israel became a prime suspect in planting the devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the Chinese, who have been regularly caught doing intelligence operations in the U.S., were also seen as potential suspects, they were determined as unlikely to have placed the devices based on a close analysis of the devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You can often, depending upon the tradecraft of the people who put them in place, figure out who’s been accessing them to pull the data off the devices,” another former senior U.S. intelligence official explained.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Washington is awash in surveillance, and efforts of foreign entities to try to spy on administration officials and other top political figures are fairly common. But not many countries have the capability — or the budget — to plant the devices found in this most recent incident, which is another reason suspicion fell on Israel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IMSI-catchers, which are often used by local police agencies to surveil criminals, can also be made by sophisticated hobbyists or by the Harris Corp., the manufacturer of StingRays, which &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/z43ka3/police-in-indianapolis-stingrays-2012&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;cost&lt;/a&gt; more than $150,000 each, according to Vice News.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The costs involved are really significant,” according to a former senior Trump administration official. “This is not an easy or ubiquitous practice.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;story-related cl-l db&quot;&gt;&lt;aside class=&quot;content-group inline-module-morning-cybersecurity&quot;&gt;&lt;section class=&quot;speedbump layout-bi&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;speedbump-item pos-alpha&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;spotlight spotlight--flex&quot; readability=&quot;5.2&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;summary link-alt fx1&quot; readability=&quot;6.4&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A daily briefing on politics and cybersecurity — weekday mornings, in your inbox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;speedbump-item pos-beta&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;js-tealium-newsletter&quot; data-subscription-module=&quot;newsletter_inline_standard_Morning Cybersecurity - POLITICO&quot; readability=&quot;6.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;dari-frame dari-frame-loaded&quot; name=&quot;inline-module-morning-cybersecurity-full-0000014f-1646-d88f-a1cf-5f46b23b0000--0000015a-a442-d857-a17a-afebb36b0000&quot; data-insertion-mode=&quot;replace&quot; data-extra-form-data=&quot;_frame.path=5c388a2e37218b65f1db610df3d5c42a&amp;amp;_frame.name=inline-module-morning-cybersecurity-full-0000014f-1646-d88f-a1cf-5f46b23b0000--0000015a-a442-d857-a17a-afebb36b0000&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;legal-disclaimer&quot;&gt;By signing up you agree to receive email newsletters or alerts from POLITICO. You can unsubscribe at any time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;Among professionals, the Israeli intelligence services have an especially fearsome reputation. But they do sometimes make mistakes and are “not 10 feet tall like you see in the movies,” a former senior intelligence official noted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2010, the secret covers of a Mossad hit team, some of whom had been posing as tennis players, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gq.com/story/the-dubai-job-mossad-assassination-hamas&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;were blown&lt;/a&gt; after almost 30 minutes of surveillance video was posted online of them going through a luxury Dubai hotel where they killed a top Hamas terrorist in his room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, U.S. officials sometimes have been taken aback by Israel’s brazen spying. One former U.S. government official recalled his frequent concern that Israel knew about internal U.S. policy deliberations that were meant to be kept private.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“There were suspicions that they were listening in,” the former official said, based on his Israeli counterparts flaunting a level of detailed knowledge “that was hard to explain otherwise.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Sometimes it was sort of knowledge of our thinking. Occasionally there were some turns of phrase like language that as far as we knew had only appeared in drafts of speeches and never been actually used publicly, and then some Israeli official would repeat it back to us and say, ‘This would be really problematic if you were to say X,’” said the former official.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back when the Obama administration was trying to jump-start negotiations with the Palestinians, for example, the Israelis were eager to get advance knowledge of the language being debated that would describe the terms of reference of the talks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“They would have had interest in what language [President Barack] Obama or [Secretary of State John] Kerry or someone else was going to use and might indeed try to find a way to lobby for language they liked or against language that they didn’t like and so having knowledge of that could be advantageous for them,” the former official said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The Israelis are aggressive intelligence collectors, but they have sworn off spying on the U.S. at various points and it’s not surprising that such efforts continue,” said Daniel Benjamin, a former coordinator of counterterrorism at the Obama State Department and now director of the John Sloan Dickey Center for International Understanding at Dartmouth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Benjamin, who emphasized that he was not aware of the FBI's investigation into the cell-phone spoofing, recalled once meeting with a former head of Mossad, the premier Israeli intelligence agency, when he was out of office. The first thing the former Mossad official told Benjamin was that Israel didn’t spy on the U.S.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I just told him our conversation was over if he had such a low estimate of my intelligence,” Benjamin said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Israeli officials often note in conversations with their American counterparts — correctly — that the U.S. regularly gathers intelligence on Israeli leaders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for Israel’s recent surveillance of the White House, one of the former senior U.S. intelligence officials acknowledged it raised security concerns but joked, “On the other hand, guess what we do in Tel Aviv?&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article has been updated to clarify that Daniel Benjamin had no knowledge of the alleged Israeli spying, and that the Israeli official he was speaking with was a former official at the time of their conversation.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;story-supplement&quot;&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;content-categories&quot;&gt;&lt;h6&gt;This article tagged under:&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;content-group&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;story-supplement&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;spotlight&quot; readability=&quot;6.0165289256198&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;summary fs-i&quot; readability=&quot;7.7355371900826&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Missing out on the latest scoops? Sign up for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.politico.com/subscribe/playbook?cid=su_stft_pb&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;POLITICO Playbook&lt;/a&gt; and get the latest news, every morning — in your inbox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 12:37:59 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>spzx</dc:creator>
<og:title>Israel accused of planting mysterious spy devices near the White House</og:title>
<og:description>The likely Israeli spying efforts were uncovered during the Trump presidency, several former top U.S. officials said.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://politi.co/2ZXxEgS</og:url>
<og:image>https://static.politico.com/e2/d5/bcfbedf64059a60391c323951235/stingray-final.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.politico.com/story/2019/09/12/israel-white-house-spying-devices-1491351</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Attempto Controlled English</title>
<link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Attempto_Controlled_English</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Attempto_Controlled_English</guid>
<description>&lt;a class=&quot;mw-jump-link&quot; href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Attempto_Controlled_English#mw-head&quot;&gt;Jump to navigation&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;a class=&quot;mw-jump-link&quot; href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Attempto_Controlled_English#p-search&quot;&gt;Jump to search&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;div id=&quot;mw-content-text&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot; class=&quot;mw-content-ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;mw-parser-output&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Attempto Controlled English&lt;/b&gt; (&lt;b&gt;ACE&lt;/b&gt;) is a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Controlled_natural_language&quot; title=&quot;Controlled natural language&quot;&gt;controlled natural language&lt;/a&gt;, i.e. a subset of standard &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_grammar&quot; title=&quot;English grammar&quot;&gt;English&lt;/a&gt; with a restricted syntax and restricted semantics described by a small set of construction and interpretation rules.&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-FLAIRS_2006_1-0&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Attempto_Controlled_English#cite_note-FLAIRS_2006-1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; It has been under development at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/University_of_Zurich&quot; title=&quot;University of Zurich&quot;&gt;University of Zurich&lt;/a&gt; since 1995. In 2013, ACE version 6.7 was announced.&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-2&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Attempto_Controlled_English#cite_note-2&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;ACE can serve as &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Knowledge_representation&quot; class=&quot;mw-redirect&quot; title=&quot;Knowledge representation&quot;&gt;knowledge representation&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Specification_language&quot; title=&quot;Specification language&quot;&gt;specification&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Query_language&quot; title=&quot;Query language&quot;&gt;query language&lt;/a&gt;, and is intended for professionals who want to use formal notations and formal methods, but may not be familiar with them. Though ACE appears perfectly natural – it can be read and understood by any speaker of English – it is in fact a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Formal_language&quot; title=&quot;Formal language&quot;&gt;formal language&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-FLAIRS_2006_1-1&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Attempto_Controlled_English#cite_note-FLAIRS_2006-1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;ACE and its related tools have been used in the fields of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Requirements_analysis&quot; title=&quot;Requirements analysis&quot;&gt;software specifications&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Theorem_proving&quot; class=&quot;mw-redirect&quot; title=&quot;Theorem proving&quot;&gt;theorem proving&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Automatic_summarization&quot; title=&quot;Automatic summarization&quot;&gt;text summaries&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ontologies&quot; class=&quot;mw-redirect&quot; title=&quot;Ontologies&quot;&gt;ontologies&lt;/a&gt;, rules, querying, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Health_informatics&quot; title=&quot;Health informatics&quot;&gt;medical documentation&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Planning&quot; title=&quot;Planning&quot;&gt;planning&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here are some simple examples:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Every woman is a human.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A woman is a human.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A man tries-on a new tie. If the tie pleases his wife then the man buys it.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;ACE construction rules require that each noun be introduced by a determiner (&lt;i&gt;a&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;every&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;no&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;some&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;at least 5&lt;/i&gt;, ...). Regarding the list of examples above, ACE interpretation rules decide that (1) is interpreted as &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Universal_quantification&quot; title=&quot;Universal quantification&quot;&gt;universally quantified&lt;/a&gt;, while (2) is interpreted as &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Existential_quantification&quot; title=&quot;Existential quantification&quot;&gt;existentially quantified&lt;/a&gt;. Sentences like &quot;Women are human&quot; do not follow ACE syntax and are consequently not valid.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Interpretation rules resolve the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Deixis#Anaphoric_reference&quot; title=&quot;Deixis&quot;&gt;anaphoric references&lt;/a&gt; in (3): &lt;i&gt;the tie&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; of the second sentence refer to &lt;i&gt;a new tie&lt;/i&gt; of the first sentence, while &lt;i&gt;his&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;the man&lt;/i&gt; of the second sentence refer to &lt;i&gt;a man&lt;/i&gt; of the first sentence. Thus an ACE text is a coherent entity of anaphorically linked sentences.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Attempto Parsing Engine (APE) translates ACE texts unambiguously into &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Discourse_Representation_Theory&quot; class=&quot;mw-redirect&quot; title=&quot;Discourse Representation Theory&quot;&gt;discourse representation structures&lt;/a&gt; (DRS) that use a variant of the language of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/First-order_logic&quot; title=&quot;First-order logic&quot;&gt;first-order logic&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-3&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Attempto_Controlled_English#cite_note-3&quot;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; A DRS can be further translated into other &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Formal_languages&quot; class=&quot;mw-redirect&quot; title=&quot;Formal languages&quot;&gt;formal languages&lt;/a&gt;, for instance AceRules with various semantics,&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-4&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Attempto_Controlled_English#cite_note-4&quot;&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web_Ontology_Language&quot; title=&quot;Web Ontology Language&quot;&gt;OWL&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-5&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Attempto_Controlled_English#cite_note-5&quot;&gt;[5]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Semantic_Web_Rule_Language&quot; title=&quot;Semantic Web Rule Language&quot;&gt;SWRL&lt;/a&gt;. Translating an ACE text into (a fragment of) first-order logic allows users to  &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Inference&quot; title=&quot;Inference&quot;&gt;reason&lt;/a&gt; about the text, for instance to &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Formal_verification&quot; title=&quot;Formal verification&quot;&gt;verify&lt;/a&gt;, to &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Formal_verification&quot; title=&quot;Formal verification&quot;&gt;validate&lt;/a&gt;, and to &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Information_retrieval&quot; title=&quot;Information retrieval&quot;&gt;query&lt;/a&gt; it.
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;Overview&quot;&gt;Overview&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an overview of the current version 6.6 of ACE this section:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Briefly describes the vocabulary&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gives an account of the syntax&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Summarises the handling of ambiguity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explains the processing of anaphoric references.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;Vocabulary&quot;&gt;Vocabulary&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The vocabulary of ACE comprises:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Predefined function words (e.g. determiners, conjunctions)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Predefined phrases (e.g. &quot;it is false that ...&quot;, &quot;it is possible that ...&quot;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Content words (e.g. nouns, verbs, adjectives, adverbs).&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;Grammar&quot;&gt;Grammar&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The grammar of ACE defines and constrains the form and the meaning of ACE sentences and texts. ACE's grammar is expressed as a set of  &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;http://attempto.ifi.uzh.ch/site/docs/ace_constructionrules.html&quot;&gt;construction rules&lt;/a&gt;. The meaning of sentences is described as a small set of &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;http://attempto.ifi.uzh.ch/site/docs/ace_interpretationrules.html&quot;&gt;interpretation rules&lt;/a&gt;. A &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;http://attempto.ifi.uzh.ch/site/docs/ace_troubleshooting.html&quot;&gt;Troubleshooting Guide&lt;/a&gt; describes how to use ACE and how to avoid pitfalls.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;ACE_texts&quot;&gt;ACE texts&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An ACE text is a sequence of declarative sentences that can be anaphorically interrelated. Furthermore, ACE supports questions and commands.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;Simple_sentences&quot;&gt;Simple sentences&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A simple sentence asserts that something is the case — a fact, an event, a state.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;&lt;dd&gt;The temperature is −2 °C.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;A customer inserts 2 cards.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;A card and a code are valid.&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;p&gt;Simple ACE sentences have the following general structure:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;&lt;dd&gt;subject + verb + complements + adjuncts&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every sentence has a subject and a verb. Complements (direct and indirect objects) are necessary for transitive verbs (&lt;i&gt;insert something&lt;/i&gt;) and ditransitive verbs (&lt;i&gt;give something to somebody&lt;/i&gt;), whereas adjuncts (adverbs, prepositional phrases) are optional.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;All elements of a simple sentence can be elaborated upon to describe the situation in more detail. To further specify the nouns &lt;i&gt;customer&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;card&lt;/i&gt;, we could add adjectives:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;&lt;dd&gt;A trusted customer inserts two valid cards.&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;p&gt;possessive nouns and &lt;i&gt;of&lt;/i&gt;-prepositional phrases:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;&lt;dd&gt;John's customer inserts a card of Mary.&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;p&gt;or variables as appositions:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;&lt;dd&gt;John inserts a card A.&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;p&gt;Other modifications of nouns are possible through relative sentences:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;&lt;dd&gt;A customer who is trusted inserts a card that he owns.&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;p&gt;which are described below since they make a sentence composite. We can also detail the insertion event, e.g. by adding an adverb:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;&lt;dd&gt;A customer inserts some cards manually.&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;p&gt;or, equivalently:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;&lt;dd&gt;A customer manually inserts some cards.&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;p&gt;or, by adding prepositional phrases:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;&lt;dd&gt;A customer inserts some cards into a slot.&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;p&gt;We can combine all of these elaborations to arrive at:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;&lt;dd&gt;John's customer who is trusted inserts a valid card of Mary manually into a slot A.&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;Composite_sentences&quot;&gt;Composite sentences&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Composite sentences are recursively built from simpler sentences through &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Coordination_(linguistics)&quot; title=&quot;Coordination (linguistics)&quot;&gt;coordination&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Subordination_(linguistics)&quot; title=&quot;Subordination (linguistics)&quot;&gt;subordination&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quantification_(linguistics)&quot; class=&quot;mw-redirect&quot; title=&quot;Quantification (linguistics)&quot;&gt;quantification&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Negation&quot; title=&quot;Negation&quot;&gt;negation&lt;/a&gt;. Note that ACE composite sentences overlap with what linguists call compound sentences and complex sentences.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;Coordination&quot;&gt;Coordination&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coordination by &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; is possible between sentences and between phrases of the same syntactic type.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;&lt;dd&gt;A customer inserts a card and the machine checks the code.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;There is a customer who inserts a card and who enters a code.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;A customer inserts a card and enters a code.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;An old and trusted customer enters a card and a code.&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;p&gt;Note that the coordination of the noun phrases &lt;i&gt;a card&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;a code&lt;/i&gt; represents a plural object.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Coordination by &lt;i&gt;or&lt;/i&gt; is possible between sentences, verb phrases, and relative clauses.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;&lt;dd&gt;A customer inserts a card or the machine checks the code.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;A customer inserts a card or enters a code.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;A customer owns a card that is invalid or that is damaged.&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;p&gt;Coordination by &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;or&lt;/i&gt; is governed by the standard binding order of logic, i.e. &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; binds stronger than &lt;i&gt;or&lt;/i&gt;. Commas can be used to override the standard binding order. Thus the sentence:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;&lt;dd&gt;A customer inserts a VisaCard or inserts a MasterCard, and inserts a code.&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;p&gt;means that the customer inserts a VisaCard and a code, or alternatively a MasterCard and a code.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;Subordination&quot;&gt;Subordination&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are four constructs of subordination: relative sentences, &lt;i&gt;if-then&lt;/i&gt; sentences, modality, and sentence subordination.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Relative sentences starting with &lt;i&gt;who&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;which&lt;/i&gt;, and &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; allow to add detail to nouns:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;&lt;dd&gt;A customer who is trusted inserts a card that he owns.&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the help of &lt;i&gt;if-then&lt;/i&gt; sentences we can specify conditional or hypothetical situations:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;&lt;dd&gt;If a card is valid then a customer inserts it.&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;p&gt;Note the anaphoric reference via the pronoun &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; in the &lt;i&gt;then&lt;/i&gt;-part to the noun phrase &lt;i&gt;a card&lt;/i&gt; in the &lt;i&gt;if&lt;/i&gt;-part.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Modality allows us to express possibility and necessity:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;&lt;dd&gt;A trusted customer can/must insert a card.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;It is possible/necessary that a trusted customer inserts a card.&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sentence subordination comes in various forms:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;&lt;dd&gt;It is true/false that a customer inserts a card.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;It is not provable that a customer inserts a card.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;A clerk believes that a customer inserts a card.&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;h5&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;Quantification&quot;&gt;Quantification&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quantification allows us to speak about all objects of a certain class (&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Universal_quantification&quot; title=&quot;Universal quantification&quot;&gt;universal quantification&lt;/a&gt;), or to denote explicitly the existence of at least one object of this class (&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Existential_quantification&quot; title=&quot;Existential quantification&quot;&gt;existential quantification&lt;/a&gt;). The textual occurrence of a universal or existential quantifier opens its scope that extends to the end of the sentence, or in coordinations to the end of the respective coordinated sentence.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To express that all involved customers insert cards we can write
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;&lt;dd&gt;Every customer inserts a card.&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;p&gt;This sentence means that each customer inserts a card that may, or may not, be the same as the one inserted by another customer. To specify that all customers insert the same card — however unrealistic that situation seems — we can write:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;&lt;dd&gt;A card is inserted by every customer.&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;p&gt;or, equivalently:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;&lt;dd&gt;There is a card that every customer inserts.&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;p&gt;To state that every card is inserted by a customer we write:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;&lt;dd&gt;Every card is inserted by a customer.&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;p&gt;or, somewhat indirectly:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;&lt;dd&gt;For every card there is a customer who inserts it.&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;h5&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;Negation&quot;&gt;Negation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Negation allows us to express that something is not the case:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;&lt;dd&gt;A customer does not insert a card.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;A card is not valid.&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;p&gt;To negate something for all objects of a certain class one uses &lt;i&gt;no&lt;/i&gt;:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;&lt;dd&gt;No customer inserts more than 2 cards.&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;p&gt;or, &lt;i&gt;there is no&lt;/i&gt;:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;&lt;dd&gt;There is no customer who inserts a card.&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;p&gt;To negate a complete statement one uses sentence negation:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;&lt;dd&gt;It is false that a customer inserts a card.&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;p&gt;These forms of negation are logical negations, i.e. they state that something is provably not the case. Negation as failure states that a state of affairs cannot be proved, i.e. there is no information whether the state of affairs is the case or not.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;&lt;dd&gt;It is not provable that a customer inserts a card.&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;Queries&quot;&gt;Queries&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ACE supports two forms of queries: &lt;i&gt;yes/no&lt;/i&gt;-queries and &lt;i&gt;wh&lt;/i&gt;-queries.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Yes/no&lt;/i&gt;-queries ask for the existence or non-existence of a specified situation. If we specified:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;&lt;dd&gt;A customer inserts a card.&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;p&gt;then we can ask:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;&lt;dd&gt;Does a customer insert a card?&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;p&gt;to get a positive answer. Note that interrogative sentences always end with a question mark.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the help of &lt;i&gt;wh&lt;/i&gt;-queries, i.e. queries with query words, we can interrogate a text for details of the specified situation. If we specified:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;&lt;dd&gt;A trusted customer inserts a valid card manually in the morning in a bank.&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;p&gt;we can ask for each element of the sentence with the exception of the verb.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;&lt;dd&gt;Who inserts a card?&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Which customer inserts a card?&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;What does a customer insert?&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;How does a customer insert a card?&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;When does a customer enter a card?&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Where does a customer enter a card?&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;p&gt;Queries can also be constructed by a sequence of declarative sentences followed by one interrogative sentence, for example:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;&lt;dd&gt;There is a customer and there is a card that the customer enters. Does a customer enter a card?&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;Commands&quot;&gt;Commands&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ACE also supports commands. Some examples:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;&lt;dd&gt;John, go to the bank!&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;John and Mary, wait!&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Every dog, bark!&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;A brother of John, give a book to Mary!&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;p&gt;A command always consists of a noun phrase (the addressee), followed by a comma, followed by an uncoordinated verb phrase. Furthermore, a command has to end with an exclamation mark.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;Constraining_ambiguity&quot;&gt;Constraining ambiguity&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To constrain the ambiguity of full natural language ACE employs three simple means:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Some ambiguous constructs are not part of the language; unambiguous alternatives are available in their place&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All remaining ambiguous constructs are interpreted deterministically on the basis of a small number of interpretation rules&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Users can either accept the assigned interpretation, or they must rephrase the input to obtain another one.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;Avoidance_of_ambiguity&quot;&gt;Avoidance of ambiguity&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In natural language, relative sentences combined with coordinations can introduce ambiguity:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;&lt;dd&gt;A customer inserts a card that is valid and opens an account.&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;p&gt;In ACE the sentence has the unequivocal meaning that the customer opens an account, as reflected by the paraphrase:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;&lt;dd&gt;A card is valid. A customer inserts the card. The customer opens an account.&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;p&gt;To express the alternative — though not very realistic — meaning that the card opens an account, the relative pronoun &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; must be repeated, thus yielding a coordination of relative sentences:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;&lt;dd&gt;A customer inserts a card that is valid and that opens an account.&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;p&gt;This sentence is unambiguously equivalent in meaning to the paraphrase:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;&lt;dd&gt;A card is valid. The card opens an account. A customer inserts the card.&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;Interpretation_rules&quot;&gt;Interpretation rules&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not all ambiguities can be safely removed from ACE without rendering it artificial. To deterministically interpret otherwise syntactically correct ACE sentences we use a small set of interpretation rules. For example, if we write:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;&lt;dd&gt;A customer inserts a card with a code.&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;p&gt;then &lt;i&gt;with a code&lt;/i&gt; attaches to the verb &lt;i&gt;inserts&lt;/i&gt;, but not to &lt;i&gt;a card&lt;/i&gt;. However, this is probably not what we meant to say. To express that &lt;i&gt;the code&lt;/i&gt; is associated with &lt;i&gt;the card&lt;/i&gt; we can employ the interpretation rule that a relative sentence always modifies the immediately preceding noun phrase, and rephrase the input as:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;&lt;dd&gt;A customer inserts a card that carries a code.&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;p&gt;yielding the paraphrase:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;&lt;dd&gt;A card carries a code. A customer inserts the card.&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;p&gt;or — to specify that the customer inserts a card and a code — as:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;&lt;dd&gt;A customer inserts a card and a code.&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;Anaphoric_references&quot;&gt;Anaphoric references&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Usually ACE texts consist of more than one sentence:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;&lt;dd&gt;A customer enters a card and a code. If a code is valid then SimpleMat accepts a card.&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;p&gt;To express that all occurrences of card and code should mean the same card and the same code, ACE provides anaphoric references via the definite article:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;&lt;dd&gt;A customer enters a card and a code. If the code is valid then SimpleMat accepts the card.&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;p&gt;During the processing of the ACE text, all anaphoric references are replaced by the most recent and most specific accessible noun phrase that agrees in gender and number. As an example of &quot;most recent and most specific&quot;, suppose an ACE parser is given the sentence:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;&lt;dd&gt;A customer enters a red card and a blue card.&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;&lt;dd&gt;The card is correct.&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;p&gt;refers to the second card, while:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;&lt;dd&gt;The red card is correct.&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;p&gt;refers to the first card.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Noun phrases within &lt;i&gt;if-then&lt;/i&gt; sentences, universally quantified sentences, negations, modality, and subordinated sentences cannot be referred to anaphorically from subsequent sentences, i.e. such noun phrases are not &quot;accessible&quot; from the following text. Thus for each of the sentences:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;&lt;dd&gt;If a customer owns a card then he enters it.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Every customer enters a card.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;A customer does not enter a card.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;A customer can enter a card.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;A clerk believes that a customer enters a card.&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;p&gt;we cannot refer to &lt;i&gt;a card&lt;/i&gt; with:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;&lt;dd&gt;The card is correct.&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anaphoric references are also possible via personal pronouns:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;&lt;dd&gt;A customer enters a card and a code. If it is valid then SimpleMat accepts the card.&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;p&gt;or via variables:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;&lt;dd&gt;A customer enters a card &lt;i&gt;X&lt;/i&gt; and a code &lt;i&gt;Y&lt;/i&gt;. If &lt;i&gt;Y&lt;/i&gt; is valid then SimpleMat accepts &lt;i&gt;X&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anaphoric references via definite articles and variables can be combined:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;&lt;dd&gt;A customer enters a card &lt;i&gt;X&lt;/i&gt; and a code &lt;i&gt;Y&lt;/i&gt;. If the code &lt;i&gt;Y&lt;/i&gt; is valid then SimpleMat accepts the card &lt;i&gt;X&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;p&gt;Note that proper names like &lt;i&gt;SimpleMat&lt;/i&gt; always refer to the same object.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;See_also&quot;&gt;See also&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gellish&quot; title=&quot;Gellish&quot;&gt;Gellish&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_Language_Processing&quot; class=&quot;mw-redirect&quot; title=&quot;Natural Language Processing&quot;&gt;Natural Language Processing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_programming&quot; class=&quot;mw-redirect&quot; title=&quot;Natural language programming&quot;&gt;Natural language programming&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Structured_English&quot; title=&quot;Structured English&quot;&gt;Structured English&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ClearTalk&quot; title=&quot;ClearTalk&quot;&gt;ClearTalk&lt;/a&gt;, another machine-readable knowledge representation language&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Inform_7&quot; class=&quot;mw-redirect&quot; title=&quot;Inform 7&quot;&gt;Inform 7&lt;/a&gt;, a programming language with English syntax&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;References&quot;&gt;References&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;reflist&quot; style=&quot;list-style-type: decimal;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;mw-references-wrap&quot;&gt;&lt;ol class=&quot;references&quot;&gt;&lt;li id=&quot;cite_note-FLAIRS_2006-1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-cite-backlink&quot;&gt;^ &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Attempto_Controlled_English#cite_ref-FLAIRS_2006_1-0&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;a&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Attempto_Controlled_English#cite_ref-FLAIRS_2006_1-1&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;b&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;reference-text&quot;&gt;&lt;cite class=&quot;citation conference&quot;&gt;Norbert E. Fuchs; Kaarel Kaljurand; Gerold Schneider (2006). &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;http://attempto.ifi.uzh.ch/site/publications/papers/FLAIRS0601FuchsN.pdf&quot;&gt;&quot;Attempto Controlled English Meets the Challenges of Knowledge Representation, Reasoning, Interoperability and User Interfaces&quot;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;cs1-format&quot;&gt;(&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PDF&quot; title=&quot;PDF&quot;&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;. &lt;i&gt;FLAIRS 2006&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;span title=&quot;ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Abook&amp;amp;rft.genre=conference&amp;amp;rft.atitle=Attempto+Controlled+English+Meets+the+Challenges+of+Knowledge+Representation%2C+Reasoning%2C+Interoperability+and+User+Interfaces&amp;amp;rft.btitle=FLAIRS+2006&amp;amp;rft.date=2006&amp;amp;rft.au=Norbert+E.+Fuchs&amp;amp;rft.au=Kaarel+Kaljurand&amp;amp;rft.au=Gerold+Schneider&amp;amp;rft_id=http%3A%2F%2Fattempto.ifi.uzh.ch%2Fsite%2Fpublications%2Fpapers%2FFLAIRS0601FuchsN.pdf&amp;amp;rfr_id=info%3Asid%2Fen.wikipedia.org%3AAttempto+Controlled+English&quot; class=&quot;Z3988&quot;/&gt;&lt;style data-mw-deduplicate=&quot;TemplateStyles:r886058088&quot;&gt;&lt;![CDATA[.mw-parser-output cite.citation{font-style:inherit}.mw-parser-output .citation q{quotes:&quot;\&quot;&quot;&quot;\&quot;&quot;&quot;'&quot;&quot;'&quot;}.mw-parser-output .citation .cs1-lock-free a{background:url(&quot;//upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/6/65/Lock-green.svg/9px-Lock-green.svg.png&quot;)no-repeat;background-position:right .1em center}.mw-parser-output .citation .cs1-lock-limited a,.mw-parser-output .citation .cs1-lock-registration a{background:url(&quot;//upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/d/d6/Lock-gray-alt-2.svg/9px-Lock-gray-alt-2.svg.png&quot;)no-repeat;background-position:right .1em center}.mw-parser-output .citation .cs1-lock-subscription a{background:url(&quot;//upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/a/aa/Lock-red-alt-2.svg/9px-Lock-red-alt-2.svg.png&quot;)no-repeat;background-position:right .1em center}.mw-parser-output .cs1-subscription,.mw-parser-output .cs1-registration{color:#555}.mw-parser-output .cs1-subscription span,.mw-parser-output .cs1-registration span{border-bottom:1px dotted;cursor:help}.mw-parser-output .cs1-ws-icon a{background:url(&quot;//upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/4/4c/Wikisource-logo.svg/12px-Wikisource-logo.svg.png&quot;)no-repeat;background-position:right .1em center}.mw-parser-output code.cs1-code{color:inherit;background:inherit;border:inherit;padding:inherit}.mw-parser-output .cs1-hidden-error{display:none;font-size:100%}.mw-parser-output .cs1-visible-error{font-size:100%}.mw-parser-output .cs1-maint{display:none;color:#33aa33;margin-left:0.3em}.mw-parser-output .cs1-subscription,.mw-parser-output .cs1-registration,.mw-parser-output .cs1-format{font-size:95%}.mw-parser-output .cs1-kern-left,.mw-parser-output .cs1-kern-wl-left{padding-left:0.2em}.mw-parser-output .cs1-kern-right,.mw-parser-output .cs1-kern-wl-right{padding-right:0.2em}]]&gt;&lt;/style&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;cite_note-2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-cite-backlink&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Attempto_Controlled_English#cite_ref-2&quot;&gt;^&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;reference-text&quot;&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external free&quot; href=&quot;http://attempto.ifi.uzh.ch/site/news/&quot;&gt;http://attempto.ifi.uzh.ch/site/news/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;cite_note-3&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-cite-backlink&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Attempto_Controlled_English#cite_ref-3&quot;&gt;^&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;reference-text&quot;&gt;&lt;cite class=&quot;citation conference&quot;&gt;Norbert E. Fuchs; Kaarel Kaljurand; Tobias Kuhn (2010). &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;http://attempto.ifi.uzh.ch/site/pubs/papers/drs_report_66.pdf&quot;&gt;&quot;Discourse Representation Structures for ACE 6.6&quot;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;cs1-format&quot;&gt;(&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PDF&quot; title=&quot;PDF&quot;&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;. &lt;i&gt;Technical Report ifi-2010.0010, Department of Informatics, University of Zurich&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;span title=&quot;ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Abook&amp;amp;rft.genre=conference&amp;amp;rft.atitle=Discourse+Representation+Structures+for+ACE+6.6&amp;amp;rft.btitle=Technical+Report+ifi-2010.0010%2C+Department+of+Informatics%2C+University+of+Zurich&amp;amp;rft.date=2010&amp;amp;rft.au=Norbert+E.+Fuchs&amp;amp;rft.au=Kaarel+Kaljurand&amp;amp;rft.au=Tobias+Kuhn&amp;amp;rft_id=http%3A%2F%2Fattempto.ifi.uzh.ch%2Fsite%2Fpubs%2Fpapers%2Fdrs_report_66.pdf&amp;amp;rfr_id=info%3Asid%2Fen.wikipedia.org%3AAttempto+Controlled+English&quot; class=&quot;Z3988&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;mw-deduplicated-inline-style&quot; href=&quot;mw-data:TemplateStyles:r886058088&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;cite_note-4&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-cite-backlink&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Attempto_Controlled_English#cite_ref-4&quot;&gt;^&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;reference-text&quot;&gt;&lt;cite class=&quot;citation conference&quot;&gt;Tobias Kuhn (2007). &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;http://attempto.ifi.uzh.ch/site/pubs/papers/kuhn07acerules.pdf&quot;&gt;&quot;AceRules: Executing Rules in Controlled Natural Language&quot;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;cs1-format&quot;&gt;(&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PDF&quot; title=&quot;PDF&quot;&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;. &lt;i&gt;First International Conference on Web Reasoning and Rule Systems (RR 2007)&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;span title=&quot;ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Abook&amp;amp;rft.genre=conference&amp;amp;rft.atitle=AceRules%3A+Executing+Rules+in+Controlled+Natural+Language&amp;amp;rft.btitle=First+International+Conference+on+Web+Reasoning+and+Rule+Systems+%28RR+2007%29&amp;amp;rft.date=2007&amp;amp;rft.au=Tobias+Kuhn&amp;amp;rft_id=http%3A%2F%2Fattempto.ifi.uzh.ch%2Fsite%2Fpubs%2Fpapers%2Fkuhn07acerules.pdf&amp;amp;rfr_id=info%3Asid%2Fen.wikipedia.org%3AAttempto+Controlled+English&quot; class=&quot;Z3988&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;mw-deduplicated-inline-style&quot; href=&quot;mw-data:TemplateStyles:r886058088&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;cite_note-5&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-cite-backlink&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Attempto_Controlled_English#cite_ref-5&quot;&gt;^&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;reference-text&quot;&gt;&lt;cite class=&quot;citation conference&quot;&gt;Kaarel Kaljurand; Norbert E. Fuchs (2007). &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;http://attempto.ifi.uzh.ch/site/pubs/papers/owled2007_kaljurand.pdf&quot;&gt;&quot;Verbalizing OWL in Attempto Controlled English&quot;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;cs1-format&quot;&gt;(&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PDF&quot; title=&quot;PDF&quot;&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;. &lt;i&gt;OWL: Experiences and Directions (OWLED 2007)&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;span title=&quot;ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Abook&amp;amp;rft.genre=conference&amp;amp;rft.atitle=Verbalizing+OWL+in+Attempto+Controlled+English&amp;amp;rft.btitle=OWL%3A+Experiences+and+Directions+%28OWLED+2007%29&amp;amp;rft.date=2007&amp;amp;rft.au=Kaarel+Kaljurand&amp;amp;rft.au=Norbert+E.+Fuchs&amp;amp;rft_id=http%3A%2F%2Fattempto.ifi.uzh.ch%2Fsite%2Fpubs%2Fpapers%2Fowled2007_kaljurand.pdf&amp;amp;rfr_id=info%3Asid%2Fen.wikipedia.org%3AAttempto+Controlled+English&quot; class=&quot;Z3988&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;mw-deduplicated-inline-style&quot; href=&quot;mw-data:TemplateStyles:r886058088&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;External_links&quot;&gt;External links&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;http://attempto.ifi.uzh.ch&quot;&gt;Project Attempto&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;!-- 
NewPP limit report
Parsed by mw1224
Cached time: 20190912143417
Cache expiry: 2592000
Dynamic content: false
Complications: [vary&amp;#8208;revision&amp;#8208;sha1]
CPU time usage: 0.216 seconds
Real time usage: 0.303 seconds
Preprocessor visited node count: 482/1000000
Preprocessor generated node count: 0/1500000
Post&amp;#8208;expand include size: 22396/2097152 bytes
Template argument size: 165/2097152 bytes
Highest expansion depth: 10/40
Expensive parser function count: 2/500
Unstrip recursion depth: 1/20
Unstrip post&amp;#8208;expand size: 12871/5000000 bytes
Number of Wikibase entities loaded: 0/400
Lua time usage: 0.126/10.000 seconds
Lua memory usage: 3.29 MB/50 MB
--&gt;&lt;!--
Transclusion expansion time report (%,ms,calls,template)
100.00%  257.832      1 -total
 50.80%  130.986      1 Template:Reflist
 43.36%  111.804      4 Template:Cite_conference
 41.39%  106.719      1 Template:Refimprove
 35.43%   91.343      2 Template:Ambox
 15.86%   40.898      1 Template:Find_sources_mainspace
  5.52%   14.224      1 Template:Unreferenced_section
  3.57%    9.207      1 Template:Unreferenced
  1.57%    4.052      1 Template:Main_other
--&gt;&lt;!-- Saved in parser cache with key enwiki:pcache:idhash:6520028-0!canonical and timestamp 20190912143417 and revision id 915318862
 --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Special:CentralAutoLogin/start?type=1x1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;border: none; position: absolute;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
		
		&lt;div class=&quot;printfooter&quot;&gt;Retrieved from &quot;&lt;a dir=&quot;ltr&quot; href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Attempto_Controlled_English&amp;amp;oldid=915318862&quot;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Attempto_Controlled_English&amp;amp;oldid=915318862&lt;/a&gt;&quot;&lt;/div&gt;
		
		
		&lt;div class=&quot;visualClear&quot;/&gt;
		
	</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 11:09:37 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>solarkraft</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Attempto_Controlled_English</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The beauty of functional languages in deep learning – Clojure and Haskell</title>
<link>https://www.welcometothejungle.co/fr/articles/btc-deep-learning-clojure-haskell</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.welcometothejungle.co/fr/articles/btc-deep-learning-clojure-haskell</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Deep learning is a subset of machine learning methods that are based on artificial neural networks. These are inspired by information processing and distributed communication nodes in biological systems such as the brain. In deep learning, each level learns to transform the input data into a slightly more abstract and composite representation. For instance, in a facial-recognition system, pixels might be one layer of the system, while edges might be another, eyes might be another, and the face might be another. The complexity of deep learning methods makes using existing packages popular in the programming community. &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://www.tensorflow.org&quot;&gt;TensorFlow&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://pytorch.org&quot;&gt;PyTorch&lt;/a&gt; in Python are popular, as is the &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://blog.rstudio.com/2017/09/05/keras-for-r/&quot;&gt;Keras&lt;/a&gt; package in R. However, in the production of deep learning systems, &lt;strong&gt;performance and safety are two issues that drive companies to choose functional programming languages such as Clojure and Haskell instead.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.welcometothejungle.co/uploads/image/file/7173/156699/86e5015a-25c4-4837-80a2-6d0bc7dbc760.png&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The difficulties of deep learning implementations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In putting deep learning systems into production, neural networks might contain a million parameters. Data can quickly explode to train these parameters. This explosion of data requires performance that can only be achieved by &lt;strong&gt;an efficient programming language with safe concurrency and parallelism capabilities&lt;/strong&gt;. Due to the complexity of neural networks, with data passed from layer to layer, simplicity and consistency in the way the programming language handles this data is important. Safety, in this case, means the ability to preserve the state of the original data in a consistent manner, while simplicity means being able to read and maintain the code base easily while maximizing performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why functional programming is more suitable for deep learning&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an attempt to resolve some of the difficulties that can occur when implementing deep learning, programmers are finding that &lt;strong&gt;functional programming languages can provide solutions&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In computer science, functional programming is a programming paradigm that treats computation as the evaluation of mathematical functions and avoids changing state and mutable data. It is a programming pattern that is closer to mathematical thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deep learning models are essentially mathematical models. For instance, artificial neural networks comprise connected nodes, each of which performs simple mathematical operations. &lt;strong&gt;By using a functional programming language, programmers are able to describe these mathematical operations in a language that’s closer to the operations themselves.&lt;/strong&gt; The explicit way these programs are written makes reading and maintaining the code base much easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time, the compositional nature of deep learning algorithms means that, at each layer of the neural work, the layers or the functions tend to chain together to perform tasks. This can be easily implemented using the functional chaining of a functional programming language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.welcometothejungle.co/uploads/image/file/7180/156699/753312dc-d7a9-4bd2-8f37-95b53687476a.png&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, &lt;strong&gt;in deep learning, when functions are applied to the data, the data does not change&lt;/strong&gt;. New values might be output sequentially down the line, but the data itself stays consistent. The immutability feature of a functional programming language will allow the programmer to create a new dataset each time new values are generated without altering the original immutable dataset. This makes it easier to maintain the consistency of the data throughout the neural network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, the large number of parameters and training data involved in the implementation of deep learning means that parallelism and concurrency are the keys to creating production-level deep learning systems. Parallelism means running threads on different CPUs to speed up the learning process. Concurrency means the ability to manage threads to avoid conflict. &lt;strong&gt;Functional programming allows for concurrency and parallelism at no cost.&lt;/strong&gt; This means that, by its nature, functional programming, where the pure function is stateless, will always produce the same output for a particular input, lead to the ability to isolate any function, and execute whenever you want it to. This makes concurrency and parallelism much easier to manage. You don’t have to deal with issues such as deadlocks and race conditions. Different threads accessing different CPUs will be able to run independently with no contentions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Clojure&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With functional programming gaining popularity in deep learning, and with the robust packages available for deep learning, &lt;strong&gt;Clojure&lt;/strong&gt; is now favored by companies such as Walmart and Facebook. It’s a high-level, dynamic functional programming language based on the LISP programming language and it has compilers that make it possible to run on both the Java and the .NET runtime environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The power of concurrent programming in Clojure&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clojure doesn’t replace the Java thread system, rather &lt;strong&gt;it works with it&lt;/strong&gt;. Since the core data structures are immutable, they can be shared readily between threads. At the same time, state changes in the program are possible, but Clojure provides mechanisms to ensure that states stay consistent. If conflicts occur between 2 transactions trying to modify the same reference, one of them will retire. There’s no need for explicit locking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;Clojure&quot;&gt;(import ‘(java.util.concurrent Executors))
(defn test-stm [nitems nthreads niters]
 (let [refs (map ref (repeat nitems 0))
   pool (Executors/newFixedThreadPool nthreads)
   tasks (map (fn [t]
               (fn []
                (dotimes [n niters]
                  (dosync
                   (doseq [r refs]
                    (alter r + 1 t))))))
              (range nthreads))]
   (doseq [future (.invokeAll pool tasks)]
      (.get future))
   (.shutdown pool)
   (map deref refs)))
(test-stm 10 10 10000) -&amp;gt; (550000 550000 550000 550000 550000 550000 550000 550000 550000 550000)&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://clojure.org/about/concurrent_programming&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Parallelism in Clojure is cheap&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In deep learning, models have to train on large amounts of data. Parallelism implies running multiple threads on different CPUs. Parallelism that is cheap will mean significant performance improvements. &lt;strong&gt;Using partition in conjunction with map can achieve parallelism that is less costly.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;Clojure&quot;&gt;(defn calculate-pixels-2 []
 (let [n (* *width* *height*)
       work (partition (/ n 16) (range 0 n))
       result (pmap (fn [x]
                  (doall (map
                   (fn [p]
                     (let [row (rem p *width*) col (int (/ p *height*))]
                       (get-color (process-pixel (/ row (double *width*)) (/ col (double *height*))))))
                   x)))
                  work)]
   (doall (apply concat result))))&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;http://www.fatvat.co.uk/2009/05/jvisualvm-and-clojure.html&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Chaining functions in Clojure means clarity&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Clojure, there are many functions for very few data types. Functions can also be passed as arguments to other functions, &lt;strong&gt;which makes chaining functions in deep learning possible&lt;/strong&gt;. With implementation closer to the actual mathematical model, Clojure code can be simple to read and maintain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;Clojure&quot;&gt;;; pipe arg to function
(-&amp;gt; &quot;x&quot; f1) ; &quot;x1&quot;

;; pipe. function chaining
(-&amp;gt; &quot;x&quot; f1 f2) ; &quot;x12&quot;&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;http://xahlee.info/clojure/clojure_function_chaining.html&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Identity and state in Clojure provide safety&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Clojure, each model’s identity has one state at any point in time. That state is a true value that never changes. If the identity appears to change, this is because it’s associated with a different state. New values are functions of old. Inside each layer of the neural network, the state of the original data is always preserved. Each set of data with new values that are outputs of functions can operate independently. This means that &lt;strong&gt;actions can be performed on these sets of data safely or without regard to contention.&lt;/strong&gt; We can refer back to the original state of the data at any time. Therefore, consistency, in this case, means safety.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Libraries and Limitations&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Historically, the &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/originrose/cortex&quot;&gt;cortex machine learning library&lt;/a&gt; contains all you need to implement machine learning algorithms in Clojure. With the recent rising popularity of the open-source MXNet framework for deep learning, it is easier to implement deep learning using the &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://mxnet.incubator.apache.org/api/clojure/index.html&quot;&gt;MXNet-Clojure API&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although there are now different APIs and machine-learning libraries available for Clojure, there is still a steep learning curve to becoming fluent in it. Error messages can be cryptic and companies will need to be willing to invest upfront to use it to scale up their machine learning systems. As more examples of production-ready systems are written in Clojure, the language will gain more popularity over the coming years, but only if the number and size of libraries accompanying the usage of Clojure grows consistently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Haskell&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Haskell is a functional language that is statically typed with type inference and lazy evaluation. It is based on the semantics of the Miranda programming language and considered to be more expressive, faster, and safer for implementing machine learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Type safety in Haskell provides safety and flexibility&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Type safety defines constraints on the types of values a variable can hold. This will &lt;strong&gt;help to prevent illegal operations, provide better memory safety, and lead to fewer logic errors&lt;/strong&gt;. Lazy evaluation means that Haskell will delay the evaluation of an expression until its value is needed. It also avoids repeated evaluations, which will save running time. At the same time, lazy evaluation allows for &lt;strong&gt;infinite data structures to be defined&lt;/strong&gt;. This gives a programmer unlimited mathematical possibilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Simple explicit code in Haskell provides clear implementations&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest benefits of Haskell is that &lt;strong&gt;it can describe algorithms in very explicit mathematical constructs.&lt;/strong&gt; You can represent a model in a few lines of code. You can also read the code in the same way you can read a math equation. This can be very powerful in complex algorithms such as deep learning algorithms in machine learning. For example, the below implementation of a single layer of a feed-forward neural network shows just how readable the code can be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;Haskell&quot;&gt;import Numeric.LinearAlgebra.Static.Backprop
logistic :: Floating a =&amp;gt; a -&amp;gt; a
logistic x = 1 / (1 + exp (-x))
feedForwardLog
   :: (KnownNat i, KnownNat o)
   =&amp;gt; Model (L o i :&amp;amp; R o) (R i) (R o)
feedForwardLog (w :&amp;amp;&amp;amp; b) x = logistic (w #&amp;gt; x + b)&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://blog.jle.im/entry/purely-functional-typed-models-1.html&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Multicore parallelism in Haskell provides performance&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In deep learning, typical neural networks will contain a million parameters that define the model. Also, a large amount of data is required to learn these parameters, which, computationally, is very time-consuming. On a single machine, using multiple cores to share the memory and process in parallel can be very powerful when it comes to implementing deep learning. In Haskell, however, &lt;strong&gt;implementing &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://wiki.haskell.org/Parallelism&quot;&gt;multicore parallelism&lt;/a&gt; is easy&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Libraries and limitations&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Haskell’s &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/mikeizbicki/HLearn&quot;&gt;HLearn library&lt;/a&gt; contains machine learning algorithm implementations, while the &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/tensorflow/haskell&quot;&gt;tensor-flow binding&lt;/a&gt; for Haskell can be used for deep learning. &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://downloads.haskell.org/~ghc/7.0.3/docs/html/users_guide/lang-parallel.html&quot;&gt;Parallel and Concurrent&lt;/a&gt;, meanwhile, are used for parallelism and concurrency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although there are some machine learning libraries developed in Haskell, ground-up implementations will still need to be done for production-ready Haskell implementations. While public libraries available for specific deep learning and machine learning tasks are limited, Haskell’s usage in AI will also be limited. Companies such as Aetion Technologies and Credit Suisse Global Modeling and Analytics Group are using Haskell in their implementations—&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://wiki.haskell.org/Haskell_in_industry&quot;&gt;here’s a complete list of the organizations using it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deep learning models are complex mathematical models that require specific layering of functions. Functional programming languages such as Clojure and Haskell can often represent the complexity with cleaner code that’s closer to the mathematics of the model. This leads to time savings, efficiency, and easy management of the code base. Specific properties of functional programming allow the implementations in these languages to be safer than those of other languages. As development in AI technology progresses, evaluating these languages for the needs of large-scale system-development projects in AI will become more prevalent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article is part of Behind the Code, the media for developers, by developers. Discover more articles and videos by visiting &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://www.welcometothejungle.co/collections/behind-the-code&quot;&gt;Behind the Code&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Want to contribute? &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSeelH8Eh0HohNrrDWnmKJGBRsFijXfMsMw1fPxOSGdMVypCyg/viewform?usp=sf_link&quot;&gt;Get published!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Follow us on &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/behind_thecode&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; to stay tuned!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Illustration by &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://fr.creasenso.com/portfolio/victoria-roussel&quot;&gt;Victoria Roussel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 10:44:16 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>wickwavy</dc:creator>
<og:title>The Beauty of Functional Languages in Deep Learning </og:title>
<og:description>Functional languages such as Clojure and Haskell can often represent the complexity with cleaner code that’s closer to the mathematics of the model.</og:description>
<og:image>https://cdn.welcometothejungle.co/uploads/article/image/6666/156699/large_clojure-haskell.png</og:image>
<og:url>https://www.welcometothejungle.co/fr/articles/btc-deep-learning-clojure-haskell</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>fr</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.welcometothejungle.co/fr/articles/btc-deep-learning-clojure-haskell</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Can I Email: ‘Can I Use’ for email</title>
<link>https://www.caniemail.com/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.caniemail.com/</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;meta charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;/&gt;&lt;title&gt;Can I email… Support tables for HTML and CSS in emails&lt;/title&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; href=&quot;/assets/css/styles.css&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;viewport&quot; content=&quot;width=device-width, initial-scale=1.0&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;shortcut icon&quot; href=&quot;/assets/images/favicon.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;prefetch&quot; href=&quot;/assets/js/features.json&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;description&quot; content=&quot;Support tables for HTML and CSS in emails.&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:title&quot; content=&quot;Can I email…&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:type&quot; content=&quot;website&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:description&quot; content=&quot;Support tables for HTML and CSS in emails.&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:url&quot; content=&quot;https://www.caniemail.com/&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:image&quot; content=&quot;https://www.caniemail.com/assets/images/og.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caniemail&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;homepage&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caniemail-block&quot;&gt;

&lt;ol class=&quot;caniemail-list&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.caniemail.com/features/css-variables/&quot;&gt;CSS Variables (Custom Properties)&lt;/a&gt;, August 23, 2019&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.caniemail.com/features/css-at-media/&quot;&gt;CSS @media&lt;/a&gt;, August 20, 2019&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.caniemail.com/features/css-at-media-orientation/&quot;&gt;CSS @media (orientation)&lt;/a&gt;, August 20, 2019&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.caniemail.com/features/css-at-media-device-pixel-ratio/&quot;&gt;CSS @media (-webkit-device-pixel-ratio)&lt;/a&gt;, August 20, 2019&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.caniemail.com/features/html-anchor-links/&quot;&gt;HTML Anchor links&lt;/a&gt;, August 08, 2019&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.caniemail.com/features/&quot; class=&quot;feature-button&quot;&gt;View all features&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caniemail-block&quot;&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;caniemail-list&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.caniemail.com/news/2019-09-09-introducing-caniemail/&quot;&gt;Introducing caniemail.com&lt;/a&gt;, September 09, 2019&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.caniemail.com/news/2019-08-28-background/&quot;&gt;Added Background&lt;/a&gt;, August 28, 2019&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.caniemail.com/news/2019-08-23-css-variables/&quot;&gt;Added CSS Variables&lt;/a&gt;, August 23, 2019&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.caniemail.com/news/2019-08-21-scoreboard/&quot;&gt;Say hello to the Scoreboard!&lt;/a&gt;, August 21, 2019&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.caniemail.com/news/2019-08-20-css-media-queries/&quot;&gt;Added Media Queries&lt;/a&gt;, August 20, 2019&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.caniemail.com/news/&quot; class=&quot;feature-button&quot;&gt;View all news&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caniemail-block&quot;&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;scoreboard&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;score-text&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;score-name&quot;&gt;Apple Mail (macOS)&lt;/span&gt; : 55&lt;small&gt;/58&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;score-text&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;score-name&quot;&gt;Apple Mail (iOS)&lt;/span&gt; : 55&lt;small&gt;/58&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;score-text&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;score-name&quot;&gt;Orange (Desktop Webmail)&lt;/span&gt; : 54&lt;small&gt;/58&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;score-text&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;score-name&quot;&gt;Samsung Email (Android)&lt;/span&gt; : 53&lt;small&gt;/57&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;score-text&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;score-name&quot;&gt;Outlook (macOS)&lt;/span&gt; : 53&lt;small&gt;/55&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.caniemail.com/scoreboard/&quot; class=&quot;feature-button&quot;&gt;View the scoreboard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 07:14:01 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>heidijavi</dc:creator>
<og:title>Can I email…</og:title>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:description>Support tables for HTML and CSS in emails.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.caniemail.com/</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.caniemail.com/assets/images/og.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.caniemail.com/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ban kids from loot box gambling in games</title>
<link>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-49661870</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-49661870</guid>
<description>&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape no-caption full-width lead&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                &lt;img class=&quot;js-image-replace&quot; alt=&quot;Boy and man holding consoles&quot; src=&quot;https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/320/cpsprodpb/14EBE/production/_108749658_kidconsole.gif&quot; width=&quot;976&quot; height=&quot;549&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image copyright&lt;/span&gt;
                 &lt;span class=&quot;story-image-copyright&quot;&gt;Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
        &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;story-body__introduction&quot;&gt;In-game spending should be regulated by gambling laws and so-called loot boxes banned entirely for children, MPs say.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The industry's UK trade body responded it would &quot;review these recommendations with utmost seriousness&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But the committee of MPs had accused some of those who had given evidence of a &quot;lack of honesty and transparency&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Free video games often encourage players to buy virtual loot boxes, which contain an unspecified amount of items to improve further game-play.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some games have associated online marketplaces where players can trade or sell these items.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Digital, Culture, Media and Sport Committee's inquiry into addictive and immersive technologies heard stories of young adults who had built up debts of thousands of pounds through spending in games. Jagex, the company behind online game RuneScape, admitted players could spend up to £1,000 a week or £5,000 a month.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But the MPs found the industry was reluctant to accept responsibility for intervening when a player was over-spending or even to put a figure on how much was too much.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And some had been &quot;wilfully obtuse&quot; in answering questions about game-play, which MPs needed to know in order to better understand how players engaged with games.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Without naming names, they said they had sometimes found it difficult to get full and clear answers from the gaming industry representatives who had appeared before them, in particular when it came to answering questions about what data they collected, how it was used and the psychology underpinning how games were designed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;story-body__crosshead&quot;&gt;Honesty system&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Social media platforms and online games makers are locked in a relentless battle to capture ever more of people's attention, time and money,&quot; Mr Collins said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Their business models are built on this but it's time for them to be more responsible in dealing with the harms these technologies can cause for some users.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In response Dr Jo Twist, the chief executive of UK Interactive Entertainment, said: &quot;&quot;The video games industry has always, and will continue to, put the welfare of players at the heart of what we do.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;The industry does not dispute that, for a minority, finding balance is a problem. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;This is why we are vocal in supporting efforts to increase digital literacy and work with schools and carers on education programmes.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But Mr Collins said the games industry should contribute financially towards independent research into the long-term effects of gaming.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Gaming disorder based on excessive and addictive game-play has been recognised by the World Health Organization,&quot; he said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;It's time for game companies to use the huge quantities of data they gather about their players to do more to proactively identify vulnerable gamers.&quot; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The MPs also called for both social media platforms and game-makers to establish effective age-verification tools. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Currently both rely on a honesty system and, as a result, there are large numbers of under-age users on social media and playing games.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape has-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
                 &lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image copyright&lt;/span&gt;
                 &lt;span class=&quot;story-image-copyright&quot;&gt;Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
            &lt;figcaption class=&quot;media-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image caption&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;media-caption__text&quot;&gt;
                    Loot boxes offer a variety of rewards that can improve game-play
                &lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;Loot boxes should not be sold to children and should instead be earned as rewards for game-play, the MPs said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Loot boxes are particularly lucrative for games companies but come at a high cost, particularly for problem gamblers, while exposing children to potential harm,&quot; Mr Collins said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Buying a loot box is playing a game of chance and it is high time the gambling laws caught up. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;We challenge the government to explain why loot boxes should be exempt from the Gambling Act.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is growing international disquiet about loot boxes, with a US senator calling for them to be banned and the government of Belgium ruling they were in violation of gambling laws.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;China has restricted the number of loot boxes players can open each day. Sweden is also investigating them.&lt;/p&gt;
            </description>
<pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 05:54:12 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>MarcScott</dc:creator>
<og:title>'Ban kids from loot box gambling in games'</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>In-game spending should be regulated by gambling laws and loot boxes banned for children, they say.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-49661870</og:url>
<og:image>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/14EBE/production/_108749658_kidconsole.gif</og:image>
<dc:language>en-GB</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-49661870</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Dissatisfied with Docker</title>
<link>https://robert.ocallahan.org/2019/09/dissatisfied-with-docker.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://robert.ocallahan.org/2019/09/dissatisfied-with-docker.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I am not satisfied with Docker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Untrusted users should be able to run their own container instances. Running a basic container instance means forking a process, putting it in the right kernel namespaces, and setting up mounts and virtual network interfaces, and those can all be done without privileges. Unfortunately, in Docker, access to the Docker daemon is tantamount to being root. Fixing this would improve both convenience and security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, a global system daemon should not be needed. Either users should be able to run their own daemons or container management should avoid having a daemon at all, by storing container state in a shared database.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Docker container builds are too slow. Installing a container image requires piping massive amounts of image data to the daemon over a socket, which is ridiculous. This could be avoided by passing a file descriptor to the container manager ... or you might even get rid of container image management and start containers by pointing directly to the files comprising the image.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Docker container instances start too slowly. It shouldn't take seconds to start or stop a simple small container. The system calls required to start a simple container run in milliseconds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No doubt these observations are old news, so I assume there are better container implementations out there. Which one do I want?&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 00:22:19 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>khuey</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://robert.ocallahan.org/2019/09/dissatisfied-with-docker.html</og:url>
<og:title>Dissatisfied With Docker</og:title>
<og:description>I am not satisfied with Docker. Untrusted users should be able to run their own container instances. Running a basic container instance mean...</og:description>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://robert.ocallahan.org/2019/09/dissatisfied-with-docker.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>