<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Open-sourcing a 10x reduction in Apache Cassandra tail latency</title>
<link>https://engineering.instagram.com/open-sourcing-a-10x-reduction-in-apache-cassandra-tail-latency-d64f86b43589</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://engineering.instagram.com/open-sourcing-a-10x-reduction-in-apache-cassandra-tail-latency-d64f86b43589</guid>
<description>&lt;p name=&quot;1d80&quot; id=&quot;1d80&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;At Instagram, we have one of the world’s largest deployments of the Apache Cassandra database. We began using Cassandra in 2012 to replace Redis and support product use cases like fraud detection, Feed, and the Direct inbox. At first we ran Cassandra clusters in an AWS environment, but migrated them over to Facebook’s infrastructure when the rest of Instagram moved. We’ve had a really good experience with the reliability and availability of Cassandra, but saw room for improvement in read latency.&lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt;Last year Instagram’s Cassandra team started working on a project to reduce Cassandra’s read latency significantly, which we call Rocksandra. In this post, I will describe the motivation for this project, the challenges we overcame, and performance metrics in both internal and public cloud environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 name=&quot;d01d&quot; id=&quot;d01d&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Motivation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;c5aa&quot; id=&quot;c5aa&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;At Instagram, we use Apache Cassandra heavily as a general key value storage service. The majority of Instagram’s Cassandra requests are online, so in order to provide a reliable and responsive user experience for hundreds of millions of Instagram users, we have very tight SLA on the metrics. &lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt;Instagram maintains a 5–9s reliability SLA, which means at any given time, the request failure rate should be less than 0.001%. For performance, we actively monitor the throughput and latency of different Cassandra clusters, especially the P99 read latency. &lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt; Here’s a graph that shows the client-side latency of one production Cassandra cluster. The blue line is the average read latency (5ms) and the orange line is the P99 read latency (in the range of 25ms to 60ms and changing a lot based on client traffic).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*Scn1Nm33oukOJpUd4Ukszw.png&quot; data-width=&quot;1052&quot; data-height=&quot;668&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*Scn1Nm33oukOJpUd4Ukszw.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*Scn1Nm33oukOJpUd4Ukszw.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*ItBORNwCXce82ZNX6qf6Vg.png&quot; data-width=&quot;1052&quot; data-height=&quot;668&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*ItBORNwCXce82ZNX6qf6Vg.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*ItBORNwCXce82ZNX6qf6Vg.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;0e33&quot; id=&quot;0e33&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;After investigation, we found the JVM garbage collector (GC) contributed a lot to the latency spikes. We defined a metric called GC stall percentage to measure the percentage of time a Cassandra server was doing stop-the-world GC (Young Gen GC) and could not serve client requests. Here’s another graph that shows the GC stall percentage on our production Cassandra servers. It was 1.25% during the lowest traffic time windows, and could be as high as 2.5% during peak hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;14d6&quot; id=&quot;14d6&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;The graph shows that a Cassandra server instance could spend 2.5% of runtime on garbage collections instead of serving client requests. The GC overhead obviously had a big impact on our P99 latency, so if we could lower the GC stall percentage, we would be able to reduce our P99 latency significantly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 name=&quot;87af&quot; id=&quot;87af&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Solution&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;5830&quot; id=&quot;5830&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;Apache Cassandra is a distributed database with it’s own LSM tree-based storage engine written in Java. We found that the components in the storage engine, like memtable, compaction, read/write path, etc., created a lot of objects in the Java heap and generated a lot of overhead to JVM. To reduce the GC impact from the storage engine, we considered different approaches and ultimately decided to develop a C++ storage engine to replace existing ones. &lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt;We did not want to build a new storage engine from scratch, so we decided to build the new storage engine on top of RocksDB. &lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt;RocksDB is an open source, high-performance embedded database for key-value data. It’s written in C++, and provides official API language bindings for C++, C, and Java. RocksDB is optimized for performance, especially on fast storage like SSD. It’s widely used in the industry as the storage engine for MySQL, mongoDB, and other popular databases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 name=&quot;cb1c&quot; id=&quot;cb1c&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Challenges&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;4c10&quot; id=&quot;4c10&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;We overcame three main challenges when implementing the new storage engine on RocksDB.&lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt;The first challenge was that Cassandra does not have a pluggable storage engine architecture yet, which means the existing storage engine is coupled together with other components in the database. To find a balance between massive refactoring and quick iterations, we defined a new storage engine API, including the most common read/write and streaming interfaces. This way we could implement the new storage engine behind the API and inject it into the related code paths inside Cassandra.&lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt;Secondly, Cassandra supports rich data types and table schema, while RocksDB provides purely key-value interfaces. We carefully defined the encoding/decoding algorithms to support Cassandra’s data model within RocksDB’s data structure and supported same-query semantics as original Cassandra. &lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt;The third challenge was about streaming. Streaming is an important component for a distributed database like Cassandra. Whenever we join or remove a node from a Cassandra cluster, Cassandra needs to stream data among different nodes to balance the load across the cluster. The existing streaming implementation was based on the details in the current storage engine. Accordingly, we had to decouple them from each other, make an abstraction layer, and re-implement the streaming using RocksDB APIs. For high streaming throughput, we now stream data into temp sst files first, and then use the RocksDB ingest file API to bulk load them into the RocksDB instance at once.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 name=&quot;a1f4&quot; id=&quot;a1f4&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Performance metrics&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;7a2f&quot; id=&quot;7a2f&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;After about a year of development and testing, we have finished a first version of the implementation and successfully rolled it into several production Cassandra clusters in Instagram. In one of our production clusters, the P99 read latency dropped from 60ms to 20ms. We also observed that the GC stalls on that cluster dropped from 2.5% to 0.3%, which was a 10X reduction!&lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt;We also wanted to verify whether Rocksandra would perform well in a public cloud environment. We setup a Cassandra cluster in an AWS environment using three i3.8 xlarge EC2 instances, each with 32 cores CPU, 244GB memory, and raid0 with 4 nvme flash disks. &lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt;We used &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Netflix/ndbench&quot; data-href=&quot;https://github.com/Netflix/ndbench&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;NDBench&lt;/a&gt; for the benchmark, and the default table schema in the framework:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;7425&quot; id=&quot;7425&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--p&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;markup--code markup--blockquote-code&quot;&gt;TABLE emp (&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;code class=&quot;markup--code markup--blockquote-code&quot;&gt;emp_uname text PRIMARY KEY,&lt;br/&gt;emp_dept text,&lt;br/&gt;emp_first text,&lt;br/&gt;emp_last text&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;code class=&quot;markup--code markup--blockquote-code&quot;&gt;)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;e302&quot; id=&quot;e302&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--blockquote&quot;&gt;We pre-loaded 250M 6KB rows into the database (each server stores about 500GB data on disk). We configured 128 readers and 128 writers in NDBench.&lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt;We tested different workloads and measured the avg/P99/P999 read/write latencies. As you can see, Rocksandra provided much lower and consistent tail read/write latency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*Mpvc-jd61xmcrE4aEth4NA.png&quot; data-width=&quot;1132&quot; data-height=&quot;725&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*Mpvc-jd61xmcrE4aEth4NA.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*Mpvc-jd61xmcrE4aEth4NA.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*zZO7xeU8fsWosWbkev873g.png&quot; data-width=&quot;1131&quot; data-height=&quot;724&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*zZO7xeU8fsWosWbkev873g.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*zZO7xeU8fsWosWbkev873g.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;7f48&quot; id=&quot;7f48&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;We also tested a read-only workload and observed that, at similar P99 read latency (2ms), Rocksandra could provide 10X higher read throughput (300K/s for Rocksandra vs. 30K/s for C* 3.0).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*E-2efj-mMo0dQWEvZyxn1g.png&quot; data-width=&quot;1483&quot; data-height=&quot;746&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*E-2efj-mMo0dQWEvZyxn1g.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*E-2efj-mMo0dQWEvZyxn1g.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*d5gs5SJzq6laocevBqA1Bg.png&quot; data-width=&quot;1359&quot; data-height=&quot;731&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*d5gs5SJzq6laocevBqA1Bg.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*d5gs5SJzq6laocevBqA1Bg.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 name=&quot;d343&quot; id=&quot;d343&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;Future work&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;5bac&quot; id=&quot;5bac&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;We have open sourced our &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Instagram/cassandra/tree/rocks_3.0&quot; data-href=&quot;https://github.com/Instagram/cassandra/tree/rocks_3.0&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Rocksandra code base&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Instagram/cassandra-aws-benchmark&quot; data-href=&quot;https://github.com/Instagram/cassandra-aws-benchmark&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;benchmark framework&lt;/a&gt;, which you can download from Github to try out in your own environment! Please let us know how it performs.&lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt;As our next step, we are actively working on the development of more C* features support, like secondary indexes, repair, etc. We are also working on a &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/CASSANDRA-13474&quot; data-href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/CASSANDRA-13474&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;C* pluggable storage engine architecture&lt;/a&gt; to contribute our work back to the Apache Cassandra community. &lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt;If you are in the Bay Area and are interested in learning more about our Cassandra developments, join us at our next meetup event &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.meetup.com/Apache-Cassandra-Bay-Area/events/248376266/&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.meetup.com/Apache-Cassandra-Bay-Area/events/248376266/&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;3171&quot; id=&quot;3171&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p graf--trailing&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;Dikang Gu is an infrastructure engineer at Instagram.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 18:20:37 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mikeyk</dc:creator>
<og:title>Open-sourcing a 10x reduction in Apache Cassandra tail latency</og:title>
<og:url>https://engineering.instagram.com/open-sourcing-a-10x-reduction-in-apache-cassandra-tail-latency-d64f86b43589</og:url>
<og:image>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*Scn1Nm33oukOJpUd4Ukszw.png</og:image>
<og:description>At Instagram, we have one of the world’s largest deployments of the Apache Cassandra database. We began using Cassandra in 2012 to replace…</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://engineering.instagram.com/open-sourcing-a-10x-reduction-in-apache-cassandra-tail-latency-d64f86b43589?gi=2d45eab87482</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Is Loneliness a Health Epidemic?</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/02/09/opinion/sunday/loneliness-health.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2018/02/09/opinion/sunday/loneliness-health.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;591&quot; data-total-count=&quot;2318&quot; id=&quot;story-continues-3&quot;&gt;The other possible cause is the rise of communications technology, including smartphones, social media and the internet. A decade ago, companies like Facebook, Apple and Google pledged that their products would help create meaningful relationships and communities. Instead, we’ve used the media system to deepen existing divisions, at both the individual and group levels. We may have thousands of “friends” and “followers” on Facebook and Instagram, but when it comes to human relationships, it turns out there’s no substitute for building them the old-fashioned way, in person.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;234&quot; data-total-count=&quot;2552&quot;&gt;In light of these two trends, it’s easy to believe we’re experiencing an “epidemic” of loneliness and isolation. Surprisingly, though, the best data do not actually show drastic spikes in either loneliness or social isolation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;582&quot; data-total-count=&quot;3134&quot;&gt;The main evidence for rising isolation comes from a widely reported sociology journal article claiming that in 2004, one in four Americans &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/000312240607100301&quot;&gt;had no one&lt;/a&gt; in their life they felt they could confide in, compared with one in 10 during the 1980s. But that study turned out to be &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/000312240907400408&quot;&gt;based on faulty data&lt;/a&gt;, and other research shows that the portion of Americans without a confidant is about the same as it has long been. Although one of the authors has &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.chronicle.com/article/The-Case-for-American/130480&quot;&gt;distanced himself from the paper&lt;/a&gt; (saying, “I no longer think it’s reliable”), scholars, journalists and policymakers continue to cite it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;567&quot; data-total-count=&quot;3701&quot;&gt;The other data on loneliness are complicated and often contradictory, in part because there are so many different ways of measuring the phenomenon. But it’s clear that the loneliness statistics cited by those who say we have an epidemic are outliers. For example, one set of statistics comes from a study that counted as lonely people who said they felt “left out” or “isolated,” or “lacked companionship” — even just “some of the time.” That’s an exceedingly low bar, and surely not one we’d want doctors or policymakers to use in their work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;319&quot; data-total-count=&quot;4020&quot;&gt;One reason we need to be careful about how we measure and respond to loneliness is that, as the University of Chicago psychologist John Cacioppo argues, an occasional and transitory feeling of loneliness can be healthy and productive. It’s a biological signal to ourselves that we need to build stronger social bonds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;695&quot; data-total-count=&quot;4715&quot;&gt;Professor Cacioppo has spent much of his career documenting the dangers of loneliness. But it’s notable that he relies on more measured statistics in his own scientific papers than the statistics described above. One of his articles, from last year, reports that around 19 percent of older Americans said they had felt lonely for much of the week before they were surveyed, and that in Britain about 6 percent of adults said they felt lonely all or most of the time. Those are worrisome numbers, but they are quite similar to the numbers reported in Britain in 1948, when about 8 percent of older adults said they often or always felt lonely, and to those in previous American studies as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;210&quot; data-total-count=&quot;4925&quot;&gt;Professor Cacioppo is one of the leading voices advocating for better treatment of loneliness. But, as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.psychologytoday.com/blog/connections/200905/epidemic-loneliness&quot;&gt;he has written&lt;/a&gt;, “to call it an epidemic of loneliness risks having it relegated to the advice columns.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;604&quot; data-total-count=&quot;5529&quot;&gt;In particular, overstating the problem can make it harder to make sure we are focusing on the people who need help the most. When Britain announced its new ministry, officials insisted that everyone, young or old, was at risk of loneliness. Yet the research tells us something more specific. In places like the United States and Britain, it’s the poor, unemployed, displaced and migrant populations that stand to suffer most from loneliness and isolation. Their lives are unstable, and so are their relationships. When they get lonely, they are the least able to get adequate social or medical support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;story-ad-2&quot; class=&quot;story-ad ad ad-placeholder nocontent robots-nocontent&quot;&gt;

&lt;a class=&quot;visually-hidden skip-to-text-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/02/09/opinion/sunday/loneliness-health.html#story-continues-4&quot;&gt;Continue reading the main story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;230&quot; data-total-count=&quot;5759&quot; id=&quot;story-continues-4&quot;&gt;I don’t believe we have a loneliness epidemic. But millions of people are suffering from social disconnection. Whether or not they have a minister for loneliness, they deserve more attention and help than we’re offering today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;visually-hidden skip-to-text-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/02/09/opinion/sunday/loneliness-health.html#whats-next&quot;&gt;Continue reading the main story&lt;/a&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 15:27:09 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>dpflan</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/02/09/opinion/sunday/loneliness-health.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Opinion | Is Loneliness a Health Epidemic?</og:title>
<og:description>Social disconnection is a serious matter. But let’s not whip up a panic.</og:description>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/02/11/opinion/sunday/11gray/11gray-facebookJumbo.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/02/09/opinion/sunday/loneliness-health.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Show HN: Hearth – A Dropbox-like, IPFS-powered personal website publisher</title>
<link>https://hearth.eternum.io/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://hearth.eternum.io/</guid>
<description>&lt;h4&gt;What… what?&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hearth aims to be your decentralized website publisher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This means that you can &lt;strong&gt;publish your personal websites&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;share files with your friends&lt;/strong&gt; without relying on third parties, quickly and easily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Why?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because nobody makes personal websites any more!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in the 90s, the web used to be a vibrant place of a myriad websites of different shapes and sizes, but nowadays it feels much more IKEA. Yes, it's much easier to start a blog by signing up with Tumblr, but that means that everything nowadays looks the same and has none of the quirkiness and personality of the old web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Places like &lt;a href=&quot;https://neocities.org/&quot;&gt;Neocities&lt;/a&gt; do good work in helping bring this back, and we wanted to lend a hand and make publishing even easier. That's why we made Hearth, so you can publish your very own, very personal website, without any of the hassle of learning how to upload files or finding suitable webhosts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;How?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To publish your amazing website, drop the folder that contains your index.html/css/js files into the Hearth folder, right-click on the former and select &quot;Copy Hearth link&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You're good to go!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 14:54:10 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>StavrosK</dc:creator>
<og:title>Hearth</og:title>
<og:description>Publish personal websites with the power of IPFS.</og:description>
<og:image>https://hearth.eternum.io/ogimage.png</og:image>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>https://hearth.eternum.io/</og:url>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://hearth.eternum.io/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Dirt Poor: Have Fruits and Vegetables Become Less Nutritious?</title>
<link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/soil-depletion-and-nutrition-loss/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/soil-depletion-and-nutrition-loss/</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;mura-region mura-region-loose&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;mura-region-local&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Dear EarthTalk&lt;/u&gt;: What’s the nutritional difference between the carrot I ate in 1970 and one I eat today? I’ve heard that that there’s very little nutrition left. Is that true?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;—Esther G., Newark, N.J.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would be overkill to say that the carrot you eat today has very little nutrition in it—especially compared to some of the other less healthy foods you likely also eat—but it is true that fruits and vegetables grown decades ago were much richer in vitamins and minerals than the varieties most of us get today. The main culprit in this disturbing nutritional trend is soil depletion: Modern intensive agricultural methods have stripped increasing amounts of nutrients from the soil in which the food we eat grows. Sadly, each successive generation of fast-growing, pest-resistant carrot is truly less good for you than the one before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A landmark study on the topic by Donald Davis and his team of researchers from the University of Texas (UT) at Austin’s Department of Chemistry and Biochemistry was published in December 2004 in the &lt;em&gt;Journal of the American College of Nutrition&lt;/em&gt;. They studied U.S. Department of Agriculture nutritional data from both 1950 and 1999 for 43 different vegetables and fruits, finding “reliable declines” in the amount of protein, calcium, phosphorus, iron, riboflavin (vitamin B2) and vitamin C over the past half century. Davis and his colleagues chalk up this declining nutritional content to the preponderance of agricultural practices designed to improve traits (size, growth rate, pest resistance) other than nutrition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Efforts to breed new varieties of crops that provide greater yield, pest resistance and climate adaptability have allowed crops to grow bigger and more rapidly,” reported Davis, “but their ability to manufacture or uptake nutrients has not kept pace with their rapid growth.” There have likely been declines in other nutrients, too, he said, such as magnesium, zinc and vitamins B-6 and E, but they were not studied in 1950 and more research is needed to find out how much less we are getting of these key vitamins and minerals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Organic Consumers Association cites several other studies with similar findings: A Kushi Institute analysis of nutrient data from 1975 to 1997 found that average calcium levels in 12 fresh vegetables dropped 27 percent; iron levels 37 percent; vitamin A levels 21 percent, and vitamin C levels 30 percent. A similar study of British nutrient data from 1930 to 1980, published in the &lt;em&gt;British Food Journal&lt;/em&gt;,found that in 20 vegetables the average calcium content had declined 19 percent; iron 22 percent; and potassium 14 percent. Yet another study concluded that one would have to eat eight oranges today to derive the same amount of Vitamin A as our grandparents would have gotten from one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What can be done? The key to healthier produce is healthier soil. Alternating fields between growing seasons to give land time to restore would be one important step. Also, foregoing pesticides and fertilizers in favor of organic growing methods is good for the soil, the produce and its consumers. Those who want to get the most nutritious fruits and vegetables should buy regularly from local organic farmers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UT’s Davis warns that just because fruits and vegetables aren’t as healthy as they used to be doesn’t mean we should avoid them. “Vegetables are extraordinarily rich in nutrients and beneficial phytochemicals,” he reported. “They are still there, and vegetables and fruits are our best sources for these.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CONTACTS&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Journal of the American College of Nutrition&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jacn.org&quot;&gt;www.jacn.org&lt;/a&gt;; Kushi Institute, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kushiinstitute.org&quot;&gt;www.kushiinstitute.org&lt;/a&gt;; Organic Consumers Association, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.organicconsumers.org&quot;&gt;www.organicconsumers.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EarthTalk®&lt;/strong&gt; is written and edited by Roddy Scheer and Doug Moss and is a registered trademark of &lt;strong&gt;E - The Environmental Magazine&lt;/strong&gt; ( &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.emagazine.com/&quot;&gt;www.emagazine.com&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;strong&gt;Send questions to:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:earthtalk@emagazine.com&quot;&gt;earthtalk@emagazine.com&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;Subscribe&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.emagazine.com/subscribe&quot;&gt;www.emagazine.com/subscribe&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;Free&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Trial Issue&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.emagazine.com/trial&quot;&gt;www.emagazine.com/trial&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 12:48:34 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>okket</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Dirt Poor: Have Fruits and Vegetables Become Less Nutritious?</og:title>
<og:description>Because of soil depletion, crops grown decades ago were much richer in vitamins and minerals than the varieties most of us get today</og:description>
<og:image>https://static.scientificamerican.com/sciam/cache/file/31DCBB9D-7896-4AED-8751B7614ED5C512_agenda.jpg?w=600&amp;h=335</og:image>
<og:url>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/soil-depletion-and-nutrition-loss/</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/soil-depletion-and-nutrition-loss/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Eight Years On, Google Fiber Is a Faint Echo of the Disruption Promised</title>
<link>https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/zmwkdx/eight-years-later-google-fiber-is-a-faint-echo-of-the-disruption-we-were-promised</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/zmwkdx/eight-years-later-google-fiber-is-a-faint-echo-of-the-disruption-we-were-promised</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;In 2010, Google stunned the telecom sector by announcing the company would be jumping into the broadband business. Under the brand banner of Google Fiber, the search giant proclaimed it would be lighting a much-needed fire under the traditionally uncompetitive broadband industry, delivering ultra-fast gigabit connections across the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initially, the gambit appeared to be paying dividends.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The nation’s media provided Google with an endless wave of free press as cities, frustrated by the high price and slow speeds of existing ISPs, &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2010/03/27/the-final-tally-more-than-1100-cities-apply-for-googles-fiber-network/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;tripped over themselves&lt;/a&gt; vying for the company’s affection. The project also drove a much-needed national conversation about a lack of broadband competition in the market and the institutional dysfunction that perpetuates it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google Fiber would, we were told, once and for all free the country from the iron grip of regional monopolies like Comcast, delivering ultra-fast broadband at a more reasonable $70 per month price point across huge chunks of the nation. And in initial launch cities like Kansas City, that dream appeared to be quickly coming true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But that was then, and this is now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some eight years on and Google Fiber’s ambitions are just a pale echo of the disruptive potential originally proclaimed by the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;article__pull-quote&quot;&gt;By late 2016, Google executives clearly started becoming disenfranchised by the slow pace and high costs of digging up the nation’s streets and challenging politically-powerful incumbents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Google Fiber did make some impressive early headway in cities like Austin, the company ran into numerous deployment headaches. Fearing competition, incumbent ISPs like AT&amp;amp;T and Comcast began a concerted effort to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fiercetelecom.com/telecom/google-fiber-battles-at-t-comcast-for-utility-pole-access-silicon-valley&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;block the company’s access to essential utility poles&lt;/a&gt;, even going so far as to file lawsuits &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dslreports.com/shownews/ATT-Sues-Nashville-to-Try-and-Slow-Google-Fiber-137958&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;against cities like Nashville&lt;/a&gt; that tried to expedite the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even in launched markets, customer uptake wasn’t quite what executives were expecting. Estimates peg Google Fiber TV subscribers at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.multichannel.com/news/content/google-fiber-ended-2016-84232-pay-tv-subs-study/411758&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;fewer than 100,000&lt;/a&gt;, thanks in large part to the cord cutting mindset embraced by early adopters. Broadband subscriber tallies (estimated as at least 500,000) were notably better, but still off from early company projections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even without anti-competitive roadblocks, progress was slow. Digging up city streets and burying fiber was already a time-consuming and expensive process. And while Google has tried to accelerate these deployments via something called “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hXMe6WGa84I&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;microtrenching&lt;/a&gt;” (machines that bury fiber an inch below roadways), broadband deployment remains a rough business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a business made all the rougher by state and local regulators and lawmakers who’ve been in the pockets of entrenched providers like Comcast for the better part of a generation. In many states, incumbent ISPs like AT&amp;amp;T and Comcast quite literally write state telecom law, resulting in protectionist legislation that can often &lt;a href=&quot;https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/qkvn4x/the-21-laws-states-use-to-crush-broadband-competition&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;make competition impossible&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By late 2016, Google executives clearly started becoming disenfranchised by the slow pace and high costs of digging up the nation’s streets and challenging politically-powerful incumbents. Company executives announced that they’d be laying off a &lt;a href=&quot;http://money.cnn.com/2016/10/26/technology/google-fiber-cuts/index.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;notable number of employees&lt;/a&gt; and temporarily pausing any expansions into new territories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;In the cities where we've launched or are under construction, our work will continue,&quot; said Craig Barratt, then CEO of the Access division at Google that oversaw Google Fiber. He added that for additional cities that were in talks to receive Google Fiber, &quot;we're going to pause our operations and offices while we refine our approaches.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it wouldn’t take long for Barratt to also leave the company, as Google Fiber burned through two CEOs in less than a year’s time. Barrett was replaced by Greg McCray, former CEO of Aero Communications, who only lasted four months at the job. McCray in turn was recently replaced by former Time Warner Cable executive Dinnie Jain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google’s “pause” is driven largely by executive frustrations with fiber deployment costs and a fascination with the potential of next-generation wireless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company has been conducting trials in the 71-76 GHz and 81-86 GHz millimeter wave bands, and is also conducting a variety of different tests in the 3.5 GHz band, the 5.8 GHz band and the 24 GHz band. And while these technologies show promise, it’s going to take a while for Google to figure out the best combination of technologies to aid its deployment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;article__pull-quote&quot;&gt;Ideally, Google Fiber’s deployments will accelerate again once Google Fiber executives have a more solid grasp on what next-generation wireless broadband will look like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And while Google Fiber has focused on wireless as an alternative to deploying fiber, those efforts have faced stiff headwinds as well. In July of 2016 Google &lt;a href=&quot;https://webpass.net/blog/google-fiber-agrees-to-acquire-webpass&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;acquired Webpass&lt;/a&gt;, a wireless ISP focused largely on urban apartment building deployments. But there too Google Fiber’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2018/1/30/16952588/webpass-google-fiber-internet-leaving-boston&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;ambitions appear to be shrinking&lt;/a&gt; with the recent news the service would be leaving Boston.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since Google executives don’t appear to actually know what these evolved wireless efforts will look like yet, the company’s public relation apparatus has been left with little more than a rotating crop of non-answers, sowing further frustration among cities trying to get on the other side of the nation’s vast digital divide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users In the company’s initial launch market of Kansas City were frustrated to find their &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kansascity.com/news/business/technology/article139910513.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;scheduled installations cancelled&lt;/a&gt; after years of waiting. Other cities, like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dslreports.com/shownews/Portland-Should-Probably-be-Pissed-About-Google-Fiber-Pause-138214&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Portland&lt;/a&gt;, state that they were strung along for more than a year only to be left standing at the altar. Some rumored target markets like San Francisco have decided to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.latimes.com/business/hiltzik/la-fi-hiltzik-sf-municipal-broadband-20161120-story.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;move forward on their own&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking at the Morgan Stanley Technology Conference this week, Alphabet CFO Ruth Porat insisted that the company’s dedication to disrupting the broadband market remains intact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The one thing that has not changed is our view that there is a real need for quality service,” Porat told attendees. “We're still implementing and executing in the cities that we announced, but we've slowed the pace of rollout so that we could spend time on how do we really bring technology to bear in a more meaningful way,” she added.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;As we were looking at our rollouts going back to 2015, 2016, our view was that we had not done enough,&quot; Porat said. The CFO added that the company hadn’t yet achieved its &quot;10x moment,&quot; or a 10-fold improvement over existing broadband technology it felt was necessary to truly be disruptive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But again, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/the-switch/wp/2016/10/26/why-google-fiber-is-no-longer-rolling-out-to-new-cities/?utm_term=.b67510a13600&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;reports indicate&lt;/a&gt; Google Fiber’s price tag is as much a reason for Google Fiber’s pause as its lagging disruptive potential. Porat has been trying to bring &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2016-12-08/google-makes-so-much-money-it-never-had-to-worry-about-financial-discipline&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;some financial constraint&lt;/a&gt; to a company long known for throwing billions at radical moonshots. But when asked when Google Fiber might hit the “unpause” button, Porat wandered into murky, non-answer territory.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“When you ask about milestones, in our view, when we have something that is substantive enough of value to justify accelerating the roll-out again, that's how we're looking at it,” said the CFO.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be clear, Google Fiber has had a massive net positive impact on the telecom market. The service not only generated a necessary conversation about the lack of competition in broadband, but Google actively worked to &lt;a href=&quot;http://nextcenturycities.org/wp-content/uploads/googlefibercitychecklist2-24-14.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;provide cities with a template&lt;/a&gt; to not only help streamline private-sector deployment, but build their own networks if so inclined.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And in markets that Google Fiber has been deployed, it has resulted in a dramatic reduction in prices among regional incumbents. AT&amp;amp;T, for example, initially charged &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tennessean.com/story/money/2015/09/29/t-drops-fiber-prices-google-fiber-levels/73023434/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;as much as $150 per month&lt;/a&gt; for its own gigabit broadband service, a service it was forced to re-price to $70 in areas where it faces competition from Google Fiber or municipal broadband networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ideally, Google Fiber’s deployments will accelerate again once Google Fiber executives have a more solid grasp on what next-generation wireless broadband will look like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there remains a steady undercurrent of concern that company executives have simply grown bored with the high cost of building broadband networks no matter what those networks look like. As such it remains a very real possibility that Google offloads the project eventually, leaving us all once again lost in the angry embrace of monopolies like Comcast.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 07:41:29 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>olds</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Eight Years Later, Google Fiber Is A Faint Echo Of The Disruption We Were Promised</og:title>
<og:image>https://video-images.vice.com/articles/5a97ee74273ac500064b3898/lede/1519906901622-GettyImages-157081282.jpeg?crop=1xw:0.8923849814912744xh;center,center&amp;resize=1200:*</og:image>
<og:url>https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/zmwkdx/eight-years-later-google-fiber-is-a-faint-echo-of-the-disruption-we-were-promised</og:url>
<og:description>Google’s 'pause' is driven largely by executive frustrations with fiber deployment costs and a fascination with the potential of next-generation wireless.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/zmwkdx/eight-years-later-google-fiber-is-a-faint-echo-of-the-disruption-we-were-promised</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>A week-long programming retreat</title>
<link>https://www.facebook.com/permalink.php?story_fbid=2110408722526967&amp;id=100006735798590</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.facebook.com/permalink.php?story_fbid=2110408722526967&amp;id=100006735798590</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;After a several year gap, I finally took another week-long programming retreat, where I could work in hermit mode, away from the normal press of work. My wife has been generously offering it to me the last few years, but I’m generally bad at taking vacations from work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a change of pace from my current Oculus work, I wanted to write some from-scratch-in-C++ neural network implementations, and I wanted to do it with a strictly base OpenBSD system. Someone remarked that is a pretty random pairing, but it worked out ok.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite not having actually used it, I have always been fond of the idea of OpenBSD — a relatively minimal and opinionated system with a cohesive vision and an emphasis on quality and craftsmanship. Linux is a lot of things, but cohesive isn’t one of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not a Unix geek. I get around ok, but I am most comfortable developing in Visual Studio on Windows. I thought a week of full immersion work in the old school Unix style would be interesting, even if it meant working at a slower pace. It was sort of an adventure in retro computing — this was fvwm and vi. Not vim, actual BSD vi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end, I didn’t really explore the system all that much, with 95% of my time in just the basic vi / make / gdb operations. I appreciated the good man pages, as I tried to do everything within the self contained system, without resorting to internet searches. Seeing references to 30+ year old things like Tektronix terminals was amusing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was a little surprised that the C++ support wasn’t very good. G++ didn’t support C++11, and LLVM C++ didn’t play nicely with gdb. Gdb crashed on me a lot as well, I suspect due to C++ issues. I know you can get more recent versions through ports, but I stuck with using the base system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In hindsight, I should have just gone full retro and done everything in ANSI C. I do have plenty of days where, like many older programmers, I think “Maybe C++ isn’t as much of a net positive as we assume...”. There is still much that I like, but it isn’t a hardship for me to build small projects in plain C.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe next time I do this I will try to go full emacs, another major culture that I don’t have much exposure to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a decent overview understanding of most machine learning algorithms, and I have done some linear classifier and decision tree work, but for some reason I have avoided neural networks. On some level, I suspect that Deep Learning being so trendy tweaked a little bit of contrarian in me, and I still have a little bit of a reflexive bias against “throw everything at the NN and let it sort it out!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the spirit of my retro theme, I had printed out several of &lt;a class=&quot;profileLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/yann.lecun?fref=mentions&quot;&gt;Yann LeCun&lt;/a&gt;’s old papers and was considering doing everything completely off line, as if I was actually in a mountain cabin somewhere, but I wound up watching a lot of the Stanford CS231N lectures on YouTube, and found them really valuable. Watching lecture videos is something that I very rarely do — it is normally hard for me to feel the time is justified, but on retreat it was great!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t think I have anything particularly insightful to add about neural networks, but it was a very productive week for me, solidifying “book knowledge” into real experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used a common pattern for me: get first results with hacky code, then write a brand new and clean implementation with the lessons learned, so they both exist and can be cross checked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I initially got backprop wrong both times, comparison with numerical differentiation was critical! It is interesting that things still train even when various parts are pretty wrong — as long as the sign is right most of the time, progress is often made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was pretty happy with my multi-layer neural net code; it wound up in a form that I can just drop it into future efforts. Yes, for anything serious I should use an established library, but there are a lot of times when just having a single .cpp and .h file that you wrote ever line of is convenient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My conv net code just got to the hacky but working phase, I could have used another day or two to make a clean and flexible implementation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I found interesting was that when testing on MNIST with my initial NN before adding any convolutions, I was getting significantly better results than the non-convolutional NN reported for comparison in LeCun ‘98 — right around 2% error on the test set with a single 100 node hidden layer, versus 3% for both wider and deeper nets back then. I attribute this to the modern best practices —ReLU, Softmax, and better initialization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is one of the most fascinating things about NN work — it is all so simple, and the breakthrough advances are often things that can be expressed with just a few lines of code. It feels like there are some similarities with ray tracing in the graphics world, where you can implement a physically based light transport ray tracer quite quickly, and produce state of the art images if you have the data and enough runtime patience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got a much better gut-level understanding of overtraining / generalization / regularization by exploring a bunch of training parameters. On the last night before I had to head home, I froze the architecture and just played with hyperparameters. “Training!” Is definitely worse than “Compiling!” for staying focused.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I get to keep my eyes open for a work opportunity to use the new skills!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am dreading what my email and workspace are going to look like when I get into the office tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 04:30:09 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>bane</dc:creator>
<og:title>John Carmack</og:title>
<og:description>After a several year gap, I finally took another week-long programming retreat, where I could work in hermit mode, away from the normal press of work. My wife has been generously offering it to me...</og:description>
<og:image>https://scontent.fphx1-2.fna.fbcdn.net/v/t1.0-1/p200x200/10525819_1515727755328403_3791257847922948008_n.jpg?oh=1f83891b2f6d231a1963abb9a11593f4&amp;oe=5B452C59</og:image>
<og:url>https://www.facebook.com/permalink.php?story_fbid=2110408722526967&amp;id=100006735798590</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.facebook.com/permalink.php?story_fbid=2110408722526967&amp;id=100006735798590&amp;_fb_noscript=1</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Facebook’s tracking of non-users ruled illegal again in Europe</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2018/02/19/facebooks-tracking-of-non-users-ruled-illegal-again/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2018/02/19/facebooks-tracking-of-non-users-ruled-illegal-again/</guid>
<description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2016/11/6886783467_2357dd120e_o.jpg?w=738&quot; class=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;p id=&quot;speakable-summary&quot;&gt;Another blow for Facebook in Europe: Judges in Belgium have &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2015/11/11/facebook-faces-privacy-fines/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;once again&lt;/a&gt; ruled the company broke privacy laws by deploying technology such as cookies and social plug-ins to track internet users across the web.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Facebook uses data it collects in this way to &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2016/05/26/facebook-starts-selling-offsite-ads-targeting-non-users-too/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;sell targeted advertising&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The social media giant failed to make it sufficiently clear how people’s digital activity was being used, the court ruled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook faces fines of up to €100 million (~$124 million), at a rate of €250,000 per day, if it fails to comply with the court ruling to stop tracking Belgians’ web browsing habits. It must also destroy any illegally obtained data, the court said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook expressed disappointment at the judgement and said it will appeal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The cookies and pixels we use are industry standard technologies and enable hundreds of thousands of businesses to grow their businesses and reach customers across the EU,” said Facebook’s VP of public policy for EMEA, Richard Allan, in a statement. “We require any business that uses our technologies to provide clear notice to end-users, and we give people the right to opt-out of having data collected on sites and apps off Facebook being used for ads.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The privacy lawsuit dates back to 2015 when the Belgium privacy watchdog &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2015/06/15/facebook-faces-privacy-lawsuit-from-belgian-watchdog/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;brought a civil suit against Facebook&lt;/a&gt; for its near invisible tracking of non-users via social plug-ins and the like. This followed an investigation by the agency that culminated in a &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2015/02/23/facebook-ad-network/#.1sssm6k:PiE2&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;highly critical report&lt;/a&gt; touching on many areas of Facebook’s data handling practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same year, after failing to obtain adequate responses to its concerns, the Belgian Privacy Commission decided to take Facebook to court over one of them: How it deploys tracking cookies and social plug-ins on third-party websites to track the internet activity of users and non-users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following its usual playbook for European privacy challenges, Facebook first tried to argue the Belgian DPA had no jurisdiction over its European business, which is headquartered in Ireland. But local judges disagreed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Subsequently, Belgian courts have twice ruled that Facebook’s use of cookies violates European privacy laws. If Facebook keeps appealing, the case could end up going all the way to Europe’s supreme court, the CJEU.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The crux of the issue here is the pervasive background surveillance of internet activity for digital ad targeting purposes which is enabled by a vast network of embedded and at times entirely invisible tracking technologies — and, specifically in this lawsuit, whether Facebook and the network of partner companies feeding data into its ad targeting systems have obtained adequate consent from their users to be so surveilled when they’re not actually using Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;notranslate&quot;&gt;“Facebook collects information about us all when we surf the Internet,” explains the Belgian privacy watchdog, referring to findings from its earlier investigation of Facebook’s use of tracking technologies.&lt;/span&gt; “&lt;span class=&quot;notranslate&quot;&gt;To this end, Facebook uses various technologies, such as the famous ‘cookies’ or the ‘social plug-ins’ (for example, the ‘Like’ or ‘Share’ buttons) or the ‘pixels’ that are invisible to the naked eye.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;notranslate&quot;&gt;It uses them on its website but also and especially on the websites of third parties.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;notranslate&quot;&gt;Thus, the survey reveals that even if you have never entered the Facebook domain, Facebook is still able to follow your browsing behavior without you knowing it, let alone, without you wanting it, thanks to these invisible pixels that Facebook has placed on more than 10,000 other sites.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook claims its use of cookie tracking is transparent and argues the technology benefits Facebook users by letting it show them more relevant content. (Presumably, it would argue non-Facebook users “benefit” from being shown ads targeted at their interests.) “Over recent years we have worked hard to help people understand how we use cookies to keep Facebook secure and show them relevant content. We’ve built teams of people who focus on the protection of privacy — from engineers to designers — and tools that give people choice and control,” said Allan in his response statement to the court ruling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But given that some of these trackers are literally invisible, coupled with the at times dubious quality of “consents” being gathered — say, for example, if there’s only a pre-ticked opt-in at the bottom of a lengthy and opaque set of T&amp;amp;Cs that actively discourage the user from reading and understanding what data of theirs is being gathered and why — there are some serious questions over the sustainability of this type of “pervasive background surveillance” adtech in the face of successful legal challenges and growing consumer dislike of ads that stalk them around the internet (which has in turn fueled growth of ad-blocking technologies).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook will face a &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/maxschrems/status/964525133951062017&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;similar complaint&lt;/a&gt; in a lawsuit in Austria, filed by privacy campaigner and lawyer Max Schrems, for example. In &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/01/25/facebooks-least-favorite-austrian-can-now-press-privacy-suit-in-vienna/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;January&lt;/a&gt; Schrems prevailed against Facebook’s attempts to stall the lawsuit after Europe’s top court threw out the company’s claim that his campaigning activities cancelled out his individual consumer rights. (Though the CJEU’s decision did not allow Schrems to pursue a class action style lawsuit against Facebook &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2014/08/06/25000-like-facebook-class-action-suit/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;as he had originally hoped&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Europe also has a major update to its data protection laws coming in May, called the &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/01/20/wtf-is-gdpr/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;GDPR&lt;/a&gt;, which beefs up the enforcement of privacy rights by introducing a new system of penalties for data protection violations that can scale as high as 4 percent of a company’s global turnover.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Essentially, GDPR means that ignoring the European Union’s fundamental right to privacy — by relying on the fact that few consumers have historically bothered to take companies to court over legal violations they may not even realize are happening — is going to get a lot more risky in just a few months’ time. (On that front, Schrems has crowdfunded a &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://noyb.eu&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;not-for-profit&lt;/a&gt; to pursue strategic privacy litigation once GDPR is in place — so start stockpiling the popcorn.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s also worth noting that GDPR strengthens the EU’s consent requirements for processing personal data — so it’s certainly not going to be easier for Facebook to obtain consents for this type of background tracking under the new framework. (The still being formulated &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://ec.europa.eu/digital-single-market/en/proposal-eprivacy-regulation&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;ePrivacy Regulation&lt;/a&gt; is also relevant to cookie consent, and aims to streamline the rules across the EU.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And indeed, such tracking will necessarily become far more visible to web users, who may then be a lot less inclined to agree to being ad-stalked almost everywhere they go online primarily for Facebook’s financial benefit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rise of &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/01/23/duckduckgo-adds-tracker-blocking-to-help-curb-the-wider-surveillance-web/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;tools offering tracker blocking&lt;/a&gt; offers another route for irate consumers to thwart online mass surveillance by ad targeting giants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We are &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/01/29/facebook-starts-polishing-its-privacy-messaging-ahead-of-gdpr/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;preparing for the new General Data Protection Regulation&lt;/a&gt; with our lead regulator the Irish Data Protection Commissioner. We’ll comply with this new law, just as we’ve complied with existing data protection law in Europe,” added Facebook’s Allan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s still not fully clear how Facebook will comply with GDPR — though it’s announced a &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/01/24/facebook-to-roll-out-global-privacy-settings-hub-thanks-to-gdpr/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;new global privacy settings hub is coming&lt;/a&gt;. It’s also running a series of data protection workshops in Europe this year, aimed at small and medium businesses — presumably to try to ensure its advertisers don’t find themselves shut out of GDPR Compliance City and on the hook for major privacy legal liabilities themselves, come May 25.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course Facebook’s ad business not only relies on people’s web browsing habits to fuel its targeting systems, it relies on advertisers liberally pumping dollars in. Which is another reason consumer trust is so vital. Yet Facebook is facing myriad &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/02/12/unilever-warns-social-media-to-clean-up-toxic-content/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;challenges on that front&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/02/18/fake-news-is-an-existential-crisis-for-social-media/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;these days&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;notranslate&quot;&gt;In a statement on its &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.privacycommission.be/fr/news/victoire-de-la-commission-vie-privee-dans-la-procedure-facebook&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;, the Belgium Privacy Commission said it was pleased with the ruling.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;notranslate&quot;&gt;“We are of course very satisfied that the court has fully followed our position.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;notranslate&quot;&gt;For the moment, Facebook is conducting a major advertising campaign where it shares its attachment to privacy.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;notranslate&quot;&gt;We hope he will put this commitment into practice,” it said. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;small&gt;Featured Image: &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/tekkebln/6886783467/&quot;&gt;Tekke&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/&quot;&gt;Flickr&lt;/a&gt; UNDER A &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nd/2.0/&quot;&gt;CC BY-ND 2.0&lt;/a&gt; LICENSE&lt;/small&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 01:03:15 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>pdcerb</dc:creator>
<og:title>Facebook’s tracking of non-users ruled illegal again</og:title>
<og:description>Another blow for Facebook in Europe: Judges in Belgium have once again ruled the company broke privacy laws by deploying technology such as cookies and..</og:description>
<og:image>https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2016/11/6886783467_2357dd120e_o.jpg</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2018/02/19/facebooks-tracking-of-non-users-ruled-illegal-again/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2018/02/19/facebooks-tracking-of-non-users-ruled-illegal-again/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ask HN: Cookies vs. JWT vs. OAuth</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16517412</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16517412</guid>
<description>&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.55737704918033&quot;&gt;&lt;td bgcolor=&quot;#FF6600&quot;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;8.9358799454297&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table class=&quot;fatitem&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;6.2551159618008&quot;&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing&quot; id=&quot;16517412&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;right&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;title&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16517412&quot; class=&quot;storylink&quot;&gt;Ask HN: Cookies vs. JWT vs. OAuth&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.8&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;subtext&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;score&quot; id=&quot;score_16517412&quot;&gt;243 points&lt;/span&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/user?id=amend&quot; class=&quot;hnuser&quot;&gt;amend&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;age&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16517412&quot;&gt;1 day ago&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span id=&quot;unv_16517412&quot;/&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/hide?id=16517412&amp;amp;goto=item%3Fid%3D16517412&quot;&gt;hide&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://hn.algolia.com/?query=Ask%20HN%3A%20Cookies%20vs.%20JWT%20vs.%20OAuth&amp;amp;sort=byDate&amp;amp;dateRange=all&amp;amp;type=story&amp;amp;storyText=false&amp;amp;prefix&amp;amp;page=0&quot; class=&quot;hnpast&quot;&gt;past&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=Ask%20HN%3A%20Cookies%20vs.%20JWT%20vs.%20OAuth&quot;&gt;web&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/fave?id=16517412&amp;amp;auth=1ed947e5eddb8ebbad11d251fc0a32425ca01f02&quot;&gt;favorite&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16517412&quot;&gt;82 comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;15&quot;&gt;I’m using passport.js with a local strategy for authentication, and I’m using sessions/cookies for keeping state and keeping the user logged in.
&lt;p&gt;I’m not very knowledgeable in security (that’s why I’m asking here), but will using JWT (with the token stored in the cookie) to keep the user logged in instead of sessions/cookies make my application more secure when the passport middleware executes req.isAuthenticated? I thiiink somewhere in that call it checks cookies or jwt, depending on implementation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, I do not plan on opening the API to other sites, so OAuth is unnecessary. Is my understanding correct?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td&gt;

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.73972602739726&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ycombinator.com/apply/&quot;&gt;Applications are open for YC Summer 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;yclinks&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/newsguidelines.html&quot;&gt;Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/newsfaq.html&quot;&gt;FAQ&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:hn@ycombinator.com&quot;&gt;Support&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/HackerNews/API&quot;&gt;API&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/security.html&quot;&gt;Security&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/lists&quot;&gt;Lists&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/bookmarklet.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Bookmarklet&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ycombinator.com/legal/&quot;&gt;Legal&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ycombinator.com/apply/&quot;&gt;Apply to YC&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:hn@ycombinator.com&quot;&gt;Contact&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2018 23:16:47 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>amend</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16517412</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>How 4000 Physicists Gave a Vegas Casino Its Worst Week (2015)</title>
<link>http://physicsbuzz.physicscentral.com/2015/09/one-winning-move.html?m=1</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://physicsbuzz.physicscentral.com/2015/09/one-winning-move.html?m=1</guid>
<description>What happens when several thousand distinguished physicists, researchers, and students descend on the nation’s gambling capital for a conference? The answer is &quot;a bad week for the casino&quot;—but you'd never guess why.&lt;p&gt;The year was 1986, and the American Physical Society’s annual April meeting was slated to be held in San Diego. But when scheduling conflicts caused the hotel arrangements to fall through just a few months before, the conference's organizers were left scrambling to find an alternative destination that could accommodate the crowd—and ended up settling on Las Vegas's MGM grand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table align=&quot;center&quot; cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;tr-caption-container&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;

&lt;a href=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-jPdMucsJ9Kg/Wpm2Oss7dwI/AAAAAAAADHY/3kFj8FFZXJ8-9CyltgrOxUTjATxkCAh5ACLcBGAs/s1600/mgm-grand-las-vegasb.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;601&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1200&quot; height=&quot;140&quot; src=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-jPdMucsJ9Kg/Wpm2Oss7dwI/AAAAAAAADHY/3kFj8FFZXJ8-9CyltgrOxUTjATxkCAh5ACLcBGAs/s280/mgm-grand-las-vegasb.jpg&quot; width=&quot;280&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tr-caption&quot;&gt;Clocking in at 5,124 rooms, the Grand is the largest standalone hotel in the US—making it a convenient landing place for such a big and unexpectedly uprooted conference.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Image Credit:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.casinoarchives.com/casino/north-america/united-states/mgm-grand-hotel-casino-las-vegas/&quot;&gt;Casino Archives&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
It was an unmitigated disaster for the Grand. Financially, it was the worst week they’d ever had. After the conference was over, APS was politely asked never to return—not just by the MGM Grand, but &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.aps.org/publications/apsnews/199908/knowledge.cfm&quot;&gt;by the entire city of Las Vegas&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;p&gt;Everyone knows that it's a near-impossibility to beat a casino's odds on a large scale. Lucky individuals' wins are always subsidized by the unlucky masses, and everyone's luck runs out eventually. So what happened? Maybe you’ve seen &lt;em&gt;21&lt;/em&gt;, and you’re picturing teams of sleek geeks using elaborate signaling systems and network analysis to gain a statistical edge over the house in blackjack. That’s been done in real life, but it wasn’t what happened at this meeting.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I first heard this story (it's practically office folklore at APS), I immediately remembered a documentary I’d seen a while back, where some science-minded gamblers proved that a roulette wheel could reliably be beaten with a timer and a pocket computer...but guess again—they didn’t play roulette, either.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some physicists have a &lt;a href=&quot;http://discovermagazine.com/2010/nov/22-one-great-frontier-for-modern-physicists-poker&quot;&gt;knack for poker&lt;/a&gt;—the quick analytical thinking that lends itself to success in the classroom can translate well to a competitive card game: a Dutch theoretician took home a gold bracelet in the 2010 World Series of Poker. Did a group of the April '86 attendees somehow devise an optimized betting strategy, analyzing risks and payoffs, assigning weights, hedging their bets to come out in the black? Still no—or at least not &lt;em&gt;en masse&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Instead, it turns out that the physicists found the one move guaranteed to provide an edge when the odds are stacked against you: You just don’t play.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;See, usually when an organization announces that it's holding a big conference in a certain region, it triggers a bidding war among that area's hotels, and each tries to undersell the others and secure the group's contract to fill up as many rooms as possible. This goes double in a gambling destination like Las Vegas, where hotels have casinos built-in; the Grand doesn't just collect on room charges, it also gets a good portion of however much each guest was planning on taking to the tables. This is so central to the business model of casino hotels that they'll often give rates much lower than what a non-casino hotel could afford to offer, under the assumption that they'll recoup at the tables—it's the same reason you can often find free alcohol and startlingly nice food at all-you-can-eat casino buffets.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So were these physicists just too busy sharing their science, seeing presentations and posters, and catching up on homework to find time for the tables? That's one possibility. The fact that a significant portion of the attendees were broke graduate students probably didn't help matters. On top of that, all the attendees had to have known enough about probability and statistics to recognize the &quot;Monte Carlo* fallacy&quot; at work: When a roulette wheel comes up black ten times in a row, it doesn't make the ball any more or less likely to land in a red slot the next time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whatever the case may have been, the week of the '86 APS April meeting found the gaming floor almost completely empty, leaving the casino with its record-low take; in the (probably apocryphal) words of one casino waitress: &quot;They each brought one shirt and a ten-dollar bill, and changed neither.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;By staying at a gambling hotel but obstinately refusing to gamble, everyone who booked their reservation with the group effectively had their stay subsidized by guests who were lured in by the chances of a big win—which is probably why Las Vegas hotels never bid on APS conference contracts anymore. The MGM Grand learned a lesson the hard way that week: Physicists &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/pdf/1301.1656.pdf&quot;&gt;do not play dice&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;—Stephen Skolnick&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;*The &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Monte_Carlo_method&quot;&gt;Monte Carlo method&lt;/a&gt;&quot; a sort of &lt;a href=&quot;http://physicsbuzz.physicscentral.com/2016/09/mathematical-divination-finding-pi-with.html&quot;&gt;large-scale statistical guess-and-check technique&lt;/a&gt;, derives its name from the same casino that gave the Monte Carlo fallacy—better known as the Gambler's Fallacy—its name. Back in the early 1900s, a roulette wheel landed on black 26 times in a row, the odds of which are something like one in 67 million. With each successive spin, people bet larger and larger sums on the assumption that it HAD to come up red, some &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.com/future/story/20150127-why-we-gamble-like-monkeys&quot;&gt;losing millions in the process&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2018 21:22:54 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jchanimal</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://physicsbuzz.physicscentral.com/2015/09/one-winning-move.html</og:url>
<og:title>How 4,000 Physicists Gave a Vegas Casino its Worst Week Ever</og:title>
<og:description>What happens when several thousand distinguished physicists, researchers, and students descend on the nation’s gambling capital for a confer...</og:description>
<og:image>https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-jPdMucsJ9Kg/Wpm2Oss7dwI/AAAAAAAADHY/3kFj8FFZXJ8-9CyltgrOxUTjATxkCAh5ACLcBGAs/w1200-h630-p-k-no-nu/mgm-grand-las-vegasb.jpg</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://physicsbuzz.physicscentral.com/2015/09/one-winning-move.html?m=1</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>How Airlines don’t care about privacy: Case Study Emirates.com</title>
<link>https://medium.com/@konarkmodi/how-airlines-dont-care-about-your-privacy-case-study-emirates-com-6271b3b8474b</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://medium.com/@konarkmodi/how-airlines-dont-care-about-your-privacy-case-study-emirates-com-6271b3b8474b</guid>
<description>&lt;p name=&quot;2273&quot; id=&quot;2273&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;I asked my wife if it is alright if her Date of Birth is known to a stranger. Only if they send me a birthday gift, she joked. What about your passport number? She lowered the book she was reading. I now had her attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;9bf9&quot; id=&quot;9bf9&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Now imagine this, I said “You try to check-in for your flight online, and see the error message — This booking does not exist. You try again, this surely is a mistake. Nope, still the same error message. The call center person repeats the same words. This has to be a mistake! You check your email, and there it is — staring back at you — email confirmation of cancellation. But you are sure you didn’t do it.” Whodunnit?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;15bd&quot; id=&quot;15bd&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;This is not a far-fetched scenario from a Sci-fi book, &lt;a href=&quot;https://media.ccc.de/v/33c3-7964-where_in_the_world_is_carmen_sandiego&quot; data-href=&quot;https://media.ccc.de/v/33c3-7964-where_in_the_world_is_carmen_sandiego&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;this really happened&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;8129&quot; id=&quot;8129&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;An organisation with a primary Digital Product that lacks even the basic data security practices is living in a utopian world where people leave their safe open and never expect a burglar to walk in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;4c6c&quot; id=&quot;4c6c&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;In the wake of full disclosure, sometime last year while booking travel for my family, I stumbled across a few data-security practices that, as a Data Security advocate, made me extremely worried. When I voiced my concerns to Emirates team, this conversation took place -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*VvnWUPs8xnWRtH92MJ5MWA.png&quot; data-width=&quot;1636&quot; data-height=&quot;1338&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*VvnWUPs8xnWRtH92MJ5MWA.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*VvnWUPs8xnWRtH92MJ5MWA.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Conversation with Emirates support.
&lt;p name=&quot;1bc7&quot; id=&quot;1bc7&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;For a layman, when you book your flight through Emirates, Domestic or International, there are approximately &lt;a href=&quot;https://pastebin.com/cAcXx2A4&quot; data-href=&quot;https://pastebin.com/cAcXx2A4&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;300 data points&lt;/a&gt; related to your booking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;e3e4&quot; id=&quot;e3e4&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;The moment you click on manage preferences to select a seat or meal for your trip or to Check-in to your flight, your Booking ID and Last name is passed on to approximately 14 different third-party trackers like Crazy egg, Boxever, Coremetrics, Google, and Facebook among others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 name=&quot;480c&quot; id=&quot;480c&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--h3-strong&quot;&gt;Details&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;536a&quot; id=&quot;536a&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;After I completed the booking on Emirates, I received an e-mail confirmation titled: Booking Confirmation — Booking Number.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*5gapaUdxr5Ogud_lV57rag.png&quot; data-width=&quot;1904&quot; data-height=&quot;546&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*5gapaUdxr5Ogud_lV57rag.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*5gapaUdxr5Ogud_lV57rag.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Booking confirmation email.
&lt;p name=&quot;9012&quot; id=&quot;9012&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;The body of the email contained Manage booking. I proceeded to select seats and meal by clicking on the Manage Booking button and reached the Manage Preference page. This was pretty straightforward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*oDj2QwYBymb-Tkp-S15n-g.png&quot; data-width=&quot;1920&quot; data-height=&quot;934&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*oDj2QwYBymb-Tkp-S15n-g.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*oDj2QwYBymb-Tkp-S15n-g.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Manage booking link in email.
&lt;p name=&quot;ad8f&quot; id=&quot;ad8f&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;While as a user, I saw the normal behaviour of clicking a link and reaching the landing page “Manage Preferences”, in the background a redirection chain took place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*U1zBmKaj5N_WH_UvupDnSw.png&quot; data-width=&quot;2000&quot; data-height=&quot;1296&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*U1zBmKaj5N_WH_UvupDnSw.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*U1zBmKaj5N_WH_UvupDnSw.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Redirection chain before reaching the landing page.
&lt;p name=&quot;2241&quot; id=&quot;2241&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;While Manage Booking link was supposed to be exclusive to me (the user and the website), this link was also shared with numerous third party trackers implemented by Emirates on their webpages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*N3g3dxhCbRUySAwrxfmKwQ.png&quot; data-width=&quot;2526&quot; data-height=&quot;1292&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*N3g3dxhCbRUySAwrxfmKwQ.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*N3g3dxhCbRUySAwrxfmKwQ.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Manage booking page.
&lt;p name=&quot;413e&quot; id=&quot;413e&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;The cherry on the cake was the HTTP link that leads to the Manage Preferences page. The insecureness of HTTP has been &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@pallavimodi/http-https-what-is-the-difference-3a97fe2f7fd8&quot; data-href=&quot;https://medium.com/@pallavimodi/http-https-what-is-the-difference-3a97fe2f7fd8&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;talked&lt;/a&gt; about over and over again, especially when it comes to maintaining the authenticity of the content and protection against interlopers. But in short, HTTP links are a Data Privacy nightmare. So, not only was Emirates passing on user information to the self-implemented third party trackers, but also allowing network adversaries to have access to the supposedly “Private” page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*8veDB-SuKCUp-g4VP-TRPQ.png&quot; data-width=&quot;508&quot; data-height=&quot;206&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*8veDB-SuKCUp-g4VP-TRPQ.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://track.emirates.email/track/click/30705682/www.emirates.com?p=eMSwicCI6IntcInVcIjozM....%28REACTED%29&quot; data-href=&quot;http://track.emirates.email/track/click/30705682/www.emirates.com?p=eMSwicCI6IntcInVcIjozM....(REACTED)&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--figure-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://track.emirates.email/track/click/30705682/www.emirates.com?p=eMSwicCI6IntcInVcIjozM....(REDACTED)&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;h3 name=&quot;f6e8&quot; id=&quot;f6e8&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--h3-strong&quot;&gt;What kind of information can third-parties access?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;f4b2&quot; id=&quot;f4b2&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;Links mentioned in (1) and (2) are currently being sent to the third-parties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*eAcZHcGPBYKR3Kz6O0pQuA.png&quot; data-width=&quot;972&quot; data-height=&quot;904&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*eAcZHcGPBYKR3Kz6O0pQuA.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*eAcZHcGPBYKR3Kz6O0pQuA.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;5333&quot; id=&quot;5333&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;Following fields take home the URL, which gives access to booking details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*uvkZ_TReV2oEv-hFuJYx7g.png&quot; data-width=&quot;1340&quot; data-height=&quot;390&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*uvkZ_TReV2oEv-hFuJYx7g.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*uvkZ_TReV2oEv-hFuJYx7g.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Fields which take home the private url.
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*HUaZDtQs5qtsxf6717XnLA.png&quot; data-width=&quot;2360&quot; data-height=&quot;76&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*HUaZDtQs5qtsxf6717XnLA.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*HUaZDtQs5qtsxf6717XnLA.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Sending url in key `dr` used by Google Analytics.
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*TNMkB_F5yi__E8NSJB-KQQ.png&quot; data-width=&quot;1088&quot; data-height=&quot;414&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*TNMkB_F5yi__E8NSJB-KQQ.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*TNMkB_F5yi__E8NSJB-KQQ.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;f43f&quot; id=&quot;f43f&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;Anyone who has access to these links can not only read but also edit the information that I as a user can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;9e2b&quot; id=&quot;9e2b&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;For example, they can now -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;postList&quot;&gt;&lt;li name=&quot;8648&quot; id=&quot;8648&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Change or Cancel flight&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;ac81&quot; id=&quot;ac81&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;Change seat or meal preference&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;6882&quot; id=&quot;6882&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;Add more products to the booking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;a070&quot; id=&quot;a070&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;Change or add Passport Information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;2807&quot; id=&quot;2807&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;Change or add Frequent Flyer Information, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*af5YBD2-igictr1nPu4_6w.png&quot; data-width=&quot;2608&quot; data-height=&quot;682&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*af5YBD2-igictr1nPu4_6w.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*af5YBD2-igictr1nPu4_6w.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*F_OjiydsqTyzr0bdWpkQsQ.png&quot; data-width=&quot;1806&quot; data-height=&quot;206&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*F_OjiydsqTyzr0bdWpkQsQ.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*F_OjiydsqTyzr0bdWpkQsQ.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*7zbTd0qeVh8NEAo2Sh0u7g.png&quot; data-width=&quot;764&quot; data-height=&quot;656&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*7zbTd0qeVh8NEAo2Sh0u7g.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*7zbTd0qeVh8NEAo2Sh0u7g.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Modify booking.
&lt;p name=&quot;787b&quot; id=&quot;787b&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;Exhibit of editable personal information on this page:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;880a&quot; id=&quot;880a&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;a. Full Name:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*15PrVhhUg95_vWoTzlxLFw.png&quot; data-width=&quot;1600&quot; data-height=&quot;228&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*15PrVhhUg95_vWoTzlxLFw.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*15PrVhhUg95_vWoTzlxLFw.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Name.
&lt;p name=&quot;3e60&quot; id=&quot;3e60&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;b. Skywards number&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*B3ZPaOocl-GZyfP5p2Z04w.png&quot; data-width=&quot;1806&quot; data-height=&quot;206&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*B3ZPaOocl-GZyfP5p2Z04w.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*B3ZPaOocl-GZyfP5p2Z04w.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Skywards number
&lt;p name=&quot;1b9f&quot; id=&quot;1b9f&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;c. Email ID / Telephone number:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*OD7kJxXdg_kPsgZdtJ_CFw.png&quot; data-width=&quot;2352&quot; data-height=&quot;322&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*OD7kJxXdg_kPsgZdtJ_CFw.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*OD7kJxXdg_kPsgZdtJ_CFw.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Read / Change personal information
&lt;p name=&quot;e0d4&quot; id=&quot;e0d4&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;d. Amount Paid, fare breakup.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*rcA9wtKii1P1kOf_lXwLGQ.png&quot; data-width=&quot;2048&quot; data-height=&quot;570&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*rcA9wtKii1P1kOf_lXwLGQ.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*rcA9wtKii1P1kOf_lXwLGQ.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Amount paid, form of payment, fare break-up.
&lt;p name=&quot;329b&quot; id=&quot;329b&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;e. Passport details, Nationality, Date of birth, Gender&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*LUj3JhInFbgGK-zcdAHy9A.png&quot; data-width=&quot;2388&quot; data-height=&quot;1080&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*LUj3JhInFbgGK-zcdAHy9A.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*LUj3JhInFbgGK-zcdAHy9A.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Passport details, DOB, Expiry, Gender, Nationality.
&lt;p name=&quot;2207&quot; id=&quot;2207&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;Note:&lt;/em&gt; In October 2017, fields such as Passport Number, Email Id and Telephone number were shown to be masked on the User Interface but were not obfuscated in source code. The web app has been revamped since then and these fields are now obfuscated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*CjavxV9t-sBeT4qvRc1EBQ.png&quot; data-width=&quot;1094&quot; data-height=&quot;166&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*CjavxV9t-sBeT4qvRc1EBQ.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*CjavxV9t-sBeT4qvRc1EBQ.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Masked fields in plain text. (October 2017)
&lt;p name=&quot;a06a&quot; id=&quot;a06a&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;I decided to take a peek into the mobile app and see if the past catches up with the present, and lo and behold there it was in its full glory — Passport Number, Email ID and Telephone number in plain text. What was obfuscated on the web app was easy to access on the mobile app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*gKK6AHYn4mHASHVn6eLeoA.png&quot; data-width=&quot;671&quot; data-height=&quot;482&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*gKK6AHYn4mHASHVn6eLeoA.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Passport details in plain text on mobile API.
&lt;p name=&quot;e4f9&quot; id=&quot;e4f9&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;Now, what is wrong with this?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;d059&quot; id=&quot;d059&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;This issue is not only limited to Emirates, a lot of airlines like Lufthansa, KLM (last checked on October 2017) suffer from the same issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;f649&quot; id=&quot;f649&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Every website uses third party trackers for improving their product and provide better web-usage experience. Data leaks are often considered collateral-damage and sometimes not even considered at all while implementation of such trackers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;a6af&quot; id=&quot;a6af&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Most of these third-parties are present on a lot of other websites and use long term identifiers like cookies etc to track users across domains. Now because one of the websites, in this case Emirates, leaks private information, these companies now potentially can not only link the user’s activity across web, but also identify who the user is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;0dd0&quot; id=&quot;0dd0&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;The questions that need answering by Emirates (and others) are -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;postList&quot;&gt;&lt;li name=&quot;b5c3&quot; id=&quot;b5c3&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Why was my booking information passed on to these third parties without my explicit consent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;c91c&quot; id=&quot;c91c&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;Why do these third parties need to receive this information?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;dc78&quot; id=&quot;dc78&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;Is Emirates even aware that sensitive user information is being leaked to these third parties?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;d120&quot; id=&quot;d120&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;Who are these third parties?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;00f3&quot; id=&quot;00f3&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;What are they doing with user information?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h3 name=&quot;7923&quot; id=&quot;7923&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf-after--li&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--h3-strong&quot;&gt;Reporting it to Emirates&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;c770&quot; id=&quot;c770&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;In the wake of responsible behaviour, on discovering these serious security flaws that violate user-data privacy, I decided to flag them to Emirates through Twitter DM in October 2017. Please note that I could not find a dedicated channel for reporting security bugs on Emirates website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;e35b&quot; id=&quot;e35b&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;The Social Media Team immediately responded to my Twitter DM with a canned response but I was not ready to give up hope. I also wrote an email to the Product Manager highlighting the security flaws. I was met with a deafening silence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;4b0e&quot; id=&quot;4b0e&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;As of today (2018–03–03) lot of these issues still persists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;f124&quot; id=&quot;f124&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;This is a serious violation of privacy, there is no point during the whole booking process, where I agreed upon sharing any of this personal information with any of these websites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;713f&quot; id=&quot;713f&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.emirates.com/english/sitetools/privacy_policy.aspx&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.emirates.com/english/sitetools/privacy_policy.aspx&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;privacy policy&lt;/a&gt; of Emirates itself is not very clear. It does &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.emirates.com/english/sitetools/cookie-policy.aspx&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.emirates.com/english/sitetools/cookie-policy.aspx&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;mention some of the of these services&lt;/a&gt;, but not all or the what data being shared with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 name=&quot;5cc1&quot; id=&quot;5cc1&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h4 graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--h4-strong&quot;&gt;Can I not opt-out?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;bc5b&quot; id=&quot;bc5b&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h4&quot;&gt;Not an option. Unfortunately, I could not find a way to opt-out of this system provided by Emirates. I finally had to fall back on using privacy preserving browser extensions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 name=&quot;8b9b&quot; id=&quot;8b9b&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h4 graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--h4-strong&quot;&gt;Can this not be fixed by Emirates?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;e0b0&quot; id=&quot;e0b0&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h4&quot;&gt;As a Software Engineer who has worked for the some of the largest eCommerce companies, I understand the need to use third party services for optimising and enhancing not only the Digital Product but also how user interacts with the product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;7fc3&quot; id=&quot;7fc3&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;It is not the usage of third party services that is of concern here in this case but the implementation of these services. Emirates has the control of their website and what the website shares with third party services. It is this control that needs to be exercised to limit the leakage of User information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;930a&quot; id=&quot;930a&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;It is not a mammoth task, it is just a matter of commitment to preserving the basic right to privacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;db8a&quot; id=&quot;db8a&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;postList&quot;&gt;&lt;li name=&quot;b0db&quot; id=&quot;b0db&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Private pages should have &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTML/Element/meta&quot; data-href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTML/Element/meta&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--li-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;noindex meta tags&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;8d03&quot; id=&quot;8d03&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;Limit the presence of third-party services on private pages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;2991&quot; id=&quot;2991&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTTP/Headers/Referrer-Policy&quot; data-href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTTP/Headers/Referrer-Policy&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--li-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Referrer-Policy&lt;/a&gt; on pages with sensitive data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;0c0a&quot; id=&quot;0c0a&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;Implement CSP and SRI. Even with a huge footprint of third-party services &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTTP/CSP&quot; data-href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTTP/CSP&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--li-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;CSP&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/Security/Subresource_Integrity&quot; data-href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/Security/Subresource_Integrity&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--li-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;SRI&lt;/a&gt; are not enabled on Emirates.com&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;f685&quot; id=&quot;f685&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;User needs to be informed when sensitive information like passport, contact details etc. is updated, edited, or deleted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;4899&quot; id=&quot;4899&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;Domain for sending e-mails : track.emirates.email, should have a valid certificate. &lt;a href=&quot;https://track.emirates.email/&quot; data-href=&quot;https://track.emirates.email/&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--li-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://track.emirates.email/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2018 21:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>kkm</dc:creator>
<og:title>Airline websites don’t care about your privacy: a case study on Emirates.com</og:title>
<og:url>https://medium.freecodecamp.org/how-airlines-dont-care-about-your-privacy-case-study-emirates-com-6271b3b8474b</og:url>
<og:image>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*61m9JVlYvpvORj2IUlp-4w.jpeg</og:image>
<og:description>I asked my wife if it is alright if her Date of Birth is known to a stranger. Only if they send me a birthday gift, she joked. What about…</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://medium.freecodecamp.org/how-airlines-dont-care-about-your-privacy-case-study-emirates-com-6271b3b8474b?gi=1703de6df1aa</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>