<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>A week-long programming retreat</title>
<link>https://www.facebook.com/permalink.php?story_fbid=2110408722526967&amp;id=100006735798590</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.facebook.com/permalink.php?story_fbid=2110408722526967&amp;id=100006735798590</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;After a several year gap, I finally took another week-long programming retreat, where I could work in hermit mode, away from the normal press of work. My wife has been generously offering it to me the last few years, but I’m generally bad at taking vacations from work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a change of pace from my current Oculus work, I wanted to write some from-scratch-in-C++ neural network implementations, and I wanted to do it with a strictly base OpenBSD system. Someone remarked that is a pretty random pairing, but it worked out ok.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite not having actually used it, I have always been fond of the idea of OpenBSD — a relatively minimal and opinionated system with a cohesive vision and an emphasis on quality and craftsmanship. Linux is a lot of things, but cohesive isn’t one of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not a Unix geek. I get around ok, but I am most comfortable developing in Visual Studio on Windows. I thought a week of full immersion work in the old school Unix style would be interesting, even if it meant working at a slower pace. It was sort of an adventure in retro computing — this was fvwm and vi. Not vim, actual BSD vi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end, I didn’t really explore the system all that much, with 95% of my time in just the basic vi / make / gdb operations. I appreciated the good man pages, as I tried to do everything within the self contained system, without resorting to internet searches. Seeing references to 30+ year old things like Tektronix terminals was amusing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was a little surprised that the C++ support wasn’t very good. G++ didn’t support C++11, and LLVM C++ didn’t play nicely with gdb. Gdb crashed on me a lot as well, I suspect due to C++ issues. I know you can get more recent versions through ports, but I stuck with using the base system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In hindsight, I should have just gone full retro and done everything in ANSI C. I do have plenty of days where, like many older programmers, I think “Maybe C++ isn’t as much of a net positive as we assume...”. There is still much that I like, but it isn’t a hardship for me to build small projects in plain C.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe next time I do this I will try to go full emacs, another major culture that I don’t have much exposure to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a decent overview understanding of most machine learning algorithms, and I have done some linear classifier and decision tree work, but for some reason I have avoided neural networks. On some level, I suspect that Deep Learning being so trendy tweaked a little bit of contrarian in me, and I still have a little bit of a reflexive bias against “throw everything at the NN and let it sort it out!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the spirit of my retro theme, I had printed out several of &lt;a class=&quot;profileLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/yann.lecun?fref=mentions&quot;&gt;Yann LeCun&lt;/a&gt;’s old papers and was considering doing everything completely off line, as if I was actually in a mountain cabin somewhere, but I wound up watching a lot of the Stanford CS231N lectures on YouTube, and found them really valuable. Watching lecture videos is something that I very rarely do — it is normally hard for me to feel the time is justified, but on retreat it was great!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t think I have anything particularly insightful to add about neural networks, but it was a very productive week for me, solidifying “book knowledge” into real experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used a common pattern for me: get first results with hacky code, then write a brand new and clean implementation with the lessons learned, so they both exist and can be cross checked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I initially got backprop wrong both times, comparison with numerical differentiation was critical! It is interesting that things still train even when various parts are pretty wrong — as long as the sign is right most of the time, progress is often made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was pretty happy with my multi-layer neural net code; it wound up in a form that I can just drop it into future efforts. Yes, for anything serious I should use an established library, but there are a lot of times when just having a single .cpp and .h file that you wrote ever line of is convenient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My conv net code just got to the hacky but working phase, I could have used another day or two to make a clean and flexible implementation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I found interesting was that when testing on MNIST with my initial NN before adding any convolutions, I was getting significantly better results than the non-convolutional NN reported for comparison in LeCun ‘98 — right around 2% error on the test set with a single 100 node hidden layer, versus 3% for both wider and deeper nets back then. I attribute this to the modern best practices —ReLU, Softmax, and better initialization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is one of the most fascinating things about NN work — it is all so simple, and the breakthrough advances are often things that can be expressed with just a few lines of code. It feels like there are some similarities with ray tracing in the graphics world, where you can implement a physically based light transport ray tracer quite quickly, and produce state of the art images if you have the data and enough runtime patience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got a much better gut-level understanding of overtraining / generalization / regularization by exploring a bunch of training parameters. On the last night before I had to head home, I froze the architecture and just played with hyperparameters. “Training!” Is definitely worse than “Compiling!” for staying focused.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I get to keep my eyes open for a work opportunity to use the new skills!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am dreading what my email and workspace are going to look like when I get into the office tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 04:30:09 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>bane</dc:creator>
<og:title>John Carmack</og:title>
<og:description>After a several year gap, I finally took another week-long programming retreat, where I could work in hermit mode, away from the normal press of work. My wife has been generously offering it to me...</og:description>
<og:image>https://scontent.fphx1-2.fna.fbcdn.net/v/t1.0-1/p200x200/10525819_1515727755328403_3791257847922948008_n.jpg?oh=1f83891b2f6d231a1963abb9a11593f4&amp;oe=5B452C59</og:image>
<og:url>https://www.facebook.com/permalink.php?story_fbid=2110408722526967&amp;id=100006735798590</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.facebook.com/permalink.php?story_fbid=2110408722526967&amp;id=100006735798590&amp;_fb_noscript=1</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Facebook’s tracking of non-users ruled illegal again in Europe</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2018/02/19/facebooks-tracking-of-non-users-ruled-illegal-again/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2018/02/19/facebooks-tracking-of-non-users-ruled-illegal-again/</guid>
<description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2016/11/6886783467_2357dd120e_o.jpg?w=738&quot; class=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;p id=&quot;speakable-summary&quot;&gt;Another blow for Facebook in Europe: Judges in Belgium have &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2015/11/11/facebook-faces-privacy-fines/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;once again&lt;/a&gt; ruled the company broke privacy laws by deploying technology such as cookies and social plug-ins to track internet users across the web.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Facebook uses data it collects in this way to &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2016/05/26/facebook-starts-selling-offsite-ads-targeting-non-users-too/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;sell targeted advertising&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The social media giant failed to make it sufficiently clear how people’s digital activity was being used, the court ruled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook faces fines of up to €100 million (~$124 million), at a rate of €250,000 per day, if it fails to comply with the court ruling to stop tracking Belgians’ web browsing habits. It must also destroy any illegally obtained data, the court said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook expressed disappointment at the judgement and said it will appeal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The cookies and pixels we use are industry standard technologies and enable hundreds of thousands of businesses to grow their businesses and reach customers across the EU,” said Facebook’s VP of public policy for EMEA, Richard Allan, in a statement. “We require any business that uses our technologies to provide clear notice to end-users, and we give people the right to opt-out of having data collected on sites and apps off Facebook being used for ads.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The privacy lawsuit dates back to 2015 when the Belgium privacy watchdog &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2015/06/15/facebook-faces-privacy-lawsuit-from-belgian-watchdog/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;brought a civil suit against Facebook&lt;/a&gt; for its near invisible tracking of non-users via social plug-ins and the like. This followed an investigation by the agency that culminated in a &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2015/02/23/facebook-ad-network/#.1sssm6k:PiE2&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;highly critical report&lt;/a&gt; touching on many areas of Facebook’s data handling practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same year, after failing to obtain adequate responses to its concerns, the Belgian Privacy Commission decided to take Facebook to court over one of them: How it deploys tracking cookies and social plug-ins on third-party websites to track the internet activity of users and non-users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following its usual playbook for European privacy challenges, Facebook first tried to argue the Belgian DPA had no jurisdiction over its European business, which is headquartered in Ireland. But local judges disagreed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Subsequently, Belgian courts have twice ruled that Facebook’s use of cookies violates European privacy laws. If Facebook keeps appealing, the case could end up going all the way to Europe’s supreme court, the CJEU.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The crux of the issue here is the pervasive background surveillance of internet activity for digital ad targeting purposes which is enabled by a vast network of embedded and at times entirely invisible tracking technologies — and, specifically in this lawsuit, whether Facebook and the network of partner companies feeding data into its ad targeting systems have obtained adequate consent from their users to be so surveilled when they’re not actually using Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;notranslate&quot;&gt;“Facebook collects information about us all when we surf the Internet,” explains the Belgian privacy watchdog, referring to findings from its earlier investigation of Facebook’s use of tracking technologies.&lt;/span&gt; “&lt;span class=&quot;notranslate&quot;&gt;To this end, Facebook uses various technologies, such as the famous ‘cookies’ or the ‘social plug-ins’ (for example, the ‘Like’ or ‘Share’ buttons) or the ‘pixels’ that are invisible to the naked eye.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;notranslate&quot;&gt;It uses them on its website but also and especially on the websites of third parties.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;notranslate&quot;&gt;Thus, the survey reveals that even if you have never entered the Facebook domain, Facebook is still able to follow your browsing behavior without you knowing it, let alone, without you wanting it, thanks to these invisible pixels that Facebook has placed on more than 10,000 other sites.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook claims its use of cookie tracking is transparent and argues the technology benefits Facebook users by letting it show them more relevant content. (Presumably, it would argue non-Facebook users “benefit” from being shown ads targeted at their interests.) “Over recent years we have worked hard to help people understand how we use cookies to keep Facebook secure and show them relevant content. We’ve built teams of people who focus on the protection of privacy — from engineers to designers — and tools that give people choice and control,” said Allan in his response statement to the court ruling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But given that some of these trackers are literally invisible, coupled with the at times dubious quality of “consents” being gathered — say, for example, if there’s only a pre-ticked opt-in at the bottom of a lengthy and opaque set of T&amp;amp;Cs that actively discourage the user from reading and understanding what data of theirs is being gathered and why — there are some serious questions over the sustainability of this type of “pervasive background surveillance” adtech in the face of successful legal challenges and growing consumer dislike of ads that stalk them around the internet (which has in turn fueled growth of ad-blocking technologies).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook will face a &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/maxschrems/status/964525133951062017&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;similar complaint&lt;/a&gt; in a lawsuit in Austria, filed by privacy campaigner and lawyer Max Schrems, for example. In &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/01/25/facebooks-least-favorite-austrian-can-now-press-privacy-suit-in-vienna/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;January&lt;/a&gt; Schrems prevailed against Facebook’s attempts to stall the lawsuit after Europe’s top court threw out the company’s claim that his campaigning activities cancelled out his individual consumer rights. (Though the CJEU’s decision did not allow Schrems to pursue a class action style lawsuit against Facebook &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2014/08/06/25000-like-facebook-class-action-suit/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;as he had originally hoped&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Europe also has a major update to its data protection laws coming in May, called the &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/01/20/wtf-is-gdpr/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;GDPR&lt;/a&gt;, which beefs up the enforcement of privacy rights by introducing a new system of penalties for data protection violations that can scale as high as 4 percent of a company’s global turnover.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Essentially, GDPR means that ignoring the European Union’s fundamental right to privacy — by relying on the fact that few consumers have historically bothered to take companies to court over legal violations they may not even realize are happening — is going to get a lot more risky in just a few months’ time. (On that front, Schrems has crowdfunded a &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://noyb.eu&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;not-for-profit&lt;/a&gt; to pursue strategic privacy litigation once GDPR is in place — so start stockpiling the popcorn.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s also worth noting that GDPR strengthens the EU’s consent requirements for processing personal data — so it’s certainly not going to be easier for Facebook to obtain consents for this type of background tracking under the new framework. (The still being formulated &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://ec.europa.eu/digital-single-market/en/proposal-eprivacy-regulation&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;ePrivacy Regulation&lt;/a&gt; is also relevant to cookie consent, and aims to streamline the rules across the EU.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And indeed, such tracking will necessarily become far more visible to web users, who may then be a lot less inclined to agree to being ad-stalked almost everywhere they go online primarily for Facebook’s financial benefit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rise of &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/01/23/duckduckgo-adds-tracker-blocking-to-help-curb-the-wider-surveillance-web/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;tools offering tracker blocking&lt;/a&gt; offers another route for irate consumers to thwart online mass surveillance by ad targeting giants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We are &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/01/29/facebook-starts-polishing-its-privacy-messaging-ahead-of-gdpr/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;preparing for the new General Data Protection Regulation&lt;/a&gt; with our lead regulator the Irish Data Protection Commissioner. We’ll comply with this new law, just as we’ve complied with existing data protection law in Europe,” added Facebook’s Allan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s still not fully clear how Facebook will comply with GDPR — though it’s announced a &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/01/24/facebook-to-roll-out-global-privacy-settings-hub-thanks-to-gdpr/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;new global privacy settings hub is coming&lt;/a&gt;. It’s also running a series of data protection workshops in Europe this year, aimed at small and medium businesses — presumably to try to ensure its advertisers don’t find themselves shut out of GDPR Compliance City and on the hook for major privacy legal liabilities themselves, come May 25.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course Facebook’s ad business not only relies on people’s web browsing habits to fuel its targeting systems, it relies on advertisers liberally pumping dollars in. Which is another reason consumer trust is so vital. Yet Facebook is facing myriad &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/02/12/unilever-warns-social-media-to-clean-up-toxic-content/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;challenges on that front&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/02/18/fake-news-is-an-existential-crisis-for-social-media/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;these days&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;notranslate&quot;&gt;In a statement on its &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.privacycommission.be/fr/news/victoire-de-la-commission-vie-privee-dans-la-procedure-facebook&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;, the Belgium Privacy Commission said it was pleased with the ruling.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;notranslate&quot;&gt;“We are of course very satisfied that the court has fully followed our position.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;notranslate&quot;&gt;For the moment, Facebook is conducting a major advertising campaign where it shares its attachment to privacy.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;notranslate&quot;&gt;We hope he will put this commitment into practice,” it said. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;small&gt;Featured Image: &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/tekkebln/6886783467/&quot;&gt;Tekke&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/&quot;&gt;Flickr&lt;/a&gt; UNDER A &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nd/2.0/&quot;&gt;CC BY-ND 2.0&lt;/a&gt; LICENSE&lt;/small&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 01:03:15 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>pdcerb</dc:creator>
<og:title>Facebook’s tracking of non-users ruled illegal again</og:title>
<og:description>Another blow for Facebook in Europe: Judges in Belgium have once again ruled the company broke privacy laws by deploying technology such as cookies and..</og:description>
<og:image>https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2016/11/6886783467_2357dd120e_o.jpg</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2018/02/19/facebooks-tracking-of-non-users-ruled-illegal-again/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2018/02/19/facebooks-tracking-of-non-users-ruled-illegal-again/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ask HN: Cookies vs. JWT vs. OAuth</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16517412</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16517412</guid>
<description>&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.55737704918033&quot;&gt;&lt;td bgcolor=&quot;#FF6600&quot;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;8.8994565217391&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table class=&quot;fatitem&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;6.2296195652174&quot;&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing&quot; id=&quot;16517412&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;right&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;title&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16517412&quot; class=&quot;storylink&quot;&gt;Ask HN: Cookies vs. JWT vs. OAuth&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.76923076923077&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;subtext&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;score&quot; id=&quot;score_16517412&quot;&gt;230 points&lt;/span&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/user?id=amend&quot; class=&quot;hnuser&quot;&gt;amend&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;age&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16517412&quot;&gt;16 hours ago&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span id=&quot;unv_16517412&quot;/&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/hide?id=16517412&amp;amp;goto=item%3Fid%3D16517412&quot;&gt;hide&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://hn.algolia.com/?query=Ask%20HN%3A%20Cookies%20vs.%20JWT%20vs.%20OAuth&amp;amp;sort=byDate&amp;amp;dateRange=all&amp;amp;type=story&amp;amp;storyText=false&amp;amp;prefix&amp;amp;page=0&quot; class=&quot;hnpast&quot;&gt;past&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=Ask%20HN%3A%20Cookies%20vs.%20JWT%20vs.%20OAuth&quot;&gt;web&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/fave?id=16517412&amp;amp;auth=1ed947e5eddb8ebbad11d251fc0a32425ca01f02&quot;&gt;favorite&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16517412&quot;&gt;79 comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;15&quot;&gt;I’m using passport.js with a local strategy for authentication, and I’m using sessions/cookies for keeping state and keeping the user logged in.
&lt;p&gt;I’m not very knowledgeable in security (that’s why I’m asking here), but will using JWT (with the token stored in the cookie) to keep the user logged in instead of sessions/cookies make my application more secure when the passport middleware executes req.isAuthenticated? I thiiink somewhere in that call it checks cookies or jwt, depending on implementation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, I do not plan on opening the API to other sites, so OAuth is unnecessary. Is my understanding correct?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td&gt;

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.73972602739726&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ycombinator.com/apply/&quot;&gt;Applications are open for YC Summer 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;yclinks&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/newsguidelines.html&quot;&gt;Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/newsfaq.html&quot;&gt;FAQ&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:hn@ycombinator.com&quot;&gt;Support&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/HackerNews/API&quot;&gt;API&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/security.html&quot;&gt;Security&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/lists&quot;&gt;Lists&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/bookmarklet.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Bookmarklet&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ycombinator.com/legal/&quot;&gt;Legal&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ycombinator.com/apply/&quot;&gt;Apply to YC&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:hn@ycombinator.com&quot;&gt;Contact&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2018 23:16:47 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>amend</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16517412</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>How 4000 Physicists Gave a Vegas Casino Its Worst Week (2015)</title>
<link>http://physicsbuzz.physicscentral.com/2015/09/one-winning-move.html?m=1</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://physicsbuzz.physicscentral.com/2015/09/one-winning-move.html?m=1</guid>
<description>What happens when several thousand distinguished physicists, researchers, and students descend on the nation’s gambling capital for a conference? The answer is &quot;a bad week for the casino&quot;—but you'd never guess why.&lt;p&gt;The year was 1986, and the American Physical Society’s annual April meeting was slated to be held in San Diego. But when scheduling conflicts caused the hotel arrangements to fall through just a few months before, the conference's organizers were left scrambling to find an alternative destination that could accommodate the crowd—and ended up settling on Las Vegas's MGM grand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table align=&quot;center&quot; cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;tr-caption-container&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;

&lt;a href=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-jPdMucsJ9Kg/Wpm2Oss7dwI/AAAAAAAADHY/3kFj8FFZXJ8-9CyltgrOxUTjATxkCAh5ACLcBGAs/s1600/mgm-grand-las-vegasb.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;601&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1200&quot; height=&quot;140&quot; src=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-jPdMucsJ9Kg/Wpm2Oss7dwI/AAAAAAAADHY/3kFj8FFZXJ8-9CyltgrOxUTjATxkCAh5ACLcBGAs/s280/mgm-grand-las-vegasb.jpg&quot; width=&quot;280&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tr-caption&quot;&gt;Clocking in at 5,124 rooms, the Grand is the largest standalone hotel in the US—making it a convenient landing place for such a big and unexpectedly uprooted conference.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Image Credit:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.casinoarchives.com/casino/north-america/united-states/mgm-grand-hotel-casino-las-vegas/&quot;&gt;Casino Archives&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
It was an unmitigated disaster for the Grand. Financially, it was the worst week they’d ever had. After the conference was over, APS was politely asked never to return—not just by the MGM Grand, but &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.aps.org/publications/apsnews/199908/knowledge.cfm&quot;&gt;by the entire city of Las Vegas&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;p&gt;Everyone knows that it's a near-impossibility to beat a casino's odds on a large scale. Lucky individuals' wins are always subsidized by the unlucky masses, and everyone's luck runs out eventually. So what happened? Maybe you’ve seen &lt;em&gt;21&lt;/em&gt;, and you’re picturing teams of sleek geeks using elaborate signaling systems and network analysis to gain a statistical edge over the house in blackjack. That’s been done in real life, but it wasn’t what happened at this meeting.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I first heard this story (it's practically office folklore at APS), I immediately remembered a documentary I’d seen a while back, where some science-minded gamblers proved that a roulette wheel could reliably be beaten with a timer and a pocket computer...but guess again—they didn’t play roulette, either.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some physicists have a &lt;a href=&quot;http://discovermagazine.com/2010/nov/22-one-great-frontier-for-modern-physicists-poker&quot;&gt;knack for poker&lt;/a&gt;—the quick analytical thinking that lends itself to success in the classroom can translate well to a competitive card game: a Dutch theoretician took home a gold bracelet in the 2010 World Series of Poker. Did a group of the April '86 attendees somehow devise an optimized betting strategy, analyzing risks and payoffs, assigning weights, hedging their bets to come out in the black? Still no—or at least not &lt;em&gt;en masse&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Instead, it turns out that the physicists found the one move guaranteed to provide an edge when the odds are stacked against you: You just don’t play.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;See, usually when an organization announces that it's holding a big conference in a certain region, it triggers a bidding war among that area's hotels, and each tries to undersell the others and secure the group's contract to fill up as many rooms as possible. This goes double in a gambling destination like Las Vegas, where hotels have casinos built-in; the Grand doesn't just collect on room charges, it also gets a good portion of however much each guest was planning on taking to the tables. This is so central to the business model of casino hotels that they'll often give rates much lower than what a non-casino hotel could afford to offer, under the assumption that they'll recoup at the tables—it's the same reason you can often find free alcohol and startlingly nice food at all-you-can-eat casino buffets.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So were these physicists just too busy sharing their science, seeing presentations and posters, and catching up on homework to find time for the tables? That's one possibility. The fact that a significant portion of the attendees were broke graduate students probably didn't help matters. On top of that, all the attendees had to have known enough about probability and statistics to recognize the &quot;Monte Carlo* fallacy&quot; at work: When a roulette wheel comes up black ten times in a row, it doesn't make the ball any more or less likely to land in a red slot the next time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whatever the case may have been, the week of the '86 APS April meeting found the gaming floor almost completely empty, leaving the casino with its record-low take; in the (probably apocryphal) words of one casino waitress: &quot;They each brought one shirt and a ten-dollar bill, and changed neither.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;By staying at a gambling hotel but obstinately refusing to gamble, everyone who booked their reservation with the group effectively had their stay subsidized by guests who were lured in by the chances of a big win—which is probably why Las Vegas hotels never bid on APS conference contracts anymore. The MGM Grand learned a lesson the hard way that week: Physicists &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/pdf/1301.1656.pdf&quot;&gt;do not play dice&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;—Stephen Skolnick&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;*The &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Monte_Carlo_method&quot;&gt;Monte Carlo method&lt;/a&gt;&quot; a sort of &lt;a href=&quot;http://physicsbuzz.physicscentral.com/2016/09/mathematical-divination-finding-pi-with.html&quot;&gt;large-scale statistical guess-and-check technique&lt;/a&gt;, derives its name from the same casino that gave the Monte Carlo fallacy—better known as the Gambler's Fallacy—its name. Back in the early 1900s, a roulette wheel landed on black 26 times in a row, the odds of which are something like one in 67 million. With each successive spin, people bet larger and larger sums on the assumption that it HAD to come up red, some &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.com/future/story/20150127-why-we-gamble-like-monkeys&quot;&gt;losing millions in the process&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2018 21:22:54 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jchanimal</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://physicsbuzz.physicscentral.com/2015/09/one-winning-move.html</og:url>
<og:title>How 4,000 Physicists Gave a Vegas Casino its Worst Week Ever</og:title>
<og:description>What happens when several thousand distinguished physicists, researchers, and students descend on the nation’s gambling capital for a confer...</og:description>
<og:image>https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-jPdMucsJ9Kg/Wpm2Oss7dwI/AAAAAAAADHY/3kFj8FFZXJ8-9CyltgrOxUTjATxkCAh5ACLcBGAs/w1200-h630-p-k-no-nu/mgm-grand-las-vegasb.jpg</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://physicsbuzz.physicscentral.com/2015/09/one-winning-move.html?m=1</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>How Airlines don’t care about privacy: Case Study Emirates.com</title>
<link>https://medium.com/@konarkmodi/how-airlines-dont-care-about-your-privacy-case-study-emirates-com-6271b3b8474b</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://medium.com/@konarkmodi/how-airlines-dont-care-about-your-privacy-case-study-emirates-com-6271b3b8474b</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*61m9JVlYvpvORj2IUlp-4w.jpeg&quot; data-width=&quot;1280&quot; data-height=&quot;720&quot; data-is-featured=&quot;true&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*61m9JVlYvpvORj2IUlp-4w.jpeg&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*61m9JVlYvpvORj2IUlp-4w.jpeg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;2273&quot; id=&quot;2273&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;I asked my wife if it is alright if her Date of Birth is known to a stranger. Only if they send me a birthday gift, she joked. What about your passport number? She lowered the book she was reading. I now had her attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;9bf9&quot; id=&quot;9bf9&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Now imagine this, I said “You try to check-in for your flight online, and see the error message — This booking does not exist. You try again, this surely is a mistake. Nope, still the same error message. The call center person repeats the same words. This has to be a mistake! You check your email, and there it is — staring back at you — email confirmation of cancellation. But you are sure you didn’t do it.” Whodunnit?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;15bd&quot; id=&quot;15bd&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;This is not a far-fetched scenario from a Sci-fi book, &lt;a href=&quot;https://media.ccc.de/v/33c3-7964-where_in_the_world_is_carmen_sandiego&quot; data-href=&quot;https://media.ccc.de/v/33c3-7964-where_in_the_world_is_carmen_sandiego&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;this really happened&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;8129&quot; id=&quot;8129&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;An organisation with a primary Digital Product that lacks even the basic data security practices is living in a utopian world where people leave their safe open and never expect a burglar to walk in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;4c6c&quot; id=&quot;4c6c&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;In the wake of full disclosure, sometime last year while booking travel for my family, I stumbled across a few data-security practices that, as a Data Security advocate, made me extremely worried. When I voiced my concerns to Emirates team, this conversation took place -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*VvnWUPs8xnWRtH92MJ5MWA.png&quot; data-width=&quot;1636&quot; data-height=&quot;1338&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*VvnWUPs8xnWRtH92MJ5MWA.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*VvnWUPs8xnWRtH92MJ5MWA.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Conversation with Emirates support.
&lt;p name=&quot;1bc7&quot; id=&quot;1bc7&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;For a layman, when you book your flight through Emirates, Domestic or International, there are approximately &lt;a href=&quot;https://pastebin.com/cAcXx2A4&quot; data-href=&quot;https://pastebin.com/cAcXx2A4&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;300 data points&lt;/a&gt; related to your booking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;e3e4&quot; id=&quot;e3e4&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;The moment you click on manage preferences to select a seat or meal for your trip or to Check-in to your flight, your Booking ID and Last name is passed on to approximately 14 different third-party trackers like Crazy egg, Boxever, Coremetrics, Google, and Facebook among others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;480c&quot; id=&quot;480c&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;Details:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;536a&quot; id=&quot;536a&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;After I completed the booking on Emirates, I received an e-mail confirmation titled: Booking Confirmation — Booking Number.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*5gapaUdxr5Ogud_lV57rag.png&quot; data-width=&quot;1904&quot; data-height=&quot;546&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*5gapaUdxr5Ogud_lV57rag.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*5gapaUdxr5Ogud_lV57rag.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Booking confirmation email.
&lt;p name=&quot;9012&quot; id=&quot;9012&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;The body of the email contained Manage booking. I proceeded to select seats and meal by clicking on the Manage Booking button and reached the Manage Preference page. This was pretty straightforward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*oDj2QwYBymb-Tkp-S15n-g.png&quot; data-width=&quot;1920&quot; data-height=&quot;934&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*oDj2QwYBymb-Tkp-S15n-g.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*oDj2QwYBymb-Tkp-S15n-g.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Manage booking link in email.
&lt;p name=&quot;ad8f&quot; id=&quot;ad8f&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;While as a user, I saw the normal behaviour of clicking a link and reaching the landing page “Manage Preferences”, in the background a redirection chain took place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*U1zBmKaj5N_WH_UvupDnSw.png&quot; data-width=&quot;2000&quot; data-height=&quot;1296&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*U1zBmKaj5N_WH_UvupDnSw.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*U1zBmKaj5N_WH_UvupDnSw.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Redirection chain before reaching the landing page.
&lt;p name=&quot;2241&quot; id=&quot;2241&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;While Manage Booking link was supposed to be exclusive to me (the user and the website), this link was also shared with numerous third party trackers implemented by Emirates on their webpages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*N3g3dxhCbRUySAwrxfmKwQ.png&quot; data-width=&quot;2526&quot; data-height=&quot;1292&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*N3g3dxhCbRUySAwrxfmKwQ.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*N3g3dxhCbRUySAwrxfmKwQ.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Manage booking page.
&lt;p name=&quot;413e&quot; id=&quot;413e&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;The cherry on the cake was the HTTP link that leads to the Manage Preferences page. The insecureness of HTTP has been &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@pallavimodi/http-https-what-is-the-difference-3a97fe2f7fd8&quot; data-href=&quot;https://medium.com/@pallavimodi/http-https-what-is-the-difference-3a97fe2f7fd8&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;talked&lt;/a&gt; about over and over again, especially when it comes to maintaining the authenticity of the content and protection against interlopers. But in short, HTTP links are a Data Privacy nightmare. So, not only was Emirates passing on user information to the self-implemented third party trackers, but also allowing network adversaries to have access to the supposedly “Private” page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*8veDB-SuKCUp-g4VP-TRPQ.png&quot; data-width=&quot;508&quot; data-height=&quot;206&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*8veDB-SuKCUp-g4VP-TRPQ.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://track.emirates.email/track/click/30705682/www.emirates.com?p=eMSwicCI6IntcInVcIjozM....%28REACTED%29&quot; data-href=&quot;http://track.emirates.email/track/click/30705682/www.emirates.com?p=eMSwicCI6IntcInVcIjozM....(REACTED)&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--figure-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://track.emirates.email/track/click/30705682/www.emirates.com?p=eMSwicCI6IntcInVcIjozM....(REDACTED)&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;f6e8&quot; id=&quot;f6e8&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;What kind of information can third-parties access?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;f4b2&quot; id=&quot;f4b2&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Links mentioned in (1) and (2) are currently being sent to the third-parties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*eAcZHcGPBYKR3Kz6O0pQuA.png&quot; data-width=&quot;972&quot; data-height=&quot;904&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*eAcZHcGPBYKR3Kz6O0pQuA.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*eAcZHcGPBYKR3Kz6O0pQuA.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;5333&quot; id=&quot;5333&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;Following fields take home the URL, which gives access to booking details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*uvkZ_TReV2oEv-hFuJYx7g.png&quot; data-width=&quot;1340&quot; data-height=&quot;390&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*uvkZ_TReV2oEv-hFuJYx7g.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*uvkZ_TReV2oEv-hFuJYx7g.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Fields which take home the private url.
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*HUaZDtQs5qtsxf6717XnLA.png&quot; data-width=&quot;2360&quot; data-height=&quot;76&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*HUaZDtQs5qtsxf6717XnLA.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*HUaZDtQs5qtsxf6717XnLA.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Sending url in key `dr` used by Google Analytics.
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*TNMkB_F5yi__E8NSJB-KQQ.png&quot; data-width=&quot;1088&quot; data-height=&quot;414&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*TNMkB_F5yi__E8NSJB-KQQ.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*TNMkB_F5yi__E8NSJB-KQQ.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;f43f&quot; id=&quot;f43f&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;Anyone who has access to these links can not only read but also edit the information that I as a user can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;9e2b&quot; id=&quot;9e2b&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;For example, they can now -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;postList&quot;&gt;&lt;li name=&quot;8648&quot; id=&quot;8648&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Change or Cancel flight&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;ac81&quot; id=&quot;ac81&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;Change seat or meal preference&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;6882&quot; id=&quot;6882&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;Add more products to the booking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;a070&quot; id=&quot;a070&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;Change or add Passport Information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;2807&quot; id=&quot;2807&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;Change or add Frequent Flyer Information, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*af5YBD2-igictr1nPu4_6w.png&quot; data-width=&quot;2608&quot; data-height=&quot;682&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*af5YBD2-igictr1nPu4_6w.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*af5YBD2-igictr1nPu4_6w.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*F_OjiydsqTyzr0bdWpkQsQ.png&quot; data-width=&quot;1806&quot; data-height=&quot;206&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*F_OjiydsqTyzr0bdWpkQsQ.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*F_OjiydsqTyzr0bdWpkQsQ.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*7zbTd0qeVh8NEAo2Sh0u7g.png&quot; data-width=&quot;764&quot; data-height=&quot;656&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*7zbTd0qeVh8NEAo2Sh0u7g.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*7zbTd0qeVh8NEAo2Sh0u7g.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Modify booking.
&lt;p name=&quot;787b&quot; id=&quot;787b&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;Exhibit of editable personal information on this page:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;880a&quot; id=&quot;880a&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;a. Full Name:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*15PrVhhUg95_vWoTzlxLFw.png&quot; data-width=&quot;1600&quot; data-height=&quot;228&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*15PrVhhUg95_vWoTzlxLFw.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*15PrVhhUg95_vWoTzlxLFw.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Name.
&lt;p name=&quot;3e60&quot; id=&quot;3e60&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;b. Skywards number&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*B3ZPaOocl-GZyfP5p2Z04w.png&quot; data-width=&quot;1806&quot; data-height=&quot;206&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*B3ZPaOocl-GZyfP5p2Z04w.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*B3ZPaOocl-GZyfP5p2Z04w.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Skywards number
&lt;p name=&quot;1b9f&quot; id=&quot;1b9f&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;c. Email ID / Telephone number:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*OD7kJxXdg_kPsgZdtJ_CFw.png&quot; data-width=&quot;2352&quot; data-height=&quot;322&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*OD7kJxXdg_kPsgZdtJ_CFw.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*OD7kJxXdg_kPsgZdtJ_CFw.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Read / Change personal information
&lt;p name=&quot;e0d4&quot; id=&quot;e0d4&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;d. Amount Paid, fare breakup.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*rcA9wtKii1P1kOf_lXwLGQ.png&quot; data-width=&quot;2048&quot; data-height=&quot;570&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*rcA9wtKii1P1kOf_lXwLGQ.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*rcA9wtKii1P1kOf_lXwLGQ.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Amount paid, form of payment, fare break-up.
&lt;p name=&quot;329b&quot; id=&quot;329b&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;e. Passport details, Nationality, Date of birth, Gender&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*LUj3JhInFbgGK-zcdAHy9A.png&quot; data-width=&quot;2388&quot; data-height=&quot;1080&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*LUj3JhInFbgGK-zcdAHy9A.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*LUj3JhInFbgGK-zcdAHy9A.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Passport details, DOB, Expiry, Gender, Nationality.
&lt;p name=&quot;2207&quot; id=&quot;2207&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;Note:&lt;/em&gt; In October 2017, fields such as Passport Number, Email Id and Telephone number were shown to be masked on the User Interface but were not obfuscated in source code. The web app has been revamped since then and these fields are now obfuscated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*CjavxV9t-sBeT4qvRc1EBQ.png&quot; data-width=&quot;1094&quot; data-height=&quot;166&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*CjavxV9t-sBeT4qvRc1EBQ.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*CjavxV9t-sBeT4qvRc1EBQ.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Masked fields in plain text. (October 2017)
&lt;p name=&quot;a06a&quot; id=&quot;a06a&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;I decided to take a peek into the mobile app and see if the past catches up with the present, and lo and behold there it was in its full glory — Passport Number, Email ID and Telephone number in plain text. What was obfuscated on the web app was easy to access on the mobile app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*gKK6AHYn4mHASHVn6eLeoA.png&quot; data-width=&quot;671&quot; data-height=&quot;482&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*gKK6AHYn4mHASHVn6eLeoA.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Passport details in plain text on mobile API.
&lt;p name=&quot;e4f9&quot; id=&quot;e4f9&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;Now, what is wrong with this?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;d059&quot; id=&quot;d059&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;This issue is not only limited to Emirates, a lot of airlines like Lufthansa, KLM (last checked on October 2017) suffer from the same issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;f649&quot; id=&quot;f649&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Every website uses third party trackers for improving their product and provide better web-usage experience. Data leaks are often considered collateral-damage and sometimes not even considered at all while implementation of such trackers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;a6af&quot; id=&quot;a6af&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Most of these third-parties are present on a lot of other websites and use long term identifiers like cookies etc to track users across domains. Now because one of the websites, in this case Emirates, leaks private information, these companies now potentially can not only link the user’s activity across web, but also identify who the user is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;0dd0&quot; id=&quot;0dd0&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;The questions that need answering by Emirates (and others) are -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;postList&quot;&gt;&lt;li name=&quot;b5c3&quot; id=&quot;b5c3&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Why was my booking information passed on to these third parties without my explicit consent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;c91c&quot; id=&quot;c91c&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;Why do these third parties need to receive this information?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;dc78&quot; id=&quot;dc78&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;Is Emirates even aware that sensitive user information is being leaked to these third parties?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;d120&quot; id=&quot;d120&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;Who are these third parties?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;00f3&quot; id=&quot;00f3&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;What are they doing with user information?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p name=&quot;7923&quot; id=&quot;7923&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--li&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;Reporting it to Emirates:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;c770&quot; id=&quot;c770&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;In the wake of responsible behaviour, on discovering these serious security flaws that violate user-data privacy, I decided to flag them to Emirates through Twitter DM in October 2017. Please note that I could not find a dedicated channel for reporting security bugs on Emirates website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;e35b&quot; id=&quot;e35b&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;The Social Media Team immediately responded to my Twitter DM with a canned response but I was not ready to give up hope. I also wrote an email to the Product Manager highlighting the security flaws. I was met with a deafening silence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;4b0e&quot; id=&quot;4b0e&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;As of today (2018–03–03) lot of these issues still persists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;f124&quot; id=&quot;f124&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;This is a serious violation of privacy, there is no point during the whole booking process, where I agreed upon sharing any of this personal information with any of these websites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;713f&quot; id=&quot;713f&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.emirates.com/english/sitetools/privacy_policy.aspx&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.emirates.com/english/sitetools/privacy_policy.aspx&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;privacy policy&lt;/a&gt; of Emirates itself is not very clear. It does &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.emirates.com/english/sitetools/cookie-policy.aspx&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.emirates.com/english/sitetools/cookie-policy.aspx&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;mention some of the of these services&lt;/a&gt;, but not all or the what data being shared with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;5cc1&quot; id=&quot;5cc1&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;Can I not opt-out?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;bc5b&quot; id=&quot;bc5b&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Not an option. Unfortunately, I could not find a way to opt-out of this system provided by Emirates. I finally had to fall back on using privacy preserving browser extensions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;8b9b&quot; id=&quot;8b9b&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;Can this not be fixed by Emirates?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;e0b0&quot; id=&quot;e0b0&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;As a Software Engineer who has worked for the some of the largest eCommerce companies, I understand the need to use third party services for optimising and enhancing not only the Digital Product but also how user interacts with the product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;7fc3&quot; id=&quot;7fc3&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;It is not the usage of third party services that is of concern here in this case but the implementation of these services. Emirates has the control of their website and what the website shares with third party services. It is this control that needs to be exercised to limit the leakage of User information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;930a&quot; id=&quot;930a&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;It is not a mammoth task, it is just a matter of commitment to preserving the basic right to privacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;db8a&quot; id=&quot;db8a&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;postList&quot;&gt;&lt;li name=&quot;b0db&quot; id=&quot;b0db&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Private pages should have &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTML/Element/meta&quot; data-href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTML/Element/meta&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--li-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;noindex meta tags&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;8d03&quot; id=&quot;8d03&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;Limit the presence of third-party services on private pages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;2991&quot; id=&quot;2991&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTTP/Headers/Referrer-Policy&quot; data-href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTTP/Headers/Referrer-Policy&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--li-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Referrer-Policy&lt;/a&gt; on pages with sensitive data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;0c0a&quot; id=&quot;0c0a&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;Implement CSP and SRI. Even with a huge footprint of third-party services &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTTP/CSP&quot; data-href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTTP/CSP&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--li-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;CSP&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/Security/Subresource_Integrity&quot; data-href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/Security/Subresource_Integrity&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--li-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;SRI&lt;/a&gt; are not enabled on Emirates.com&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;f685&quot; id=&quot;f685&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;User needs to be informed when sensitive information like passport, contact details etc. is updated, edited, or deleted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;4899&quot; id=&quot;4899&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;Domain for sending e-mails : track.emirates.email, should have a valid certificate. &lt;a href=&quot;https://track.emirates.email/&quot; data-href=&quot;https://track.emirates.email/&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--li-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://track.emirates.email/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*rKlBksjOrOqggqh6pGJhxA.png&quot; data-width=&quot;2466&quot; data-height=&quot;1554&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*rKlBksjOrOqggqh6pGJhxA.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*rKlBksjOrOqggqh6pGJhxA.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;0ec1&quot; id=&quot;0ec1&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;If you are interested in reading more about the presence of trackers on your favourite websites, I highly recommend checking out &lt;a href=&quot;https://whotracks.me/&quot; data-href=&quot;https://whotracks.me/&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;WhoTracksMe&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;be08&quot; id=&quot;be08&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Happy Hacking !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;7ccc&quot; id=&quot;7ccc&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/konarkmodi&quot; data-href=&quot;https://twitter.com/konarkmodi&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Konark Modi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;d8b0&quot; id=&quot;d8b0&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Thanks for reading and sharing ! :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;93e2&quot; id=&quot;93e2&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;If you liked this story, feel free to 👏👏👏 a few times (Up to 50 times. Seriously).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;cd20&quot; id=&quot;cd20&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p graf--trailing&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;Credits: Special thanks to Aldo,&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Pythux&quot; data-href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Pythux&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;Remi&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt; ,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Pi_Modi&quot; data-href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Pi_Modi&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;Pallavi&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;for reviewing the post.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2018 21:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>kkm</dc:creator>
<og:title>How Airlines don’t care about your privacy: Case Study Emirates.com</og:title>
<og:url>https://medium.com/@konarkmodi/how-airlines-dont-care-about-your-privacy-case-study-emirates-com-6271b3b8474b</og:url>
<og:image>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*61m9JVlYvpvORj2IUlp-4w.jpeg</og:image>
<og:description>I asked my wife if it is alright if her Date of Birth is known to a stranger. Only if they send me a birthday gift, she joked. What about…</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://medium.com/@konarkmodi/how-airlines-dont-care-about-your-privacy-case-study-emirates-com-6271b3b8474b</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Make Medium Readable Again</title>
<link>https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/make-medium-readable-agai/kljjfejkagofbgklifblndjelgabcmig</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/make-medium-readable-agai/kljjfejkagofbgklifblndjelgabcmig</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Neutralizes annoying parts of the Medium reading experience so it's more enjoyable to read things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;C-b-p-j-Oa&quot;&gt;
Medium is pretty annoying to read when you're not logged in. This extension quietly fixes that on any Medium publication you visit.

It makes your reading experience more bearable by:

* Keeping the top navigation bar from sticking around
* Hiding the bottom &quot;Get Updates&quot; bar completely
* Shrinking massive header images
* (Optionally) hiding the clap / share bar
* (Optionally) loading all post images up front, instead of lazy loading as you scroll

This extension is open source software! Want to contribute? Feel free: https://github.com/thebaer/MMRA

UPDATES

v1.3

* Automatically shrink massive header images

v1.2

* Fix extension not applying after navigating to a post from a publication
* Add option to disable loading dynamic / lazy image loading
&lt;/pre&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2018 19:30:22 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>thangngoc89</dc:creator>
<og:title>Make Medium Readable Again</og:title>
<og:description>Neutralizes annoying parts of the Medium reading experience so it's more enjoyable to read things.</og:description>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/make-medium-readable-agai/kljjfejkagofbgklifblndjelgabcmig</og:url>
<og:image>https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/EPTu4qEAngAO8hdfmJ4nN1wBoe0TUTmN6VJt7uGoczzN0P4n1GhMp4tVrJO2woZXhMyDo6jMhQ=w128-h128-e365</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/make-medium-readable-agai/kljjfejkagofbgklifblndjelgabcmig</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The British amateur who debunked the mathematics of happiness (2014)</title>
<link>https://www.theguardian.com/science/2014/jan/19/mathematics-of-happiness-debunked-nick-brown</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.theguardian.com/science/2014/jan/19/mathematics-of-happiness-debunked-nick-brown</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;drop-cap&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;drop-cap__inner&quot;&gt;N&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;ick Brown does not look like your average student. He's 53 for a start and at 6ft 4in with a bushy moustache and an expression that jackknifes between sceptical and alarmed, he is reminiscent of a mid-period John Cleese. He can even sound a bit like the great comedian when he embarks on an extended sardonic riff, which he is prone to do if the subject rouses his intellectual suspicion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A couple of years ago that suspicion began to grow while he sat in a lecture at the University of East London, where he was taking a postgraduate course in applied positive psychology. There was a slide showing a butterfly graph – the branch of mathematical modelling most often associated with chaos theory. On the graph was a tipping point that claimed to identify the precise emotional co-ordinates that divide those people who &quot;flourish&quot; from those who &quot;languish&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the graph, it all came down to a specific ratio of positive emotions to negative emotions. If your ratio was greater than 2.9013 positive emotions to 1 negative emotion you were flourishing in life. If your ratio was less than that number you were languishing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was as simple as that. The mysteries of love, happiness, fulfilment, success, disappointment, heartache, failure, experience, random luck, environment, culture, gender, genes, and all the other myriad ingredients that make up a human life could be reduced to the figure of 2.9013.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seemed incredible to Brown, as though it had been made up. But the number was no invention. Instead it was the product of research that had been published, after peer review, in no less authoritative a journal than &lt;em&gt;American Psychologist&lt;/em&gt; – the pre-eminent publication in the world of psychology that is delivered to every member of the American Psychological Association. Co-authored by Barbara Fredrickson and Marcial Losada and entitled &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.unc.edu/peplab/publications/Fredrickson%20&amp;amp;%20Losada%202005.pdf&quot; title=&quot;&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Positive Affect and the Complex Dynamics of Human Flourishing&lt;/a&gt;, the paper was subsequently cited more than 350 times in other academic journals. And aside from one partially critical paper, no one had seriously questioned its validity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;u-responsive-ratio&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;gu-image&quot; itemprop=&quot;contentUrl&quot; alt=&quot;Masters student Nick Brown&quot; src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/static/sys-images/Admin/BkFill/Default_image_group/2014/1/15/1389799662251/Masters-student-Nick-Brow-001.jpg?w=300&amp;amp;q=55&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;usm=12&amp;amp;fit=max&amp;amp;s=ae350690374b9e065dc4c604340c57cb&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Masters student Nick Brown: 'If you want to be a whistleblower you have to be prepared to lose your job. I’m able to do what I’m doing here because I’m nobody.'
&lt;p&gt;Fredrickson is a distinguished psychologist, a professor at the University of North Carolina, a winner of several notable psychology awards and bestselling author of a number of psychology books, including &lt;em&gt;Positivity&lt;/em&gt;, which took her and Losada's academic research and recast it for a mass audience – the subtitle ran &quot;Top-Notch Research Reveals the 3-to-1 Ratio That Will Change Your Life&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Just as zero degrees celsius is a special number in thermodynamics,&quot; wrote Fredrickson in &lt;em&gt;Positivity&lt;/em&gt;, &quot;the 3-to-1 positivity ratio may well be a magic number in human psychology.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fredrickson is the object of widespread admiration in the field of psychology. Martin Seligman, former president of the American Psychological Association and a bestselling author in his own right, went so far as to call her &quot;the genius of the positive psychology movement&quot;. On top of which she is also an associate editor at &lt;em&gt;American Psychologist&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By contrast, Brown was a first-term, first-year, part-time masters student who was about to take early retirement from what he calls a &quot;large international organisation&quot; in Strasbourg, where he had been head of IT network operations. Who was he to doubt the work of a leading professional which had been accepted by the psychological elite? What gave him the right to suggest that the emperor had gone naturist?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;The answer,&quot; says Brown when I meet him in a north London cafe, &quot;is because that's how it always happens. Look at whistleblower culture. If you want to be a whistleblower you have to be prepared to lose your job. I'm able to do what I'm doing here because I'm nobody. I don't have to keep any academics happy. I don't have to think about the possible consequences of my actions for people I might admire personally who may have based their work on this and they end up looking silly. There are 160,000 psychologists in America and they've got mortgages. I've got the necessary degree of total independence.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Armed with that independence, he went away and looked at the maths that underpinned Fredrickson and Losada's ratio. Complex or non-linear dynamics are not easy for an untrained mathematician to understand, much less work out. Losada, who claimed expertise in non-linear dynamics, was working as a business consultant and making mathematical models of business team behaviour when he first met Fredrickson.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;Positivity&lt;/em&gt;, Fredrickson describes the moment when Losada explained how he could apply complex dynamics to her theories of positive psychology. &quot;Hours into our lively discussion, he made a bold claim: based on his mathematical work, he could locate the exact positivity ratio that would distinguish those who flourished from those who didn't.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So impressed was she by this boast that Fredrickson arranged a sabbatical from her teaching duties &quot;so I could immerse myself in the science of dynamic systems that Marcial had introduced me to&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were several psychologists, versed in non-linear dynamics, who smelt something fishy about the maths in the published paper. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.marquette.edu/psyc/facstaff_guastello.shtml&quot; title=&quot;&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Stephen Guastello&lt;/a&gt;, from Marquette University, wrote a note of mild complaint to &lt;em&gt;American Psychologist&lt;/em&gt;, which it chose not to publish because &quot;there wasn't enough interest in the article&quot;. Guastello feels now that he should have been more forceful in his opinions. &quot;In retrospect,&quot; he says, &quot;I see how I could have been more clearly negative and less supportive of what looked like an article that could move the field forward if someone would follow up with some strong empirical work.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John Gottman, a leading authority in the psychology of successful relationships, wrote to Losada because he couldn't follow the equations. &quot;I thought it was something I didn't know about, because he's a smart guy, Losada. He never answered my email,&quot; he says. Gottman also wrote to Fredrickson. &quot;She said she didn't understand the math either.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Not many psychologists are very good at maths,&quot; says Brown. &quot;Not many psychologists are even good at the maths and statistics you have to do as a psychologist. Typically you'll have a couple of people in the department who understand it. Most psychologists are not capable of organising a quantitative study. A lot of people can get a PhD in psychology without having those things at their fingertips. And that's the stuff you're meant to know. Losada's maths were of the kind you're not meant to encounter in psychology. The maths you need to understand the Losada system is hard but the maths you need to understand that this cannot possibly be true is relatively straightforward.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brown had studied maths to A-level and then took a degree in engineering and computer science at Cambridge. &quot;But I actually gave up the engineering because the maths was too hard,&quot; he says, laughing at the irony. &quot;So I'm really not that good at maths. I can read simple calculus but I can't solve differential equations. But then neither could Losada!&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He went back over Losada's equations and he noticed that if he put in the numbers Fredrickson and Losada had then you could arrive at the appropriate figures. But he realised that it only worked on its own terms. &quot;When you look at the equation, it doesn't contain any data. It's completely self-referential.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, while his grasp of maths was strong enough to see the problem, it wasn't sufficiently firm to be able to mount an academic takedown of Fredrickson's and Losada's work. Yet that was what he wanted to do. Once he knew to his own satisfaction that their research was fundamentally flawed, he was not going to be content to let things pass. So he decided to seek the help of an academic mathematician. Not just any academic mathematician either, but one who had made a name for himself by puncturing the bogus use of maths and science in another discipline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in 1996, Alan Sokal wrote a paper called &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.physics.nyu.edu/faculty/sokal/transgress_v2/transgress_v2_singlefile.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Transgressing the Boundaries: Towards a Transformative Hermeneutics of Quantum Gravity&lt;/a&gt; and submitted it to an academic cultural studies journal called &lt;em&gt;Social Text&lt;/em&gt;, which promptly published the article. As the title suggested, the paper was dense with impenetrable theory. Among other things, it disparaged the scientific method and western intellectual hegemony and claimed that quantum gravity could only be understood through its political context.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The paper, as Sokal quickly admitted, was a hoax, a deliberate pastiche of the sorts of nonsensical postmodern appropriations of maths and physics at which French critical theorists particularly excelled – among them Jacques Derrida, Jacques Lacan, Gilles Deleuze and Julia Kristeva. A major intellectual controversy ensued in which postmodernists stood accused of pseudo-science, absurd cultural relativism and the concealing of ignorance and innumeracy behind obscurantist prose. In response Sokal was derided as a pedant, a literalist and a cultural imperialist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the counterattacks, Sokal gained a reputation as a formidable enemy of bad science. As such he was regularly approached by people who believed they had uncovered an intellectual imposture, be it in architecture, history or musicology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;I don't think I'm a crank,&quot; Brown had said in his email to Sokal. &quot;I am just this grad student with no qualifications or credentials, starting out in the field. I don't know how to express this kind of idea especially coherently in academic written form, and I suspect that even if I did, it would be unlikely to be published.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But like many such requests, it began to disappear beneath a pile of other emails. It was only several weeks later that Sokal came across it again and realised that on this occasion he could help because it was in a field he knew something about: mathematics and physics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Losada had derived his mathematical model from a system of differential equations known as the Lorenz equations, after &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Edward_Norton_Lorenz&quot; title=&quot;&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Edward Lorenz, a pioneer of chaos theory&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;The Lorenz equation Losada used was from fluid dynamics,&quot; says Sokal, &quot;which is not the field that I'm specialised in, but it's elementary enough that any mathematician or physicist knows enough. In 10 seconds I could see it was total bullshit. Nick had written a very long critique and basically it was absolutely right. There were some points where he didn't quite get the math right but essentially Nick had seen everything that was wrong with the Losada and Fredrickson paper.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sokal did a little research and was amazed at the standing the Fredrickson and Losada paper enjoyed. &quot;I don't know what the figures are in psychology but I know that in physics having 350 citations is a big deal,&quot; he says. &quot;Look on Google you get something like 27,000 hits. This theory is not just big in academia, there's a whole industry of coaching and it intersects with business and business schools. There's a lot of money in it.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The concept of positive thinking dates back at least as far as the ancient Greeks. Throughout written history, metaphysicians have grappled with questions of happiness and free will. The second-century Stoic sage Epictetus argued that &quot;Your will needn't be affected by an incident unless you let it&quot;. In other words, we can be masters and not victims of fate because what we believe our capability to be determines the strength of that capability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In one way or another, positive thinking has always been concerned with optimising human potential, which is a key component of psychology. But in the 20th century, confronting the great traumas of two annihilating wars, the psychology profession became increasingly focused on the dysfunctional and pathological aspects of the human mind. The emphasis was on healing the ill rather than improving the well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So it was left to popular or amateur psychology, and in particular that sector specialising in business success, to accentuate the positive. Books such as Norman Vincent Peale's &lt;em&gt;The Power of Positive Thinking&lt;/em&gt;, published in 1952, became huge bestsellers. By the 1970s and 1980s, self-help had mushroomed into a vast literary genre that encompassed everything from the secrets of material achievement to the new age promises of chakras, reiki and self-realisation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On becoming president of the American Psychological Association in 1998, Martin Seligman set out to bring scientific rigour to the issue of self-improvement. In his inaugural speech, he announced a shift in psychology towards a &quot;new science of human strengths&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;u-responsive-ratio&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;gu-image&quot; itemprop=&quot;contentUrl&quot; alt=&quot;Barbara Frederickson&quot; src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/static/sys-images/Admin/BkFill/Default_image_group/2014/1/15/1389799735742/Barbara-Frederickson-001.jpg?w=300&amp;amp;q=55&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;usm=12&amp;amp;fit=max&amp;amp;s=d239db0e37f69ff55c6222bc91282219&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Barbara Frederickson, associate editor of American Psychologist, accepts the errors in the maths that Nick Brown pointed out, but still stands by her theory of positivity.
&lt;p&gt;&quot;It's my belief,&quot; said Seligman, &quot;that since the end of the second world war, psychology has moved too far away from its original roots, which were to make the lives of all people more fulfilling and productive, and too much toward the important, but not all-important, area of curing mental illness.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He called for &quot;a reoriented science that emphasises the understanding and building of the most positive qualities of an individual&quot;. It was an optimistic period in American history. The economy was buoyant, US geopolitical power was unchallenged and no major conflicts were raging. As a result, there was almost a messianic note of global ambition in Seligman's address. &quot;We can show the world what actions lead to wellbeing, to positive individuals, to flourishing communities, and to a just society,&quot; he declared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suddenly a plethora of positive psychology books began to appear, written by eminent psychologists. There was &lt;em&gt;Flow: The Psychology of Happiness&lt;/em&gt; by Mihaly Csikszentmihalyi, who with Seligman is seen as the co-founder of the modern positive psychology movement; &lt;em&gt;Authentic Happiness: Using the New Positive &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/science/psychology&quot; data-link-name=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; data-component=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Psychology&lt;/a&gt; to Realise Your Potential for Lasting Fulfilment&lt;/em&gt; by Seligman himself. And of course Fredrickson's &lt;em&gt;Positivity&lt;/em&gt;, approved by both Seligman and Csikszentmihalyi. Each of them appeared to quote and promote one another, creating a virtuous circle of recommendation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And these books were not only marketed like a previous generation of self-help manuals, they often shared the same style of cod-sagacious prose. &quot;Positivity opens your mind naturally, like the water lily that opens with sunlight,&quot; writes Fredrickson in &lt;em&gt;Positivity&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then there was the lucrative lecture circuit. Both Seligman and Fredrickson are hired speakers. One website lists Seligman's booking fee at between $30,000 and $50,000 an engagement. In this new science of happiness, it seemed that all the leading proponents were happy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But then Nick Brown started to ask questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Around the time Brown first came across Fredrickson's work, a case came to light in Holland in which a psychologist called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/science/2012/sep/13/scientific-research-fraud-bad-practice&quot; title=&quot;&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Diederik Stapel&lt;/a&gt;, who was dean of faculty at Tilburg University, was caught by his graduate students making up data. It turned out he'd been falsifying his research for the previous 15 years. Brown, who is currently translating Stapel's autobiography, got in touch with him and asked him why he did it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;The way he describes it,&quot; says Brown, &quot;is that the environment was conducive to it. He said, 'I could either do the hard work or put my hand in the jar and take out a biscuit'.&quot; It does a massive amount of harm to science when this sort of thing happens. Nobody's accusing Fredrickson of making anything up. She just basically invented her own method. Is that worse than inventing your own data?&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After he had established contact with Sokal, Brown sent him a 15,000-word draft, which was much too long for publication. At first the professor agreed to give Brown advice on cleaning up the draft. He also told him that he should go to &lt;em&gt;American Psychologist&lt;/em&gt;, and he contributed a pedagogic section, explaining the maths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;I still wasn't thinking that I was going to be a co-author but Nick sent me drafts and I just liked his writing style,&quot; recalls Sokal. &quot;It made me laugh. He had this gift for English understatement.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting their critique of Fredrickson into the publication of which she was an associate editor was a tall order. To help him get across the line, Brown had already recruited Harris Friedman, a sympathetic psychologist who had doubts about Fredrickson's claims but was not sufficiently versed in maths to make a case on his own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sending revised versions back and forth among themselves, the three men gradually composed what they considered to be a watertight argument. The initial title they submitted to &lt;em&gt;American Psychologist&lt;/em&gt; was The Complex Dynamics of an Intellectual Imposture – an ironic play on Fredrickson and Losada's original piece. That was rejected by the editor because he argued that the word &quot;imposture&quot; implied a deliberate fraud on the part of Fredrickson and Losada.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sokal insists that this was never their intention. As Brown puts it in characteristic manner. &quot;This particular paper wasn't an act of fraud and it wasn't about statistics. It's that someone had a brain-fart one day.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following much negotiation, Brown, Sokal and Friedman had their paper accepted by &lt;em&gt;American Psychologist&lt;/em&gt; and it was published online last July under the only slightly less provocative title of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.physics.nyu.edu/sokal/complex_dynamics_final_clean.pdf&quot; title=&quot;&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;The Complex Dynamics of Wishful Thinking&lt;/a&gt;. Referring to the bizarrely precise tipping point ratio of 2.9013 that Fredrickson and Losada trumpeted applied to all humans regardless of age, gender, race or culture, the authors – in fact Brown, in this sentence – wrote: &quot;The idea that any aspect of human behaviour or experience should be universally and reproducibly constant to five significant digits would, if proven, constitute a unique moment in the history of the social sciences.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The paper mounted a devastating case against the maths employed by Fredrickson and Losada, who were offered the chance to respond in the same online issue of &lt;em&gt;American Psychologist&lt;/em&gt;. Losada declined and has thus far failed to defend his input in any public forum. But Fredrickson did write a reply, which, putting a positive spin on things, she titled &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.unc.edu/peplab/publications/Fredrickson%202013%20Updated%20Thinking.pdf&quot; title=&quot;&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Updated Thinking on Positivity Ratios&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She effectively accepted that Losada's maths was wrong and admitted that she never really understood it anyway. But she refused to accept that the rest of the research was flawed. Indeed she claimed that, if anything, the empirical evidence was even stronger in support of her case. Fredrickson subsequently removed the critical chapter that outlines Losada's input from further editions of &lt;em&gt;Positivity&lt;/em&gt;. She has avoided speaking to much of the press but in an email exchange with me, she maintained that &quot;on empirical grounds, yes, tipping points are highly probable&quot; in relation to positive emotions and flourishing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;She's kind of hoping the Cheshire cat has disappeared but the grin is still there,&quot; says Brown, who is dismissive of Fredrickson's efforts at damage limitation. &quot;She's trying to throw Losada over the side without admitting that she got conned. All she can really show is that higher numbers are better than lower ones. What you do in science is you make a statement of what you think will happen and then run the experiment and see if it matches it. What you don't do is pick up a bunch of data and start reading tea leaves. Because you can always find something. If you don't have much data you shouldn't go round theorising. Something orange is going to happen to you today, says the astrology chart. Sure enough, you'll notice if an orange bicycle goes by you.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But social psychology is full of theorising and much of it goes unquestioned. This is particularly the case when the research involves, as it does with Fredrickson, self-report, where the subjects assess themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As John Gottman says: &quot;Self-report data is easier to obtain, so a lot of social psychologists have formed an implicit society where they won't challenge one another. It's a collusion that makes it easier to publish research and not look at observational data or more objective data.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In general, says Gottman, the results of self-report have been quite reliable in the area of wellbeing. The problem is that when it comes down to distinguishing, say, those who &quot;languish&quot; from those who &quot;flourish&quot;, there may be all manner of cultural and personal reasons why an individual or group might wish to deny negative feelings or even downplay positive ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;It's a lot more complicated than Fredrickson is suggesting,&quot; says Gottman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After initially being turned down, Brown, Sokal and Friedman went through &lt;em&gt;American Psychologist's&lt;/em&gt; lengthy appeals procedure and won the right to reply to Fredrickson's reply. They are currently working on what is certain to be a very carefully considered response. But it doesn't take a psychologist to work out that, given the nature of human behaviour, it's unlikely to be the last word.&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2018 18:33:02 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>IntronExon</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://www.theguardian.com/science/2014/jan/19/mathematics-of-happiness-debunked-nick-brown</og:url>
<og:description>Andrew Anthony: The astonishing story of the British man who began a part-time psychology course in his 50s – and ended up taking on America's academic establishment</og:description>
<og:image>https://i.guim.co.uk/img/static/sys-images/Admin/BkFill/Default_image_group/2014/1/16/1389887801855/Illustration-by-Chris-Gas-011.jpg?w=1200&amp;h=630&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;fit=crop&amp;crop=faces%2Centropy&amp;bm=normal&amp;ba=bottom%2Cleft&amp;blend64=aHR0cHM6Ly91cGxvYWRzLmd1aW0uY28udWsvMjAxOC8wMS8zMS9mYWNlYm9va19kZWZhdWx0LnBuZw&amp;s=584ce18a277b0f2df762d9eff7560c85</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>The British amateur who debunked the mathematics of happiness</og:title>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.theguardian.com/science/2014/jan/19/mathematics-of-happiness-debunked-nick-brown</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ask HN: Move to product management at 35?</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16515470</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16515470</guid>
<description>&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.55737704918033&quot;&gt;&lt;td bgcolor=&quot;#FF6600&quot;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.775&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table class=&quot;fatitem&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.5375&quot;&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing&quot; id=&quot;16515470&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;right&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;title&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16515470&quot; class=&quot;storylink&quot;&gt;Ask HN: Move to product management at 35?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.68965517241379&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;subtext&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;score&quot; id=&quot;score_16515470&quot;&gt;260 points&lt;/span&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/user?id=neofrommatrix&quot; class=&quot;hnuser&quot;&gt;neofrommatrix&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;age&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16515470&quot;&gt;22 hours ago&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span id=&quot;unv_16515470&quot;/&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/hide?id=16515470&amp;amp;goto=item%3Fid%3D16515470&quot;&gt;hide&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://hn.algolia.com/?query=Ask%20HN%3A%20Move%20to%20product%20management%20at%2035%3F&amp;amp;sort=byDate&amp;amp;dateRange=all&amp;amp;type=story&amp;amp;storyText=false&amp;amp;prefix&amp;amp;page=0&quot; class=&quot;hnpast&quot;&gt;past&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=Ask%20HN%3A%20Move%20to%20product%20management%20at%2035%3F&quot;&gt;web&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/fave?id=16515470&amp;amp;auth=1d23116cf8ebe2a8e20f96509835daab112195c7&quot;&gt;favorite&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16515470&quot;&gt;117 comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;Hi all,
&lt;p&gt;I need some advice from all the wonderful people on Hacker News. I am a Backend engineer looking to move into a product management role. I have no experience in product management. In addition, I am 35. Does age matter? Are certifications such as the one from Product School worth it and help in the transition process? How do engineers typically transition to the role? I’d appreciate any advice from anyone. Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td&gt;

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.73972602739726&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ycombinator.com/apply/&quot;&gt;Applications are open for YC Summer 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;yclinks&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/newsguidelines.html&quot;&gt;Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/newsfaq.html&quot;&gt;FAQ&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:hn@ycombinator.com&quot;&gt;Support&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/HackerNews/API&quot;&gt;API&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/security.html&quot;&gt;Security&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/lists&quot;&gt;Lists&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/bookmarklet.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Bookmarklet&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ycombinator.com/legal/&quot;&gt;Legal&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ycombinator.com/apply/&quot;&gt;Apply to YC&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:hn@ycombinator.com&quot;&gt;Contact&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2018 17:21:08 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>neofrommatrix</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16515470</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Three girls, a dead raccoon, and a crockpot</title>
<link>http://www.poweredbyosteons.org/2018/03/two-girls-dead-raccoon-and-my-crockpot.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.poweredbyosteons.org/2018/03/two-girls-dead-raccoon-and-my-crockpot.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I was out of town giving a public talk last week when I got this picture along with a text from my husband: &quot;Zooarch consult plz.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-zvuKsDmXhJ4/WpsLxRsj2cI/AAAAAAAAJjY/UdjIz3MY8PoaYvGYQs7JlQ1vENFM16qIgCLcBGAs/s1600/920.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1200&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1600&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-zvuKsDmXhJ4/WpsLxRsj2cI/AAAAAAAAJjY/UdjIz3MY8PoaYvGYQs7JlQ1vENFM16qIgCLcBGAs/s400/920.jpg&quot; width=&quot;400&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;That's my 8-year-old, Cecilia, on the right along with her BFF. They were traipsing through the small patch of woods behind our house and found some... dead stuff. Squinting at my phone, I typed back that there was a turtle and maybe a small dog or something, but that I'd check it out when I got home. And to wash their hands well.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;The girls gathered the bones-and-fur mess and tied it off in a plastic bag.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-Q8oxWsiWmk4/WpsN40O1PEI/AAAAAAAAJj8/XtjRCDaLYccPGC1anPHXirKDABZDMyubQCLcBGAs/s1600/IMG_20180223_073620908.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1200&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1600&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-Q8oxWsiWmk4/WpsN40O1PEI/AAAAAAAAJj8/XtjRCDaLYccPGC1anPHXirKDABZDMyubQCLcBGAs/s400/IMG_20180223_073620908.jpg&quot; width=&quot;400&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;Once I got a look at it, and posted to Facebook for a consult, I realized it wasn't a dog but rather a raccoon. The next step was to separate the raccoon from the turtle shell and pick off the gross decaying fur. So I brought home some nitrile gloves from my lab.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-2lJRDbaNNLY/WpsOQnUwfwI/AAAAAAAAJkA/834o2IVkNBMrs4ngGGiaIN5mWm1KOAClwCLcBGAs/s1600/IMG_20180224_152443848_BURST000_COVER_TOP.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1200&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1600&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-2lJRDbaNNLY/WpsOQnUwfwI/AAAAAAAAJkA/834o2IVkNBMrs4ngGGiaIN5mWm1KOAClwCLcBGAs/s400/IMG_20180224_152443848_BURST000_COVER_TOP.jpg&quot; width=&quot;400&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;Cecilia liked this part, and was excited to find some vertebrae still articulated:&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-Q-J72ZUHhOQ/WpsOhO2TB3I/AAAAAAAAJkE/c6Q8Pk8E57kB8DsSHfHC2edTzv8dzMVsQCLcBGAs/s1600/IMG_20180224_152549510_HDR.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1200&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1600&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-Q-J72ZUHhOQ/WpsOhO2TB3I/AAAAAAAAJkE/c6Q8Pk8E57kB8DsSHfHC2edTzv8dzMVsQCLcBGAs/s400/IMG_20180224_152549510_HDR.jpg&quot; width=&quot;400&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;She put all the bones into the crockpot that I brought home from my lab as well (which we keep for the express purpose of defleshing stuff that, well, still has squishy/hairy bits on it):&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-pOJcjVD-yMM/WpsO0Ki5e4I/AAAAAAAAJkM/Yfb4utZ6lU8bMMe4EEwdNfL-pBIhsaaYwCLcBGAs/s1600/IMG_20180224_152820183.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1600&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1200&quot; height=&quot;320&quot; src=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-pOJcjVD-yMM/WpsO0Ki5e4I/AAAAAAAAJkM/Yfb4utZ6lU8bMMe4EEwdNfL-pBIhsaaYwCLcBGAs/s320/IMG_20180224_152820183.jpg&quot; width=&quot;240&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;She filled it about 2/3rds of the way up with water from the garden hose (which she wanted to put in the watering can for some reason). Then, we had to add detergent. Biz was recommended to me by our resident faunal expert in the department, so I bought a small amount of it at Publix.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-_seE8YUDeP0/WpsPUh2favI/AAAAAAAAJkY/sW8zSHHv_KkRZrmmF37JP9Tvd8sA8QhUQCLcBGAs/s1600/IMG_20180224_153028272_BURST000_COVER_TOP.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1200&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1600&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-_seE8YUDeP0/WpsPUh2favI/AAAAAAAAJkY/sW8zSHHv_KkRZrmmF37JP9Tvd8sA8QhUQCLcBGAs/s400/IMG_20180224_153028272_BURST000_COVER_TOP.jpg&quot; width=&quot;400&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;At this point, my 4-year-old, Linnea, wanted to help out. After Cecilia dumped in the detergent, she and Linnea took turns gently stirring it. (Linnea, by the way, was quite disappointed in the raccoon - she really wanted to macerate a bat, to see how its wing looked on the inside. But that's not gonna happen because of the risk of rabies.)&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-pCIfLOf1MXY/WpsPjHGdSPI/AAAAAAAAJkc/iqXqlBBwfAkMcVy9wS7eW1fTIWrlgU15gCLcBGAs/s1600/IMG_20180224_153319630_BURST000_COVER_TOP.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1200&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1600&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-pCIfLOf1MXY/WpsPjHGdSPI/AAAAAAAAJkc/iqXqlBBwfAkMcVy9wS7eW1fTIWrlgU15gCLcBGAs/s400/IMG_20180224_153319630_BURST000_COVER_TOP.jpg&quot; width=&quot;400&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;We put the lid on, turned the crockpot on to the low/4-hour setting, and left it alone.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-PvMm86_kvNM/WpsPwoVXs3I/AAAAAAAAJkg/IU_Op1VTIPMpUi2Sl-EkTZSyEhGggOzqgCLcBGAs/s1600/IMG_20180224_153649375.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1200&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1600&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-PvMm86_kvNM/WpsPwoVXs3I/AAAAAAAAJkg/IU_Op1VTIPMpUi2Sl-EkTZSyEhGggOzqgCLcBGAs/s400/IMG_20180224_153649375.jpg&quot; width=&quot;400&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;Since we didn't start this quite early enough in the day, by the time we turned the crockpot off, it was getting dark. I decanted the sudsy water off carefully, and then dumped the rest of the water-and-bones out onto the cement patio. We collected the bones and set them on the metal table outside, and I let Cecilia and her friend scrub the bones with old toothbrushes to get the remaining fur off.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-VWEHaaZ17qM/WpsQXYYBWLI/AAAAAAAAJkw/LCPf9cMxryo38NB21LwJm16RDE5ezaL2ACLcBGAs/s1600/IMG_20180224_191545399.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1200&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1600&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-VWEHaaZ17qM/WpsQXYYBWLI/AAAAAAAAJkw/LCPf9cMxryo38NB21LwJm16RDE5ezaL2ACLcBGAs/s400/IMG_20180224_191545399.jpg&quot; width=&quot;400&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;Once the bones were cleaned, I tossed them into a disposable tupperware bowl, dumped in all the hydrogen peroxide I had (maybe 1.5 cups), and topped the bowl off with water and capped it. I didn't take any pictures of this, but we left it on the kitchen counter for like 3 days, swirling it occasionally.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;When we were happy with the color, we dumped the bones out of the hydrogen peroxide solution and let them dry on the table outside.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-O5Agd5qX1Cc/WpsQ8k7tC1I/AAAAAAAAJk8/zyDQIL20Z2IVvPYhF5XjHakiTLP052ljwCLcBGAs/s1600/IMG_20180228_074201169.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1600&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1200&quot; height=&quot;320&quot; src=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-O5Agd5qX1Cc/WpsQ8k7tC1I/AAAAAAAAJk8/zyDQIL20Z2IVvPYhF5XjHakiTLP052ljwCLcBGAs/s320/IMG_20180228_074201169.jpg&quot; width=&quot;240&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-yrDCgiOhw4w/WpsRA6NfSRI/AAAAAAAAJlA/pmfbATd963I89PaZDstDL6HRdj3YKyH4QCLcBGAs/s1600/IMG_20180228_074157208_HDR.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1600&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1200&quot; height=&quot;320&quot; src=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-yrDCgiOhw4w/WpsRA6NfSRI/AAAAAAAAJlA/pmfbATd963I89PaZDstDL6HRdj3YKyH4QCLcBGAs/s320/IMG_20180228_074157208_HDR.jpg&quot; width=&quot;240&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;After the bones were dry, I printed out two diagrams of raccoon skeletons. I gave those to Cecilia along with the clean, dry bones, and let her puzzle out where they all went.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-dIqyuesDU-w/WpsRqRJl1vI/AAAAAAAAJlM/9dHnNtoOuWEe2Pv9CYYiU-Q_sCpLIvvTwCLcBGAs/s1600/IMG_20180303_100808352.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1600&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1200&quot; height=&quot;320&quot; src=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-dIqyuesDU-w/WpsRqRJl1vI/AAAAAAAAJlM/9dHnNtoOuWEe2Pv9CYYiU-Q_sCpLIvvTwCLcBGAs/s320/IMG_20180303_100808352.jpg&quot; width=&quot;240&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;This is what we ended up with, once I helped identify and side the bones. (Those of you with better faunal anatomy skills, don't yell at me! I totally punted on the metatarsals and tarsals(?) but think I did OK on the major bones.)&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-34nyz_oqA3w/WpsSDGlFpyI/AAAAAAAAJlQ/aOygs6NxujQxoeQYg9C2VjMl-AIx-xJUgCLcBGAs/s1600/IMG_20180303_104436401.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;718&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1600&quot; height=&quot;178&quot; src=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-34nyz_oqA3w/WpsSDGlFpyI/AAAAAAAAJlQ/aOygs6NxujQxoeQYg9C2VjMl-AIx-xJUgCLcBGAs/s400/IMG_20180303_104436401.jpg&quot; width=&quot;400&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;Cecilia wanted to label the bones and put them in labeled boxes or bags, so I helped her by telling her the correct plurals where relevant.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-p8A1RBtzuR4/WpsSSIER0-I/AAAAAAAAJlY/8WmFSwsxOJoVfTw3BX12Fb6wtikm2Jh5wCLcBGAs/s1600/IMG_20180303_104708588.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1600&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1200&quot; height=&quot;320&quot; src=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-p8A1RBtzuR4/WpsSSIER0-I/AAAAAAAAJlY/8WmFSwsxOJoVfTw3BX12Fb6wtikm2Jh5wCLcBGAs/s320/IMG_20180303_104708588.jpg&quot; width=&quot;240&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;And that's it! We finished labeling the bones this afternoon, and now they're in little bags and boxes, waiting for... well, who knows. I'm interested to find out what Cecilia wants to do with her raccoon!&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-5Eo5pPa0YAw/WpsSq6TAvgI/AAAAAAAAJlg/RgiqS8GTLnUGJmJMOnNvuMBsL1wso19fgCLcBGAs/s1600/IMG_20180303_111813599.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;671&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1600&quot; height=&quot;167&quot; src=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-5Eo5pPa0YAw/WpsSq6TAvgI/AAAAAAAAJlg/RgiqS8GTLnUGJmJMOnNvuMBsL1wso19fgCLcBGAs/s400/IMG_20180303_111813599.jpg&quot; width=&quot;400&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;So, if your kid brings home a random dead thing, all you need are a crockpot, some detergent, and hydrogen peroxide, and... voilà! A STEM-worthy project. &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;




</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2018 16:43:02 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>fanf2</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://www.poweredbyosteons.org/2018/03/two-girls-dead-raccoon-and-my-crockpot.html</og:url>
<og:title>Three Girls, a Dead Raccoon, and My Crockpot: A Photo-Essay</og:title>
<og:description>I was out of town giving a public talk last week when I got this picture along with a text from my husband: &quot;Zooarch consult plz.&quot; Th...</og:description>
<og:image>https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-zvuKsDmXhJ4/WpsLxRsj2cI/AAAAAAAAJjY/UdjIz3MY8PoaYvGYQs7JlQ1vENFM16qIgCLcBGAs/w1200-h630-p-k-no-nu/920.jpg</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.poweredbyosteons.org/2018/03/two-girls-dead-raccoon-and-my-crockpot.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Show HN: Emacs Anywhere</title>
<link>https://github.com/zachcurry/emacs-anywhere</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/zachcurry/emacs-anywhere</guid>
<description>&lt;h3&gt;README.md&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;markdown-body entry-content&quot; itemprop=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/07025e282fc67f96621ed0ae5a7376d157e1dacc/68747470733a2f2f696d6775722e636f6d2f4b4576615654502e6a7067&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/07025e282fc67f96621ed0ae5a7376d157e1dacc/68747470733a2f2f696d6775722e636f6d2f4b4576615654502e6a7067&quot; width=&quot;250px&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://imgur.com/KEvaVTP.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Inspired by&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/cknadler/vim-anywhere&quot;&gt;cknadler/vim-anywhere&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/2c52476623b3375b5eca7bf3654b4d9dbe409905/68747470733a2f2f7468756d62732e6766796361742e636f6d2f506c756d70446561646c79416c70696e65676f61742d73697a655f726573747269637465642e676966&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img align=&quot;right&quot; src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/2c52476623b3375b5eca7bf3654b4d9dbe409905/68747470733a2f2f7468756d62732e6766796361742e636f6d2f506c756d70446561646c79416c70696e65676f61742d73697a655f726573747269637465642e676966&quot; width=&quot;500px&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://thumbs.gfycat.com/PlumpDeadlyAlpinegoat-size_restricted.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What it does&lt;/h2&gt;
A keyboard shortcut of your choosing creates a temporary frame and buffer. The text is automatically inserted into the application you're using. Bust your moves on the fly, with fewer keystrokes. Invoke the shortcut with selected text and it will be replaced.
&lt;h2&gt;Install&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;OSX&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Clone the repo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
git clone https://github.com/zachcurry/emacs-anywhere.git
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;Run the install script from the root of the repo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;Open System Preferences and navigate to &lt;code&gt;keyboard &amp;gt; shortcuts &amp;gt; Services&lt;/code&gt;. Check the box beside &quot;Emacs Anywhere&quot; and click &quot;Add Shortcut&quot; and key a shortcut.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Linux (alpha)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Linux implementation requires&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;xdotool&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;be installed. Install as needed.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
sudo apt-get install xdotool
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Clone the repo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
git clone https://github.com/zachcurry/emacs-anywhere.git
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;Run the install script from the root of the repo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;Create a keyboard shortcut with this command &lt;code&gt;$HOME/.emacs_anywhere/bin/run&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Windows&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TBD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How to&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Invoke the shortcut. A new frame will be created and display an empty buffer titled &lt;code&gt;*Emacs Anywhere*&lt;/code&gt;. When the frame is deleted the buffer's content is inserted into the application you're using and the buffer is deleted. Any text selected when the keyboard shortcut is invoked will be replaced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Uninstall &lt;strong&gt;Emacs Anywhere&lt;/strong&gt; by running the &lt;code&gt;uninstall&lt;/code&gt; script from the root of the repo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
./uninstall
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Slow?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If your Emacs server isn't running when you use the keyboard shortcut, &lt;strong&gt;Emacs Anywhere&lt;/strong&gt; will start it (this is slower). Run Emacs as a daemon (&lt;code&gt;emacs --daemon&lt;/code&gt;) to start your server from the command line, or use &lt;code&gt;server-start&lt;/code&gt; command in Emacs. Once you've a got a running server, new frames are created much faster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;TODO&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Emacs command to toggle &lt;strong&gt;Emacs Anywhere&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Homebrew&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Windows&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have a question? Like the tool? Don't like it? Open an issue and let's talk about it! Pull requests are appreciated!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Copyright © 2018, Zach Curry, All rights reserved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2018 09:20:47 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>curryz</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars2.githubusercontent.com/u/7032632?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>zachcurry/emacs-anywhere</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/zachcurry/emacs-anywhere</og:url>
<og:description>emacs-anywhere - Use. Emacs. Anywhere.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/zachcurry/emacs-anywhere</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>