<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Show HN: What would mechanical programming look like?</title>
<link>https://mockmechanics.com/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://mockmechanics.com/</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://mockmechanics.com/&quot;&gt;https://mockmechanics.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24934722&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24934722&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 215&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 53&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2020 19:40:41 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>felipereigosa</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://mockmechanics.com/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ruby on Rails in a week</title>
<link>https://www.simplethread.com/ruby-on-rails-in-a-week/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.simplethread.com/ruby-on-rails-in-a-week/</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;default st-post-thumbnail -st-not-illo st-box-shadow st-anim-trigger&quot; data-anim=&quot;post-image&quot;&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;2000&quot; height=&quot;1182&quot; src=&quot;https://3otebq2knmnf3smsj0374a9u-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/time-watch.jpg&quot; class=&quot;attachment-medium-large size-medium-large wp-post-image&quot; alt=&quot;Ruby on Rails in a Week&quot; srcset=&quot;https://3otebq2knmnf3smsj0374a9u-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/time-watch.jpg 2000w, https://3otebq2knmnf3smsj0374a9u-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/time-watch-300x177.jpg 300w, https://3otebq2knmnf3smsj0374a9u-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/time-watch-1024x605.jpg 1024w, https://3otebq2knmnf3smsj0374a9u-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/time-watch-768x454.jpg 768w, https://3otebq2knmnf3smsj0374a9u-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/time-watch-1536x908.jpg 1536w, https://3otebq2knmnf3smsj0374a9u-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/time-watch-2048x1211.jpg 2048w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 2000px) 100vw, 2000px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;2000&quot; height=&quot;1182&quot; src=&quot;data:image/svg+xml,%3Csvg%20xmlns=%22http://www.w3.org/2000/svg%22%20viewBox=%220%200%202000%201182%22%3E%3C/svg%3E&quot; data-src=&quot;https://3otebq2knmnf3smsj0374a9u-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/time-watch.jpg&quot; class=&quot;lazyload attachment-medium-large size-medium-large wp-post-image&quot; alt=&quot;Ruby on Rails in a Week&quot; data-srcset=&quot;https://3otebq2knmnf3smsj0374a9u-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/time-watch.jpg 2000w, https://3otebq2knmnf3smsj0374a9u-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/time-watch-300x177.jpg 300w, https://3otebq2knmnf3smsj0374a9u-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/time-watch-1024x605.jpg 1024w, https://3otebq2knmnf3smsj0374a9u-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/time-watch-768x454.jpg 768w, https://3otebq2knmnf3smsj0374a9u-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/time-watch-1536x908.jpg 1536w, https://3otebq2knmnf3smsj0374a9u-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/time-watch-2048x1211.jpg 2048w&quot; data-sizes=&quot;(max-width: 2000px) 100vw, 2000px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;st-blogpost--subscribe&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;st-emphasized mb-0&quot;&gt;Worried you’ll miss us?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;mb-2&quot;&gt;Subscribe to get our articles and updates in your inbox.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Preface&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Note: this post builds off of my previous post,&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.simplethread.com/learning-to-learn/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Learning to Learn&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;, and references it a few times—however, this post should still make sense if you missed the first one. Also, this is not a tutorial, but rather a log of my experience learning Ruby on Rails.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently found myself in a situation where I had 7 days to learn Ruby on Rails. This was mentioned briefly in my &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.simplethread.com/learning-to-learn/&quot;&gt;previous blog post&lt;/a&gt;, but I wanted to take the time now to elaborate on this experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My last blog post was all about how to learn, and taking the best approach to learning. This blog post is about putting those ideas into practice—a case study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Interview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First things first—I was in the midst of an interview process. It was a Friday afternoon, and next Friday I would be taking part in a live coding exercise. Most of this exercise would involve working on a Ruby on Rails application. This meant that I had a 7 day crunch to learn the framework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may speculate on how I found myself in this situation. Maybe it was the result of some forgery or deceit. Maybe I had lied about my experience in order to get my foot in the door, and was now left scrambling. But alas, no. It was not all that exciting. There was no dishonesty, and no nefarious behaviors. Instead, it was a shared understanding between me and interviewers that I was bringing no preexisting knowledge of Rails.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The agreement was that I would learn a new technology, and they would judge me on how well I picked it up. I would learn, but not master, the technology, and they would take my greenness into account while assessing my knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As such, I reasoned that I wasn’t really being tested on my knowledge of the Rails framework. Of course, when the time came, I would have to demonstrate some degree of functional knowledge. However if that was all that they were looking for they could have just quizzed me—given me a competency test or something of the like. But instead, they wanted to investigate a much more important skill—they wanted to watch me&lt;em&gt; learn&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This ability to learn new technologies is fundamental to being a successful software engineer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet, as important as it may be, gauging someone’s ability to learn is difficult! You can’t fully understand an individual or the soft skills they might have from a simple résumé or cover letter. And technical interviews, no matter the rigor, end up missing the point as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-3321&quot; src=&quot;https://3otebq2knmnf3smsj0374a9u-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/EelADOtWkAEVZ6o.png&quot; alt=&quot;EelADOtWkAEVZ6o&quot; srcset=&quot;https://3otebq2knmnf3smsj0374a9u-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/EelADOtWkAEVZ6o.png 1600w, https://3otebq2knmnf3smsj0374a9u-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/EelADOtWkAEVZ6o-300x188.png 300w, https://3otebq2knmnf3smsj0374a9u-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/EelADOtWkAEVZ6o-1024x643.png 1024w, https://3otebq2knmnf3smsj0374a9u-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/EelADOtWkAEVZ6o-768x482.png 768w, https://3otebq2knmnf3smsj0374a9u-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/EelADOtWkAEVZ6o-1536x964.png 1536w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazyload wp-image-3321&quot; src=&quot;data:image/svg+xml,%3Csvg%20xmlns=%22http://www.w3.org/2000/svg%22%20viewBox=%220%200%20210%20140%22%3E%3C/svg%3E&quot; data-src=&quot;https://3otebq2knmnf3smsj0374a9u-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/EelADOtWkAEVZ6o.png&quot; alt=&quot;EelADOtWkAEVZ6o&quot; data-srcset=&quot;https://3otebq2knmnf3smsj0374a9u-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/EelADOtWkAEVZ6o.png 1600w, https://3otebq2knmnf3smsj0374a9u-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/EelADOtWkAEVZ6o-300x188.png 300w, https://3otebq2knmnf3smsj0374a9u-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/EelADOtWkAEVZ6o-1024x643.png 1024w, https://3otebq2knmnf3smsj0374a9u-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/EelADOtWkAEVZ6o-768x482.png 768w, https://3otebq2knmnf3smsj0374a9u-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/EelADOtWkAEVZ6o-1536x964.png 1536w&quot; data-sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Image by Vincent Déniel, on Twitter &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/vincentdnl&quot;&gt;@vincentdnl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve never felt represented by technical assessments, or interviews which follow silly methods (like the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Situation,_task,_action,_result&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;STAR&lt;/a&gt; method). But by including a learning process in the interview (i.e., learning Ruby on Rails), it gave me a chance to fully represent myself. It benefited both of us. They were able to test me on some very important, yet hard to quantify skills, and I was able to represent myself in a way that I typically would have not been able to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Approach&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I thought about the interview and what I was really being evaluated for, I started to form a strategy—a mind set.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The way in which I would approach the next 7 days was very intentional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I set out to take a higher-level approach to the learning, and, throughout the process, remind myself to focus on the concepts, the bigger picture, and how the things I’m learning relate to my existing knowledge. This was new ground for me. For the first time in my career, I was not just aware of what I was learning, but &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; I was learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To better summarize some aspects of the approach I would be taking:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Focus on the concepts—think bigger&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, take the idea of inheritance. Low level thinking might sound like, “All the other classes are adding &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt; ApplicationController&lt;/code&gt; if they want to use this method, so I need to do that too. Otherwise it throws an error.’’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But high level thinking might be more like, “I need to access the ApplicationController class’ methods. Ruby supports inheritance, so I’ll add  &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt; ApplicationController&lt;/code&gt; to the class definition to let the compiler know that I’m inheriting it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Compare and contrast&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This could be very simple things, like “In Python it’s &lt;code&gt;None&lt;/code&gt;, in Javascript it’s &lt;code&gt;null&lt;/code&gt;, but in Ruby it’s called &lt;code&gt;nil&lt;/code&gt;”, or making connections like “oh, this is like Rail’s version of &lt;code&gt;pip&lt;/code&gt;, or &lt;code&gt;npm&lt;/code&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be curious&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I haven’t seen anything about string interpolation, I wonder if Ruby supports some version of that?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“How would I do something like this in Python? Javascript? Would it be easier or harder?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anticipate&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Rails generates a lot of functions and methods for you that aren’t defined in the code—I bet that will be hard to debug.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be active&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like to take handwritten notes to make sure that I’m not daydreaming, or just moving my eyes over words. If I’m being really purposeful, I like to do the little bonus activities and exercises that tutorials or textbooks often include. Sometimes they’re silly, and feel wasteful, but they do force me to be active, to think about, and to use what I’m learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Take it slow&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone has their own pace, and increasing that pace too much can degrade the other aspects of learning. I find that when I speed up too much, I stop taking notes and start skipping over useful activities. I get lazy, and I don’t learn as much. Moving at a healthy pace, and also taking breaks when needed is very important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Approach (continued)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being able to take a step back and approach a problem at a high-level like this was a significant milestone for me. Simply put, when you’re learning your first programming language, you don’t have anything to compare it to. The only things that you can focus on are the low-level details—things like syntax, iteration, and data structures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s possible, however, that a learner never graduates from this mindset. A developer could know three, four, or more languages on a functional level, but still be unaware of the concepts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It might be that up until this point, I just didn’t have enough experience to see the bigger picture. Or, though I hate to say, maybe I was the developer who never graduated from the mindset of memorizing low-level details. Or it could’ve been that I &lt;em&gt;was&lt;/em&gt; thinking about concepts, taking apart information, and categorizing knowledge, but I just wasn’t very conscious that the process was taking place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But for whatever reason, when I set out to learn Ruby on Rails, I was acutely aware that I had a new approach to learning. It’s like I had hiked up to a new vantage point. After hacking my way through a forest where all I could see was the vines and foliage, I now stood atop a mountain, with a clear view of where I had been, and the trails I had walked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Armed with my new mindset and approach to learning, I couldn’t wait to start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Michael Hartl’s &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.learnenough.com/ruby-on-rails-6th-edition&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Ruby on Rails Tutorial&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; was the main resource I used when learning Rails. It’s a very impressive learning tool that leads you through building what is essentially a Twitter clone. Unfortunately it’s not free (apparently it used to be—I guess I missed out on that), however I believe that the $31 price tag to gain access to the online version is well worth the investment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also consulted the &lt;a href=&quot;https://api.rubyonrails.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Rails API Docs&lt;/a&gt; a few times when I was feeling curious, or looking for more specific information on a certain Rails module. Thanks to the tutorial, I didn’t really need to dive too much into the docs, but I think it’s always good to get familiar with the source documentation of any language or framework you’re using.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And of course Google, which led me to Stack Overflow, GitHub issues, and random blog posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Setting Up The Environment&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started by downloading Ruby, which brought me my first few lessons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, I learned that Ruby is a programming language! Well, I sort of already knew this, but before this moment some smooth-talker could have convinced me otherwise. You know when you kind of think you know about something, you’ve heard people talk about it, but you don’t &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; know about it? I had never used Ruby, and I had never really had a reason to. So as elementary as it may sound, this is where I started—with the recognition of Ruby as a language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building on that knowledge, I learned that Rails is a web framework that is written in the Ruby programming language. &lt;em&gt;Now we’re getting somewhere!&lt;/em&gt; I’m starting to understand the components that make up Ruby on Rails, and I can relate them to what I already know. Saying Ruby on Rails is &lt;em&gt;kind of&lt;/em&gt; like saying Javascript on React (although that doesn’t quite have the same ring to it, does it?).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My next run in with curiosity—is there a version manager I should be using?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am familiar with &lt;code&gt;nvm&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;pyenv&lt;/code&gt; for managing Node and Python versions, respectively, however the tutorial I was following did not mention any Ruby version manager. I took to the internet and found the highly popular, &lt;code&gt;rbenv&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perfect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With &lt;code&gt;rbenv&lt;/code&gt; in hand, installing Rails came easily and generating a project was a breeze. I found the &lt;code&gt;rails new&lt;/code&gt; command to be powerful, automated, and that it gave me everything I needed to get a project up and running in the browser. It’s always nice to see some sort of early success, even if it’s “Hello world!”, or in this case, “Yay! You’re on Rails!”. I likened it to my experience with &lt;code&gt;npx create-react-app&lt;/code&gt;, which generates a simple React application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Directories and File Structure&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first impression after generating a project—“There’s a lot going on.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generating a Rails application resulted in 46 directories and subdirectories, and 89 files. Some of these files were familiar to me, like a &lt;code&gt;README.md&lt;/code&gt;, and the &lt;code&gt;public/&lt;/code&gt; folder which holds the standard &lt;code&gt;404.html&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;favicon.ico&lt;/code&gt;. But most of everything else was uncharted territory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make things simpler, we can try and strip down the excess and focus on the core of the app. Arguably the most important directory—where you can find the meat and potatoes of the application—is the &lt;code&gt;/app&lt;/code&gt; directory. But even there it’s hard to get an idea of what’s going on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s what you see in the &lt;code&gt;/app&lt;/code&gt; directory after generating a new application—&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;├── app&lt;br/&gt;│   ├── assets&lt;br/&gt;│   │   ├── config&lt;br/&gt;│   │   │   └── manifest.js&lt;br/&gt;│   │   ├── images&lt;br/&gt;│   │   ├── javascripts&lt;br/&gt;│   │   │   ├── application.js&lt;br/&gt;│   │   │   ├── cable.js&lt;br/&gt;│   │   │   └── channels&lt;br/&gt;│   │   └── stylesheets&lt;br/&gt;│   │       └── application.css&lt;br/&gt;│   ├── channels&lt;br/&gt;│   │   └── application_cable&lt;br/&gt;│   │       ├── channel.rb&lt;br/&gt;│   │       └── connection.rb&lt;br/&gt;│   ├── controllers&lt;br/&gt;│   │   ├── application_controller.rb&lt;br/&gt;│   │   └── concerns&lt;br/&gt;│   ├── helpers&lt;br/&gt;│   │   └── application_helper.rb&lt;br/&gt;│   ├── jobs&lt;br/&gt;│   │   └── application_job.rb&lt;br/&gt;│   ├── mailers&lt;br/&gt;│   │   └── application_mailer.rb&lt;br/&gt;│   ├── models&lt;br/&gt;│   │   ├── application_record.rb&lt;br/&gt;│   │   └── concerns&lt;br/&gt;│   └── views&lt;br/&gt;│       └── layouts&lt;br/&gt;│           ├── application.html.erb&lt;br/&gt;│           ├── mailer.html.erb&lt;br/&gt;│           └── mailer.text.erb&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was the dark side of automation. When the work is done for you, you don’t have to understand it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But as I followed the tutorial, I began to pick up on some familiarities. I was at first confused by the &lt;code&gt;.html.erb&lt;/code&gt; file extensions littering the project, but then learned that &lt;code&gt;ERb&lt;/code&gt; is an HTML file with Ruby code embedded in it. That makes sense—I’m familiar with the concept from PHP files, or the JSX that’s used in React. And the Gemfile is the equivalent of other manifest/dependency files that I’m used to such as Node’s &lt;code&gt;package.json&lt;/code&gt; and Python’s &lt;code&gt;requirements.txt&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are just a couple examples, but similar thought processes followed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was certainly a learning curve, and it took me a while to get comfortable, but the Rails directories structure began to make sense over time. And (spoiler alert!) it turns out that this standard directory structure is actually one of my favorite things about Rails. It lets you hop into almost any Rails project and quickly get a sense for what’s going on. This seems to be a common theme with Ruby on Rails—something seems very intimidating or confusing at first, but after getting over the learning curve, it becomes a very useful element of the framework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Model-View-Controller&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had never used the Model-View-Controller design pattern before Rails. I had heard of the idea from Android Studio and Android app development, but hadn’t really gotten to know it too well. It can be thought of as—&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;M&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;odels&lt;/em&gt; for handling data and business logic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;V&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;iews&lt;/em&gt; for handling graphical user interface objects and presentation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;C&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;ontrollers&lt;/em&gt; for handling the user interface and application&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.learnenough.com/ruby-on-rails-4th-edition-tutorial/beginning&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;tutorial I was following&lt;/a&gt; described MVC as an, “…architectural pattern, which enforces a separation between the data in the application (such as user information) and the code used to display it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I was trying to focus on high-level thinking, this high level view of the architecture of Rails applications stuck out as particularly important. This was exactly the type of thing that, if I was being lazy, I could probably skim over and not pay too much attention to. And without ever learning the importance of MVC, I could still probably manage to build Rails applications, &lt;em&gt;but they would be messy&lt;/em&gt;. They wouldn’t work as well, would take longer to develop, and would be harder to maintain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I took my time, took notes, and I let the MVC knowledge settle in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Rails, they’re conveniently separated into files in separate directories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;├── app&lt;br/&gt;│   ├── controllers&lt;br/&gt;│   ├── models&lt;br/&gt;│   └── views&lt;br/&gt;│   └── (several other directories)&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would take some actual, hands-on development for me to get a practical understanding of what MVC meant, because abstract knowledge is often different from practical knowledge, but it was now something that I was aware of as I began programming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later on I would learn of the “skinny controller, fat model” mantra, and since I had already been in the MVC mindset, this actually made a lot of sense to me. I adjusted my development strategy accordingly. If I had ignored the high level architecture, I might have just thrown all of the logic into the controller. I wouldn’t have understood what was meant by “skinny controller, fat model”, my projects would have suffered, and perhaps worst of all, I could have embarrassed myself in front of other developers!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Magic of Rails&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This has been a topic of great discussion for as long as Rails has been around. Ruby on Rails is confusing to newcomers, and it has been described as, “too magical”. I, too, was confused at first. All over the application, there were references to functions or files that I couldn’t find definitions for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rails feels magical because it does a lot for you. It imports things, renders things, passes instance variables from the controller to the view, and more. Just adding a resource to the &lt;code&gt;routes.rb&lt;/code&gt; file (i.e., &lt;code&gt;resources :users&lt;/code&gt;), adds &lt;em&gt;seven&lt;/em&gt; different routes for CRUD operations. There are the reusable &lt;a href=&quot;https://guides.rubyonrails.org/layouts_and_rendering.html#using-partials&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;partials&lt;/a&gt;, which are special types of views indicated by an underscore at the beginning of their filename. And don’t even get me started on the magic involved when &lt;code&gt;has_secure_password&lt;/code&gt; is added to a model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s intimidating! People can, and do, say things like, “if you think Rails is magical, you just haven’t read the documentation.” Kudos to the people who can sit down, read, and understand documentation that easily, but I know that, for me, I had to experience it first hand before it began to make sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But with practice and research, the magic fades away. All of the implicitness, abstraction, and “magic” in Rails serves a purpose. It’s not just there to be confusing. After becoming comfortable, the payoff is that development is fast, time consuming tasks are lifted away, and the developer’s quality of life is high. Being able to utilize the magic of Rails becomes a sort of superpower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That being said, there are potential downsides. Firstly, the steep learning curve is a barrier to entry for those looking to use Rails. There is also the risk, especially when it comes to &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Metaprogramming&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;metaprogramming&lt;/a&gt;, that code can become too complex and errors too hard to trace. Ruby on Rails is a framework where code can do the exact same thing but look so very different, which can make it hard to maintain a project, especially across a development team where multiple individuals are contributing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Ruby&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Ruby language could have its own dedicated post, so I’ll limit myself to the three things that stuck out to me the most.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;h.yz8t8ucged2m&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Everything is an object&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not &lt;em&gt;entirely&lt;/em&gt; true, but it’s mostly true. Ruby is extremely object-oriented. Of course there’s exceptions (like &lt;code&gt;if&lt;/code&gt; statements, or flow control keywords such as &lt;code&gt;break&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;continue&lt;/code&gt;), but still, mostly everything is an object. And objects have classes. And classes have methods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a fun little experiment, we can inspect the nature of the number 1—&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;1.class&lt;/code&gt; =&amp;gt; &lt;code&gt;Integer&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;1.class.superclass&lt;/code&gt; =&amp;gt; &lt;code&gt;Numeric&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;1.class.superclass.superclass&lt;/code&gt; =&amp;gt; &lt;code&gt;Object&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And finally, &lt;code&gt;1.class.superclass.superclass.superclass&lt;/code&gt; =&amp;gt; &lt;code&gt;BasicObject&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same can be done with &lt;code&gt;nil&lt;/code&gt;—&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;nil.class&lt;/code&gt; =&amp;gt; &lt;code&gt;NilClass&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;nil.class.superclass&lt;/code&gt; =&amp;gt; &lt;code&gt;Object&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;nil.class.superclass.superclass&lt;/code&gt; =&amp;gt; &lt;code&gt;BasicObject&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So both the integer, 1, and the nil object, &lt;code&gt;nil&lt;/code&gt;, eventually inherit &lt;code&gt;BasicObject&lt;/code&gt;. And, as it goes, anything that is a subclass of &lt;code&gt;BasicObject&lt;/code&gt; has access to &lt;code&gt;BasicObject&lt;/code&gt;’s methods. I just think that is so cool. Everything has a common ancestor–there’s a sort of &lt;em&gt;oneness&lt;/em&gt; to it all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;h.g1w0ytvrjh3o&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Return values&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Ruby, you can print to the console using &lt;code&gt;puts “Hello World!”&lt;/code&gt;. This alone isn’t very interesting, but if you inspect the behavior of &lt;code&gt;puts&lt;/code&gt;, it shines a light on the inner machinations of Ruby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Calling &lt;code&gt;puts&lt;/code&gt; will print a string, but afterwards the method will return &lt;code&gt;nil&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ruby is strange in this way, and it’s important for a developer to be very aware of this peculiarity. In Ruby, &lt;strong&gt;everything evaluates to a value&lt;/strong&gt;. The &lt;code&gt;puts&lt;/code&gt; method &lt;em&gt;must&lt;/em&gt; return something, so it returns &lt;code&gt;nil&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And in the methods that you’re writing, if there’s not a return call, what ends up being returned will be the &lt;strong&gt;last evaluated piece of code in the method&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This behavior was very different from other languages I’ve used before, and stuck out to me as very important—it’s a fundamental element of Ruby. Not understanding an aspect of a language such as this could cause lots of frustration and heartache further down the road.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blocks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blocks are one of the most confusing, yet most powerful elements of Ruby. They allow you to group expressions, save them to a variable, and even pass them to a method. I’m still getting used to blocks and realizing their usefulness, but overall I feel that they condense a lot of code, and also make code more reusable and extensible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That being said, right now I usually just use blocks for simple iteration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example—&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;10.times { &quot;Howdy y’all&quot; }&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or iterating over an array—&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;[‘h’, ‘o’, ‘w’, ‘d’, ‘y’].each do |letter|&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;puts &quot;#{letter} is in the block&quot;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;end&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;h.3ltf4eh7q3as&quot;&gt;Takeaways—What I Really Like&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I alluded to this earlier, but one of my favorite things about Ruby on Rails is the directory structure. It was overwhelming at first, but now it reveals itself as one of Rails greatest qualities. There’s a homely consistency across different Rails projects, which is a &lt;em&gt;huge&lt;/em&gt; benefit for developers (especially us consultants), who are frequently hopping between different projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another of my favorite aspects of Rails is the passionate community. From such a community stems solid documentation, community support, very good tutorials, and lots of online discussions. The community impact has also seeped into Rails through the form of coding conventions and development styles. These conventions are not required by any means, but they’re so ingrained in Rails as a framework that they can’t help but promote better applications and inspire better development practices. (A lot of the conventions can be found &lt;a href=&quot;http://rubyglasses.blogspot.com/2007/08/actsasgoodstyle.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;in this blog post&lt;/a&gt;, and they include the DRY principle, test-driven design, and utilizing data migrations.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And finally, harnessing the “magic” of Rails has become such a joy during the development process. Developing in Rails now feels faster than any other framework I’ve used before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Takeaways—What’s Not So Good&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The learning curve. There was a significant learning curve. I did not like this. That being said, once I got over the hump, I appreciated almost everything that was originally difficult (in fact, most of which was difficult is now in the &lt;em&gt;What I Really Like&lt;/em&gt; section above!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another thing that I keep finding difficult, which I talked briefly about in the &lt;em&gt;Magic of Rails&lt;/em&gt; section, is that Ruby code can look so different depending on how you choose to write it. There’s optional parenthesis, the option to leave out &lt;code&gt;return&lt;/code&gt; statements, complex blocks, metaprogramming, and more. It’s easy in Ruby on Rails to get a little fancy, and the drawback is that it’s hard to maintain someone else’s code when you see that they got all fancy with things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are ways to remedy this problem—always aim to do things in the most simple way, use tools like &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rubocop-hq/rubocop&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;RuboCop&lt;/a&gt; that enforce syntax rules, follow the Rails coding conventions, and you can maybe even go so far as to have standard coding conventions within a company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;h.fvhrvu5mdxuv&quot;&gt;Fast-forward&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m now a couple months into using Ruby on Rails (thankfully I got the job).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unsurprisingly, there was so still much more to learn about the framework than what I was able to learn over the course of 7 days. And I’m still learning every day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But nowadays, although I don’t have to worry about the time-crunch of an approaching interview, or demonstrating to someone that I know how to learn, I still try to keep the same mindset that I had when I was originally learning Rails—I try to remain aware of what I’m learning, and I aim to get the most out of every learning experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;st-blogpost--cta&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;st-text mb-3&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;mb-0&quot;&gt;Loved the article? Hated it? Didn’t even read it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;st-emphasized&quot;&gt;We’d love to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.simplethread.com/contact&quot; class=&quot;button st-btn -small&quot;&gt;Reach Out&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2020 19:28:28 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Tenhundfeld</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Ruby on Rails in a Week - Simple Thread</og:title>
<og:description>I had 7 days to learn Ruby on Rails. I often think about approaches to learning, and it was time to put my ideas into practice.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.simplethread.com/ruby-on-rails-in-a-week/</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.simplethread.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/time-watch.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.simplethread.com/ruby-on-rails-in-a-week/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>My Resignation from the Intercept</title>
<link>https://greenwald.substack.com/p/my-resignation-from-the-intercept</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://greenwald.substack.com/p/my-resignation-from-the-intercept</guid>
<description>&lt;a class=&quot;image-link image2 image2-971-1456&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://cdn.substack.com/image/fetch/f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fbucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2Fa4a7aa1e-2a2d-4c88-ac21-57f6c1d1145c_4809x3206.jpeg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.substack.com/image/fetch/w_1456,c_limit,f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fbucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2Fa4a7aa1e-2a2d-4c88-ac21-57f6c1d1145c_4809x3206.jpeg&quot; data-attrs=&quot;{&amp;quot;src&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://bucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com/public/images/a4a7aa1e-2a2d-4c88-ac21-57f6c1d1145c_4809x3206.jpeg&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;height&amp;quot;:971,&amp;quot;width&amp;quot;:1456,&amp;quot;resizeWidth&amp;quot;:null,&amp;quot;bytes&amp;quot;:1622628,&amp;quot;alt&amp;quot;:null,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:null,&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;image/jpeg&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;href&amp;quot;:null}&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Today I sent&lt;/strong&gt; my intention to resign from The Intercept, the news outlet I &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/erik-wemple/wp/2013/10/15/glenn-greenwald-bolts-the-guardian-for-some-fabulous-media-organization/&quot;&gt;co-founded in 2013&lt;/a&gt; with Jeremy Scahill and Laura Poitras, as well as from its parent company First Look Media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final, precipitating cause is that The Intercept’s editors, in violation of my contractual right of editorial freedom, censored an article I wrote this week, refusing to publish it unless I remove all sections critical of Democratic presidential candidate Joe Biden, the candidate vehemently supported by all New-York-based Intercept editors involved in this effort at suppression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The censored article, based on recently revealed emails and witness testimony, raised critical questions about Biden’s conduct. Not content to simply prevent publication of this article at the media outlet I co-founded, these Intercept editors also demanded that I refrain from exercising a separate contractual right to publish this article with any other publication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had no objection to their disagreement with my views of what this Biden evidence shows: as a last-ditch attempt to avoid being censored, I encouraged them to air their disagreements with me by writing their own articles that critique my perspectives and letting readers decide who is right, the way any confident and healthy media outlet would. But modern media outlets do not air dissent; they quash it. So censorship of my article, rather than engagement with it, was the path these Biden-supporting editors chose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The censored article will be published on this page shortly (it is now published &lt;a href=&quot;https://greenwald.substack.com/p/article-on-joe-and-hunter-biden-censored&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, and the emails with Intercept editors showing the censorship are &lt;a href=&quot;https://greenwald.substack.com/p/emails-with-intercept-editors-showing&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;). My letter of intent to resign, which I sent this morning to First Look Media’s President Michael Bloom, is published below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of now, I will be publishing my journalism here on Substack, where numerous other journalists, including my good friend, the great intrepid reporter Matt Taibbi, have come in order to practice journalism free of the increasingly repressive climate that is engulfing national mainstream media outlets across the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was not an easy choice: I am voluntarily sacrificing the support of a large institution and guaranteed salary in exchange for nothing other than a belief that there are enough people who believe in the virtues of independent journalism and the need for free discourse who will be willing to support my work by subscribing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like anyone with young children, a family and numerous obligations, I do this with some trepidation, but also with the conviction that there is no other choice. I could not sleep at night knowing that I allowed any institution to censor what I want to say and believe — least of all a media outlet I co-founded with the explicit goal of ensuring this never happens to other journalists, let alone to me, let alone because I have written an article critical of a powerful Democratic politician vehemently supported by the editors in the imminent national election.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the pathologies, illiberalism, and repressive mentality that led to the bizarre spectacle of my being censored by my own media outlet are ones that are by no means unique to The Intercept. These are the viruses that have contaminated virtually every mainstream center-left political organization, academic institution, and newsroom. I began writing about politics fifteen years ago with the goal of combatting media propaganda and repression, and — regardless of the risks involved — simply cannot accept any situation, no matter how secure or lucrative, that forces me to submit my journalism and right of free expression to its suffocating constraints and dogmatic dictates.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;From the time&lt;/strong&gt; I began writing about politics in 2005, journalistic freedom and editorial independence have been sacrosanct to me. Fifteen years ago, I &lt;a href=&quot;http://glenngreenwald.blogspot.com/&quot;&gt;created a blog&lt;/a&gt; on the free Blogspot software when I was still working as a lawyer: not with any hopes or plans of starting a new career as a journalist, but just as a citizen concerned about what I was seeing with the War on Terror and civil liberties, and wanting to express what I believed needed to be heard. It was a labor of love, based in an ethos of cause and conviction, dependent upon a guarantee of complete editorial freedom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It thrived because the readership I built knew that, even when they disagreed with particular views I was expressing, I was a free and independent voice, unwedded to any faction, controlled by nobody, endeavoring to be as honest as possible about what I was seeing, and always curious about the wisdom of seeing things differently. The title I chose for that blog, “Unclaimed Territory,” reflected that spirit of liberation from captivity to any fixed political or intellectual dogma or institutional constraints.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Salon offered me a job as a columnist in 2007, and then again when the Guardian did the same in 2012, I accepted their offers on the condition that I would have the right, except in narrowly defined situations (such as articles that could create legal liability for the news outlet), to publish my articles and columns directly to the internet without censorship, advanced editorial interference, or any other intervention permitted or approval needed. Both outlets revamped their publication system to accommodate this condition, and over the many years I worked with them, they always honored those commitments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-24545344&quot;&gt;left the Guardian&lt;/a&gt; at the height of the Snowden reporting in 2013 in order to create a new media outlet, I did not do so, needless to say, in order to impose upon myself &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; constraints and restrictions on my journalistic independence. The exact opposite was true: the intended core innovation of The Intercept, above all else, was to create a new media outlets where all talented, responsible journalists would enjoy the same right of editorial freedom I had always insisted upon for myself. As I told former New York Times Executive Editor Bill Keller in a 2013 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2013/10/28/opinion/a-conversation-in-lieu-of-a-column.html&quot;&gt;exchange we had in The New York Times&lt;/a&gt; about my critiques of mainstream journalism and the idea behind The Intercept: “editors should be there to empower and enable strong, highly factual, aggressive adversarial journalism, not to serve as roadblocks to neuter or suppress the journalism.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the three of us as co-founders made the decision early on that we would not attempt to manage the day-to-day operations of the new outlet, so that we could instead focus on our journalism, we negotiated the right of approval for senior editors and, especially the editor-in-chief. The central responsibility of the person holding that title was to implement, in close consultation with us, the unique journalistic vision and journalistic values on which we founded this new media outlet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chief among those values was editorial freedom, the protection of a journalist’s right to speak in an honest voice, and the airing rather than suppression of dissent from mainstream orthodoxies and even collegial disagreements with one another. That would be accomplished, above all else, by ensuring that journalists, once they fulfilled the first duty of factual accuracy and journalistic ethics, would be not just permitted but encouraged to express political and ideological views that deviated from mainstream orthodoxy and those of their own editors; to express themselves in their own voice of passion and conviction rather stuffed into the corporatized, contrived tone of artificial objectivity, above-it-all omnipotence; and to be completely free of anyone else’s dogmatic beliefs or ideological agenda — including those of the three co-founders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The current iteration&lt;/strong&gt; of The Intercept is completely unrecognizable when compared to that original vision. Rather than offering a venue for airing dissent, marginalized voices and unheard perspectives, it is rapidly becoming just another media outlet with mandated ideological and partisan loyalties, a rigid and narrow range of permitted viewpoints (ranging from establishment liberalism to soft leftism, but always anchored in ultimate support for the Democratic Party), a deep fear of offending hegemonic cultural liberalism and center-left Twitter luminaries, and an overarching need to secure the approval and admiration of the very mainstream media outlets we created The Intercept to oppose, critique and subvert.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result, it is a rare event indeed when a radical freelance voice unwelcome in mainstream precincts is published in The Intercept. Outside reporters or writers with no claim to mainstream acceptability — exactly the people we set out to amplify — have almost no chance of being published. It is even rarer for The Intercept to publish content that would not fit very comfortably in at least a dozen or more center-left publications of similar size which pre-dated its founding, from Mother Jones to Vox and even MSNBC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Courage is required to step out of line, to question and poke at those pieties most sacred in one’s own milieu, but fear of alienating the guardians of liberal orthodoxy, especially on Twitter, is the predominant attribute of The Intercept’s New-York based editorial leadership team. As a result, The Intercept has all but abandoned its core mission of challenging and poking at, rather than appeasing and comforting, the institutions and guardians most powerful in its cultural and political circles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making all of this worse, The Intercept — while gradually excluding the co-founders from any role in its editorial mission or direction, and making one choice after the next to which I vocally objected as a betrayal of our core mission — continued publicly to trade on my name in order to raise funds for journalism it knew I did not support. It purposely allowed the perception to fester that I was the person responsible for its journalistic mistakes in order to ensure that blame for those mistakes was heaped on me rather than the editors who were consolidating control and were responsible for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most egregious, but by no means only, example of exploiting my name to evade responsibility was the Reality Winner debacle. As The New York Times &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2020/09/13/business/media/the-intercept-source-reality-winner.html&quot;&gt;recently reported&lt;/a&gt;, that was a story in which I had no involvement whatsoever. While based in Brazil, I was never asked to work on the documents which Winner sent to our New York newsroom with no request that any specific journalist work on them. I did not even learn of the existence of that document until very shortly prior to its publication. The person who oversaw, edited and controlled that story was Betsy Reed, which was how it should be given the magnitude and complexity of that reporting and her position as editor-in-chief.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was Intercept editors who pressured the story’s reporters to quickly send those documents for authentication to the government — because they was eager to prove to mainstream media outlets and prominent liberals that The Intercept was willing to get on board the Russiagate train. They wanted to counter-act the perception, created by my articles expressing skepticism about the central claims of that scandal, that The Intercept had stepped out of line on a story of high importance to U.S. liberalism and even the left. That craving — to secure the approval of the very mainstream media outlets we set out to counteract — was the root cause for the speed and recklessness with which that document from Winner was handled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But The Intercept, to this very day, has refused to provide any public accounting of what happened in the Reality Winner story: to explain who the editors were who made mistakes and why any of it happened. As the New York Times article makes clear, that refusal persists to this very day notwithstanding vocal demands from myself, Scahill, Laura Poitras and others that The Intercept, as an institution that demands transparency from others, has the obligation to provide it for itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason for this silence and this cover-up is obvious: accounting to the public about what happened with the Reality Winner story would reveal who the actual editors are who are responsible for that deeply embarrassing newsroom failure, and that would negate their ability to continue to hide behind me and let the public continue to assume that I was the person at fault for a reporting process from which I was completely excluded from the start. That is just one example illustrating the frustrating dilemma of having a newsroom exploit my name, work and credibility when it is convenient to do so, while increasingly denying me any opportunity to influence its journalistic mission and editorial direction, all while pursuing an editorial mission completely anathema to what I believe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Despite all of this&lt;/strong&gt;, I did not want to leave The Intercept. As it deteriorated and abandoned its original mission, I reasoned to myself — perhaps rationalized — that as long as The Intercept at least continued to provide me the resources to personally do the journalism I believe in, and never to interfere in or impede my editorial freedom, I could swallow everything else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the brute censorship this week of my article — about the Hunter Biden materials and Joe Biden’s conduct regarding Ukraine and China, as well my critique of the media’s rank-closing attempt, in a deeply unholy union with Silicon Valley and the “intelligence community,” to suppress its revelations — eroded the last justification I could cling to for staying. It meant that not only does this media outlet not provide the editorial freedom to &lt;em&gt;other journalists&lt;/em&gt;, as I had so hopefully envisioned seven years ago, but now no longer even provides it to me. In the days heading into a presidential election, I am somehow silenced from expressing any views that random editors in New York find disagreeable, and now somehow have to conform my writing and reporting to cater to their partisan desires and eagerness to elect specific candidates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To say that such censorship is a red line for me, a situation I would never accept no matter the cost, is an understatement. It is astonishing to me, but also a reflection of our current discourse and illiberal media environment, that I have been silenced about Joe Biden by my own media outlet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Numerous other episodes were also contributing causes to my decision to leave: the Reality Winner cover-up; the decision to hang Lee Fang out to dry and even force &lt;em&gt;him&lt;/em&gt; to apologize when a colleague tried to destroy his reputation by publicly, baselessly and repeatedly branding him a racist; its refusal to report on the daily proceedings of the Assange extradition hearing because the freelance reporter doing an outstanding job was politically distasteful; its utter lack of editorial standards when it comes to viewpoints or reporting that flatter the beliefs of its liberal base (The Intercept published some of the most credulous and false affirmations of maximalist Russiagate madness, and, horrifyingly, took the lead in falsely branding the Hunter Biden archive as “Russian disinformation” by mindlessly and uncritically citing — of all things — a letter by former CIA officials that contained this baseless insinuation).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know it sounds banal to say, but — even with all of these frustrations and failures — I am leaving, and writing this, with genuine sadness, not fury. That news outlet is something I and numerous close friends and colleagues poured an enormous amount of our time, energy, passion and love into building.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Intercept has done great work. Its editorial leaders and First Look’s managers steadfastly supported the &lt;a href=&quot;https://apnews.com/0e998ebedbd64f6d868a3fa570ed1f6c&quot;&gt;difficult and dangerous reporting&lt;/a&gt; I did last year with my brave young colleagues at The Intercept Brasil to expose corruption at the highest levels of the Bolsonaro government, and stood behind us as we endured &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2020/02/06/world/americas/greenwald-charges-dropped-brazil.html&quot;&gt;threats of death and imprisonment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It continues to employ some of my closest friends, outstanding journalists whose work — when it overcomes editorial resistance — produces nothing but the highest admiration from me: Jeremy Scahill, Lee Fang, Murtaza Hussain, Naomi Klein, Ryan Grim and others. And I have no personal animus for anyone there, nor any desire to hurt it as an institution. Betsy Reed is an exceptionally smart editor and a very good human being with whom I developed a close and valuable friendship. And Pierre Omidyar, the original funder and publisher of First Look, always honored his personal commitment never to interfere in our editorial process even when I was publishing articles directly at odds with his strongly held views and even when I was attacking other institutions he was funding. I’m not leaving out of vengeance or personal conflict but out of conviction and cause.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And none of the critiques I have voiced about The Intercept are unique to it. To the contrary: these are the raging battles over free expression and the right of dissent raging within every major cultural, political and journalistic institution. That’s the crisis that journalism, and more broadly values of liberalism, faces. Our discourse is becoming increasingly intolerant of dissenting views, and our culture is demanding more and more submission to prevailing orthodoxies imposed by self-anointed monopolists of Truth and Righteousness, backed up by armies of online enforcement mobs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And nothing is crippled by that trend more severely than journalism, which, above all else, requires the ability of journalists to offend and anger power centers, question or reject sacred pieties, unearth facts that reflect negatively even on (&lt;em&gt;especially on&lt;/em&gt;) the most beloved and powerful figures, and highlight corruption no matter where it is found and regardless of who is benefited or injured by its exposure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prior to the extraordinary&lt;/strong&gt; experience of being censored this week by my own news outlet, I had already been exploring the possibility of creating a new media outlet. I have spent a couple of months in active discussions with some of the most interesting, independent and vibrant journalists, writers and commentators across the political spectrum about the feasibility of securing financing for a new outlet that would be designed to combat these trends. The first two paragraphs of our working document reads as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;19&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American media is gripped in a polarized culture war that is forcing journalism to conform to tribal, groupthink narratives that are often divorced from the truth and cater to perspectives that are not reflective of the broader public but instead a minority of hyper-partisan elites. The need to conform to highly restrictive, artificial cultural narratives and partisan identities has created a repressive and illiberal environment in which vast swaths of news and reporting either do not happen or are presented through the most skewed and reality-detached lens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With nearly all major media institutions captured to some degree by this dynamic, a deep need exists for media that is untethered and free to transgress the boundaries of this polarized culture war and address a demand from a public that is starved for media that doesn’t play for a side but instead pursues lines of reporting, thought, and inquiry wherever they lead, without fear of violating cultural pieties or elite orthodoxies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have definitely not relinquished hope that this ambitious project can be accomplished. And I theoretically could have stayed at The Intercept until then, guaranteeing a stable and secure income for my family by swallowing the dictates of my new censors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I would be deeply ashamed if I did that, and believe I would be betraying my own principles and convictions that I urge others to follow. So in the meantime, I have decided to follow in the footsteps of numerous other writers and journalists who have been expelled from increasingly repressive journalistic precincts for various forms of heresy and dissent and who have sought refuge here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope to exploit the freedom this new platform offers not only to continue to publish the independent and hard-hitting investigative journalism and candid analysis and opinion writing that my readers have come to expect, but also to develop a podcast, and continue the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLW0Gy9pTgVntTChFgj0xwMrsc1GO32-DZ&amp;amp;app=desktop&quot;&gt;YouTube program&lt;/a&gt;, “System Update,” I launched earlier this year in partnership with The Intercept.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To do that, to make this viable, I will need your support: people who are able to subscribe and sign up for the newsletter attached to this platform will enable my work to thrive and still be heard, perhaps even more so than before. I began my journalism career by depending on my readers’ willingness to support independent journalism which they believe is necessary to sustain. It is somewhat daunting at this point in my life, but also very exciting, to return to that model where one answers only to the public a journalist should be serving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;* * * * * * * *&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LETTER OF INTENT TO RESIGN&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-------- Forwarded Message --------&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Subject: ResignationDate: Thu, 29 Oct 2020 10:20:54 -0300From: Glenn Greenwald &amp;lt;xxxxxxxx@theintercept.com&amp;gt;To: Michael Bloom &amp;lt;xxxxxxxxx@firstlook.media&amp;gt;, Betsy Reed &amp;lt;xxxxxxx@theintercept.com&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Michael -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am writing to advise you that I have decided that I will be resigning from First Look Media (FLM) and The Intercept.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The precipitating (but by no means only) cause is that The Intercept is attempting to censor my articles in violation of both my contract and fundamental principles of editorial freedom. The latest and perhaps most egregious example is an opinion column I wrote this week which, five days before the presidential election, is critical of Joe Biden, the candidate who happens to be vigorously supported by all of the Intercept editors in New York who are imposing the censorship and refusing to publish the article unless I agree to remove all of the sections critical of the candidate they want to win. All of that violates the right in my contract with FLM to publish articles without editorial interference except in very narrow circumstances that plainly do not apply here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Worse, The Intercept editors in New York, not content to censor publication of my article at the Intercept, are also demanding that I not exercise my separate contractual right with FLM regarding articles I have written but which FLM does not want to publish itself. Under my contract, I have the right to publish any articles FLM rejects with another publication. But Intercept editors in New York are demanding I not only accept their censorship of my article at The Intercept, but also refrain from publishing it with any other journalistic outlet, and are using thinly disguised lawyer-crafted threats to coerce me not to do so (proclaiming it would be “detrimental” to The Intercept if I published it elsewhere).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been extremely disenchanted and saddened by the editorial direction of The Intercept under its New York leadership for quite some time. The publication we founded without those editors back in 2014 now bears absolutely no resemblance to what we set out to build -- not in content, structure, editorial mission or purpose. I have grown embarrassed to have my name used as a fund-raising tool to support what it is doing and for editors to use me as a shield to hide behind to avoid taking responsibility for their mistakes (including, but not only, with the Reality Winner debacle, for which I was publicly blamed despite having no role in it, while the editors who actually were responsible for those mistakes stood by silently, allowing me to be blamed for their errors and then covering-up any public accounting of what happened, knowing that such transparency would expose their own culpability).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But all this time, as things worsened, I reasoned that as long as The Intercept remained a place where my own right of journalistic independence was not being infringed, I could live with all of its other flaws. But now, not even that minimal but foundational right is being honored for my own journalism, suppressed by an increasingly authoritarian, fear-driven, repressive editorial team in New York bent on imposing their own ideological and partisan preferences on all writers while ensuring that nothing is published at The Intercept that contradicts their own narrow, homogenous ideological and partisan views: &lt;em&gt;exactly&lt;/em&gt; what The Intercept, more than any other goal, was created to prevent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have asked my lawyer to get in touch with FLM to discuss how best to terminate my contract. Thank you -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glenn Greenwald&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2020 17:44:38 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>yasp</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>My Resignation From The Intercept</og:title>
<og:description>The same trends of repression, censorship and ideological homogeneity plaguing the national press generally have engulfed the media outlet I co-founded, culminating in censorship of my own articles.</og:description>
<og:image>https://cdn.substack.com/image/fetch/h_600,c_limit,f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fbucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2Fa4a7aa1e-2a2d-4c88-ac21-57f6c1d1145c_4809x3206.jpeg</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://greenwald.substack.com/p/my-resignation-from-the-intercept</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Laptev Sea hasn&amp;#039;t frozen</title>
<link>https://www.economist.com/graphic-detail/2020/10/28/more-bad-news-for-the-arctic-the-laptev-sea-hasnt-frozen</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.economist.com/graphic-detail/2020/10/28/more-bad-news-for-the-arctic-the-laptev-sea-hasnt-frozen</guid>
<description>&lt;aside class=&quot;article__aside&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;time itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/DateTime&quot; datetime=&quot;2020-10-28T00:00:00Z&quot; class=&quot;article__dateline-datetime&quot;&gt;Oct 28th 2020&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;article__body-text&quot;&gt;THE LAPTEV SEA, nestled between the north coast of Siberia and Russia’s New Siberian Islands, is known as the birthplace of ice. Every year, ice forms along its coasts in the autumn before being pushed west across the Arctic Ocean to Greenland and Norway’s Svalbard archipelago, where it breaks up come spring. Every year, that is, until this one. For the first time since records began, the Laptev Sea has not begun to freeze by late October (see chart). This is only the latest example of how climate change is rapidly transforming the Arctic. Scientists worry that it could have damaging knock-on effects across the region.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;article__body-text-image&quot; readability=&quot;51&quot;&gt;
&lt;div itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemprop=&quot;image&quot; itemtype=&quot;https://schema.org/ImageObject&quot; data-slim=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; src=&quot;https://www.economist.com/img/b/608/644/90/sites/default/files/20201031_WOM906.png&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.economist.com/img/b/200/212/90/sites/default/files/20201031_WOM906.png 200w,https://www.economist.com/img/b/300/318/90/sites/default/files/20201031_WOM906.png 300w,https://www.economist.com/img/b/400/424/90/sites/default/files/20201031_WOM906.png 400w,https://www.economist.com/img/b/600/636/90/sites/default/files/20201031_WOM906.png 600w,https://www.economist.com/img/b/640/678/90/sites/default/files/20201031_WOM906.png 640w,https://www.economist.com/img/b/800/847/90/sites/default/files/20201031_WOM906.png 800w,https://www.economist.com/img/b/1000/1059/90/sites/default/files/20201031_WOM906.png 1000w,https://www.economist.com/img/b/1280/1356/90/sites/default/files/20201031_WOM906.png 1280w&quot; sizes=&quot;300px&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;article__body-text&quot;&gt;The delayed freeze is the result of an unprecedented heatwave in Siberia in the first half of the year. The record high temperatures, in addition to fuelling an outbreak of Arctic wildfires that have burned an area the size of Greece, have warmed ocean waters by more than 5°C. That heat has not yet dissipated, preventing the Laptev Sea from freezing on schedule. The peculiar weather is no coincidence. According to the World Weather Attribution project, a team of scientists that analyses possible links between climate change and extreme weather events, Siberia’s scorching temperatures would not have been possible without climate change. Changes to Atlantic currents, also the result of climate change, may also be contributing to the lack of ice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;article__body-text&quot;&gt;The Laptev Sea’s woes are part of a broader transformation in the region. In the last four decades, the amount of so-called multi-year ice—sea ice that survives the warmer months—in the Arctic has been reduced by a half. Scientists expect that soon there may be none at all. What is happening in the Laptev Sea is a grim foreshadowing of this. In the 1980s, multi-year ice covered two-thirds of the sea; these days ice can be absent for months at a time. This causes ocean temperatures to rise further, as open water retains more heat than ice. It also plays havoc with the Arctic’s delicate ecosystem and is likely to threaten Arctic plankton, which play an important role in absorbing carbon dioxide. The open water of the Laptev Sea is another warning of the consequences of a fast-warming world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;layout-article-links&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;ds-actioned-link ds-actioned-link--reuse-this-content&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://s100.copyright.com/AppDispatchServlet?publisherName=economist&amp;amp;publication=economist&amp;amp;title=More%20bad%20news%20for%20the%20Arctic%3A%20the%20Laptev%20Sea%20hasn%E2%80%99t%20frozen&amp;amp;publicationDate=2020-10-28&amp;amp;contentID=%2Fcontent%2Fj3vq86nd45hc044dckk092uhlbpio2lj&amp;amp;type=A&amp;amp;orderBeanReset=TRUE&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Reuse this content&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;ds-actioned-link ds-actioned-link--the-trust-project&quot; href=&quot;https://www.economist.com/about-the-economist&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;The Trust Project&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2020 16:48:26 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>xenocratus</dc:creator>
<og:title>More bad news for the Arctic: the Laptev Sea hasn’t frozen</og:title>
<og:type>Article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.economist.com/graphic-detail/2020/10/28/more-bad-news-for-the-arctic-the-laptev-sea-hasnt-frozen</og:url>
<og:description>Yet another symptom of man-made climate change</og:description>
<og:image>https://www.economist.com/img/b/1280/755/90/sites/default/files/20201031_WOC015.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.economist.com/graphic-detail/2020/10/28/more-bad-news-for-the-arctic-the-laptev-sea-hasnt-frozen</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>MDN Web Docs evolves: Lowdown on the upcoming new platform</title>
<link>https://hacks.mozilla.org/2020/10/mdn-web-docs-evolves-lowdown-on-the-upcoming-new-platform/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://hacks.mozilla.org/2020/10/mdn-web-docs-evolves-lowdown-on-the-upcoming-new-platform/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The time has come for &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mdn/kuma&quot;&gt;Kuma&lt;/a&gt; — the platform that powers MDN Web Docs — to evolve. For quite some time now, the MDN developer team has been planning a radical platform change, and we are ready to start sharing the details of it. The question on your lips might be “What does a Kuma evolve into? A KumaMaMa?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-46679&quot; src=&quot;https://2r4s9p1yi1fa2jd7j43zph8r-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/files/2020/10/kuma-preevolve.png&quot; alt=&quot;What? Kuma is evolving!&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;677&quot; srcset=&quot;https://hacks.mozilla.org/files/2020/10/kuma-preevolve.png 900w, https://hacks.mozilla.org/files/2020/10/kuma-preevolve-250x188.png 250w, https://hacks.mozilla.org/files/2020/10/kuma-preevolve-500x376.png 500w, https://hacks.mozilla.org/files/2020/10/kuma-preevolve-768x578.png 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 900px) 100vw, 900px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those of you not so into Pokémon, the question might instead be “How exactly is MDN changing, and how does it affect MDN users and contributors”?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For general users, the answer is easy — there will be very little change to how we serve the great content you use everyday to learn and do your jobs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For contributors, the answer is a bit more complex.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The changes in a nutshell&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, we are updating the platform to move the content from a MySQL database to being hosted in a GitHub repository (codename: Project &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yari&quot;&gt;Yari&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-46691&quot; src=&quot;https://2r4s9p1yi1fa2jd7j43zph8r-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/files/2020/10/yari-postevolve.png&quot; alt=&quot;Congratulations! Your Kuma evolved into Yari&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;678&quot; srcset=&quot;https://hacks.mozilla.org/files/2020/10/yari-postevolve.png 900w, https://hacks.mozilla.org/files/2020/10/yari-postevolve-250x188.png 250w, https://hacks.mozilla.org/files/2020/10/yari-postevolve-500x377.png 500w, https://hacks.mozilla.org/files/2020/10/yari-postevolve-768x579.png 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 900px) 100vw, 900px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main advantages of this approach are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Less developer maintenance burden: The existing (Kuma) platform is complex and hard to maintain. Adding new features is very difficult. The update will vastly simplify the platform code — we estimate that we can remove a significant chunk of the existing codebase, meaning easier maintenance and contributions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Better contribution workflow: We will be using GitHub’s contribution tools and features, essentially moving MDN from a Wiki model to a pull request (PR) model. This is so much better for contribution, allowing for intelligent linting, mass edits, and inclusion of MDN docs in whatever workflows you want to add it to (you can edit MDN source files directly in your favorite code editor).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Better community building: At the moment, MDN content edits are published instantly, and then reverted if they are not suitable. This is really bad for community relations. With a PR model, we can review edits and provide feedback, actually having conversations with contributors, building relationships with them, and helping them learn.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved front-end architecture: The existing MDN platform has a number of front-end inconsistencies and accessibility issues, which we’ve wanted to tackle for some time. The move to a new, simplified platform gives us a perfect opportunity to fix such issues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The exact form of the platform is yet to be finalized, and we want to involve you, the community, in helping to provide ideas and test the new contribution workflow! We will have a beta version of the new platform ready for testing on November 2, and the first release will happen on December 14.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Simplified back-end platform&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are replacing the current MDN Wiki platform with a &lt;a href=&quot;https://jamstack.org/&quot;&gt;JAMStack&lt;/a&gt; approach, which publishes the content managed in a GitHub repo. This has a number of advantages over the existing Wiki platform, and is something we’ve been considering for a number of years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we discuss our new approach, let’s review the Wiki model so we can better understand the changes we’re making.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Current MDN Wiki platform&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-46687&quot; src=&quot;https://2r4s9p1yi1fa2jd7j43zph8r-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/files/2020/10/old-platform.png&quot; alt=&quot;workflow diagram of the old kuma platform&quot; width=&quot;624&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; srcset=&quot;https://hacks.mozilla.org/files/2020/10/old-platform.png 624w, https://hacks.mozilla.org/files/2020/10/old-platform-250x180.png 250w, https://hacks.mozilla.org/files/2020/10/old-platform-500x361.png 500w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 624px) 100vw, 624px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s important to note that both content contributors (writers) and content viewers (readers) are served via the same architecture. That architecture has to accommodate both use cases, even though more than 99% of our traffic comprises document page requests from readers. Currently, when a document page is requested, the latest version of the document is read from our MySQL database, rendered into its final HTML form, and returned to the user via the CDN.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That document page is stored and served from the CDN’s cache for the next 5 minutes, so subsequent requests — as long as they’re within that 5-minute window — will be served directly by the CDN. That caching period of 5 minutes is kept deliberately short, mainly due to the fact that we need to accommodate the needs of the writers. If we only had to accommodate the needs of the readers, we could significantly increase the caching period and serve our document pages more quickly, while at the same time reducing the workload on our backend servers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’ll also notice that because MDN is a Wiki platform, we’re responsible for managing all of the content, and tasks like storing document revisions, displaying the revision history of a document, displaying differences between revisions, and so on. Currently, the MDN development team maintains a large chunk of code devoted to just these kinds of tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;New MDN platform&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-46683&quot; src=&quot;https://2r4s9p1yi1fa2jd7j43zph8r-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/files/2020/10/new-platform.png&quot; alt=&quot;workflow diagram of the new yari platform&quot; width=&quot;624&quot; height=&quot;492&quot; srcset=&quot;https://hacks.mozilla.org/files/2020/10/new-platform.png 624w, https://hacks.mozilla.org/files/2020/10/new-platform-250x197.png 250w, https://hacks.mozilla.org/files/2020/10/new-platform-500x394.png 500w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 624px) 100vw, 624px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the new &lt;a href=&quot;https://jamstack.org/&quot;&gt;JAMStack&lt;/a&gt; approach, the writers are served separately from the readers. The writers manage the document content via &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mdn/content&quot;&gt;a GitHub repository&lt;/a&gt; and pull request model, while the readers are served document pages more quickly and efficiently via pre-rendered document pages served from S3 via a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Content_delivery_network&quot;&gt;CDN&lt;/a&gt; (which will have a much longer caching period). The document content from our GitHub repository will be rendered and deployed to S3 on a daily basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’ll notice, from the diagram above, that even with this new approach, we still have a Kubernetes cluster with Django-based services relying on a relational database. The important thing to remember is that this part of the system is no longer involved with the document content. Its scope has been dramatically reduced, and it now exists solely to provide APIs related to user accounts (e.g. login) and search.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This separation of concerns has multiple benefits, the most important three of which are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;First, the document pages are served to readers in the simplest, quickest, and most efficient way possible. That’s really important, because 99% of MDN’s traffic is for readers, and worldwide performance is fundamental to the user experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Second, because we’re using GitHub to manage our document content, we can take advantage of the world-class functionality that GitHub has to offer as a content management system, and we no longer have to support the large body of code related to our current Wiki platform. It can simply be deleted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Third, and maybe less obvious, is that this new approach brings more power to the platform. We can, for example, perform automated linting and testing on each content pull request, which allows us to better control quality and security.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;New contribution workflow&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because MDN content is soon to be contained in a GitHub repo, the contribution workflow will change significantly. You will no longer be able to click &lt;em&gt;Edit&lt;/em&gt; on a page, make and save a change, and have it show up nearly immediately on the page. You’ll also no longer be able to do your edits in a WYSIWYG editor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, you’ll need to use git/GitHub tooling to make changes, submit pull requests, then wait for changes to be merged, the new build to be deployed, etc. For very simple changes such as fixing typos or adding new paragraphs, this may seem like a step back — Kuma is certainly convenient for such edits, and for non-developer contributors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, making a simple change is arguably no more complex with Yari. You can use the GitHub UI’s edit feature to directly edit a source file and then submit a PR, meaning that you don’t have to be a git genius to contribute simple fixes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more complex changes, you’ll need to use the git CLI tool, or a GUI tool like &lt;a href=&quot;https://desktop.github.com/&quot;&gt;GitHub Desktop&lt;/a&gt;, but then again git is such a ubiquitous tool in the web industry that it is safe to say that if you are interested in editing MDN, you will probably need to know git to some degree for your career or course. You could use this as a good opportunity to learn git if you don’t know it already! On top of that there is a file system structure to learn, and some new tools/commands to get used to, but nothing terribly complex.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another possible challenge to mention is that you won’t have a WYSIWYG to instantly see what the page looks like as you add your content, and in addition you’ll be editing raw HTML, at least initially (we are talking about converting the content to markdown eventually, but that is a bit of a ways off). Again, this sounds like a step backwards, but we are providing a tool inside the repo so that you can locally build and preview the finished page to make sure it looks right before you submit your pull request.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at the advantages now, consider that making MDN content available as a GitHub repo is a very powerful thing. We no longer have spam content live on the site, with us then having to revert the changes after the fact. You are also free to edit MDN content in whatever way suits you best — your favorite IDE or code editor — and you can add MDN documentation into your preferred toolchain (and write your own tools to edit your MDN editing experience). A lot of engineers have told us in the past that they’d be much happier to contribute to MDN documentation if they were able to submit pull requests, and not have to use a WYSIWYG!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are also looking into a powerful toolset that will allow us to enhance the reviewing process, for example as part of a CI process — automatically detecting and closing spam PRs, and as mentioned earlier on, linting pages once they’ve been edited, and delivering feedback to editors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having MDN in a GitHub repo also offers much easier mass edits; blanket content changes have previously been very difficult.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, the “time to live” should be acceptable — we are aiming to have a quick turnaround on the reviews, and the deployment process will be repeated every 24 hours. We think that your changes should be live on the site in 48 hours as a worst case scenario.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Better community building&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently MDN is not a very lively place in terms of its community. We have a fairly active &lt;a href=&quot;https://discourse.mozilla.org/c/mdn/learn/250&quot;&gt;learning forum&lt;/a&gt; where people ask beginner coding questions and seek help with assessments, but there is not really an active place where MDN staff and volunteers get together regularly to discuss documentation needs and contributions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part of this is down to our contribution model. When you edit an MDN page, either your contribution is accepted and you don’t hear anything, or your contribution is reverted and you … don’t hear anything. You’ll only know either way by looking to see if your edit sticks, is counter-edited, or is reverted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This doesn’t strike us as very friendly, and I think you’ll probably agree. When we move to a git PR model, the MDN community will be able to provide hands-on assistance in helping people to get their contributions right — offering assistance as we review their PRs (and offering automated help too, as mentioned previously) — and also thanking people for their help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’ll also be much easier for contributors to show how many contributions they’ve made, and we’ll be adding in-page links to allow people to file an issue on a specific page or even go straight to the source on GitHub and fix it themselves, if a problem is encountered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of finding a good place to chat about MDN content, you can join the discussion on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://chat.mozilla.org/#/room/#mdn:mozilla.org&quot;&gt;MDN Web Docs chat room&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.mozilla.org/Matrix&quot;&gt;Matrix&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Improved front-end architecture&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The old Kuma architecture has a number of front-end issues. Historically we have lacked a well-defined system that clearly describes the constraints we need to work within, and what our site features look like, and this has led to us ending up with a bloated, difficult to maintain front-end code base. Working on our current HTML and CSS is like being on a roller coaster with no guard-rails.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be clear, this is not the fault of any one person, or any specific period in the life of the MDN project. There are many little things that have been left to fester, multiply, and rot over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among the most significant problems are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Accessibility: There are a number of accessibility problems with the existing architecture that really should be sorted out, but were difficult to get a handle on because of Kuma’s complexity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Component inconsistency: Kuma doesn’t use a proper design system — similar items are implemented in different ways across the site, so implementing features is more difficult than it needs to be.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;When we started to move forward with the back-end platform rewrite, it felt like the perfect time to again propose the idea of a design system. After many conversations leading to an acceptable compromise being reached, our design system — MDN Fiori — was born.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Front-end developer Schalk Neethling and UX designer Mustafa Al-Qinneh took a whirlwind tour through the core of MDN’s reference docs to identify components and document all the inconsistencies we are dealing with. As part of this work, we also looked for areas where we can improve the user experience, and introduce consistency through making small changes to some core underlying aspects of the overall design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This included a defined color palette, simple, clean typography based on a well-defined type scale, consistent spacing, improved support for mobile and tablet devices, and many other small tweaks. This was never meant to be a redesign of MDN, so we had to be careful not to change too much. Instead, we played to our existing strengths and made rogue styles and markup consistent with the overall project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides the visual consistency and general user experience aspects, our underlying codebase needed some serious love and attention — we decided on a complete rethink. Early on in the process it became clear that we needed a base library that was small, nimble, and minimal. Something uniquely MDN, but that could be reused wherever the core aspects of the MDN brand was needed. For this purpose we created &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mdn/mdn-minimalist&quot;&gt;MDN-Minimalist&lt;/a&gt;, a small set of core atoms that power the base styling of MDN, in a progressively enhanced manner, taking advantage of the beautiful new layout systems we have access to on the web today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each component that is built into Yari is styled with MDN-Minimalist, and also has its own style sheet that lives right alongside to apply further styles only when needed. This is an evolving process as we constantly rethink how to provide a great user experience while staying as close to the web platform as possible. The reason for this is two fold:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;First, it means less code. It means less reinventing of the wheel. It means a faster, leaner, less bandwidth-hungry MDN for our end users.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Second, it helps address some of the accessibility issues we have begrudgingly been living with for some time, which are simply not acceptable on a modern web site. One of Mozilla’s accessibility experts, Marco Zehe, has given us a lot of input to help overcome these. We won’t fix everything in our first iteration, but our pledge to all of our users is that we will keep improving and we welcome your feedback on areas where we can improve further.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;A wise person once said that the best way to ensure something is done right is to make doing the right thing the easy thing to do. As such, along with all of the work already mentioned, we are documenting our front-end codebase, design system, and pattern library in Storybook (see &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mdn/yari/tree/8dcbbd63aa5b75c2d4e08e39cd2ea65bb099a801/client/src/stories&quot;&gt;Storybook files inside the yari repo&lt;/a&gt;) with companion design work in Figma (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.figma.com/file/YYVJ8uqG8UFBBvQhdI7fxR/MDN-Web-Docs?node-id=184%3A3&quot;&gt;see typography example&lt;/a&gt;) to ensure there is an easy, public reference for anyone who wishes to contribute to MDN from a code or design perspective. This in itself is a large project that will evolve over time. More communication about its evolution will follow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The future of MDN localization&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One important part of MDN’s content that we have talked about a lot during the planning phase is the localized content. As you probably already know, MDN offers facilities for translating the original English content and making the localizations available alongside it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is good in principle, but the current system has many flaws. When an English page is moved, the localizations all have to be moved separately, so pages and their localizations quite often go out of sync and get in a mess. And a bigger problem is that there is no easy way of signalling that the English version has changed to all the localizers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;General management is probably the most significant problem. You often get a wave of enthusiasm for a locale, and lots of translations done. But then after a number of months interest wanes, and no-one is left to keep the translations up to date. The localized content becomes outdated, which is often harmful to learning, becomes a maintenance time-suck, and as a result, is often considered worse than having no localizations at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note that we are not saying this is true of all locales on MDN, and we are not trying to downplay the amount of work volunteers have put into creating localized content. For that, we are eternally grateful. But the fact remains that we can’t carry on like this.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We did a bunch of research, and talked to a lot of non-native-English speaking web developers about what would be useful to them. Two interesting conclusions were made:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;We stand to experience a significant but manageable loss of users if we remove or reduce our localization support. 8 languages cover 90% of the accept-language headers received from MDN users (en, zh, es, ja, fr, ru, pt, de), while 14 languages cover 95% of the accept-languages. We predict that we would expect to lose at most 19% of our traffic if we dropped L10n entirely.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Machine translations are an acceptable solution in most cases, if not a perfect one. We looked at the quality of translations provided by automated solutions such as Google Translate and got some community members to compare these translations to manual translations. The machine translations were imperfect, and sometimes hard to understand, but many people commented that a non-perfect language that is up-to-date is better than a perfect language that is out-of-date. We appreciate that some languages (such as CJK languages) fare less well than others with automated translations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;So what did we decide? With the initial release of the new platform, we are planning to include all translations of all of the current documents, but in a frozen state. Translations will exist in their own mdn/translated-content repository, to which we will not accept any pull requests. The translations will be shown with a special header that says “This is an archived translation. No more edits are being accepted.” This is a temporary stage until we figure out the next step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note: In addition, the text of the UI components and header menu will be in English only, going forward. They will not be translated, at least not initially.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the initial release, we want to work with you, the community, to figure out the best course of action to move forward with for translations. We would ideally rather not lose localized content on MDN, but we need to fix the technical problems of the past, manage it better, and ensure that the content stays up-to-date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will be planning the next phase of MDN localization with the following guiding principles:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;We should never have outdated localized content on MDN.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manually localizing all MDN content in a huge range of locales seems infeasible, so we should drop that approach.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Losing ~20% of traffic is something we should avoid, if possible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;We are making no promises about deliverables or time frames yet, but we have started to think along these lines:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Cut down the number of locales we are handling to the top 14 locales that give us 95% of our recorded accept-language headers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Initially include non-editable Machine Learning-based automated translations of the “tier-1” MDN content pages (i.e. a set of the most important MDN content that excludes the vast long tail of articles that get no, or nearly no views). Ideally we’d like to use the existing manual translations to train the Machine Learning system, hopefully getting better results. This is likely to be the first thing we’ll work on in 2021.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Regularly update the automated translations as the English content changes, keeping them up-to-date.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start to offer a system whereby we allow community members to improve the automated translations with manual edits. This would require the community to ensure that articles are kept up-to-date with the English versions as they are updated.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Sign up for the beta test&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we mentioned earlier, we are going to launch a beta test of the new MDN platform on November 2nd. We would love your help in testing out the new system and contribution workflow, letting us know what aspects seem good and what aspects seem painful, and suggesting improvements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to be notified when the new system is ready for testing, please let us know using &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfl5dKsY1hsT82QfVj8zFlhLWaR1FjHpVpDJ6QtMYHcqy565Q/viewform&quot;&gt;this form&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Acknowledgements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d like to thank my colleagues Schalk Neethling, Ryan Johnson, Peter Bengtsson, Rina Tambo Jensen, Hermina Condei, Melissa Thermidor, and anyone else I’ve forgotten who helped me polish this article with bits of content, feedback, reviews, edits, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;about&quot; readability=&quot;14.944680851064&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chris Mills is a senior tech writer at Mozilla, where he writes docs and demos about open web apps, HTML/CSS/JavaScript, A11y, WebAssembly, and more. He loves tinkering around with web technologies, and gives occasional tech talks at conferences and universities. He used to work for Opera and W3C, and enjoys playing heavy metal drums and drinking good beer. He lives near Manchester, UK, with his good lady and three beautiful children.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;url&quot; href=&quot;https://hacks.mozilla.org/author/cmillsmozilla-com/&quot;&gt;More articles by Chris Mills…&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2020 15:56:50 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>headalgorithm</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://hacks.mozilla.org/2020/10/mdn-web-docs-evolves-lowdown-on-the-upcoming-new-platform</og:url>
<og:title>MDN Web Docs evolves! Lowdown on the upcoming new platform – Mozilla Hacks - the Web developer blog</og:title>
<og:description>The time has come for Kuma — the platform that powers MDN Web Docs — to evolve. “What does a Kuma evolve into? A KumaMaMa?”</og:description>
<og:image>https://hacks.mozilla.org/files/2020/10/kuma-preevolve.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://hacks.mozilla.org/2020/10/mdn-web-docs-evolves-lowdown-on-the-upcoming-new-platform/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Grubhub sued for listing restaurants without permission</title>
<link>https://www.axios.com/grubhub-sued-restaurants-delivery-5fa51bda-73c4-44b0-93f7-314660d8b7af.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.axios.com/grubhub-sued-restaurants-delivery-5fa51bda-73c4-44b0-93f7-314660d8b7af.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Two restaurant owners have filed a potential class action lawsuit against Grubhub, saying that the online food delivery service added their establishments without permission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why it matters:&lt;/strong&gt; While intermediary services have touted their role in supporting independent restaurants and businesses during the pandemic, many have gone to great lengths to grab business that otherwise might have gone direct to the establishment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Driving the news:&lt;/strong&gt; The &lt;a class=&quot;gtm-content-click&quot; data-vars-link-text=&quot;lawsuit&quot; data-vars-click-url=&quot;https://link.axios.com/click/21931079.5/aHR0cHM6Ly93d3cuY2xhc3NsYXdncm91cC5jb20vZ3J1Ymh1Yi1mcmF1ZHVsZW50LXJlc3RhdXJhbnQtbGlzdGluZy1sYXdzdWl0Lz91dG1fc291cmNlPW5ld3NsZXR0ZXImdXRtX21lZGl1bT1lbWFpbCZ1dG1fY2FtcGFpZ249c2VuZHRvX25ld3NsZXR0ZXJ0ZXN0JnN0cmVhbT10b3A/5cee9cc47e55544e860fbf4eB9a43745b&quot; data-vars-event-category=&quot;story&quot; data-vars-sub-category=&quot;story&quot; data-vars-item=&quot;in_content_link&quot; href=&quot;https://link.axios.com/click/21931079.5/aHR0cHM6Ly93d3cuY2xhc3NsYXdncm91cC5jb20vZ3J1Ymh1Yi1mcmF1ZHVsZW50LXJlc3RhdXJhbnQtbGlzdGluZy1sYXdzdWl0Lz91dG1fc291cmNlPW5ld3NsZXR0ZXImdXRtX21lZGl1bT1lbWFpbCZ1dG1fY2FtcGFpZ249c2VuZHRvX25ld3NsZXR0ZXJ0ZXN0JnN0cmVhbT10b3A/5cee9cc47e55544e860fbf4eB9a43745b&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;lawsuit&lt;/a&gt; argues that such listings create confusion and could harm restaurants' reputations. A Grubhub representative said the company doesn't comment on pending litigation, but the company was slow to move into delivering from what the industry dubs &quot;non-partner&quot; restaurants. Grubhub has also supported a California law that would stop the practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The big picture:&lt;/strong&gt; Critics charge that intermediary services use hardball tactics including adding restaurants without permission and setting up phone numbers and web sites that go to the intermediaries rather than the merchants themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Go deeper:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;gtm-content-click&quot; data-vars-link-text=&quot;Help Main Street allows orders directly from struggling small shops&quot; data-vars-click-url=&quot;https://link.axios.com/click/21931079.5/aHR0cHM6Ly93d3cuYXhpb3MuY29tL2hlbHAtbWFpbi1zdHJlZXQtY29yb25hdmlydXMtZGlyZWN0LWZvb2Qtb3JkZXJzLWExMjdmZmMwLTFjMjktNDIwZC04NzVmLTU0OTA5ZGQ0ZmYyMi5odG1sP3V0bV9zb3VyY2U9bmV3c2xldHRlciZ1dG1fbWVkaXVtPWVtYWlsJnV0bV9jYW1wYWlnbj1zZW5kdG9fbmV3c2xldHRlcnRlc3Qmc3RyZWFtPXRvcA/5cee9cc47e55544e860fbf4eB3cf5860b&quot; data-vars-event-category=&quot;story&quot; data-vars-sub-category=&quot;story&quot; data-vars-item=&quot;in_content_link&quot; href=&quot;https://link.axios.com/click/21931079.5/aHR0cHM6Ly93d3cuYXhpb3MuY29tL2hlbHAtbWFpbi1zdHJlZXQtY29yb25hdmlydXMtZGlyZWN0LWZvb2Qtb3JkZXJzLWExMjdmZmMwLTFjMjktNDIwZC04NzVmLTU0OTA5ZGQ0ZmYyMi5odG1sP3V0bV9zb3VyY2U9bmV3c2xldHRlciZ1dG1fbWVkaXVtPWVtYWlsJnV0bV9jYW1wYWlnbj1zZW5kdG9fbmV3c2xldHRlcnRlc3Qmc3RyZWFtPXRvcA/5cee9cc47e55544e860fbf4eB3cf5860b&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Help Main Street allows orders directly from struggling small shops&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2020 13:49:55 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>cwwc</dc:creator>
<og:title>Grubhub sued for listing restaurants without permission</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.axios.com/grubhub-sued-restaurants-delivery-5fa51bda-73c4-44b0-93f7-314660d8b7af.html</og:url>
<og:image>https://images.axios.com/ATGUaYe347o9Z3ZdOpHpElhx8qQ=/fit-in/1366x1366/2020/10/29/1603977909709.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>The lawsuit argues that such listings create confusion and could harm restaurants' reputations.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.axios.com/grubhub-sued-restaurants-delivery-5fa51bda-73c4-44b0-93f7-314660d8b7af.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Vim-Mario: Mario on Vim</title>
<link>https://github.com/rbtnn/vim-mario</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/rbtnn/vim-mario</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;meta charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;dns-prefetch&quot; href=&quot;https://github.githubassets.com&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;dns-prefetch&quot; href=&quot;https://avatars0.githubusercontent.com&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;dns-prefetch&quot; href=&quot;https://avatars1.githubusercontent.com&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;dns-prefetch&quot; href=&quot;https://avatars2.githubusercontent.com&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;dns-prefetch&quot; href=&quot;https://avatars3.githubusercontent.com&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;dns-prefetch&quot; href=&quot;https://github-cloud.s3.amazonaws.com&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;dns-prefetch&quot; href=&quot;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/&quot;/&gt;&lt;link crossorigin=&quot;anonymous&quot; media=&quot;all&quot; integrity=&quot;sha512-KwgA2T1yNYtSjccdWkggIHevOjkIgZqdsUtA0GyLMFalickiFVC+1RUh0JVQ5/gWaj/HQ/p5JIbABYtB68iwcQ==&quot; rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; href=&quot;https://github.githubassets.com/assets/frameworks-2b0800d93d72358b528dc71d5a482020.css&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot;/&gt;&lt;link crossorigin=&quot;anonymous&quot; media=&quot;all&quot; integrity=&quot;sha512-jlDry7Lvhm9Xj5gH5j+6IESsbRyoGnFJMhI3zWyssDHvBLv1By6KSCiMJ5xco9+rbyxQvLdA0sR1voMv/Jcr1Q==&quot; rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; href=&quot;https://github.githubassets.com/assets/site-8e50ebcbb2ef866f578f9807e63fba20.css&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot;/&gt;&lt;link crossorigin=&quot;anonymous&quot; media=&quot;all&quot; integrity=&quot;sha512-3EQZMz9X71y4aLpUyKFQ90/+xbWLiR/qNgiWwc800eUITfcbHOlf2PEmHDAVE/Fr3CZDpH5SQN2auQWu+8bcpA==&quot; rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; href=&quot;https://github.githubassets.com/assets/github-dc4419333f57ef5cb868ba54c8a150f7.css&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;viewport&quot; content=&quot;width=device-width&quot;/&gt;&lt;title&gt;GitHub - rbtnn/vim-mario: Mario on Vim&lt;/title&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;description&quot; content=&quot;Mario on Vim. Contribute to rbtnn/vim-mario development by creating an account on GitHub.&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;search&quot; type=&quot;application/opensearchdescription+xml&quot; href=&quot;/opensearch.xml&quot; title=&quot;GitHub&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;fluid-icon&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/fluidicon.png&quot; title=&quot;GitHub&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;fb:app_id&quot; content=&quot;1401488693436528&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;apple-itunes-app&quot; content=&quot;app-id=1477376905&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:image:src&quot; content=&quot;https://avatars0.githubusercontent.com/u/1595779?s=400&amp;amp;v=4&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:site&quot; content=&quot;@github&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:card&quot; content=&quot;summary&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:title&quot; content=&quot;rbtnn/vim-mario&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:description&quot; content=&quot;Mario on Vim. Contribute to rbtnn/vim-mario development by creating an account on GitHub.&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:image&quot; content=&quot;https://avatars0.githubusercontent.com/u/1595779?s=400&amp;amp;v=4&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:site_name&quot; content=&quot;GitHub&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:type&quot; content=&quot;object&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:title&quot; content=&quot;rbtnn/vim-mario&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:url&quot; content=&quot;https://github.com/rbtnn/vim-mario&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:description&quot; content=&quot;Mario on Vim. Contribute to rbtnn/vim-mario development by creating an account on GitHub.&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;assets&quot; href=&quot;https://github.githubassets.com/&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;request-id&quot; content=&quot;D388:59B6:1C4A17:2CCD27:5F9B65EC&quot; data-pjax-transient=&quot;true&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;html-safe-nonce&quot; content=&quot;52e5d961f9c20179d2d8518f80dc4931994146ea&quot; data-pjax-transient=&quot;true&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;visitor-payload&quot; content=&quot;eyJyZWZlcnJlciI6Imh0dHA6Ly93d3cuZ29vZ2xlLmNvLnVrL3VybD9zYT10XHUwMDI2c291cmNlPXdlYlx1MDAyNmNkPTEiLCJyZXF1ZXN0X2lkIjoiRDM4ODo1OUI2OjFDNEExNzoyQ0NEMjc6NUY5QjY1RUMiLCJ2aXNpdG9yX2lkIjoiNDEwMzk5MDAwOTEyNDMxNjY1MyIsInJlZ2lvbl9lZGdlIjoiaWFkIiwicmVnaW9uX3JlbmRlciI6ImlhZCJ9&quot; data-pjax-transient=&quot;true&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;visitor-hmac&quot; content=&quot;fd092a68b6edf6e3d29eb70ed0b4bc493abb52c3432ddccccbca2905e39d04e3&quot; data-pjax-transient=&quot;true&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;cookie-consent-required&quot; content=&quot;false&quot; data-pjax-transient=&quot;true&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;hovercard-subject-tag&quot; content=&quot;repository:22571678&quot; data-pjax-transient=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;github-keyboard-shortcuts&quot; content=&quot;repository&quot; data-pjax-transient=&quot;true&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;selected-link&quot; value=&quot;repo_source&quot; data-pjax-transient=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;google-site-verification&quot; content=&quot;c1kuD-K2HIVF635lypcsWPoD4kilo5-jA_wBFyT4uMY&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;google-site-verification&quot; content=&quot;KT5gs8h0wvaagLKAVWq8bbeNwnZZK1r1XQysX3xurLU&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;google-site-verification&quot; content=&quot;ZzhVyEFwb7w3e0-uOTltm8Jsck2F5StVihD0exw2fsA&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;google-site-verification&quot; content=&quot;GXs5KoUUkNCoaAZn7wPN-t01Pywp9M3sEjnt_3_ZWPc&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;octolytics-host&quot; content=&quot;collector.githubapp.com&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;octolytics-app-id&quot; content=&quot;github&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;octolytics-event-url&quot; content=&quot;https://collector.githubapp.com/github-external/browser_event&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;octolytics-dimension-ga_id&quot; content=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;js-octo-ga-id&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;analytics-location&quot; content=&quot;/&amp;lt;user-name&amp;gt;/&amp;lt;repo-name&amp;gt;&quot; data-pjax-transient=&quot;true&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;google-analytics&quot; content=&quot;UA-3769691-2&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta class=&quot;js-ga-set&quot; name=&quot;dimension10&quot; content=&quot;Responsive&quot; data-pjax-transient=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta class=&quot;js-ga-set&quot; name=&quot;dimension1&quot; content=&quot;Logged Out&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;hostname&quot; content=&quot;github.com&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;user-login&quot; content=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;expected-hostname&quot; content=&quot;github.com&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;enabled-features&quot; content=&quot;MARKETPLACE_PENDING_INSTALLATIONS&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta http-equiv=&quot;x-pjax-version&quot; content=&quot;925311fcacec763a868c7032a0022604658191900047c7dfb85d5ea25984d1e7&quot;/&gt;&lt;link href=&quot;https://github.com/rbtnn/vim-mario/commits/master.atom&quot; rel=&quot;alternate&quot; title=&quot;Recent Commits to vim-mario:master&quot; type=&quot;application/atom+xml&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;go-import&quot; content=&quot;github.com/rbtnn/vim-mario git https://github.com/rbtnn/vim-mario.git&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;octolytics-dimension-user_id&quot; content=&quot;1595779&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;octolytics-dimension-user_login&quot; content=&quot;rbtnn&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;octolytics-dimension-repository_id&quot; content=&quot;22571678&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;octolytics-dimension-repository_nwo&quot; content=&quot;rbtnn/vim-mario&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;octolytics-dimension-repository_public&quot; content=&quot;true&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;octolytics-dimension-repository_is_fork&quot; content=&quot;false&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;octolytics-dimension-repository_network_root_id&quot; content=&quot;22571678&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;octolytics-dimension-repository_network_root_nwo&quot; content=&quot;rbtnn/vim-mario&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;octolytics-dimension-repository_explore_github_marketplace_ci_cta_shown&quot; content=&quot;false&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;canonical&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/rbtnn/vim-mario&quot; data-pjax-transient=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;browser-stats-url&quot; content=&quot;https://api.github.com/_private/browser/stats&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;browser-errors-url&quot; content=&quot;https://api.github.com/_private/browser/errors&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;browser-optimizely-client-errors-url&quot; content=&quot;https://api.github.com/_private/browser/optimizely_client/errors&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;mask-icon&quot; href=&quot;https://github.githubassets.com/pinned-octocat.svg&quot; color=&quot;#000000&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;alternate icon&quot; class=&quot;js-site-favicon&quot; type=&quot;image/png&quot; href=&quot;https://github.githubassets.com/favicons/favicon.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;icon&quot; class=&quot;js-site-favicon&quot; type=&quot;image/svg+xml&quot; href=&quot;https://github.githubassets.com/favicons/favicon.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;theme-color&quot; content=&quot;#1e2327&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;manifest&quot; href=&quot;/manifest.json&quot; crossorigin=&quot;use-credentials&quot;/&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body class=&quot;logged-out env-production page-responsive&quot; id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot; readability=&quot;40.534850640114&quot;&gt;


&lt;div data-pjax-replace=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;js-flash-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;flash flash-full {{ className }}&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot; px-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;{{ message }}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;application-main&quot; data-commit-hovercards-enabled=&quot;&quot; data-discussion-hovercards-enabled=&quot;&quot; data-issue-and-pr-hovercards-enabled=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/SoftwareSourceCode&quot; class=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bg-gray-light pt-3 hide-full-screen mb-5&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;d-block d-md-none mb-2 px-3 px-md-4 px-lg-5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;f4 mb-3&quot;&gt;Mario on Vim&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;nav aria-label=&quot;Repository&quot; data-pjax=&quot;#js-repo-pjax-container&quot; class=&quot;js-repo-nav js-sidenav-container-pjax js-responsive-underlinenav overflow-hidden UnderlineNav px-3 px-md-4 px-lg-5 bg-gray-light&quot;&gt;
&lt;/nav&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;container-xl clearfix new-discussion-timeline px-3 px-md-4 px-lg-5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;repository-content&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;signup-prompt p-4 text-center mb-4 rounded-1&quot; readability=&quot;31.129518072289&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;position-relative&quot; readability=&quot;9.578313253012&quot;&gt;&lt;button type=&quot;button&quot; class=&quot;position-absolute top-0 right-0 btn-link link-gray&quot; data-action=&quot;click:signup-prompt#dismiss&quot; data-ga-click=&quot;(Logged out) Sign up prompt, clicked Dismiss, text:dismiss&quot;&gt;Dismiss&lt;/button&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;pt-2&quot;&gt;Join GitHub today&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;col-6 mx-auto&quot;&gt;GitHub is home to over 50 million developers working together to host and review code, manage projects, and build software together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;btn btn-primary&quot; data-ga-click=&quot;(Logged out) Sign up prompt, clicked Sign up, text:sign-up&quot; data-hydro-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;event_type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;authentication.click&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;payload&amp;quot;:{&amp;quot;location_in_page&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;files signup prompt&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;repository_id&amp;quot;:null,&amp;quot;auth_type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;SIGN_UP&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;originating_url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://github.com/rbtnn/vim-mario&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;user_id&amp;quot;:null}}&quot; data-hydro-click-hmac=&quot;7bbe9ac72685d634594841007494531da43a6ccf09a33e62fc72e88e30f67501&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/join?source=prompt-code&amp;amp;source_repo=rbtnn%2Fvim-mario&quot;&gt;Sign up&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gutter-condensed gutter-lg flex-column flex-md-row d-flex&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;flex-shrink-0 col-12 col-md-9 mb-4 mb-md-0&quot; readability=&quot;4.0769230769231&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;Box mb-3&quot; readability=&quot;3.8941979522184&quot;&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;files&quot; class=&quot;sr-only&quot;&gt;Files&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;d-none js-permalink-shortcut&quot; data-hotkey=&quot;y&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/rbtnn/vim-mario/tree/c984617e459d9eaebd4f42386c3e848f56ef106f&quot;&gt;Permalink&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Failed to load latest commit information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;js-details-container Details&quot;&gt;
&lt;div role=&quot;grid&quot; aria-labelledby=&quot;files&quot; class=&quot;Details-content--hidden-not-important js-navigation-container js-active-navigation-container d-md-block&quot; data-pjax=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sr-only&quot; role=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Type&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Name&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Latest commit message&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Commit time&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div role=&quot;row&quot; class=&quot;Box-row Box-row--focus-gray py-2 d-flex position-relative js-navigation-item&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Dec 6, 2014&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div role=&quot;row&quot; class=&quot;Box-row Box-row--focus-gray py-2 d-flex position-relative js-navigation-item&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Dec 6, 2014&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div role=&quot;row&quot; class=&quot;Box-row Box-row--focus-gray py-2 d-flex position-relative js-navigation-item&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Aug 3, 2014&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div role=&quot;row&quot; class=&quot;Box-row Box-row--focus-gray py-2 d-flex position-relative js-navigation-item&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Jan 28, 2020&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div role=&quot;row&quot; class=&quot;Box-row Box-row--focus-gray py-2 d-flex position-relative js-navigation-item&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Aug 9, 2014&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;readme&quot; class=&quot;Box md js-code-block-container Box--responsive&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;Box-body px-5 pb-5&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;markdown-body entry-content container-lg&quot; itemprop=&quot;text&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/ec99e0fdf7ae339ea6eae266066f37e24b4123ec/68747470733a2f2f7261772e6769746875622e636f6d2f7262746e6e2f6d6172696f2e76696d2f6d61737465722f6d6172696f2e676966&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/ec99e0fdf7ae339ea6eae266066f37e24b4123ec/68747470733a2f2f7261772e6769746875622e636f6d2f7262746e6e2f6d6172696f2e76696d2f6d61737465722f6d6172696f2e676966&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://raw.github.com/rbtnn/mario.vim/master/mario.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;USAGE&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;    &quot; Play mario.vim
    :Mario
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How-to&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Space key : Jump mario.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;h key : Move mario to the left.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;l key : Move mario to the right.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;q key : exit mario.vim(same as GameOver).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Dependency plugin&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;flex-shrink-0 col-12 col-md-3&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;BorderGrid BorderGrid--spacious&quot; data-pjax=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;BorderGrid-row hide-sm hide-md&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;BorderGrid-cell&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;mb-3 h4&quot;&gt;About&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;f4 mt-3&quot;&gt;Mario on Vim&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sr-only&quot;&gt;Resources&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;sr-only&quot;&gt;License&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;BorderGrid-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;BorderGrid-cell&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No releases published&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;BorderGrid-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;BorderGrid-cell&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No packages published&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can’t perform that action at this time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;js-stale-session-flash flash flash-warn flash-banner&quot; hidden=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;js-stale-session-flash-signed-in&quot; hidden=&quot;&quot;&gt;You signed in with another tab or window. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rbtnn/vim-mario&quot;&gt;Reload&lt;/a&gt; to refresh your session.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;js-stale-session-flash-signed-out&quot; hidden=&quot;&quot;&gt;You signed out in another tab or window. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rbtnn/vim-mario&quot;&gt;Reload&lt;/a&gt; to refresh your session.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;details class=&quot;details-reset details-overlay details-overlay-dark lh-default text-gray-dark hx_rsm&quot; open=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;js-cookie-consent-banner&quot; hidden=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;hx_cookie-banner p-2 p-sm-3 p-md-4&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Box hx_cookie-banner-box box-shadow-medium mx-auto&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Box-body border-0 py-0 px-3 px-md-4&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;js-main-cookie-banner hx_cookie-banner-main&quot; readability=&quot;31.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;d-md-flex flex-items-center py-3&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;f5 flex-1 mb-3 mb-md-0&quot;&gt;We use &lt;span class=&quot;text-bold&quot;&gt;optional&lt;/span&gt; third-party analytics cookies to understand how you use GitHub.com so we can build better products. &lt;span class=&quot;btn-link js-cookie-consent-learn-more&quot;&gt;Learn more&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;button class=&quot;btn btn-outline flex-1 mr-1 mx-sm-1 m-md-0 ml-md-2 js-cookie-consent-accept&quot;&gt;Accept&lt;/button&gt; &lt;button class=&quot;btn btn-outline flex-1 ml-1 m-md-0 ml-md-2 js-cookie-consent-reject&quot;&gt;Reject&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;js-cookie-details hx_cookie-banner-details&quot; hidden=&quot;&quot; readability=&quot;7.085201793722&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;d-md-flex flex-items-center py-3&quot; readability=&quot;9.3436293436293&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;f5 flex-1 mb-2 mb-md-0&quot;&gt;We use &lt;span class=&quot;text-bold&quot;&gt;optional&lt;/span&gt; third-party analytics cookies to understand how you use GitHub.com so we can build better products.&lt;br/&gt;You can always update your selection by clicking &lt;span class=&quot;text-bold&quot;&gt;Cookie Preferences&lt;/span&gt; at the bottom of the page. For more information, see our &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.github.com/en/free-pro-team@latest/github/site-policy/github-privacy-statement&quot;&gt;Privacy Statement&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;d-md-flex flex-items-center py-3 border-top&quot; readability=&quot;6.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;f5 flex-1 mb-2 mb-md-0&quot; readability=&quot;8.2857142857143&quot;&gt;
&lt;h5 class=&quot;mb-1&quot;&gt;Essential cookies&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;f6 mb-md-0&quot;&gt;We use essential cookies to perform essential website functions, e.g. they're used to log you in. &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.github.com/en/github/site-policy/github-subprocessors-and-cookies&quot;&gt;Learn more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h5 class=&quot;text-blue&quot;&gt;Always active&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;d-md-flex flex-items-center py-3 border-top&quot; readability=&quot;7.2011952191235&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;f5 flex-1 mb-2 mb-md-0&quot; readability=&quot;9.57805907173&quot;&gt;
&lt;h5 class=&quot;mb-1&quot;&gt;Analytics cookies&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;f6 mb-md-0&quot;&gt;We use analytics cookies to understand how you use our websites so we can make them better, e.g. they're used to gather information about the pages you visit and how many clicks you need to accomplish a task. &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.github.com/en/github/site-policy/github-subprocessors-and-cookies&quot;&gt;Learn more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;text-right&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;button class=&quot;btn btn-outline BtnGroup-item js-accept-analytics-cookies&quot; type=&quot;button&quot;&gt;Accept&lt;/button&gt; &lt;button class=&quot;btn btn-outline BtnGroup-item js-reject-analytics-cookies&quot; type=&quot;button&quot;&gt;Reject&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;button class=&quot;btn btn-primary js-save-cookie-preferences&quot; type=&quot;button&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot;&gt;Save preferences&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2020 13:09:43 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>tambourine_man</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars0.githubusercontent.com/u/1595779?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>rbtnn/vim-mario</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/rbtnn/vim-mario</og:url>
<og:description>Mario on Vim. Contribute to rbtnn/vim-mario development by creating an account on GitHub.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/rbtnn/vim-mario</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Remarkable Number 1/89 (2004)</title>
<link>http://www2.math.ou.edu/~dmccullough/teaching/miscellanea/miner.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www2.math.ou.edu/~dmccullough/teaching/miscellanea/miner.html</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;meta http-equiv=&quot;Content-Type&quot; content=&quot;text/html; charset=UTF-8&quot; /&gt;&lt;title&gt;The remarkable number 1/89&lt;/title&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body bgcolor=&quot;#FFFFDE&quot; id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot; readability=&quot;102.6047329709&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www2.math.ou.edu/~dmccullough/teaching/miscellanea/&quot; onmouseover=&quot;window.status='Return to Mathematical Miscellanea'; return true&quot; onmouseout=&quot;status=(' '); return true&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www2.math.ou.edu/~dmccullough/images/arrows/left_darkbluearrow.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;Return to Mathematical Miscellanea&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Remarkable Number 1/89&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;center&gt;by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.geom.umn.edu/about/people/home/rminer.html&quot; onmouseover=&quot;window.status='Go to Robert Miner\'s home page'; return true&quot; onmouseout=&quot;status=(' '); return true&quot;&gt;Robert Miner&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The following remarkable fact was discovered by Cody Birsner, a student at the University of Oklahoma, in the fall of 1994. The discovery arose out of work for a term paper on the Fibonacci series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Fibonacci Series&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Fibonacci series is a famous example of an object with a simple mathematical description, but a nearly inexhaustable list of bizarre and complicated properties. Originally, the series was described by Fibonacci in the 15th century in connection with the following problem:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Assume that a pair of rabbits will breed another pair of rabbits every month of their lives, after sexual maturity. Assume also that rabbits become sexually mature after two months. Starting with one newborn pair of rabbits, describe how many rabbits you get in successive months.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the first month you have 1 pair. After another month, you still have 1 pair. However, at the end of the third, the first pair has become sexually mature, and produced offspring, so you have 2 pair. At the end of the next month, the first pair reporduces again, while the second pair remains immature, so you have a total of 3 pair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proceeding in this fashion, one sees that the following list of numbers describes the breeding of the rabbits:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1,1,2,3,5,8,13,21,34,55,89,144,...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Interesting Facts about the Fibonacci Series&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Each term in the sequence is the sum of the previous two. That is, 2 = 1 + 1, 3 = 2 + 1, 5 = 2 + 3, and so on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Fibonacci series appears in a number of places throughout nature, for example, in the pattern in which sunflower seeds grow, and the leaf patterns of many plants.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The successive ratios of the terms, i.e. 1/1, 2/1, 3/2, 5/3 ... tend to a number called the Golden Ratio by the Greeks. This number also appears thoughout nature, describing the spiral behavior of shells among other things. In addition, this number appears in many mathematical contexts, being related to pentagons and logarithmic spirals, to name a couple.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Fibbonaci series itself has many bizarre and curious properties, such as the one concerning 1/89 we are about to describe. In fact, there are so many of these strange interrelations, there is a mathematical journal called the Fibonacci Quarterly, entirely devoted to the series and its properties.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;The Punch Line&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The decimal expansion of 1/89 is just the Fibonacci series, added together in an appropriate fashion.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Specifically, think of the Fibonacci series as being a sequence of decimal fractions, arranged so the right most digit of the &lt;em&gt;n&lt;/em&gt;th Fibonacci number is in the &lt;em&gt;n+1&lt;/em&gt;th decimal place. Then add:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
  .01
  .001
  .0002
  .00003
  .000005
  .0000008
  .00000013
  .000000021
  .0000000034
  .00000000055
  .000000000089
  .0000000000144
        .
        .
+       .
----------------
  .01123595505...
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can easily check, 1/89 = .01123595595... Bizarre, eh?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sketch of Proof&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This proof arose from discussions with Prof. Andy Magid and others in the math lounge at OU.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&quot;bottom&quot; src=&quot;http://www2.math.ou.edu/~dmccullough/teaching/miscellanea/miner1.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Proof.&lt;/em&gt; Consider the matrix&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&quot;bottom&quot; src=&quot;http://www2.math.ou.edu/~dmccullough/teaching/miscellanea/miner2.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&quot;bottom&quot; src=&quot;http://www2.math.ou.edu/~dmccullough/teaching/miscellanea/miner3.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consequently, it follows that&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&quot;bottom&quot; src=&quot;http://www2.math.ou.edu/~dmccullough/teaching/miscellanea/miner4.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, by diagonalizing A, one easily checks that the geometric series converges, and in fact,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&quot;bottom&quot; src=&quot;http://www2.math.ou.edu/~dmccullough/teaching/miscellanea/miner5.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&quot;bottom&quot; src=&quot;http://www2.math.ou.edu/~dmccullough/teaching/miscellanea/miner6.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The result now follows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2020 12:25:45 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>nonsapreiche</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www2.math.ou.edu/~dmccullough/teaching/miscellanea/miner.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>A Little Money Laundering Can Have a Big Impact on Real Estate Prices (2019)</title>
<link>https://betterdwelling.com/how-a-little-money-laundering-can-have-a-big-impact-on-real-estate-prices/#_</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://betterdwelling.com/how-a-little-money-laundering-can-have-a-big-impact-on-real-estate-prices/#_</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Money laundering in Canadian real estate is a widely accepted fact of life these days, but the impact isn’t. Government and academics are still debating how much money is needed to distort a market. The truth is, not a whole lot is required to distort any asset market. This is a problem the stock market has been dealing with since the 1920s, and the reason it’s so highly regulated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key to understanding how laundering impacts prices, is understanding the marginal buyer. If you understand how prices are set, it doesn’t take long to see it’s not the amount of money that’s the issue. Price distortions can be the result of capital velocity, and the intention of the marginal buyer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Squad Goal: Money Laundering&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, let’s clarify laundering. Money laundering is the process of making illegally-gained proceeds appear legit. Those proceeds can be from monstrous activity, like fentanyl trafficking. Sometimes it’s less nefarious, like earned income evading a country’s arbitrary capital controls. All of it is illegal however, and is people are trying to hide it. There’s a few ways to do it – but the all follow the same basic process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Money laundering is usually done in three phases – placement, layering, and integration. Placement is the introduction of cash into a legitimate system. Layering is conducting multiple transactions through multiple accounts, to obfuscate a trail. Integration is working the money back into the legit system. Properly laundered money should be extremely difficult to tell from legitimate business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One last time, the goal is clean money. Parking cash long term in assets is not typical – these aren’t investors. That said, the layering process usually involves moving cash around very quickly. Fast moving cash often leaves a wake, especially if it’s moving through real estate. To understand why, you need to understand a few concepts – marginal buyers, money laundering, and sales comps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Marginal Buyers Be Cray, Cray&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The marginal buyer is an important part of any asset market, especially fast moving ones. This is the person(s) or company that’s willing to pay the most for an asset. They are a small percent of the potential buyer pool, but the ones that actually buy the assets. The competition between marginal buyers is key to asset price escalation. Every market has one on the way up, but skill and motive determine how healthy the outcome is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the marginal buyer is a rational investor, they’re thinking about liquidity. They’re restrained in their bidding price, because they need to be able to make a profit. Rational consideration helps to keep a market sane. If the buyer isn’t bound by rationale or logic, things start to get sloppy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A cannabis company making $20 million a year in revenue fetching close to the valuation of GM? An investment condo that produces negative cash flow? The buyers of these things aren’t making rational decisions. It doesn’t mean they can’t make money, but they are playing a game of greater fool. You’re hoping that the next buyer is more irrational than you – whether you know that’s the plan or not. When you have an influx of irrational money, it’s hard to figure out what’s real.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Objective of Money Laundering&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you buy an asset, whether a home or an oz of pink kush, you try to get the best value for your time and money. You want a deal. The seller is trying to extract the maximum price they can get from you, without driving you away. They don’t want you to get a great deal. The balance of interests go back and forth, and is a fundamental part of a functioning market. Opposing interests help balance things, plus or minus a dash of exuberance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are money laundering, that’s not the case. The objective is to move as much cash, as fast as possible. This often involves large assets, and the bigger the price – the better. Especially if there’s a recurring payment component. Both the seller and the money laundering buyer want the highest acceptable price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sellers often feel somewhere between a genius and a lottery winner when they find this buyer. Competition between interests align, and there’s minimal friction preventing prices from going higher. The seller assumes their master negotiation skills prevailed. The money laundering buyer gets to move more money than they were asking for. The buyer seems “irrational,” but that’s just the market. Real estate agents without a clue, begin to rationalize and normalize this behavior. There’s no more land is a popular explanation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Understanding How Real Estate Prices Are Born&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all know how prices are born. When a homeowner finds a selling agent they love, they go into a quiet backroom, make a few strokes, and boom! The multiple listing service spits out the comparables, a.k.a. your comps. Comps are a fancy way of saying what has sold around you, like the neighbor’s house. These numbers are then used to establish a baseline price, which a selling agent tries to push higher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No comps in your neighborhood? No problem, we’ll use the neighborhood next door. Eventually, the arbitrary line disappears that separates the pricing in neighborhoods. This is when you hear dumb things, like “Shaughnessy Heights adjacent.” This spreads like a virus, from one neighborhood to the next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Vancouver Real Estate Prices Overheating&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A time-lapse of real estate sales in the City of Vancouver. Herd behavior can be observed in clusters, as people pay over or under the list price – based on whether other people are doing it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;jetpack-video-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;embed-youtube&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe class=&quot;youtube-player&quot; width=&quot;1140&quot; height=&quot;642&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/RBy42L3zsp4?version=3&amp;amp;rel=1&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;autohide=2&amp;amp;showsearch=0&amp;amp;showinfo=1&amp;amp;iv_load_policy=1&amp;amp;wmode=transparent&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: Better Dwelling. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Poisoning The Comp System&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smarter real estate agents can already spot the problem here. Let’s look at an example, say you’re shopping for a home in Anyplace, BC. You’re watching the homes in the neighborhood climb at an average of 5% from last year. You find a place you’re ready to put on offer on, do some research, and come up with an offer. All of a sudden, a money launderer shows up, and offers the owner 10% over ask for a “quick close.” You’re not too worried, your agent told you the place a few doors down is going to be on the market next week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the new place now uses the home owned by the money launder as a comp. Now the ask is 10% more than you were expecting, because the marginal buyer set the price down the street. Someone else bites, and buys it before it “goes too high.” Now the money launderer’s buy was just validated in the system. But wait – there’s more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember, the goal of laundering isn’t to buy a house, it’s to clean the money. They list the home again, let’s say another 10 points higher than bought. Bonus points if they can turn it into a wash trade, and sell it to another associated launderer. A regular family shopping down the street uses your washing machine as a comp for their buy. Behavior typically only seen in the frothiest of asset bubbles, can surface quickly. Exuberant buyers, both illicit and legit, compete and drive prices higher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Driving Exuberance In Canadian Real Estate&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;An index of exuberance Canadian real estate buyers are demonstrating, in relation to pricing fundamentals. Once above the critical threshold is breached, buyers are no longer using fundementals. Instead they resort to market momentum, and the possiblity of reward is justification enough.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: Federal Reserve Bank of Dallas, Better Dwelling.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now in this example, just a few sales would have helped to push the comps up to 21% higher. There would also be hundreds of sales validating the price movements in between. Each time the launder injects capital, they inject a new marginal buyer. The whole time, Boomers are stoking the coals on this fire, explaining this is “earned equity.” If you want your own, you need to work as hard as they did. Standing by as each irrational player enters the market is exhausting work. Boomers also had to save uphill for a down payment… both ways, in the snow or something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;“It Wasn’t That Much Money”&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still think a small amount of money can’t influence prices? Clearly you’re not familiar with another asset class – stocks. CNBC host Jim Cramer once ranted that his fund &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/gMShFx5rThI?t=23&quot;&gt;could manipulate stock prices with as little as $5 million&lt;/a&gt;. Nav Singh Sarao, spoofing just $170 million worth of orders, set off events that led to the DJIA losing $1 trillion in just a few minutes. Note: the orders were spoofed – meaning he only had a fraction of the money. More formally, academics determined &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jstor.org/stable/42002571&quot;&gt;traders can use less than $500,000 to raise a stock price 1%&lt;/a&gt;, by targeting the bottom half of the liquidity spectrum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Smack That Ask: It’s Not What You Pay, It’s What You Think People Will Pay&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;An example of&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Dynamic Layering&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;, the spoofing technique used by Nav Singh Sarao. The lower dots are bids placed, that only sometimes execute as a trade. Free markets can’t effectively determine if participants are executing trades in good faith – required for natural price balance.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-11145 jetpack-lazy-image&quot; src=&quot;https://betterdwelling.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/How-A-Little-Money-Laundering-Can-Have-A-Big-Impact-On-Real-Estate-Prices-Nav-Sarao.png?is-pending-load=1&quot; alt=&quot;How A Little Money Laundering Can Have A Big Impact On Real Estate Prices - Nav Sarao&quot; width=&quot;2560&quot; height=&quot;1388&quot; data-lazy-srcset=&quot;https://betterdwelling.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/How-A-Little-Money-Laundering-Can-Have-A-Big-Impact-On-Real-Estate-Prices-Nav-Sarao.png 2560w, https://betterdwelling.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/How-A-Little-Money-Laundering-Can-Have-A-Big-Impact-On-Real-Estate-Prices-Nav-Sarao-721x391.png 721w, https://betterdwelling.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/How-A-Little-Money-Laundering-Can-Have-A-Big-Impact-On-Real-Estate-Prices-Nav-Sarao-768x416.png 768w, https://betterdwelling.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/How-A-Little-Money-Laundering-Can-Have-A-Big-Impact-On-Real-Estate-Prices-Nav-Sarao-1170x634.png 1170w, https://betterdwelling.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/How-A-Little-Money-Laundering-Can-Have-A-Big-Impact-On-Real-Estate-Prices-Nav-Sarao-92x50.png 92w, https://betterdwelling.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/How-A-Little-Money-Laundering-Can-Have-A-Big-Impact-On-Real-Estate-Prices-Nav-Sarao-210x114.png 210w, https://betterdwelling.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/How-A-Little-Money-Laundering-Can-Have-A-Big-Impact-On-Real-Estate-Prices-Nav-Sarao-140x76.png 140w, https://betterdwelling.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/How-A-Little-Money-Laundering-Can-Have-A-Big-Impact-On-Real-Estate-Prices-Nav-Sarao-1126x611.png 1126w&quot; data-lazy-sizes=&quot;(max-width:2560px) 100vw, 2560px&quot; srcset=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-11145&quot; src=&quot;https://betterdwelling.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/How-A-Little-Money-Laundering-Can-Have-A-Big-Impact-On-Real-Estate-Prices-Nav-Sarao.png&quot; alt=&quot;How A Little Money Laundering Can Have A Big Impact On Real Estate Prices - Nav Sarao&quot; width=&quot;2560&quot; height=&quot;1388&quot; srcset=&quot;https://betterdwelling.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/How-A-Little-Money-Laundering-Can-Have-A-Big-Impact-On-Real-Estate-Prices-Nav-Sarao.png 2560w, https://betterdwelling.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/How-A-Little-Money-Laundering-Can-Have-A-Big-Impact-On-Real-Estate-Prices-Nav-Sarao-721x391.png 721w, https://betterdwelling.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/How-A-Little-Money-Laundering-Can-Have-A-Big-Impact-On-Real-Estate-Prices-Nav-Sarao-768x416.png 768w, https://betterdwelling.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/How-A-Little-Money-Laundering-Can-Have-A-Big-Impact-On-Real-Estate-Prices-Nav-Sarao-1170x634.png 1170w, https://betterdwelling.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/How-A-Little-Money-Laundering-Can-Have-A-Big-Impact-On-Real-Estate-Prices-Nav-Sarao-92x50.png 92w, https://betterdwelling.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/How-A-Little-Money-Laundering-Can-Have-A-Big-Impact-On-Real-Estate-Prices-Nav-Sarao-210x114.png 210w, https://betterdwelling.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/How-A-Little-Money-Laundering-Can-Have-A-Big-Impact-On-Real-Estate-Prices-Nav-Sarao-140x76.png 140w, https://betterdwelling.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/How-A-Little-Money-Laundering-Can-Have-A-Big-Impact-On-Real-Estate-Prices-Nav-Sarao-1126x611.png 1126w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width:2560px) 100vw, 2560px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: US Department of Justice. &lt;/em&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each of the situations are different, but have two common things – influence and intent. While not that much money, each example precipitated events that had a big impact. The actual trades weren’t so important, so much as influencing volatility. Setting the marginal buyer definitely counts as an event that influences market direction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each one of these events are also easily mistaken for an accident, which conceals intent. Fat finger, trade algo gone wild, and/or eager market buyer. Each one of these situations could have been caused by regular, everyday occurrences. Now it’s unlikely that money laundering is focusing on systematic trading of homes to inflate prices. It could however, be one of the times an unintentional destabilization of a market is just a side effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Velocity may also be playing a large roll here. When cash goes into one house, it’s eventually sold. That cash likely gets pumped through multiple transactions for the purposes of layering. That means more houses are being bought with the money, and profits. More sophisticated operations also have combine layering with an integration platform. Bonus points if the integration platform is registered with FINTRAC. That way the integration platform is also in charge of submitting suspicious transaction reports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Combine this with an opaque comp system with closed data, and it’s really hard to catch. The chances of buyers being able to do their own due diligence on a property buy is virtually nil. Closed systems also mean no wide scale analysis of the transaction. There’s very little way for anyone outside of regulators to actually be able to determine it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Where’s The Money At?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Canadian cities are debating whether dirty money impacts prices, the rest of the world made up its mind. Transparency International UK found a significant correlation between shell companies, and elevated prices. London for instance, has 87,000 homes owned by anonymous companies. According to Christoph Trautvetter of Netzwerk Steuergerechtigkeit, the estimated impact from dirty money in London is 20% of the price increases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;London, UK Average Home Sale Price&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The average sale price of a London, UK home. The estimate removes the 20% of annual gains attributed to the influence of money laundering. The number also assumes no laundering was done prior to 2008. LOL.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: HM Land Registry (UK), Better Dwelling.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s a similar setup brewing in Canada, politicians are just a little less willing to look into it. Transparency International Canada &lt;a href=&quot;https://betterdwelling.com/billions-in-toronto-real-estate-bought-anonymously-with-funds-of-unknown-origin/&quot;&gt;found 50,000+ Greater Toronto homes bought by companies without known beneficial ownership&lt;/a&gt;. Even worse, $20 billion of the funds used were not subject to any anti-money laundering checks. In Vancouver, local politicians are still claiming money laundering is over exaggerated. Meanwhile, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.europarl.europa.eu/cmsdata/161086/TAX3%20Verbatim%205%20February%202019_OR.pdf&quot;&gt;in European Parliament&lt;/a&gt;, Vancouver is literally being used as an example of opaque ownership distorting home prices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Money Laundering Through Commodities Is Old News, The Velocity Is New&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Laundering money through real estate is far from new, but the velocity and volume is. Traditionally, launderers would buy, hold, and sometimes even rent the places out. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.curbed.com/2018/8/10/17674584/money-laundering-real-estate-paul-manafort-trial&quot;&gt;lack of scrutiny in real estate transactions&lt;/a&gt;, has always made it a prime landing spot. Every city has a few well known families connected to local mobs, that just happen to be in real estate. The impact to home prices are minimal when the volume is low and slow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Treating real estate like a global commodity market makes it fast and high volume. The real estate industry in Canada encourages foreign capital. In fact, Canadian banks openly helped clients with “placement,” obfuscating deposit trails. The faster you can place, the faster prices rise, and the more they welcome foreign capital – the easier the wash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This has always been an issue stock markets have had to deal with. Equity is issued, artificial volume inflates prices, and launderers liquidate to unsuspecting victims. Equity markets have increased ownership transparency on larger exchanges, making it more difficult. However, it’s still common, especially on &lt;a href=&quot;https://eurasiangroup.org/files/Typologii%20EAG/WGTYP_2013_4_eng_copy0.pdf&quot;&gt;European and Asian stock exchanges&lt;/a&gt;. Treating real estate like a stock market encourages the same type of laundering, without the transparency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fun fact: The now defunct Vancouver Stock Exchange was popular with money launderers. It was so popular, &lt;a href=&quot;https://scamcouver.files.wordpress.com/2012/04/scam-capital.pdf&quot;&gt;Forbes called Vancouver the “Scam Capital of The World&lt;/a&gt;” in 1989. The Coordinated Law Enforcement Unit in British Columbia &lt;a href=&quot;http://asperchairwp.bryan-schwartz.com/wp-content/uploads/images/stories/Asper/Conferences/2003_Dirty_Money/Papers/10_Money_Laundering_Through_Securities.pdf&quot;&gt;warned the government of organized crime on the exchange as early as 1974&lt;/a&gt;. Those warnings were largely ignored. Are you also sensing a pattern here?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Money laundering is not the sole reason for much higher prices, but it fans the flames. Low interest rates and easy lending allow regular families to provide liquidity. If a launderer can’t get clean cash, they don’t transact. There’s no appeal without house horny buyers overbidding comps, or rapidly flipping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Money laundering investors however, can influence the direction of the market. A real estate market is only as good as its last comp, set by the marginal buyer. If that marginal buyer was laundering money, they have motivation to overpay. Regular households buying into this, provide comp validation, and liquidity. Most households never consider where their liquidity is going to come from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Like this post? Like us on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/betterdwelling&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; for the next one in your feed.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2020 12:21:44 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>throw0101a</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>How A Little Money Laundering Can Have A Big Impact On Real Estate Prices | Better Dwelling</og:title>
<og:description>Money laundering in Canadian real estate is a widely accepted fact of life these days, but the impact isn’t. Government and academics are still debating how much money is needed to distort a market. The truth is, not a whole lot is required to distort any asset market. This is a problem the stock market […]</og:description>
<og:url>https://betterdwelling.com/how-a-little-money-laundering-can-have-a-big-impact-on-real-estate-prices/</og:url>
<og:image>https://betterdwelling.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/How-A-Little-Money-Laundering-Can-Have-A-Big-Impact-On-Real-Estate-Prices.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://betterdwelling.com/how-a-little-money-laundering-can-have-a-big-impact-on-real-estate-prices/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>RIAA Obtains Subpoenas Targeting 40 YouTube-Ripping Platforms and Pirate Sites</title>
<link>https://torrentfreak.com/riaa-obtains-subpoenas-targeting-40-youtube-ripping-platforms-pirate-sites-201029/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://torrentfreak.com/riaa-obtains-subpoenas-targeting-40-youtube-ripping-platforms-pirate-sites-201029/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://torrentfreak.com/images/riaa.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; src=&quot;https://torrentfreak.com/images/riaa.png&quot; alt=&quot;RIAA&quot; width=&quot;250&quot; height=&quot;134&quot; class=&quot;alignright size-full wp-image-108672&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Even erring on the side of caution with conservative estimates, there are at least hundreds of piracy-related sites on the Internet today that the RIAA would like to shut down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To have any chance of doing that, however, early work has to be done to collect various pieces of information. This can include the owners of the platforms’ domains, the IP addresses of their servers and where that hardware is physically hosted, plus any other specifics that may help to build a case or back site operators into a corner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As reported on a number of occasions here on TorrentFreak, one of the tools in the box of the RIAA and other rightsholders is the DMCA subpoena. Easily obtained from US courts without any oversight needed from a judge, DMCA subpoenas can be served on various companies, requiring them to hand over information on their allegedly-infringing clients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;RIAA Obtains DMCA Subpoenas Targeting More Than 40 Domains&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to gaining access to information on sites and their operators, DMCA subpoenas aimed at Cloudflare are a popular choice. The company not only has access to the customer information handed over as part of the account creation and maintenance process but in some instances can also identify the true server locations/IP address of ‘pirate’ site servers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same can be said of domain registrar companies such as Namecheap. Information on who bought the domain, when and how, plus how it has been used since can yield valuable information for many anti-piracy investigations. The RIAA recently decided to take advantage of both possibilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following two separate applications at a California court, the music industry group obtained DMCA subpoenas requiring both Cloudflare and Namecheap to hand over information on a large number of their allegedly-infringing customers. The Cloudflare subpoena contains 35 domains and the Namecheap subpoena 15 domains. However, due to a considerable overlap, when combined they target 41 domains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Targeting YouTube-Rippers Including the Giant Y2Mate.com&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the RIAA appears to have slowly but surely declared war on YouTube-ripping platforms and tools, it will come as no surprise that the subpoenas partially continue along that theme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Y2Mate.com, an insanely popular YouTube-ripping platform with more than 113 million visits per month according to SimilarWeb, features in both subpoenas. A notable element here is that the RIAA went through this exact process with both &lt;a href=&quot;https://torrentfreak.com/riaa-subpoenas-target-yet-another-huge-youtube-ripping-site-190527/&quot;&gt;Cloudflare and Namecheap last May&lt;/a&gt; but is now back for a second bite of the cherry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the irritants here is that despite RIAA pressure, Y2Mate appears to have almost doubled its traffic, from 62 million visits per month last year to the current extraordinary levels. &lt;a href=&quot;https://torrentfreak.com/riaa-takes-down-popular-open-source-youtube-dl-software-201024/&quot;&gt;Like YouTube-DL recently&lt;/a&gt;, Y2Mate was also &lt;a href=&quot;https://torrentfreak.com/riaa-delists-youtube-rippers-from-google-using-rare-anti-circumvention-notices-191108/&quot;&gt;accused by the RIAA&lt;/a&gt; of circumventing YouTube’s “rolling cipher”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next up is Notube.net, which bills itself simply as a YouTube converter. Back in April the site was enjoying around 24 million visits per month, traffic that has now steadied to around 16 million according to SimilarWeb. YouTubeConverter.io, which claims to offer a similar service, has around three million visitors while Ontiva.com and ListentoYouTube.online are relative minnows with around 350K visits each.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Torrent Indexes and File-Hosting Platforms&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the RIAA and the music industry as a whole consider YouTube-ripping sites and tools to be the number one piracy threat, the DMCA subpoenas also include more traditional targets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Major torrent site 1337x.to makes an appearance in the Cloudflare application which puts the RIAA in good company. As &lt;a href=&quot;https://torrentfreak.com/ace-obtains-dmca-subpoena-to-unmask-operators-of-major-pirate-sites-201025/&quot;&gt;recently reported&lt;/a&gt;, anti-piracy group ACE has just obtained a similar subpoena requiring the Tonic domain registry to hand over details relating to the torrent site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both of the subpoenas obtained by the RIAA also list TorrentDownloads.me, another popular torrent site. In these instances, the site is accused of participating in the infringement of tracks released by Ed Sheeran, Drake, and One Direction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since music files are relatively small and can be squirreled away on file-hosting platforms, it’s no surprise that these also make the list. Anonfiles.com, which currently enjoys more than 7.5 million visits per month, is accused of hosting tracks by The Killers and Beyoncé. Ddownload.com, a site with around five million visitors and most popular in Germany, also makes an appearance along with Hexupload.net and DoUploads.net&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;An Interesting Addition – A Platform for Buying &amp;amp; Selling Leaked Music&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thesource.to appears to be something of an outlier in the RIAA’s list of targets. While most other platforms clearly offer direct access to music in the form of a download or stream, this platform claims to act as a marketplace for people to buy and sell unreleased music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“On THE SOURCE legit sellers can sell real exclusive unreleased music and serious buyers can purchase them. Everything in a secure and verified environment. You are a serious seller and you are sick of having to be online 24/7 hours and doing everything manually? Then we can make your life easier,” its advertising reads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You are a serious buyer and you are sick of having to wait for every seller or middleman for hours or even for days? Then we can also make your life easier. THE SOURCE has game-changing systems which both serve sellers and buyers, just for example the integrated automated Satoshi system.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The site is paid-entry, currently for the sum of $10, but according to the RIAA’s subpoena application, someone posted the track Warlords by Childish Gambino there. The listed URL tends to suggest that someone was only offering to sell their “vault” but nevertheless, the subpoena was granted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The full list of all domains targeted in both subpoenas can be viewed below. Any domain marked with an asterisk appears in both subpoenas. The subpoenas themselves are also available for download.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Domains Targeted in Cloudflare Subpoena&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1337x.to&lt;br/&gt;pluspremieres.to&lt;br/&gt;thesource.to&lt;br/&gt;ddownload.com&lt;br/&gt;hiphopde.com*&lt;br/&gt;ontiva.com*&lt;br/&gt;anonfiles.com&lt;br/&gt;audioz.download&lt;br/&gt;dirrtyremix.es&lt;br/&gt;discografiaspormega.com&lt;br/&gt;douploads.net&lt;br/&gt;ghanamotion.com&lt;br/&gt;hd24bit.com&lt;br/&gt;hexupload.net&lt;br/&gt;intmusic.net&lt;br/&gt;iplusfree.org&lt;br/&gt;listentoyoutube.online&lt;br/&gt;mp3global.org&lt;br/&gt;musiconworldoffmx.com&lt;br/&gt;muzobzor.ru&lt;br/&gt;naijaonpoint.com*&lt;br/&gt;newalbumreleases.net&lt;br/&gt;ngleakers.co*&lt;br/&gt;rlsbb.ru&lt;br/&gt;rnbxclusive.vip&lt;br/&gt;sanet.ws&lt;br/&gt;songslover.cam*&lt;br/&gt;torrentdownloads.me*&lt;br/&gt;xclusivejams.nl&lt;br/&gt;zoop.su&lt;br/&gt;notube.net&lt;br/&gt;alegemuzica.top&lt;br/&gt;topmusic.uno*&lt;br/&gt;y2mate.com*&lt;br/&gt;youtubeconverter.io*&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Domains Targeted in Namecheap Subpoena&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;getrockmusic.net&lt;br/&gt;hiphopde.com*&lt;br/&gt;hiphoptrendsnow.com&lt;br/&gt;ontiva.com*&lt;br/&gt;songslover.com*&lt;br/&gt;stannova.com&lt;br/&gt;toryextra.com&lt;br/&gt;vevosongs.com&lt;br/&gt;ddownload.com&lt;br/&gt;torrentdownloads.me*&lt;br/&gt;ngleakers.co*&lt;br/&gt;naijaonpoint.com*&lt;br/&gt;topmusic.uno*&lt;br/&gt;y2mate.com*&lt;br/&gt;youtubeconverter.io*&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The DMCA subpoenas can be found &lt;a href=&quot;https://torrentfreak.com/images/4-20-mc-80172-RIAA-v-Namecheap-DMCA-subpoena-201001.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://torrentfreak.com/images/4-20-mc-80174-RIAA-v-Cloudflare-DMCA-subpoena-201001.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; (pdf)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2020 11:18:19 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Cantbekhan</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://torrentfreak.com/riaa-obtains-subpoenas-targeting-40-youtube-ripping-platforms-pirate-sites-201029/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>