<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Zdog – Pseudo-3D JavaScript engine for Canvas and SVG</title>
<link>https://zzz.dog/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://zzz.dog/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Zdog is a 3D JavaScript engine for &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;canvas&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; and SVG. With Zdog, you can design and render simple 3D models on the Web. Zdog is a &lt;em&gt;pseudo&lt;/em&gt;-3D engine. Its geometries exist in 3D space, but are rendered as flat shapes. This makes Zdog special.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zdog is small.&lt;/strong&gt; 2,100 lines of code for the entire library. 28KB un-minified.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zdog is round.&lt;/strong&gt; All circular shapes are rendered as proper circles with rounded edges. No polygonal jaggies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zdog is friendly.&lt;/strong&gt; Modeling is done with a straight-forward declarative API.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Zdog was designed to bring the simplicity of vector illustration into 3D. Drawing circles and squares is easy and fun. Zdog just adds another dimension.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Link directly to Zdog JS on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unpkg.com/&quot;&gt;unpkg&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;html&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;span class=&quot;name&quot;&gt;script&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;attr&quot;&gt;src&lt;/span&gt;=&lt;span class=&quot;string&quot;&gt;&quot;https://unpkg.com/zdog@1/dist/zdog.dist.min.js&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/&lt;span class=&quot;name&quot;&gt;script&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Install with npm: &lt;code&gt;npm install zdog&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install with Bower: &lt;code&gt;bower install zdog --save&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create 3D models with Zdog by adding shapes. See &lt;a href=&quot;https://zzz.dog/getting-started&quot;&gt;Getting started&lt;/a&gt; for a walk-through of this demo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;example&quot; readability=&quot;15.245283018868&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;example__code&quot; readability=&quot;25&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;js&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;keyword&quot;&gt;let&lt;/span&gt; isSpinning = &lt;span class=&quot;literal&quot;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;;

&lt;span class=&quot;keyword&quot;&gt;let&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;demo_var&quot;&gt;illo&lt;/span&gt; = &lt;span class=&quot;keyword&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;zdog_class&quot;&gt;Zdog.Illustration&lt;/span&gt;({
  &lt;span class=&quot;attr&quot;&gt;element&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span class=&quot;string&quot;&gt;'.zdog-canvas'&lt;/span&gt;,
  &lt;span class=&quot;attr&quot;&gt;dragRotate&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span class=&quot;literal&quot;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;,
  
  onDragStart: &lt;span class=&quot;function&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;keyword&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt;() &lt;/span&gt;{
    isSpinning = &lt;span class=&quot;literal&quot;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;;
  },
});


&lt;span class=&quot;keyword&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;zdog_class&quot;&gt;Zdog.Ellipse&lt;/span&gt;({
  &lt;span class=&quot;attr&quot;&gt;addTo&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span class=&quot;demo_var&quot;&gt;illo&lt;/span&gt;,
  &lt;span class=&quot;attr&quot;&gt;diameter&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;80&lt;/span&gt;,
  &lt;span class=&quot;attr&quot;&gt;translate&lt;/span&gt;: { &lt;span class=&quot;attr&quot;&gt;z&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;40&lt;/span&gt; },
  &lt;span class=&quot;attr&quot;&gt;stroke&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;20&lt;/span&gt;,
  &lt;span class=&quot;attr&quot;&gt;color&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span class=&quot;string&quot;&gt;'#636'&lt;/span&gt;,
});


&lt;span class=&quot;keyword&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;zdog_class&quot;&gt;Zdog.Rect&lt;/span&gt;({
  &lt;span class=&quot;attr&quot;&gt;addTo&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span class=&quot;demo_var&quot;&gt;illo&lt;/span&gt;,
  &lt;span class=&quot;attr&quot;&gt;width&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;80&lt;/span&gt;,
  &lt;span class=&quot;attr&quot;&gt;height&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;80&lt;/span&gt;,
  &lt;span class=&quot;attr&quot;&gt;translate&lt;/span&gt;: { &lt;span class=&quot;attr&quot;&gt;z&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;-40&lt;/span&gt; },
  &lt;span class=&quot;attr&quot;&gt;stroke&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;12&lt;/span&gt;,
  &lt;span class=&quot;attr&quot;&gt;color&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span class=&quot;string&quot;&gt;'#E62'&lt;/span&gt;,
  &lt;span class=&quot;attr&quot;&gt;fill&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span class=&quot;literal&quot;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;,
});

&lt;span class=&quot;function&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;keyword&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;animate&lt;/span&gt;() &lt;/span&gt;{
  &lt;span class=&quot;demo_var&quot;&gt;illo&lt;/span&gt;.rotate.y += isSpinning ? &lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;0.03&lt;/span&gt; : &lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;;
  &lt;span class=&quot;demo_var&quot;&gt;illo&lt;/span&gt;.updateRenderGraph();
  requestAnimationFrame( animate );
}
animate();&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hi! &lt;a href=&quot;https://desandro.com&quot;&gt;Dave here&lt;/a&gt;. I wanted to make a video game. I needed a 3D engine, but most engines were too powerful and complex for me. I made Zdog so I could design and display simple 3D models without a lot of overhead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zdog is directly inspired by &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Petz&quot;&gt;Dogz&lt;/a&gt;, a virtual pet game by P.F. Magic released in 1995. It used flat 2D circle sprites to render the Dogz’ models, but in a 3D scene. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6lKSn_cHw5k&quot;&gt;See Dogz playthrough video here.&lt;/a&gt; Dogz were fully animated in real time, running, flopping, scratching (on Windows 3.1!). It was remarkable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zdog uses the same principal. It renders all shapes using 2D drawing API in &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/API/Canvas_API/Tutorial&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;canvas&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;svg&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;. Spheres are actually dots. Toruses are actually circles . Capsules are actually thick lines. It’s a simple, but effective trick. The underlying 3D math comes from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.khanacademy.org/computing/computer-programming/programming-games-visualizations/programming-3d-shapes/a/rotating-3d-shapes&quot;&gt;Rotating 3D Shapes&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://petercollingridge.appspot.com/3D-tutorial/rotating-objects&quot;&gt;Peter Collingridge&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zdog is pronounced “Zee-dog” in American parlance or “Zed-dog” in British.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zdog v1 is a beta-release, of sorts. This is my first time creating a 3D engine, so I probably got some stuff wrong. Expect lots of changes for v2. Provide input and select new features on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/metafizzy/zdog/issues&quot;&gt;Zdog issue tracker on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 01:47:53 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>tomek_zemla</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://zzz.dog/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Advertising as a source of dissatisfaction: cross-national evidence</title>
<link>https://voxeu.org/article/advertising-major-source-human-dissatisfaction</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://voxeu.org/article/advertising-major-source-human-dissatisfaction</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Advertising as a major source of human dissatisfaction: Cross-national evidence on one million Europeans&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;362&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advertising is ubiquitous. In recent decades, the volume of advertising has been growing dramatically. Therefore, it is natural to ask if this harms our wellbeing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We do not perfectly understand the link between advertising and individual wellbeing. It is reasonable to assume that it might operate through two broad channels that have opposing effects:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Positive: advertising informs&lt;/strong&gt;. It may promote human welfare by allowing people to make better choices about products. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Negative: advertising stimulates desires that are not feasible&lt;/strong&gt;. This creates dissatisfaction. Hence, advertising might reduce welfare by unduly raising consumption aspirations. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the national level, we do not know which of the two effects is dominant. Many national variables influence wellbeing, in particular the generosity of the welfare state and variables such as unemployment (DiTella et al. 2001, DiTella et al. 2003, and Radcliff 2013). But recent research on subjective wellbeing, described in sources such as Easterlin (2003), Oswald (1997), Layard (2005) and Clark (2018), has paid little attention to the role of advertising, and so there are no cross-country econometric studies of the effect of advertising using representative samples of adults. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Keeping up with the Joneses&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this context, is a reasonable hypothesis that advertising has a negative effect on wellbeing. Easterlin (1974) found early evidence suggesting that society does not become happier as it grows richer. He suggested that one mechanism might be that individuals compare themselves with their neighbours. Easterlin’s thesis, in part, assumes that we desire conspicuous consumption (Veblen 1899, 1904). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If individuals have ‘relativistic’ preferences, so that they look at others before deciding how satisfied they feel, then when they consume more goods, they fail to become happier because they see others also consuming more. The pleasure of my new car is taken away if Ms Jones, in the parking spot next to mine, has also just bought one. More recent evidence on ‘comparison effects’ has been reviewed by Clark (2018). Mujcic and Oswald (2018) also find longitudinal evidence of negative wellbeing consequences based on envy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since Veblen, many researchers have worried about negative effects on wellbeing of advertising. In some cases they have found small-scale evidence (examples include Richins 1995, Easterlin and Crimmins 1991, Bagwell and Bernheim 1996, Sirgy et al. 1998, Dittmar et al. 2014, Frey et al. 2007, and Harris et al. 2009). Research has focused on the likely detrimental effects upon children (Andreyeva et al. 2011, Borzekowski and Robinson 2001, Buijzen and Valkenburg 2003a, Opree et al. 2013, and Buijzen and Valkenburg 2003b), although the most recent work, by Opree et al. (2016), produced inconclusive results. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Evidence of a negative effect&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have found evidence of negative links between national advertising and national wellbeing (Michel et al. 2019). Using longitudinal information on countries, from pooled cross-sectional surveys, we find that rises and falls in advertising are followed, a few years later, by falls and rises in national life-satisfaction, giving an inverse connection between advertising levels and the later wellbeing levels of nations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We took a sample of slightly over 900,000 randomly sampled European citizens in 27 countries, surveyed annually from 1980 to 2011. Respondents reported their level of life satisfaction and many other aspects of themselves and their lives. We also recorded total advertising expenditure levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Figure 1 illustrates the study’s key idea. It divides the data into tertiles and then plots the (uncorrected) relationship between the change in advertising and the change in life satisfaction. The three vertical bars separate the data into countries that had particularly large increases in advertising expenditure, moderate increases, and small increases. Figure 1 shows that the greater the rise in advertising within a nation, the smaller the later improvement in life satisfaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 1&lt;/strong&gt; The inverse longitudinal relationship between changes in advertising and changes in the life satisfaction of countries, 1980 to 2011&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://voxeu.org/sites/default/files/image/FromMay2014/proto27mayfig1.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;Notes&lt;/em&gt;: Based on a sample of approximately 1 million individuals. Based on shorter period if data not available for that country. Bottom Tertile consists of Czech Republic, Germany after 1989, Estonia, Finland, Lithuania, Hungary, Latvia, Poland, Romania, Slovakia. Mean change 2.93. Middle Tertile consists of Bulgaria, Western Germany (before 1989), Denmark, UK, Sweden, Slovenia, Netherlands, Turkey, Spain. Mean Change: 2.15. Top tertile consists of Austria, Belgium, France, Greece, Croatia, Ireland, Italy, Norway, Portugal. Mean change 1.46.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advertising does not have a spurious association with life satisfaction that is attributable merely to the business cycle. Using standard regression analysis, we were able to show that the negative effect of advertisement on life satisfaction is not due to the correlation of both variables with the GDP. This negative effect is robust to the inclusion of other variables like country and year fixed effects, unemployment, and individual socioeconomic characteristics that are typically included in any happiness equation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The effect implies that a hypothetical doubling of advertising expenditure would result in a 3% drop in life satisfaction. That is approximately one half the absolute size of the marriage effect on life satisfaction, or approximately one quarter of the absolute size of the effect of being unemployed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These results are consistent with concerns that were first more than a century ago, and regularly since (Veblen 1904 and Robinson 1933, for example). They are consistent with Easterlin (1974, 2003) and Layard (1980). They may also be consistent with ideas about the negative consequences of materialism (Sirgy et al. 2012, Burroughs and Rindfleisch 2002, Speck and Roy 2008, and Snyder and Debono 1985). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although there is evidence of an inverse longitudinal relationship between national advertising and national dissatisfaction, we still need to uncover the causal mechanism. But this demands investigation, because the size of the estimated effect here is both substantial and statistically well-determined. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andreyeva T, I R Kelly, R Inas, and J L Harris (2011), &quot;Exposure to food advertising on television: Associations with children’s fast food and soft drink consumption and obesity&quot;, &lt;em&gt;Economics and Human Biology&lt;/em&gt; 9: 221-313.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bagwell L S and B D Bernheim (1996), &quot;Veblen effects in a theory of conspicuous consumption&quot;, &lt;em&gt;American Economic Review&lt;/em&gt; 86: 349-373.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Borzekowski D L G and T N Robinson (2001), &quot;The 30-second effect: An experiment revealing the impact of television commercials on food preferences of pre-schoolers&quot;, &lt;em&gt;Journal of the American Dietetic Association&lt;/em&gt; 101: 42–46.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Buijzen M and P M Valkenburg PM (2003a), &quot;The unintended effects of television advertising: A parent-child survey&quot;, &lt;em&gt;Communication Research&lt;/em&gt; 30: 483–503.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Buizjen M and P M Valkenburg PM (2003b), &quot;The effects of television advertising on materialism, parent-child conflict, and unhappiness: A review of research&quot;, &lt;em&gt;Journal of Applied Developmental Psychology&lt;/em&gt; 24: 437-456.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Burroughs J E and A Rindfleisch (2002), &quot;Materialism and well-being: A conflicting values perspective&quot;, &lt;em&gt;Journal of Consumer Research&lt;/em&gt; 29: 348-370.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clark A E (2018), &quot;Four decades of the economics of happiness: Where next?&quot;, &lt;em&gt;Review of Income and Wealth&lt;/em&gt; 64: 245-269.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Di Tella R, R J MacCulloch, and A J Oswald (2001), &quot;Preferences over inflation and unemployment: Evidence from surveys of happiness&quot;, &lt;em&gt;American Economic Review&lt;/em&gt; 91: 335-341.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Di Tella R, R J MacCulloch, and A J Oswald (2003), &quot;The macroeconomics of happiness&quot;, &lt;em&gt;Review of Economics and Statistics&lt;/em&gt; 85: 809-827.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dittmar H, R Bond, M Hurst M, and T Kassar (2014), &quot;The relationship between materialism and personal well-being: A meta-analysis&quot;, &lt;em&gt;Journal of Personality and Social Psychology&lt;/em&gt; 107: 879-924.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Easterlin R A (1974), Does economic growth improve the human lot? Some empirical evidence, in: P A David and M W Reder (eds.), Nations and households in economic growth: Essays in honor of Moses Abramowitz&lt;/em&gt;. Academic Press: 89-125.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Easterlin R A (2003), &quot;Explaining happiness&quot;, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the USA&lt;/em&gt; 100: 11176-11183.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Easterlin R A and Crimmins E M (1991), &quot;Private materialism, personal self-fulfillment, family life, and public interest&quot;, &lt;em&gt;Public Opinion Quarterly&lt;/em&gt; 55: 499-533.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frey B, C Denesch, and A Stutzer (2007), &quot;Does watching TV makes us happy?&quot;, &lt;em&gt;Journal of Economic Psychology&lt;/em&gt; 28: 283–313.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harris J L, J A Bargh, and K D Brownell (2009), &quot;Priming effects of television food advertising on eating behaviour&quot;, &lt;em&gt;Health Psychology&lt;/em&gt; 28: 404–413.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Layard R (2005), &lt;em&gt;Happiness: Lessons from a new science,&lt;/em&gt; Penguin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Michel C, M Sovinsky, E Proto, A J Oswald (forthcoming), &quot;Advertising as a Major Source of Human Dissatisfaction: Cross-National Evidence on One Million Europeans&quot;, to be published in 2019 in a volume in honor of Richard Easterlin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Opree S J, M Buizjen and E A van Reijmersdal (2016), &quot;The impact of advertising on children’s psychological wellbeing and life satisfaction&quot;, &lt;em&gt;European Journal of Marketing&lt;/em&gt; 50: 1975-1992.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oswald A J (1997), &quot;Happiness and economic performance&quot;, &lt;em&gt;Economic Journal&lt;/em&gt; 107: 1815-1831.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Radcliff B (2013), &lt;em&gt;The political economy of human happiness: How voters’ choices determine the quality of life,&lt;/em&gt; Cambridge University Press.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robinson J (1933), &lt;em&gt;Economics of imperfect competition&lt;/em&gt;, Macmillan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sirgy M J, D J Lee, R Kosenko, H L Meadow, D Rahtz, M Cicic, G Xi Jin, D Yarsuvat, D L Blenkhorn, and N Wright (1998), Does television viewership play a role in the perception of quality of life? Journal of Advertising 27: 125-142.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sirgy J M, E Gurel-Atay, D Webb, M Cicic, M Husic, A Ekici, A Herrmann, I Hegazy, D-J Lee, and J S Johar (2012), &quot;Linking advertising, materialism, and life satisfaction&quot;, Social Indicators Research 107: 79-101.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Snyder M and K G Debono (1985), &quot;Appeals to image and claims about quality – Understanding the psychology of advertising&quot;, Journal of Personality and Social Psychology 49: 586-597.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speck S K, A Roy (2008), &quot;The interrelationships between television viewing, values and perceived well-being: A global perspective&quot;, Journal of International Business Studies 39: 1197-1219.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Veblen T (1899), The Theory of the Leisure Class, Macmillan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Veblen T (1904), The Theory of Business Enterprise, Charles Scribner’s Sons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 20:26:43 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>howard941</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://voxeu.org/article/advertising-major-source-human-dissatisfaction</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Scene report from the Chernobyl Zone</title>
<link>https://moxie.org/stories/chernobyl-scene-report/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://moxie.org/stories/chernobyl-scene-report/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Surreptitiously crossing the Uzh river at 2am, with the full moon starting to set low on the horizon, the first thing that strikes you about the Chernobyl Exclusion Zone is the sound of it. Just two hours outside of Kiev, all the sounds of civilization disappear, and only our radiation dosimeters are left ticking softly with the wind.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But moving into the zone on the other side of the river, it's not silence we're met with. Even in the darkness, it's immediately clear that the forest has retaken the Chernobyl Zone, and the forest is &lt;em&gt;alive&lt;/em&gt;. It's a reverberating symphony of birds, frogs, crickets, cicadas — even wolves howling in the distance. Navigating hesitantly through those first few kilometers, we moved as silently and nimbly as we could, in quiet awe to the sounds of life and the expanse of the moonlit trees around us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then, with the shock of a sound that doesn't belong, &quot;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WHAM-&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&quot; a 6-liter bottle of water fell off the back of Geoff's bicycle, exploding when it hit the ground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The three of us had decided to try to explore the zone by bicycle. Even after 30 years and an intensive 10-year remediation effort, it's a contaminated landscape. It's dangerous to consume anything from within the zone, since it could contain Strontium-90, which your body can mistake for calcium and absorb into your bones, eventually causing bone cancer. That meant we would have to carry in all the food and water we'd need for the duration of our trip. Hiking with food isn't so bad, but water?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We considered a number of options. Could we just carry it? No, we'd need at least 5 gallons each, which would mean 180lbs for the three of us. There was no way we'd make it 80 kilometers with that. Maybe a hand truck, or a wagon? Eventually we settled on bicycles, figuring that even if the terrain didn't always allow us to ride, we'd at least be able to push them with the water strapped to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;10 minutes in, we were down 6 liters. We spent some time re-securing everything, all of us keen to avoid a situation where we'd have to make a choice between dehydration and drinking radioactive water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our immediate destination was the city of Pripyat. When the V.I. Lenin Nuclear Power Station was built, the closest major town was Chernobyl (14km away), which is how people came to refer to the plant. But a new city of 50,000 called Pripyat was built simultaneously with the plant to both house workers and serve as a utopian model for future Soviet development. This ghost city was our first destination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We didn't know exactly what to expect for the trip, or if it would work at all. We had Google Maps satellite imagery, a rough idea of where the military checkpoints were, and a $5 compass. In the end, the easiest thing to do was just follow the old power lines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was 40km from the edge of the zone to Pripyat, and we wanted to be there before 7am, which is when we surmised that security would become more of an issue. We spent the night tiptoing around razor wire, coasting silently through sleeping checkpoints, and riding frantically through the dark from some surprisingly alert and vigilant guard dogs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But mostly, we just gasped at the beauty and wonder of our surroundings. Watching an enormous buck with towering antlers cross through the twilight in front of us, it felt more like we were in some remote part of Alaska, but superimposed onto the rusting hammers and sickles of forgotten Soviet infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-permalink=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/Bxyb79uhdRh/&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;12&quot; readability=&quot;-10.616071428571&quot;&gt;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-permalink=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/BxyekrXh8Gm/&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;12&quot; readability=&quot;-10.616071428571&quot;&gt;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-permalink=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/BxyeVDKheEP/&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;12&quot; readability=&quot;-10.616071428571&quot;&gt;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a much longer and much harder ride than we expected. The sun came up at 4am, and we rode on through the early hours, pushing to reach Pripyat on time. Once or twice we considered ducking off in little abandoned villages we'd come across in order to wait out the day, but the radiation levels were always too high in the structures we found. So we kept riding, passing old rail yards, forgotten communist monuments, and rusting machinery. When we eventually found ourselves in the city, the lack of transition was surreal. As we were riding through the forest, willing ourselves to keep a steady pace after an all-night journey, we suddenly became aware that there were already 7-story apartment buildings looming up all around us, just behind the first few rows of trees. Block after block after block of giant imponderable buildings, all standing silently within the surrounding woods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exhausted, we picked an apartment building at random and went in. Our initial thought was to camp on the roof, but the radiation on the roof's surface was over 50 μSv/hr, so we moved to apartment #23 instead. The radiation there was only 0.08 μSv/hr (actually lower than our apartment in California). The former occupants must have had their windows closed when the explosion occurred. We collapsed and slept for most of the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-permalink=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/BxzxyBche1R/&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;12&quot; readability=&quot;-10.616071428571&quot;&gt;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When reactor No 4 exploded, there was a lot of initial confusion about the magnitude of the accident. For a number of reasons, it was a full 36 hours before authorities realized that four days in Pripyat would result in a lethal dose for its occupants, and finally ordered the evacuation. Residents were given 2 hours to pack whatever they could carry and get on a bus. Most were under the impression that they would be returning within 3 or 4 days, but they were never allowed back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at the newspapers and books scattered about apartment #23, the packed suitcases sitting where they were left, the clothes pins still sitting on the same clothes lines where they must have been 33 years ago, you can feel the abruptness of the city's end. This wasn't a ghost town that slowly petered out over decades until there was nobody left, it was a densely constructed city of 50 thousand where everyone left at the exact same moment, and nobody ever came back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-permalink=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/Bxzze2eBHTm/&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;12&quot; readability=&quot;-10.616071428571&quot;&gt;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-captioned=&quot;&quot; data-instgrm-permalink=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/Bx0DvrrBAAn/&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;12&quot; readability=&quot;-8.3393665158371&quot;&gt;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our time in Pripyat was vivid. We'd have to hide and move cautiously during the day, but at night! The night was ours. We wandered around the rooftops, through the squares of the city, and into as many buildings as we could — each one more stunning than the one before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We found the stadium, which underscores the vibe of the entire place: where the crumbling empty stands should look out onto the pitch, there is only forest. Standing in the bleachers, listening to the Pripyat municipal overture of resounding bird song, the only thing we could do was stare out at the trees and wonder &quot;how long until New York looks like this?&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-permalink=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/Bx0-GIuBWf6/&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;12&quot; readability=&quot;-10.616071428571&quot;&gt;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-captioned=&quot;&quot; data-instgrm-permalink=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/Bx07ZKRBIit/&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;12&quot; readability=&quot;-5.8378378378378&quot;&gt;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-captioned=&quot;&quot; data-instgrm-permalink=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/Bx1AQJ7BzZN/&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;12&quot; readability=&quot;-12.16&quot;&gt;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over six hundred thousand people were directly involved in dealing with the aftermath of the Chernobyl explosion. The early days were filled with incredible sacrifice. Immediately after the accident, one of the first priorities was to put out the burning nuclear material that was sending a radioactive steam cloud billowing into the sky. Without a way to approach the reactor directly, they flew helicopter sorties over it with crews inside who &lt;em&gt;threw bags of sand out the doors&lt;/em&gt; and into the crater, slowly filling it. When the sand started to melt, they did the same thing with lead. Some pilots flew up to 33 sorties into the steam cloud, and &lt;em&gt;six hundred helicopter pilots were killed&lt;/em&gt; by the radiation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When that material then started to smolder downwards out through the floor of the chamber, it threatened to come into contact with a large amount of water that had pooled there as a result of early firefighter attempts to put it out with hoses. This would have ignited a second reaction that would have been the equivalent of a 5 megaton explosion. It would have leveled Kiev and Minsk, and would have ejected the nuclear material from the other 3 Chernobyl reactors with a force that would have rendered much of Europe uninhabitable for hundreds of years. With only days to stop it, Alexei Ananenko, Valeri Bezpalov, and Boris Baranov went into the ruins of the plant, knowingly facing almost certain death from that level of radiation exposure, to release valves that would drain 5 million gallons of water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the same radioactive magma threatened to melt through the concrete pad below that and into the groundwater for 50 million people, miners dug a 150 meter tunnel 12ft under ground &lt;em&gt;by hand&lt;/em&gt; to stop it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the firefighters from the first night, before they understood that this was not just a fire, showed up at the hospital sick and suffering from radiation burns, the medical staff there knew that they must have been severely contaminated, but they stayed and treated them anyway, potentially exposing themselves to the same fate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every interview I've seen or account that I've read from those involved, most of whom died within weeks or have suffered life-long health problems, has a common theme of no regrets; the sentiment almost universally &quot;It had to be done. Who would I expect to do it instead of me?&quot; &lt;img src=&quot;https://moxie.org/stories/chernobyl-scene-report/theobject.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Object&quot; class=&quot;center&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;The New Safe Confinment, also known as 'The Object'. This cost $1.8 billion to construct, $60 million a year to maintain, and is rated for 100 years. The financial costs of the accident appear to be never ending.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's so much in Pripyat that by the time we had to leave, we had probably explored less than 1% of the city. We went out on the same road that the residents did 33 years ago. Riding across the zone under the full moon, we'd stop sometimes and stare out at the woods and fields around us, all alone in the middle of that huge seeming expanse. The experience is full of tensions. It is so beautiful and so peaceful that it really feels like paradise, but it's a paradise that you can't enjoy. You have to be careful about where you sit, what you eat, how you eat it, what you touch; which is — ironically — why it exists. The reason it's so beautiful and so peaceful is precisely because we can't consume it. Like, perhaps, all real paradises everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-captioned=&quot;&quot; data-instgrm-permalink=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/Bx2YGEeh5Fe/&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;12&quot; readability=&quot;-6.9105058365759&quot;&gt;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we finally left the zone and made it back to Kiev, I was largely struck by how normal everything is there — there's almost no sign that the apocalypse is only 2hrs away. No physical signs at all, in fact. Around town there are statues of former princes, religious monuments, a memorial to the veterans of the Afghanistan war. On the bills of the currency, the faces of 10th century princes, politicians, poets, and writers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What of the helicopter pilots who killed themselves to put out the most toxic fire in history? What about the people who knowingly sacrificed themselves to stop a reaction that would have destroyed most of Europe? Who were the miners that dug the tunnel through radioactive ground to save the water supply for 50 million people? They have no public monuments, we do not know their faces, their names are not etched onto the buildings that are still standing because of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't know all of their names, but I'm thinking of them here, in this place, amongst the living.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 16:45:34 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>BCM43</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://moxie.org/stories/chernobyl-scene-report/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Simple Dockerfile examples are often broken by default</title>
<link>https://pythonspeed.com/articles/dockerizing-python-is-hard/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://pythonspeed.com/articles/dockerizing-python-is-hard/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;When it’s time to package up your Python application into a Docker image, the natural thing to do is search the web for some examples. And a quick search will provide you with plenty of simple, easy examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, these simple, easy examples are often broken in a variety of ways, some obvious, some less so. To demonstrate just some of the ways they’re broken, I’m going to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Start with an example &lt;code&gt;Dockerfile&lt;/code&gt; that comes up fairly high on some Google searches.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Show how it’s broken.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Give some suggestions on how to make it less broken.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; Outside the specific topic under discussion, the Dockerfiles in this article are not examples of best practices, since the added complexity would obscure the main point of the article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn more about &lt;a href=&quot;https://pythonspeed.com/products/pythoncontainer/&quot;&gt;best-practices Docker images for Python&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Broken by default&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider the following &lt;code&gt;Dockerfile&lt;/code&gt;, which I found by searching for Python Dockerization examples. I’ve made some minor changes to disguise its origin, but otherwise it is the same:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-dockerfile&quot; data-lang=&quot;dockerfile&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# DO NOT USE THIS DOCKERFILE AS AN EXAMPLE, IT IS BROKEN&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;FROM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt; python:3&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;COPY&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt; yourscript.py /&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;RUN &lt;/span&gt;pip &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;install &lt;/span&gt;flask

&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;CMD&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt; [ &quot;python&quot;, &quot;./yourscript.py&quot; ]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Some of the problems with this Dockerfile&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How many different problems can you spot in this image?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Problem #1: Non-reproducible builds re Python version&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing to notice is that this &lt;code&gt;Dockerfile&lt;/code&gt; is based off of the &lt;code&gt;python:3&lt;/code&gt; image. At the time of writing this will install Python 3.7, but at some point it will switch to installing Python 3.8.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At that point rebuilding the image will switch to a different version of Python, which might break the software: a minor change in your code can lead to a deploy that breaks production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solution:&lt;/strong&gt; Use &lt;code&gt;python:3.7&lt;/code&gt; as the base image.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Problem #2: Non-reproducible builds re dependencies.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, &lt;code&gt;flask&lt;/code&gt; is installed with no versioning, so each time the image is rebuilt potentially a new version of &lt;code&gt;flask&lt;/code&gt; (or one of its dependencies, or one of its dependencies’ dependencies) will change. If they’re compatible, great, but there’s no guarantee that is the case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solution:&lt;/strong&gt; Create &lt;code&gt;requirements.txt&lt;/code&gt; with transitively-pinned versions of all dependencies, e.g. &lt;a href=&quot;https://hynek.me/articles/python-app-deps-2018/&quot;&gt;by using &lt;code&gt;pip-tools&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Problem #3: Changes to source code invalidate the build cache&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want fast builds, you want to rely on Docker’s layer caching. But by copying in the file before running &lt;code&gt;pip install&lt;/code&gt;, all later layers are invalidated—this image will be rebuilt from scratch every time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solution:&lt;/strong&gt; Copy in files only when they’re first needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Problem #4: Running as root, which is insecure&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By default Docker containers run as root, &lt;a href=&quot;http://canihaznonprivilegedcontainers.info/&quot;&gt;which is a security risk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solution:&lt;/strong&gt; It’s much better to run as a non-root user, and do so in the image itself so that you don’t listen on ports&amp;lt;1024 or do other operations that require a subset of root’s permissions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;A somewhat better image&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s a somewhat better—though still not ideal—Dockerfile that addresses the issues above:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-dockerfile&quot; data-lang=&quot;dockerfile&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;FROM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt; python:3.7&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;COPY&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt; requirements.txt /tmp/&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;RUN &lt;/span&gt;pip &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;install&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;-r&lt;/span&gt; /tmp/requirements.txt

&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;RUN &lt;/span&gt;useradd &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;--create-home&lt;/span&gt; appuser
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;WORKDIR&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt; /home/appuser&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;USER&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt; appuser&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;COPY&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt; yourscript.py .&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;CMD&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt; [ &quot;python&quot;, &quot;./yourscript.py&quot; ]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if the resulting image was something you’d want to run in production—and it almost certainly isn’t!—the image is still insufficient on its own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, you also need to regularly update &lt;code&gt;requirements.txt&lt;/code&gt; in a controlled manner, in order to get security updates and bug fixes, and you’ll need to &lt;a href=&quot;https://pythonspeed.com/articles/docker-cache-insecure-images/&quot;&gt;regularly rebuild your images without caching to get security updates&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And there are many more improvements you could make to get this closer to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://pythonspeed.com/products/pythoncontainer/&quot;&gt;production-ready Python container&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Be careful what you learn from&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A broken Docker image can lead to production outages, and building best-practices images is a lot harder than it seems.&lt;/strong&gt; So don’t just copy the first example you find on the web: do your research, and spend some time reading about best practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a starting point, I recommend the &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.docker.com/develop/develop-images/dockerfile_best-practices/&quot;&gt;official Dockerfile&lt;/a&gt; best practices documentation, &lt;a href=&quot;https://hynek.me/articles/&quot;&gt;Hynek’s articles&lt;/a&gt;, and of course the various articles on this site about &lt;a href=&quot;https://pythonspeed.com/articles/#docker&quot;&gt;Docker packaging for Python&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 16:33:59 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>itamarst</dc:creator>
<og:title>Broken by default: why you should avoid most Dockerfile examples</og:title>
<og:description>When it’s time to package up your Python application into a Docker image, the natural thing to do is search the web for some examples. And a quick search will provide you with plenty of simple, easy examples. Unfortunately, these simple, easy examples are often broken in a variety of ways, some obvious, some less so. To demonstrate just some of the ways they’re broken, I’m going to: Start with an example Dockerfile that comes up fairly high on some Google searches. Show how it’s broken. Give some suggestions on how to make it less broken. Note: Outside the specific topic under discussion, the Dockerfiles in this article are not examples of best practices, since the added complexity would obscure the main point of the article. Learn more about best-practices Docker images for Python.</og:description>
<og:url>https://pythonspeed.com/articles/dockerizing-python-is-hard/</og:url>
<og:image>https://pythonspeed.com/assets/titles/dockerizing-python-is-hard.png</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://pythonspeed.com/articles/dockerizing-python-is-hard/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Blackbird SR-71 Flight Manual (2010)</title>
<link>https://www.sr-71.org/blackbird/manual/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.sr-71.org/blackbird/manual/</guid>
<description>&lt;h2 class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the first time, the SR-71 Flight Manual is available online. The manual was declassified several years ago and has now been made free to the public. When a document becomes declassified, it also becomes public domain. No copyright is asserted for the content that is presented on this web site from the SR-71 Flight Manual. However, I do ask that you cite SR-71 Online as your source if you plan to use this content. I hold distribution rights on this particular presentation since this reproduction is my work in general, and a lot of work was put into this production. If you plan to mirror this site, please be sure to ask for permission at my &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sr-71.org/contact/&quot;&gt;contact page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;How To Use This Resource&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This resource is to educate the public about the operation of the SR-71 reconnaissance aircraft. All sections of the manual have been included in the web-based reproduction. This section of the site is best viewed at 1280 x 1024 resolution. A resolution of 1024 x 768 is recommended and a minimum resolution of 800 x 600 is required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Table of Contents below is as how it appears in the actual flight manual, but has been presented in web form for easy access to the manual's content. The manual may be read continuously by clicking on the 'Next' or 'Back' links found on each page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;Missing Pages Report&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All pages from any known current declassified editions are posted on this web site. A few pages are still missing from the manual that this was scanned from. Be sure to check back for updates and new additions. This manual is ISSUE E, CHANGE 2 and is 1052 pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;1-28A, 1-28B, 1-174, 1-175: Lost or missing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;4-150 through 4-160: Still classified&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 16:30:25 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>hazzamanic</dc:creator>
<dc:format>application/xhtml+xml</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.sr-71.org/blackbird/manual/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>iPhone apps share data with trackers, ad companies and research firms</title>
<link>https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2019/05/28/its-middle-night-do-you-know-who-your-iphone-is-talking/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2019/05/28/its-middle-night-do-you-know-who-your-iphone-is-talking/</guid>
<description>&lt;div data-elm-loc=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;inline-content inline-photo inline-photo-normal&quot;&gt; &lt;img class=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/j-lXsZIPDTCITSMZAeLQTVTw2BI=/1484x0/arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/7YLP3KO5JJABVNGSZKTDRQ4UMY.jpg&quot; data-hi-res-src=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/j-lXsZIPDTCITSMZAeLQTVTw2BI=/1484x0/arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/7YLP3KO5JJABVNGSZKTDRQ4UMY.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/vMYQqahPR9Yh3PoU_wUnso47_nU=/480x0/arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/7YLP3KO5JJABVNGSZKTDRQ4UMY.jpg 480w,https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/j-lXsZIPDTCITSMZAeLQTVTw2BI=/1484x0/arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/7YLP3KO5JJABVNGSZKTDRQ4UMY.jpg 1484w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 768px) 50vw, 100vw&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pb-caption&quot;&gt;While you’re sleeping, your iPhone stays busy. (Washington Post Illustration; iStock/The Washington Post)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;author-sig-line-wrapper analysis-story&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author-headshot&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/people/geoffrey-a-fowler/&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;unprocessed _1-to-1 placeholder&quot; src=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/yAFxThroW-CI5t-yu8Q6FsF7kHI=/1x1/www.washingtonpost.com/pb/resources/img/spacer.gif&quot; data-hi-res-src=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/K1R5VDaeWWm3l3fmT-2pACLFafo=/90x90/s3.amazonaws.com/arc-authors/washpost/059a0168-736b-43cb-9473-20e8b42e454f.png&quot; data-low-res-src=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/2ruBmULaYoBtOnrmlVVrYJaE5EY=/29x29/s3.amazonaws.com/arc-authors/washpost/059a0168-736b-43cb-9473-20e8b42e454f.png&quot; data-raw-src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/arc-authors/washpost/059a0168-736b-43cb-9473-20e8b42e454f.png&quot; data-threshold=&quot;29&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author-sig-line&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;author-wrapper&quot; data-authorname=&quot;Geoffrey A. Fowler&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author-info&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author-role&quot;&gt;Technology columnist&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;author-timestamp&quot; itemprop=&quot;datePublished&quot; content=&quot;2019-05-28T08:00-500&quot;&gt;May 28 at 8:00 AM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;2&quot;&gt;It’s 3 a.m. Do you know what your iPhone is doing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;3&quot;&gt;Mine has been alarmingly busy. Even though the screen is off and I’m snoring, apps are beaming out lots of information about me to companies I’ve never heard of. Your iPhone probably is doing the same — and Apple could be doing more to stop it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;4&quot;&gt;On a recent Monday night, a dozen marketing companies, research firms and other personal data guzzlers got reports from my iPhone. At 11:43 p.m., a company called Amplitude learned my phone number, email and exact location. At 3:58 a.m., another called Appboy got a digital fingerprint of my phone. At 6:25 a.m., a tracker called Demdex received a way to identify my phone and sent back a list of other trackers to pair up with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;5&quot;&gt;And all night long, there was some startling behavior by a household name: Yelp. It was receiving a message that included my IP address -— once every five minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;6&quot; class=&quot;interstitial-link&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;[&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2019/05/28/how-limit-iphone-app-tracking/?utm_term=.bddbf9fe7418&quot;&gt;What you can do to limit app tracking: 5 privacy tips&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;7&quot;&gt;Our data has a secret life in many of the devices we use every day, from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2019/05/06/alexa-has-been-eavesdropping-you-this-whole-time/?utm_term=.adaaa67e5b7d&quot;&gt;talking Alexa speakers&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/the-switch/wp/2018/06/15/hands-off-my-data-15-more-default-privacy-settings-you-should-change-on-your-tv-cellphone-plan-linkedin-and-more/?utm_term=.ad4a09e04d65&quot;&gt;smart TVs&lt;/a&gt;. But we’ve got a giant blind spot when it comes to the data companies probing our phones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;8&quot;&gt;You might assume you can count on Apple to sweat all the privacy details. After all, it &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2019/01/07/apple-burns-google-giant-billboard-touting-privacy-ces/?utm_term=.098a6ad77172&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;touted in a recent ad&lt;/a&gt;, “What happens on your iPhone stays on your iPhone.” My investigation suggests otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;9&quot;&gt;IPhone apps I discovered tracking me by passing information to third parties — just while I was asleep — include Microsoft OneDrive, Intuit’s Mint, Nike, Spotify, The Washington Post and IBM’s the Weather Channel. One app, the crime-alert service Citizen, shared personally identifiable information in violation of its published privacy policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;10&quot;&gt;And your iPhone doesn’t only feed data trackers while you sleep. In a single week, I encountered over 5,400 trackers, mostly in apps, not including the incessant Yelp traffic. According to privacy firm &lt;a href=&quot;https://disconnect.me/&quot;&gt;Disconnect&lt;/a&gt;, which helped test my iPhone, those unwanted trackers would have spewed out 1.5 gigabytes of data over the span of a month. That’s half of an entire basic wireless service plan from AT&amp;amp;T.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div data-elm-loc=&quot;11&quot; class=&quot;inline-content inline-video&quot;&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;12&quot;&gt;“This is your data. Why should it even leave your phone? Why should it be collected by someone when you don’t know what they’re going to do with it?” says Patrick Jackson, a former National Security Agency researcher who is chief technology officer for Disconnect. He hooked my iPhone into special software so we could examine the traffic. “I know the value of data, and I don’t want mine in any hands where it doesn’t need to be,” he told me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;13&quot;&gt;In a world of data brokers, Jackson is the data breaker. He developed an app called &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/disconnect-privacy-pro-entire/id1057771839?ls=1&amp;amp;mt=8&quot;&gt;Privacy Pro&lt;/a&gt; that identifies and blocks many trackers. If you’re a little bit techie, I recommend trying the free iOS version to glimpse the secret life of your iPhone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;14&quot;&gt;Yes, trackers are a problem on phones running Google’s Android, too. Google &lt;a href=&quot;https://disconnect.me/blog/update-android-app-is-still-banned-from-play-and-google-wont-talk-about-it&quot;&gt;won’t even let Disconnect’s tracker-protection software&lt;/a&gt; into its Play Store. (Google’s rules prohibit apps that might interfere with another app displaying ads.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;15&quot; class=&quot;interstitial-link&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;[&lt;a href=&quot;https://hosted-washpost.submissionplatform.com/sub/hosted/5c7808290310870034cc0d8f&quot;&gt;Help Desk: Ask our tech columnist a question&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;16&quot;&gt;Part of Jackson’s objection to trackers is that many feed the personal data economy, used to target us for marketing and political messaging. Facebook’s fiascos have made us all more aware of how our data can be passed along, stolen and misused — but Cambridge Analytica was just the beginning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;17&quot;&gt;Jackson’s biggest concern is transparency: If we don’t know where our data is going, how can we ever hope to keep it private?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div data-elm-loc=&quot;18&quot; class=&quot;inline-content inline-photo inline-photo-normal&quot;&gt; &lt;img class=&quot;unprocessed _3-to-2 placeholder&quot; src=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/TXJKur-cQ3m4AF9lqk_kkjfemkk=/3x2/www.washingtonpost.com/pb/resources/img/spacer.gif&quot; data-hi-res-src=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/_2UQidN5lv7YhOgvY5JU1B-kT2c=/1484x0/arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/2ATIAYAQSZDDHFGVKG6OFSSWDM.jpg&quot; data-low-res-src=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/8l5HqLX3l6mOLNweB9pi3tC6VIw=/480x0/arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/2ATIAYAQSZDDHFGVKG6OFSSWDM.jpg&quot; data-raw-src=&quot;https://arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/2ATIAYAQSZDDHFGVKG6OFSSWDM.jpg&quot; data-threshold=&quot;480&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pb-caption&quot;&gt;Patrick Jackson, chief technology officer for Disconnect, hooked columnist Geoffrey A. Fowler's iPhone into software so they could examine the personal data flowing out of the phone. (James Pace-Cornsilk/The Washington Post)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 data-elm-loc=&quot;19&quot;&gt;The app gap&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;20&quot;&gt;App trackers are like the cookies on websites that slow load times, waste battery life and cause creepy ads to follow you around the Internet. Except in apps, there’s little notice trackers are lurking and you can’t choose a different browser to block them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;21&quot;&gt;Why do trackers activate in the middle of the night? Some app makers have them call home at times the phone is plugged in, or think they won’t interfere with other functions. These late-night encounters happen on the iPhone if you have allowed “background app refresh,” which is Apple’s default.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;22&quot;&gt;With Yelp, the company says the behavior I uncovered wasn’t a tracker but rather an “unintended issue” that’s been acting like a tracker. Yelp thinks my discovery affects 1 percent of its iOS users, particularly those who’ve made reservations through Apple Maps. At best, it is shoddy software that sent Yelp data it didn’t need. At worst, Yelp was amassing a data trove that could be used to map people’s travels, even when they weren’t using its app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;23&quot;&gt;A more typical example is DoorDash, the food-delivery service. Launch that app, and you’re sending data to nine third-party trackers — though you’d have no way to know it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;24&quot;&gt;App makers often use trackers because they’re shortcuts to research or revenue. They run the gamut from innocuous to insidious. Some are like consultants that app makers pay to analyze what people tap on and look at. Other trackers pay the app makers, squeezing value out of our data to target ads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;25&quot; class=&quot;interstitial-link&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;[&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/the-switch/wp/2018/06/01/hands-off-my-data-15-default-privacy-settings-you-should-change-right-now/?utm_term=.cf475188071c&quot;&gt;Hands off my data! 15 default privacy settings you should change right now.&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;26&quot;&gt;In the case of DoorDash, one tracker called Sift Science gets a fingerprint of your phone (device name, model, ad identifier and memory size) and even accelerometer motion data to help identify fraud. Three more trackers help DoorDash monitor app performance — including one called Segment that routes onward data including your delivery address, name, email and cell carrier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;27&quot;&gt;DoorDash’s other five trackers, including Facebook and Google Ad Services, help it understand the effectiveness of its marketing. Their presence means Facebook and Google know every time you open DoorDash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;28&quot;&gt;The delivery company tells me it doesn’t allow trackers to sell or share our data, which is great. But its &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.doordash.com/privacy/&quot;&gt;privacy policy&lt;/a&gt; throws its hands up in the air: “DoorDash is not responsible for the privacy practices of these entities,” it says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;29&quot;&gt;All but one of DoorDash’s nine trackers made Jackson’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/disconnectme/disconnect-tracking-protection&quot;&gt;naughty list&lt;/a&gt; for Disconnect, which also &lt;a href=&quot;https://disconnect.me/trackerprotection&quot;&gt;powers the Firefox browser’s private browsing mode&lt;/a&gt;. To him, any third party that collects and retains our data is suspect unless it also has pro-consumer privacy policies like limiting data retention time and anonymizing data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;30&quot;&gt;Microsoft, Nike and the Weather Channel told me they were using the trackers I uncovered to improve performance. Mint, owned by Intuit, said it uses an Adobe marketing tracker to help figure out how to advertise to Mint users. The Post said its trackers were used to make sure ads work. Spotify pointed me to its privacy policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;31&quot;&gt;Privacy policies don’t necessarily provide protection. Citizen, the app for location-based crime reports, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sp0n.com/citizen/privacy.html&quot;&gt;published&lt;/a&gt; that it wouldn’t share “your name or other personally identifying information.” Yet when I ran my test, I found it repeatedly sent my phone number, email and exact GPS coordinates to the tracker Amplitude.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;32&quot;&gt;After I contacted Citizen, it updated its app and removed the Amplitude tracker. (Amplitude, for its part, says data it collects for clients is kept private and not sold.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;33&quot;&gt;“We will do a better job of making sure our privacy policy is clear about the specific types of data we share with providers like these,” Citizen spokesman J. Peter Donald said. “We do not sell user data. We never have and never will.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;34&quot;&gt;The problem is, the more places personal data flies, the harder it becomes to hold companies accountable for bad behavior — including inevitable breaches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;35&quot;&gt;As Jackson kept reminding me: “This is your data.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div data-elm-loc=&quot;36&quot; class=&quot;inline-content inline-photo inline-photo-normal&quot;&gt; &lt;img class=&quot;unprocessed _3-to-2 placeholder&quot; src=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/TXJKur-cQ3m4AF9lqk_kkjfemkk=/3x2/www.washingtonpost.com/pb/resources/img/spacer.gif&quot; data-hi-res-src=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/lbHCCq5O7fbMEYp0rF3Vgj-I9fU=/1484x0/arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/REV6FAUBIII6TNMF4NVRNJJRVI.jpg&quot; data-low-res-src=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/Mh4tCrPEpDbns9Bgrxw7VMMkTrU=/480x0/arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/REV6FAUBIII6TNMF4NVRNJJRVI.jpg&quot; data-raw-src=&quot;https://arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/REV6FAUBIII6TNMF4NVRNJJRVI.jpg&quot; data-threshold=&quot;480&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pb-caption&quot;&gt;A billboard advertising Apple's iPhone privacy is displayed during CES 2019 in Las Vegas. (David Becker/Getty Images)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 data-elm-loc=&quot;37&quot;&gt;The letdown&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;38&quot;&gt;What disappoints me is that the data free-for-all I discovered is happening on an iPhone. Isn’t Apple supposed to be better at privacy?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;39&quot;&gt;“At Apple we do a great deal to help users keep their data private,” the company says in a statement. “Apple hardware and software are designed to provide advanced security and privacy at every level of the system.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;40&quot;&gt;In some areas, Apple is ahead. Most of Apple’s own apps and services take care to either encrypt data or, even better, to not collect it in the first place. Apple offers a privacy setting called “Limit Ad Tracking” (sadly off by default) which makes it a little bit harder for companies to track you across apps, by way of a unique identifier for every iPhone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;41&quot;&gt;And with iOS 12, Apple took shots at the data economy by improving the “intelligent tracking prevention” in its Safari web browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;42&quot; class=&quot;interstitial-link&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;[&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2019/05/06/alexa-has-been-eavesdropping-you-this-whole-time/?utm_term=.8514f3a17b1c&quot;&gt;Alexa has been eavesdropping on you this whole time&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;43&quot;&gt;Yet these days, we spend more time in apps. Apple is strict about requiring apps to get permission to access certain parts of the iPhone, including your camera, microphone, location, health information, photos and contacts. (You can check and change those permissions under privacy settings.) But Apple turns more of a blind eye to what apps do with data we provide them or they generate about us — witness the sorts of tracking I found by looking under the covers for a few days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;44&quot;&gt;“For the data and services that apps create on their own, our App Store Guidelines require developers to have clearly posted privacy policies and to ask users for permission to collect data before doing so. When we learn that apps have not followed our Guidelines in these areas, we either make apps change their practice or keep those apps from being on the store,” Apple says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;45&quot;&gt;Yet very few apps I found using third-party trackers disclosed the names of those companies or how they protect my data. And what good is burying this information in privacy policies, anyway? What we need is accountability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;46&quot;&gt;Getting more deeply involved in app data practices is complicated for Apple. Today’s technology frequently is built on third-party services, so Apple couldn’t simply ban all connections to outside servers. And some companies are so big they don’t even need the help of outsiders to track us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;47&quot;&gt;The result shouldn’t be to increase Apple’s power. “I would like to make sure they’re not stifling innovation,” says Andrés Arrieta, the director of consumer privacy engineering at the Electronic Frontier Foundation. If Apple becomes the Internet’s privacy police, it could shut down rivals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;48&quot;&gt;Jackson suggests Apple could also add controls into iOS like the ones built into Privacy Pro to give everyone more visibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;49&quot;&gt;Or perhaps Apple could require apps to label when they’re using third-party trackers. If I opened the DoorDash app and saw nine tracker notices, it might make me think twice about using it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;50&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read more tech advice and analysis from Geoffrey A. Fowler:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;51&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2019/03/07/when-tax-prep-is-free-you-may-be-paying-with-your-privacy/?utm_term=.5ebf062cb8dd&quot;&gt;When tax prep is free, you may be paying with your privacy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;52&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2019/04/12/not-all-iphones-are-same-these-cost-less-are-better-earth/?utm_term=.859cc5c06417&quot;&gt;Not all iPhones are the same. These cost less and are better for the Earth.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;53&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2019/05/16/best-way-review-wireless-earbuds-is-have-sammy-hagar-headbang-with-them/?utm_term=.3f59d31f1134&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Rock this way: AirPods, Beats and Bose wireless ear buds take the headbang test&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 16:04:13 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>akeck</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2019/05/28/its-middle-night-do-you-know-who-your-iphone-is-talking/</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/j-lXsZIPDTCITSMZAeLQTVTw2BI=/1484x0/arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/7YLP3KO5JJABVNGSZKTDRQ4UMY.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>Perspective | It’s the middle of the night. Do you know who your iPhone is talking to?</og:title>
<og:description>We ran a privacy experiment to see how many hidden trackers are running from the apps on our iPhone. The tally is astounding.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2019/05/28/its-middle-night-do-you-know-who-your-iphone-is-talking/?noredirect=on</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Update on await syntax in Rust</title>
<link>https://boats.gitlab.io/blog/post/await-decision-ii/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://boats.gitlab.io/blog/post/await-decision-ii/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;In my &lt;a href=&quot;https://boats.gitlab.io/blog/post/await-decision/&quot;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt; I said that the lang team would be making our final decision about the syntax of the await operator in the May 23 meeting. That was last Thursday, and we did reach a decision. In brief, we decided to go forward with the preliminary proposal I outlined earlier: a postfix dot syntax, &lt;code&gt;future.await&lt;/code&gt;. For more background, in addition the previous post on my blog, you can read &lt;a href=&quot;https://paper.dropbox.com/doc/Await-Syntax-Write-Up-t9NlOSeI4RQ8AINsaSSyJ&quot;&gt;this write up about some of the trade offs from April&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are a few things I want to make clear about this proposal and about our design process in general.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, there a very few absolutes in the design of the Rust language. There are a few things we &lt;em&gt;can’t&lt;/em&gt; do (or &lt;em&gt;must&lt;/em&gt; do) - our type system must be sound, for example. But the vast majority of questions are questions of &lt;em&gt;trade offs&lt;/em&gt; - weighing the pros and cons of different proposals to find the path forward we believe is most preferable. Often, there is a choice that is clearly superior to just about everyone. But sometimes all of the proposals have different positive and negative attributes, and the way each of us weighs those attributes is different, leading to conflicting opinions. This was certainly one of those times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve seen in these discussions costs that people weigh heavily raised to the level of absolutes. This negative attribute of some proposal is held to be so bad that we simply &lt;em&gt;can’t&lt;/em&gt; do that. For the most part, this is an unhelpful framing. It closes the discussion because it makes it difficult for people who disagree to acknowledge that this problem is real while also arguing that we should hold a different balance of the cost, which makes it still the preferable choice. We need to be able to avoid this sort of dichotomizing, black and white thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And as an additional addendum to this idea, each member of the language team weighs these costs differently. Individually, several of us might have made a different selection than the syntax we have chosen here. I know that the way I weigh the costs personally, it is not my most preferred proposal. But we are all united in the desire to move forward with providing the feature that users need and the understanding that several of these proposals are viable. This decision has been justified well and reflects the “consensus weighting” of the different costs among the members of the language team. If you weighted these costs such that you would have made a different choice, I would like to imagine that you can also embrace these values and feel glad that we are moving forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a few further clarifications regarding some conversations that have arisen in the discussion the last few weeks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Dot keyword:”&lt;/strong&gt; In the previous post, a sketch was made of an idea in which certain keywords could be postfixed or infixed using the dot operator. This idea is only a sketch, and is not implied or guaranteed by the decision we’ve made here. While this operator might provide some additional motivation for that proposal, it will still need to go through its own RFC process, and has its own clear drawbacks that users have already identified that will need to be weighed separately from this decision.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sigil syntaxes:&lt;/strong&gt; In the previous summary, sigil syntaxes like &lt;code&gt;@await&lt;/code&gt; were only very briefly addressed. I want to be clear that this is once again a question of weighing costs. The costs of introducing a new sigil with meaning in the language are real: we only have so many sigils available (non-ASCII sigils are not considered viable from an input accessibility perspective), each new sigil increases the surface area that users need to learn, using overmany sigils is considered aesthetically unpleasant by many people. Comparing the costs of using a new sigil to the costs of reusing the already overloaded &lt;code&gt;.&lt;/code&gt; operator, we felt that using &lt;code&gt;.&lt;/code&gt; was less costly. Some users may disagree, but I hope you can understand that this isn’t a black and white question, but a comparison of options each with their own pros and cons.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m working actively on drafting a stabilization report to propose stabilizing a minimum viable version of async/await in the 1.37 release of Rust. 1.37 will be released in mid-August, and branches on July 4. That means we have about a month to make sure the implementation, documentation, and design are all in a sufficient state to stabilize the minimum version of this feature. That won’t be the end of the async/await feature - there will be a lot of extensions left out of the minimum feature - but it will be an important milestone for everyone who wants to use Rust for high performance network services.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 14:36:05 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>steveklabnik</dc:creator>
<og:title>Update on await syntax</og:title>
<og:description>In my previous post I said that the lang team would be making our final decision about the syntax of the await operator in the May 23 meeting. That was last Thursday, and we did reach a decision. In brief, we decided to go forward with the preliminary proposal I outlined earlier: a postfix dot syntax, future.await. For more background, in addition the previous post on my blog, you can read this write up about some of the trade offs from April.</og:description>
<og:url>https://boats.gitlab.io/blog/post/await-decision-ii/</og:url>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://boats.gitlab.io/blog/post/await-decision-ii/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Google Now Forces Edge Preview Users to Use Chrome for the Modern YouTube</title>
<link>https://www.thurrott.com/google/207371/google-now-forces-microsoft-edge-preview-users-to-use-chrome-for-the-modern-youtube-experience</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.thurrott.com/google/207371/google-now-forces-microsoft-edge-preview-users-to-use-chrome-for-the-modern-youtube-experience</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thurrott.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2019/05/youtubeedge.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-207372&quot; src=&quot;https://www.thurrott.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2019/05/youtubeedge.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1280&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.thurrott.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2019/05/youtubeedge.jpg 1280w, https://www.thurrott.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2019/05/youtubeedge-450x253.jpg 450w, https://www.thurrott.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2019/05/youtubeedge-768x432.jpg 768w, https://www.thurrott.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2019/05/youtubeedge-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://www.thurrott.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2019/05/youtubeedge-800x450.jpg 800w, https://www.thurrott.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2019/05/youtubeedge-310x175.jpg 310w, https://www.thurrott.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2019/05/youtubeedge-500x281.jpg 500w, https://www.thurrott.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2019/05/youtubeedge-600x338.jpg 600w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1280px) 100vw, 1280px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft started &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thurrott.com/microsoft/204539/microsofts-new-chromium-based-edge-browser-is-finally-here&quot;&gt;testing a new Microsoft Edge browser&lt;/a&gt; based on Chromium a little while ago. The company has been releasing new canary and dev builds for the browser over the last few weeks, and the preview is actually really great. In fact, I have been using the new Microsoft Edge Canary on my main Windows machine and my MacBook Pro for more than a month, and it’s really good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But if you watch YouTube quite a lot, you will face a new problem on the new Edge. It turns out, Google has randomly disabled the modern YouTube experience for users of the new Microsoft Edge. Users are now redirected to the old YouTube experience, which lacks the modern design as well as the dark theme for YouTube, as first &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/gus33000/status/1133327800809807872&quot;&gt;spotted by Gustave Monce&lt;/a&gt;. And when you try to manually access the new YouTube from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/new&quot;&gt;youtube.com/new,&lt;/a&gt; YouTube simply asks users to download Google Chrome, stating that the Edge browser isn’t supported. Ironically, the same page states “We support the latest versions of Chrome, Firefox, Opera, Safari, and Edge.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The change affects the latest versions of Microsoft Edge Canary and Dev channels. It is worth noting that the classic Microsoft Edge based on EdgeHTML continues to work fine with the modern YouTube experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The weird thing here is that Microsoft has been working &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thurrott.com/windows/windows-10/205701/google-gives-a-thumbs-up-to-chromium-based-microsoft-edge&quot;&gt;closely with Google engineers&lt;/a&gt; on the new Edge and Chromium. Both the companies engineers are working closely to improve Chromium and introduce &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thurrott.com/windows/windows-10/205026/living-on-the-new-edge-whats-missing&quot;&gt;new features like ARM64&lt;/a&gt; support to Chromium. So it’s very odd that Google would prevent users of the new Microsoft Edge browser from using the modern YouTube experience. This is most likely an error on Google’s part, but it could be intentional, too — we really don’t know for now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tagged with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thurrott.com/tag/chromum&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;Chromum&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thurrott.com/tag/google&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thurrott.com/tag/microsoft-edge&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;Microsoft Edge&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thurrott.com/tag/microsoft-edge-preview&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;Microsoft Edge Preview&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thurrott.com/tag/youtube&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 14:10:42 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>MikusR</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Google Now Forces Microsoft Edge Preview Users to Use Chrome for the Modern YouTube Experience - Thurrott.com</og:title>
<og:description>Users of Microsoft's new Chromium-based Edge browser are now forced to use Chrome for the modern YouTube experience.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.thurrott.com/google/207371/google-now-forces-microsoft-edge-preview-users-to-use-chrome-for-the-modern-youtube-experience</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.thurrott.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2019/05/youtubeedge.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.thurrott.com/google/207371/google-now-forces-microsoft-edge-preview-users-to-use-chrome-for-the-modern-youtube-experience</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Malaysia will return contaminated plastic waste to the countries that shipped it</title>
<link>https://www.cnn.com/2019/05/28/asia/malaysia-plastic-waste-return-intl/index.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.cnn.com/2019/05/28/asia/malaysia-plastic-waste-return-intl/index.html</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnn.com/2019/05/28/asia/malaysia-plastic-waste-return-intl/index.html&quot;&gt;https://www.cnn.com/2019/05/28/asia/malaysia-plastic-waste-return-intl/index.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=20030065&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=20030065&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 200&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 137&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 14:01:21 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>DoreenMichele</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Google Now Forces Microsoft Edge Preview Users to Use Chrome for the Modern YouTube Experience - Thurrott.com</og:title>
<og:description>Users of Microsoft's new Chromium-based Edge browser are now forced to use Chrome for the modern YouTube experience.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.thurrott.com/google/207371/google-now-forces-microsoft-edge-preview-users-to-use-chrome-for-the-modern-youtube-experience</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.thurrott.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2019/05/youtubeedge.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.thurrott.com/google/207371/google-now-forces-microsoft-edge-preview-users-to-use-chrome-for-the-modern-youtube-experience</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>CSS Grid Generator</title>
<link>https://cssgrid-generator.netlify.com/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://cssgrid-generator.netlify.com/</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://cssgrid-generator.netlify.com/&quot;&gt;https://cssgrid-generator.netlify.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=20029981&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=20029981&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 224&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 47&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 13:53:19 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>raju</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/s.cdpn.io/28963/og-cssgrid.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://cssgrid-generator.netlify.com/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>