<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Bungie departs from Activision</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2019/01/10/bungie-takes-back-its-destiny-and-departs-from-activision/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2019/01/10/bungie-takes-back-its-destiny-and-departs-from-activision/</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;speakable-summary&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://crunchbase.com/organization/bungie-software&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;bungie-software&quot;&gt;Bungie,&lt;/a&gt; creator of the popular Halo and &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://crunchbase.com/organization/destiny-2&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;destiny-2&quot;&gt;Destiny&lt;/a&gt; franchises, is splitting from publisher Activision and will go its own way, the company announced today. It’s almost certainly good news for gamers and the company itself, but it also won’t fix the problems that plagued Destiny and its sequel since their launches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bungie.net/en/Explore/Detail/News/47569&quot;&gt;In a blog post&lt;/a&gt;, the company explained that the partnership had run its course:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;15&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have enjoyed a successful eight-year run and would like to thank Activision for their partnership on Destiny. Looking ahead, we’re excited to announce plans for Activision to transfer publishing rights for Destiny to Bungie. With our remarkable Destiny community, we are ready to publish on our own, while Activision will increase their focus on owned IP projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The planned transition process is already underway in its early stages, with Bungie and Activision both committed to making sure the handoff is as seamless as possible&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bungie and Activision teamed up &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2011/03/03/confirmed-bungies-next-game-will-be-an-mmo/&quot;&gt;all those years ago&lt;/a&gt; essentially because the former needed a jump-start to develop Destiny, and the latter was of course always looking for big titles to produce and milk for cash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The deal was, briefly stated, $500 million for four games over 10 years — which sounds reasonable on its face, but the first Destiny had a troubled development and took years to become the game people expected; the sequel infamously was rumored to have been rebooted less than a year and a half before release. Meanwhile, both games needed a steady drip of new content to keep players online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pressure from Activision meant Bungie had to focus on meeting deadlines rather than pursue the “it’s ready when it’s ready” philosophy that companies like Rockstar have the luxury of. This may have contributed to the widely berated microtransaction store built into Destiny 2 and the half-baked nature of its early content releases, like the much-maligned Curse of Osiris.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But ultimately these choices have been shown to be Bungie’s, and the responsibility rests on them as the developer. Delivering for both gamers and shareholders is tough, but that’s the deal they struck, and it seems as if they simply weren’t able to do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting the rights to Destiny back must have been like pulling teeth, but it may also be that Activision would rather cut Bungie loose while it’s ahead rather than attempt to rush the third entry in the series. Although both companies are being very polite about it right now, chances are the inside story will emerge soon; &lt;a href=&quot;https://kotaku.com/bungie-splits-with-activision-1831651740&quot;&gt;Kotaku’s Jason Schreier&lt;/a&gt;, who has followed the game and company closely for years, reported that champagne corks were flying at Bungie headquarters, so clearly some tension has been relieved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;History repeats, it seems: Bungie was originally an independent developer (and creator of the beloved Marathon games) and was acquired by Microsoft during the development of its breakout hit Halo. It later negotiated its independence from Microsoft, only to apparently walk into the same trap again a few years afterward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What this means for Destiny players is unclear, but the trend away from yearly installments and toward longer development times and bigger payoffs has generally been a good one for players. If Bungie leans that way and Destiny 3 ends up coming out a year after it might have under Activision, it will almost certainly be better for it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2019 01:04:10 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>kposehn</dc:creator>
<og:title>Bungie takes back its Destiny and departs from Activision</og:title>
<og:description>Bungie, creator of the popular Halo and Destiny franchises, is splitting from publisher Activision and will go its own way, the company announced today. It's almost certainly good news for gamers and the company itself, but it also won't fix the problems that plagued Destiny and its sequel since th…</og:description>
<og:image>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/destiny-bungie.jpg?w=711</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2019/01/10/bungie-takes-back-its-destiny-and-departs-from-activision/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2019/01/10/bungie-takes-back-its-destiny-and-departs-from-activision/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>AT&amp;T says it’ll stop selling location data amid calls for federal investigation</title>
<link>https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2019/01/10/phone-companies-are-selling-your-location-data-now-some-lawmakers-want-federal-investigation/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2019/01/10/phone-companies-are-selling-your-location-data-now-some-lawmakers-want-federal-investigation/</guid>
<description>&lt;div data-elm-loc=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;inline-content inline-photo inline-photo-normal&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/wBBM2bo7uh0OoWDlQOYo31SrrCw=/480x0/arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/UGVMS2QUPMI6TK3ZGDGU66JG6I.jpg&quot; data-hi-res-src=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/EkoZ_oishOB3UiADuQNggiVSZcI=/1484x0/arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/UGVMS2QUPMI6TK3ZGDGU66JG6I.jpg&quot; data-low-res-src=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/wBBM2bo7uh0OoWDlQOYo31SrrCw=/480x0/arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/UGVMS2QUPMI6TK3ZGDGU66JG6I.jpg&quot; data-raw-src=&quot;https://arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/UGVMS2QUPMI6TK3ZGDGU66JG6I.jpg&quot; data-threshold=&quot;480&quot; class=&quot;unprocessed&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pb-caption&quot;&gt;Sen. Kamala D. Harris (D-Calif.) is among the senators who are calling for government action to restrict the sale of Americans' phone location data. (Sait Serkan Gurbuz/AP)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;author-sig-line-wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author-sig-line&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author-byline multiple&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;author-wrapper&quot; data-authorname=&quot;Brian Fung&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;author-hover-card&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author-headshot&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/people/brian-fung/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/UZzaqKFOl4D_j3OEicirT04uKHU=/200x200/s3.amazonaws.com/arc-authors/washpost/6efb8cfd-9f57-4773-8617-55c61b93c081.png&quot; class=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;author-name&quot; href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/people/brian-fung/&quot;&gt;Brian Fung&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author-bio&quot;&gt;Policy reporter focusing on telecommunications, media, cryptocurrencies and competition&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;author-timestamp&quot; itemprop=&quot;datePublished&quot; content=&quot;2019-01-10T11:32-500&quot;&gt;January 10 at 11:32 AM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;1&quot;&gt;AT&amp;amp;T said Thursday it will stop selling its customers' location data to third-party service providers after a report this week said the information was winding up in the wrong hands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;2&quot;&gt;The announcement follows sharp demands by federal lawmakers for an investigation into the alleged misuse of data, which came to light when &lt;a href=&quot;https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/nepxbz/i-gave-a-bounty-hunter-300-dollars-located-phone-microbilt-zumigo-tmobile&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Motherboard&lt;/a&gt; revealed a complex chain of unauthorized information-sharing that ended with a bounty hunter successfully tracking down a reporter’s device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;3&quot;&gt;AT&amp;amp;T had already suspended its data sharing agreements with a number of so-called “location aggregators” last year in light of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/the-switch/wp/2018/06/19/verizon-will-suspend-sales-of-customer-location-data-after-a-prison-phone-company-was-caught-misusing-it/?utm_term=.6002f14b71da&quot;&gt;a congressional probe&lt;/a&gt; finding that some of Verizon’s location data was being misused by prison officials to spy on innocent Americans. AT&amp;amp;T also said at the time it would be maintaining those of its agreements that provided clear consumer benefits, such as location sharing for roadside assistance services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;4&quot;&gt;But AT&amp;amp;T’s announcement Thursday goes much further, pledging to terminate all of the remaining deals it had — even the ones that it said were actively helpful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;5&quot;&gt;“In light of recent reports about the misuse of location services, we have decided to eliminate all location aggregation services — even those with clear consumer benefits,&quot; AT&amp;amp;T said in a statement. “We are immediately eliminating the remaining services and will be done in March.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;6&quot; class=&quot;interstitial-link&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;[&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/the-switch/wp/2018/06/19/verizon-will-suspend-sales-of-customer-location-data-after-a-prison-phone-company-was-caught-misusing-it/?utm_term=.d15df21246cd&quot;&gt;Carriers to suspend sales of location data after a prison phone company was caught misusing the information&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;7&quot;&gt;In characteristic fashion, T-Mobile chief executive John Legere &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/JohnLegere/status/1082824623740248065&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;tweeted&lt;/a&gt; Tuesday that his firm would be “completely ending location aggregator work&quot; in March. Verizon said in a statement Thursday that it, too, was winding down its four remaining location-sharing agreements, which are all with roadside assistance services -- after that, customers would have to give the company permission to share their data with roadside assistance firms. A Sprint spokeswoman didn’t immediately respond to a request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;8&quot;&gt;The announcements reflect a major victory for privacy advocates who have slammed corporate America over its handling of consumers' personal information, often to their personal and economic expense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;9&quot;&gt;“Carriers are always responsible for who ends up with their customers data — it’s not enough to lay the blame for misuse on downstream companies,” said Sen. Ron Wyden (D-Ore.), in a statement. “The time for taking these companies at their word is long past. Congress needs to pass strong legislation to protect Americans’ privacy and finally hold corporations accountable when they put your safety at risk by letting stalkers and criminals track your phone on the dark web.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;10&quot;&gt;Other critics said Americans have an “absolute right” to their privacy of their data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;11&quot;&gt;“I’m extraordinarily troubled by reports of this system of repackaging and reselling location data to unregulated third party services for potentially nefarious purposes,” &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/kamala-harris-says-she-was-raised-to-fix-problems-and-washington-is-a-hot-mess/2019/01/08/1ceb84b6-134b-11e9-90a8-136fa44b80ba_story.html?utm_term=.9eaff147c4c0&quot;&gt;Sen. Kamala D. Harris (D-Calif.)&lt;/a&gt; said in a statement after the Motherboard report was published. “If true, this practice represents a legitimate threat to our personal and national security.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;12&quot;&gt;Harris called on the Federal Communications Commission to immediately open an investigation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;13&quot; class=&quot;interstitial-link&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;[&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2018/10/12/facebook-says-fewer-users-were-affected-by-data-breach-more-information-was-taken/?utm_term=.dff34dcd831a&quot;&gt;Facebook says millions of users had phone numbers, search history and location data stolen in recent hack&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;14&quot;&gt;Motherboard reported that major U.S. wireless carriers T-Mobile, AT&amp;amp;T and Sprint have been selling the location data of its customers in an unregulated market in which Americans’ personal information travels through several layers of third-party entities that buy the location data but are not authorized to handle such information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;15&quot;&gt;Following the report, FCC Commissioner Jessica Rosenworcel &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/JRosenworcel/status/1082712600390127616&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; on Twitter, “The @fcc needs to investigate. Stat.” In a subsequent post in which she agreed with Harris and others &lt;a href=&quot;https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/j5z74d/senators-harris-warner-wyden-fcc-investigate-att-sprint-tmobile-bounty-hunters&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;calling for an investigation, Rosenworcel added:&lt;/a&gt; “It shouldn’t be that you pay a few hundred dollars to a bounty hunter and then they can tell you in real time where a phone is within a few hundred meters. That’s not right. This entire ecosystem needs oversight.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;16&quot;&gt;The FCC did not immediately respond to requests for comment; the agency’s operations are limited because of the ongoing government shutdown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;17&quot;&gt;The sharing of the phone location data at the center of the report began at T-Mobile, which shared it with a “location aggregator,” who shared it with a phone location service, which shared it with a bounty hunter, who shared it with a source, who ultimately sent the phone’s location to Motherboard, according to the report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;18&quot; class=&quot;interstitial-link&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;[&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2019/01/08/att-is-being-criticized-upgrading-its-phones-fake-g-now-t-mobile-is-piling/?utm_term=.4e4fc245700e&quot;&gt;AT&amp;amp;T is being criticized for upgrading its phones to ‘fake’ 5G. Now Sprint, T-Mobile and Verizon are piling on.&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;19&quot;&gt;“We take the privacy and security of our customers’ information very seriously and will not tolerate any misuse of our customers’ data” T-Mobile said in a statement. Chief executive John Legere said on Twitter that T-Mobile is “completely ending location aggregator work,” which will terminate in March.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;20&quot;&gt;As Motherboard reported, there are legitimate uses for the sharing of location data, including detecting financial fraud or locating motorists who need roadside assistance. But according to the report, in some cases the sensitive information was resold without authorization for purposes that violated data-sharing policies and without the knowledge of the phone company and its third-party partners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;21&quot;&gt;Wyden has previously called on the FCC to investigate the relationship between wireless carriers and data brokers. He sees the new report as another urgent motivation for government action, including an investigation by the Federal Trade Commission. “Major carriers pledged to end these practices, but it appears to have been more empty promises to consumers,” Wyden &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/RonWyden/status/1082691563447304194&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;said on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;. He said Congress should advance his legislation that would grant the FTC greater authority to safeguard consumer data and fine companies for privacy and security violations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;22&quot;&gt;Sprint said in a statement: “Protecting our customers’ privacy and security is a top priority, and we are transparent about that in our Privacy Policy. We do not knowingly share personally identifiable geolocation information except with customer consent or in response to a lawful request such as a validated court order from law enforcement.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;23&quot;&gt;Responding to the report, AT&amp;amp;T said in a statement: “We only permit sharing of location when a customer gives permission for cases like fraud prevention or emergency roadside assistance, or when required by law. Over the past few months, as we committed to do, we have been shutting down everything else.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;24&quot;&gt;Sen. Mark R. Warner (D-Va.), who has &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2018/09/28/facebook-says-million-accounts-affected-by-hackers/?utm_term=.d40a329d6e89&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;criticized the privacy practices&lt;/a&gt; of Facebook and other companies that collect massive quantities of user data, said the report highlights how customers and policymakers “have been kept in the dark” about the ways personal information is gathered, repackaged and sold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;25&quot;&gt;“Responsible federal agencies and the U.S. Congress should continue to hold hearings to shine a light on these practices, and look at regulations to ensure companies are actually upfront with consumers about whether and how their sensitive data is being used and sold,” Warner said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 23:49:35 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>tareqak</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2019/01/10/phone-companies-are-selling-your-location-data-now-some-lawmakers-want-federal-investigation/</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/EkoZ_oishOB3UiADuQNggiVSZcI=/1484x0/arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/UGVMS2QUPMI6TK3ZGDGU66JG6I.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>AT&amp;T says it’ll stop selling your location data, amid calls for a federal investigation</og:title>
<og:description>A report from Motherboard on major U.S. wireless carriers revealed the shadowy business of collecting and reselling phone location data.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2019/01/10/phone-companies-are-selling-your-location-data-now-some-lawmakers-want-federal-investigation/?noredirect=on</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>How I Built a $5K a Month Side Project</title>
<link>https://campfirelabs.co/blog-1/2019/1/10/how-i-built-a-5000-per-month-side-project</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://campfirelabs.co/blog-1/2019/1/10/how-i-built-a-5000-per-month-side-project</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Passive income. The 4 hour work week. The dream. As a millennial there are few things that rank as desirable as finding a recurring source of income that doesn’t take much work (or a boss). In April of 2015 I decided to seek that out and build a side project that could pay my bills while I read books and traveled the world. Within a few months I achieved my dream and booked $5,000 in monthly recurring revenue (MRR).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s been almost 3 years since I started SimpleData, my passive income muse. I grew the business to $30,000 per month in revenue within six months, automated and delegated just about everything, and for all of 2016 I worked an average of 5-10 hours per week. My new freedom enabled me to spend five months living in Argentina and then Europe. It afforded me the time to study things like history, political science, and other liberal arts that I felt I missed after dropping out of college. This muse changed my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In January 2017—18 months after starting the business—I sold SimpleData. It’s hard to imagine what my life would look like today if I didn’t sit down at my computer one night back in 2015 and come up a plan to quit my job, make passive income and travel the world. This simple act put me on the path to financial independence and wealth. It gave me the time and money to volunteer and give back, which opened my mind to a set of questions I never thought to ask previously—about my responsibility to help people less fortunate than me, about the work that makes me happy, and what to do when those two things are in conflict. This path also led to depression, social isolation, and the hardest time of my life, which previously I’ve been hesitant to share. &lt;em&gt;(Is there anything worse than a rich guy complaining about his life?)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this 3 part series I’ll break down how I built and sold my business, including how I came up with the idea, found my first customers, scaled operations, and found potential acquirers. I’ll also share some of the more personal things that I learned along the way and how I learned to calm some of the demons in my head.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;#1 — Monetize your brain&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thesis of the project was simple: take what was in my head and monetize it. In other words, build a business that leverages all of the skills that I had learned over the first three years of my career in entrepreneurship, marketing and sales.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I started SkyRocket — my last (failed) startup — I solved someone else’s problem which meant the time-to-market was significantly longer and the investment had to be much larger. I had to stay up late in the night reading industry journals just to be on the same playing field as my competition. In my second go-around I didn’t want to do that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that in mind I decided to solve a problem in the sales development space. At Highfive I made a name for myself as a “saleshacker” by applying some basic web scraping and front end development to my job. I had carved out a niche by applying what I knew about technology to sales. This was my unique skill, and I wanted to monetize it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;#2 — Find the pain&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finding a skill that I could use as leverage pointed me in the right direction, but in order to actually make money I knew I’d need more clarity. I needed the specifics of what problem I would solve, who I’d solve it for and how it would make money. And all of that could be found if I were able to answer a simple question: what do people in sales development need, and is there any pain in the current process of achieving that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I thought about problems to solve I remembered a story one of Highfive’s account executives told me. She was $5,000 short of quota (her quarterly revenue goal) and the only way to hit it was to email and call as many people as she possibly could to see if they needed video conferencing. In order to get that list of people she stayed up until 1am and built a prospect list (a spreadsheet of people to reach out to). 1am is painful. 1am is opportunity for improvement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I took over the Sales Development effort at Highfive the first thing I did was hire a team in the Philipinnes to ensure I never had to stay up until 1am building lists — or build any lists for that matter. I made a couple videos with instructions, bought some tools and found a virtual assistant on oDesk named Jonathan. For most sales development reps building lists can take two hours out of their day. I had eliminated it entirely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I put two and two together I realized that sales development outsourcing was an idea worth pursuing. If I could prevent salespeople from having an end of quarter frenzy like my co-worker, I could probably make a buck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Need help producing engaging thought leadership content like this? Visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://campfirelabs.co&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Campfire Labs&lt;/a&gt; to learn about my new business.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;#3 — Competition isn’t always a bad thing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In March of 2015 I decided that I would build a sales outsourcing side project. The goal would be to provide a turn-key service for sales teams to request leads. But there was a problem with the idea: the market was highly competitive. Whenever I told people about what I was building they replied, “Oh something like [competitor].” Most people I spoke with told me I shouldn’t build the business for this reason. That’s when I learned play #3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most people in the tech industry are brainwashed by Silicon Valley group think. These people believe that every business must have a billion dollar opportunity. This isn’t true, especially for side projects. In fact, when pursuing the passive income dream competition is your friend. Let me explain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Competitive markets are by their very nature mature markets. And the more mature a market, the less time and money a business has to spend educating that market on the problem. Think about real examples. Coca-cola isn’t spending money on ads telling you why you should drink soda. They spend money telling you why Coke is better than Pepsi. Soylent — the future of food startup — on the other hand must spend money educating people on why they should drink their food. In order to succeed, Soylent will have to spend tens of millions of dollars and years in the market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creating a new soda to compete with Coke would take less time and money than creating a new food and beverage category entirely (like Soylent). Coke has spent billions educating people on why they should drink soda. And you could educate people on why they need to drink your soda. You could pick a small niche that Coca-Cola executives see as a rounding error ($1-10 million) Granted, the long term opportunity may be smaller. That’s besides the point. The passive income dream isn’t about making billions, it’s about making thousands per month and doing it quick.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So is it better to create a “future of food” side project or a soda side project? I put my money on the mature, yet competitive market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;#4 — Find a position in the market&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By April I decided that competition wasn’t going to stop me from starting a sales outsourcing startup. But in the back of my head I heard the voice of one of my mentors — Highfive’s VP of Product Marketing. I recalled a lesson he gave me during a 1:1 at Backyard Coffee in Redwood City.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you hear Volvo what comes to mind? Scandanavians, but more importantly you probably think “Safe car.” How about Honda? Odds are “Reliable car” came to mind. This is the basic idea of positioning. What comes to mind when people hear {company name}?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The concept of positioning is incredibly important when starting a business because it determines who will buy your product. A product with no positioning that sells to “everyone” is likely to sell to no one. That’s because people need to identify with your product and brand in order to buy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To put this in context I’ll give an example of positioning in my life. I no longer buy Abercrombie and Fitch because they position themselves as the high end clothing brand for middle schoolers. I do buy from Urban Outfitters though because as Highfive’s VP of Sales liked to say, I’m a wannabe “urban hipster.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previously I thought positioning was just another business school buzzword. But it’s important. At it’s core, positioning means “Pick a niche to get rich.” Isn’t the entire point of a side project to get rich?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to find a unique position in the market you must look at the competitive landscape. When I looked at the lead generation space I realized that companies fell into three categories:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Platforms:&lt;/strong&gt; Data.com, Hoovers and DiscoverOrg are all examples of companies that charge annually for a set amount of lead exports from their platform. These databases are sold to thousands of companies which means everyone is emailing the same person. This results in worse response rates for their customer. And the average cost is about $30,000 per year (billed upfront). Ouch. Bad data for a high price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Service-as-a-service&lt;/strong&gt;: LeadGenius is an example of a company that charges annually for a team that prospects for you. Great concept, but there business model is built to work for them, not the customer. The cost is about $24,000 upfront ($2,000 per month billed annually). Not so great for a startup on a tight budget with changing business needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Freelancers&lt;/strong&gt;: oDesk and Elance are examples of platforms where you can hire your own virtual assistant team to prospect. Customers have to train their team and the billing is variable so your cost per lead ranges from $.50 to $5. Cheap entry point, but time intensive and unpredictable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I knew that there was an opportunity to create a turn-key service with a pricing model that customers could love. And thus, the first pay-as-you-go lead generation service was born.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 23:20:39 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jaxsonkhan</dc:creator>
<og:title>How I Built A $5,000 Per Month Side Project</og:title>
<og:url>https://campfirelabs.co/blog-1/2019/1/10/how-i-built-a-5000-per-month-side-project</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>Passive income. The 4 hour work week. The dream. As a millennial there are few things that rank as desirable as finding a recurring source of income that doesn’t take much work (or a boss). In April of 2015 I decided to seek that out and build a side project that could pay my bills while I read book</og:description>
<og:image>http://static1.squarespace.com/static/5706d181b09f95e331b219de/t/5c3778eff950b7bb44f102ff/1547139320991/4+hour+post+img+1.png?format=1500w</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://campfirelabs.co/blog-1/2019/1/10/how-i-built-a-5000-per-month-side-project</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>pgsql: Use perfect hashing, instead of binary search, for keyword lookup</title>
<link>https://www.postgresql.org/message-id/flat/E1ghOVt-0007os-2V%40gemulon.postgresql.org</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.postgresql.org/message-id/flat/E1ghOVt-0007os-2V%40gemulon.postgresql.org</guid>
<description>&lt;div readability=&quot;59.586532782044&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use perfect hashing, instead of binary search, for keyword lookup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've been speculating for a long time that hash-based keyword lookup&lt;br/&gt;ought to be faster than binary search, but up to now we hadn't found&lt;br/&gt;a suitable tool for generating the hash function. Joerg Sonnenberger&lt;br/&gt;provided the inspiration, and sample code, to show us that rolling our&lt;br/&gt;own generator wasn't a ridiculous idea. Hence, do that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The method used here requires a lookup table of approximately 4 bytes&lt;br/&gt;per keyword, but that's less than what we saved in the predecessor commit&lt;br/&gt;afb0d0712, so it's not a big problem. The time savings is indeed&lt;br/&gt;significant: preliminary testing suggests that the total time for raw&lt;br/&gt;parsing (flex + bison phases) drops by ~20%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Patch by me, but it owes its existence to Joerg Sonnenberger;&lt;br/&gt;thanks also to John Naylor for review.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discussion: &lt;a href=&quot;https://postgr.es/m/20190103163340.GA15803@britannica.bec.de&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://postgr.es/m/20190103163340.GA15803@britannica.bec.de&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Branch&lt;br/&gt;------&lt;br/&gt;master&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Details&lt;br/&gt;-------&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://git.postgresql.org/pg/commitdiff/c64d0cd5ce24a344798534f1bc5827a9199b7a6e&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://git.postgresql.org/pg/commitdiff/c64d0cd5ce24a344798534f1bc5827a9199b7a6e&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Modified Files&lt;br/&gt;--------------&lt;br/&gt;src/common/Makefile | 9 +-&lt;br/&gt;src/common/kwlookup.c | 73 +++---&lt;br/&gt;src/include/common/kwlookup.h | 4 +&lt;br/&gt;src/include/parser/kwlist.h | 3 +-&lt;br/&gt;src/interfaces/ecpg/preproc/Makefile | 13 +-&lt;br/&gt;src/interfaces/ecpg/preproc/c_keywords.c | 51 ++--&lt;br/&gt;src/interfaces/ecpg/preproc/c_kwlist.h | 3 +-&lt;br/&gt;src/interfaces/ecpg/preproc/ecpg_kwlist.h | 3 +-&lt;br/&gt;src/pl/plpgsql/src/Makefile | 13 +-&lt;br/&gt;src/pl/plpgsql/src/pl_reserved_kwlist.h | 5 +-&lt;br/&gt;src/pl/plpgsql/src/pl_unreserved_kwlist.h | 7 +-&lt;br/&gt;src/tools/PerfectHash.pm | 376 ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++&lt;br/&gt;src/tools/gen_keywordlist.pl | 53 ++++-&lt;br/&gt;src/tools/msvc/Solution.pm | 10 +-&lt;br/&gt;14 files changed, 516 insertions(+), 107 deletions(-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;48.745353159851&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Wed, Jan 9, 2019 at 7:48 PM Tom Lane &amp;lt;tgl(at)sss(dot)pgh(dot)pa(dot)us&amp;gt; wrote:&lt;br/&gt;&amp;gt; Use perfect hashing, instead of binary search, for keyword lookup.&lt;br/&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;br/&gt;&amp;gt; We've been speculating for a long time that hash-based keyword lookup&lt;br/&gt;&amp;gt; ought to be faster than binary search, but up to now we hadn't found&lt;br/&gt;&amp;gt; a suitable tool for generating the hash function. Joerg Sonnenberger&lt;br/&gt;&amp;gt; provided the inspiration, and sample code, to show us that rolling our&lt;br/&gt;&amp;gt; own generator wasn't a ridiculous idea. Hence, do that.&lt;br/&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;br/&gt;&amp;gt; The method used here requires a lookup table of approximately 4 bytes&lt;br/&gt;&amp;gt; per keyword, but that's less than what we saved in the predecessor commit&lt;br/&gt;&amp;gt; afb0d0712, so it's not a big problem. The time savings is indeed&lt;br/&gt;&amp;gt; significant: preliminary testing suggests that the total time for raw&lt;br/&gt;&amp;gt; parsing (flex + bison phases) drops by ~20%.&lt;br/&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;br/&gt;&amp;gt; Patch by me, but it owes its existence to Joerg Sonnenberger;&lt;br/&gt;&amp;gt; thanks also to John Naylor for review.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wow. That is a VERY significant improvement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;--&lt;br/&gt;Robert Haas&lt;br/&gt;EnterpriseDB: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.enterprisedb.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://www.enterprisedb.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The Enterprise PostgreSQL Company&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 22:50:32 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>boshomi</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.postgresql.org/message-id/flat/E1ghOVt-0007os-2V%40gemulon.postgresql.org</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Skin printer wipes years from your face [video]</title>
<link>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/av/technology-46831270/ces-2019-skin-printer-wipes-years-from-your-face</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/av/technology-46831270/ces-2019-skin-printer-wipes-years-from-your-face</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;A handheld printer for the face and hands is on show at the CES tech expo in Las Vegas.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Procter and Gamble's device scans the skin and precisely applies tiny amounts of make-up to remove age spots, burst blood vessels and other blemishes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The BBC challenged the firm to make its technology correspondent Rory Cellan-Jones look younger.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Read and watch all our CES coverage at &lt;/i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.com/ces2019&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link&quot;&gt;bbc.com/ces2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 20:58:24 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>hanoz</dc:creator>
<og:title>Skin printer wipes years from your face</og:title>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:description>Procter &amp; Gamble has developed a handheld device that precisely covers blemishes.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.bbc.com/news/av/technology-46831270/ces-2019-skin-printer-wipes-years-from-your-face</og:url>
<og:image>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/4121/production/_105137661_p06xr1s4.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-GB</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/av/technology-46831270/ces-2019-skin-printer-wipes-years-from-your-face</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Anxiety and burnout: why kids are consumed with worry</title>
<link>https://www.vox.com/first-person/2019/1/10/18174263/anxiety-kids-burnout</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.vox.com/first-person/2019/1/10/18174263/anxiety-kids-burnout</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;BUfrQW&quot;&gt;While on a youth retreat with my church a few months ago, I asked about 10 kids, ages 13 to 18, to take a few minutes and write down three words to describe what their lives felt like. They go to a variety of schools, from private and religious to urban public and magnet, and come from a range of backgrounds. After a few minutes writing down their answers silently, we sat in a circle in the living room of our rented cabin and began sharing. One student wrote on a whiteboard each word that the group agreed aptly described their lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;LIGjsY&quot;&gt;By the end of the exercise, the following words were written on the whiteboard: stressful, complicated, overinvolved, full of transitions, anxiety, uncertainty, pressure, and exhaustion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;t9O7UX&quot;&gt;For the past year and a half, I’ve worked as a pastor to the youth at my church, ministering to a dozen sixth- to 12th-grade students at a mainline Baptist church in North Carolina. About a year ago, I decided I wanted to find out more about their lives. I’d heard from parents, teachers, and friends with children that kids today live increasingly busy and stressful lives compared to previous generations. I wanted to know not only what that looked like but how the kids themselves felt and thought about it. What I discovered gave me a good deal of pause about the world kids live in today and what it’s doing to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;LfresN&quot;&gt;As the retreat group started to tell me more about why they felt such a collective sense of stress and pressure, a few major themes emerged. All of them said they voluntarily get their grades pushed to their phones through notifications. It took me a minute to realize just how annoying and agonizing that must feel. It means that at any moment, they could find out they bombed a test or missed an assignment. Instead of having the time to mentally prepare to receive a bad grade when a teacher returns an assignment, they receive a notification as soon as the teacher posts their grade to the online portal they all use. Further, their parents sometimes receive the same notifications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;wxyqD8&quot;&gt;In addition to grades, they use multiple apps such as Remind through which their teachers can send them updates or reminders about upcoming assignments and tests. Like their grades, these can come through to their phone at any time of day or night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;0hVOle&quot;&gt;For all the fear I hear from adults about screen-addicted kids, this seems like a far more destructive relationship to technology. It’s not one in which they use their phones to avoid their friends or family, but one in which technology serves as a source of constant intrusion into their lives, never allowing them to forget about their schoolwork or grades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;Oy3Dyz&quot;&gt;This was just one of the pressures these students felt they faced to ensure survival in the adult world. And the more I spoke with these kids, the more scared I became for the world we adults have created for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;ygdGpN&quot;&gt;The constant pressure to optimize their futures&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;SSXLAl&quot;&gt;As we continued to talk over the course of that school year, I also noticed how much their schools force them to think about their careers at increasingly young ages. The kids often used workplace lingo to describe their lives. One sixth-grader talked about a school assignment in which she had to develop a life plan that included her future career, which schools she should attend, and what she ought to major in at her chosen university. It was only later that I realized visualizing the future like this meant that every grade, every volunteer hour, every achievement or failure carried the weight of fulfilling that imagined future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;scbbKp&quot;&gt;Over the past year, I’ve continued to ask questions and pay attention. One afternoon, I sat in our church’s common area with a sophomore. “Ugh, I’m so stressed about picking classes for next year,” she said holding up her course registration manual. It looked more extensive than I remembered from my time in high school. I asked to flip through it for a minute — it was 43 pages long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;knbe47&quot;&gt;Significant parts of the manual were organized by “career clusters” that encouraged students to take classes to prepare them for future work in fields like agriculture or finance. These clusters, the manual claimed, are “designed as a tool to assist in streamlining the path through which students meet their educational goals and are ultimately employed in high-skill, high-wage, or high-demand occupations and nontraditional fields.” After doing some research, I learned that these career cluster classes are part of a nationwide movement in states across the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;tPtYyG&quot;&gt;Given all this emphasis on career readiness, perhaps I shouldn’t have been surprised that at one point in our conversation at the retreat, a middle school student said, “Things are stressful, but you just have to have a good work-life balance.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;WyXTiO&quot;&gt;Kids today live with the baggage of their parents’ economic anxiety&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;K3BRli&quot;&gt;I’ve talked about these observations with friends who work with kids, parents, and other students when our church goes to summer camp. (The specific youth I worked with gave me permission to share these parts of our conversations.) As I’ve talked about them, I’ve heard that this is the reality for almost all kids today. There’s variance as to how they experience these things based on the types of privilege they come from, but I have to say I’m convinced that most kids today can’t escape this stress and pressure — only survive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;kroc3T&quot;&gt;In my role as their pastor, I tried to carve out some space for them to acknowledge what they’re going through and to be with each other in ways that didn’t force them to work and experience stress, but I have to admit, it all feels woefully inadequate to what they actually need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;8IGTGC&quot;&gt;Kids today have to constantly consider the perils of work and career with enough specificity to worry about it. At the same time that they stress about the future that’s so very far off, they live with technology that keeps that anxiety consistently in the front of their minds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;5ew4E6&quot;&gt;Here’s where it gets even more depressing: I rarely heard them frame any of this work and stress in terms of future success or even just stability. They usually didn’t talk about their lives according to the myth so many parents, teachers, and community members raised Gen X and millennials with, the one that promises that if you work hard, you’ll get a good job and have a nice, stable life or at least do better than your parents did. When they brought up their futures, if they weren’t talking about careers, they understood that student debt was inevitable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;U2cGEZ&quot;&gt;It later dawned on me: Why would they believe this myth? People in their 20s, 30s, and 40s teach and raise these kids. Those generations now know from experience that the idea that hard work and a little luck pays off isn’t true. Between 30 years of stagnant wages, the rising costs of housing, health care, and education, and a recession just as many of us graduated from college, it’s no wonder that millennials are on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ft.com/content/e5246526-8c2c-11e7-a352-e46f43c5825d&quot;&gt;course&lt;/a&gt; to do financially worse than previous generations, just as Gen X did before us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;3ANMay&quot;&gt;In a recent piece at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/annehelenpetersen/millennials-burnout-generation-debt-work&quot;&gt;BuzzFeed&lt;/a&gt;, Anne Helen Petersen described the burnout so many millennials experience. As she puts it, burnout is “the millennial condition. It’s our base temperature. It’s our background music. It’s the way things are. It’s our lives.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;ZoAfdK&quot;&gt;While many of us who work with kids don’t want to name the likelihood that the generation behind us will do even worse than us, it’s hard not to see that we communicate it to them regardless. These kids aren’t even being told that the point of all the work and the stress is a better life — they’re being told it’s necessary just to survive. These kids live with what philosopher Pascal Bruckner calls “tension without intention.” They’re constantly stressed, and they’re growing aware that there’s no payoff for it all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;TQgwTP&quot;&gt;When I talk about these realities, I often have parents or concerned adults ask what we can do about it, and I confess that I don’t have any answers. These kids are the products of their institutions, and structural institutional problems don’t have individual solutions. But as &lt;a href=&quot;https://books.google.com/books?id=qGjBCwAAQBAJ&amp;amp;pg=PA24&amp;amp;lpg=PA24&amp;amp;dq=%E2%80%9CBefore+a+disease+can+be+treated,+it+must+be+diagnosed.+And+you+do+not+need+to+know+the+prescription+before+you+diagnose+a+disease.%E2%80%9D&amp;amp;source=bl&amp;amp;ots=xFajHzyW3K&amp;amp;sig=w0VRfx38QYQAcG9dNuPlWdUK760&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ved=2ahUKEwid1rTvzuPfAhUHTN8KHZJeBN0Q6AEwAHoECAIQAQ#v=onepage&amp;amp;q=%E2%80%9CBefore%20a%20disease%20can%20be%20treated%2C%20it%20must%20be%20diagnosed.%20And%20you%20do%20not%20need%20to%20know%20the%20prescription%20before%20you%20diagnose%20a%20disease.%E2%80%9D&amp;amp;f=false&quot;&gt;Rebecca Solnit writes&lt;/a&gt;, “Before a disease can be treated, it must be diagnosed. And you do not need to know the prescription before you diagnose a disease.” We owe it to the kids in our country to at least diagnose their disease, which is a society that turns children into stressed, anxious, competitive, indebted consumers. We do this to prepare them for their grown-up lives in a society that turns all people into stressed, anxious, competitive, indebted consumers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;QQ2SdA&quot;&gt;I find some measure of hope in the fact that the kids I’ve worked with and others I’ve talked to seem to know something is askew, that their lives ought not to be like this. I’ve found that they want people to take them seriously without adding pressure. They want a bigger and better story to be a part of, a better world to live in. I just hope that they’re not too exhausted to live in it by the time those of us who care about them gain the power to give it to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;ic4hSa&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;John Thornton Jr. is a Baptist pastor living in Winston-Salem, North Carolina.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;p-entry-hr&quot; id=&quot;uB4yJ3&quot;/&gt;&lt;p id=&quot;uy07mG&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vox.com/first-person&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First Person&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is Vox’s home for compelling, provocative narrative essays. Do you have a story to share? Read our &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vox.com/2015/6/12/8767221/vox-first-person-explained&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;submission guidelines&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and pitch us at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:firstperson@vox.com&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;firstperson@vox.com&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 18:31:02 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>petethomas</dc:creator>
<og:description>It’s not social media.</og:description>
<og:image>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/eQQgY2WZaYMQXWswNzy9PEEf4KE=/0x302:5685x3278/fit-in/1200x630/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13681599/GettyImages_962353670.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>&quot;I work with kids. Here’s why they’re consumed with anxiety.&quot;</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.vox.com/first-person/2019/1/10/18174263/anxiety-kids-burnout</og:url>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.vox.com/first-person/2019/1/10/18174263/anxiety-kids-burnout</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Microsoft Bing not only shows child pornography, it suggests it</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2019/01/10/unsafe-search/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2019/01/10/unsafe-search/</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;speakable-summary&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;featured__span-first-words&quot;&gt;Illegal child exploitation&lt;/span&gt; imagery is easy to find on Microsoft’s Bing search engine. But even more alarming is that Bing will suggest related keywords and images that provide pedophiles with more child pornography. Following an anonymous tip, TechCrunch commissioned a report from online safety startup AntiToxin to investigate. The results were alarming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_1767426&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-1767426 size-large&quot; src=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Bing-Child-Exploitation-Image-Results.png?w=680&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;680&quot; height=&quot;506&quot; srcset=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Bing-Child-Exploitation-Image-Results.png 1574w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Bing-Child-Exploitation-Image-Results.png?resize=150,112 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Bing-Child-Exploitation-Image-Results.png?resize=300,223 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Bing-Child-Exploitation-Image-Results.png?resize=768,572 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Bing-Child-Exploitation-Image-Results.png?resize=680,506 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Bing-Child-Exploitation-Image-Results.png?resize=50,37 50w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Bing searches can return illegal child abuse imagery&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[WARNING: Do not search for the terms discussed in this article on Bing or elsewhere as you could be committing a crime. AntiToxin is closely supervised by legal counsel and works in conjunction with Israeli authorities to perform this research and properly hand its findings to law enforcement. No illegal imagery is contained in this article, and it has been redacted with red boxes here and inside AntiToxin’s report.]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The research found that terms like “porn kids,” “porn CP” (a known abbreviation for “child pornography”) and “nude family kids” all surfaced illegal child exploitation imagery. And even people not seeking this kind of disgusting imagery could be led to it by Bing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When researchers searched for “Omegle Kids,” referring to a video chat app popular with teens, Bing’s auto-complete suggestions included “Omegle Kids Girls 13” that revealed extensive child pornography when searched. And if a user clicks on those images, Bing showed them more illegal child abuse imagery in its Similar Images feature. Another search for “Omegle for 12 years old” prompted Bing to suggest searching for “Kids On Omegle Showing,” which pulled in more criminal content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_1767428&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-1767428 size-large&quot; src=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Microsoft-Bing-Child-Exploitation-Similar-Images.png?w=680&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;680&quot; height=&quot;353&quot; srcset=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Microsoft-Bing-Child-Exploitation-Similar-Images.png 1580w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Microsoft-Bing-Child-Exploitation-Similar-Images.png?resize=150,78 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Microsoft-Bing-Child-Exploitation-Similar-Images.png?resize=300,156 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Microsoft-Bing-Child-Exploitation-Similar-Images.png?resize=768,399 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Microsoft-Bing-Child-Exploitation-Similar-Images.png?resize=680,353 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Microsoft-Bing-Child-Exploitation-Similar-Images.png?resize=50,26 50w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Bing’s Similar Images feature can suggest additional illegal child abuse imagery&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The evidence shows a massive failure on Microsoft’s part to adequately police its Bing search engine and to prevent its suggested searches and images from assisting pedophiles. Similar searches on Google did not produce as clearly illegal imagery or as much concerning content as did Bing. Internet companies like Microsoft Bing must invest more in combating this kind of abuse through both scalable technology solutions and human moderators. There’s no excuse for a company like Microsoft, which earned $8.8 billion in profit last quarter, to be underfunding safety measures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TechCrunch received an anonymous tip regarding the disturbing problem on Bing after &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/12/20/whatsapp-pornography/&quot;&gt;my reports last month regarding WhatsApp child exploitation image trading group chats&lt;/a&gt;, the third-party Google Play apps that make these groups easy to find, and how &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/12/27/funding-filth/&quot;&gt;these apps ran Google and Facebook’s ad networks&lt;/a&gt; to make themselves and the platforms money. In the wake of those reports, WhatsApp banned more of these groups and their members, Google kicked the WhatsApp group discovery apps off Google Play and both Google and Facebook blocked the apps from running their ads, with the latter agreeing to refund advertisers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unsafe search&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following up on the anonymous tip, TechCrunch commissioned AntiToxin to investigate the Bing problem, which conducted research from December 30th, 2018 to January 7th, 2019 with proper legal oversight. Searches were conducted on the desktop version of Bing with “Safe Search” turned off. &lt;a href=&quot;http://antitoxin.com/&quot;&gt;AntiToxin&lt;/a&gt; was founded last year to build technologies that protect networks against bullying, predators and other forms of abuse. [Disclosure: The company also employs Roi Carthy, who contributed to TechCrunch from 2007 to 2012.]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AntiToxin CEO Zohar Levkovitz tells me that “Speaking as a parent, we should expect responsible technology companies to double, and even triple-down to ensure they are not adding toxicity to an already perilous online environment for children. And as the CEO of AntiToxin Technologies, I want to make it clear that we will be on the beck and call to help any company that makes this its priority.” The full report, published for the first time, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scribd.com/document/397195137/AntiToxin-Report-On-Child-Exploitation-In-Bing-Search-TechCrunch&quot;&gt;can be found here&lt;/a&gt; and embedded below:&lt;/p&gt;
[gallery size=&quot;medium&quot; ids=&quot;1767951,1767952,1767953,1767954,1767955,1767956,1767957,1767958,1767959,1767960,1767961,1767962,1767963&quot;]
&lt;p&gt;TechCrunch provided a full list of troublesome search queries to Microsoft along with questions about how this happened. Microsoft’s chief vice president of Bing &amp;amp; AI Products Jordi Ribas provided this statement: “Clearly these results were unacceptable under our standards and policies and we appreciate TechCrunch making us aware. We acted immediately to remove them, but we also want to prevent any other similar violations in the future. We’re focused on learning from this so we can make any other improvements needed.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_1767876&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-1767876 size-large&quot; src=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Bing-Child-Exploitation-From-Suggested-Searches.png?w=680&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;680&quot; height=&quot;390&quot; srcset=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Bing-Child-Exploitation-From-Suggested-Searches.png 1302w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Bing-Child-Exploitation-From-Suggested-Searches.png?resize=150,86 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Bing-Child-Exploitation-From-Suggested-Searches.png?resize=300,172 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Bing-Child-Exploitation-From-Suggested-Searches.png?resize=768,440 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Bing-Child-Exploitation-From-Suggested-Searches.png?resize=680,390 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Bing-Child-Exploitation-From-Suggested-Searches.png?resize=50,29 50w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;A search query suggested by Bing surfaces illegal child abuse imagery&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft claims it assigned an engineering team that fixed the issues we disclosed and it’s now working on blocking any similar queries as well problematic related search suggestions and similar images. However, AntiToxin found that while some search terms from its report are now properly banned or cleaned up, others still surface illegal content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company tells me it’s changing its Bing flagging options to include a broader set of categories users can report, including “child sexual abuse.” When asked how the failure could have occurred, a Microsoft spokesperson told us that “W&lt;span&gt;e index everything, as does Google, and we do the best job we can of screening it. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;We use a combination of PhotoDNA and human moderation but that doesn’t get us to perfect every time. We’re committed to getting better all the time.” &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_1512857&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption alignright&quot; readability=&quot;33&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot; wp-image-1512857&quot; src=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/gettyimages-626738964-e1547142850916.jpg?w=680&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;377&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;BELLEVUE, WA – NOVEMBER 30: Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella (Photo by Stephen Brashear/Getty Images)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft’s spokesperson refused to disclose how many human moderators work on Bing or whether it planned to increase its staff to shore up its defenses. But they then tried to object to that line of reasoning, saying, “&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;I sort of get the sense that you’re saying we totally screwed up here and we’ve always been bad, and that’s clearly not the case in the historic context.” The truth is that it did totally screw up here, and the fact that it pioneered illegal imagery detection technology PhotoDNA that’s used by other tech companies doesn’t change that.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bing child pornography problem is another example of tech companies refusing to adequately reinvest the profits they earn into ensuring the security of their own customers and society at large. The public should no longer accept these shortcomings as repercussions of tech giants irresponsibly prioritizing growth and efficiency. Technology solutions are proving insufficient safeguards, and more human sentries are necessary. These companies must pay now to protect us from the dangers they’ve unleashed, or the world will be stuck paying with its safety.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 18:16:32 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>a-wu</dc:creator>
<og:title>Microsoft Bing not only shows child pornography, it suggests it</og:title>
<og:description>Illegal child exploitation imagery is easy to find on Microsoft’s Bing search engine. But even more alarming is that Bing will suggest related keywords and images that provide pedophiles with more child pornography. Following an anonymous tip, TechCrunch commissioned a report from online safe…</og:description>
<og:image>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Microsoft-Bing-Child-Exploitation-Search-Results-redacted.png?w=741</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2019/01/10/unsafe-search/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2019/01/10/unsafe-search/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>How We Designed the Librem 5 Dev Kit with Free Software</title>
<link>https://puri.sm/posts/how-we-designed-the-librem-5-dev-kit-with-100-free-software/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://puri.sm/posts/how-we-designed-the-librem-5-dev-kit-with-100-free-software/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Today we’re going to cover the journey of designing the Librem 5 Developer Kit and how we used 100% Free Software in its development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our dev kit’s design is released under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+, its hardware Git repository can be found here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://source.puri.sm/Librem5/dvk-mx8m-bsb&quot;&gt;https://source.puri.sm/Librem5/dvk-mx8m-bsb&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before the development of the dev kit began, it was not completely clear which path we would take to produce the design, specifically, which &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Electronic_design_automation&quot;&gt;Electronic Design Automation (EDA)&lt;/a&gt; tool would be used. Initially, the idea was to modify &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imx6rex.com/open-rex/&quot;&gt;FEDEVEL’s i.MX 6QP OpenRex&lt;/a&gt; board, which would have satisfied the dev kit’s basic requirements, but we quickly met two major issues: it used the archaic i.MX 6QP, and even worse was that it was designed in the proprietary EDA suite Altium. Luckily, I had prior experience designing electronics using the EDA tool KiCad, so Purism had the opportunity to create a dev kit design which used 100% Free Software. &lt;a href=&quot;http://kicad-pcb.org/&quot;&gt;KiCad&lt;/a&gt; was also an obvious choice not only due to its freedom respecting license (GNU GPLv3+), but also because it is a very capable electronics design suite that even outperforms several pricey proprietary tools out there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first step when designing our dev kit involved searching for components which met the requirements that we defined in our campaign. In addition to meeting the specs outlined in the campaign, while searching for components, we decided to add quite a few extra bells and whistles; including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;a charge controller (BQ25896)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;18650 battery holder for an optional li-ion battery&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;USB-C&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;mini-HDMI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SD card controller &amp;amp; micro-SD slot (since the i.MX 8M only has two uSDHC controllers)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ethernet/RJ45&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;audio codec&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;earpiece speaker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;microphone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CTIA/AHJ 4-pole 3.5mm headphone jack (with selection between on-board and external mic)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GPG smart card reader &amp;amp; slot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;haptic/vibration motor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;user/software-controllable LED&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;volume &amp;amp; power buttons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hardware kill switches &amp;amp; boot-mode switch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;16Mb SPI NOR flash&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a real-time clock (RTC)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;We also added the to-be-expected through-holes for a UART debug header which is unpopulated by default (serial over USB works on the default image shipped with your dev kit). Hint: If you are not comfortable with a soldering iron then you may be able to use a press-fit header on these through-holes, search for the part-number Autosplice 23-1063. We included an SMD 2×5 JTAG footprint on the board and verified its functionality during our prototype phase; if this is something you’re interested in playing around with then have a look for the part-number GRPB052VWQS-RC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the WWAN/baseband modem and the Wi-Fi + BT we knew we needed to go with some sort of modules, surface-mount or otherwise. Early on, Nicole had the brilliant idea of using mPCIe and M.2 modules so as to make the dev kits modular and future-proof. We eventually nailed it down to the mPCIe SIMCom SIM7100A/E baseband modem module and the M.2 RedPine RS9116 Wi-Fi+BT module.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initially, when the research phase was effectively over and we had to begin bringing our ideas into life, the i.MX 8M Quad had just recently become available on the market. In order to get a head-start in the development, add some extra modularity and future-proofness, we decided to go with a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System_on_module&quot;&gt;System-On-Module (SOM)&lt;/a&gt;, which includes the SoC, SDRAM, eMMC, and PMIC. However, even in the early stages of our development when we began drawing the schematics, there were SOMs we were interested in that still didn’t get to their first production run. At around mid-April we established a natural relationship with EmCraft who were just getting into their first big SOM production run and were close to releasing its Hardware Architecture spec sheet. We determined that EmCraft’s SOM and their general resources were exactly what we needed. Once the specific SOM we were going to use was nailed down we were able to really begin cranking through the design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The process of defining the specific components to be used on the dev kits was done concurrently with drawing the schematics. The entirety of our design was done using Git as our revision control system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-61870 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/figure1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1157&quot; height=&quot;812&quot; srcset=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/figure1.png 1157w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/figure1-300x211.png 300w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/figure1-768x539.png 768w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/figure1-1024x719.png 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1157px) 100vw, 1157px&quot;/&gt;Figure 1: An early revision of the dev kit’s schematics from May 2nd (Git commit hash 023915d5)
&lt;p&gt;After the schematic drawing was completed, we then exported our &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Netlist&quot;&gt;netlist&lt;/a&gt; file, getting us that much closer to the physical implementation of the dev kit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to using KiCad for the design of the dev kit, we also used a free software tool called &lt;a href=&quot;https://ra3xdh.github.io/&quot;&gt;Qucs-S&lt;/a&gt; and the free software SPICE-compatible simulation kernel called &lt;a href=&quot;https://xyce.sandia.gov/&quot;&gt;Xyce&lt;/a&gt; to simulate our headphone detect circuit, which included a zener diode used to protect the respective GPIO from too high or too low of input voltage from the audio codec’s HP DAC output. The combination of Qucs-S and Xyce allowed us to use the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.onsemi.com/PowerSolutions/supportDoc.do?type=models&amp;amp;rpn=MMSZ4688&quot;&gt;MMSZ4688T1G diode’s SPICE model&lt;/a&gt; in a circuit that best represented the physical conditions of nothing being inserted into the 3.5mm jack but the HP DAC output being active.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-61871 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/figure2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1227&quot; height=&quot;454&quot; srcset=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/figure2.png 1227w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/figure2-300x111.png 300w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/figure2-768x284.png 768w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/figure2-1024x379.png 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1227px) 100vw, 1227px&quot;/&gt;Figure 2: Qucs-S + Xyce simulation of the HP_DET circuit
&lt;p&gt;This simulation, as well as the simple DC case where the 3.5mm jack’s internal switch is open and only the 1MΩ pull-up to 3V3_P, the optional internal pull-up, and the zerner are present allowed us to prove that this protection method would work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around mid-June, when the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bill_of_materials&quot;&gt;Bill-Of-Materials (BOM)&lt;/a&gt; was complete and we began placing orders for the components, we were generating footprints for everything (chips, connectors, modules, etc). The process of creating these footprints involved going through each IC’s recommended land pattern as defined in their datasheet and quadruple checking to make sure everything was correct.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-61873&quot; src=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/figure3.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1920&quot; height=&quot;1016&quot; srcset=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/figure3.png 1920w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/figure3-300x159.png 300w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/figure3-768x406.png 768w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/figure3-1024x542.png 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px&quot;/&gt;Figure 3: BQ25896 charge controller’s footprint (U301 on the dev kit board, found underneath the SOM)
&lt;p&gt;Using KiCad’s amazing 3D viewer, we were able to give nearly every component a 3D model so as to help establish a tangible visualizer for the progress being made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-61874&quot; src=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/figure4.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;800&quot; srcset=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/figure4.png 800w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/figure4-150x150.png 150w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/figure4-300x300.png 300w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/figure4-768x768.png 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px&quot;/&gt;Figure 4: BQ25896 charge controller’s 3D view

&lt;p&gt;Early on, a rough &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Floorplan_(microelectronics)&quot;&gt;floorplan&lt;/a&gt; was made to help us establish how much board area was needed (90x180mm) and where the various larger components would go (connectors, receptacles, card slots, mPCIe &amp;amp; M.2 sockets, modules, etc). After really getting into the layout, some things continued to move around but were quickly pinned down on their specific locations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In late-June we began routing, starting with the USB-C receptacle (commit a1bfc689). This marked the beginning of our layout process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-61875&quot; src=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/figure5.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;688&quot; height=&quot;632&quot; srcset=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/figure5.png 688w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/figure5-300x276.png 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 688px) 100vw, 688px&quot;/&gt;Figure 5: First commit with routing involved&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-61913 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/figure6-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;733&quot; height=&quot;670&quot; srcset=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/figure6-1.png 733w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/figure6-1-300x274.png 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 733px) 100vw, 733px&quot;/&gt;Figure 6: What the USB-C routing eventually became&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-61877&quot; src=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/figure7.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1495&quot; height=&quot;694&quot; srcset=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/figure7.png 1495w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/figure7-300x139.png 300w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/figure7-768x357.png 768w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/figure7-1024x475.png 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1495px) 100vw, 1495px&quot;/&gt;Figure 7: Early rats nest before component placement &amp;amp; routing
&lt;p&gt;The routing process involved a delicate balance between working as quickly as possible while making sure everything done properly without error, including carefully routing controlled-impedance tracks and sensitive analog lines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initially we were unsure how many layers were needed and whether we needed components on both sides of the board. We knew that EmCraft’s i.MX 8M baseboard used 8-layers and had components on both sides, but we were pretty confident that we could at least cut down on the number of layers. We quickly realized that since we were going to have some components on the “back” of our board (display side), including the display connectors, proximity/ambient light sensor, user LED, speaker, and microphone, there would certainly be components on both sides of the board. Having components on both sides made the layout process somewhat easier since this freed up some space for where we could place the SPI NOR flash, smart card reader, RTC, 2.8V LDO, various ICs, passives, and other components. As for the number of layers, we decided to cut it down to 6-layers and would only add 2 additional layers if we were to hit a gridlock and not be able to route some nets; luckily this never happened and we were able to stick with just 6.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We opted to use a common stack-up which provides the best balance between ease of routing and reduces unintentional radiated emissions. The dielectric substrate that was used was NAN YA’s NP-180TL copper clad laminate, which has a relative permittivity of ~4.11 at our average operating frequency of ~1.7GHz. Our RF feedline calculations for the board’s microstrip and coplanar waveguide (CPW) feedlines using this stackup can be found in the Git repo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-61881&quot; src=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/figure8.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;634&quot; height=&quot;447&quot; srcset=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/figure8.png 634w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/figure8-300x212.png 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 634px) 100vw, 634px&quot;/&gt;Figure 8: Dev kit stack-up
&lt;p&gt;Before we began implementing the dev kit in KiCad we were not too sure if we wanted to use the nightly builds or stick with the somewhat older 4.0.7 stable release. Even though the nightly builds had several desirable features, we decided to go with the stable release so as to not have to frequently update KiCad and risk being on different versions. After getting a small dent into our layout, KiCad 5.0.0 was released! On July 16th we managed to update our dev kit project to KiCad 5.0.0 (specifically commits 4f70b865 and a4e3de8a) without much hiccup. Luckily, this update coincided with our switch from most passive components being 0603 to being 0402, since KiCad’s new passive footprints are a bit different than the old default ones, the pads having rounded corners which is more effective for lead-free solder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the updating the project to 5.0.0 we were able to focus heavily on getting through the layout and were able to get the unrouted net count down to 0 within a month (August 14th, specifically commit 9b4dd2e0).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-61885&quot; src=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/figure9.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;815&quot; height=&quot;623&quot; srcset=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/figure9.png 815w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/figure9-300x229.png 300w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/figure9-768x587.png 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 815px) 100vw, 815px&quot;/&gt;Figure 9: DRC on August 14th commit 9b4dd2e0 showing no unrouted nets and everything passing
&lt;p&gt;When all nets were routed and the Design Rules Check (DRC) was passing, we were able to go back and tidy everything up for the next week or so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our most useful resources when laying out the board were the ICs’ layout reference found in either their datasheet or their evaluation board and Toradex’s Layout Design Guide which can be found here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.toradex.com/102492-layout-design-guide.pdf&quot;&gt;https://docs.toradex.com/102492-layout-design-guide.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-61886&quot; src=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/figure10.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1500&quot; height=&quot;2995&quot; srcset=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/figure10.png 1500w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/figure10-150x300.png 150w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/figure10-768x1533.png 768w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/figure10-513x1024.png 513w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1500px) 100vw, 1500px&quot;/&gt;Figure 10: The final state of the layout (copper filled zones hidden)

&lt;p&gt;After the layout was considered complete, we had to export all of the necessary manufacturing files used to fabricate and assemble the boards. Exporting the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gerber_format&quot;&gt;Gerber files&lt;/a&gt; was straightforward since KiCad makes this step quite easy. However, our assembly house requested that we also provide a fabrication and assembly drawing which took more involvement to produce.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We mostly used gEDA’s Gerbv to preview our design’s exported Gerber files. A neat web tool that uses Gerbv and ImageMagick as its renderer is Gerblook, here’s a static link to our dev kits in Gerblook: &lt;a href=&quot;http://gerblook.org/pcb/rTgd4Aqusxr7XQLSdKa9V3&quot;&gt;http://gerblook.org/pcb/rTgd4Aqusxr7XQLSdKa9V3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-61887&quot; src=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/figure11.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;430&quot; height=&quot;848&quot; srcset=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/figure11.png 430w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/figure11-152x300.png 152w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 430px) 100vw, 430px&quot;/&gt;Figure 11: Dev kit’s Gerbers as viewed in Gerbv
&lt;p&gt;In order to generate a proper assembly drawing, we made use of KiCad’s F.Fab/B.Fab layers to show the locations, outlines, polarity, and reference designators of all components on the board. By using each of the footprints’ F/B.Fab layers we were able to generate the final drawing by printing F.Fab and B.Fab onto separate PDFs and combining them afterwards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-61888&quot; src=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/figure12.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;994&quot; srcset=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/figure12.png 500w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/figure12-151x300.png 151w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px&quot;/&gt;Figure 12: SOM side of the assembly drawing
&lt;p&gt;The fabrication drawing was even more involved. To produce this, we needed to export the fabrication notes found on the Cmts.User layer along with the board’s outline as one DXF file and then export all of the drill marks as another DXF file. After these two files are generated, they are then combined and adjusted inside a footprint drawing. Then, once we have this special “footprint” that combines the two DXF files, we hide just about everything in the layout and import this special “fab” footprint (without saving this temporary layout). At this point, everything we need is found on the Dwgs.User layer; so we are able to print this along with the frame reference onto a final fabrication drawing PDF.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-61889&quot; src=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/figure13.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;490&quot; height=&quot;967&quot; srcset=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/figure13.png 490w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/figure13-152x300.png 152w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 490px) 100vw, 490px&quot;/&gt;Figure 13: Drill markings in the fabrication drawing
&lt;p&gt;Each of these files and documents are used along with the IPC-D-356 netlist (which allows the fabrication house to do a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flying_probe&quot;&gt;flying probe test&lt;/a&gt; on the boards to make sure there are no short/open circuits), a component placement list CSV file (for the assembly house to know where and what orientation all components are placed), and finally a manually-edited GenCAD file (which is used by the assembly house to program their solder paste machines for our board).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After all of the final manufacturing files were delivered to the fabrication and assembly firms, we answered any questions they may have had during the process, and tweaked anything that may need to be adjusted based on their feedback. At around late August, the files were sent off and we were anxiously waiting for our design to hit the fabrication floor in Shenzhen. Unfortunately, as outlined in an &lt;a href=&quot;https://puri.sm/posts/librem5-2018-11-hardware-report/&quot;&gt;earlier blog post&lt;/a&gt;, several unforeseen circumstances such as severe weather and most of China observing Golden Week, we saw significant delays in the production of our prototypes. Due to these delays we decided to switch to a domestic factory for the fabrication of our prototypes, which managed to get the boards to us two weeks faster than the ones being made overseas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-61890 size-large&quot; src=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/figure14-1024x1002.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;626&quot; srcset=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/figure14-1024x1002.png 1024w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/figure14-300x294.png 300w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/figure14-768x752.png 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px&quot;/&gt;Figure 14: Prototype v0.1.2 dev kit panel (before assembly)
&lt;p&gt;After the small batch of prototypes were assembled they were quickly shipped to team members for debugging and software development. Luckily, due to constant review of the design from several parties as well as persistent scrutinization, there were very few errors found in the prototype’s hardware design (three relatively minor layout/netlist adjustments and one mechanical fix). For the following two months the prototypes were used to help bring the software to a more polished state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At around early-to-mid November, after making the minor adjustments needed to the hardware design, and once we were at a comfortable state where nearly every hardware subsystem was &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.puri.sm/Librem5/Development_Environment/Boards/Known_Issues.html&quot;&gt;validated&lt;/a&gt;, we went through the process of re-exporting and delivering the manufacturing files to our hand-picked fabrication and assembly house for the final build. At this point, a few of us at Purism used December 10th-22nd as a dedicated time to help with the assembly, testing, packing, and shipping of the final units which went out to backers (many of which were delivered before Christmas!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-61894&quot; src=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/figure16.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;895&quot; height=&quot;881&quot; srcset=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/figure16.png 895w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/figure16-300x295.png 300w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/figure16-768x756.png 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 895px) 100vw, 895px&quot;/&gt;Figure 15: Final v1.0.0 dev kit panel (before assembly)
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone wp-image-61928 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/devkit-figure16a.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;441&quot; height=&quot;876&quot; srcset=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/devkit-figure16a.png 441w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/devkit-figure16a-151x300.png 151w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 441px) 100vw, 441px&quot;/&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone wp-image-61896 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/figure17b.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;462&quot; height=&quot;846&quot; srcset=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/figure17b.png 462w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/figure17b-164x300.png 164w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 462px) 100vw, 462px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Figure 16: Fully assembled dev kit compared to the 3D view (display side)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone wp-image-61929 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/devkit-figure17a.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;441&quot; height=&quot;876&quot; srcset=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/devkit-figure17a.png 441w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/devkit-figure17a-151x300.png 151w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 441px) 100vw, 441px&quot;/&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone wp-image-61899 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/figure18b.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;434&quot; height=&quot;890&quot; srcset=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/figure18b.png 434w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/figure18b-146x300.png 146w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 434px) 100vw, 434px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Figure 17: Fully assembled dev kit compared to the 3D view (SOM side)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The entire process was quite an intense time crunch but it was well worth it, especially after we see what the community is able to produce with our efforts. Some have even already begun designing 3D printed cases for the dev kit. We look forward to seeing what cool software and uses you come up with for these awesome boards! Feel free to share all of the cool stuff you develop for the dev kit by emailing us at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:feedback@puri.sm&quot;&gt;feedback@puri.sm&lt;/a&gt;, if it’s super awesome we may just have to share it on a future blog post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now our efforts are focused getting the Librem 5 phone out the door. So until next time, stay inventive!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 16:04:52 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>aquabeagle</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://puri.sm/posts/how-we-designed-the-librem-5-dev-kit-with-100-free-software/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Unity Engine ToS change makes cloud-based SpatialOS games illegal</title>
<link>https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2019/01/unity-engine-tos-change-makes-cloud-based-spatialos-games-illegal/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2019/01/unity-engine-tos-change-makes-cloud-based-spatialos-games-illegal/</guid>
<description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/worldsadrift-800x424.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bossa Studios' MMO &amp;lt;em&amp;gt;Worlds Adrift&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt; is one of the games affected by Unity's sudden blocking of SpatialOD development tools.&quot;/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;caption-text&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/worldsadrift.jpg&quot; class=&quot;enlarge-link&quot; data-height=&quot;1017&quot; data-width=&quot;1920&quot;&gt;Enlarge&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;sep&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; Bossa Studios' MMO &lt;em&gt;Worlds Adrift&lt;/em&gt; is one of the games affected by Unity's sudden blocking of SpatialOD development tools.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;aside id=&quot;social-left&quot; aria-label=&quot;Read the comments or share this article&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;comment-count-before&quot;&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;85 posters participating, including story author&quot; class=&quot;comment-count icon-comment-bubble-down&quot; href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2019/01/unity-engine-tos-change-makes-cloud-based-spatialos-games-illegal/?comments=1&quot;&gt;reader comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;a title=&quot;85 posters participating, including story author&quot; class=&quot;comment-count icon-comment-bubble-down&quot; href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2019/01/unity-engine-tos-change-makes-cloud-based-spatialos-games-illegal/?comments=1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;comment-count-number&quot;&gt;126&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;visually-hidden&quot;&gt;with 85 posters participating, including story author&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;share-links&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Share this story&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unity Engine games developed with SpatialOS' cloud-based multiplayer Game Development Kit (GDK) are now in violation of Unity's terms of service, according to SpatialOS maker Improbable. The decision imperils the operation of many in-development game projects, including some that have already been released to the public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since its open beta release in 2017 (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/2016/12/14/spatialos-mmo-cloud-server-platform/&quot;&gt;in partnership with Google&lt;/a&gt;), SpatialOS has allowed developers to easily integrate mass-scale multiplayer into their games by running a persistent version of the game in the cloud. But Improbable &lt;a href=&quot;https://improbable.io/company/news/2019/01/10/unity-blocks-spatialos&quot;&gt;now says&lt;/a&gt; that a recent change in Unity's terms of service means the SpatialOS is essentially blocked from working with the Unity Engine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The newly updated &lt;a href=&quot;https://unity3d.com/legal/terms-of-service/software&quot;&gt;clause 2.4 of the Terms of Service&lt;/a&gt; now specifically excludes &quot;managed service[s] running on cloud infrastructure&quot; which &quot;install or execute the Unity Runtime on the cloud or a remote server.&quot; Though the terms of service were changed on December 5, Improbable says Unity confirmed directly to them this week that the update &quot;specifically disallow[s] services like Improbable’s to function with their engine. This was previously freely possible in their terms, as with other major engines.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result, Improbable says, &quot;this change effectively makes it a breach of terms to operate or create SpatialOS games using Unity, including in development and &lt;em&gt;production&lt;/em&gt; games.&quot; That &lt;a href=&quot;https://improbable.io/games/blog/category/featured-games&quot;&gt;list of imperiled games&lt;/a&gt; includes Bossa Studios MMO &lt;em&gt;Worlds Adrift&lt;/em&gt;, VR MMO &lt;em&gt;MetaWorld&lt;/em&gt;, and Klang Games' upcoming MMO &lt;em&gt;Seed&lt;/em&gt;, among others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Improbable says the ToS change comes as the company was actively negotiating with Unity &quot;to find a way to do more together.&quot; Improbable also says it is continuing to talk to Unity in an effort to reverse the decision, though its license to work with the Engine has currently been revoked. A Unity representative was not immediately available to respond to a request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Overnight, this is an action by Unity that has immediately done harm to projects across the industry, including those of extremely vulnerable or small-scale developers and damaged major projects in development over many years,&quot; Improbable says. &quot;Games that have been funded based on the promise of SpatialOS to deliver next-generation multiplayer are now endangered due to their choice of game engine. Live games are now in legal limbo.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Improbable is promising to &quot;do everything in our power to help developers using SpatialOS with Unity to finish, release, and operate their games,&quot; including using an emergency fund to help with developers' finances, releasing the Unity GDK as an open source project, and assisting in porting to new engines as a last resort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;SpatialOS [has made] it easier [for me] to build large-scale multiplayer games using a cloud-based solution,&quot; developer AtomiCal &lt;a href=&quot;https://forum.unity.com/threads/recent-tos-update-blocks-the-use-of-spatialos-to-make-games-in-unity.610447/&quot;&gt;writes on the Unity forums&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;Today I woke up to a message essentially pulling the rug from under my feet saying that I can't do that anymore. Unity won't let it happen.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll update this story as we hear back from Unity and any other developers affected by this decision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt; Bossa Studios Head of Marketing Daniel King &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mcvuk.com/development/unity-blocks-improbables-spatial-os-all-live-and-in-development-games-affected&quot;&gt;tells MCV&lt;/a&gt; &quot;Bossa’s main priority is our players. Whatever is happening in the background is outside of our control, our focus is ensuring the players are looked after and their memorable experiences in the game are protected. For now, &lt;em&gt;Worlds Adrift&lt;/em&gt; is operating as normal.&quot;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;strong&gt;Update 2, 6:26 pm ET:&lt;/strong&gt; Unity has officially denied Improbable's allegations. In &lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.unity3d.com/2019/01/10/our-response-to-improbables-blog-post-and-why-you-can-keep-working-on-your-spatialos-game/&quot;&gt;a lengthy blog post on the matter&lt;/a&gt;, the game-engine company offered a clarification for any Unity game makers concerned about their use of SpatialOS: &quot;Projects that are currently in production or live using SpatialOS are not affected by any actions we have taken with Improbable,&quot; the blog post says. &quot;If a game developer runs a Unity-based game server on their own servers or generic cloud instances (like GCP, AWS or Azure), they are covered by our EULA.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You'll have to scroll through the entire blog post to find Unity's version of the Unity-versus-Improbable story: &quot;If a third-party service wants to run the Unity Runtime in the cloud with their additional SDK, we consider this a platform. In these cases, we require the service to be an approved Unity platform partner.&quot; This, Unity alleges, was the sticking point in a negotiation process that went on for &quot;over a year&quot; with Improbable. Unity claims it sent formal, written notice of this ToS violation to Improbable &quot;six months ago.&quot; Unity adds that &quot;game developers should never pay the price&quot; for Improbable's &quot;violation&quot; of the Unity EULA, and as a result, &quot;games currently in production and/or games that are live [with use of Improbable's tech] are unaffected.&quot;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;strong&gt;Update 3, 10 pm ET:&lt;/strong&gt; Unreal Engine maker Epic Games and Improbable have teamed up to announce a $25 million fund that they say will &quot;assist developers who are left in limbo by the new engine and service incompatibilities that were introduced today... [to] transition to more open engines, services, and ecosystems.&quot; The money for this fund will be drawn from &quot;Unreal Dev Grants, Improbable developer assistance funds, and Epic Games store funding&quot; among other sources, Epic said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Epic Games’ partnership with Improbable, and the integration of Improbable’s cloud-based development platform SpatialOS, is based on shared values, and a shared belief in how companies should work together to support mutual customers in a straightforward, no-surprises way,&quot; the engine maker wrote in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Unity maintains that its ToS update does not actually imperil SpatialOS games, and that its disagreement with Improbable stems from separate license negotiations, it seems the damage to the relationship between the two companies has been done. In &lt;a href=&quot;https://improbable.io/company/news/2019/01/10/an-update-on-todays-events&quot;&gt;a follow-up blog post tonight&lt;/a&gt;, Improbable writes that &quot;a commercial dispute between two companies, in which both sides have certainly made errors, should never threaten access to essential technology used by a large number of developers. A world where this happens frequently will be a world with very little innovation in gaming.&quot;]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 15:17:36 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>MikusR</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2019/01/unity-engine-tos-change-makes-cloud-based-spatialos-games-illegal/</og:url>
<og:title>Improbable snubs Unity, partners with Epic for $25M “open engine” fund [Updated]</og:title>
<og:image>https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/worldsadrift-760x380.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>Unity says ToS change doesn't actually imperil SpatialOS games.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2019/01/unity-engine-tos-change-makes-cloud-based-spatialos-games-illegal/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>So Long, Macbook. Hello Again, Linux</title>
<link>http://richardmavis.info/so-long-macbook-hello-again-linux</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://richardmavis.info/so-long-macbook-hello-again-linux</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Long story short, after a decade on my Macbook, I switched back to Linux. Recently I’ve just found myself disenchanted with Apple in a way similar to how I felt maybe twelve years earlier with Microsoft, when I switched to Linux the first time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Linux was much more difficult back then. My first attempt installing Fedora on my laptop was a disaster. And now there are companies that sell laptops with come with Linux already installed, with hardware tested, etc. Earlier this year, my colleague &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/glreed/&quot;&gt;Garrett Reed&lt;/a&gt; suggested I look into the &lt;a href=&quot;https://puri.sm/products/librem-13/&quot;&gt;Librem&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://puri.sm/&quot;&gt;Purism&lt;/a&gt;. I bought a Librem 13. It’s been so great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back when I bought my first Macbook, I didn’t want to have to worry about my machine not working. I was sold on Unix and Apple sold the most user-friendly Unix available. They still do. I also had a laptop running Linux then but it was not that friendly—I wanted the convenience Apple provided.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I spent a decade with my Macbook and came to realize that investing some time in learning a system can pay off. I still don’t want to have to worry about hardware problems—and investing time in hunting down driver files and recompiling kernels is not the sort of investment I’m talking about—but I’m much more comfortable now with reading about a program, exploring its interface, writing or customizing config files, etc, maybe all before even using the program, than I was before. That sort of investment can pay off, particularly if it exposes you to new or unfamiliar things. The world of software can be a weird, wild, and wonderful place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here’s what I’m using now:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;PureOS, PureBrowser, etc.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-block&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;blockimg&quot; src=&quot;http://richardmavis.info/images/hello-again-linux/pure-os-and-browser.png&quot; alt=&quot;PureOS: PureBrowser and neofetch&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Librem 13 ships with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pureos.net/&quot;&gt;PureOS&lt;/a&gt;. It’s based on Debian, uses &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnome.org/gnome-3/&quot;&gt;Gnome 3&lt;/a&gt; by default, and comes with its own special version of Firefox called PureBrowser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other Linux distributions can run on the hardware but I’ve found no reason to switch. Neither have I needed to install a different browser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;i3, st&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-block&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;blockimg&quot; src=&quot;http://richardmavis.info/images/hello-again-linux/i3.png&quot; alt=&quot;i3 and st&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I have switched from Gnome to &lt;a href=&quot;https://i3wm.org/&quot;&gt;i3&lt;/a&gt;. Over the years I’ve migrated from graphical to text-based applications for most things, and when you spend most of your time on a command line or some other text-based, keyboard-driven interface, tiling window managers are amazing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re not familiar with i3 or tiling window managers in general, there are a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=j1I63wGcvU4&quot;&gt;lot&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uD3qSgsQPRg&quot;&gt;videos&lt;/a&gt; out there. But the general idea is: when you open new windows, the window manager both sizes and places it for you. And there are keyboard shortcuts for opening and closing windows, stacking and floating and resizing them, calling custom scripts, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unless you specify some other program to open, the program opened in new windows is your terminal emulator. I’m currently using &lt;a href=&quot;https://st.suckless.org/&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;st&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. It’s neat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another fun thing about i3 in particular and Linux in general is that it’s highly customizable. You can tweak so many more aspects of your experience, both the workflow and the aesthetics, than you can in other systems. You might not be impressed much with my environment—I pretty much just copied the &lt;a href=&quot;http://acme.cat-v.org/&quot;&gt;acme&lt;/a&gt; colors—but some people have put a lot of work into making their setups &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/unixporn/&quot;&gt;look sexy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;dmenu (and scripts!)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://tools.suckless.org/dmenu/&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;dmenu&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is easily the most versatile (except maybe for emacs) and delightful tool I’m using, and is the one I miss most when I use other systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’ve never used it, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=R9m723tAurA&quot;&gt;here’s a good introduction&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But if you don’t want to watch that: &lt;code&gt;dmenu&lt;/code&gt; is a simple program. It opens a window and displays a list of items and a text input area with an optional prompt. You can filter the list by typing, you can move the selection indicator with the arrow keys, and you can select an item by hitting the enter key. And it returns the text of the item you selected. And that’s it. But it adheres to the Unix philosophy, so it can be used in all sorts of different ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its default behavior is to list executable items in your &lt;code&gt;$PATH&lt;/code&gt; (which is why it’s sometimes thought of as an application launcher), and its default look is pretty gross.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-block&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;blockimg&quot; src=&quot;http://richardmavis.info/images/hello-again-linux/dmenu-default.png&quot; alt=&quot;default dmenu&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But you can customize its colors and font, you can add a prompt, and you can specify the items it lists by piping in any text you like. I like it to fit in with the rest of my theme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-block&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;blockimg&quot; src=&quot;http://richardmavis.info/images/hello-again-linux/dmenu-theme.png&quot; alt=&quot;dmenu themed&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can use it in scripts, like this one to exit i3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-block&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;blockimg&quot; src=&quot;http://richardmavis.info/images/hello-again-linux/dmenu-i3-exit.png&quot; alt=&quot;script with dmenu to exit i3&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/cdown/clipmenu&quot;&gt;clipboard manager&lt;/a&gt; that uses dmenu. I’ve styled it to fit in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-block&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;blockimg&quot; src=&quot;http://richardmavis.info/images/hello-again-linux/clipmenu.png&quot; alt=&quot;clipmenu&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://richardmavis.info/something-like-the-plumber&quot;&gt;something like the plumber&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-block&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;blockimg&quot; src=&quot;http://richardmavis.info/images/hello-again-linux/dmenu-plumber.png&quot; alt=&quot;dmenu + plumber = awesome&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;img-block&quot;&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;emacs&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;blockimg&quot; src=&quot;http://richardmavis.info/images/hello-again-linux/emacs.png&quot; alt=&quot;emacs&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;emacs is great. I’ve been using it for almost twelve years. The more I learn about it, the more I love it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;mbsync and notmuch&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-block&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;blockimg&quot; src=&quot;http://richardmavis.info/images/hello-again-linux/email.png&quot; alt=&quot;email with mbsync and notmuch in emacs&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://isync.sourceforge.net/&quot;&gt;mbsync&lt;/a&gt; is a program for syncing mailboxes. Essentially, when you run it, the program downloads new messages, syncs deletions, etc, between your local machine and your mail server(s). It’s a great way to pull your mail down to your local computer, both for backups and for reading and writing offline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://notmuchmail.org/&quot;&gt;notmuch&lt;/a&gt; handles indexing and tagging your email for fast and easy searching (everywhere) and also presents a great interface (in emacs).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;cmus&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-block&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;blockimg&quot; src=&quot;http://richardmavis.info/images/hello-again-linux/cmus.png&quot; alt=&quot;cmus&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For music, I’m using &lt;a href=&quot;https://cmus.github.io/&quot;&gt;cmus&lt;/a&gt;. It’s a big change from iTunes, and I miss seeing album art, but it’s super fast and fairly easy to use once you get used to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;In Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-block&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;blockimg&quot; src=&quot;http://richardmavis.info/images/hello-again-linux/great-cow.png&quot; alt=&quot;linux is great&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 14:46:08 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Chirael</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://richardmavis.info/so-long-macbook-hello-again-linux</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>