<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>DirectX on Linux</title>
<link>https://lkml.org/lkml/2020/5/19/742</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://lkml.org/lkml/2020/5/19/742</guid>
<description>&lt;pre itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
There is a blog post that goes into more detail about the bigger&lt;br /&gt;picture, and walks through all the required pieces to make this work. It&lt;br /&gt;is available here:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://devblogs.microsoft.com/directx/directx-heart-linux&quot;&gt;https://devblogs.microsoft.com/directx/directx-heart-linux&lt;/a&gt; . The rest of&lt;br /&gt;this cover letter will focus on the Linux Kernel bits.&lt;p&gt;Overview&lt;br /&gt;========&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the first draft of the Microsoft Virtual GPU (vGPU) driver. The&lt;br /&gt;driver exposes a paravirtualized GPU to user mode applications running&lt;br /&gt;in a virtual machine on a Windows host. This enables hardware&lt;br /&gt;acceleration in environment such as WSL (Windows Subsystem for Linux)&lt;br /&gt;where the Linux virtual machine is able to share the GPU with the&lt;br /&gt;Windows host.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The projection is accomplished by exposing the WDDM (Windows Display&lt;br /&gt;Driver Model) interface as a set of IOCTL. This allows APIs and user&lt;br /&gt;mode driver written against the WDDM GPU abstraction on Windows to be&lt;br /&gt;ported to run within a Linux environment. This enables the port of the&lt;br /&gt;D3D12 and DirectML APIs as well as their associated user mode driver to&lt;br /&gt;Linux. This also enables third party APIs, such as the popular NVIDIA&lt;br /&gt;Cuda compute API, to be hardware accelerated within a WSL environment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Only the rendering/compute aspect of the GPU are projected to the&lt;br /&gt;virtual machine, no display functionality is exposed. Further, at this&lt;br /&gt;time there are no presentation integration. So although the D3D12 API&lt;br /&gt;can be use to render graphics offscreen, there is no path (yet) for&lt;br /&gt;pixel to flow from the Linux environment back onto the Windows host&lt;br /&gt;desktop. This GPU stack is effectively side-by-side with the native&lt;br /&gt;Linux graphics stack.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The driver creates the /dev/dxg device, which can be opened by user mode&lt;br /&gt;application and handles their ioctls. The IOCTL interface to the driver&lt;br /&gt;is defined in dxgkmthk.h (Dxgkrnl Graphics Port Driver ioctl&lt;br /&gt;definitions). The interface matches the D3DKMT interface on Windows.&lt;br /&gt;Ioctls are implemented in ioctl.c.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When a VM starts, hyper-v on the host adds virtual GPU devices to the VM&lt;br /&gt;via the hyper-v driver. The host offers several VM bus channels to the&lt;br /&gt;VM: the global channel and one channel per virtual GPU, assigned to the&lt;br /&gt;VM.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The driver registers with the hyper-v driver (hv_driver) for the arrival&lt;br /&gt;of VM bus channels. dxg_probe_device recognizes the vGPU channels and&lt;br /&gt;creates the corresponding objects (dxgadapter for vGPUs and dxgglobal&lt;br /&gt;for the global channel).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The driver uses the hyper-V VM bus interface to communicate with the&lt;br /&gt;host. dxgvmbus.c implements the communication interface.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The global channel has 8GB of IO space assigned by the host. This space&lt;br /&gt;is managed by the host and used to give the guest direct CPU access to&lt;br /&gt;some allocations. Video memory is allocated on the host except in the&lt;br /&gt;case of existing_sysmem allocations. The Windows host allocates memory&lt;br /&gt;for the GPU on behalf of the guest. The Linux guest can access that&lt;br /&gt;memory by mapping GPU virtual address to allocations and then&lt;br /&gt;referencing those GPU virtual address from within GPU command buffers&lt;br /&gt;submitted to the GPU. For allocations which require CPU access, the&lt;br /&gt;allocation is mapped by the host into a location in the 8GB of IO space&lt;br /&gt;reserved in the guest for that purpose. The Windows host uses the nested&lt;br /&gt;CPU page table to ensure that this guest IO space always map to the&lt;br /&gt;correct location for the allocation as it may migrate between dedicated&lt;br /&gt;GPU memory (e.g. VRAM, firmware reserved DDR) and shared system memory&lt;br /&gt;(regular DDR) over its lifetime. The Linux guest maps a user mode CPU&lt;br /&gt;virtual address to an allocation IO space range for direct access by&lt;br /&gt;user mode APIs and drivers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Implementation of LX_DXLOCK2 ioctl&lt;br /&gt;==================================&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We would appreciate your feedback on the implementation of the&lt;br /&gt;LX_DXLOCK2 ioctl.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This ioctl is used to get a CPU address to an allocation, which is&lt;br /&gt;resident in video/system memory on the host. The way it works:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;1. The driver sends the Lock message to the host&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;2. The host allocates space in the VM IO space and maps it to the&lt;br /&gt;allocation memory&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;3. The host returns the address in IO space for the mapped allocation&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;4. The driver (in dxg_map_iospace) allocates a user mode virtual address&lt;br /&gt;range using vm_mmap and maps it to the IO space using&lt;br /&gt;io_remap_ofn_range)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;5. The VA is returned to the application&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Internal objects&lt;br /&gt;================&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following objects are created by the driver (defined in dxgkrnl.h):&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;- dxgadapter - represents a virtual GPU&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;- dxgprocess - tracks per process state (handle table of created&lt;br /&gt;objects, list of objects, etc.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;- dxgdevice - a container for other objects (contexts, paging queues,&lt;br /&gt;allocations, GPU synchronization objects)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;- dxgcontext - represents thread of GPU execution for packet&lt;br /&gt;scheduling.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;- dxghwqueue - represents thread of GPU execution of hardware scheduling&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;- dxgallocation - represents a GPU accessible allocation&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;- dxgsyncobject - represents a GPU synchronization object&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;- dxgresource - collection of dxgalloction objects&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;- dxgsharedresource, dxgsharedsyncobj - helper objects to share objects&lt;br /&gt;between different dxgdevice objects, which can belong to different&lt;br /&gt;processes&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Object handles&lt;br /&gt;==============&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;All GPU objects, created by the driver, are accessible by a handle&lt;br /&gt;(d3dkmt_handle). Each process has its own handle table, which is&lt;br /&gt;implemented in hmgr.c. For each API visible object, created by the&lt;br /&gt;driver, there is an object, created on the host. For example, the is a&lt;br /&gt;dxgprocess object on the host for each dxgprocess object in the VM, etc.&lt;br /&gt;The object handles have the same value in the host and the VM, which is&lt;br /&gt;done to avoid translation from the guest handles to the host handles.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Signaling CPU events by the host&lt;br /&gt;================================&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The WDDM interface provides a way to signal CPU event objects when&lt;br /&gt;execution of a context reached certain point. The way it is implemented:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;- application sends an event_fd via ioctl to the driver&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;- eventfd_ctx_get is used to get a pointer to the file object&lt;br /&gt;(eventfd_ctx)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;- the pointer to sent the host via a VM bus message&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;- when GPU execution reaches a certain point, the host sends a message&lt;br /&gt;to the VM with the event pointer&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;- signal_guest_event() handles the messages and eventually&lt;br /&gt;eventfd_signal() is called.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sasha Levin (4):&lt;br /&gt;gpu: dxgkrnl: core code&lt;br /&gt;gpu: dxgkrnl: hook up dxgkrnl&lt;br /&gt;Drivers: hv: vmbus: hook up dxgkrnl&lt;br /&gt;gpu: dxgkrnl: create a MAINTAINERS entry&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;MAINTAINERS                      |    7 +&lt;br /&gt;drivers/gpu/Makefile             |    2 +-&lt;br /&gt;drivers/gpu/dxgkrnl/Kconfig      |   10 +&lt;br /&gt;drivers/gpu/dxgkrnl/Makefile     |   12 +&lt;br /&gt;drivers/gpu/dxgkrnl/d3dkmthk.h   | 1635 +++++++++&lt;br /&gt;drivers/gpu/dxgkrnl/dxgadapter.c | 1399 ++++++++&lt;br /&gt;drivers/gpu/dxgkrnl/dxgkrnl.h    |  913 ++++++&lt;br /&gt;drivers/gpu/dxgkrnl/dxgmodule.c  |  692 ++++&lt;br /&gt;drivers/gpu/dxgkrnl/dxgprocess.c |  355 ++&lt;br /&gt;drivers/gpu/dxgkrnl/dxgvmbus.c   | 2955 +++++++++++++++++&lt;br /&gt;drivers/gpu/dxgkrnl/dxgvmbus.h   |  859 +++++&lt;br /&gt;drivers/gpu/dxgkrnl/hmgr.c       |  593 ++++&lt;br /&gt;drivers/gpu/dxgkrnl/hmgr.h       |  107 +&lt;br /&gt;drivers/gpu/dxgkrnl/ioctl.c      | 5269 ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++&lt;br /&gt;drivers/gpu/dxgkrnl/misc.c       |  280 ++&lt;br /&gt;drivers/gpu/dxgkrnl/misc.h       |  288 ++&lt;br /&gt;drivers/video/Kconfig            |    2 +&lt;br /&gt;include/linux/hyperv.h           |   16 +&lt;br /&gt;18 files changed, 15393 insertions(+), 1 deletion(-)&lt;br /&gt;create mode 100644 drivers/gpu/dxgkrnl/Kconfig&lt;br /&gt;create mode 100644 drivers/gpu/dxgkrnl/Makefile&lt;br /&gt;create mode 100644 drivers/gpu/dxgkrnl/d3dkmthk.h&lt;br /&gt;create mode 100644 drivers/gpu/dxgkrnl/dxgadapter.c&lt;br /&gt;create mode 100644 drivers/gpu/dxgkrnl/dxgkrnl.h&lt;br /&gt;create mode 100644 drivers/gpu/dxgkrnl/dxgmodule.c&lt;br /&gt;create mode 100644 drivers/gpu/dxgkrnl/dxgprocess.c&lt;br /&gt;create mode 100644 drivers/gpu/dxgkrnl/dxgvmbus.c&lt;br /&gt;create mode 100644 drivers/gpu/dxgkrnl/dxgvmbus.h&lt;br /&gt;create mode 100644 drivers/gpu/dxgkrnl/hmgr.c&lt;br /&gt;create mode 100644 drivers/gpu/dxgkrnl/hmgr.h&lt;br /&gt;create mode 100644 drivers/gpu/dxgkrnl/ioctl.c&lt;br /&gt;create mode 100644 drivers/gpu/dxgkrnl/misc.c&lt;br /&gt;create mode 100644 drivers/gpu/dxgkrnl/misc.h&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;-- &lt;br /&gt;2.25.1&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 22:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>modeless</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://lkml.org/lkml/2020/5/19/742</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Introducing Facebook Shops</title>
<link>https://about.fb.com/news/2020/05/introducing-facebook-shops/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://about.fb.com/news/2020/05/introducing-facebook-shops/</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;content uk-width-4-5@m uk-width-1-1@s&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Facebook has always been about connecting you to what you love. That means friends and family, but also products, brands and businesses. For years, people have used our apps to buy and sell things from the early days of posting a photo of a bicycle with the caption “for sale,” to selling your coffee table on Marketplace and now shopping styles from your favorite brands and influencers on Instagram. It was the people who use our apps who envisioned social commerce. We’re helping them make it a reality. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;We want to give people a place to experience the joy of shopping versus the chore of buying. And we want to help small businesses adapt and make it easier for people to discover and shop for things they love.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Right now many&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://about.fb.com/news/2020/05/state-of-small-business-report/&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;small businesses are struggling&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, and with stores closing, more are looking to bring their business online. Our goal is to make shopping seamless and empower anyone from a small business owner to a global brand to use our apps to connect with customers. That’s why we’re launching Facebook Shops and investing in features across our apps that inspire people to shop and make buying and selling online easier. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introducing Facebook Shops&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Facebook Shops make it easy for businesses to set up a single online store for customers to access on both Facebook and Instagram. Creating a Facebook Shop is free and simple. Businesses can choose the products they want to feature from their catalog and then customize the look and feel of their shop with a cover image and accent colors that showcase their brand. This means any seller, no matter their size or budget, can bring their business online and connect with customers wherever and whenever it’s convenient for them. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;People can find Facebook Shops on a business’ Facebook Page or Instagram profile, or discover them through stories or ads. From there, you can browse the full collection, save products you’re interested in and place an order&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;—&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;either on the business’ website or without leaving the app if the business has enabled&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://about.instagram.com/blog/announcements/introducing-instagram-checkout&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;checkout&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;in the US.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;jetpack-slideshow-noscript robots-nocontent&quot;&gt;This slideshow requires JavaScript.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;And just like when you’re in a physical store and need to ask someone for help, in Facebook Shops you’ll be able to message a business through WhatsApp, Messenger or Instagram Direct to ask questions, get support, track deliveries and more. And in the future, you’ll be able to view a business’ shop and make purchases right within a chat in WhatsApp, Messenger or Instagram Direct. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;jetpack-slideshow-noscript robots-nocontent&quot;&gt;This slideshow requires JavaScript.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;We’re starting to roll out Facebook Shops today, and it will be more widely available in the coming months. You can learn more about how we built Shops with privacy in mind &lt;a href=&quot;https://about.fb.com/news/2020/05/privacy-matters-facebook-shops/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;We’re also investing in features across our apps like Instagram Shop, live shopping and more that will be integrated with Facebook Shops to help customers discover products they’re interested in and make purchasing easier.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Instagram Shop: A New Place to Discover Products and Brands&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;This summer, starting in the US, we’re introducing Instagram Shop, a new way to discover and buy products you love in Instagram Explore. You can get inspired by collections from&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/shop/&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;@shop&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, browse selections from your favorite brands and creators, filter by categories like beauty and home, and purchase the looks you love all in one place. And later this year, we’re adding a new shop tab in the navigation bar, so you can get to Instagram Shop in just one tap. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://about.fb.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/IGShopCheckout_Colored.jpeg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-large wp-image-23003&quot; src=&quot;https://about.fb.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/IGShopCheckout_Colored.jpeg?w=890&amp;amp;resize=890%2C501&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshots of Instagram Shop&quot; width=&quot;890&quot; height=&quot;501&quot; srcset=&quot;https://about.fb.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/IGShopCheckout_Colored.jpeg?w=1920 1920w, https://about.fb.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/IGShopCheckout_Colored.jpeg?w=300 300w, https://about.fb.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/IGShopCheckout_Colored.jpeg?w=768 768w, https://about.fb.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/IGShopCheckout_Colored.jpeg?w=1024 1024w, https://about.fb.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/IGShopCheckout_Colored.jpeg?w=1536 1536w, https://about.fb.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/IGShopCheckout_Colored.jpeg?w=800 800w, https://about.fb.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/IGShopCheckout_Colored.jpeg?w=1780 1780w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 890px) 100vw, 890px&quot; data-recalc-dims=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Live Shopping Features&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;People have been using live video on our apps to showcase products for years, from shoe stores announcing new sneakers to beauty influencers trying on different lipsticks. Now, we’re making it easier to shop for products in real time. Soon, sellers, brands and creators will be able to tag products from their Facebook Shop or catalog before going live and those products will be shown at the bottom of the video so people can easily tap to learn more and purchase. We’re starting to test this with businesses on Facebook and Instagram, and we’ll roll it out more broadly in the coming months. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://about.fb.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/LiveShopping_FB_Colored.jpeg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone wp-image-23001 size-large&quot; src=&quot;https://about.fb.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/LiveShopping_FB_Colored.jpeg?w=890&amp;amp;resize=890%2C501&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot of Live shopping on Facebook&quot; width=&quot;890&quot; height=&quot;501&quot; srcset=&quot;https://about.fb.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/LiveShopping_FB_Colored.jpeg?w=1920 1920w, https://about.fb.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/LiveShopping_FB_Colored.jpeg?w=300 300w, https://about.fb.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/LiveShopping_FB_Colored.jpeg?w=768 768w, https://about.fb.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/LiveShopping_FB_Colored.jpeg?w=1024 1024w, https://about.fb.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/LiveShopping_FB_Colored.jpeg?w=1536 1536w, https://about.fb.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/LiveShopping_FB_Colored.jpeg?w=800 800w, https://about.fb.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/LiveShopping_FB_Colored.jpeg?w=1780 1780w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 890px) 100vw, 890px&quot; data-recalc-dims=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://about.fb.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/LiveShopping_IG_Colored.jpeg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone wp-image-23002 size-large&quot; src=&quot;https://about.fb.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/LiveShopping_IG_Colored.jpeg?w=890&amp;amp;resize=890%2C501&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot of Live shopping on Instagram&quot; width=&quot;890&quot; height=&quot;501&quot; srcset=&quot;https://about.fb.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/LiveShopping_IG_Colored.jpeg?w=1920 1920w, https://about.fb.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/LiveShopping_IG_Colored.jpeg?w=300 300w, https://about.fb.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/LiveShopping_IG_Colored.jpeg?w=768 768w, https://about.fb.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/LiveShopping_IG_Colored.jpeg?w=1024 1024w, https://about.fb.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/LiveShopping_IG_Colored.jpeg?w=1536 1536w, https://about.fb.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/LiveShopping_IG_Colored.jpeg?w=800 800w, https://about.fb.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/LiveShopping_IG_Colored.jpeg?w=1780 1780w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 890px) 100vw, 890px&quot; data-recalc-dims=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Connecting Loyalty Programs to Your Facebook Account&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;We’re also testing ways to make it easier to earn rewards with businesses you love by enabling you to connect your loyalty programs, like the points program at your local cafe, to your Facebook account. You’ll be able to easily see and keep track of your points and rewards. And we’re exploring ways to help small businesses create, manage and surface a loyalty program on Facebook Shops. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://about.fb.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/FBLoyaltyProgram_Colored.jpeg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-large wp-image-23004&quot; src=&quot;https://about.fb.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/FBLoyaltyProgram_Colored.jpeg?w=890&amp;amp;resize=890%2C501&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshots of connected loyalty programs on Facebook&quot; width=&quot;890&quot; height=&quot;501&quot; srcset=&quot;https://about.fb.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/FBLoyaltyProgram_Colored.jpeg?w=1920 1920w, https://about.fb.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/FBLoyaltyProgram_Colored.jpeg?w=300 300w, https://about.fb.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/FBLoyaltyProgram_Colored.jpeg?w=768 768w, https://about.fb.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/FBLoyaltyProgram_Colored.jpeg?w=1024 1024w, https://about.fb.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/FBLoyaltyProgram_Colored.jpeg?w=1536 1536w, https://about.fb.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/FBLoyaltyProgram_Colored.jpeg?w=800 800w, https://about.fb.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/FBLoyaltyProgram_Colored.jpeg?w=1780 1780w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 890px) 100vw, 890px&quot; data-recalc-dims=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Working With Partners&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;We’re also working more closely with partners like&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;Shopify, BigCommerce, WooCommerce, ChannelAdvisor, CedCommerce, Cafe24, Tienda Nube and Feedonomics to give small businesses the support they need. These organizations offer powerful tools to help entrepreneurs start and run their businesses and move online. Now they’ll help small businesses build and grow their Facebook Shops and use our other commerce tools.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;We hope these tools can relieve some of the pressure small businesses are facing right now and help businesses of all sizes prepare for the future.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 17:46:30 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>davidbarker</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Introducing Facebook Shops: Helping Small Businesses Sell Online - About Facebook</og:title>
<og:description>We’re launching Facebook Shops and investing in features across our apps that inspire people to shop and make selling online easier. </og:description>
<og:url>https://about.fb.com/news/2020/05/introducing-facebook-shops/</og:url>
<og:image>https://about.fb.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NRP-f8_Commerce_Banner_FINAL-2.jpg?w=1200</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://about.fb.com/news/2020/05/introducing-facebook-shops/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Simple Personal Finance Tracking with GnuCash</title>
<link>https://www.csun.io/2020/05/17/gnucash-finance.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.csun.io/2020/05/17/gnucash-finance.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;May 17, 2020&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.csun.io/images/gnucash/ytd_food.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can recall in great detail the first time I learned about GnuCash. It was a sunny spring morning in Clear Creek Canyon, CO. My little white Prius, freshly dented by the previous week’s hail, was parked precariously on the thin strip of gravel separating the road from the steep, 30ft slope to the creek below. Looking down at it from beneath the rocky cliff band we were preparing to climb, it almost seemed poised to tumble into the rushing water at any moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I wasn’t worried about that. I was too busy complaining about my troubles with tracking my personal finances. “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ledger-cli.org/&quot;&gt;Ledger’s&lt;/a&gt; simple plaintext interface was charming at first, but it’s getting a little tedious to input transactions like that. And I’m starting to want a more advanced GUI for plotting and generating reports,” I griped, stepping into my harness. My friends’ eyes glazed over as they nodded politely in agreement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that’s when it happened. That’s when the man belaying on the route next to us turned to me and said, “you should try GnuCash.” Though shrouded by the hood of his gray sweatshirt and his tinted wraparound sunglasses, his face was the face of someone who deeply &lt;em&gt;cared&lt;/em&gt; about open source accounting software. And in that instant, my decision was made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would switch to GnuCash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, dear reader, let me be your man in gray hoodie and wrap around sunglasses. I will help you take your first steps down the path to financial enlightenment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnucash.org/&quot;&gt;GnuCash&lt;/a&gt; is free, cross-platform, open source accounting software. I would like to explain to you how to use it to keep track of your personal finances, and in turn make better decisions about your spending and saving. You can also use its data to make cool graphs, like the one above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using GnuCash might interest you if:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You’ve ever wanted to quickly answer questions about your finances, like “how much of my income am I actually saving each month?” or, “how has this pandemic affected my spending habits?”&lt;/strong&gt; In the graph above, notice when my spending on groceries overtakes my spending on takeout. It’s roughly on the date of the first stay-at-home order here in Washington. Cool, right? Those are the sorts of trends you can unearth with this data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You want to own all of your financial data.&lt;/strong&gt; I know there are some online offerings out there that promise to automagically handle the tedious parts of using GnuCash, and I would encourage you to research those as well. I choose not to use any of them because I would like to have access to my data indefinitely. I don’t want that access to hinge on a company staying in business for the rest of my life, or having the goodwill to let me download it in a future-proof file format. Because GnuCash is open source and already has good cross-platform support, I feel comfortable trusting that it (or a free replacement) will still be around in N years.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You want to promote good financial habits.&lt;/strong&gt; Most of the value I get from using GnuCash comes from being forced to think about every single transaction I make. Stupid purchases have a lot more weight when you can see their impact on your finances as a whole. Also, by forcing yourself to log and verify all of your transactions, you’ll be much more likely to catch fraudulent activity on your accounts early before they can cause damage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GnuCash might not be for you if:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A time investment of 2-4 hours a month is too much for you.&lt;/strong&gt; Those numbers could be higher or lower depending on the complexity of your personal financial situation, but that’s roughly the amount of time I spend.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You wouldn’t benefit from having more granular financial data.&lt;/strong&gt; If you’re happy with just knowing that your credit card balance is less than a certain amount each month, that’s great! You don’t need GnuCash. If, however, you want to know &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; your credit card balance is a certain amount each month, you might want to read the rest of this post.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finance people care about returns. So in the spirit of doing finance-y stuff, I figured I’d showcase the sorts of returns you can expect from investing your time into GnuCash. Just a heads-up, all of these graphs have had the dollar values redacted (because it’s my real data), but rest assured that these would show actual amounts if you were to generate them yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lets’s start with some examples from GnuCash’s built-in suite of customizable reports and graphs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.csun.io/images/gnucash/expenses_piechart.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.csun.io/images/gnucash/income_expense.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These can reveal all sorts of trends at a glance, which can then be dug into using robust search functionalities built into the program. And if the built-in search and reports don’t have the functionality you need, that’s ok! We own all of our data, and can choose to save it in a variety of friendly formats (XML, SQLite, etc.) If there’s something you want to see calculated or plotted, you can always use a package like &lt;a href=&quot;https://pythonhosted.org/piecash/&quot;&gt;piecash&lt;/a&gt; to query against your data and generate custom plots. That’s what I did in order to generate the reports below, which show me in real-time how close I am to meeting my monthly and yearly budgets. I’ve also released these scripts &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/csun/simple_gnucash_budget_plots&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; so you can use them for your own GnuCash purposes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.csun.io/images/gnucash/month_4_food.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.csun.io/images/gnucash/ytd_expenses.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the highest level, you can think of GnuCash as a place to keep track of a set of &lt;em&gt;accounts&lt;/em&gt;, where each account represents a source of money. For the most part, each real-world money account you own will be tracked by its own GnuCash account. Your checking account, 401k, credit card, and Venmo would all be individual accounts in GnuCash. However, not every GnuCash account necessarily represents a single real-world money account, as we’ll address later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to keep the values in these accounts up to date, we create &lt;em&gt;transactions&lt;/em&gt;. Each transaction has an associated date, description, and amount. Every time something happens that changes the amount of money that you have, you record it in GnuCash as one of these transactions. For example, if you were to go to a bakery and buy a cake, you would create a corresponding transaction in your credit card GnuCash account - like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.csun.io/images/gnucash/gnucash_transaction.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This should be a very familiar sight, as it’s nearly identical to how your bank or credit card display things on your statement. When a $13.19 transaction is added to your credit card statement, your total balance increases by $13.19. The exact same thing happens here. However, there is one major difference that you need to understand:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In GnuCash, money is never created - only transferred.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That may sound very abstract and zen proverbe-esque, but it’s at the heart of what makes GnuCash so powerful, and is the most important thing to understand when using GnuCash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can see this principle in action in my bakery example. Take a look at the “Transfer” column: it shows that the $13.19 we’re adding to our credit card bill is not appearing out of thin air, but is instead being &lt;em&gt;transferred&lt;/em&gt; from an account named “Expenses:Food:Take Out”. If you think about it, this is exactly what happens in the real world, too. That $13.19 on your credit card statement doesn’t just appear out of thin air. Behind the scenes, the credit card company is paying the bakery $13.19 (sans fees) and then taking that $13.19 from you. The money wasn’t &lt;em&gt;created&lt;/em&gt;, it was &lt;em&gt;transferred&lt;/em&gt; from your credit card balance to the bakery’s bank account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This simple but powerful concept is called &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Double-entry_bookkeeping&quot;&gt;double-entry bookkeeping&lt;/a&gt;, and its purpose is twofold. First and foremost, it protects you from making accounting errors. There’s no way to record a $1000 payment for rent, and then accidentally forget a zero and only deduct $100 from your bank account. By definition, every single dollar needs to come from somewhere, so GnuCash will notice $900 that are unaccounted for and will complain. A state of balance is strictly enforced. Secondly, this system automatically categorizes every transaction you make. Every time we earn or spend money, we by definition know where it came from and where it went. This makes things a whole lot easier when trying to generate reports later down the line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice, however, that GnuCash is transferring money to an account called “Expenses:Food:Take Out”, not “Bakery Bank Account”. So what gives? Well, while it is entirely possible to make a new virtual account for every real-world money account that we interact with, it just doesn’t benefit us to do so. From a budgeting standpoint, we don’t care how much we spend at Whole Foods vs Trader Joe’s, we just care about how much we’ve spent on groceries in general - so we can throw all of those transactions in an “Expenses:Food:Groceries” account (GnuCash uses colons to denote nested accounts, so this is really the “Groceries” child account of a “Food” account in the “Expenses” grandparent account.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same goes for other things as well. We don’t care about how much money we’ve spent at Amazon, we care about &lt;em&gt;what we’ve spent our money on when we’ve shopped at Amazon.&lt;/em&gt; Bought a desk? Charge it to the “Expenses:Furniture” account. A whisk? That goes in “Expenses:Kitchen Supplies”. Not specific enough for you? Create an “Expenses:Furniture:Office” account, or an “Expenses:Kitchen Supplies:Metallic” account. Too much work? Just throw those transactions into the root “Expenses” account and be done with it. &lt;em&gt;With GnuCash, you are completely in control of how you organize your transactions.&lt;/em&gt; How you choose to do this will affect the level of granularity you can achieve in your reports and plots, but it’s otherwise all the same to GnuCash. All that GnuCash cares about is whether or not the transactions are balanced - when money enters one account, the same amount of money must leave from another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.csun.io/images/gnucash/gnucash_main.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you first start up GnuCash, it will pop up a little setup wizard that forces you to create some accounts. As alluded to above, you can choose to organize your accounts however you like. With that being said, there are five top-level accounts that GnuCash will automatically create, and all other accounts you create will likely fall under these top-level accounts (as can be seen in my accounts page above). These accounts are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Assets&lt;/strong&gt; are things you actually own, like checking accounts, brokerage accounts, 401ks, Venmo account, cash in your wallet, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Equity&lt;/strong&gt; is described by the GnuCash docs as “overall net worth”, but I’ve always been iffy on how that differs from Assets for my use case. As such, I mostly choose not to use it. It may serve a purpose if you’re doing some more advanced accounting or using certain built-in reports.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Expenses&lt;/strong&gt; are destinations for money that you spend, like groceries, rent, taxes, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Income&lt;/strong&gt; accounts are sources of money that you receive, like salary from an employer, gifts, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Liabilities&lt;/strong&gt; are things you owe - money that you’re going to have to pay eventually, but haven’t yet. Personally, I only use this as the parent account for my credit cards, but you could track things like personal debts or loans here as well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is important to create these specific accounts because GnuCash treats transactions between them differently based on their account types. For example, a positive balance in a “Liabilities:” account indicates that you own a negative amount of money whereas a positive balance in an “Assets:” account indicates a positive amount. Similarly, some of the GnuCash built-in reports rely on having the right account types set as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you make it through the setup wizard, take a look through some of the default accounts that GnuCash has created for you. Feel free to delete the ones you won’t use, and create new ones that you will. When you’re done with that, you’ll have a bunch of accounts - all with a balance of $0. Obviously, most of your real-world money accounts have some non-zero amount of money in them, so our final step in the setup process is to change the GnuCash ones to reflect that. As we know by now, we can’t just create this money - it needs to be transferred from somewhere. GnuCash helpfully gives us a premade “Equity:Opening Balances” account to use just for this purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.csun.io/images/gnucash/empty_checking_account.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;img-medium&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s say we’ve just created an empty account named “Assets:Checking Account”, and we want to set it up so that it reflects the balance of our real-world checking account, which has $1000 in it. To do this, we’d fill out a new transaction entry with the current date, a description of “Opening Balance”, a transfer account of “Equity:Opening Balances”, and a Deposit of $1000. When we enter that transaction, our account page will update to reflect our new balance of $1000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.csun.io/images/gnucash/full_checking_account.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;img-medium&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, if you open up the “Equity:Opening Balances” account, you’ll actually be able to see and edit the transaction there as well. This is GnuCash’s golden rule in action. To get the $1000 into your bank account, it needed to leave the opening balances account. As such, both accounts will display the transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re quick, you can finish this initial setup in less than 10 minutes. Congrats! You’re on your way to a wealth of rich financial data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now comes the hard part: remembering to actually log all of your transactions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to maintain a state of balance, you’re going to record every single transaction you make - which sounds scary, but only takes me around 2-4 hours a month split across two sessions. If you’re more disciplined than I am, you can do your logging incrementally instead of all at once. I haven’t tried that, but I’d bet it could cut the total time invested down to around an hour or so per month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being successful at logging your data all starts with having a good workflow for &lt;em&gt;collecting&lt;/em&gt; the data (receipts, invoices, etc.) In practice, I handle three separate cases here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;In the ideal case, I log purchases in the GnuCash mobile app. So, as soon as I pay the bill at a bar/restaurant/store, I’ll immediately pull out my phone and log the transaction. The app support both Android and iOS, and you can import your account structure from desktop so that autocomplete works.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sometimes I forget to use the mobile app, so for restaurants that support email receipts (and online purchases), I prefer those over paper receipts. The next time I check my email, I immediately move any receipts to a receipts folder to get them out of my inbox (I practice &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fastcompany.com/40507663/the-7-step-guide-to-achieving-inbox-zero-and-staying-there-in-2018&quot;&gt;inbox zero&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paper receipts are the worst-case, but many places are still paper-only. These suck because they’re easy to lose. I recommend buying a little &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/JMAF-Straight-Paper-Holder-Spike/dp/B07CR7S1FQ/ref=sr_1_4?dchild=1&amp;amp;keywords=receipt+spike&amp;amp;qid=1589768035&amp;amp;sr=8-4&quot;&gt;receipt spike&lt;/a&gt; off of Amazon for $6, and sticking any amassed paper receipts on it as soon as you get home (which has the added benefit of keeping them in chronological order).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Next comes the actual data entry. The first step here is to import any transactions logged from GnuCash mobile. The app has a nice feature where it remembers the last time you exported, and then will only dump new transactions to any number of file formats, which can then be ingested by the desktop version of the app. Once this is done, it’s just a matter of hammering away at entering all the receipts you’ve saved. If you remember the steps we went through for setting our opening balances, that’s essentially all you need to do for each receipt - just changing the date, description, amount, and transfer account for each one. This might sound terrible, but it’s very easy once you get into the habit. Honestly, it can be super relaxing at times. I tend to do my logging first thing on a Sunday morning - just throw a soccer game or some mindless YouTube on the second monitor and enter cruise control for a little.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, there’s a potential (large) shortcut here. Instead of saving and entering all of your receipts manually, you could just export all of your credit card/bank account transactions from your bank website, then &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnucash.org/docs/v3/C/gnucash-help/trans-import.html&quot;&gt;import them into GnuCash&lt;/a&gt;. There are a few reasons why I don’t personally do this, though. First of all, going through each transaction manually forces me to think about how I’m spending, which is really (IMO) the whole point of using GnuCash as an individual. Secondly, I manually log my transactions because I want more granularity than the categories that my credit card company auto-assigns to each transaction (though you could always just edit these after import). Finally, auto-importing transactions from another source is also going to auto-import any potentially fraudulent charges that might be in there. Of course, you could (should) go through each one of the imported transactions and look for suspicious ones, but I feel like I’d personally be more likely to miss something that way than if I were to manually enter everything I have receipts for and &lt;em&gt;then&lt;/em&gt; inspect any discrepancies. Maybe that’s just me. Regardless, these are things to consider. For what it’s worth, I imagine it would save a ton of time to do this sort of import workflow. Especially when it comes to reconciling your accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One important thing to consider - some transactions might involve from more than two accounts. For example, some of your paycheck goes to taxes, some to your 401k, some to your bank account, etc. Instead of creating separate transactions for each of these, we can create a single &lt;a href=&quot;https://cvs.gnucash.org/docs/C/gnucash-guide/txns-registers-txntypes.html&quot;&gt;split transaction&lt;/a&gt; that groups all of them together. Don’t forget that the golden rule of GnuCash still applies here - even split transactions need to be fully balanced. We’re just balancing them across multiple accounts. So, for example, if your employer pays you $1000 and $300 goes to taxes, exactly $700 must go to your bank account, or be further divided among other accounts (so long as their values sum to exactly $700).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of paychecks (or rent, or other things that happen periodically), you can save time by using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnucash.org/docs/v3/C/gnucash-help/trans-sched.html&quot;&gt;scheduled transactions&lt;/a&gt;. This feature just automatically creates templated transactions at set dates, and is really handy for anything that happens on a schedule.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok. Now that we’re done entering all of our data, it’s time to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnucash.org/docs/v3/C/gnucash-help/acct-reconcile.html&quot;&gt;reconcile&lt;/a&gt; our accounts - basically just making sure that there’s a 1:1 mapping of transactions in our GnuCash file to transactions in our real-world accounts. You don’t have to do this for every account, or even at all if you don’t want to. A delta of a few bucks between your real-world and GnuCash accounts probably isn’t a big deal. However, if you’re off by a little bit &lt;em&gt;every time&lt;/em&gt; you log, that couple bucks difference can quickly grow into much, much more. And trying to find a mistake in your accounting over a &amp;gt;1 month period is a pain in the ass. Trust me. If you’re going to do it at all, it’s a whole lot easier to reconcile incrementally instead of all at once.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To reconcile an account, start by opening up both the reconciliation window (Actions-&amp;gt;Reconcile) and whatever corresponding documentation you have for the real-world account. In this case, let’s pretend we’re looking at an online credit card statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.csun.io/images/gnucash/reconcile_1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;img-small&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is what it looks like when you open the reconciliation window. In the “Ending Balance” field, you should put the most recent balance displayed on your credit card statement. Then, go through each transaction on the statement and find the corresponding transaction in the reconciliation list. Click the checkbox next to that transaction. As you check each transaction, you’ll see the “Difference” field in the bottom right of the window change value. Your goal is to get this field to zero out, indicating that there’s no difference between virtual and real-world accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.csun.io/images/gnucash/reconcile_2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;img-medium&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you get to the end and see a non-zero difference, you should have either a) encountered a transaction that was present in your real account but not your virtual one, or b) vice versa. In the case of a), make sure that you recognize the charge, then add a matching virtual transaction. I often find that case b) only happens when a transaction has not been processed by my bank yet. In the picture above, notice how our virtual account exceeds our real one by $25. I would bet that the $25 charge for “food” just hasn’t posted to the credit card statement yet. In that case, just uncheck it. It will show up next time you enter the reconciliation dialog, whereas the other, fully reconciled charges will not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you own stocks or assets in different currencies, GnuCash has tools to help you out, but your accounting will become a little harder. I don’t personally mess with any of this functionality, so I can’t help you out unfortunately. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnucash.org/docs.phtml&quot;&gt;GnuCash docs&lt;/a&gt; are pretty decent though, if a bit dense and scary looking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For my stocks and non-money assets, I opt not to track them super closely in order to avoid having to update the values of each stock every time. So, I have one “Assets:Brokerage:Stocks” account that tracks the rough value of all of my holdings in USD. Whenever I log transactions, I go in and adjust that real money value of my entire portfolio with a single transaction from an “Income:Stock Value” or “Income:Interest and Dividends” account. This has served me well enough, but your mileage may vary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s it! You now have an up-to-date, categorized record of all of your financial transactions. Take this time to reflect on your spending, make an informed budget, look at nice graphs, etc. Or don’t! &lt;em&gt;You&lt;/em&gt; own the data, so you can be sure it’s not going anywhere, just don’t forget to back up all of your files (I keep it under version control).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope this helped!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 17:20:41 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>igpay</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.csun.io/2020/05/17/gnucash-finance.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Notion for everyone</title>
<link>https://www.notion.so/personal</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.notion.so/personal</guid>
<description>&lt;style&gt;&lt;![CDATA[body{background:#fff}body.dark{background:#2f3437}.initial-loading-spinner{-webkit-animation:rotate 1s linear infinite;animation:rotate 1s linear infinite;-webkit-transform-origin:center center;transform-origin:center center;width:1em;height:1em;opacity:.5;display:block;pointer-events:none}@-webkit-keyframes rotate{0%{-webkit-transform:rotate(0) translateZ(0);transform:rotate(0) translateZ(0)}100%{-webkit-transform:rotate(360deg) translateZ(0);transform:rotate(360deg) translateZ(0)}}@keyframes rotate{0%{-webkit-transform:rotate(0) translateZ(0);transform:rotate(0) translateZ(0)}100%{-webkit-transform:rotate(360deg) translateZ(0);transform:rotate(360deg) translateZ(0)}}]]&gt;&lt;/style&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 16:29:38 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>FireBeyond</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.notion.so</og:url>
<og:title>Notion – The all-in-one workspace for your notes, tasks, wikis, and databases.</og:title>
<og:description>A new tool that blends your everyday work apps into one. It's the all-in-one workspace for you and your team</og:description>
<og:image>https://www.notion.so/images/meta/default.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.notion.so/personal</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Florida scientist fired for refusing to manipulate Covid-19 data</title>
<link>https://www.floridatoday.com/story/news/2020/05/19/florida-scientist-refused-manipulate-covid-19-data-and-fired/5219137002/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.floridatoday.com/story/news/2020/05/19/florida-scientist-refused-manipulate-covid-19-data-and-fired/5219137002/</guid>
<description>&lt;div id=&quot;module-position-SuEY-q1d1V4&quot; class=&quot;story-asset video-asset&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui-video-wrapper&quot; itemprop=&quot;video&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/VideoObject&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;story-video js-video-avp automatedvideoplayerhidden automatedvideoplayer ui-teal-video js-teal-player js-ui-video-init&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;js-ptb pluto-title-bar&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;js-ptb-close pluto-title-bar-vcenter pluto-title-bar-close&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;CLOSE&lt;img class=&quot;pluto-title-bar-close-icon&quot; src=&quot;https://www.gannett-cdn.com/uxstatic/floridatoday/uscp-web-static-4525.40.0/images/sprites/icon_close.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div id=&quot;module-position-SuEY-q0dAkk&quot; class=&quot;story-asset image-asset&quot; readability=&quot;31&quot;&gt;
&lt;aside itemprop=&quot;associatedMedia&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/ImageObject&quot; class=&quot;wide single-photo&quot; readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;img itemprop=&quot;url&quot; src=&quot;https://www.gannett-cdn.com/presto/2020/05/18/PBRE/e9d0bf83-e6c9-4a85-9fd0-c775168ef33f-Jones_dashboard-768x432.jpg?width=540&amp;amp;height=&amp;amp;fit=bounds&amp;amp;auto=webp&quot; alt=&quot;Rebekah Jones is the architect of Florida's COVID-19 dashboard&quot; width=&quot;540&quot; data-mycapture-src=&quot;https://www.gannett-cdn.com/presto/2020/05/18/PBRE/e9d0bf83-e6c9-4a85-9fd0-c775168ef33f-Jones_dashboard-768x432.jpg&quot; data-mycapture-sm-src=&quot;https://www.gannett-cdn.com/presto/2020/05/18/PBRE/e9d0bf83-e6c9-4a85-9fd0-c775168ef33f-Jones_dashboard-768x432.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rebekah Jones is the architect of Florida's COVID-19 dashboard &lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;(Photo: provided)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;speakable-p-1 p-text&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;exclude-from-newsgate&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EDITORS NOTE:&lt;/strong&gt; We chose to make this story free because of the importance of its content. But quality, fact-checked journalism isn’t free. Reporting and fact-checking news is a costly and time-consuming endeavor and perhaps has never mattered more than it does now. Please show your support for quality reporting like this by subscribing to FLORIDA TODAY. Subscribe &lt;a data-track-label=&quot;inline|intext|n/a&quot; href=&quot;https://cm.floridatoday.com/specialoffer/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;speakable-p-2 p-text&quot;&gt;The scientist who created Florida's COVID-19 data portal wasn't just removed from her position on May 5, she was fired on Monday by the Department of Health, she said, for refusing to manipulate data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;Rebekah Jones said in an email to FLORIDA TODAY that she single-handedly created two applications in two languages, four dashboards, six unique maps with layers of data functionality for 32 variables covering a half a million lines of data. Her objective was to create a way for Floridians and researchers to see what the COVID-19 situation was in real time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;Then, she was dismissed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;exclude-from-newsgate&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Previously:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a data-track-label=&quot;inline|intext|n/a&quot; href=&quot;https://www.floridatoday.com/story/news/2020/05/18/censorship-covid-19-data-researcher-removed-florida-moves-re-open-state/5212398002/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;As Florida re-opens, COVID-19 data chief gets sidelined and researchers cry foul&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;&quot;I worked on it alone, sixteen hours a day for two months, most of which I was never paid for, and now that this has happened I'll probably never get paid for,&quot; she wrote in an email, confirming that she had not just been reassigned on May 5, but fired from her job as Geographic Information Systems manager for the Florida Department of Health.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;After FLORIDA TODAY first reported Jones' removal from her position in charge of the &lt;a data-track-label=&quot;inline|intext|n/a&quot; href=&quot;https://experience.arcgis.com/experience/96dd742462124fa0b38ddedb9b25e429&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Florida COVID-19 Data and Surveillance Dashboard&lt;/a&gt; she created, she confirmed, as reported by CBS-12 in West Palm Beach&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;that she was fired because she was ordered to censor some data, but refused to &quot;manually change data to drum up support for the plan to reopen.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;She provided no further details. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;&lt;a data-track-label=&quot;inline|intext|n/a&quot; href=&quot;https://www.floridatoday.com/story/news/2020/05/18/censorship-covid-19-data-researcher-removed-florida-moves-re-open-state/5212398002/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;In an email last Friday to researchers and other data users&lt;/a&gt;, Jones warned that with her removal changes were likely coming to the accessibility and transparency of the dashboard data. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;&quot;They are making a lot of changes. I would advise being diligent in your respective uses of this data,&quot; she wrote.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;Researchers who saw the email reacted with shock and dismay, suggesting it could be&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;evidence that the Gov. Ron De Santis' government was censoring information tosupport the case for re-opening Florida.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;Lucky Tran a Biologist and public health communicator at Columbia University on Twitter reacted to the news in a series of tweets.  &quot;When politicians censor scientists and manipulate the numbers, the rest of us suffer,&quot; he wrote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;US Congresswoman representing Tampa Bay, Kathy Castor wrote: &quot;Floridians will not feel safe in opening up without transparency.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;Governor Ron DeSantis' spokeswoman, Helen Aguirre Ferré,  issued a statement to the Miami Herald, saying: “The Florida COVID-19 Dashboard was created by the Geographic Information System (GIS) team in the Division of Disease Control and Health Protection at the Florida Department of Health. Although Rebekah Jones is no longer involved, the GIS team continues to manage and update the Dashboard providing accurate and important information that is publicly accessible.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;But emails from Jones through April showed that Jones was the one responding to feedback from researchers in a bid to improve and update her product. Jones told FLORIDA TODAY that she alone was responsible for &quot;every line of code.&quot; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;In a May 5 email in which she announced the launch of a Spanish-language version of the dashboard, Jones wrote: &quot;Please be patient as we get all this connected and running smoothly, and do let me know if you see any errors.&quot; It was sent the same day she was removed from her role managing of the dashboard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;For 60-days Jones said she never took a day off, not even when a powerful April 12 Easter tornado leveled her parents' home in Southeast Mississippi. &lt;a data-track-label=&quot;inline|intext|n/a&quot; href=&quot;https://www.gofundme.com/f/1z7ryznn6o?utm_source=customer&amp;amp;utm_medium=copy_link-tip&amp;amp;utm_campaign=p_cp+share-sheet&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;A GoFundMe page was set up to help her family recover&lt;/a&gt;. Luckily, her mother survived. Her father, a truck driver, was in Texas at the time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;&quot;Sorry if I’ve been a little slow to respond these last few days,&quot; she wrote to data users in an email just 3 days later reporting updates to how data was organized, and the inclusion of county-level race data. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;Jones provided detailed updates in emails every few days, often technical and always responsive to user feedback. At the time was dismissed, she was working on making historical data more accessible to users. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;On April 25, Jones provided an explanation to why the data set would go from morning and evening daily updates to just once per day. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;&quot;We’re gearing up to provide more analytics and data, and would not be able to process the full dataset twice daily with the staff we have,&quot; she wrote. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;&quot;We have been directed to start tracking data related to reopening, and it is consuming a lot of staff hours on very short notice.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;Days later she would be removed from the position entirely and her data users sounded the alarm that government might be censoring science. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;Jones had worked with the Department of Health as a geospatial analyst and then a Geographic Information System (GIS) manager since obtaining her doctorate in Geography from Florida State University in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;She holds a masters of science degree in geography and mass communication from Louisiana State University and a bachelors in Journalism and Geography from Syracuse University. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;The Department of Health has so far not replied to request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;Terrie Rizzo, chair of the Florida Democratic Party, released a statement on Tuesday calling for an investigation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;“Allegations that Florida’s government may have tried to manipulate or alter data to make reopening appear safer is outrageous. These kinds of actions are dangerous and, frankly, should be criminal,&quot; she wrote.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text&quot;&gt;&quot;An independent investigation into these allegations is needed immediately. Meanwhile, city and state officials across Florida should closely monitor the situation to protect the public’s health.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-text p-text-last&quot; id=&quot;article-body-p-last&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alessandro Marazzi Sassoon is a watchdog reporter for FLORIDA TODAY. Contact him at 321-355-8144, or asassoon@floridatoday.com. Twitter: @alemzs&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read or Share this story: https://www.floridatoday.com/story/news/2020/05/19/florida-scientist-refused-manipulate-covid-19-data-and-fired/5219137002/&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 16:18:37 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>tmountain</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://www.gannett-cdn.com/presto/2020/05/19/PPEN/8fa3e150-c90b-437e-be0d-e4740c60764e-Floridacovid.PNG?crop=1569,883,x0,y0&amp;width=1600&amp;height=800&amp;fit=bounds</og:image>
<og:title>Florida scientist was fired for 'refusing to manipulate' COVID-19 data, she said</og:title>
<og:description>Rebekah Jones worked for 60 days nonstop to provide Floridians with good COVID-19 data, then she was fired</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.floridatoday.com/story/news/2020/05/19/florida-scientist-refused-manipulate-covid-19-data-and-fired/5219137002/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.floridatoday.com/story/news/2020/05/19/florida-scientist-refused-manipulate-covid-19-data-and-fired/5219137002/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Graduate Student Solves Decades-Old Conway Knot Problem</title>
<link>https://www.quantamagazine.org/graduate-student-solves-decades-old-conway-knot-problem-20200519/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.quantamagazine.org/graduate-student-solves-decades-old-conway-knot-problem-20200519/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;But our world is four-dimensional if we include time as a dimension, so it is natural to ask if there is a corresponding theory of knots in 4D space. This isn’t just a matter of taking all the knots we have in 3D space and plunking them down in 4D space: With four dimensions to move around in, any knotted loop can be unraveled if strands are moved over each other in the fourth dimension.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make a knotted object in four-dimensional space, you need a two-dimensional sphere, not a one-dimensional loop. Just as three dimensions provide enough room to build knotted loops but not enough room for them to unravel, four dimensions provide such an environment for knotted spheres, which mathematicians first constructed in the 1920s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s hard to visualize a knotted sphere in 4D space, but it helps to first think about an ordinary sphere in 3D space. If you slice through it, you’ll see an unknotted loop. But when you slice through a knotted sphere in 4D space, you might see a knotted loop instead (or possibly an unknotted loop or a link of several loops, depending on where you slice). Any knot you can make by slicing a knotted sphere is said to be “slice.” Some knots are not slice — for instance, the three-crossing knot known as the trefoil.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slice knots “provide a bridge between the three-dimensional and four-dimensional stories of knot theory,” Greene said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there’s a wrinkle that lends richness and peculiarity to the four-dimensional story: In 4D topology, there are two different versions of what it means to be slice. In a series of revolutionary developments in the early 1980s (which earned both &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/research/people/michaelf/&quot;&gt;Michael Freedman&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://wwwf.imperial.ac.uk/~skdona/&quot;&gt;Simon Donaldson&lt;/a&gt; Fields Medals), mathematicians discovered that 4D space doesn’t just contain the smooth spheres we intuitively visualize — it also contains spheres so pervasively crumpled that they could never be ironed smooth. The question of which knots are slice depends on whether you choose to include these crumpled spheres.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“These are very, very strange objects, that sort of exist by magic,” said &lt;a href=&quot;https://math.rice.edu/~shelly/&quot;&gt;Shelly Harvey&lt;/a&gt; of Rice University. (It was at Harvey’s talk in 2018 that Piccirillo first learned about the Conway knot problem.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These strange spheres are not a bug of four-dimensional topology, but a feature. Knots that are “topologically slice” but not “smoothly slice” — meaning they are a slice of some crumpled sphere, but no smooth one — allow mathematicians to build so-called “exotic” versions of ordinary four-dimensional space. These copies of four-dimensional space look the same as normal space from a topological viewpoint but are irretrievably crumpled. The existence of these exotic spaces sets dimension four apart from all other dimensions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The question of sliceness is “the lowest-dimensional probe” of these exotic four-dimensional spaces, Greene said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the years, mathematicians discovered an assortment of knots that were topologically but not smoothly slice. Among knots with 12 or fewer crossings, however, there didn’t seem to be any — except possibly the Conway knot. Mathematicians could figure out the slice status of all other knots with 12 or fewer crossings, but the Conway knot eluded them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conway, who &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.quantamagazine.org/john-conway-solved-mathematical-problems-with-his-bare-hands-20200420/&quot;&gt;died of COVID-19 last month&lt;/a&gt;, was famous for making influential contributions to one area of mathematics after another. He first became interested in knots as a teenager in the 1950s and came up with a simple way to list essentially all the knots up to 11 crossings (previous complete lists had gone up to only 10 crossings).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the list was one knot that stood out. “Conway, I think, realized that there was something quite special about it,” Greene said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Conway knot, as it came to be known, is topologically slice — mathematicians realized this amid the revolutionary discoveries of the 1980s. But they couldn’t figure out whether it was smoothly slice. They suspected that it was not, because it seemed to lack a feature called “ribbonness” that smoothly slice knots typically have. But it also had a feature that made it immune to every attempt to show it was not smoothly slice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Namely, the Conway knot has a sort of sibling — what’s known as a mutant. If you draw the Conway knot on paper, cut out a certain portion of the paper, flip the fragment over and then rejoin its loose ends, you get another knot known as the &lt;a href=&quot;https://projecteuclid.org/euclid.ojm/1200689158&quot;&gt;Kinoshita-Terasaka knot&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 16:17:53 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>theafh</dc:creator>
<og:title>Graduate Student Solves Decades-Old Conway Knot Problem</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.quantamagazine.org/graduate-student-solves-decades-old-conway-knot-problem-20200519/</og:url>
<og:image>https://d2r55xnwy6nx47.cloudfront.net/uploads/2020/05/Lisa-Piccirillo_1200_social.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.quantamagazine.org/graduate-student-solves-decades-old-conway-knot-problem-20200519/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Microsoft announces Lists, a new Airtable-like app</title>
<link>https://techcommunity.microsoft.com/t5/microsoft-365-blog/announcing-microsoft-lists-your-smart-information-tracking-app/ba-p/1372233</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcommunity.microsoft.com/t5/microsoft-365-blog/announcing-microsoft-lists-your-smart-information-tracking-app/ba-p/1372233</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Build 2020 brought a lot of &lt;a href=&quot;https://aka.ms/MSLists/blog/M365BuildNews&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Microsoft 365 news and announcements&lt;/a&gt; for businesses and developers – including the first disclosure of &lt;strong&gt;Microsoft Lists&lt;/strong&gt;. We are pleased to share our vision for Lists – to highlight how you use it to track issues, manage inventory, build out event agendas, report status, manage FAQs, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Microsoft Lists is a Microsoft 365 app that helps you track information and organize your work. Lists are simple, smart, and flexible, so you can stay on top of what matters most to your team. Track issues, assets, routines, contacts, inventory and more using customizable views and smart rules and alerts to keep everyone in sync. With ready-made templates, you can quickly start lists online, on our new mobile app, and directly from within Microsoft Teams. And because it is part of Microsoft 365, you can rely on enterprise-grade security and compliance.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Summary of what was shared today at Build (more details below):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Microsoft Lists home (web) and mobile app&lt;/strong&gt; – Create new lists, share and access recent and favorite lists in one location&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Microsoft Teams&lt;/strong&gt; ♥ &lt;strong&gt;Microsoft Lists&lt;/strong&gt; – Create a new list or embed an existing list directly in a Teams channel - combining lists with side-by-side conversation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ready-made templates help you get started quickly&lt;/strong&gt; – Jumpstart common scenarios with preconfigured structure, forms, views, and formatting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Customizable views, smart rules, and sharing keep everyone in sync&lt;/strong&gt; – Visualize your information, build if/then rules, and share with confidence&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline&quot; image-alt=&quot;MSLists_M365_001_Create-a-list-collage.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://gxcuf89792.i.lithium.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/192994iFA469EC57A66D7F4/image-size/large?v=1.0&amp;amp;px=999&quot; title=&quot;MSLists_M365_001_Create-a-list-collage.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Create a list from the Lists home page in Microsoft 365 (top left) or from within Microsoft Teams (bottom left). Use the list across team members in SharePoint (top right) or continue in Microsoft Teams (bottom right).&quot; li-image-url=&quot;https://gxcuf89792.i.lithium.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/192994iFA469EC57A66D7F4?v=1.0&quot; li-image-display-id=&quot;'192994iFA469EC57A66D7F4'&quot; li-message-uid=&quot;'1372233'&quot; li-messages-message-image=&quot;true&quot; li-bindable=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;lia-media-image&quot; tabindex=&quot;0&quot; li-bypass-lightbox-when-linked=&quot;true&quot; li-use-hover-links=&quot;false&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lia-inline-image-caption&quot; onclick=&quot;event.preventDefault();&quot;&gt;Create a list from the Lists home page in Microsoft 365 (top left) or from within Microsoft Teams (bottom left). Use the list across team members in SharePoint (top right) or continue in Microsoft Teams (bottom right).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing something down is one thing. Tracking it and thousands of other related items – across geographies, keeping in sync with team members as status and details fluctuate – well, that’s Lists; an app to track your information and get to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;lia-indent-padding-left-30px&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lia-deferred-image lia-image-emoji&quot; src=&quot;https://gxcuf89792.i.lithium.com/html/images/emoticons/cool_40x40.gif&quot; alt=&quot;:cool:&quot; title=&quot;:cool:&quot;/&gt; Take a moment to &lt;strong&gt;see Lists in action&lt;/strong&gt;... &lt;br/&gt;Watch &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcommunity.microsoft.com/t5/user/viewprofilepage/user-id/32817&quot;&gt;@Miceile Barrett&lt;/a&gt; (Lists program manager) share a &lt;a href=&quot;https://aka.ms/MSLists/demo-video&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;First look at Microsoft Lists&lt;/a&gt; (demo video). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And now, let’s dive into the details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Microsoft Lists home (web) and mobile app&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It all starts with Lists Home, a single place to see and manage all your lists. To get there, click the &lt;strong&gt;Lists&lt;/strong&gt; icon within the Microsoft 365 app launcher (aka, the “waffle”). Here, you can start a list in several ways - easily from scratch or with ready-made templates. In addition, you can create new lists from existing lists or by importing Excel table data to jumpstart. Beyond creation, you will see all your favorited and recent lists – ones you own or that have been shared with you. You will be able to create both personal lists you own and can share, and team lists owned by members of your teams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lists home brings all your lists at your fingertips, on the web and on the go via the Lists mobile app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline&quot; image-alt=&quot;MSLists_M365_002_Lists-home-mobile.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://gxcuf89792.i.lithium.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/192315iBBB85457F7E89EDF/image-size/large?v=1.0&amp;amp;px=999&quot; title=&quot;MSLists_M365_002_Lists-home-mobile.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Left-to-right: Microsoft Lists home page in Microsoft 365 and the mobile app - both access to all your lists in one place.&quot; li-image-url=&quot;https://gxcuf89792.i.lithium.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/192315iBBB85457F7E89EDF?v=1.0&quot; li-image-display-id=&quot;'192315iBBB85457F7E89EDF'&quot; li-message-uid=&quot;'1372233'&quot; li-messages-message-image=&quot;true&quot; li-bindable=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;lia-media-image&quot; tabindex=&quot;0&quot; li-bypass-lightbox-when-linked=&quot;true&quot; li-use-hover-links=&quot;false&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lia-inline-image-caption&quot; onclick=&quot;event.preventDefault();&quot;&gt;Left-to-right: Microsoft Lists home page in Microsoft 365 and the mobile app - both access to all your lists in one place.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Never miss out on a list that is important to you, just favorite it and you will always be able to access it from the &quot;Favorites&quot; section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline&quot; image-alt=&quot;MSLists_M365_003_Lists-mobile-animated.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://gxcuf89792.i.lithium.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/192316iCDBA1CE58E2CFFF8/image-size/large?v=1.0&amp;amp;px=999&quot; title=&quot;MSLists_M365_003_Lists-mobile-animated.gif&quot; alt=&quot;MSLists_M365_003_Lists-mobile-animated.gif&quot; li-image-url=&quot;https://gxcuf89792.i.lithium.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/192316iCDBA1CE58E2CFFF8?v=1.0&quot; li-image-display-id=&quot;'192316iCDBA1CE58E2CFFF8'&quot; li-message-uid=&quot;'1372233'&quot; li-messages-message-image=&quot;true&quot; li-bindable=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;lia-media-image&quot; tabindex=&quot;0&quot; li-bypass-lightbox-when-linked=&quot;true&quot; li-use-hover-links=&quot;false&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can expect to see Lists home later this summer on the web and the Lists mobile app later this year. Both provide access to all your lists in one place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See more about getting started with Microsoft Lists in this new &lt;a href=&quot;https://demobuilderwebcpptxz.blob.core.windows.net/microsoft-lists-create-a-list/startdemo.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;“Create a list” click-thru demo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;lia-indent-padding-left-30px&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Roadmap IDs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; | Lists home (ID # &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.microsoft.com/microsoft-365/roadmap?filters=&amp;amp;searchterms=64160&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;64160&lt;/a&gt;) and Lists mobile app (ID # &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.microsoft.com/microsoft-365/roadmap?filters=&amp;amp;searchterms=64161&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;64161&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Microsoft Teams ♥ Microsoft Lists&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft Lists is for people who get things done - together. Use Microsoft Teams to collaborate on lists, using flexible views like grids, cards, and calendar. This brings content and conversation side-by-side in one integrated experience. You can either add an existing list to a Teams channel or create a new list directly in Teams and chat on individual list items.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline&quot; image-alt=&quot;MSLists_M365_004_Lists-plus-Teams_pt1-event-itinerary.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://gxcuf89792.i.lithium.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/192317i58BCA8AC166C5722/image-size/large?v=1.0&amp;amp;px=999&quot; title=&quot;MSLists_M365_004_Lists-plus-Teams_pt1-event-itinerary.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Create, share, and track list all from within Microsoft Teams.&quot; li-image-url=&quot;https://gxcuf89792.i.lithium.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/192317i58BCA8AC166C5722?v=1.0&quot; li-image-display-id=&quot;'192317i58BCA8AC166C5722'&quot; li-message-uid=&quot;'1372233'&quot; li-messages-message-image=&quot;true&quot; li-bindable=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;lia-media-image&quot; tabindex=&quot;0&quot; li-bypass-lightbox-when-linked=&quot;true&quot; li-use-hover-links=&quot;false&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lia-inline-image-caption&quot; onclick=&quot;event.preventDefault();&quot;&gt;Create, share, and track list all from within Microsoft Teams.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you click “+” to add a new tab to a Teams channel, select the Lists app to begin. The Lists app is used to both create new and embed existing lists – all within Teams. Further refine your list by adding new columns, defining choices in a drop-down menu, create view or edit share links, create custom views and filters and set up rules – all to ensure the list works for you and your team. No compromises. You get the full power to configure what your list looks like and how it works for you – all from inside Teams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline&quot; image-alt=&quot;MSLists_M365_005_Lists-plus-Teams_pt2-create-in-Teams.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://gxcuf89792.i.lithium.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/192318i48972C7176732F6B/image-size/large?v=1.0&amp;amp;px=999&quot; title=&quot;MSLists_M365_005_Lists-plus-Teams_pt2-create-in-Teams.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Create a new list directly inside Teams or bring in one that already exists in Microsoft 365.&quot; li-image-url=&quot;https://gxcuf89792.i.lithium.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/192318i48972C7176732F6B?v=1.0&quot; li-image-display-id=&quot;'192318i48972C7176732F6B'&quot; li-message-uid=&quot;'1372233'&quot; li-messages-message-image=&quot;true&quot; li-bindable=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;lia-media-image&quot; tabindex=&quot;0&quot; li-bypass-lightbox-when-linked=&quot;true&quot; li-use-hover-links=&quot;false&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lia-inline-image-caption&quot; onclick=&quot;event.preventDefault();&quot;&gt;Create a new list directly inside Teams or bring in one that already exists in Microsoft 365.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline&quot; image-alt=&quot;MSLists_M365_006_Lists-plus-Teams_pt3-list-item-plus-chat.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://gxcuf89792.i.lithium.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/192319iDA28EEBA5526FDBE/image-size/large?v=1.0&amp;amp;px=999&quot; title=&quot;MSLists_M365_006_Lists-plus-Teams_pt3-list-item-plus-chat.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Viewing an individual list item inside of Microsoft Teams alongside chat.&quot; li-image-url=&quot;https://gxcuf89792.i.lithium.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/192319iDA28EEBA5526FDBE?v=1.0&quot; li-image-display-id=&quot;'192319iDA28EEBA5526FDBE'&quot; li-message-uid=&quot;'1372233'&quot; li-messages-message-image=&quot;true&quot; li-bindable=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;lia-media-image&quot; tabindex=&quot;0&quot; li-bypass-lightbox-when-linked=&quot;true&quot; li-use-hover-links=&quot;false&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lia-inline-image-caption&quot; onclick=&quot;event.preventDefault();&quot;&gt;Viewing an individual list item inside of Microsoft Teams alongside chat.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;lia-indent-padding-left-30px&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;Roadmap ID&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; | Lists app in Microsoft Teams (ID # &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.microsoft.com/microsoft-365/roadmap?filters=&amp;amp;searchterms=64162&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;64162&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Ready-made templates help you get started quickly&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've designed templates tailored to specific use cases like tracking issues, onboarding new hires, handling an event's itinerary, managing assets, and many more. These templates come with a base structure, formatting, forms, conditional formatting, and everything you will need to get a quick start on the work that matters to you. Find inspiration in them or modify them to bring your vision to life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline&quot; image-alt=&quot;MSLists_M365_007_Templates.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://gxcuf89792.i.lithium.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/192320i2FECA0CD5BC2E915/image-size/large?v=1.0&amp;amp;px=999&quot; title=&quot;MSLists_M365_007_Templates.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Get started quickly with ready-to-use list templates – above shows the “Event itinerary” template.&quot; li-image-url=&quot;https://gxcuf89792.i.lithium.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/192320i2FECA0CD5BC2E915?v=1.0&quot; li-image-display-id=&quot;'192320i2FECA0CD5BC2E915'&quot; li-message-uid=&quot;'1372233'&quot; li-messages-message-image=&quot;true&quot; li-bindable=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;lia-media-image&quot; tabindex=&quot;0&quot; li-bypass-lightbox-when-linked=&quot;true&quot; li-use-hover-links=&quot;false&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lia-inline-image-caption&quot; onclick=&quot;event.preventDefault();&quot;&gt;Get started quickly with ready-to-use list templates – above shows the “Event itinerary” template.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the ready-made templates, there are two other time-saving ways to create lists. You can &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.office.com/article/0D397414-D95F-41EB-ADDD-5E6EFF41B083&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;create a list from an existing list&lt;/a&gt; – inheriting structure and formatting. And you can &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.office.com/en-us/article/Create-a-list-based-on-a-spreadsheet-380CFEB5-6E14-438E-988A-C2B9BEA574FA&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;create a list from Microsoft Excel&lt;/a&gt; – importing the Excel table data while choosing how to best represent the information. Once started, you have all the new formatting, views, rules and more to best represent your information and get back to business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;lia-indent-padding-left-30px&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Roadmap ID&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; | Ready-made templates (ID # &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.microsoft.com/microsoft-365/roadmap?filters=&amp;amp;searchterms=64166&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;64166&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Customizable views, smart rules and sharing keep everyone in sync&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Customize your lists for whatever your business needs. Lists not only help track information; they help make your information &lt;em&gt;speak&lt;/em&gt; for you, clearly and visually. You’ll keep everyone in sync – especially when things change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Default views&lt;/strong&gt; | There are four main views when configuring lists: list, grid, gallery, and calendar. Grid (pictured above in Teams) is the main style you see when you first create a list – primarily rows and columns that can be configured and reordered.  Grid is best when you want list information to be easily edited.  List is similar to grid, but without point and click editing capabilities – it's the view that existing SharePoint list users will be most familiar with.  Gallery is a great way to highlight lists that include images; cards are configurable and display a row of information. And when your information includes dates, the best way to visualize all items is to use calendar view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can adjust how information appears in these views by using conditional formatting. For example, you can change the background fill color of an item from orange when status is “In review” to green when status equals “Approved.” Background, font color and icons dynamically change when certain criteria are met.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline&quot; image-alt=&quot;MSLists_M365_008_Views_Gallery.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://gxcuf89792.i.lithium.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/192321iBBD0A0F5FBAEED3B/image-size/large?v=1.0&amp;amp;px=999&quot; title=&quot;MSLists_M365_008_Views_Gallery.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A list in gallery view – visual and configurable.&quot; li-image-url=&quot;https://gxcuf89792.i.lithium.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/192321iBBD0A0F5FBAEED3B?v=1.0&quot; li-image-display-id=&quot;'192321iBBD0A0F5FBAEED3B'&quot; li-message-uid=&quot;'1372233'&quot; li-messages-message-image=&quot;true&quot; li-bindable=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;lia-media-image&quot; tabindex=&quot;0&quot; li-bypass-lightbox-when-linked=&quot;true&quot; li-use-hover-links=&quot;false&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lia-inline-image-caption&quot; onclick=&quot;event.preventDefault();&quot;&gt;A list in gallery view – visual and configurable.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline&quot; image-alt=&quot;MSLists_M365_009_Views_Calendar.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://gxcuf89792.i.lithium.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/192322i3B8DD5BB49EBCE7F/image-size/large?v=1.0&amp;amp;px=999&quot; title=&quot;MSLists_M365_009_Views_Calendar.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A list in calendar view – showcasing any item with a date associated to it.&quot; li-image-url=&quot;https://gxcuf89792.i.lithium.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/192322i3B8DD5BB49EBCE7F?v=1.0&quot; li-image-display-id=&quot;'192322i3B8DD5BB49EBCE7F'&quot; li-message-uid=&quot;'1372233'&quot; li-messages-message-image=&quot;true&quot; li-bindable=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;lia-media-image&quot; tabindex=&quot;0&quot; li-bypass-lightbox-when-linked=&quot;true&quot; li-use-hover-links=&quot;false&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lia-inline-image-caption&quot; onclick=&quot;event.preventDefault();&quot;&gt;A list in calendar view – showcasing any item with a date associated to it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can create custom views to organize and show items that are most important to you (like certain columns), to add filtering or sorting, or to have a more engaging style. You can create personal views that only you can see and public views for everyone who uses the list to see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rules&lt;/strong&gt; | Building rules is as easy as writing a sentence. Once you decide on the outcome, click-fill if/then steps to design your rules. Choose people, status, and value changes to send notifications or programmatically update values elsewhere in the list. Finally, use rules to set reminders to keep everyone informed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline&quot; image-alt=&quot;MSLists_M365_010_Rules.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://gxcuf89792.i.lithium.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/192323i15A0D05366E1714A/image-size/large?v=1.0&amp;amp;px=999&quot; title=&quot;MSLists_M365_010_Rules.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Keep everyone in sync with smart alerts by creating rules.&quot; li-image-url=&quot;https://gxcuf89792.i.lithium.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/192323i15A0D05366E1714A?v=1.0&quot; li-image-display-id=&quot;'192323i15A0D05366E1714A'&quot; li-message-uid=&quot;'1372233'&quot; li-messages-message-image=&quot;true&quot; li-bindable=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;lia-media-image&quot; tabindex=&quot;0&quot; li-bypass-lightbox-when-linked=&quot;true&quot; li-use-hover-links=&quot;false&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lia-inline-image-caption&quot; onclick=&quot;event.preventDefault();&quot;&gt;Keep everyone in sync with smart alerts by creating rules.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sharing&lt;/strong&gt; | Whether a list is short or long, simple or complex, it’s important to work with others and do so in a way that is efficient and manageable. When you share a list, you can share the entire list with edit or read-only permissions. Or share individual items, where you allow or disable the ability to edit, set an expiration date, or require a password before granting access. And once shared, invitees can add comments on the full list or on individual list items.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline&quot; image-alt=&quot;MSLists_M365_011_Sharing.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://gxcuf89792.i.lithium.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/192324i365EDC1B1EB99953/image-size/large?v=1.0&amp;amp;px=999&quot; title=&quot;MSLists_M365_011_Sharing.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Share the full list or individual list items and use comments to share ideas and provide feedback.&quot; li-image-url=&quot;https://gxcuf89792.i.lithium.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/192324i365EDC1B1EB99953?v=1.0&quot; li-image-display-id=&quot;'192324i365EDC1B1EB99953'&quot; li-message-uid=&quot;'1372233'&quot; li-messages-message-image=&quot;true&quot; li-bindable=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;lia-media-image&quot; tabindex=&quot;0&quot; li-bypass-lightbox-when-linked=&quot;true&quot; li-use-hover-links=&quot;false&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lia-inline-image-caption&quot; onclick=&quot;event.preventDefault();&quot;&gt;Share the full list or individual list items and use comments to share ideas and provide feedback.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;lia-indent-padding-left-30px&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Roadmap IDs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; | Views (ID # &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.microsoft.com/microsoft-365/roadmap?filters=&amp;amp;searchterms=64167&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;64167&lt;/a&gt;), Rules (ID # &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.microsoft.com/microsoft-365/roadmap?filters=&amp;amp;searchterms=64163&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;64163&lt;/a&gt;), Sharing (ID # &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.microsoft.com/microsoft-365/roadmap?filters=&amp;amp;searchterms=64164&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;64164&lt;/a&gt;), and Comments (ID # &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.microsoft.com/microsoft-365/roadmap?filters=&amp;amp;searchterms=64169&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;64169&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Your lists just got a whole lot smarter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Millions of SharePoint users have benefitted from using lists over the years. Microsoft Lists builds on this trusted information platform – bringing new user experiences and capabilities to the foundational innovation of SharePoint lists. Rest assured that all your lists, including lists that you have inside SharePoint sites today, will benefit from all the innovations described here. Lists are lists are lists. Additionally, the value of existing integrations with the Power Platform continue when you need to further customize list forms with &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.microsoft.com/powerapps/maker/canvas-apps/customize-list-form&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Power Apps&lt;/a&gt; and design robust workflows with &lt;a href=&quot;https://preview.flow.microsoft.com/connectors/shared_sharepointonline/sharepoint/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Power Automate&lt;/a&gt;. And for developers, the power and value of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.microsoft.com/sharepoint/dev/sp-add-ins/working-with-lists-and-list-items-with-rest&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Lists API&lt;/a&gt; extends custom solutions to connect the list data as a source via &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.microsoft.com/graph/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Microsoft Graph&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We cannot wait to share more details and documentation when we begin roll out of Lists later this summer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Resources to learn more:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Track what matters most. Make a list and let it flow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seth Patton, General Manager, Microsoft 365&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lia-inline-image-display-wrapper lia-image-align-inline&quot; image-alt=&quot;MSLists_M365_012_Hero-on-devices.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://gxcuf89792.i.lithium.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/192325i276C6B09844F2F67/image-size/large?v=1.0&amp;amp;px=999&quot; title=&quot;MSLists_M365_012_Hero-on-devices.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Microsoft Lists - your smart information tracking app in Microsoft 365 (https://aka.ms/MSLists).&quot; li-image-url=&quot;https://gxcuf89792.i.lithium.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/192325i276C6B09844F2F67?v=1.0&quot; li-image-display-id=&quot;'192325i276C6B09844F2F67'&quot; li-message-uid=&quot;'1372233'&quot; li-messages-message-image=&quot;true&quot; li-bindable=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;lia-media-image&quot; tabindex=&quot;0&quot; li-bypass-lightbox-when-linked=&quot;true&quot; li-use-hover-links=&quot;false&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lia-inline-image-caption&quot; onclick=&quot;event.preventDefault();&quot;&gt;Microsoft Lists - your smart information tracking app in Microsoft 365 (https://aka.ms/MSLists).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 16:02:47 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>prostoalex</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://gxcuf89792.i.lithium.com/t5/image/serverpage/image-id/192994iFA469EC57A66D7F4?v=1.0</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>Build 2020 brought a lot of Microsoft 365 news and announcements for businesses and developers – including the first disclosure of Microsoft Lists. We are pleased to share our vision for Lists – to highlight how you use it to track issues, manage inventory, build out event agendas, report status, ma...</og:description>
<og:title>Announcing Microsoft Lists - Your smart information tracking app in Microsoft 365</og:title>
<og:url>https://techcommunity.microsoft.com/t5/microsoft-365-blog/announcing-microsoft-lists-your-smart-information-tracking-app/ba-p/1372233</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcommunity.microsoft.com/t5/microsoft-365-blog/announcing-microsoft-lists-your-smart-information-tracking-app/ba-p/1372233</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Windows Package Manager Preview</title>
<link>https://devblogs.microsoft.com/commandline/windows-package-manager-preview</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://devblogs.microsoft.com/commandline/windows-package-manager-preview</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;row justify-content-center&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col-md-4&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://devblogs.microsoft.com/commandline/wp-content/uploads/sites/33/2020/05/Demitrius-150x150.png&quot; width=&quot;58&quot; height=&quot;58&quot; alt=&quot;Demitrius Nelon&quot; class=&quot;avatar avatar-58 wp-user-avatar wp-user-avatar-58 alignnone photo&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Demitrius&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;entry-meta&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;May 19th, 2020&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are thrilled to announce the Windows Package Manager preview!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re already familiar with what a package manager is, feel free to skip this paragraph. If you’re still reading, you’re going to love this! A package manager is designed to help you save time and frustration. Essentially, it is a set of software tools that help you automate the process of getting software on your machine. You specify which apps you want installed, and it does the work of finding the latest version (or the exact one you specified) and installing it on your machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just about every developer has wanted a native package manager in Windows. That day is finally here. You are going to be able to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;winget install&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; your way to bliss. One of the best parts is that it is open source. I had to pinch myself when I was able to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;winget install terminal&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, and then &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;winget install powershell&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, and then &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;winget install powertoys&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. You get the idea, and If you do not see an app you use, just create a new manifest, and submit a pull request.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://devblogs.microsoft.com/commandline/wp-content/uploads/sites/33/2020/05/winget01.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://devblogs.microsoft.com/commandline/wp-content/uploads/sites/33/2020/05/winget01.png&quot; alt=&quot;Execute winget in Windows Terminal&quot; width=&quot;1216&quot; height=&quot;812&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-5609&quot; srcset=&quot;https://devblogs.microsoft.com/commandline/wp-content/uploads/sites/33/2020/05/winget01.png 1216w, https://devblogs.microsoft.com/commandline/wp-content/uploads/sites/33/2020/05/winget01-300x200.png 300w, https://devblogs.microsoft.com/commandline/wp-content/uploads/sites/33/2020/05/winget01-1024x684.png 1024w, https://devblogs.microsoft.com/commandline/wp-content/uploads/sites/33/2020/05/winget01-768x513.png 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1216px) 100vw, 1216px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;When can I try it?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of &lt;strong&gt;today&lt;/strong&gt;, the Windows Package Manager preview has been made open source. You can clone, build, run and test the code from the GitHub repository (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/microsoft/winget-cli&quot;&gt;https://github.com/microsoft/winget-cli&lt;/a&gt;). There are other &lt;em&gt;possibly&lt;/em&gt; easier ways to get your hands on it if that doesn’t sound appealing. Please continue reading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What functionality is included?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;install&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; any app with a valid manifest (even local ones &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;-- manifest&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;). The command line client “winget.exe” is already pre-configured to point to the Microsoft community repository. That means you can install any package with a manifest that has been published.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you ever had to completely re-install all your apps and tools on your PC? How long did it take? How did you remember where to go to find, download, and install all your editors &amp;amp; IDEs, languages &amp;amp; runtimes, source control tools, etc.?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Did you enjoy it&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;? Yeah, neither did we … which is why we created Windows Package Manager.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you can install all your favorite apps &amp;amp; tools simply by typing &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;winget install &amp;lt;foo&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; into your command-line. Or better still, you can create a script file that installs ALL your tools while you sit back enjoy a well-earned coffee break!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;search&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for available packages and display information using the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;show&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; command. There are also commands to help with manifest creation and validation (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;hash&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;validate&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;). Once the first third-party repository is published, you will be able to add that repository as a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;source&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; as well. We’re providing documentation at &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.microsoft.com/windows/package-manager&quot;&gt;https://docs.microsoft.com/windows/package-manager&lt;/a&gt; and both of the GitHub repositories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://devblogs.microsoft.com/commandline/wp-content/uploads/sites/33/2020/05/winget02.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://devblogs.microsoft.com/commandline/wp-content/uploads/sites/33/2020/05/winget02.png&quot; alt=&quot;Executing the winget install vscode command in Windows Terminal&quot; width=&quot;1208&quot; height=&quot;804&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-5610&quot; srcset=&quot;https://devblogs.microsoft.com/commandline/wp-content/uploads/sites/33/2020/05/winget02.png 1208w, https://devblogs.microsoft.com/commandline/wp-content/uploads/sites/33/2020/05/winget02-300x200.png 300w, https://devblogs.microsoft.com/commandline/wp-content/uploads/sites/33/2020/05/winget02-1024x682.png 1024w, https://devblogs.microsoft.com/commandline/wp-content/uploads/sites/33/2020/05/winget02-768x511.png 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1208px) 100vw, 1208px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;How do I get it?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have provided three different ways for you to get your hands on the Windows Package Manager. If you are a Windows Insider, you may already have it. First, you can head over to the open source GitHub repository for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.github.com/microsoft/winget-cli&quot;&gt;client&lt;/a&gt;. Second, you can join any of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://insider.windows.com/&quot;&gt;Windows Insider&lt;/a&gt; rings. Third, you can join the Windows Package Manager Insider program by providing your Microsoft Account (MSA) to &lt;a href=&quot;http://aka.ms/winget-InsiderProgram&quot;&gt;Windows Package Manager Insider Program&lt;/a&gt; and request to be included in the preview. Either of the Insider programs will ensure you automatically receive updates as we progress from preview to general availability. After you have joined either Insider program, head over to the Microsoft Store and get the &lt;a href=&quot;ms-windows-store:/pdp/?productid=9nblggh4nns1&quot;&gt;App Installer&lt;/a&gt;. The Windows Package manager will be available after you get the update.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://devblogs.microsoft.com/commandline/wp-content/uploads/sites/33/2020/05/winget03.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://devblogs.microsoft.com/commandline/wp-content/uploads/sites/33/2020/05/winget03.png&quot; alt=&quot;The App Installer in the Microsoft Store&quot; width=&quot;1248&quot; height=&quot;343&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-5611&quot; srcset=&quot;https://devblogs.microsoft.com/commandline/wp-content/uploads/sites/33/2020/05/winget03.png 1248w, https://devblogs.microsoft.com/commandline/wp-content/uploads/sites/33/2020/05/winget03-300x82.png 300w, https://devblogs.microsoft.com/commandline/wp-content/uploads/sites/33/2020/05/winget03-1024x281.png 1024w, https://devblogs.microsoft.com/commandline/wp-content/uploads/sites/33/2020/05/winget03-768x211.png 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1248px) 100vw, 1248px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Why not contribute to another open source package manager?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We looked at several other package managers. There were several reasons leading us to create a new solution. One critical concern we had was how to build a repository of trusted applications. We are automatically checking each manifest. We leverage SmartScreen, static analysis, SHA256 hash validation and a few other processes to reduce the likelihood of malicious software making its way into the repository and onto your machine. Another key challenge was all the changes required to be able to deliver the client program as a native Windows application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Which versions of Windows will be supported?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Windows Package Manager will support every Windows 10 version since the Fall Creators Update (1709)! The Windows Package Manager will be delivered with the Desktop App Installer when we ship version 1.0. If you are building software to run on Windows 10 you will have a simple way for your customers to install your software on billions of machines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;But what about…&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are expecting you have plenty of questions. What does this mean for the Windows store? It doesn’t mean anything for the Windows store. The Windows Package Manager is a command line interface, no marketing, no images, no commerce. Although we do plan on making those apps installable too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What about &lt;em&gt;insert any other package manager here&lt;/em&gt;? We think they are great. If they want to leverage our repository of validated packages, they can. If they want to see how we are doing it, it is open source. We’re open to feedback and suggestions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have already talked with a few of the well-known package manager teams. Chocolatey has a vibrant community with a massive collection of applications, and a rich history supporting both open source and enterprise customers. Scoop provides a convenient way to allow software to be installed without the UAC popups. Ninite keeps an eye on updates for all the apps it installed. There are many others like AppGet, Npackd and the PowerShell based OneGet package manager-manager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are happy with your current package manager, keep using it. Our goal is to make installing software on Windows better for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What’s next?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have a long list of features we think you will like. Take a look at the list of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.github.com/microsoft/winget-cli/issues&quot;&gt;issues&lt;/a&gt; we have already created on GitHub. Be sure to +1 any issues you feel strongly about. If you do not see something, and you would like us to consider it, just create a new issue.&lt;/p&gt;



</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 15:52:18 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>zeusly</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Windows Package Manager Preview | Windows Command Line</og:title>
<og:description>We are thrilled to announce the Windows Package Manager preview! If you’re already familiar with what a package manager is, feel free to skip this paragraph. If you’re still reading, you’re going to love this! A package manager is designed to help you save time and frustration.</og:description>
<og:url>https://devblogs.microsoft.com/commandline/windows-package-manager-preview/</og:url>
<og:image>https://devblogs.microsoft.com/commandline/wp-content/uploads/sites/33/2020/05/winget01.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://devblogs.microsoft.com/commandline/windows-package-manager-preview/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>When SimCity Got Serious: Story of Maxis Business Simulations and SimRefinery</title>
<link>https://obscuritory.com/sim/when-simcity-got-serious/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://obscuritory.com/sim/when-simcity-got-serious/</guid>
<description>&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_16282&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://obscuritory.com/sim/when-simcity-got-serious/&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-16282 size-full&quot; title=&quot;Thumbnail of the title screen from SimRefinery&quot; src=&quot;https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery.png&quot; alt=&quot;Thumbnail of the title screen from SimRefinery&quot; width=&quot;612&quot; height=&quot;468&quot; srcset=&quot;https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery.png 612w, https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery-150x115.png 150w, https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery-300x229.png 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 612px) 100vw, 612px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Thumbnail of the &lt;em&gt;SimRefinery&lt;/em&gt; title screen.&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;SimCity&lt;/em&gt; wasn’t meant to be taken seriously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game was inspired by research on real-world urban planning concepts,&lt;sup&gt;2,3&lt;/sup&gt; and although it was created as a way for players to experiment running a city, the goal was to be fun rather than accurate. “I realized early on, because of chaos theory and a lot of other things,” said designer Will Wright, “that it’s kind of hopeless to approach simulations like that, as predictive endeavors. But we’ve kind of caricatured our systems. &lt;em&gt;SimCity&lt;/em&gt; was always meant to be a caricature of the way a city works, not a realistic model of the way a city works.”&lt;sup&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I think if we tried to make it realistic, we would be doing something that we wouldn’t want to do,” Wright said in an interview in 1999.&lt;sup&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt; But that didn’t stop companies from believing Maxis could design realistic simulations. Will Wright didn’t believe that was even possible. “Many people come to us and say, ‘You should do the professional version,'” he continued. “That really scares me because I know how pathetic the simulations are, really, compared to reality. The last thing I want people to come away with is that we’re on the verge of being able to simulate the way that a city really develops, because we’re not.”&lt;sup&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maxis didn’t want to make professional simulation games. But for two brief, strange years, they did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From 1992 to 1994, a division called Maxis Business Simulations was responsible for making serious professional simulations that looked and played like Maxis games. After Maxis cut the division loose, the company continued to operate independently, taking the simulation game genre in their own direction. Their games found their way into in corporate training rooms and even went as far as the White House.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almost nothing they developed was ever released to the public. But their software raises questions about the role we want games to play in society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the past few years, I’ve spoken with employees from Maxis and the Business Simulations team to learn more about their company. For the first time, this is their story.&lt;span id=&quot;more-11225&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;


&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;. . .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;1. Delta Logic&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The history of Maxis Business Simulations is really a biography of John Hiles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hiles had just left the Peace Corps in the 1970s when he decided to teach himself programming. He was interested in astronomy,&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt; and so he started off his programming career with the aerospace industry, working on the Skylab space station that launched in 1973. He quickly made his way into the nascent Silicon Valley tech industry.&lt;sup&gt;7&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the mid-80s, he had become the senior vice president of product development at Digital Research in Monterey, California.&lt;sup&gt;8&lt;/sup&gt; Digital Research was a company that arguably had their biggest days behind them. They had designed the operating system CP/M, which powered most computers in the United States until IBM and Microsoft took over the personal computer market; within a decade, they would be out of business. But it was here, and in other jobs in the early tech industry, that Hiles started to think about computers differently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_16502&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption alignright&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_23.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-16502 size-medium&quot; title=&quot;An article from Computerworld titled &amp;quot;Digital Research to form connectivity software unit.&amp;quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_23-286x300.png&quot; alt=&quot;An article from Computerworld titled &amp;quot;Digital Research to form connectivity software unit.&amp;quot;&quot; width=&quot;286&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; srcset=&quot;https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_23-286x300.png 286w, https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_23-143x150.png 143w, https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_23.png 673w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 286px) 100vw, 286px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;John Hiles got to run his own unit at Digital Research but soon left to start his own company.&lt;sup&gt;67&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hiles wanted to learn more about artificial intelligence. Not like trying to make computers smart, because as he put it, “that turned out to be largely be baloney.” Computer technology was nowhere near advanced enough for that yet. “It’s like saying we’re gonna start building a 40-story building on the 14th floor,” Hiles said. He wanted to start lower, at the level of &lt;em&gt;unconscious&lt;/em&gt; thinking. He had been reading about cognitive theory, and he was fascinated by how the brain makes it possible for us to do things like speak and interpret language, all without a conscious action on our part, just an instinctive behavior.&lt;sup&gt;7&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Could you make a computer think like &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; instead? Could you give a computer program an unconscious mind?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“For the entire time I knew him,” Bruce Skidmore remembered, “he had ideas just bubbling out of his head all the time, and it was restless trying to scramble to keep up to make some of them real.” Skidmore was a software networking manager at Digital Research, and his impression was the same one everyone had about John Hiles: he was a fast thinker with ideas that were almost too big to be practical.&lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Digital Research had given Hiles the leeway to explore his big ideas in a new division called Interconnexions, but even then, he found it constraining.&lt;sup&gt;9,67&lt;/sup&gt; So shortly after in 1986, he quit to start his own company.&lt;sup&gt;10&lt;/sup&gt; Skidmore followed, as did another programmer from Digital Research, Bruce Montague. “We used to joke that we were gonna name it ‘John &amp;amp; Bruce,'” Skidmore said. They went with Delta Logic instead.&lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tech news service &lt;em&gt;Microbytes Daily&lt;/em&gt; described Delta Logic as “a group of refugees from Digital Research.”&lt;sup&gt;11&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_16287&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; readability=&quot;34&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-16287&quot; title=&quot;John Hiles demonstrates Entryway, a software platform by Delta Logic.&quot; src=&quot;https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;John Hiles demonstrates Entryway, a software platform by Delta Logic. Hiles is sitting in front of an old computer with an assortment of floppy disks on the desk.&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;492&quot; srcset=&quot;https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_1.jpg 702w, https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_1-150x115.jpg 150w, https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_1-300x231.jpg 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;John Hiles demonstrates &lt;em&gt;Entryway&lt;/em&gt;, a software platform by Delta Logic. Video courtesy of Susan Hiles.&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first, they weren’t quite sure what the company was actually going to do. Skidmore vaguely remembers that their first product was squashed when Digital Research objected that it was too similar to their own software, perhaps fearing a misappropriation of trade secrets.&lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt; Delta Logic was eventually scooped up by another Silicon Valley start-up, the Poqet Computer Corporation, where they developed a software platform called &lt;em&gt;Entryway&lt;/em&gt; for the corporation’s line of pocket computers.&lt;sup&gt;11,12&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, Delta Logic was small and scrappy. The promotional video for &lt;em&gt;Entryway&lt;/em&gt; was a homemade production filmed at Hiles’s home, re-recorded over a home astronomy video, with a piece of loose-leaf paper used as a clapboard in front of the camera. Hiles’s voice is all but drowned out by the classical music being played in the background.&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hiles and his team – now including programmer Greg Rossi, another escapee from Digital Research&lt;sup&gt;9,10&lt;/sup&gt; – still wanted to explore this concept of computer programs that could think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was interested in the idea of “agent-based modeling,” a way of simulating complicated behavior from the bottom-up. The way he explained it in a lecture at George Washington University in 1995, he used the example of writing a computer program that simulates a flock of birds. We could come up with a complicated formula to control an entire flock of birds flying around. Or instead, we could make each of the birds “think” for themselves, and when they’re all together, we can see larger patterns of behavior emerge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s easy enough to do with birds. But what if we could build that idea into something about society? What if we could use this bottom-up approach to simulate the behavior of a business? Or a marketplace? Or a country?&lt;sup&gt;13&lt;/sup&gt; If we could make a simulation like this, it could help us better understand the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a big idea, but they needed to find a way to make a simulation like this into an actual product.&lt;sup&gt;7&lt;/sup&gt; In 1989, they found their answer. It was a new computer game called &lt;em&gt;SimCity&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;SimWhatever&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;SimCity&lt;/em&gt; changed the way people think about simulation games. It was an astounding, unexpected success for Maxis when it was released in 1989, with over $5 million sales in the first two years and nearly tripling the size of the company. Suddenly, this quirky boutique software developer was stretched so thin that CEO and co-founder Jeff Braun was the only manager for a staff of 32 people – even for the financial staff, a problem that was swiftly corrected after Maxis got audited by the IRS.&lt;sup&gt;14&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But more importantly than being a financial success for the company, &lt;em&gt;SimCity&lt;/em&gt; started to influence the way that the public thought about computer simulations and urban planning. There’s no better example of this than a stunt by the &lt;em&gt;Providence Journal&lt;/em&gt; during the 1990 Democratic primary, when the candidates for mayor of Providence, Rhode island were invited to play the newly popular city-building game &lt;em&gt;SimCity&lt;/em&gt;. It was a close race, and the results of the &lt;em&gt;SimCity&lt;/em&gt; contest seem to have actually affected the outcome, with one candidate judged so harshly for their inadvertent mistakes playing the game that they believed it cost them the election.&lt;sup&gt;15&lt;/sup&gt; Whether or not &lt;em&gt;SimCity&lt;/em&gt; could &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; simulate how a city works, in people’s minds, it was close enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To an extent, this is what Will Wright wanted to happen. For Wright, games were a way of helping people create “mental models” for understanding parts of the world. The team at Maxis would research a topic like urban dynamics – or something like ant colony behavior, in the case of another game they made called &lt;em&gt;SimAnt&lt;/em&gt; – and create a game where players could experiment with those ideas. The goal wasn’t to teach anything directly, but rather to help the player get the model of &lt;em&gt;SimCity&lt;/em&gt; in their head, so that playing this game could help them understand how the different systems within a city interact.&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_16480&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption alignright&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_21.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-16480 size-medium&quot; title=&quot;Boston scenario from SimCity for Windows.&quot; src=&quot;https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_21-300x193.png&quot; alt=&quot;Boston scenario from SimCity for Windows.&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;193&quot; srcset=&quot;https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_21-300x193.png 300w, https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_21-150x96.png 150w, https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_21.png 545w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;SimCity&lt;/em&gt; helped players build a “mental model” of how a city worked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For many people though, that nuance was lost, and instead they treated it like Maxis could build accurate simulations of the real world. And they wouldn’t stop asking about it. “In the first couple months after &lt;em&gt;SimCity&lt;/em&gt; appeared,” Wright told &lt;em&gt;Wired&lt;/em&gt;, “we were approached by a number of companies saying, ‘Hey that’s great! If you can do a city like that, we want you to do &lt;em&gt;SimPizzaHut&lt;/em&gt;, or &lt;em&gt;SimWhatever&lt;/em&gt;.’ We thought these things were so weird that we said no, but they kept coming in.”&lt;sup&gt;16&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“So at some point, as we got big enough, we decided to give it a go.”&lt;sup&gt;16&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John Hiles knew about &lt;em&gt;SimCity&lt;/em&gt;. He also believed in the power of building mental models, and he saw something in &lt;em&gt;SimCity&lt;/em&gt; that was missing from the simulation modeling work happening at Delta Logic: it was fun. It had an intuitive interface and friendly graphics. That was the missing ingredient. Hiles believed that if they teamed up – Maxis’s style with Delta Logic’s systems – they could create simulations that were fun &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; powerful. Maxis had been looking for new partners for software development, so Hiles used that as an opportunity to get in their orbit. He approached Jeff Braun, and in 1991, his company became a contractor for Maxis.&lt;sup&gt;7,9&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That might have seemed like an unusual move for Maxis. Will Wright considered his games to be more like toys,&lt;sup&gt;17&lt;/sup&gt; and he even though he embraced the educational side of Maxis’s software,&lt;sup&gt;18&lt;/sup&gt; he doubted the real-world value of simulation games.&lt;sup&gt;5,7,9&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It turns out that the companies had a lot in common. Maxis producer Mike Perry remembers that they had similar points of view. “In many ways, we were making science ‘fun,’ and we knew we were making games like no other game company could. I think most of us thought Monterey was simply an extension of that culture,” he said. “Will Wright tends to make everyone around him smarter, or at least more curious, so [they] seemed like a comfortable match with [us]. And John Hiles was even smarter.”&lt;sup&gt;19&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A big part of the reason Maxis was eager to join together was because it meant Maxis would have do less work. “We were getting a lot of external interest in making business sims,” Perry explained, “so it was great that they could take on that work.”&lt;sup&gt;19&lt;/sup&gt; Jeff Braun said that under the arrangement they made, he could give Delta Logic a bunch of code and then “let them run with it. I didn’t want to distract from the games team.”&lt;sup&gt;20&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it also might have been the result of a mandate from a new investor. As part of the company’s restructuring in the wake of &lt;em&gt;SimCity&lt;/em&gt;, in the summer of 1992, Maxis accepted a $10 million investment from Warburg Pincus Ventures, who took a 30% stake in the company and a seat at the board. According to Braun, Warburg Pincus wanted Maxis to start doing business simulation games more seriously.&lt;sup&gt;20,21&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With their new directive, Maxis decided to jump in all the way. That July, they purchased Delta Logic, turning them into a new division of the company – Maxis Business Simulations.&lt;sup&gt;22&lt;/sup&gt; John Hiles was named VP and general manager.&lt;sup&gt;23&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their first project? Chevron wanted them to make a game about an oil refinery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;. . .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;2. &lt;em&gt;SimRefinery&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_16296&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; readability=&quot;33&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-16296 size-large&quot; title=&quot;Satellite view of the Chevron Richmond Refinery. Via Microsoft Maps, copyright Vexcel Imaging.&quot; src=&quot;https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_2-1024x529.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Satellite view of the Chevron Richmond Refinery. Via Microsoft Maps, copyright Vexcel Imaging.&quot; width=&quot;860&quot; height=&quot;444&quot; srcset=&quot;https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_2-1024x529.jpg 1024w, https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_2-150x77.jpg 150w, https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_2-300x155.jpg 300w, https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_2-768x396.jpg 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 860px) 100vw, 860px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Satellite view of the Chevron Richmond Refinery. Via Microsoft Maps, copyright Vexcel Imaging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oil refineries are really, really complicated. That’s why Chevron wanted Maxis to make them a game like &lt;em&gt;SimCity&lt;/em&gt;, to teach the employees at their oil refinery in Richmond, California how it all worked.&lt;sup&gt;22&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be clear, they didn’t want a game that was supposed to accurately train people how to run an oil refinery or replace an education in chemical engineering. That would’ve been incredibly dangerous. What they wanted instead was something that showed you how the dynamics of the refinery worked, how all the different pieces invisibly fit together, like &lt;em&gt;SimCity&lt;/em&gt; did for cities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The operators at the refinery sometimes had trouble getting a big picture for what was happening at the plant beyond their particular area of focus. “The whole goal if this was to teach operators that they are part of a bigger system,” Skidmore said. “Their concern at the time was that operators tended to be very focused on their one plant, and their one thing they do, and so [they] weren’t keeping in mind that what they do affected other parts of the plant. So they wanted a training tool that allowed operators to manipulate inputs and outputs of the various pieces of the refinery process to see how they impact.”&lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The non-technical staff at the Richmond refinery needed to know how it worked too. The people in human resources and accounting weren’t chemical engineers, but it would help their work to see how the different areas of the plant were networked together, how one department affected another department.&lt;sup&gt;7,22&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_16438&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption alignright&quot; readability=&quot;33&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_10.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-16438 size-medium&quot; title=&quot;One of the few surviving screenshots of SimRefinery.&quot; src=&quot;https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_10-300x224.png&quot; alt=&quot;One of the few surviving screenshots of SimRefinery. The screenshot depicts a top-down view of an oil refinery with a pop-up menu listing various components of the plant. The colors in the screenshot appear to be glitched or incorrect.&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;224&quot; srcset=&quot;https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_10-300x224.png 300w, https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_10-150x112.png 150w, https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_10.png 512w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;One of the few surviving screenshots of &lt;em&gt;SimRefinery&lt;/em&gt;. The colors in the screenshot appear to be glitched or incorrect.&lt;sup&gt;24&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chevron paid Maxis $75,000 for a prototype of a refinery simulator.&lt;sup&gt;22,25&lt;/sup&gt; The project began even before Maxis bought Delta Logic, back when they were still just contractors.&lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do you get started on a project like this? They did it the same way Maxis developed their own games: they did research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John Hiles and the Bruces took a visit to the Chevron Richmond Refinery, where they met with a specialist who took them on a tour of the plant and explained how it worked. It was a collaborative relationship with Chevron throughout the development process; Chevron sent them the raw formulas they used at the refinery, and as Maxis Business Simulations turned that into a game, Chevron would double-check their work.&lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt; Hiles compared it to being a field anthropologist:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;23&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I came up and said, “How about, these concepts, principles, and their relation?” and they say, “Oh, John, you screwed up, look at – this is wrong.” And I say, “Okay. Help me understand what to do about that.” They did, and they taught me. And all I was doing was field work. I was asking questions and listening carefully. And I’d say, “What about this?” I’d look at a photograph of their oil refinery, and I’d say, “What’s this big pile of sulfur doing here?” “Oh, well you weren’t paying attention to the chemistry, John.”&lt;sup&gt;7&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neither Hiles or Skidmore could recall the Chevron employee’s name, though they remembered him as “a genuine, brilliant, super-experienced guy who was patient enough to teach us all about oil refineries,” as Hiles said.&lt;sup&gt;7&lt;/sup&gt; Skidmore called him a guy who “knew the process of refining backwards and forwards.”&lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt; In all likelihood, it was Terrell Touchstone, a staff engineer at Chevron Richmond. Touchstone’s memory about &lt;em&gt;SimRefinery&lt;/em&gt; is hazy, but he suspects that he may have been the only person at Chevron who actually worked hands-on with the game. Or at least, he was the one who sent Business Simulations all the math behind the refinery.&lt;sup&gt;26&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The platform coding was all done by [Hiles’ team] using Maxis’ cobbled together development environment,” Touchstone told me. “We – but again most likely just myself – only specified the underlying physical (refinery processing) models as sets of multivariable equations. These were standard component mass and energy balances which were intentionally kept as simple as possible. John did all the real magic.”&lt;sup&gt;26&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Touchstone’s description of the “cobbled together development environment” seems to be accurate. According to Bruce Skidmore, Maxis supplied Business Simulations with the code behind one of their games, most likely &lt;em&gt;SimCity&lt;/em&gt;, which they heavily modified into a new patched-up, Frankensteined system that could support what they were trying to do. “We started with a framework that Maxis had,” Skidmore said. “It was not a tool, per se, but it was the guts of another game, I believe, so we could learn how to manipulate the graphics on the screen.”&lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt; They called this the Whiteboard engine, a proprietary system designed by Greg Rossi that bridged the gap between their agent-based simulation modeling software and the graphical interface.&lt;sup&gt;10&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I was unable to reach Rossi or Bruce Montague, who may have also helped design the Whiteboard engine, but Skidmore had nothing but praise for them both. He described Montague as “technical, very technical,” and called the core team from Delta Logic “just phenomenal people to work with.”&lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;How to blow up the refinery&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an editorial in &lt;em&gt;Forbes&lt;/em&gt;, Esther Dyson – who would later serve on the board of Maxis Business Simulations once it was spun off into its own company – described how &lt;em&gt;SimRefinery&lt;/em&gt; was played:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;21&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The refinery model includes inputs, various grades of oil at various prices; outputs, petroleum products at various products; and a whole set of refinery tradeoffs. Produce more heating oil, for example, and you have less left over for high-priced gasoline and jet fuel. Skimp on maintenance spending and a plant goes down, cutting production for a week, lowering the plant’s income, and cutting further into the maintenance budget. […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The overall objective is to maximize the refinery’s long-term profitability, or whatever you want it to be. Like a business, the game doesn’t come to a conclusion; you just keep trying to get better from period to period.&lt;sup&gt;27&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;SimRefinery&lt;/em&gt; also let players record and play back their actions. It could be used as an evaluation method, but it also allowed instructors to quickly make their own scenarios for their trainees to play, without needing programming experience.&lt;sup&gt;28&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It sounds a lot like other Maxis games, an open-ended game where you were meant to experiment and set your own objectives. And like other Maxis games, there were some dramatic ways to screw things up. Bruce Skidmore said that if you really messed up the chemical balance, you could actually cause part of the refinery to explode.&lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone who’s played &lt;em&gt;SimCity&lt;/em&gt; knows that the best part of the game is blowing things up. It’s the universal &lt;em&gt;SimCity&lt;/em&gt; experience. Maxis even gave you a Disaster menu to make giant monsters attack. You were meant to destroy everything once in a while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was even the main takeaway for some people. In her book on educational game research, &lt;em&gt;Engineering Play&lt;/em&gt;, Mizuko Ito remembers a story where she introduced &lt;em&gt;SimCity 2000&lt;/em&gt; to a child at the Boys and Girls Club:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Do you know &lt;em&gt;SimCity&lt;/em&gt;?” I asked a boy whom I hadn’t seen before, maybe seven years old or so. “Yeah!” he declared. “That’s the game where you blow up the cities!”&lt;sup&gt;29&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Destroying a simulation can be an educational experience too, and this is how &lt;em&gt;SimRefinery&lt;/em&gt; was &lt;em&gt;meant&lt;/em&gt; to be played. John Hiles said that most of the trainers at Chevron wanted to use it as a conventional training tool, “but some of the more astute teachers said, ‘Let’s just get you started here by seeing if you can wreck the oil refinery, if you can abuse the inputs and the settings and essentially get fired,'” he remembered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_16439&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_11.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-16439 size-medium&quot; title=&quot;One of the other few surviving screenshots of SimRefinery.&quot; src=&quot;https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_11-300x289.png&quot; alt=&quot;One of the other few surviving screenshots of SimRefinery. The screenshot is black-and-white and depicts a top-down view of an oil refinery. Caption: &amp;quot;A screen from the SimRefinery simulation game by Maxis.&amp;quot;&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;289&quot; srcset=&quot;https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_11-300x289.png 300w, https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_11-150x145.png 150w, https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_11-768x740.png 768w, https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_11.png 920w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;One of the other few surviving screenshots of &lt;em&gt;SimRefinery&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;sup&gt;25&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was a legitimate way to learn how a refinery worked: if you start breaking the refinery, you can see how ruining one part of the plant will affect the other parts of the plant. “The tool – the game – was agnostic,” Hiles explained, correcting himself. “It would work for someone trying to ruin an oil refinery just as well as somebody trying to run it efficiently.”&lt;sup&gt;7&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;SimRefinery&lt;/em&gt; was finished in fall 1992,&lt;sup&gt;27&lt;/sup&gt; earlier than the 1993 date that’s usually reported online. The trademark registration for &lt;em&gt;SimRefinery&lt;/em&gt; suggests that the game was officially handed over to Chevron on Monday, October 26, 1992. (It’s unusual to have a specific release date for a corporate training product, but that’s a result of Maxis trademarking the &lt;em&gt;SimRefinery&lt;/em&gt; name almost a year after it was completed.)&lt;sup&gt;30&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chevron liked it.&lt;sup&gt;25&lt;/sup&gt; They started testing the game with their staff in September, and Chevron reported that communication from marketing and finance staff “improved dramatically.”&lt;sup&gt;37&lt;/sup&gt; Speaking to &lt;em&gt;The Plain Dealer&lt;/em&gt; in Cleveland, Chevron training specialist Susan Gustin praised the game’s effectiveness. “Just dumping information on people isn’t effective,” she said. “People only remember what they use.”&lt;sup&gt;31&lt;/sup&gt; She told &lt;em&gt;Computerworld&lt;/em&gt;, “Some of these relationships aren’t at all obvious until you play the game a bit.”&lt;sup&gt;22&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems to have even won over one of its critics, Will Wright. “He was initially skeptical,” Skidmore said. “I think when we eventually finished &lt;em&gt;SimRefinery&lt;/em&gt;, I think he approved of it.”&lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_16345&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-16345 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Will Wright and Jeff Braun pose with a computer running SimRefinery.&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;462&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Will Wright and Jeff Braun pose with a computer running &lt;em&gt;SimRefinery&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;sup&gt;32&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But still, &lt;em&gt;SimRefinery&lt;/em&gt; didn’t get widespread use within Chevron. The press – as well as Terrell Touchstone&lt;sup&gt;33&lt;/sup&gt; – characterized &lt;em&gt;SimRefinery&lt;/em&gt; as being a prototype, something that might evolve into a final product later.&lt;sup&gt;21,25&lt;/sup&gt; Esther Dyson called it a “pilot project,” which would lead to “other simulated refineries” if it was successful.&lt;sup&gt;27&lt;/sup&gt; San Francisco’s &lt;em&gt;Upside&lt;/em&gt; magazine went as far as saying it was never implemented at the company at all. Touchstone chalks it up to the political environment at Chevron when &lt;em&gt;SimRefinery&lt;/em&gt; was developed. “In the middle of downsizing and layoffs, a computer game wasn’t politically acceptable,” he told &lt;em&gt;Upside&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;sup&gt;34&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite this, &lt;em&gt;SimRefinery&lt;/em&gt; seems to have found a quiet second life in the engineering industry. Touchstone reported in 1993 that the University of California Davis wanted to use &lt;em&gt;SimRefinery&lt;/em&gt; in their teaching;&lt;sup&gt;33&lt;/sup&gt; Professor Karen McDonald at UC Davis Department of Chemical Enginering said they had they used the game in their computer labs as late as 1997.&lt;sup&gt;35&lt;/sup&gt; Even within Chevron, the game still received attention years later. Bruce Skidmore says that after he left Maxis Business Simulations, he was contacted by an employee at Chevron, who requested an update to the program.&lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt; Hiles even claimed &lt;em&gt;SimRefinery&lt;/em&gt; was in use by an unidentified oil refinery as recently as 2016, but given the technical issues with maintaining a 24-year-old computer program for business use, that seems unlikely.&lt;sup&gt;7&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever the long-term interest in &lt;em&gt;SimRefinery&lt;/em&gt;, it wasn’t adopted at Chevron out of the gate, and that was the start of a pattern for the games by Maxis Business Simulations – a skepticism towards the idea that a simulation game could teach you something. Or &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; teach you something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;. . .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;3. Growth&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-16478 size-full&quot; title=&quot;A painting of a sailboat in the water on a clear day from Project Challenge.&quot; src=&quot;https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_20.png&quot; alt=&quot;A painting of a sailboat in the water on a clear day from Project Challenge.&quot; width=&quot;388&quot; height=&quot;269&quot; srcset=&quot;https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_20.png 388w, https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_20-150x104.png 150w, https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_20-300x208.png 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 388px) 100vw, 388px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Around this time in 1992 and 1993, Maxis was working on their next big game, &lt;em&gt;SimCity 2000&lt;/em&gt;. Meanwhile, over in Monterey, this separate wing of the company was doing their own thing. They had wrapped up their work on an oil refinery simulation for Chevron, and now they had even more business simulations lined up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their next game was &lt;em&gt;SimEnvironment&lt;/em&gt;, commissioned by the Logistics Management Institute, a contractor for the Environmental Protection Agency.&lt;sup&gt;9,36&lt;/sup&gt; Skidmore remembers that the project – led by the other Bruce, this time&lt;sup&gt;28&lt;/sup&gt; – was less a game than it was an interactive demonstration, designed to show the spread of pollution and the challenges of toxic waste site cleanup. “I don’t think in this case it was a simulation training so much as a way to explore [these concepts],”&lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt; Skidmore recalled. The game would be used to help summarize complicated scientific data for laypeople, allowing them to see how pollution would affect different climates and soils.&lt;sup&gt;37&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They also worked on &lt;em&gt;SimSite&lt;/em&gt;, a simulation for managing the closure of a military base.&lt;sup&gt;31&lt;/sup&gt; And there’s other game titles littered around in press reports, like &lt;em&gt;SimPower&lt;/em&gt;, a game modeling the operation of a power grid, developed jointly for the Pacific Gas &amp;amp; Electric Company and the Electric Power Research Institute. The game would have allowed players to compare the efficiency of different types of power sources and generators.&lt;sup&gt;21,22,37,38&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None of these titles are well-remembered by the Maxis Business Simulations staff. They’re uncertain whether those games were even actually finished. &lt;em&gt;SimEnvironment&lt;/em&gt; was completed,&lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt; but a game like &lt;em&gt;SimPower&lt;/em&gt; seems to have faded away, perhaps never even making it out of the pre-planning stage, only existing in one sentence in a magazine article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was typical for Business Simulations: bold concepts and partnerships that were difficult to bring to fruition. It was part of the way Hiles did business. He was the face of the company, and he tried to get their name out there as much as possible, even if it sometimes didn’t yield results. “John was such an incredible idea man, and he saw it as his mission for the company to get the word out about agent-based modeling,” Skidmore said. “So he was on the road three weeks out of four, attending conferences and giving lectures, and this whole time, he would talk to people, and these ideas would just spring forth. And he’d come back to us and throw it out there, but as often as not, the entities that he’d been talking to would not follow through.”&lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But John Hiles wanted Maxis Business Simulations to keep growing. He wanted the division to reach $2 million annual revenue,&lt;sup&gt;22&lt;/sup&gt; a number that might have been unattainable, but it was their moonshot. So they kept pitching more projects to more companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While going through their home, the family of John Hiles found one of these original pitches – &lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.org/details/simenergy-pitch&quot;&gt;a proposal for an unproduced game by Maxis called &lt;em&gt;SimEnergy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_16362&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-16362&quot; title=&quot;Excerpt from the pitch document for SimEnergy.&quot; src=&quot;https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_5.png&quot; alt=&quot;Excerpt from the pitch document for SimEnergy. &amp;quot;SimEnergy -- Proposed by Maxis. Maxis is a leading producer of simulation products for entertainment. In July 1992, Maxis announced the formation of a new Business Simulation Division that concentrates on bringing the company's award winning game technology to business and education simulations. SimEnergy will be produced by the Business Simulation Division.&amp;quot;&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;204&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Excerpt from the pitch document for &lt;em&gt;SimEnergy&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;sup&gt;28&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If it had been produced, &lt;em&gt;SimEnergy&lt;/em&gt; would have been the strangest game in the entire &lt;em&gt;Sim&lt;/em&gt; series: an educational game for schools that would teach students about energy consumption by following the impact of their lifestyle choices across multiple generations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The proposal was made for an unnamed Japanese electrical company, identified only by an employee named “Mr. Majima.” There’s no date on the document, but the references to other Maxis games places it somewhere around 1992.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pitch document is a walkthrough of &lt;em&gt;SimEnergy&lt;/em&gt;, following a player named Yoshi as he goes through forty years of his life as a manager at a power plant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;28&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Yoshi] chooses his life style by picking a house, car, motorcycle, two TVs, some appliances, and a subway ride to work. […] Now SimEnergy asks Yoshi whether his use of energy is about average, or much less than others, or much more. […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He points at his car, next points at a gas pump, then finally a supertanker. SimEnergy shows how these are connected and displays background information. Next Yoshi points at his TV set. SimEnergy shows him the TV’s energy costs: how much energy it took to build and how much it takes to operate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now Yoshi goes to work, where he is power utility manager. He decides to build a mix of different kinds of power plants. But when his customers complain about high costs, Yoshi decides to spend less on training and safety at his old coal-powered plant. This is a mistake that leads to accidents and reduced efficiency. Yoshi has a problem: complaints about cost led to reduced spending on safety, that led to lower efficiency and higher cost; more complaints followed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then the game jumps forward twenty years, when Yoshi’s children have all grown up. They confront him about the choices he made in his life. Then the clock advances another twenty years, as Yoshi comes face-to-face with his grandchildren. “What will their lives be like?”&lt;sup&gt;28&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is &lt;em&gt;wild&lt;/em&gt;. Not only would it have been a combination of a power plant simulation and a life simulation, it would’ve forced players to reckon with the long-term environmental impact of their choices. Even more than a game like &lt;em&gt;SimRefinery&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;SimEnvironment&lt;/em&gt;, it would’ve held a mirror up to the player’s decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So it’s understandable why the Japanese power company might have passed on &lt;em&gt;SimEnergy&lt;/em&gt;. Maybe the power plant simulation aspects (the practical piece of the proposal) were repurposed into the &lt;em&gt;SimPower&lt;/em&gt; concept that also wasn’t developed, but it shows the grandiose scale that John Hiles was thinking about – simulation games that wouldn’t just teach but would challenge society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the weird cul-de-sacs that Maxis Business Simulations went down, Maxis was proud of the division and saw them as maybe even being the future of the company. “This is a way to take complex simulations and make them understandable to lots of people,” Jeff Braun told the &lt;em&gt;San Francisco Chronicle.&lt;/em&gt; “In the next three years, there’s the potential for this new business to be bigger than the game business.”&lt;sup&gt;21&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Business Simulations didn’t reach this point without a few bumps. &lt;em&gt;SimRefinery&lt;/em&gt; was the first time the former Delta Logic team had ever designed a game. Compared to the software they were used to creating – programming infrastructure like &lt;em&gt;Entryway&lt;/em&gt; – they suddenly had a lot to learn. They had to adjust to the way that game development teams were structured, which Skidmore compared to being more like a movie production than software development.&lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One big change was that Maxis had an art team, something that Business Simulations had never worked with before. They had never done graphics at all, in fact. Jenny Martin, the art director at Maxis, was also the lead artist for &lt;em&gt;SimRefinery&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;sup&gt;9,39&lt;/sup&gt; but it probably wasn’t sustainable to rely entirely on the artists from the main Maxis team in Orinda, California. During the development of &lt;em&gt;SimRefinery&lt;/em&gt;, Bruce Skidmore’s partner had even done some of the artwork.&lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt; As Maxis Business Simulations planned to scale up the company for their next big project, they would need to build their own art team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So for the first time, they hired an artist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The closing of Fort Ord&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Located about 100 miles south of San Francisco along the Pacific coast, Monterey is a relatively small city, with about 32,000 people in the early 90s.&lt;sup&gt;40&lt;/sup&gt; To a degree, Monterey was a military town, or at least there was always a military presence. It was home to the Defense Language Institute and the Naval Postgraduate School; one of the city’s focal points was Fort Ord, an army base that had been in operation since World War I.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the aftermath of the Cold War, when a full-scale American military seemed less necessary, the Defense Base Closure and Realignment Commission recommended closing 34 military bases across the United States. One of them was Fort Ord.&lt;sup&gt;41&lt;/sup&gt; Maybe this is what prompted the development of &lt;em&gt;SimSite&lt;/em&gt;, the game that simulated a military base closure, a problem that was close to home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was an existential crisis for Monterey. When the local news ran a special report on the base closure, the massive impact it would have on the community was almost a foregone conclusion.&lt;sup&gt;42&lt;/sup&gt; A column in the &lt;em&gt;Santa Cruz Sentinel&lt;/em&gt; asked: “Can there be life in Monterey County after Fort Ord?”&lt;sup&gt;43&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_16325&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_3.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-16325 size-medium&quot; src=&quot;https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_3-300x142.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Santa Cruz Sentinel asks: &amp;quot;Can there be life in Monterey County after Fort Ord?&amp;quot;&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;142&quot; srcset=&quot;https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_3-300x142.jpg 300w, https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_3-150x71.jpg 150w, https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_3-768x363.jpg 768w, https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_3-1024x484.jpg 1024w, https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_3.jpg 1340w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;“Can there be life in Monterey County after Fort Ord?”&lt;sup&gt;43&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was the backdrop when Wendy Wibbens arrived in Monterey to teach English at a local middle school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I was really not cut out to be a middle school English teacher,” Wibbens admitted. “I loved the kids. I didn’t like the parents. I didn’t like having to deal with the parents, and I didn’t like the energy that it sucked from me.” Wibbens was an English major and a working single mother, and becoming an English teacher made sense for her, in theory. “The school schedule made really good sense,” she said, “but I am not a person to be up in front of a classroom every day with an audience, and I’m more an introvert.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Fort Ord closed, she realized it was time to change careers. “[Ford Ord] was a big part of the influx of students into the school district that I was working in, so they knew at the beginning of the year that they would be laying off 300 teachers,” Wibbens said. “And since I was one of the most recently hired, I knew I was going to be laid off.”&lt;sup&gt;44&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She turned to help from her friend Steve Snyder, who she met in art class back in high school. Snyder was now an art director at Sega of America,&lt;sup&gt;45&lt;/sup&gt; and he knew that pixel artists were in demand in the video game industry. He convinced Wibbens to teach herself how to use &lt;em&gt;Studio/8&lt;/em&gt;, a digital art program by Electronic Arts that was popular in the industry, and even before the end of the school year, she had a few contract gigs with game developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wibbens kept searching for work, and as luck would have it, in early 1993, she found an opening for a computer artist at a local company in Monterey called Maxis Business Simulations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It was amazing!” Wibbens excitedly recalled. “Because I was like, ‘Oh my god, that just, um… happened. This isn’t the way life…'” She trailed off, almost getting too excited remembering how excited she was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The small seven-person team at Business Simulations consisted mostly of software engineers. Coming from the education system, it was her first time working with a group like this – with people like Greg Rossi, who she described as “genius” and “nerdy.” But she remembers John Hiles most strongly. She laughed as she talked about Hiles, seeming to run through the memories of all their interactions where Hiles would have talked up some bold idea he had. “[He was] such a storyteller and such a visionary, and was just like, it wasn’t like any other person I’d ever been involved with in terms of trying to work with somebody, because he would just kind of wax philosophically and go off into these grand ideas,” Wibbens said. “He was brilliant, and I really admired him.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wibbens said she loved the back-and-forth she would have with Hiles and the programmers, these very different parts of the team trying to realize their vision. The process usually went that one of the engineers like Skidmore, Richard Rosenbaum, or Dan Riddle would come to Wibbens with a blueprint for the simulation that needed graphics. “They would just have this wireframe of the functionality,” she explained. “‘And now [you] need to go in and paint a picture over it so that it looks like what John has in his head.’ And I loved that part of it. […] We had just brilliant, sharp people.”&lt;sup&gt;44&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With an artist on their team, and as the city of Monterey prepared for their new future, Maxis Business Simulations began work on their most ambitious game ever. It was the only game by the division that was ever released to the general public, and for the first time, it would open up their ideas to scrutiny at a national level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;. . .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;4. &lt;em&gt;SimHealth&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_16475&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-16475&quot; title=&quot;Box art for SimHealth.&quot; src=&quot;https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_19.png&quot; alt=&quot;Box art for SimHealth.&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;513&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Box art for &lt;em&gt;SimHealth&lt;/em&gt;. Courtesy of MobyGames.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shortly after &lt;em&gt;SimRefinery&lt;/em&gt; was completed, Maxis Business Simulations was approached by the Markle Foundation, a non-profit organization that tries to advance the public discourse around government, politics, and health policy. They had a radical proposal: they wanted to make a business simulation game for the public instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Markle Foundation wanted to see if a game could educate people about a complicated policy issue. And in December 1992, there was no more relevant policy issue than health care. President Clinton’s election guaranteed that health care reform would become a highly contested topic in America, and for the Markle Foundation, it was the perfect time for an experiment – to see if games could be a future arena for public debate.&lt;sup&gt;13,46,47&lt;/sup&gt; “If people think the game is fun and interesting, we will try it elsewhere,” Markle Foundation president Lloyd Morrison told the &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt;, “perhaps with budget policy, welfare reform or the environment.”&lt;sup&gt;48&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was exactly the sort of provocative, personally challenging game idea that Hiles wanted to create. With a $350,000 budget – nearly five times the cost of &lt;em&gt;SimRefinery&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup&gt;47&lt;/sup&gt; – it was the biggest project yet for Maxis Business Simulations, and it would put their ideas to the test in the public realm. Could a simulation game help people understand how the world works? Could it make you challenge your own assumptions about an issue as polarizing as health care reform?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key was to make the player part of the story. Hiles believed that the reason &lt;em&gt;SimCity&lt;/em&gt; was so compelling was that it let the players customize their city, which made the city simulation aspects of the game so much more meaningful.&lt;sup&gt;46&lt;/sup&gt; This was, in fact, a core part of the Maxis philosophy. “The fun and challenge of playing with our toys lies in exploring the worlds you create out of your own imagination,” Maxis wrote in one of their earlier product catalogs. “You’re rewarded for creativity, experimentation, and understanding, with a healthy, thriving universe to call your own.”&lt;sup&gt;49&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this new game, &lt;a href=&quot;https://obscuritory.com/sim/simhealth/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;SimHealth&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Hiles wanted to take that idea to another level. He wanted players to have to explicitly state their beliefs about health care – about individual liberty, or the importance of community – then see if they could overhaul the American health care system in a way that matched their ideals. He wanted the player to have to confront their own ideology and understand what that ideology looked like as a real policy.&lt;sup&gt;7&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just like &lt;em&gt;SimRefinery&lt;/em&gt; wasn’t supposed to teach you how to run an oil refinery, this game wasn’t meant to accurately simulate the health care system. But instead, it was a way to see what &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; happen if you rewrote the laws of health care – and then question if that’s what you really wanted.&lt;sup&gt;7&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hiles talked about his vision in grandiose terms that the rest of the company struggled to wrap their heads around. There was an image he had in his mind that he kept sharing with rest of the team. It was a dinner plate with a meager bit of food on it – a pea, or a meatball – teetering on the edge. As the economy changed, the plate would get bigger or smaller, the food coming closer to the brink of falling onto the floor. It was supposed to be a metaphor for the precarity of the American family. Or something.&lt;sup&gt;9,44&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nobody really knew what to do with that.&lt;sup&gt;9,44&lt;/sup&gt; “Well, that’s a cool idea, but I don’t know how to do that,” Skidmore said he told Hiles, “and we’re not quite sure that gets across the intent.”&lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_16471&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; readability=&quot;33&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-16471 size-full&quot; title=&quot;Main Street from SimHealth.&quot; src=&quot;https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_17.png&quot; alt=&quot;Main Street from SimHealth is a downtown district with a city hall, office and governmental buildings, a police department, a hospital, and industrial research facility, and a few houses.&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; srcset=&quot;https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_17.png 640w, https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_17-150x113.png 150w, https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_17-300x225.png 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Main Street in &lt;em&gt;SimHealth&lt;/em&gt; lets you see how your town is changing as the costs of health care are shifted between institutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But like Hiles’s other grand ideas, the Business Simulations team found a way to translate that into a playable game. Jenny Martin returned as the art director to advise Wibbens, and borrowing from the art style of &lt;em&gt;SimCity&lt;/em&gt;, they drew a city that would respond to the economy, with buildings growing or shrinking, rather than a plate of peas. Hiles had originally wanted the pea plate graphic to be done in the style of a Works Progress Administration mural – creating a parallel between the health care debate and the social reforms of the New Deal – which would be a huge undertaking for that one picture. So Wibbens got to track down a local artist who worked for the WPA in the 40s, Bruce Ariss, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_22.png&quot;&gt;he painted a mural for the title screen instead&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(“I hope John kept that canvas, because we had it in the office up for a long time,” Wibbens said.)&lt;sup&gt;44&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“John had incredible ideas, and we had to knock him down to things that you could just implement,” Skidmore added.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Newcomer producer Greg Wolfson was tasked with the research phase of the game, and compared to learning about how a refinery or a power plant works, boiling down the entire health care system into a computer game ended up being an endlessly complicated task. “Basically, Greg Wolfson was driving himself nuts,” Skidmore said. “He became a health expert, and as he researched, he realized that there were 100 different factors that impacted the same particular element, and so we had to focus on what elements would have the most impact visually. Cause again, this was supposed to be a simulation training game.”&lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Greg Wolfson was a very good critical thinker,” Skidmore recalled. “He had a really good mind, in general, for detail, so he would ask questions like […] ‘Are we saying the right thing?'”&lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The team always knew that their model would come under scrutiny. Skidmore acknowledged that no matter what they did, “there certainly was always going to be a perception of bias.”&lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt; Hiles agreed that if people thought &lt;em&gt;SimHealth&lt;/em&gt; was intentionally biased in any directoin, they would “push it over into a ditch.”&lt;sup&gt;13&lt;/sup&gt; To counteract this, they let players look inside the simulation itself. &lt;em&gt;SimHealth&lt;/em&gt; as an “Assumptions” menu, where you can view the hundreds of variables that power the simulation. If you disagreed, for instance, about the game’s predictions for the national employment rate, you could go in and change them yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;SimHealth&lt;/em&gt; was meant to be a tool that could guide the debate around health care – as long as the players understood how it was meant to be used. But once it was in the public’s hands, all bets were off. Like John Hiles told an internet talk radio program in 1994, “I’ve never met anyone who read a manual to start playing a game.”&lt;sup&gt;46&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;“A Tool For National Debate”&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the launch deadline from the Markle Foundation grew closer, &lt;em&gt;SimHealth&lt;/em&gt; needed some help, and Maxis hunkered down. Mike Perry and longtime Maxis tester Kevin O’Hare were called in to help fix things; the lead engineer from Business Simulations, Richard Rosenbaum, would periodically drive two hours up to Maxis’s office in Orinda to work more closely with the team. There was a lot riding on &lt;em&gt;SimHealth&lt;/em&gt; for many different organizations, and getting it into any acceptable state of completion was an ordeal. “Trying to coordinate Orinda, MBS, Markle, marketing, etc., all while trying to get an incomplete product finished was a challenge,” Perry said. “There were a number of stakeholders that needed to approve most aspects of the product. Even the box art was subject to external revisions and reviews.”&lt;sup&gt;19&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It still wasn’t ready for release, but they had to move forward. The Markle Foundation would still hold a high-profile launch event for lawmakers in Washington D.C., as planned, but the public version of &lt;em&gt;SimHealth&lt;/em&gt; wouldn’t roll out until four months later.&lt;sup&gt;19,47&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_16468&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption alignright&quot; readability=&quot;33&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_16.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-16468 size-medium&quot; title=&quot;The pre-release box art for SimHealth.&quot; src=&quot;https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_16-251x300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The pre-release box art for SimHealth. The box art is a blue-silver color, with a large drawing of a caduceus superimposed over a crowd people. The game's subtitle is &amp;quot;A Democracy and Society Computer Simulation.&amp;quot;&quot; width=&quot;251&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; srcset=&quot;https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_16-251x300.jpg 251w, https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_16-126x150.jpg 126w, https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_16-768x917.jpg 768w, https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_16-858x1024.jpg 858w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 251px) 100vw, 251px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;The unpolished pre-release version of &lt;em&gt;SimHealth&lt;/em&gt; had a different box art that billed the game as “A Democracy and Society Computer Simulation.” Courtesy of Clint Basinger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;SimHealth&lt;/em&gt; debuted in November 1993 at a press conference on Capitol Hill as part of a publicity stunt targeting the American government.&lt;sup&gt;47,50&lt;/sup&gt; The Markle Foundation gave copies of an early version of the game to congressional staffers and the White House;&lt;sup&gt;48&lt;/sup&gt; Perry remembered that Maxis actually got a call from the Secret Service asking for help getting the game running on Chelsea Clinton’s computer.&lt;sup&gt;51&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although it was the most popular game by Business Simulations – by default – &lt;em&gt;SimHealth&lt;/em&gt; was not a success. Markle subsidized the cost of the game so it could be sold for $29.99, below the average price of a computer game, to help get it out into the public.&lt;sup&gt;47,48&lt;/sup&gt; (“No one is going to make money on SimHealth,” Hiles told the &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt;.)&lt;sup&gt;48&lt;/sup&gt; Still, it only shipped around 50,000 copies, far less than they hoped for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Markle Foundation president Morrison blamed it on the game’s stilted marketing campaign, which focused on lawmakers rather than the public.&lt;sup&gt;47,48&lt;/sup&gt; Edith Bjornson from the Markle Foundation admitted in August 1994 that “the effect of the game on the quality of the debate was not on the scale we would have liked.”&lt;sup&gt;52&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although it was a certainly less successful than its stakeholders wanted, the game did get the attention of a narrower audience – academics, policymakers, and insurance companies. Using a game to learn about the health care system was a novel idea for them. The University of Missouri at Kansas City started using &lt;em&gt;SimHealth&lt;/em&gt; as part of a certificate training program on health care administration.&lt;sup&gt;47&lt;/sup&gt; MetLife’s director of information and computer services called the game “pretty sophisticated,” and she said that everyone at the company who played it had “really enjoyed it and appreciated the educational benefits that can be derived from it.”&lt;sup&gt;53&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, the game got a public seal of approval from the White House. Jeff Eller, spokesperson for the President’s Task Force on National Health Care Reform, said it helped him understand how games can shape the public discourse. “I think &lt;em&gt;SimHealth&lt;/em&gt; is an intriguing alternative,” Eller told the &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt;. “You can’t dismiss this as another &lt;em&gt;Pac-Man&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Tetris&lt;/em&gt;.”&lt;sup&gt;48&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hiles achieved his goal: they had gotten the word out about agent-based modeling. But with all this new attention, some people strongly disagreed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;No apologies&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the political journal &lt;em&gt;The American Prospect&lt;/em&gt;, Paul Starr, a senior advisor on health care policy for President Clinton, wrote a scathing editorial that criticized not just &lt;em&gt;SimHealth&lt;/em&gt; but the entire concept of simulation games. “&lt;em&gt;SimHealth&lt;/em&gt; contains so much misinformation that no one could possibly understand competing proposals and policies, much less evaluate them, on the basis of the program,” Starr said. “Once the novelty of making health policy into a game has worn off, I doubt &lt;em&gt;SimHealth&lt;/em&gt; will hold much interest. It certainly has no value in assessing health care reform.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem ran deeper, Starr believed. Games like &lt;em&gt;SimCity&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;SimHealth&lt;/em&gt; threatened to blur the lines of reality for players. Simulation games were “seductive,” he argued, and there was no clear way to understand &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; their models differed from reality. The Assumptions menu, in his mind, was far too impenetrable, “an unreachable black box” that most players would never look at. And so players would never question the math, just accept the game at face value. “What assumptions were buried in the underlying models?” Starr asked, “What was their ‘hidden curriculum’? Did a conservative or a liberal determine the response to changes in tax rates in &lt;em&gt;SimCity&lt;/em&gt;?”&lt;sup&gt;54&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other words, we would accept the truth from faulty, inaccurate, or malicious simulation models because they’re fun, or because they seem smart. Social theorist Sherry Turkle called this problem the “abdication of authority” to a simulation.&lt;sup&gt;55&lt;/sup&gt; It’s exactly what Will Wright had feared. &lt;em&gt;SimCity&lt;/em&gt; is a much more light-hearted game than &lt;em&gt;SimHealth&lt;/em&gt;, yet it was still taken seriously enough to change the outcome of an election. &lt;em&gt;SimHealth&lt;/em&gt;, meanwhile, was being marketed to Congress. Did it ever stand a chance to &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; be taken literally?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It gets to the heart of a question that followed Hiles for his entire career. Do we really trust a computer game to change how people think about the world?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_16473&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot; readability=&quot;33&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_18.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-16473 size-medium&quot; title=&quot;The Assumptions screen from SimHealth.&quot; src=&quot;https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_18-300x225.png&quot; alt=&quot;The Assumptions screen from SimHealth, showing a graph of &amp;quot;Demand for Specialist Care&amp;quot; versus &amp;quot;Acute Care Benefits Level.&amp;quot;&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;225&quot; srcset=&quot;https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_18-300x225.png 300w, https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_18-150x113.png 150w, https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_18.png 640w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;SimHealth&lt;/em&gt; let you change the math of the simulation, but would anyone actually go that far?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I was researching &lt;em&gt;SimHealth&lt;/em&gt; in 2016, I spoke with John Hiles, and I gave him a chance to respond to these criticisms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Hiles’s view, it was everyone else’s fault for not getting it. It wasn’t about predicting the future; it was about understanding the relationships between a complicated network of concepts. He proudly had no apologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“[&lt;em&gt;SimHealth&lt;/em&gt;] didn’t tell us what health care system to build,” he told me. “Certainly discussing the relation between justice and liberty doesn’t calculate the amount of money you should spend on improving Medicare. It doesn’t calculate the number of citizens that you want to cover who don’t have catastrophic disease protection in their insurance. None of that is present in the value projection.” The player had to think for themselves about what the results meant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Now, if you’re not thinking,” he continued, “then you’re just using the tool to either bullshit other people, make them think that you’re smart, or to just occupy your time and, you know, twiddle. So I’m not responsible for how people want to misuse human thought.” He made a lot of people angry, and frankly, he loved it, because it meant his games were challenging them. “I’m unapologetic about taking some of the wonderful things that are present in the world of games and translating them or projecting them into an area of real discourse and real social concern.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With &lt;em&gt;SimHealth&lt;/em&gt; completed, Hiles and company would have a chance to piss off even more people. This time, it would be without Maxis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;. . .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;5. Thinking Tools&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_16434&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; readability=&quot;34&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_9.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-16434&quot; title=&quot;A comparison of the opening credits for SimHealth.&quot; src=&quot;https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_9-1024x378.png&quot; alt=&quot;A comparison of the opening credits for SimHealth. On the left, the pre-release version credits &amp;quot;Maxis Business Simulations and the Markle Foundation present.&amp;quot; The final version (right) says &amp;quot;Distributed by Maxis, Thinking Tools, Inc. and The Markle Foundation present.&amp;quot;&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;258&quot; srcset=&quot;https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_9-1024x378.png 1024w, https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_9-150x55.png 150w, https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_9-300x111.png 300w, https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_9-768x284.png 768w, https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_9.png 1300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 700px) 100vw, 700px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Before &lt;em&gt;SimHealth&lt;/em&gt; was released, Maxis Business Simulations was spun off into its own company. The 1993 pre-release version of the game (left) still credits the company by their original name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the final development of &lt;em&gt;SimHealth&lt;/em&gt;, Maxis axed their Business Simulations division.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Business Simulations had just become too much work for Maxis. Projects kept disappearing, like &lt;em&gt;SimPower&lt;/em&gt;, and especially after the chaotic launch of &lt;em&gt;SimHealth&lt;/em&gt;, it was too hard for Maxis to wrangle their clients. “We were spending more time negotiating contracts with these clients than developing the software,” Will Wright told &lt;em&gt;CNN&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;sup&gt;18&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“In those pre-internet days, Monterey seemed pretty far away,” Mike Perry recalled. “Outside of &lt;em&gt;SimHealth&lt;/em&gt;, I don’t remember how many of us in Orinda other than Will and Jeff spent much time with them. We were kind of hoping to see another &lt;em&gt;SimRefinery&lt;/em&gt;, a specialized &lt;em&gt;SimCity&lt;/em&gt;-like game that let us graphically play with a complex system like a power plant or something. But since we never really saw many deliverables, I’d say most of the company accepted the split as a matter of course.”&lt;sup&gt;19&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More than that, Maxis had decided that business games weren’t the direction they wanted to go as a company after all. “The Monterey team was disbanded because the gap between building simulations for entertainment and simulations for businesses was too great,” Braun explained. “One was a product, the other was a service.”&lt;sup&gt;20&lt;/sup&gt; As Will Wright told the magazine &lt;em&gt;Architectural Record&lt;/em&gt;, “for us the main point was to develop programs that put the fun back into architectural and building software.” From time to time, Maxis would revisit the idea, “but the business model was almost certainly never going to work, especially for a public company,” Perry said.&lt;sup&gt;19&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And besides, games like &lt;em&gt;SimCity&lt;/em&gt; were already having a bigger educational impact than something like &lt;em&gt;SimHealth&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;sup&gt;18&lt;/sup&gt; Maxis had made an educational edition of &lt;em&gt;SimCity&lt;/em&gt; for schools,&lt;sup&gt;56&lt;/sup&gt; and according to Perry, they had run a contest called the “Future City Competition,” where kids got to design their own cities in the game and the winners went to the White House to meet President Clinton.&lt;sup&gt;19&lt;/sup&gt; So why did they need a serious games division?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_16449&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption alignright&quot; readability=&quot;36&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_12.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-16449 size-medium&quot; title=&quot;Two screenshots from TeleSim.&quot; src=&quot;https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_12-200x300.png&quot; alt=&quot;Two screenshots from TeleSim. The top picture shows the title screen with various stock illustrations of telecommunications and business. The bottom picture is a map of New York City, drawn from an isometric perspective in the style of a game like SimCity 2000. These are photos taken of a TV playing a VHS recording of a projector screen, so the quality is marginal.&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; srcset=&quot;https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_12-200x300.png 200w, https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_12-100x150.png 100w, https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_12-768x1152.png 768w, https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_12-683x1024.png 683w, https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_12.png 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Two screenshots from &lt;em&gt;TeleSim&lt;/em&gt;. These are off-screen photos, taken with a phone camera, of a VHS recording of a projector screen, so please forgive the quality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hiles bought out the Business Simulation division in January 1994, and &lt;em&gt;SimHealth&lt;/em&gt; was eventually realeaesd the new name for the company, Thinking Tools.&lt;sup&gt;34&lt;/sup&gt; Everyone got fancy new titles. Bruce Skidmore became vice president of engineering.&lt;sup&gt;10&lt;/sup&gt; And less than a year after she had been a middle school English teacher, Wendy Wibbens had now become the art director. She even got to hire her first employee, Kelly McFadden, a digital artist from Buffalo, New York.&lt;sup&gt;44&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was still some work to wrap up from the Maxis days. The company had been working on &lt;em&gt;TeleSim&lt;/em&gt;, a simulation of how regional telephone companies compete for business. After the breakup of the Bell System that had monopolized the American telecom industry, the new smaller telecom corporations (the “Baby Bells”) were struggling to adapt to an environment where they actually had to compete with other companies. The consulting company Coopers &amp;amp; Lybrand had been working with two of the Baby Bells – Pacific Bell in California and NYNEX in New York – so they commissioned a simulation game to help teach them about how to compete in a crowded marketplace.&lt;sup&gt;9,34,36,44&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;TeleSim&lt;/em&gt; sounds like it was the most game-y simulation that Thinking Tools had made up to that point. Up to eight computer-controlled telecom companies would squabbling with the player over their market territory, while &lt;em&gt;SimCity&lt;/em&gt;-style disasters like earthquakes and fires break out, forcing the companies to adjust. Like everything else by Thinking Tools, it came with an elaborate visual metaphor, courtesy of John Hiles – “a boardroom painting of a sailing vessel steering boldly into the wind – or sinking.”&lt;sup&gt;34&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;em&gt;Project Challenge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of the projects at Thinking Tools still kept the &lt;em&gt;Sim&lt;/em&gt; name, at least internally.&lt;sup&gt;7&lt;/sup&gt; But with their newfound independence, the company was free to take their philosophy in a new direction, unconstrained by the expectations for working for Maxis. The scope of their games had continued to grow, with an average project now costing upwards of $350,000, as large as the budget for &lt;em&gt;SimHealth&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;sup&gt;34&lt;/sup&gt; They did more work for the military, like &lt;em&gt;LogLab&lt;/em&gt;, a logistics simulation led by Thinking Tools engineer Dan Riddle.&lt;sup&gt;1,44&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their big game as an independent company was &lt;em&gt;Project Challenge&lt;/em&gt;, a project management training game developed for the tech firm SHL Systemhouse.&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Hiles family recovered &lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.org/details/ProjectChallengeDemo_1996_ThinkingTools&quot;&gt;an interactive demo copy of &lt;em&gt;Project Challenge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which would have been given out to prospective customers. For the first time since the game’s release in 1996, we have a chance to look at it up-close. This is now the only other game by Thinking Tools that has ever been seen publicly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Project Challenge&lt;/em&gt; was supposed to teach managers how to keep their projects on track. There’s lots of graphs and budgets, but another big element was managing the people on your team. They would fall into conflicts that might require closer attention to improve their interpersonal skills, or they might need to be re-negotiated to stay on the team if they accepted an offer from another company. They speak robotically about their feelings. It’s dry business management material, but maybe it’s just what a business struggling with project management would have wanted out of a game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can see the similarities to &lt;em&gt;SimHealth&lt;/em&gt; almost immediately. The art style and the interface are nearly identical, even reusing some of the same window layouts and icons. This was how the Thinking Tools house style evolved after they separated from Maxis. Wibbens served as art director on &lt;em&gt;Project Challenge&lt;/em&gt;, bringing her influences from &lt;em&gt;SimHealth&lt;/em&gt;, though she says McFadden was responsible for much of the actual art.&lt;sup&gt;44&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game is heavy with the sort of heavy communication metaphors that John Hiles loved putting in his games, like your team members who wear buttons that literally describe their emotions with happy faces or sad faces. This was part of Hiles’s desire for the company’s simulation games to “flood [you] with feedback,”&lt;sup&gt;46&lt;/sup&gt; but the production in &lt;em&gt;Project Challenge&lt;/em&gt; is much more ambitious than &lt;em&gt;SimHealth&lt;/em&gt;. You can read the unsubtle body language of your employees as they accusingly gesture at the other members of the team, one of whom seems to have trouble staying alert during a team meeting. The game even seems like it would have been fully voice-acted, an unexpected addition to a business simulation game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And of course, that painting of the sailboat from &lt;em&gt;TeleSim&lt;/em&gt; shows up again too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;em&gt;Race for the White House&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thinking Tools was taking more risks. They were emboldened, and they pushed their games further than what they could get away with under Maxis. However, there was still a limit. The most notable case was a failed project they developed for their old friends at the Markle Foundation, &lt;em&gt;Race for the White House&lt;/em&gt;. Everyone I spoke with who worked on &lt;em&gt;Race for the White House&lt;/em&gt; remembered it as a spectacular disaster.&lt;sup&gt;7,9,44&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the shortcomings of &lt;em&gt;SimHealth&lt;/em&gt;, the Markle Foundation still loved the game, and they wanted to work with Thinking Tools again to continue exploring their ideas about games and public policy.&lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt; They signed on to co-produce a new series of games called &lt;em&gt;PowerTrip&lt;/em&gt;, which were going to “enhance civic dialog” around topics like political campaigns and foreign policy.&lt;sup&gt;57&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;em&gt;Race for the White House&lt;/em&gt; must have been the first of these, as well as the last.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Markle Foundation had requested a simulation game about the dynamics of political campaigns in the United States. Players would take on the role of a campaign manager with a limited amount of political capital to spend to get things done, and along the way, they would learn about the forces at work behind-the-scenes in politics, like money and lobbying influence.&lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt; By the time a prototype was delivered, the project had run totally amuck. Rather than being a simulation with charts and menus, it was going to be a first-person adventure in the style of &lt;em&gt;Myst&lt;/em&gt;, complete with live-action film sequences and voice actors. “It was… very ambitious on our part,” Skidmore recalled, sighing. “We didn’t have the resources at all for that kind of thing. Looking in hindsight at the time, it was like, ‘Oh sure, we can do this!'”&lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On top of that, Hiles had taken the message of the project too far. “I made the mistake of bragging that [&lt;em&gt;Race for the White House&lt;/em&gt;] would help people to understand that given enough money and a dog that looked like Rin Tin Tin, you could make Rin Tin Tin become the president,” he said.&lt;sup&gt;7&lt;/sup&gt; The Markle Foundation wanted something that would ask challenging questions about American politics,&lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt; but not like that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Between the bizarrely failed &lt;em&gt;Myst&lt;/em&gt; approach and the bleak message, it was too much for the Markle Foundation. “They were horrified and shocked and said, ‘We can’t have our name associated with that!'” Hiles said. “They actually had it destroyed, the entire stock, the entire product.”&lt;sup&gt;7&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_16455&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; readability=&quot;33&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-16455 size-full&quot; title=&quot;The credits for Project Challenge.&quot; src=&quot;https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_14.png&quot; alt=&quot;The credits for Project Challenge. &amp;quot;A demonstration of the project management training simulation, Project Challemge by Thinking Tools, Inc. Mike Bailey, John Hiles, Rick Rosenbaum, Bernadette Smith, Wendy J. Wibbens.&amp;quot;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; srcset=&quot;https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_14.png 640w, https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_14-150x113.png 150w, https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_14-300x225.png 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Thinking Tools had reached 15 employees by 1996,&lt;sup&gt;10&lt;/sup&gt; but they stayed small and close.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thinking Tools was a close-knit company, especially as Wibbens remembers it.&lt;sup&gt;44&lt;/sup&gt; John, the Bruces, the Gregs, and a few other people like Richard Rosenbaum had been working together for nearly a decade as the company continued to grow, weathering the transition into an independent business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a personal level, Thinking Tools reminds me of my dad’s small business, formed by three partners who jumped ship from their old employer after their division was shut down. It’s grown and shrunk over the years, employees coming and going as their financial situation changed, but they’ve maintained their core, the same people who have worked together for now thirty years – not quite a family, but with bonds stronger than just being co-workers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s the reality of running a small business. You look out for each other. “[John] really took care of us all,” Wibbens recalled.&lt;sup&gt;44&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The close bonds of the company were tested when they were hit by an embezzlement scandal, when they discovered that their long-time bookkeeper had been stealing from them for years. It remains a painful, sensitive topic for the Thinking Tools employees, who asked not to discuss the incident in detail. But it underscored how much they had come to depend on each other, this unconventional tech startup in a small military town along the central coast of California.&lt;sup&gt;9,44&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John Hiles was fiercely proud and protective of Thinking Tools, and when we spoke, he elided over the bad times for the company. But they’re vividly remembered by his colleagues – the gradual dismantling of Thinking Tools at the hands of venture capital.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;. . .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;6. Collapse&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-16451 size-full&quot; title=&quot;A painting of a sailboat riding through a storm from Project Challenge.&quot; src=&quot;https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_13.png&quot; alt=&quot;A painting of a sailboat riding through a storm from Project Challenge.&quot; width=&quot;388&quot; height=&quot;269&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thinking Tools took on a bunch of projects. Just like when they were Maxis Business Simulations, many of them had a habit of not panning out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was &lt;a href=&quot;https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_15.png&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;TransPort&lt;/em&gt;, a transportation network model for Texas Instruments&lt;/a&gt;; the mass social behavior model &lt;em&gt;Sugarscape&lt;/em&gt; for the Brookings Institution; an unrealized triage simulator for the Tripler Army Medical Center in Hawaii;&lt;sup&gt;13&lt;/sup&gt; some kind of decision-making simulation called &lt;em&gt;PEG&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;sup&gt;8&lt;/sup&gt; They had worked on &lt;em&gt;The Justice System&lt;/em&gt; for Harcourt Brace, designed to simulate the flow of the criminal justice system as a companion to a textbook about criminal justice,&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; but Bruce Skidmore says it never got off the ground. They had a deal with the parent company for TJ Maxx, but that never happened either. Systemhouse started work with Thinking Tools on a follow-up to &lt;em&gt;Project Challenge&lt;/em&gt; about arranging office spaces, but that project quickly ended too when it couldn’t live up to the original concept.&lt;sup&gt;9,44&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hiles was the heart of Thinking Tools, but his tendency to think in terms of big ideas and metaphors made it difficult to operate as a business. With Hiles so often on the road, Skidmore found himself running the day-to-day of the company.&lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“As genius as John Hiles was, the way I look back on it was the piece that he was missing was having a partner who was a really savvy businessperson,” Wibbens said. “John really couldn’t be bothered with the details of running the business. His mind was above all that, and rightly so, but that kind of hurt us off and on.” The producers at Thinking Tools – Greg Wolfson, Bernadette Smith, and Debra Louison Lavoy – were essentially acting as translators for Hiles to turn his visions into tangible products that the company could actually make.&lt;sup&gt;44&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a big swing for new investments, Thinking Tools went public on NASDAQ in 1996.&lt;sup&gt;10&lt;/sup&gt; As they faced the scrutiny of their board of directors and new shareholders, it became clear that if the company was going to continue, they needed to change how they did business. “The perception was, and some of it is true, is that we were struggling trying to keep enough of these boutique-type consulting projects [going] to build to a successfully funded company,” Skidmore said.&lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In December 1996, Thinking Tools brought in a new president and CEO, Phillip Whalen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The last project&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whalen had been the vice president of European operations as a company called Digital Tools&lt;sup&gt;58&lt;/sup&gt; – a bonafide tech executive – and he immediately set about putting his own imprint on the company. He brought in his own staff to run finances and human resources. He ousted Skidmore and Wibbens from their job titles, installing his own vice president of engineering and art director. He decided that Monterey was “a dead end,” as Skidmore described it, and that the company would need to relocate to Silicon Valley, starting with a sales office.&lt;sup&gt;9,44&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Change was necessary and inevitable for Thinking Tools, but the sudden overhaul to this close-knit company rubbed people the wrong way. “We all kind of loathed this group that had come in and tried to notch themselves in,” Wibbens said. “Even though we all knew that there was a need for some of that, we didn’t think that this one had their heart in the right place.” Wibbens had particularly harsh words to say about their new art director, who she described as a “loathsome, offensive person” who terrified the office with his uncouth behavior. “It was like… no no no, this can’t be. We’re not gonna have to live like this, are we?”&lt;sup&gt;44&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_16414&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/19980206102358/http://www.thinkingtools.com:80/html/think_2000.html&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-16414&quot; title=&quot;Promotional website for Think 2000.&quot; src=&quot;https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_6.png&quot; alt=&quot;Promotional website for Think 2000, captured using oldweb.today.&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;519&quot; srcset=&quot;https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_6.png 812w, https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_6-150x111.png 150w, https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_6-300x222.png 300w, https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_6-768x569.png 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 700px) 100vw, 700px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Promotional website for &lt;em&gt;Think 2000&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;sup&gt;59&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whalen’s top priority was to come up with a new business model for Thinking Tools, while still taking advantage of the company’s strength for designing simulation games. With input from Hiles, he devised an idea for a new product, a simulation to help companies analyze the impact the Y2K bug could have on their business.&lt;sup&gt;9,59&lt;/sup&gt; It sounds like a spiritual successor to &lt;em&gt;Project Challenge&lt;/em&gt;, but instead of being commissioned by a specific company, like Thinking Tools had always done, it was a general product that they could sell to any business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Think 2000&lt;/em&gt; was a Hail Mary to change the business model of Thinking Tools, from tailor-made simulations to being an office software company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It sold one copy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Maybe two, I dunno,” Skidmore said. “It wasn’t enough.”&lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of Q1 1998, Thinking Tools reported zero revenue.&lt;sup&gt;60&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Exit plan&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The writing was on the wall for Thinking Tools. The new direction didn’t work. Whatever Hiles’s weaknesses as an executive, he had a vision for the company and the future of software, and now there was nothing, except the hollow business logic that caused them to lease out a seemingly unused sales office in Silicon Valley.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Hiles, the top priority was taking care of his employees – the people who had believed in his wild ideas and supported him since his days at Digital Research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hiles entered negotiations with BiosGroup, an agent-based modeling company in Santa Fe, New Mexico, to buy Thinking Tools and preserve everyone’s jobs.&lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt; The sale was nearly finalized, and the president of BiosGroup had even come out to Monterey to meet them. But the chairman of the Thinking Tools board, Fred Knoll,&lt;sup&gt;58&lt;/sup&gt; got in a personal spat with the head of BiosGroup and abruptly canceled the deal. The new Thinking Tools leadership realized that their employees were looking for a way out, and they set up a petty firewall, threatening to sue BiosGroup if the company tried to poach any of their staff.&lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final months of Thinking Tools sound like something close to purgatory, as the staff couldn’t leave, funding ran dry, and it became clear there would be no next project. A new executive, Moshe Zarmi, came onboard to figure out what could be salvaged; Wibbens described him in much kinder terms as a conscientious man, though one in an unenviable position as the teardown guy.&lt;sup&gt;44&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of 1998, Phillip Whalen gathered the staff together for a final meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Well, I wanted to bring you all together,” Wibbens remembered him announcing. “The good news is that you’ll be able to spend more time with your families this holiday.”&lt;sup&gt;44&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“They couldn’t even pay severance,” Skidmore said, frustrated. Whalen told the staff to take home their office equipment instead. “That’s your severance.”&lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt; It was the last insult, the ignoble end to the company at the hands of growth capitalism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The employees of Thinking Tools did take their work home… and they burned it. They held a bonfire, gathering together one last time – with their project files, their pink slips, whatever – and letting the past burn away.&lt;sup&gt;9,44&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Greg Wolfson, I remember, bringing stacks of things that he had worked on, and… just burning them,” Wibbens said, laughing.&lt;sup&gt;44&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Aftermath&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the last days of Thinking Tools, Whalen was fired. Moshe Zarmi was left to handle the aftermath.&lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt; The husk of the company was ultimately merged into GVI Security, a video surveillance vendor in Carrollton, Texas.&lt;sup&gt;61,62&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_16417&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption alignright&quot; readability=&quot;33&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_7.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-16417 size-medium&quot; title=&quot;A low-resolution screenshot of SimNavy, developed at the Naval Postgraduate Academy.&quot; src=&quot;https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_7-300x200.png&quot; alt=&quot;A low-resolution screenshot of SimNavy, developed at the Naval Postgraduate Academy.&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; srcset=&quot;https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_7-300x200.png 300w, https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_7-150x100.png 150w, https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_7-768x512.png 768w, https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_7-1024x683.png 1024w, https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_7.png 1187w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;A low-resolution screenshot of &lt;em&gt;SimNavy&lt;/em&gt;, developed at the Naval Postgraduate Academy.&lt;sup&gt;63&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As soon as Thinking Tools shut down and the coast was clear, Bruce Skidmore left town to join BiosGroup after all.&lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt; Wendy Wibbens, the artist for &lt;em&gt;SimHealth&lt;/em&gt;, oddly enough went on to work for the health care company Kaiser Permanente.&lt;sup&gt;44&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John Hiles stayed in Monterey. He went to teach at the local military academies he had become familiar with, where he could continue exploring his ideas about agent-based modeling with some of his old colleagues. He worked at the Defense Language Institute – for a brief time with Mike Daily, another former producer from Thinking Tools – and then the Naval Postgraduate School.&lt;sup&gt;44&lt;/sup&gt; He served as advisor on a student project at the NPS with Richard Rosenbaum called &lt;em&gt;SimNavy&lt;/em&gt; ,&lt;sup&gt;8,63&lt;/sup&gt; and he kept consulting on simulation games elsewhere, like &lt;em&gt;SimIraq&lt;/em&gt;, a game he designed for the intelligence community.&lt;sup&gt;7&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you might expect, &lt;em&gt;SimIraq&lt;/em&gt; really, &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; pissed people off. John Hiles couldn’t have been prouder.&lt;sup&gt;7&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;What happened to &lt;em&gt;SimRefinery&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest questions surrounding Maxis Business Simulations that’s followed me ever since starting this research is whether &lt;em&gt;SimRefinery&lt;/em&gt; is still around somewhere. To my knowledge, there are no surviving copies, and that’s okay. Given how frequently this question comes up, I want to document my research for the sake of completion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mike Perry said that Maxis would have kept a backup copy of &lt;em&gt;SimRefinery&lt;/em&gt; in a binder of floppy disks that held many of the master copies of their software. Perry said the binder was likely thrown out or lost when the studio moved to Emeryville in 2004. A second copy would have been kept in off-site storage; for all intents and purposes, this copy is missing or destroyed.&lt;sup&gt;64&lt;/sup&gt; None of the Maxis, Thinking Tools, or Chevron alumni I spoke with had saved a personal copy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I reached out to several universities with chemical engineering programs in the Bay Area – including UC Davis, which definitely taught with &lt;em&gt;SimRefinery&lt;/em&gt; in the 90s.&lt;sup&gt;35&lt;/sup&gt; None of them still had it around. Or if they did, it was so far deep in storage that nobody knew they had it and had no reason to look for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through an unrelated connection, the family of John Hiles was able to get in touch with the engineers at Chevron Richmond. Even they don’t have a copy anymore.&lt;sup&gt;65&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe somebody took it home with their office hardware severance package. As for any paperwork from Thinking Tools? It probably went up in that bonfire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nobody saved &lt;em&gt;SimRefinery&lt;/em&gt; because it didn’t seem important. It was a one-off, somewhat unsuccessful training program for an oil refinery in California. In the grand scheme of Maxis, it was one of their least important titles, which has only now become an object of interest in the video game community because of its unavailability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not impossible that a copy of the game could eventually surface. As amazing as it would be to play &lt;em&gt;SimRefinery&lt;/em&gt;, the thing is, we don’t need to. In practice, &lt;em&gt;SimRefinery&lt;/em&gt; would be a fairly accurate simulation of an oil refinery. What’s more important is that we understand the context around it. We can learn why it was made, how it was made, and what it meant to people. If we can learn about that, it’s less important to actually play the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;. . .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;7. Finale&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_16419&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-16419 size-full&quot; title=&quot;A photo of John Hiles.&quot; src=&quot;https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A photo of John Hiles wearing a red windbreaker.&quot; width=&quot;247&quot; height=&quot;306&quot; srcset=&quot;https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_8.jpg 247w, https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_8-121x150.jpg 121w, https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery_8-242x300.jpg 242w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 247px) 100vw, 247px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;John Hiles.&lt;sup&gt;66&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few months after we spoke in 2016, John Hiles died suddenly from an aggressive brain cancer. “He was a polymath, an autodidact, and perhaps the gentlest person any of us have ever known,” his obituary reads. “We owe him so much.”&lt;sup&gt;66&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John Hiles’s work was hidden from public view for his entire life. Despite leading a division at a now-legendary game studio, despite being interviewed by the &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt; – despite one of his games being played in the White House – Maxis Business Simulations and Thinking Tools were always a trivia fact, something mentioned in passing as a novelty in an article about &lt;em&gt;SimCity&lt;/em&gt;. Whenever I spoke with an employee from Maxis or Thinking Tools, they were shocked to hear that Hiles had passed away, having now been out of touch with him for years as their time working together seemed to slip further into the past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But like his one-time boss Will Wright, Hiles had grand ideas in mind. As far back as the 80s, he had a vision for what computers could do, how they could inform us about the world we live in. He saw a connection between the advanced simulation modeling work happening in Silicon Valley and the fun, playful software coming out of the video game industry, and in the face of the resistance his company faced in public and private, he wanted to bring those worlds together. Thirty years later, as “serious games” and STEM learning have become buzzwords in games academia, the rest of the world seems to have caught up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps it’s fair to say that Thinking Tools lived in a bubble of tech optimism, the notion that a new emerging technology could solve problems in society, and then the industry and their money would flock to another idea when the reality proved more complicated. Whenever a company announces that they’re going on the blockchain or using deep-learning AI, it feels like another iteration of that, the same sort of triumphant announcement as when Jeff Braun declared that business simulation games could be the future of Maxis, only to abandon them less than a year later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a company, Thinking Tools struggled. Hiles was not a business leader, and the rest of his company knew that. He was the idea man, and ideas don’t necessarily play the bills. But when he would go off on one of his tangents at a public speaking gig, bringing ideas about neuroscience and meteorology into a lecture about software, people listened. There’s a reason the Bruces followed him when he left Digital Research. Far from the company being an ego trip, as it so easily could have been for a tech leader with an unusual approach to their work, Hiles knew it was a team mission. He cared deeply about his company and his employees up until the end, when Thinking Tools was finally driven into the ground by tech industry capitalists. They were all sharing this wild idea together, trying to make games that weren’t just fun approximations of the real world but would actively challenge how we thought about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s weird to think that those ideas resulted in games as odd as &lt;em&gt;SimRefinery&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Race for the White House&lt;/em&gt;. But it was a new vision for what educational games could be, not to make them work for us, but what they could teach us back instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;. . .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Special thanks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the most in-depth article I have ever written. It was a long research process, and I owe a debt to a number of people:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The family of John Hiles, in particular Susan Hiles, who has been unendingly supportive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jenny Martin and the Maxis Alumni group for their kindness in providing access to the Maxoids.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mike Perry, for answering many questions I’ve bugged him with over the years.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jon-Paul Dyson, director of the International Center for the History of Electronic Games at the Strong Museum of Play, for sharing his correspondence with Jeff Braun.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kevin Bunch, for scanning the &lt;em&gt;SimEnergy&lt;/em&gt; pitch documents for me while stay-at-home orders were in effect in Maryland.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Video Game History Foundation and the MAGFest MAGES communities, for their continued inspiration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;. . .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1. Thinking Tools. (n.d.). &lt;em&gt;Projects for Partners&lt;/em&gt;. Retrieved from &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/19991111231328fw_/http://www.thinkingtools.com/html/products_for_partners_fs.html&quot;&gt;https://web.archive.org/web/19991111231328fw_/http://www.thinkingtools.com/html/products_for_partners_fs.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2. Whitehead, Ingrid. (2000, March). Will Wright wants you to rule your own urban empire. &lt;em&gt;Architectural Record, 188&lt;/em&gt;(3), p.246. Retrieved from LexisNexis&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3. Maxis Software. (1995). Will TV. &lt;em&gt;SimCity 2000: Special Edition&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4. Donovan, Tristan. (2011, May 23). The Replay Interviews: Will Wright. &lt;em&gt;Gamasutra&lt;/em&gt;. Retrieved from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gamasutra.com/view/feature/134754/the_replay_interviews_will_wright.php?page=3&quot;&gt;https://www.gamasutra.com/view/feature/134754/the_replay_interviews_will_wright.php?page=3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5. Ito, Mizuko. (2012). Engineering Play: A Cultural History of Children’s Software. Cambridge, MA: MIT Press, p. 153. Retrieved from ProQuest Ebook Central&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6. Delta Logic. ([1989]). &lt;em&gt;Entryway / Astronomy&lt;/em&gt; [Video]. Courtesy of Susan Hiles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7. Hiles, John. (2016, August 12). Phone interview.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8. Zyda, M., Hiles, J., Rosenbaum, R., et al. (1998). &lt;em&gt;SimNavy – Phase 0: Building an Enterprise Model of the US Navy&lt;/em&gt;. Naval Postgraduate School. Retrieved from &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20170809043437/gamepipe.usc.edu/~zyda/resources/pubs/SimNavyPaper98.pdf&quot;&gt;https://web.archive.org/web/20170809043437/gamepipe.usc.edu/~zyda/resources/pubs/SimNavyPaper98.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;9. Skidmore, Bruce. (2019, February 16). Phone interview.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;10. U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission. (1996, October 18). &lt;em&gt;Prospectus&lt;/em&gt;. Retrieved from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1021444/0000950146-96-001829.txt&quot;&gt;https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1021444/0000950146-96-001829.txt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;11. Poqet Computer’s Delta Logic takes wraps off its object oriented interface generator. (1989, July 9). &lt;em&gt;Microbytes Daily&lt;/em&gt;. Retrieved from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cbronline.com/news/poqet_computers_delta_logic_takes_wraps_off_its_object_oriented_interface_generator&quot;&gt;https://www.cbronline.com/news/poqet_computers_delta_logic_takes_wraps_off_its_object_oriented_interface_generator&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;12. Parker, Rachel. (1989, September 11). Poqet Recruits Support For Lightweight Laptop. &lt;em&gt;InfoWorld, 11&lt;/em&gt;(37), p.8. Retrieved from &lt;a href=&quot;https://books.google.com/books?id=xDAEAAAAMBAJ&amp;amp;lpg=PA1&amp;amp;pg=PT3&quot;&gt;https://books.google.com/books?id=xDAEAAAAMBAJ&amp;amp;lpg=PA1&amp;amp;pg=PT3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;13. Hiles, John, &amp;amp; Epstein, Joshua. (1995, Oct. 20). &lt;em&gt;Lessons learned from SimHealth: the promise and limits of health policy simulation&lt;/em&gt; [VHS], Special Collections Research Center, Estelle and Melvin Gelman Library at the George Washington University, Washington, D.C.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;14. Greco, Susan. (1994, May 1). Looking for Mr. Right. &lt;em&gt;Inc.&lt;/em&gt; Retrieved from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.inc.com/magazine/19940501/2910.html&quot;&gt;https://www.inc.com/magazine/19940501/2910.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;15. Koebler, Jason. (2015, May 8). The Real Mayors of ‘SimCity.” &lt;em&gt;Vice&lt;/em&gt;. Retrieved from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/ezv7wp/the-real-mayors-of-simcity&quot;&gt;https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/ezv7wp/the-real-mayors-of-simcity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;16. Kelly, Kevin. (1994, January). Will Wright: The Mayor of SimCity. &lt;em&gt;Wired, 2&lt;/em&gt;(1). Retrieved from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/1994/01/wright/&quot;&gt;https://www.wired.com/1994/01/wright/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;17. Will Wright collection, Brian Sutton-Smith Library and Archives of Play at The Strong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;18. Will Wright. (2000, January 20). &lt;em&gt;CNN&lt;/em&gt;. Retrieved from &lt;a href=&quot;http://edition.cnn.com/chat/transcripts/2000/1/wright/index.html&quot;&gt;http://edition.cnn.com/chat/transcripts/2000/1/wright/index.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;19. Perry, Mike. (2020, May 17). Twitter direct message.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;20. Braun, Jeff. (2020, May 15). Email correspondence with Jon-Paul Dyson.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;21. Siegmann, Ken, &amp;amp; Wildavsky, Ben. (1993, March 5). Simulations let companies solve complex problems. &lt;em&gt;The San Francisco Chronicle&lt;/em&gt;, D1, D8.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;22. Booker, Ellis. (1993, March 8). Simulations growing up. &lt;em&gt;Computerworld, 27&lt;/em&gt;(10), pp.35, 37. Retrieved from &lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.org/details/computerworld2710unse/&quot;&gt;https://archive.org/details/computerworld2710unse/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;23. Maxis. (1992). &lt;em&gt;Corporate Fact Sheet&lt;/em&gt; [Press release]. Retrieved from the collections at &lt;em&gt;Game Informer&lt;/em&gt; magazine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;24. Barr, Christopher. (1993, June 15). Businesses Play War Games. &lt;em&gt;PC Mag, 12&lt;/em&gt;(11), p.31. Retrieved from &lt;a href=&quot;https://books.google.com/books?id=jMKfH6i9OcYC&amp;amp;pg=PA31&quot;&gt;https://books.google.com/books?id=jMKfH6i9OcYC&amp;amp;pg=PA31&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;25. Burgress, John. (1993, April 23). The Realities of Simulations Mirror Work, Play Realities. &lt;em&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/em&gt;, F13. Retrieved from &lt;a href=&quot;https://search.proquest.com/docview/307639981&quot;&gt;https://search.proquest.com/docview/307639981&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;26. Touchstone, Terrell. (2017, July 10). Email correspondence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;27. Dyson, Esther. (1992, October 12). What if? &lt;em&gt;Forbes, 150&lt;/em&gt;(8), p.142. Retrieved from &lt;a href=&quot;http://search.ebscohost.com/login.aspx?direct=true&amp;amp;db=buh&amp;amp;AN=9210123858&amp;amp;site=ehost-live&amp;amp;scope=site&quot;&gt;http://search.ebscohost.com/login.aspx?direct=true&amp;amp;db=buh&amp;amp;AN=9210123858&amp;amp;site=ehost-live&amp;amp;scope=site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;28. Maxis. ([1992]). &lt;em&gt;SimEnergy — PROPOSED BY MAXIS&lt;/em&gt;. Scanned copy uploaded to &lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.org/details/simenergy-pitc&quot;&gt;https://archive.org/details/simenergy-pitch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;29. Mizuko, p. 137.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;30. SIMREFINERY – Trademark Details. (2001). &lt;em&gt;Justia&lt;/em&gt;. Retrieved from &lt;a href=&quot;https://trademarks.justia.com/743/89/simrefinery-74389727.html&quot;&gt;https://trademarks.justia.com/743/89/simrefinery-74389727.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;31. Technology Briefs. (1993, April 11). &lt;em&gt;The Plain Dealer&lt;/em&gt;, 4E. Retrieved from &lt;a href=&quot;https://search.proquest.com/docview/291535171&quot;&gt;https://search.proquest.com/docview/291535171&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;32. Levy, Tom. (1993, March 5). Simulations let companies solve complex problems. &lt;em&gt;The San Francisco Chronicle&lt;/em&gt;, D1. Retrieved from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/simprograms/4029188285/in/album-72157623067694211/&quot;&gt;Beyond Sims on Flickr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;33. Touchstone, Terrell. (1993, December 21). &lt;em&gt;SimSchool Project&lt;/em&gt; [Usenet discussion on comp.simulation]. Retrieved from &lt;a href=&quot;https://groups.google.com/forum/#!search/simrefinery/comp.simulation/fXYxYGytEBs/nyQFhktuYzgJ&quot;&gt;https://groups.google.com/forum/#!search/simrefinery/comp.simulation/fXYxYGytEBs/nyQFhktuYzgJ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;34. Ditlea, Steve. (1994, November). Imitation of life. &lt;em&gt;Upside, 6&lt;/em&gt;(11). Retrieved from &lt;a href=&quot;https://search.proquest.com/docview/217963040&quot;&gt;https://search.proquest.com/docview/217963040&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;35. McDonald, Karen. (2017, August 2). Email correspondence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;36. Nelson, Jorge O. (1993, November). &lt;em&gt;School System Simulation: An Effective Model for Educational Leaders&lt;/em&gt;. Memphis, TN: Memphis State University (ED 371 444), p.6. Retrieved from &lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.org/details/ERIC_ED371444/&quot;&gt;https://archive.org/details/ERIC_ED371444/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;37. Louderback, Jim. (1993, March 1). Maxis industry-simulation packages don’t play games. &lt;em&gt;PC Week, 10&lt;/em&gt;(8), p. 80.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;38. Hendricks, Robert C. (1994, July 1). &lt;em&gt;Environmental and customer-driven seal requirements&lt;/em&gt;. National Aeronautics and Space Administration, p.68. Retrieved from &lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.org/details/NASA_NTRS_Archive_19950007175/&quot;&gt;https://archive.org/details/NASA_NTRS_Archive_19950007175/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;39. Martin, Jenny. (2017, April 25). Personal correspondence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;40. U.S. Department of Commerce, Economics and Statistics Administration, Bureau of the Census. (1990). &lt;em&gt;1990 Census of Population, Social and Economic Characteristics, California&lt;/em&gt;. p.6. Retrieved from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www2.census.gov/library/publications/decennial/1990/cp-2/cp-2-6-1.pdf&quot;&gt;https://www2.census.gov/library/publications/decennial/1990/cp-2/cp-2-6-1.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;41. Associated Press. (1991, June 11). Bush accepts base-closing recommendations. &lt;em&gt;Santa Cruz Sentinel&lt;/em&gt;, C11. Retrieved from Newspapers.com&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;42. KCBA-35 News. (1991, November 3). Special report [Advertisement]. &lt;em&gt;Santa Cruz Sentinel&lt;/em&gt;, 19.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;43. Lydon, Sandy. (1991, May 12). Life after a military base closes. &lt;em&gt;Santa Cruz Sentinel&lt;/em&gt;, D1, D3. Retrieved from Newspapers.com&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;44. Wibbens, Wendy. (2019, February 9). Phone interview.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;45. Snyder, Steve. (n.d.) &lt;em&gt;Career Portfolio, 1983-1992&lt;/em&gt;. Retrieved from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.stevesnyderdesign.com/games&quot;&gt;https://www.stevesnyderdesign.com/games&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;46. Gunn, Moira, &amp;amp; Hiles, John. (1994, July 22). Tech: Technology and Health Care. &lt;em&gt;Tech Nation&lt;/em&gt;. Recording retrieved from &lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.org/details/RTFM-Tech-940722&quot;&gt;https://archive.org/details/RTFM-Tech-940722&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;47. MacPherson, Peter. (1995, December 20). Playing the game. &lt;em&gt;Hospitals &amp;amp; Health Networks, 69&lt;/em&gt;(24), p. 82. Retrieved from &lt;a href=&quot;https://search.proquest.com/docview/215311773&quot;&gt;https://search.proquest.com/docview/215311773&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;48. Passell, Peter. (1993, December 24). Pac-Man It’s Not. The Future of a Presidency and U.S. Health Care, Maybe. &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;. Retrieved from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/1993/12/24/us/pac-man-it-s-not-the-future-of-a-presidency-and-us-health-care-maybe.html&quot;&gt;http://www.nytimes.com/1993/12/24/us/pac-man-it-s-not-the-future-of-a-presidency-and-us-health-care-maybe.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;49. Maxis Software. (1992). Maxis Software Toys Catalog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;50. Mitgang, Lee D. (2000). Big Bird and beyond: the new media and The Markle Foundation. New York: Fordham University Press, pp. 258-259.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;51. Perry, Mike. (2016, July 28). One of us old Maxis folks should tell the story of when the secret service called our tech support in 1993 to help Chelsea play SimHealth. [Tweet]. Retrieved from &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mike_perry/status/758856064645214212&quot;&gt;https://twitter.com/mike_perry/status/758856064645214212&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;52. Angus, Jeffrey Gordon. (1994, August 7). Sim-Ply Fascinating — Simulation ‘Games’ Offer Real Educational Opportunities. &lt;em&gt;The Seattle Times&lt;/em&gt;. Retrieved from &lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.seattletimes.com/archive/?date=19940807&amp;amp;slug=1924051&quot;&gt;https://archive.seattletimes.com/archive/?date=19940807&amp;amp;slug=1924051&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;53. Jones, David C. (1994, August 15). Simulation software tackles health care reform. &lt;em&gt;National Underwriter,&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;98&lt;/em&gt;(33), 5. Retrieved from &lt;a href=&quot;http://search.proquest.com/docview/228457061&quot;&gt;http://search.proquest.com/docview/228457061&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;54. Starr, Paul. (1994, Spring). Seductions of Sim: Policy as a Simulation Game. &lt;em&gt;The American Prospect&lt;/em&gt;. Retrieved from &lt;a href=&quot;https://prospect.org/environment/seductions-sim-policy-simulation-game/&quot;&gt;https://prospect.org/environment/seductions-sim-policy-simulation-game/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;55. Turkle, Shelly. (1997, March-April). Seeing Through Computers: Education in a Culture of Simulation. The American Prospect, 31, 76-82. Retrieved from http://web.mit.edu/sturkle/www/pdfsforstwebpage/ST_Seeing%20thru%20computers.pdf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;56. Basinger, Clint. (2011, March 18). Maxis “Educational Version” Software. &lt;em&gt;lazygamereviews&lt;/em&gt;. Retrieved from &lt;a href=&quot;https://lazygamereviews.wordpress.com/2011/03/18/maxis-educational-versions/&quot;&gt;https://lazygamereviews.wordpress.com/2011/03/18/maxis-educational-versions/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;57. Millison, Doug. (1995, April 12). &lt;em&gt;daily spectrum 12 april 95&lt;/em&gt; [Usenet discussion on comp.graphics.animation]. Retrieved from &lt;a href=&quot;https://groups.google.com/forum/#!topic/comp.graphics.animation/cCoK7n82pHE&quot;&gt;https://groups.google.com/forum/#!topic/comp.graphics.animation/cCoK7n82pHE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;58. U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission. (1997, October 16). &lt;em&gt;Prospectus&lt;/em&gt;. Retrieved from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1021444/0000950146-97-001541.txt&quot;&gt;https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1021444/0000950146-97-001541.txt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;59. Thinking Tools. (n.d.). &lt;em&gt;Think 2000&lt;/em&gt;. Retrieved from &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/19980206102358/http://www.thinkingtools.com:80/html/think_2000.html&quot;&gt;https://web.archive.org/web/19980206102358/http://www.thinkingtools.com:80/html/think_2000.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;60. Thinking Tools, Inc. Announces First Quarter Results. (1998, May 1). &lt;em&gt;PR Newswire&lt;/em&gt;. Retrieved from &lt;a href=&quot;https://search.proquest.com/docview/447307426/A13E260FC00C48DCPQ/4&quot;&gt;https://search.proquest.com/docview/447307426/A13E260FC00C48DCPQ/4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;61. Thinking Tools, Inc. Acquires GVI Security, Inc.; Acquisition Positions Thinking Tools in $2.9 Billion Video Surveillance Market. (2004, February 23). &lt;em&gt;Business Wire&lt;/em&gt;. Retrieved from Factiva.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;62. Thinking Tools, Inc. Effects a Change in Name and a 65 to 1 Reverse Stock Split. (2004, April 14). Business Wire. Retrieved from Factiva.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;63. Zyda, Michael. (1998, September 21). &lt;em&gt;SimNavy – Phase 0: Building an Enterprise Model of the US Navy&lt;/em&gt; [Powerpoint slides]. Naval Postgraduate School. Retrieved from &lt;a href=&quot;https://calhoun.nps.edu/bitstream/handle/10945/41520/SimNavyTalk98.pdf?sequence=1&quot;&gt;https://calhoun.nps.edu/bitstream/handle/10945/41520/SimNavyTalk98.pdf?sequence=1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;64. Perry, Mike. (2016, October 9). Twitter direct message.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;65. Hiles, Susan. (2018, July 1). Personal correspondence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;66. Obituary for John E. Hiles. (2016, December 28). &lt;em&gt;Bermudez Family Cremations and Funerals&lt;/em&gt;. Retrieved from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bermudezfamilyfunerals.com/notices/John-Hiles&quot;&gt;https://www.bermudezfamilyfunerals.com/notices/John-Hiles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;67. Beeler, Jeffrey. (1986, October 6). Digital Research to form connectivity software unit. &lt;em&gt;Computerworld, 20&lt;/em&gt;(40), p.180. Retrieved from &lt;a href=&quot;https://books.google.com/books?id=botwBgcSATQC&amp;amp;pg=PA180&quot;&gt;https://books.google.com/books?id=botwBgcSATQC&amp;amp;pg=PA180&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 15:46:15 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>danso</dc:creator>
<og:title>When SimCity got serious: the story of Maxis Business Simulations and SimRefinery | The Obscuritory</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://obscuritory.com/sim/when-simcity-got-serious/</og:url>
<og:image>https://obscuritory.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/simrefinery.png</og:image>
<og:description>The creators of SimCity had a division that made Sim games for corporations. They were never released to the public. For the first time ever, this is the story of Maxis Business Simulations.</og:description>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://obscuritory.com/sim/when-simcity-got-serious/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>A Google Cloud support engineer solves a tough DNS case</title>
<link>https://cloud.google.com/blog/topics/inside-google-cloud/google-cloud-support-engineer-solves-a-tough-dns-case</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://cloud.google.com/blog/topics/inside-google-cloud/google-cloud-support-engineer-solves-a-tough-dns-case</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;This message is incredibly useful because it contains a lot of detailed information:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The specific VM with the issue&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The issue - DNS resolution not working&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where the issue is visible - the VM and the container&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Which troubleshooting steps were already performed to narrow down the problem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The case was filed as “P1: Critical Impact - Service Unusable in production“. This means that the case will “Follow the Sun” by default, to provide 24/7 support (click here to read more about &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/support/docs/procedures#support_case_priority&quot;&gt;support case prioritization&lt;/a&gt;), and at the end of every regional shift will be assigned to the next regional team. In fact, by the time our Zurich-based team got to it, the case had already bounced to the other regional support teams around the world a couple of times. During this time the customer had already put in place a mitigation. But because they hadn’t found the root cause, they were worried that the issue could present itself again in the production system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far, here’s following information we’ve collected:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Content of &lt;code&gt;/etc/hosts&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Content of &lt;code&gt;/etc/resolv.conf&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Output of &lt;code&gt;iptables-save&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pcap file collected using the &lt;code&gt;ngrep&lt;/code&gt; command&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And with all that information, we are ready to start the &quot;sleuthing&quot; part of our troubleshooting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Our first steps&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing we do is check the logs and status of the metadata server to ensure it is working correctly. It is. The metadata server responds to the 169.254.169.254 IP address and is responsible, among other things, for resolving the domain names. We also double check that the firewall rules applied to the VM are correct and not blocking packets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This issue is weird. Until now, our only hypothesis had been that UDP packets are being dropped, but the output of nmap now proves that they are not. We mentally come up with some more hypotheses and ways to verify them:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;1.9822485207101&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are packets being selectively dropped? =&amp;gt; check iptable rules&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;-0.94&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Maximum_transmission_unit&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;MTU&lt;/a&gt; too small? =&amp;gt; check output of &lt;code&gt;ip a show&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is the problem UDP-only or does it also involve TCP? =&amp;gt; run &lt;code&gt;dig +tcp&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are packets generated by dig not coming back? =&amp;gt; run &lt;code&gt;tcpdump&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is libdns working properly? =&amp;gt; run &lt;code&gt;strace&lt;/code&gt; to check it is actually sending and receiving packets&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The current owner of the case asks for suggestions, so we decide to jump on a call with the customer to do some live troubleshooting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the call we test a few more things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;3.5&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We flush iptables rules without success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We check network interfaces and routing tables. We double-check that the MTU is correct.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We find out that &lt;code&gt;dig +tcp google.com&lt;/code&gt; (TCP) works, but &lt;code&gt;dig google.com&lt;/code&gt; (UDP) does not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We run &lt;code&gt;tcpdump&lt;/code&gt; while running &lt;code&gt;“dig”&lt;/code&gt;, and we see that UDP packets are coming back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We run &lt;code&gt;strace dig google.com&lt;/code&gt; and we see that dig correctly calls &lt;code&gt;sendmsg()&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;recvmsg()&lt;/code&gt; but that the latter times out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s the end of our shift, so unfortunately we have to let go of the case to a different timezone. The case is already famous in our team, and a colleague suggests using the python &lt;a href=&quot;https://scapy.net/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;scapy&lt;/a&gt; module to create a raw DNS packet:&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 15:35:25 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>sciurus</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:title>A Google Cloud support engineer solves a tough DNS case | Google Cloud Blog</og:title>
<og:description>How a Google Cloud support engineer found one customer’s missing DNS packets</og:description>
<og:image>https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-cloudblog-publish/images/GCP_11.2083116141672302.max-2200x2200.jpg</og:image>
<og:url>https://cloud.google.com/blog/topics/inside-google-cloud/google-cloud-support-engineer-solves-a-tough-dns-case/</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://cloud.google.com/blog/topics/inside-google-cloud/google-cloud-support-engineer-solves-a-tough-dns-case</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>