<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Dijo: A terminal-based habit tracker written in Rust</title>
<link>https://github.com/NerdyPepper/dijo</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/NerdyPepper/dijo</guid>
<description>&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/6738a3084691b4ae0b2178e96489a049d1247e33/68747470733a2f2f752e70657070652e72732f6c7a2e706e67&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/6738a3084691b4ae0b2178e96489a049d1247e33/68747470733a2f2f752e70657070652e72732f6c7a2e706e67&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://u.peppe.rs/lz.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;About&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;dijo&lt;/code&gt; is a habit tracker. It is curses-based, it runs in your terminal. &lt;code&gt;dijo&lt;/code&gt; is scriptable, hook it up &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/NerdyPepper/dijo/wiki/Auto-Habits&quot;&gt;with external programs&lt;/a&gt; to track events without moving a finger. &lt;code&gt;dijo&lt;/code&gt; is modal, much like a certain text editor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Features&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;vim like motions&lt;/strong&gt;: navigate &lt;code&gt;dijo&lt;/code&gt; with &lt;code&gt;hjkl&lt;/code&gt;!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;dijo&lt;/code&gt; is modal&lt;/strong&gt;: different modes to view different stats!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;vim like command mode&lt;/strong&gt;: add with &lt;code&gt;:add&lt;/code&gt;, delete with &lt;code&gt;:delete&lt;/code&gt; and above all, quit with &lt;code&gt;:q&lt;/code&gt;!.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;fully scriptable&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/NerdyPepper/dijo/blob/master/Auto-Habits&quot;&gt;configure &lt;code&gt;dijo&lt;/code&gt; to track your &lt;code&gt;git&lt;/code&gt; commits&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Install&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get &lt;code&gt;dijo&lt;/code&gt; by running the following at the nearest prompt:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt; dijo requires rustc &amp;gt;= v1.42&lt;/span&gt;
$ rustup update

$ cargo install dijo
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you aren't familiar with &lt;code&gt;cargo&lt;/code&gt; or Rust, read the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/NerdyPepper/dijo/wiki/Install&quot;&gt;complete installation&lt;/a&gt; guide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Usage&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;dijo&lt;/code&gt; has a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/NerdyPepper/dijo/wiki/&quot;&gt;detailed wiki&lt;/a&gt;, here are some good places to start out:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Gallery&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Day mode, shows days of the current month:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/f70606aceda00ea47c198c82f1540a8bcd1c89a3/68747470733a2f2f752e70657070652e72732f71492e706e67&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/f70606aceda00ea47c198c82f1540a8bcd1c89a3/68747470733a2f2f752e70657070652e72732f71492e706e67&quot; alt=&quot;day.png&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://u.peppe.rs/qI.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Week mode, shows weekly summary for the weeks of the month:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/363b82021c1fff14b91d3a6caf45573637a7c6ac/68747470733a2f2f752e70657070652e72732f485a2e706e67&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/363b82021c1fff14b91d3a6caf45573637a7c6ac/68747470733a2f2f752e70657070652e72732f485a2e706e67&quot; alt=&quot;weekly.png&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://u.peppe.rs/HZ.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2020 18:36:53 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>catacombs</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars3.githubusercontent.com/u/23743547?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>NerdyPepper/dijo</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/NerdyPepper/dijo</og:url>
<og:description>scriptable, curses-based, digital habit tracker. Contribute to NerdyPepper/dijo development by creating an account on GitHub.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/NerdyPepper/dijo</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The FBI is secretly using Sabre as a global travel surveillance tool</title>
<link>https://www.forbes.com/sites/thomasbrewster/2020/07/16/the-fbi-is-secretly-using-a-2-billion-company-for-global-travel-surveillance--the-us-could-do-the-same-to-track-covid-19</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.forbes.com/sites/thomasbrewster/2020/07/16/the-fbi-is-secretly-using-a-2-billion-company-for-global-travel-surveillance--the-us-could-do-the-same-to-track-covid-19</guid>
<description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://specials-images.forbesimg.com/imageserve/35368962/960x0.jpg?fit=scale&quot; alt=&quot;Sabre helps US government carry out real-time, global travel surveillance&quot; data-height=&quot;2640&quot; data-width=&quot;3960&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;color-body light-text&quot;&gt;Sabre, a public company on the Nasdaq, has been helping the U.S. government carry out surveillance &lt;span class=&quot;plus&quot; data-ga-track=&quot;caption expand&quot;&gt;... [+]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;expanded-caption&quot;&gt;on suspect travellers since 2001. (Photographer: Scott Eells/Bloomberg)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;small&gt;© 2014 Bloomberg Finance LP&lt;/small&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American border patrol already has significant surveillance powers and collects vast amounts of data on who is flying into and out of the country. But the U.S. has another tool to watch over travellers across the world thanks to a little-known but influential Texan business called Sabre. As the biggest of three companies that store the vast majority of the world’s travel information—from airline seats to hotel bookings — Sabre has been called on to hand over that travellers’ data and, on at least one occasion, do “real-time” tracking of a suspect. And, say former employees, the same powerful trove of information could be used to help monitor the spread of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/coronavirus/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot; class=&quot;color-link&quot; title=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/coronavirus/&quot; data-ga-track=&quot;InternalLink:https://www.forbes.com/coronavirus/&quot; aria-label=&quot;Covid-19 pandemic&quot;&gt;Covid-19 pandemic&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To understand how Sabre, which is publicly traded on NASDAQ with a $2 billion plus market cap, came to control such a vast trove of data, you have to go back to the mid-1950s, the very beginnings of what would become the booming - though currently beleaguered - travel industry. In American Airlines offices, bookings staff would take calls sitting at large round tables mounted by a Byzantine-looking contraption: a huge lazy Susan, full of cubbyholes. In each were filed index cards, little records of every separate travel booking, the whole system designed to keep track of who had booked what seat for when. Thanks to predictable human error, it led to inaccurate records, over- and under-booked flights, and peeved travellers who were hoping to explore the world at their leisure in the postwar era of American expansionism and openness. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make the system more efficient and accurate, American turned to the nascent computer industry, calling on IBM and MIT scientists to build the industry’s first “passenger name record,” a vast database of travel bookings that could be updated and tracked at far greater efficiency. American Airlines dubbed the system the Semi-Automated Business Research Environment and Sabre was born, going live on two IBM mainframes in 1964. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The system worked so well that Sabre would later become its own company and expand to cover other airlines. It would grow further, becoming even more vital to the industry by tracking not just airline bookings but almost anything to do with travel, from the hotel to the rental car. Anyone who’s ever booked a holiday will likely have been facilitated by the Texan company’s technology. It processes well over a third of all air travel bookings in the world, amounting to more than $260 billion worth of global travel spend annually. It’s vast too, with 9,000 employees today (though workers are being laid off and Sabre’s value has dipped thanks to the severe damage wrought by the Covid-19 pandemic). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s the biggest of just three players who dominate the hidden connecting tissue of the travel market - known in the industry as “global distribution systems” - the other two being Madrid-based Amadeus and the British Travelport. Together they sit on huge networks and databases full of information on the world’s travel plans: itineraries, fares, reservations, connecting flights and ticket costs are all there, as are crew schedules and other logistical information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“They have [built] up humongous databases,” says Gloria Guevara, former CEO of Sabre’s Mexican business, now chief executive of the World Travel &amp;amp; Tourism Council (WTTC). She recalls that when she was at Sabre, between 1995 and 2010, it had one of the top two largest privately-owned databases in the world. “They could tell you where [a traveller] came from and the flight that they were on, where they were sitting. Sabre maintains those records,” adds Jim Menge, another former Sabre VP from 1994 to 2004.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sabre’s US government assistance&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Publicly, Sabre’s entanglement with the U.S. government has been apparent for some time. Former CEOs have given testimony to Congressional panels and made it onto presidential committees. Then there’s the secret side of the relationship. Stretching back to at least the 2001 September 11 terror attacks, the government has, on numerous occasions, secretly asked the company to actively spy on suspects’ movements, in both major and minor criminal cases. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For years, the government has asked telecom giants and banks to help track individuals worldwide, whether through tapping calls or sharing the location of bank withdrawals. But with Sabre, it has a particularly powerful snooping option. With financial institutions or the telecoms industry, the government has to go to each separate bank or operator and serve an order on them. It could take a similar approach with the travel industry, asking each airline, hotel and booking agent. But with Sabre, or one of its two chief competitors, it can serve one order to cover all bases. That’s one explanation as to why the company played a role in assisting the U.S. in tracking the movements of the 9/11 hijackers after the attacks on the Twin Towers, as Guevara and Menge tell &lt;em&gt;Forbes&lt;/em&gt;. (Sabre didn’t respond to requests for comment).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In that case, the government came knocking only after the atrocity had occurred. But, as detailed in one international cybercrime investigation, Sabre can be compelled to proactively watch and report on a persons’ whereabouts as soon as they start travelling. In an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/6989724-All-Writs-Act-Order-on-Sabre-to-Give-Real-Time.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;color-link&quot; title=&quot;https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/6989724-All-Writs-Act-Order-on-Sabre-to-Give-Real-Time.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot; data-ga-track=&quot;ExternalLink:https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/6989724-All-Writs-Act-Order-on-Sabre-to-Give-Real-Time.html&quot; aria-label=&quot;order from December 2019&quot;&gt;order from December 2019&lt;/a&gt;, feds asked Sabre to provide the FBI with “real-time” updates on the travel activities of a hacking suspect, an Indian fugitive called Deepanshu Kher. Sabre was told to provide “complete and contemporaneous ‘real time’ account activity information of the traveler [Kher] on a weekly basis” for six months. Sabre would provide “any travel orders, transactions or reservations” for the suspect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s little information about Kher’s case; an indictment from November 2019 simply notes he was charged with attacking the computer hosting a website of an unnamed San Diego company, causing more than $5,000 in damage. Now under home arrest, Kher was apprehended in January and has pleaded not guilty to one charge of intentional damage to a protected computer. (His legal counsel didn’t respond to requests for comment. The Justice Department declined to comment.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The order is one of at least four where Sabre agreed to provide such traveller information. In 2015, the FBI was hunting down Aleksei Yurievich Burkov, whom investigators believed was running Cardplanet, a $20 million bazaar for buying and selling stolen credit card data. To track him down, the U.S. government told not just Sabre, but also the U.K.-based, New York Stock Exchange-listed Travelport to provide records on the Russian. That’s according to a brief note on the court docket (a list of events in the course of a court case) for the Burkov case. Further details are under seal. Burkov was extradited from Israel in November 2019 and pleaded guilty to charges of fraud, identity theft, computer intrusion, wire fraud and money laundering in January.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The latest order on Sabre also notes the company had previously complied with three similar orders to “assist in effectuating arrest warrants”: two in the Western District of Washington in 2017 and 2019, another in the Northern District of California in 2016. Again, the documents remain under seal. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;‘Unusual and excessive’&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Legal experts tell &lt;em&gt;Forbes&lt;/em&gt; that not only does the Kher order appear unprecedented and disturbing in showing how secretive the snooping operations have been, it is also legally questionable, due to its application of a 1789 law known as the All Writs Act. The law allows the U.S. to force third parties into providing assistance to execute a prior order of the court. Many will remember the Act from its most infamous case in 2016, when &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/mattdrange/2016/03/28/fbi-gets-into-san-bernardino-iphone-without-apples-help-court-vacates-order/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot; class=&quot;color-link&quot; title=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/mattdrange/2016/03/28/fbi-gets-into-san-bernardino-iphone-without-apples-help-court-vacates-order/&quot; data-ga-track=&quot;InternalLink:https://www.forbes.com/sites/mattdrange/2016/03/28/fbi-gets-into-san-bernardino-iphone-without-apples-help-court-vacates-order/&quot; aria-label=&quot;the government tried to have Apple unlock an iPhone&quot;&gt;the government tried to have Apple unlock an iPhone&lt;/a&gt; of the shooter in the San Bernardino terror incident of 2015. In that case Apple fought the government, which eventually stopped chasing the Cupertino company after a hacker found a way onto the iPhone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marc Zwillinger, who represented Apple in that case, warns the order threatens to turn Sabre into an “agent” of law enforcement. “It struck me as unusual and excessive… I'd be concerned that the government will now use this as a matter of course every time they want to track a fugitive,” says Zwillinger, whose past clients also include Yahoo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://specials-images.forbesimg.com/imageserve/499962860/960x0.jpg?fit=scale&quot; alt=&quot;Community Mourns As Investigation Continues Into San Bernardino Mass Shooting&quot; data-height=&quot;2082&quot; data-width=&quot;3000&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;color-body light-text&quot;&gt;The San Bernardino terror attack on December 4, 2015, led to an FBI tussle with Apple over the &lt;span class=&quot;plus&quot; data-ga-track=&quot;caption expand&quot;&gt;... [+]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;expanded-caption&quot;&gt;application of an old law called the All Writs Act to force the tech company into helping gain access to the shooter's iPhone. (Photo by Joe Raedle/Getty Images)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;small&gt;Getty Images&lt;/small&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He says that if it wants to leverage the All Writs Act, the government has to show a third party is necessary and close enough to the matter at hand. With Sabre, given there were other ways of getting the information on Kher’s travel, such as records of him entering the U.S. via Customs and Border Protection databases, that necessity was questionable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are also questions on the “reasonableness of the burden” on Sabre, another requirement for All Writs Act orders, he adds. “In one particular order, it might not be that burdensome, but once you start to get some volume here, then it really turns Sabre into a sort of … government agent every time they want to find a fugitive.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Covid-19 tracking&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sabre’s valuable database could soon go from hunting fugitives to stopping an invisible virus. The same data tap that’s been turned on by the FBI could prove a boon for the U.S. government in surveilling the spread of the Covid-19 pandemic, providing a constant and accurate record of the movements of global populations. It would be possible, for instance, to see how many people flew to New York from Wuhan, and through which airports they travelled. “They can say here's how many people are travelling from China, whether it's nonstop via Japan, via Taiwan, Hawaii, Guam, you know, all of these secondary points back to the US,” says Menge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sabre hasn’t revealed any such plans. Such secrecy only means more questions about how deep Sabre and the U.S. government’s ties go and how often the All Writs Act has forced it into becoming an arm of America’s globe-spanning intelligence operations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No one really knows just how often or widely the government has used the All Writs Act to force companies into surveillance, says Riana Pfefferkorn, associate director of surveillance and cybersecurity at the Stanford Center for Internet and Society. “As long as the government can get away with secret orders to companies that don't fight back, and judges continue to sign off on the orders the government drafts for them, we won't know.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/thomasbrewster/2020/07/13/inside-americas-secretive-2-billion-research-hub-collecting-fingerprints-from-facebook-hacking-smartwatches-and-fighting-covid-19/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot; class=&quot;color-link&quot; title=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/thomasbrewster/2020/07/13/inside-americas-secretive-2-billion-research-hub-collecting-fingerprints-from-facebook-hacking-smartwatches-and-fighting-covid-19/&quot; data-ga-track=&quot;InternalLink:https://www.forbes.com/sites/thomasbrewster/2020/07/13/inside-americas-secretive-2-billion-research-hub-collecting-fingerprints-from-facebook-hacking-smartwatches-and-fighting-covid-19/&quot; aria-label=&quot;READ MORE: Inside America’s Secretive $2 Billion Research Hub Collecting Fingerprints From Facebook, Hacking Smartwatches And Fighting Covid-19&quot;&gt;&lt;strong data-ga-track=&quot;InternalLink:https://www.forbes.com/sites/thomasbrewster/2020/07/13/inside-americas-secretive-2-billion-research-hub-collecting-fingerprints-from-facebook-hacking-smartwatches-and-fighting-covid-19/&quot;&gt;&lt;em data-ga-track=&quot;InternalLink:https://www.forbes.com/sites/thomasbrewster/2020/07/13/inside-americas-secretive-2-billion-research-hub-collecting-fingerprints-from-facebook-hacking-smartwatches-and-fighting-covid-19/&quot;&gt;READ MORE: Inside America’s Secretive $2 Billion Research Hub Collecting Fingerprints From Facebook, Hacking Smartwatches And Fighting Covid-19&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2020 17:14:01 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>AndrewBissell</dc:creator>
<og:title>The FBI Is Secretly Using A $2 Billion Travel Company As A Global Surveillance Tool</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.forbes.com/sites/thomasbrewster/2020/07/16/the-fbi-is-secretly-using-a-2-billion-company-for-global-travel-surveillance--the-us-could-do-the-same-to-track-covid-19/</og:url>
<og:image>https://thumbor.forbes.com/thumbor/fit-in/1200x0/filters%3Aformat%28jpg%29/https%3A%2F%2Fspecials-images.forbesimg.com%2Fimageserve%2F35368962%2F0x0.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>An unprecedented order on a huge travel company reveals how the FBI tracks suspects around the world.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.forbes.com/sites/thomasbrewster/2020/07/16/the-fbi-is-secretly-using-a-2-billion-company-for-global-travel-surveillance--the-us-could-do-the-same-to-track-covid-19/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Reasonably priced color e-ink display</title>
<link>https://www.waveshare.com/5.65inch-e-paper-module-f.htm</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.waveshare.com/5.65inch-e-paper-module-f.htm</guid>
<description>&lt;div readability=&quot;15&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5.65&quot; &lt;span class=&quot;hilitColor&quot;&gt;7-Color&lt;/span&gt; e-Paper Module&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;richDesc&quot;&gt;low power consumption, wide viewing angle, paper-like displaying without electricity&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;hilitBlock2&quot;&gt;Ideal for price tags, shelf labels, industrial instruments...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.waveshare.com/img/devkit/LCD/5.65inch-e-Paper-Module-F/5.65inch-e-Paper-Module-F-details-1.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Features at a glance&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bgGrey alignl subBlock mgnTB&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Advanced Color ePaper (ACeP) technology, supports 7-Color display&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No backlight, keeps displaying last content for a long time even when power down&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ultra low power consumption, basically power is only required for refreshing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SPI interface, for connecting with controller boards like Raspberry Pi/Jetson Nano/Arduino/STM32, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Onboard voltage translator, compatible with 3.3V / 5V MCUs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Comes with development resources and manual (examples for Raspberry Pi/Jetson Nano/Arduino/STM32)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Specifications&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class=&quot;tabSty-2 mgnTB&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;operating voltage&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.3V/5V&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;th&gt;display color&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ACeP 7-Color&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;interface&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3-wire SPI, 4-wire SPI&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;th&gt;grey scale&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;outline dimensions&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td&gt;138.5 × 100.5mm&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;th&gt;full refresh time&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td&gt;15s&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;display size&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td&gt;114.9 × 85.8mm&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;th&gt;refresh power&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td&gt;50mW (typ.)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;dot pitch&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.1915 × 0.1915mm&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;th&gt;standby current&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;lt;0.01uA (almost none)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;resolution&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td&gt;600 × 448 pixels&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;th&gt;viewing angle&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;gt;170°&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;15&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advantages of EINK&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;alignl subBlock&quot;&gt;E-paper display utilizes microcapsule electrophoretic technology for displaying, the principle is: charged particles suspended in clear fluid will move to sides of microcapsule when electric field is applied, making the microcapsule become visible by reflecting ambient light, just as traditional printed paper.&lt;br/&gt;E-paper display will clearly display images/texts under lamplight or natural light, requires no backlight, and features nearly up to 180° viewing angle. It is usually used as e-reader due to its paper-like effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.waveshare.com/img/devkit/LCD/common/epaper-advantage.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SPI control interface&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;richDesc&quot;&gt;supports control boards including Raspberry Pi/Jetson Nano/Arduino/STM32...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.waveshare.com/img/devkit/LCD/5.65inch-e-Paper-Module-F/5.65inch-e-Paper-Module-F-details-3.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Multiple voltage level support&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;richDesc&quot;&gt;Onboard voltage translator, compatible with 3.3V / 5V MCUs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.waveshare.com/img/devkit/LCD/5.65inch-e-Paper-Module-F/5.65inch-e-Paper-Module-F-details-5.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Application examples&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;richDesc&quot;&gt;Suitable for price Tags, asset/equipment Tags, shelf labels, conference name tags...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.waveshare.com/img/devkit/LCD/common/epaper-app.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outline dimensions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.waveshare.com/img/devkit/LCD/5.65inch-e-Paper-Module-F/5.65inch-e-Paper-Module-F-details-size.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;6.65625&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resources &amp;amp; Services&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.waveshare.com/img/devkit/LCD/common/res_banner.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;bgGrey&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.waveshare.com/img/devkit/LCD/common/res_content.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;subBlock alignl&quot;&gt;* Resources for different product may vary, please check the wiki page to confirm the actually provided resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2020 15:06:45 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>zdw</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.waveshare.com/5.65inch-e-paper-module-f.htm</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Mars images rendered in 4K [video]</title>
<link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZEyAs3NWH4A</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZEyAs3NWH4A</guid>
<description>&lt;!-- end of chunk --&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;player&quot; class=&quot;skeleton flexy&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div id=&quot;player-wrap&quot;&gt;
        
            &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;!-- end of chunk --&gt;&lt;ytd-app disable-upgrade=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;ytd-masthead id=&quot;masthead&quot; slot=&quot;masthead&quot; class=&quot;shell  chunked&quot; disable-upgrade=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;svg id=&quot;menu-icon&quot; class=&quot;external-icon&quot; preserveaspectratio=&quot;xMidYMid meet&quot;&gt;&lt;g id=&quot;menu&quot; class=&quot;yt-icons-ext&quot; viewbox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot;&gt;&lt;path d=&quot;M3 18h18v-2H3v2zm0-5h18v-2H3v2zm0-7v2h18V6H3z&quot;/&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;masthead-logo&quot; slot=&quot;masthead-logo&quot;&gt;  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;svg id=&quot;yt-logo-svg&quot; class=&quot;external-icon&quot; viewbox=&quot;0 0 200 60&quot;&gt;&lt;g id=&quot;yt-logo&quot; viewbox=&quot;0 0 200 60&quot; preserveaspectratio=&quot;xMidYMid meet&quot;&gt;&lt;g&gt;&lt;path fill=&quot;#FF0000&quot; d=&quot;M63,14.87c-0.72-2.7-2.85-4.83-5.56-5.56C52.54,8,32.88,8,32.88,8S13.23,8,8.32,9.31&amp;#10;            c-2.7,0.72-4.83,2.85-5.56,5.56C1.45,19.77,1.45,30,1.45,30s0,10.23,1.31,15.13c0.72,2.7,2.85,4.83,5.56,5.56&amp;#10;            C13.23,52,32.88,52,32.88,52s19.66,0,24.56-1.31c2.7-0.72,4.83-2.85,5.56-5.56C64.31,40.23,64.31,30,64.31,30&amp;#10;            S64.31,19.77,63,14.87z&quot;/&gt;&lt;polygon fill=&quot;#FFFFFF&quot; points=&quot;26.6,39.43 42.93,30 26.6,20.57&quot;/&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;g&gt;&lt;g id=&quot;youtube-paths&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill=&quot;#282828&quot; d=&quot;M92.69,48.03c-1.24-0.84-2.13-2.14-2.65-3.91c-0.52-1.77-0.79-4.12-0.79-7.06v-4&amp;#10;              c0-2.97,0.3-5.35,0.9-7.15c0.6-1.8,1.54-3.11,2.81-3.93c1.27-0.82,2.94-1.24,5.01-1.24c2.04,0,3.67,0.42,4.9,1.26&amp;#10;              c1.23,0.84,2.13,2.15,2.7,3.93c0.57,1.78,0.85,4.16,0.85,7.12v4c0,2.94-0.28,5.3-0.83,7.08c-0.55,1.78-1.45,3.09-2.7,3.91&amp;#10;              c-1.24,0.82-2.93,1.24-5.06,1.24C95.65,49.29,93.93,48.87,92.69,48.03z M99.66,43.71c0.34-0.9,0.52-2.37,0.52-4.4v-8.59&amp;#10;              c0-1.98-0.17-3.42-0.52-4.34c-0.34-0.91-0.95-1.37-1.82-1.37c-0.84,0-1.43,0.46-1.78,1.37c-0.34,0.91-0.52,2.36-0.52,4.34v8.59&amp;#10;              c0,2.04,0.16,3.51,0.49,4.4c0.33,0.9,0.93,1.35,1.8,1.35C98.71,45.06,99.31,44.61,99.66,43.71z&quot;/&gt;&lt;path fill=&quot;#282828&quot; d=&quot;M188.16,37.13v1.39c0,1.77,0.05,3.09,0.16,3.98c0.1,0.88,0.32,1.53,0.65,1.93&amp;#10;              c0.33,0.4,0.84,0.61,1.53,0.61c0.93,0,1.57-0.36,1.91-1.08c0.34-0.72,0.53-1.92,0.56-3.6l5.35,0.31&amp;#10;              c0.03,0.24,0.04,0.57,0.04,0.99c0,2.55-0.7,4.45-2.09,5.71c-1.39,1.26-3.36,1.89-5.91,1.89c-3.06,0-5.2-0.96-6.43-2.88&amp;#10;              c-1.23-1.92-1.84-4.88-1.84-8.9v-4.81c0-4.14,0.64-7.15,1.91-9.06c1.27-1.9,3.45-2.85,6.54-2.85c2.13,0,3.76,0.39,4.9,1.17&amp;#10;              c1.14,0.78,1.94,1.99,2.41,3.64c0.46,1.65,0.7,3.93,0.7,6.83v4.72H188.16z M188.95,25.53c-0.31,0.39-0.52,1.03-0.63,1.91&amp;#10;              c-0.11,0.88-0.16,2.23-0.16,4.02v1.98h4.54v-1.98c0-1.77-0.06-3.11-0.18-4.02c-0.12-0.91-0.34-1.56-0.65-1.93&amp;#10;              c-0.31-0.37-0.8-0.56-1.46-0.56C189.75,24.94,189.26,25.14,188.95,25.53z&quot;/&gt;&lt;path fill=&quot;#282828&quot; d=&quot;M77.59,36.61l-7.06-25.49h6.16l2.47,11.55c0.63,2.85,1.09,5.27,1.39,7.28h0.18&amp;#10;              c0.21-1.44,0.67-3.85,1.39-7.24l2.56-11.6h6.16L83.7,36.61v12.23h-6.11V36.61z&quot;/&gt;&lt;path fill=&quot;#282828&quot; d=&quot;M126.45,21.28v27.55h-4.85l-0.54-3.37h-0.13c-1.32,2.55-3.3,3.82-5.93,3.82c-1.83,0-3.18-0.6-4.05-1.8&amp;#10;              c-0.87-1.2-1.3-3.07-1.3-5.62V21.28h6.2v20.23c0,1.23,0.13,2.11,0.4,2.63c0.27,0.52,0.72,0.79,1.35,0.79&amp;#10;              c0.54,0,1.06-0.16,1.55-0.49c0.49-0.33,0.86-0.75,1.1-1.26V21.28H126.45z&quot;/&gt;&lt;path fill=&quot;#282828&quot; d=&quot;M158.27,21.28v27.55h-4.85l-0.54-3.37h-0.13c-1.32,2.55-3.3,3.82-5.93,3.82c-1.83,0-3.18-0.6-4.05-1.8&amp;#10;              c-0.87-1.2-1.3-3.07-1.3-5.62V21.28h6.2v20.23c0,1.23,0.13,2.11,0.4,2.63c0.27,0.52,0.72,0.79,1.35,0.79&amp;#10;              c0.54,0,1.06-0.16,1.55-0.49c0.49-0.33,0.86-0.75,1.1-1.26V21.28H158.27z&quot;/&gt;&lt;path fill=&quot;#282828&quot; d=&quot;M143.31,16.11h-6.16v32.72h-6.07V16.11h-6.16v-4.99h18.38V16.11z&quot;/&gt;&lt;path fill=&quot;#282828&quot; d=&quot;M178.8,25.69c-0.38-1.74-0.98-3-1.82-3.78c-0.84-0.78-1.99-1.17-3.46-1.17c-1.14,0-2.2,0.32-3.19,0.97&amp;#10;              c-0.99,0.64-1.75,1.49-2.29,2.54h-0.05l0-14.52h-5.98v39.11h5.12l0.63-2.61h0.13c0.48,0.93,1.2,1.66,2.16,2.2&amp;#10;              c0.96,0.54,2.02,0.81,3.19,0.81c2.1,0,3.64-0.97,4.63-2.9c0.99-1.93,1.48-4.95,1.48-9.06v-4.36&amp;#10;              C179.36,29.84,179.17,27.43,178.8,25.69z M173.11,36.93c0,2.01-0.08,3.58-0.25,4.72c-0.16,1.14-0.44,1.95-0.83,2.43&amp;#10;              c-0.39,0.48-0.91,0.72-1.57,0.72c-0.51,0-0.98-0.12-1.42-0.36c-0.43-0.24-0.79-0.6-1.06-1.08V27.71&amp;#10;              c0.21-0.75,0.57-1.36,1.08-1.84c0.51-0.48,1.06-0.72,1.66-0.72c0.63,0,1.12,0.25,1.46,0.74c0.34,0.49,0.58,1.33,0.72,2.49&amp;#10;              c0.13,1.17,0.2,2.83,0.2,4.99V36.93z&quot;/&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;svg id=&quot;yt-logo-red-svg&quot; class=&quot;external-icon&quot; viewbox=&quot;0 0 98 24&quot;&gt;&lt;g id=&quot;yt-logo-red&quot; viewbox=&quot;0 0 98 24&quot; preserveaspectratio=&quot;xMidYMid meet&quot;&gt;&lt;g&gt;&lt;path fill=&quot;#FF0000&quot; d=&quot;M28.4,5.12c-0.34-1.24-1.31-2.2-2.55-2.52C23.62,2,14.68,2,14.68,2S5.75,2,3.52,2.6&amp;#10;            C2.29,2.93,1.33,3.89,1,5.12C0.59,7.39,0.39,9.69,0.4,12c-0.01,2.31,0.19,4.61,0.6,6.88c0.33,1.23,1.29,2.19,2.52,2.52&amp;#10;            C5.75,22,14.68,22,14.68,22s8.93,0,11.16-0.6c1.24-0.32,2.22-1.28,2.56-2.52c0.41-2.27,0.61-4.57,0.6-6.88&amp;#10;            C29.01,9.69,28.81,7.39,28.4,5.12z&quot;/&gt;&lt;polygon fill=&quot;#FFFFFF&quot; points=&quot;11.83,16.29 19.25,12 11.83,7.71&quot;/&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;g id=&quot;youtube-red-paths&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill=&quot;#282828&quot; d=&quot;M41.67,8.35V9c0,3.45-1.53,5.48-4.88,5.48h-0.51v6h-2.74V3.42h3.49C40.22,3.42,41.67,4.77,41.67,8.35z&amp;#10;            M38.79,8.6c0-2.49-0.45-3.09-2-3.09h-0.51v7h0.47c1.47,0,2-1.06,2-3.37L38.79,8.6z&quot;/&gt;&lt;path fill=&quot;#282828&quot; d=&quot;M48.14,7.83L48,11.08c-1.17-0.24-2.13-0.08-2.6,0.69v8.78h-2.67V8h2.17l0.24,2.71h0.1c0.28-2,1.2-3,2.39-3&amp;#10;            C47.8,7.73,47.98,7.77,48.14,7.83z&quot;/&gt;&lt;path fill=&quot;#282828&quot; d=&quot;M51.27,15.25v0.63c0,2.21,0.12,3,1.06,3s1.1-0.69,1.12-2.12l2.43,0.14c0.18,2.7-1.23,3.9-3.61,3.9&amp;#10;            c-2.9,0-3.76-1.9-3.76-5.35v-2.23c0-3.64,1-5.41,3.84-5.41s3.64,1.51,3.64,5.29v2.15H51.27z M51.27,12.67v0.9h2.06v-0.89&amp;#10;            c0-2.3-0.16-3-1-3s-1,0.67-1,3L51.27,12.67z&quot;/&gt;&lt;path fill=&quot;#282828&quot; d=&quot;M70.02,11.1v9.46H67.2v-9.25c0-1-0.27-1.53-0.88-1.53c-0.54,0.02-1.02,0.34-1.25,0.82&amp;#10;            c0.01,0.17,0.01,0.34,0,0.51v9.46h-2.79v-9.26c0-1-0.27-1.53-0.88-1.53c-0.53,0.02-1,0.33-1.23,0.8v10H57.4V8h2.23l0.25,1.59l0,0&amp;#10;            c0.51-1.12,1.63-1.85,2.86-1.86c1.05-0.07,1.98,0.67,2.16,1.7c0.55-1.01,1.61-1.65,2.76-1.66C69.4,7.78,70.02,9,70.02,11.1z&quot;/&gt;&lt;path fill=&quot;#282828&quot; d=&quot;M71.4,4.83c0-1.35,0.49-1.74,1.53-1.74s1.53,0.45,1.53,1.74s-0.47,1.74-1.53,1.74S71.4,6.22,71.4,4.83z&amp;#10;            M71.59,8h2.7v12.56h-2.7V8z&quot;/&gt;&lt;path fill=&quot;#282828&quot; d=&quot;M83.5,8v12.56h-2.2L81.05,19h-0.06c-0.46,1.08-1.53,1.77-2.7,1.74c-1.67,0-2.43-1.06-2.43-3.37V8h2.82&amp;#10;            v9.19c0,1.1,0.23,1.55,0.8,1.55c0.52-0.02,0.98-0.33,1.2-0.8V8H83.5z&quot;/&gt;&lt;path fill=&quot;#282828&quot; d=&quot;M97.8,11.1v9.46h-2.82v-9.25c0-1-0.27-1.53-0.88-1.53c-0.54,0.02-1.02,0.34-1.25,0.82&amp;#10;            c0.01,0.17,0.01,0.34,0,0.51v9.46h-2.79v-9.26c0-1-0.27-1.53-0.88-1.53c-0.53,0.02-1,0.33-1.23,0.8v10h-2.81V8h2.26l0.24,1.59l0,0&amp;#10;            c0.51-1.12,1.63-1.85,2.86-1.86c1.04-0.07,1.97,0.64,2.17,1.66c0.55-0.99,1.6-1.61,2.73-1.62C97.15,7.78,97.8,9,97.8,11.1z&quot;/&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;country-code&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;masthead-skeleton-icons&quot; slot=&quot;masthead-skeleton&quot;/&gt;&lt;/ytd-masthead&gt;&lt;a slot=&quot;guide-links-primary&quot; href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/about/&quot;&gt;About&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a slot=&quot;guide-links-primary&quot; href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/about/press/&quot;&gt;Press&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a slot=&quot;guide-links-primary&quot; href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/about/copyright/&quot;&gt;Copyright&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a slot=&quot;guide-links-primary&quot; href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/t/contact_us&quot;&gt;Contact us&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a slot=&quot;guide-links-primary&quot; href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/creators/&quot;&gt;Creators&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a slot=&quot;guide-links-primary&quot; href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/ads/&quot;&gt;Advertise&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a slot=&quot;guide-links-primary&quot; href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/youtube&quot;&gt;Developers&lt;/a&gt;

      &lt;a slot=&quot;guide-links-secondary&quot; href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/t/terms&quot;&gt;Terms&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a slot=&quot;guide-links-secondary&quot; href=&quot;https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/&quot;&gt;Privacy&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a slot=&quot;guide-links-secondary&quot; href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/about/policies/&quot;&gt;Policy &amp;amp; Safety&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a slot=&quot;guide-links-secondary&quot; href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/howyoutubeworks&quot;&gt;How YouTube works&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a slot=&quot;guide-links-secondary&quot; href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/new&quot;&gt;Test new features&lt;/a&gt;

      

      &lt;div id=&quot;copyright&quot; slot=&quot;copyright&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;© 2020 Google LLC&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;/ytd-app&gt;&lt;!-- end of chunk --&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;watch-page-skeleton&quot; class=&quot;watch-skeleton &quot;&gt;
    &lt;div id=&quot;container&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div id=&quot;related&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;autoplay skeleton-light-border-bottom&quot;&gt;
          
            &lt;div class=&quot;video-skeleton&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;video-details&quot;&gt;
      
      &lt;div class=&quot;details flex-1&quot;&gt;
        
        
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;video-skeleton&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;video-details&quot;&gt;
      
      &lt;div class=&quot;details flex-1&quot;&gt;
        
        
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

            &lt;div class=&quot;video-skeleton&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;video-details&quot;&gt;
      
      &lt;div class=&quot;details flex-1&quot;&gt;
        
        
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

            &lt;div class=&quot;video-skeleton&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;video-details&quot;&gt;
      
      &lt;div class=&quot;details flex-1&quot;&gt;
        
        
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

            &lt;div class=&quot;video-skeleton&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;video-details&quot;&gt;
      
      &lt;div class=&quot;details flex-1&quot;&gt;
        
        
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

            &lt;div class=&quot;video-skeleton&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;video-details&quot;&gt;
      
      &lt;div class=&quot;details flex-1&quot;&gt;
        
        
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

            &lt;div class=&quot;video-skeleton&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;video-details&quot;&gt;
      
      &lt;div class=&quot;details flex-1&quot;&gt;
        
        
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

            &lt;div class=&quot;video-skeleton&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;video-details&quot;&gt;
      
      &lt;div class=&quot;details flex-1&quot;&gt;
        
        
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

            &lt;div class=&quot;video-skeleton&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;video-details&quot;&gt;
      
      &lt;div class=&quot;details flex-1&quot;&gt;
        
        
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

            &lt;div class=&quot;video-skeleton&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;video-details&quot;&gt;
      
      &lt;div class=&quot;details flex-1&quot;&gt;
        
        
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div id=&quot;info-container&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div id=&quot;primary-info&quot; class=&quot;skeleton-light-border-bottom&quot;&gt;
          
          &lt;div id=&quot;info&quot;&gt;
            
            
            &lt;div id=&quot;menu&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
            &lt;/div&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div id=&quot;secondary-info&quot; class=&quot;skeleton-light-border-bottom&quot;&gt;
          &lt;div id=&quot;top-row&quot;&gt;
            &lt;div id=&quot;video-owner&quot; class=&quot;flex-1&quot;&gt;
              
              &lt;div id=&quot;upload-info&quot; class=&quot;flex-1&quot;&gt;
                
                
              &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
            
          &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

    &lt;link rel=&quot;canonical&quot; href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZEyAs3NWH4A&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;alternate&quot; media=&quot;handheld&quot; href=&quot;https://m.youtube.com/watch?v=ZEyAs3NWH4A&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;alternate&quot; media=&quot;only screen and (max-width: 640px)&quot; href=&quot;https://m.youtube.com/watch?v=ZEyAs3NWH4A&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;theme-color&quot; content=&quot;#ff0000&quot;/&gt;&lt;title&gt;New: Mars In 4K - YouTube&lt;/title&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;title&quot; content=&quot;New: Mars In 4K&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;description&quot; content=&quot;A world first. New footage from Mars rendered in stunning 4K resolution. We also talk about the cameras on board the Martian rovers and how we made the video...&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;keywords&quot; content=&quot;mars in 4k, elderfox, elder fox, 2020 mars footage&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;alternate&quot; href=&quot;android-app://com.google.android.youtube/http/www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZEyAs3NWH4A&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;alternate&quot; href=&quot;ios-app://544007664/vnd.youtube/www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZEyAs3NWH4A&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;alternate&quot; type=&quot;application/json+oembed&quot; href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/oembed?format=json&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3DZEyAs3NWH4A&quot; title=&quot;New: Mars In 4K&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;alternate&quot; type=&quot;text/xml+oembed&quot; href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/oembed?format=xml&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3DZEyAs3NWH4A&quot; title=&quot;New: Mars In 4K&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;image_src&quot; href=&quot;https://i.ytimg.com/vi/ZEyAs3NWH4A/maxresdefault.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:site_name&quot; content=&quot;YouTube&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:url&quot; content=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZEyAs3NWH4A&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:title&quot; content=&quot;New: Mars In 4K&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:image&quot; content=&quot;https://i.ytimg.com/vi/ZEyAs3NWH4A/maxresdefault.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:image:width&quot; content=&quot;1280&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:image:height&quot; content=&quot;720&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:description&quot; content=&quot;A world first. New footage from Mars rendered in stunning 4K resolution. We also talk about the cameras on board the Martian rovers and how we made the video...&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;al:ios:app_store_id&quot; content=&quot;544007664&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;al:ios:app_name&quot; content=&quot;YouTube&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;al:ios:url&quot; content=&quot;vnd.youtube://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZEyAs3NWH4A&amp;amp;feature=applinks&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;al:android:url&quot; content=&quot;vnd.youtube://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZEyAs3NWH4A&amp;amp;feature=applinks&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;al:android:app_name&quot; content=&quot;YouTube&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;al:android:package&quot; content=&quot;com.google.android.youtube&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;al:web:url&quot; content=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZEyAs3NWH4A&amp;amp;feature=applinks&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:type&quot; content=&quot;video.other&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:video:url&quot; content=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZEyAs3NWH4A&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:video:secure_url&quot; content=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZEyAs3NWH4A&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:video:type&quot; content=&quot;text/html&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:video:width&quot; content=&quot;1280&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:video:height&quot; content=&quot;720&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:video:tag&quot; content=&quot;mars in 4k&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:video:tag&quot; content=&quot;elderfox&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:video:tag&quot; content=&quot;elder fox&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:video:tag&quot; content=&quot;2020 mars footage&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;fb:app_id&quot; content=&quot;87741124305&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:card&quot; content=&quot;player&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:site&quot; content=&quot;@youtube&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:url&quot; content=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZEyAs3NWH4A&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:title&quot; content=&quot;New: Mars In 4K&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:description&quot; content=&quot;A world first. New footage from Mars rendered in stunning 4K resolution. We also talk about the cameras on board the Martian rovers and how we made the video...&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:image&quot; content=&quot;https://i.ytimg.com/vi/ZEyAs3NWH4A/maxresdefault.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:app:name:iphone&quot; content=&quot;YouTube&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:app:id:iphone&quot; content=&quot;544007664&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:app:name:ipad&quot; content=&quot;YouTube&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:app:id:ipad&quot; content=&quot;544007664&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:app:url:iphone&quot; content=&quot;vnd.youtube://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZEyAs3NWH4A&amp;amp;feature=applinks&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:app:url:ipad&quot; content=&quot;vnd.youtube://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZEyAs3NWH4A&amp;amp;feature=applinks&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:app:name:googleplay&quot; content=&quot;YouTube&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:app:id:googleplay&quot; content=&quot;com.google.android.youtube&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:app:url:googleplay&quot; content=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZEyAs3NWH4A&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:player&quot; content=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZEyAs3NWH4A&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:player:width&quot; content=&quot;1280&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:player:height&quot; content=&quot;720&quot;/&gt;

      </description>
<pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2020 14:32:10 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>oscarpaz</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZEyAs3NWH4A</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Coronavirus: Oxford vaccine triggers immune response</title>
<link>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-53469839</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-53469839</guid>
<description>&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape no-caption full-width lead&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                &lt;img class=&quot;js-image-replace&quot; alt=&quot;Woman being vaccinated&quot; src=&quot;https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/320/cpsprodpb/14FA4/production/_113542958_clinic-injection04--credit-.jpg&quot; width=&quot;976&quot; height=&quot;549&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image copyright&lt;/span&gt;
                 &lt;span class=&quot;story-image-copyright&quot;&gt;Oxford University&lt;/span&gt;
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
        &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;story-body__introduction&quot;&gt;A coronavirus vaccine developed by the University of Oxford appears safe and triggers an immune response. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Trials involving 1,077 people showed the injection led to them making antibodies and T-cells that can fight coronavirus. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thelancet.com/lancet/article/s0140-6736(20)31604-4&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link-external&quot;&gt;The findings&lt;/a&gt; are hugely promising, but it is still too soon to know if this is enough to offer protection and larger trials are under way.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The UK has already ordered 100 million doses of the vaccine. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;story-body__crosshead&quot;&gt;How does the vaccine work?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The vaccine - called ChAdOx1 nCoV-19 - is being developed at unprecedented speed. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is made from a genetically engineered virus that causes the common cold in chimpanzees.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It has been heavily modified, first so it cannot cause infections in people and also to make it &quot;look&quot; more like coronavirus. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Scientists did this by transferring the genetic instructions for the coronavirus's &quot;spike protein&quot; - the crucial tool it uses to invade our cells - to the vaccine they were developing. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This means the vaccine resembles the coronavirus and the immune system can learn how to attack it. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;story-body__crosshead&quot;&gt;What are antibodies and T-cells?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Much of the focus on coronavirus so far has been about antibodies, but these are only one part of our immune defence.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Antibodies are small proteins made by the immune system that stick onto the surface of viruses.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Neutralising antibodies can disable the coronavirus. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;T-cells, a type of white blood cell, help co-ordinate the immune system and are able to spot which of the body's cells have been infected and destroy them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nearly all effective vaccines induce both an antibody and a T-cell response.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape has-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
                 &lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image copyright&lt;/span&gt;
                 &lt;span class=&quot;story-image-copyright&quot;&gt;Oxford University&lt;/span&gt;
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
            &lt;figcaption class=&quot;media-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image caption&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;media-caption__text&quot;&gt;
                    Sample from patients are analysed as part of the trial.
                &lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;Levels of T-cells peaked 14 days after vaccination and antibody levels peaked after 28 days. The study has not run for long enough to understand how long they may last, the study in the Lancet showed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Prof Andrew Pollard, from the Oxford research group told the BBC: &quot;We're really pleased with the results published today as we're seeing both neutralising antibodies and T-cells.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;They're extremely promising and we believe the type of response that may be associated with protection.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;But the key question everyone wants to know is does the vaccine work, does it offer protection... and we're in a waiting game.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The study showed 90% of people developed neutralising antibodies after one dose. Only ten people were given two doses and all of them produced neutralising antibodies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;We don't know the level needed for protection, but we can maximise responses with a second dose,&quot; Prof Pollard told the BBC.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;story-body__crosshead&quot;&gt;Is it safe?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yes, but there are side-effects.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There were no dangerous side-effects from taking the vaccine, however, 70% of people on the trial developed either fever or headache.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The researchers say this could be managed with paracetamol.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Prof Sarah Gilbert, from the University of Oxford, UK, says: &quot;There is still much work to be done before we can confirm if our vaccine will help manage the Covid-19 pandemic, but these early results hold promise.&quot; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;story-body__crosshead&quot;&gt;What are the next steps in the trial?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The results so far are promising, but their main purpose is to ensure the vaccine is safe enough to give to people.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The study cannot show whether the vaccine can either prevent people from becoming ill or even lessen their symptoms of Covid-19.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;More than 10,000 people will take part in the next stage of the trials in the UK.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, the trial has also been expanded to other countries because levels of coronavirus are low in the UK, making it hard to know if the vaccine is effective.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There will be a large trial involving 30,000 people in the US as well 2,000 in South Africa and 5,000 in Brazil.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are also calls to perform &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/health-53426367&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link&quot;&gt;&quot;challenge trials&quot;&lt;/a&gt; in which vaccinated people are deliberately infected with coronavirus. However, there are ethical concerns due to a lack of treatments.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;story-body__crosshead&quot;&gt;When will I get a vaccine?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is possible a coronavirus vaccine will be proven effective before the end of the year, however, it will not be widely available.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Health and care workers will be prioritised as will people who are deemed at high risk from Covid-19 due to their age or medical conditions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, widespread vaccination is likely to be, at the earliest, next year even if everything goes to plan.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Boris Johnson said: &quot;Obviously I'm hopeful, I've got my fingers crossed, but to say I'm 100% confident we'll get a vaccine this year, or indeed next year, is, alas, just an exaggeration.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;We're not there yet.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;story-body__crosshead&quot;&gt;What progress is being made with other vaccines?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Oxford vaccine is not the first to reach this stage, with groups in the US and China also publishing similar results.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The US company Moderna was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/health-52677203&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link&quot;&gt;first out of the blocks&lt;/a&gt; and its vaccine can produce neutralising antibodies. They are injecting coronavirus RNA (its genetic code), which then starts making viral proteins in order to trigger an immune response. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pfizer.com/news/press-release/press-release-detail/pfizer-and-biontech-announce-early-positive-data-ongoing-0&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link-external&quot;&gt;The companies BioNtech and Pfizer &lt;/a&gt;have also had positive results using their RNA vaccine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-portrait no-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
        &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;A technique similar to the Oxford one, developed in China, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thelancet.com/lancet/article/s0140-6736(20)31605-6&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link-external&quot;&gt;also seems promising&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, all these approaches are at the absolute boundary of science and have not been proven to work before.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;More traditional methods of vaccine development are also being investigated. The company Valneva is taking the whole coronavirus, inactivating it and then inject it. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In total there are 23 coronavirus vaccines in clinical trials around the world and another 140 in early stage development.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;story-body__crosshead&quot;&gt;Will the UK get a coronavirus vaccine?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The UK government has struck deals for 190 million doses &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/health-53469269&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link&quot;&gt;of different vaccines&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This includes: &lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul class=&quot;story-body__unordered-list&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;100 million doses of the Oxford vaccine made from a genetically engineered virus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;30 million doses of the BioNtech/Pfizer vaccine, which injects part of the coronavirus' genetic code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;60 million doses of the Valneva inactivated coronavirus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;These have been paid for even though it is uncertain which, if any, of the vaccines may prove effective for immunising a nation with 66m people.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Kate Bingham, chairwoman of the UK Vaccine Taskforce, told the BBC: &quot;What we are doing is identifying the most promising vaccines across the different categories, or different types of vaccine, so that we can be sure that we do have a vaccine in case one of those actually proves to be both safe and effective.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;It's unlikely to be a single vaccine for everybody.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;We may well need different vaccines for different groups of people.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Follow &lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;James &lt;/i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/JamesTGallagher&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link-external&quot;&gt;on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape no-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
        &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;ul class=&quot;story-body__unordered-list&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;INSIDE HEALTH: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.co.uk/sounds/play/m000kty9?xtor=CS8-1000-%5BIn_Article_Promo_Box%5D-%5BNews_Promo_In_Article%5D-%5BNews_Promo_In_Article_BBCGeneric%5D-%5BPS_SOUNDS~N~m000kty9~Inside_Health_4th_July%5D&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link&quot;&gt;Why is there an elevated risk from Covid-19 for some groups in society&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;DIET AND MENTAL WELLBEING: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.co.uk/food/articles/diet_wellbeing?xtor=CS8-1000-%5BIn_Article_Promo_Box%5D-%5BNews_Promo_In_Article%5D-%5BNews_Promo_In_Article_BBCGeneric%5D-%5BPS_FOOD~N~~Diet_and_mental_health%5D&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link&quot;&gt;Does the food you eat help or hinder you emotionally...&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;hr class=&quot;story-body__line&quot;/&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape no-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
        &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What questions do you have about vaccines and the coronavirus?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;i&gt;In some cases your question will be published, displaying your name, age and location as you provide it, unless you state otherwise. Your contact details will never be published. Please ensure you have read our &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.co.uk/usingthebbc/terms/&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link&quot;&gt;terms &amp;amp; conditions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;i&gt; and &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.co.uk/usingthebbc/privacy-policy/&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link&quot;&gt;privacy policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Use this form to ask your question: &lt;/p&gt;
  
  
  
  
  &lt;div readability=&quot;8.6973180076628&quot;&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;If you are reading this page and can't see the form you will need to visit the mobile version of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/have_your_say&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link&quot;&gt;BBC website&lt;/a&gt; to submit your question or send them via email to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:YourQuestions@bbc.co.uk&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link-email&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;icon email&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;story-body__link-email-text&quot;&gt;YourQuestions@bbc.co.uk&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Please include your name, age and location with any question you send in. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
            </description>
<pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2020 13:49:03 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ceocoder</dc:creator>
<og:title>Oxford coronavirus vaccine triggers immune response</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>Study shows the vaccine is safe, but it is still too soon to know if it can stop people from being infected.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.bbc.com/news/uk-53469839</og:url>
<og:image>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/14FA4/production/_113542958_clinic-injection04--credit-.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-GB</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-53469839</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Turns out half the internet has a single-point-of-failure called “Cloudflare”</title>
<link>https://easydns.com/blog/2020/07/20/turns-out-half-the-internet-has-a-single-point-of-failure-called-cloudflare/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://easydns.com/blog/2020/07/20/turns-out-half-the-internet-has-a-single-point-of-failure-called-cloudflare/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;label for=&quot;accountUserModal&quot;&gt;Create a username&lt;/label&gt; &lt;input required=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;accountUserModal&quot; aria-describedby=&quot;accountUserHelpModal&quot; type=&quot;text&quot; name=&quot;user&quot; class=&quot;form-control&quot; pattern=&quot;^(?=.{5,32}$)(?![_.])(?!.*[_.]{2})[a-zA-Z0-9._]+$&quot;/&gt;&lt;small id=&quot;accountUserHelpModal&quot; class=&quot;form-text text-muted&quot;&gt;Use 5-32 characters, no _ or . at the beginning, no __ or _. or ._ or .. inside, and no _ or . at the end.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;label for=&quot;accountEmailModal&quot;&gt;Email address&lt;/label&gt; &lt;input required=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;accountEmailModal&quot; aria-describedby=&quot;accountEmailHelpModal&quot; type=&quot;email&quot; name=&quot;email&quot; class=&quot;form-control&quot; pattern=&quot;[a-z0-9._%+-]+@[a-z0-9.-]+\.[a-z]{2,}$&quot;/&gt;&lt;small id=&quot;accountEmailHelpModal&quot; class=&quot;form-text text-muted&quot;&gt;Use a valid email address as this is where we will contact you about your account.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;label for=&quot;accountPassword2Modal&quot;&gt;Re-enter your password&lt;/label&gt; &lt;input required=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;accountPassword2Modal&quot; type=&quot;password&quot; name=&quot;password2&quot; class=&quot;form-control&quot; pattern=&quot;^(?=.*?[A-Z])(?=.*?[a-z])(?=.*?[0-9]).{8,30}$&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;label for=&quot;accountSecretQuestion1Modal&quot;&gt;Enter a security question 1&lt;/label&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;label for=&quot;accountSecretAnswer1Modal&quot;&gt;Enter your answer 1&lt;/label&gt; &lt;input required=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;accountSecretAnswer1Modal&quot; aria-describedby=&quot;accountSecretAnswer1Help&quot; type=&quot;text&quot; name=&quot;secret_answer1&quot; class=&quot;form-control&quot;/&gt;&lt;small id=&quot;accountSecretAnswer1Help&quot; class=&quot;form-text text-muted&quot;&gt;Use only alphanumeric characters, spaces, hyphens, or periods.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;label for=&quot;accountSecretQuestion2Modal&quot;&gt;Enter a security question 2&lt;/label&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;label for=&quot;accountSecretAnswer2Modal&quot;&gt;Enter your answer 2&lt;/label&gt; &lt;input required=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;accountSecretAnswer2Modal&quot; aria-describedby=&quot;accountSecretAnswer2Help&quot; type=&quot;text&quot; name=&quot;secret_answer2&quot; class=&quot;form-control&quot;/&gt;&lt;small id=&quot;accountSecretAnswer2Help&quot; class=&quot;form-text text-muted&quot;&gt;Use only alphanumeric characters, spaces, hyphens, or periods.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;label for=&quot;accountSecretQuestion3Modal&quot;&gt;Enter a security question 3&lt;/label&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;label for=&quot;accountSecretAnswer3Modal&quot;&gt;Enter your answer 3&lt;/label&gt; &lt;input required=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;accountSecretAnswer3Modal&quot; aria-describedby=&quot;accountSecretAnswer3Help&quot; type=&quot;text&quot; name=&quot;secret_answer3&quot; class=&quot;form-control&quot;/&gt;&lt;small id=&quot;accountSecretAnswer3Help&quot; class=&quot;form-text text-muted&quot;&gt;Use only alphanumeric characters, spaces, hyphens, or periods.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;button type=&quot;submit&quot; class=&quot;btn btn-default btn-account-create&quot;&gt;CREATE ACCOUNT&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2020 13:42:27 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>StuntPope</dc:creator>
<og:title>Turns out half the internet has a Single-Point-of-Failure called “Cloudflare”</og:title>
<og:url>https://easydns.com/blog/2020/07/20/turns-out-half-the-internet-has-a-single-point-of-failure-called-cloudflare/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>On Friday a large chunk of the internet went off the air when Cloudflare apparently fat-fingered a routing update and sent all of their global traffic to a single POP, vaporizing it almost instantly. This affected their DNS service, and of course, as everybody knows, when your DNS is gone, so are</og:description>
<og:image>https://easydns.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/shutterstock_280363592-e1539959403250.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://easydns.com/blog/2020/07/20/turns-out-half-the-internet-has-a-single-point-of-failure-called-cloudflare/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ireland donates contact tracing app to Linux Foundation</title>
<link>https://www.nearform.com/blog/ireland-donates-contact-tracing-app-to-linux-foundation/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nearform.com/blog/ireland-donates-contact-tracing-app-to-linux-foundation/</guid>
<description>&lt;div readability=&quot;89.84696969697&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hse.ie/eng/&quot;&gt;Ireland’s Health Service Executive&lt;/a&gt; (HSE) announced today that it is donating the code for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://covidtracker.gov.ie/&quot;&gt;COVID Tracker app&lt;/a&gt; as Open Source to the not-for-profit &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linuxfoundation.org/&quot;&gt;Linux Foundation.&lt;/a&gt; This will enable jurisdictions worldwide to quickly build and deploy their own contact tracing apps using a wildly successful proven base. The donated app has been named COVID Green.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NearForm is honoured to be part of such an important initiative and will play a key role as part of the Technical Steering Committee in continuing to manage the development and direction of COVID Green in the Linux Foundation. We will work closely with developers, designers, public health experts, academics and public health authorities in building a vibrant, diverse community to drive the project forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rapid adoption of the COVID Tracker app in Ireland exceeded all expectations. One million people installed it in the first 36 hours, and the app currently has over 1.3 million installations. That figure represents more than 30% of people in Ireland with compatible devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The code is also being used in the app for Gibraltar and the upcoming apps for Northern Ireland, other jurisdictions in EMEA and multiple US states. NearForm continues to enable public health authorities to get a contact tracing application into production within four weeks of project start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By donating the source code to the new &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lfph.io/&quot;&gt;Linux Foundation Public Health&lt;/a&gt; (LFPH) project, under the Apache License 2.0, the HSE is playing an active role in helping to fight Covid-19 worldwide. Source code for the COVID Green mobile app is &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/covidgreen&quot;&gt;available now on GitHub&lt;/a&gt; and soon will be followed by all matching backend code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Linux Foundation is dedicated to building sustainable ecosystems around open source projects to accelerate technology development and industry adoption. LFPH is launching with a mission to use open source software to help public health authorities (PHAs) around the world combat Covid-19 and future epidemics. One of the roles of LFPH is to serve as a forum for collaboration between PHAs, developers, technology companies and academics to ensure the implementation and dissemination of best practices, including privacy and security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Accelerated Solutions for Covid&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a part of delivering our first government contact tracing apps, NearForm has prepared to roll the solution out to other governments quickly and easily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The NearForm team can get a government or state set up and launched with a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nearform.com/work/covid-app-development/&quot;&gt;best-in-class, privacy-protecting contact tracing system&lt;/a&gt; in approximately one month and at a fraction of the cost of other solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our aim is to take the friction out of the process of implementing this technology. We can facilitate the entire project, including app design that is focused on accessibility and support for multiple languages, integration with national test systems and, importantly, interoperability across governments to enable travel. Plus, NearForm takes care of the cloud environment to run the system with a 24×7 support team and ongoing feature development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being open source, the solution intentionally does not aim to lock governments into something closed and proprietary. The aim is to enable governments to use the technology, and for their own teams to be able to develop, manage and support this contact tracing app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h5 class=&quot;title-heading-center&quot;&gt;Follow us for more information on this and other topics.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2020 13:17:15 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>donaltroddyn</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Ireland donates its COVID Tracker app to Linux Foundation</og:title>
<og:description>Ireland's HSE has donated the world's most successful contact tracing app as open source to Linux Foundation Public Health, supporting the global effort against Covid-19.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.nearform.com/blog/ireland-donates-contact-tracing-app-to-linux-foundation/</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.nearform.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Blog_CovidGreentoLFPH_HeaderImg-scaled.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-GB</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nearform.com/blog/ireland-donates-contact-tracing-app-to-linux-foundation/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Any claim without a URI should be treated as suspicious</title>
<link>https://shkspr.mobi/blog/2020/07/any-claim-without-a-uri-should-be-treated-as-suspicious/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://shkspr.mobi/blog/2020/07/any-claim-without-a-uri-should-be-treated-as-suspicious/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve recently seen lots of people tweeting this supposed newspaper clipping. An olde-timey warning about wearing flu masks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://shkspr.mobi/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Neckties.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&amp;quot;Many a man who wears laughable clothes from neckties to socks is afraid to put on an influenza mask for fear it might hurt his personal appearance.&amp;quot;&quot; width=&quot;590&quot; height=&quot;190&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-35871&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But is it too good to be true?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing to do with any image of a text quote is to search for the text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=&amp;quot;Many+a+man+who+wears+laughable+clothes&amp;quot;&amp;amp;oq=&amp;quot;Many+a+man+who+wears+laughable+clothes&amp;quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://shkspr.mobi/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Screenshot_2020-07-09-Many-a-man-who-wears-laughable-clothes-Google-Search.png&quot; alt=&quot;Hundreds of Google results - all pointing back to tumblr.&quot; width=&quot;1018&quot; height=&quot;922&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-35872&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look, I’m not saying tumblr isn’t great, but… I wouldn’t exactly trust it as a primary source!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said, tumblr has a neat feature which makes it easy to see where a popular image originally was posted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this case it appears to have originated at &lt;a href=&quot;https://yesterdaysprint.tumblr.com/post/619212350364516365/the-evening-star-washington-dc-october-16-1918&quot;&gt;Yesterday In Print&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://yesterdaysprint.tumblr.com/post/619212350364516365/the-evening-star-washington-dc-october-16-1918&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://shkspr.mobi/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Screenshot_2020-07-09-yesterdaysprint.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tumblr website with a citation.&quot; width=&quot;973&quot; height=&quot;706&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-35873&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s nothing on the site which screams “spoof” or “fake”. The site FAQ claims it posts genuine newspaper clippings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this case, from “The Evening Star, Washington DC, October 16, 1918”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The USA’s Library of Congress has a good collection of old local newspapers. They’re all scanned and OCR’d.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1918-10-16/ed-1/&quot;&gt;The Evening Star, Washington DC, October 16, 1918&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rather than labouriously read through each thrilling page, it is possible to &lt;a href=&quot;https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/search/pages/results/?state=&amp;amp;date1=1789&amp;amp;date2=1963&amp;amp;proxtext=%22Many+a+man+who+wears+laughable%22&amp;amp;x=0&amp;amp;y=0&amp;amp;dateFilterType=yearRange&amp;amp;rows=20&amp;amp;searchType=basic&quot;&gt;search for the “many a man” phrase directly&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey presto! &lt;a href=&quot;https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1918-10-16/ed-1/seq-6/&quot;&gt;There’s the quote on page 6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://shkspr.mobi/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Screenshot_2020-07-09-Evening-star-volume-Washington-D-C-1854-1972-October-16-1918-Page-6-Image-6.png&quot; alt=&quot;The quote in the middle of a newpaper column.&quot; width=&quot;663&quot; height=&quot;405&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-35874&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is the trail complete? Perhaps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can argue whether you think the Library of Congress is a trustworthy source, and you can contact Louisiana State University to see if the original paper is in their records, and you can believe the Illuminati have rewritten history. But you’ll do so from a place of informed knowledge – rather than from a graphic which &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; have been manipulated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The whole investigation took me 5 minutes. A Web search, a few clicks, and some &lt;kbd&gt;ctrl&lt;/kbd&gt;+&lt;kbd&gt;f&lt;/kbd&gt;‘ing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are basic skills, and you should use those skills before you share something which sounds too good to be true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Treat any claim without a URl as suspicious.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2020 11:57:06 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>pavel_lishin</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Any claim without a URl should be treated as suspicious</og:title>
<og:url>https://shkspr.mobi/blog/2020/07/any-claim-without-a-uri-should-be-treated-as-suspicious/</og:url>
<og:description>I’ve recently seen lots of people tweeting this supposed newspaper clipping. An olde-timey warning about wearing flu masks. But is it too good to be true? The first thing to do with any image…</og:description>
<og:image>https://shkspr.mobi/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Screenshot_2020-07-09-Many-a-man-who-wears-laughable-clothes-Google-Search.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-GB</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://shkspr.mobi/blog/2020/07/any-claim-without-a-uri-should-be-treated-as-suspicious/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Show HN: 3D Book Image CSS Generator</title>
<link>https://3d-book-css.netlify.app/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://3d-book-css.netlify.app/</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://3d-book-css.netlify.app/&quot;&gt;https://3d-book-css.netlify.app/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23896856&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23896856&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 542&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 77&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2020 11:51:38 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>scastiel</dc:creator>
<og:title>3D Book Image CSS Generator</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://3d-book-css.netlify.app/</og:url>
<og:description>Generate an animated 3D image from a book cover and export to HTML/CSS to embed on your website.</og:description>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://3d-book-css.netlify.app/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Minecraft@Home</title>
<link>https://minecraftathome.com/minecrafthome/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://minecraftathome.com/minecrafthome/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lead&quot;&gt;That was fast&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The origin of the panorama image used in the Minecraft main menu from beta version 1.8.1, released in September 2011, has remained a mystery until now.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;In less than 24 hours after launching the panorama application; a volunteer host for Minecraft@Home, in a sheer stroke of luck, found the world seed, 25357015387625.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This was approximately &lt;span&gt;93 days of processing time at a total of 54.5 exaFLOPs&lt;/span&gt; compressed into the last 24 hours.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The specific host which located the seed belongs to the user &lt;a href=&quot;https://minecraftathome.com/minecrafthome/show_user.php?userid=2558&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;vanos0512&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br/&gt;Thank you to the 137 users who contributed 181 hosts with 231 GPUs over the last 24 hours. You all accomplished this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img hspace=&quot;8&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/f6lGCEn.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here are the details if you want to generate this world for yourself:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Minecraft version:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Beta 1.7&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Either of these two valid world seeds:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;2151901553968352745 or 8091867987493326313&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Co-ordinates:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;x60, y76, z-67&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=caLCZNLPgrM&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;See the video released by EarthComputer announcing the finding.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;small&quot;&gt;18 Jul 2020, 15:32:11 UTC · &lt;a href=&quot;https://minecraftathome.com/minecrafthome/forum_thread.php?id=42&quot;&gt;Discuss&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br clear=&quot;all&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lead&quot;&gt;Enjoy the scenery&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;Minecraft@Home is now &lt;span&gt;over one month old&lt;/span&gt;! To celebrate this milestone, I present a new research focus; the panorama project.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you were here during beta-testing, you might have received a very early version of panorama tasks, and the eagle-eyed among you may have seen the application details &lt;a href=&quot;https://minecraftathome.com/minecrafthome/server_status.php&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;on the server status page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The panorama app is a CUDA-only app for Linux and Windows with an Nvidia driver version of 418.96 or higher.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This project attempts to find the world seed of the iconic panorama image which appeared in the background of the main menu of Minecraft between 2011 and 2018. The first phase of this project will only last a few days, and we shall update you with their progress in the coming weeks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img hspace=&quot;8&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/3dyexWe.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Right now, the application is quite substantial. Unlike the OpenCL applications for the Kaktwoos project, &lt;strong&gt;if you allow BOINC to run tasks always; you may experience some stuttering or lag in your desktop environment while running these tasks&lt;/strong&gt;. These tasks do not have checkpointing support, but run in around 1 hour on an average host to mitigate the majority of lost cycles.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;As always, &lt;a href=&quot;https://minecraftathome.com/minecrafthome/prefs.php?subset=project&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;you can change which projects of which you decide to participate in your user preferences&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let us know if you have any questions, and as always join the discussion over on &lt;a href=&quot;https://discord.gg/xVFh9bp&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;the Discord server.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;small&quot;&gt;17 Jul 2020, 15:31:43 UTC · &lt;a href=&quot;https://minecraftathome.com/minecrafthome/forum_thread.php?id=39&quot;&gt;Discuss&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br clear=&quot;all&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lead&quot;&gt;Kaktwoos 2.03 and Badges!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;You may have seen many workunits just disappear from existence today.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img hspace=&quot;8&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; src=&quot;https://munin.kiska.pw/munin-cgi/munin-cgi-graph/Munin-Node/Munin-Node/results_minecraftathome-pinpoint=1594193183,1594247603.png?&amp;amp;lower_limit=&amp;amp;upper_limit=&amp;amp;size_x=400&amp;amp;size_y=200&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Worry not! We realised there were far too many workunits scanning duplicate seeds, so we've scaled back the original workunits to the correct seed ranges &lt;span&gt;&lt;em&gt;(no in-progress results were touched, so none of you should have lost any credit)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We have located some promising seed candidates which were missed from processing and can be used as an input to this job, so they are currently set as the highest priority.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also, &lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;we now have badges&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;! If you view the forums, any comments in threads, or on the leaderboards; you will see the new badges.&lt;br/&gt;We're open to suggestions for future badges, so please leave us some comments on this thread.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;small&quot;&gt;8 Jul 2020, 21:06:03 UTC · &lt;a href=&quot;https://minecraftathome.com/minecrafthome/forum_thread.php?id=30&quot;&gt;Discuss&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br clear=&quot;all&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lead&quot;&gt;Profile creation and OpenCL vendor pinning&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;In the last news post, I advised everyone to create a profile in order to be eligible for 'user of the day' selection.&lt;br/&gt;Unfortunately, there was an issue with the ReCaptcha implementation which prevented this. This issue is now resolved.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now, you are able to &lt;a href=&quot;https://minecraftathome.com/minecrafthome/create_profile.php&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;create a profile here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also, good news for hosts with OpenCL capable hardware from more than one vendor &lt;em&gt;(e.g. an Intel iGPU and an Nvidia GPU)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The latest update to the kaktwoos app should ensure the tasks run on the correct device.&lt;br/&gt;If you are a user with a multi-vendor host, please keep an eye on your results and let us know if you're having any issues.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As always, please get involved with the conversation in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://minecraftathome.com/minecrafthome/forum_index.php&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;message boards&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://discord.gg/xVFh9bp&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;join the Discord&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;small&quot;&gt;3 Jul 2020, 16:57:49 UTC · &lt;a href=&quot;https://minecraftathome.com/minecrafthome/forum_thread.php?id=22&quot;&gt;Discuss&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br clear=&quot;all&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lead&quot;&gt;MultiGPU, checkpointing, and another record breaking cactus (22 blocks tall)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finally, support for multiple GPUs and checkpointing has landed.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• If you have multiple GPUs, the research apps will now make use of all available GPUs.&lt;br/&gt;• We now support Intel GPUs.&lt;br/&gt;• If work is suspended, or your machine is powered off, checkpoints will now ensure work does not start from the beginning.&lt;br/&gt;• You will also notice work estimates are far more accurate.&lt;br/&gt;• You do not need to take any actions to enable these features.&lt;br/&gt;• We are also taking steps to increase the priority of additional results added to workunits after computation errors. This in order to speed up validation of incomplete workunits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;Thank you to Hypprs, nicoboss, DutChen18, BalintCsala, and anyone else who was involved in testing and updating the app.&lt;p&gt;For the third time in 1 week, Minecraft@Home has broken the tallest cactus height record in normal terrain generation.&lt;br/&gt;I present, a &lt;strong&gt;22 block tall cactus&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img hspace=&quot;8&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/nA5IPDe.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.14.4 world seed: 11343195073417814, co-ordinates: 14955936 64 -3750655.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Congratulations to volunteer &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://minecraftathome.com/minecrafthome/show_user.php?userid=212&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;SirNapkin1334&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, your host was responsible for locating this one!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While I have your attention, user profiles are now enabled, please ensure you &lt;a href=&quot;https://minecraftathome.com/minecrafthome/create_profile.php&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;create a user profile&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br/&gt;This will ensure you can be selected for &lt;em&gt;'user of the day'&lt;/em&gt; which is displayed on the homepage.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please post any issues on our &lt;a href=&quot;https://minecraftathome.com/minecrafthome/forum_index.php&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;message boards&lt;/a&gt;. Alternatively, for real-time discussion, &lt;a href=&quot;https://discord.gg/xVFh9bp&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;join our Discord&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;small&quot;&gt;1 Jul 2020, 12:44:20 UTC · &lt;a href=&quot;https://minecraftathome.com/minecrafthome/forum_thread.php?id=14&quot;&gt;Discuss&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br clear=&quot;all&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://minecraftathome.com/minecrafthome/old_news.php&quot;&gt;... more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;News is available as an &lt;a href=&quot;https://minecraftathome.com/minecrafthome/rss_main.php&quot;&gt;RSS feed   &lt;img src=&quot;https://minecraftathome.com/minecrafthome/img/rss_icon.gif&quot; alt=&quot;RSS&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2020 08:19:22 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>networked</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://minecraftathome.com/minecrafthome/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>