<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>American Mercenaries Were Hired to Assassinate Politicians in the Middle East</title>
<link>https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/aramroston/mercenaries-assassination-us-yemen-uae-spear-golan-dahlan?fbclid=IwAR08TqB-uGvRrRsnylMTMTiHmvuPEdQ0hj0xFSBSH3tT4SN9S3VBNqf4nbA</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/aramroston/mercenaries-assassination-us-yemen-uae-spear-golan-dahlan?fbclid=IwAR08TqB-uGvRrRsnylMTMTiHmvuPEdQ0hj0xFSBSH3tT4SN9S3VBNqf4nbA</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;subbuzz subbuzz-text xs-mb4 xs-relative&quot; data-module=&quot;subbuzz-text&quot; readability=&quot;59.286713286713&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cradling an AK-47&lt;/strong&gt; and sucking a lollipop, the former American Green Beret bumped along in the back of an armored SUV as it wound through the darkened streets of Aden. Two other commandos on the mission were former Navy SEALs. As elite US special operations fighters, they had years of specialized training by the US military to protect America. But now they were working for a different master: a private US company that had been hired by the United Arab Emirates, a tiny desert monarchy on the Persian Gulf.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On that night, December 29, 2015, their job was to carry out an assassination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their armed attack, described to BuzzFeed News by two of its participants and corroborated by drone surveillance footage, was the first operation in a startling for-profit venture. For months in war-torn Yemen, some of America’s most highly trained soldiers worked on a mercenary mission of murky legality to kill prominent clerics and Islamist political figures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their target that night: Anssaf Ali Mayo, the local leader of the Islamist political party Al-Islah. The UAE considers Al-Islah to be the Yemeni branch of the worldwide Muslim Brotherhood, which the UAE calls a terrorist organization. Many experts insist that Al-Islah, one of whose members won the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2011/oct/07/tawakkul-karman-profile&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Nobel Peace Prize&lt;/a&gt;, is no terror group. They say it's a legitimate political party that threatens the UAE not through violence but by speaking out against its ambitions in Yemen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;hr class=&quot;subbuzz subbuzz__section-divider subbuzz__section-divider--thin xs-block xs-mb4 xs-col-11&quot;/&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;subbuzz subbuzz__section-divider subbuzz__section-divider--thin xs-block xs-mb4 xs-col-11&quot;/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;subbuzz subbuzz-text xs-mb4 xs-relative&quot; data-module=&quot;subbuzz-text&quot; readability=&quot;48&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mercenaries’ plan was to attach a bomb laced with shrapnel to the door of Al-Islah’s headquarters, located near a soccer stadium in central Aden, a key Yemeni port city. The explosion, one of the leaders of the expedition explained, was supposed to “kill everybody in that office.”&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When they arrived at 9:57 at night, all seemed quiet. The men crept out of the SUV, guns at the ready. One carried the explosive charge toward the building. But just as he was about to reach the door, another member of the team opened fire, shooting back along the dimly lit street, and their carefully designed plan went haywire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;subbuzz subbuzz-image xs-mb4 xs-relative subbuzz-image--outset-both&quot; data-module=&quot;subbuzz-image&quot;&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;flex xs-flex-column&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;subbuzz__attribution js-subbuzz__attribution xs-text-6 xs-block&quot;&gt;Obtained by BuzzFeed News&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;subbuzz__description&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drone footage of the operation in Yemen to assassinate a Yemeni leader of Al-Islah, an Islamist political party.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;subbuzz subbuzz-text xs-mb4 xs-relative&quot; data-module=&quot;subbuzz-text&quot; readability=&quot;44&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The operation against Mayo&lt;/strong&gt; — which was reported at the time but until now was not known to have been carried out by American mercenaries — marked a pivot point in the war in Yemen, a brutal conflict that has seen children starved, villages bombed, and epidemics of cholera roll through the civilian population. The bombing was the first salvo in a string of unsolved assassinations that killed more than two dozen of the group’s leaders.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company that hired the soldiers and carried out the attack is Spear Operations Group, incorporated in Delaware and founded by Abraham Golan, a charismatic Hungarian Israeli security contractor who lives outside of Pittsburgh. He led the team’s strike against Mayo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;subbuzz subbuzz-pullquote xs-relative col xs-col-12 xs-z1 xs-mb4 md-mb2 md-col-5 md-pr4&quot; data-module=&quot;subbuzz-quote&quot; readability=&quot;5.4271844660194&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;pullquote js-subbuzz__title-text&quot; readability=&quot;27.553398058252&quot;&gt;Got a tip? You can email tips@buzzfeed.com. To learn how to reach us securely, go to &lt;a href=&quot;https://tips.buzzfeed.com&quot;&gt;tips.buzzfeed.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;subbuzz subbuzz-text xs-mb4 xs-relative&quot; data-module=&quot;subbuzz-text&quot; readability=&quot;84.942675159236&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There was a targeted assassination program in Yemen,” he told BuzzFeed News. “I was running it. We did it. It was sanctioned by the UAE within the coalition.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The UAE and Saudi Arabia lead an alliance of nine countries in Yemen, fighting what is largely a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/un-probe-details-fallout-of-proxy-war-in-yemen-between-saudi-coalition-and-iran-/2018/01/11/3e3f9302-f644-11e7-9af7-a50bc3300042_story.html?utm_term=.c64bf6a1c93e&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;proxy war&lt;/a&gt; against Iran. The US is helping the Saudi-UAE side by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/verabergengruen/khashoggi-congress-yemen-saudi-arabia-military-aid&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;providing&lt;/a&gt; weapons, intelligence, and other support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The press office of the UAE’s US Embassy, as well as its US public affairs company, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.odwyerpr.com/story/public/9954/2018-01-02/uae-extends-harbour-groups-10m-pact.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Harbour Group&lt;/a&gt;, did not respond to multiple phone calls and emails.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The revelations that a Middle East monarchy hired Americans to carry out assassinations comes at a moment when the world is focused on the alleged murder of dissident journalist Jamal Khashoggi by Saudi Arabia, an autocratic regime that has close ties to both the US and the UAE. (The Saudi Embassy in the US did not respond to a request for comment. Riyadh &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/article/us-saudi-politics-dissident-minister/saudi-arabia-denies-allegations-regarding-murder-of-khashoggi-interior-minister-idUSKCN1MM2PM&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;has denied&lt;/a&gt; it killed Khashoggi, though &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnn.com/2018/10/16/middleeast/khashoggi-saudi-pompeo-intl/index.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;news reports&lt;/a&gt; suggest it is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/10/15/us/politics/trump-saudi-king-journalist-khashoggi.html?action=click&amp;amp;module=Top%20Stories&amp;amp;pgtype=Homepage&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;considering&lt;/a&gt; blaming his death on a botched interrogation.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Golan said that during his company’s months-long engagement in Yemen, his team was responsible for a number of the war’s high-profile assassinations, though he declined to specify which ones. He argued that the US needs an assassination program similar to the model he deployed. “I just want there to be a debate,” he said. “Maybe I’m a monster. Maybe I should be in jail. Maybe I’m a bad guy. But I’m right.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spear Operations Group’s private assassination mission marks the confluence of three developments transforming the way war is conducted worldwide:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;0.5&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Modern counterterrorism combat has shifted away from traditional military objectives — such as destroying airfields, gun emplacements, or barracks — to killing specific individuals, largely reshaping war into organized assassinations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;War has become increasingly privatized, with many nations outsourcing most military support services to private contractors, leaving frontline combat as virtually the only function that the US and many other militaries have not contracted out to for-profit ventures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul readability=&quot;-0.5&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The long US wars in Afghanistan and Iraq have relied heavily on elite special forces, producing tens of thousands of highly trained American commandos who can demand high private-sector salaries for defense contracting or outright mercenary work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;With Spear Operations Group’s mission in Yemen, these trends converged into a new and incendiary business: militarized contract killing, carried out by skilled American fighters.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Experts said it is almost inconceivable that the United States would not have known that the UAE — whose military the US has trained and armed at virtually every level — had hired an American company staffed by American veterans to conduct an assassination program in a war it closely monitors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the mercenaries, according to three sources familiar with the operation, used to work with the CIA’s “ground branch,” the agency’s equivalent of the military’s special forces. Another was a special forces sergeant in the Maryland Army National Guard. And yet another, according to four people who knew him, was still in the Navy Reserve as a SEAL and had a top-secret clearance. He was a veteran of SEAL Team 6, or DEVGRU, the sources told BuzzFeed News. The New York Times once described that elite unit, famous for killing Osama bin Laden, as a “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2015/06/07/world/asia/the-secret-history-of-seal-team-6.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;global manhunting machine with limited outside oversight&lt;/a&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;subbuzz subbuzz-pullquote xs-relative col xs-col-12 xs-z1 xs-mb4 md-mb2 md-col-5 md-pr4&quot; data-module=&quot;subbuzz-quote&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What vetting procedures are there to make sure the guy you just smoked is really a bad guy?”&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;subbuzz subbuzz-text xs-mb4 xs-relative&quot; data-module=&quot;subbuzz-text&quot; readability=&quot;88.702508960573&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CIA said it had no information about the mercenary assassination program, and the Navy's Special Warfare Command declined to comment. A former CIA official who has worked in the UAE initially told BuzzFeed News there was no way that Americans would be allowed to participate in such a program. But after checking, he called back: “There were guys that were basically doing what you said.” He was astonished, he said, by what he learned: “What vetting procedures are there to make sure the guy you just smoked is really a bad guy?” The mercenaries, he said, were “almost like a murder squad.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether Spear’s mercenary operation violates US law is surprisingly unclear. On the one hand, US law makes it illegal to “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gpo.gov/fdsys/pkg/USCODE-2015-title18/html/USCODE-2015-title18-partI-chap45-sec956.htm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;conspire to kill, kidnap, maim&lt;/a&gt;” someone in another country. Companies that provide military services to foreign nations are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pmddtc.state.gov/?id=ddtc_kb_article_page&amp;amp;sys_id=b9a933addb7c930044f9ff621f961932&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;supposed to be regulated by the State Department&lt;/a&gt;, which says it has never granted any company the authority to supply combat troops or mercenaries to another country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet, as BuzzFeed News has previously reported, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/aramroston/stephen-toumajan-general-us-uae-yemen-contractor&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;the US doesn’t ban mercenaries&lt;/a&gt;. And with some exceptions, it is perfectly legal to serve in foreign militaries, whether one is motivated by idealism or money. With no legal consequences, Americans have served in the Israel Defense Forces, the French Foreign Legion, and even a militia fighting ISIS in Syria. Spear Operations Group, according to three sources, arranged for the UAE to give military rank to the Americans involved in the mission, which might provide them legal cover.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite operating in a legal and political gray zone, Golan heralds his brand of targeted assassinations as a precision counterterrorism strategy with fewer civilian casualties. But the Mayo operation shows that this new form of warfare carries many of the same old problems. The commandos’ plans went awry, and the intelligence proved flawed. And their strike was far from surgical: The explosive they attached to the door was designed to kill not one person but everyone in the office.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aside from moral objections, for-profit targeted assassinations add new dilemmas to modern warfare. Private mercenaries operate outside the US military’s chain of command, so if they make mistakes or commit war crimes, there is no clear system for holding them accountable. If the mercenaries had killed a civilian in the street, who would have even investigated?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Mayo mission exposes an even more central problem: the choice of targets. Golan insists that he killed only terrorists identified by the government of the UAE, an ally of the US. But who is a terrorist and who is a politician? What is a new form of warfare and what is just old-fashioned murder for hire? Who has the right to choose who lives and who dies — not only in the wars of a secretive monarchy like the UAE, but also those of a democracy such as the US?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BuzzFeed News has pieced together the inside story of the company’s attack on Al-Islah’s headquarters, revealing what mercenary warfare looks like now — and what it could become.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;subbuzz subbuzz-image xs-mb4 xs-relative subbuzz-image--outset-both&quot; data-module=&quot;subbuzz-image&quot;&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;flex xs-flex-column&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;subbuzz__attribution js-subbuzz__attribution xs-text-6 xs-block&quot;&gt;Provided to BuzzFeed News&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;subbuzz__description&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Left to right: Isaac Gilmore, Mohammed Dahlan, and Abraham Golan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;subbuzz subbuzz-text xs-mb4 xs-relative&quot; data-module=&quot;subbuzz-text&quot; readability=&quot;55.61295971979&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The deal that&lt;/strong&gt; brought American mercenaries to the streets of Aden was hashed out over a lunch in Abu Dhabi, at an Italian restaurant in the officers’ club of a UAE military base. Golan and a chiseled former US Navy SEAL named Isaac Gilmore had flown in from the US to make their pitch. It did not, as Gilmore recalled, begin well.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their host was Mohammed Dahlan, the fearsome former security chief for the Palestinian Authority. In a well-tailored suit, he eyed his mercenary guests coldly and told Golan that in another context they’d be trying to kill each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, they made an unlikely pair. Golan, who says he was born in Hungary to Jewish parents, maintains long-standing connections in Israel for his security business, according to several sources, and he says he lived there for several years. Golan once partied in London with former Mossad chief Danny Yatom, according to a 2008 Mother Jones article, and his specialty was “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.motherjones.com/politics/2008/11/kurdistan-k-street-2/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;providing security for energy clients in Africa&lt;/a&gt;.” One of his contracts, according to three sources, was to protect ships drilling in Nigeria’s offshore oil fields from sabotage and terrorism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;subbuzz subbuzz-image xs-mb4 xs-relative col xs-col-12 xs-z1 md-col-6 xs-mb4 md-mb2 md-pl3 md-float-right subbuzz-image--align-right&quot; data-module=&quot;subbuzz-image&quot;&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;flex xs-flex-column&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;subbuzz__attribution js-subbuzz__attribution xs-text-6 xs-block&quot;&gt;Said Khatib / AFP / Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;subbuzz__description&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mohammed Dahlan on a video conference last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;subbuzz subbuzz-text xs-mb4 xs-relative&quot; data-module=&quot;subbuzz-text&quot; readability=&quot;64&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Golan, who sports a full beard and smokes Marlboro Red cigarettes, radiates enthusiasm. A good salesman is how one former CIA official described him. Golan himself, who is well-read and often cites philosophers and novelists, quotes André Malraux: “Man is not what he thinks he is but what he hides.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Golan says he was educated in France, joined the French Foreign Legion, and has traveled around the world, often fighting or carrying out security contracts. In Belgrade, he says, he got to know the infamous paramilitary fighter and gangster Željko Ražnatović, better known as Arkan, who was assassinated in 2001. “I have a lot of respect for Arkan,” he told BuzzFeed News.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BuzzFeed News was unable to verify parts of Golan’s biography, including his military service, but Gilmore and another US special operations veteran who has been with him in the field said it’s clear he has soldiering experience. He is considered competent, ruthless, and calculating, said the former CIA official. He’s “prone to exaggeration,” said another former CIA officer, but “for crazy shit he’s the kind of guy you hire.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;subbuzz subbuzz-pullquote xs-relative col xs-col-12 xs-z1 xs-mb4 md-mb2 md-col-5 md-pr4&quot; data-module=&quot;subbuzz-quote&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;For crazy shit he’s the kind of guy you hire.”&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;subbuzz subbuzz-text xs-mb4 xs-relative&quot; data-module=&quot;subbuzz-text&quot; readability=&quot;70.049543676662&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dahlan, who did not respond to multiple messages sent through associates, grew up in a refugee camp in Gaza, and during the 1980s intifada he became a major political player. In the ’90s he was named the Palestinian Authority’s head of security in Gaza, overseeing a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2007/07/15/magazine/15HAMAS-t.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;harsh crackdown on Hamas in 1995 and 1996&lt;/a&gt;. He later met President George W. Bush and developed strong ties to the CIA, meeting the agency’s director, George Tenet, several times. Dahlan was once touted as a possible leader of the Palestinian Authority, but in 2007 he fell from grace, accused by the Palestinian Authority of corruption and by Hamas of cooperating with the CIA and Israel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A man without a country, he fled to the UAE. There he &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ft.com/content/e943240e-a21d-11e4-aba2-00144feab7de&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;reportedly&lt;/a&gt; remade himself as a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jpost.com/Blogs/A-Mid-East-Journal/The-controversial-Mohammed-Dahlan-463624&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;key adviser&lt;/a&gt; to Crown Prince Mohammed bin Zayed Al Nahyan, or MBZ, known as the true ruler of Abu Dhabi. The former CIA officer who knows Dahlan said, “The UAE took him in as their pit bull.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, over lunch in the officers’ club, the pit bull challenged his visitors to tell him what was so special about fighters from America. Why were they any better than Emirati soldiers?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Golan replied with bravado. Wanting Dahlan to know that he could shoot, train, run, and fight better than anyone in the UAE’s military, Golan said: Give me your best man and I’ll beat him. Anyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Palestinian gestured to an attentive young female aide sitting nearby. She’s my best man, Dahlan said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The joke released the tension, and the men settled down. Get the spaghetti, recommended Dahlan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;subbuzz subbuzz-image xs-mb4 xs-relative subbuzz-image--outset-center&quot; data-module=&quot;subbuzz-image&quot;&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;flex xs-flex-column&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;subbuzz__attribution js-subbuzz__attribution xs-text-6 xs-block&quot;&gt;Taehoon Kim for BuzzFeed News; Courtesy Abraham Golan&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;subbuzz__description&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Left: Gilmore. Right: Golan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;subbuzz subbuzz-text xs-mb4 xs-relative&quot; data-module=&quot;subbuzz-text&quot; readability=&quot;47.37345971564&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The UAE, with&lt;/strong&gt; vast wealth but only about 1 million citizens, relies on migrant workers from all over the world to do everything from cleaning its toilets to teaching its university students. Its military is no different, paying lavish sums to eager US defense companies and former generals. The US Department of Defense has approved at least &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ciponline.org/images/uploads/actions/Bill_Hartung_UAE_Arms_Report_92117.docx.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;$27 billion in arms sales and defense services to the UAE&lt;/a&gt; since 2009.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Retired US Army Gen. Stanley McChrystal once signed up to sit on the board of a UAE military company. Former Navy SEAL and Vice Admiral Robert Harward runs the UAE division of Lockheed Martin. The security executive Erik Prince, now entangled in special counsel Robert Mueller’s investigation into Russian election interference, set up shop there for a time, helping the UAE hire Colombian mercenaries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And as BuzzFeed News reported earlier this year, the country embeds foreigners in its military and gave the rank of major general to an American lieutenant colonel, Stephen Toumajan, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/aramroston/stephen-toumajan-general-us-uae-yemen-contractor&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;placing him in command of a branch of its armed forces.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;subbuzz subbuzz-pullquote xs-relative col xs-col-12 xs-z1 xs-mb4 md-mb2 md-col-5 md-pr4&quot; data-module=&quot;subbuzz-quote&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The US draws the line at combat; it does not hire mercenaries to carry out attacks. But that line can get blurry.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;subbuzz subbuzz-text xs-mb4 xs-relative&quot; data-module=&quot;subbuzz-text&quot; readability=&quot;51.055214723926&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The UAE is hardly alone in using defense contractors; in fact, it is the US that helped pioneer the worldwide move toward privatizing the military. The Pentagon pays companies to carry out many traditional functions, from feeding soldiers to maintaining weapons to guarding convoys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The US draws the line at combat; it does not hire mercenaries to carry out attacks or engage directly in warfare. But that line can get blurry. Private firms &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fbo.gov/index?s=opportunity&amp;amp;mode=form&amp;amp;tab=core&amp;amp;id=6247a35a5d9816a4b5e4f067b8758ecc&amp;amp;_cview=0&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;provide heavily armed security details&lt;/a&gt; to protect diplomats in war zones or intelligence officers in the field. Such contractors can engage in firefights, as they did in Benghazi, Libya, when two contractors died in 2012 defending a CIA post. But, officially, the mission was protection, not warfare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outside the US, hiring mercenaries to conduct combat missions is rare, though it has happened. In Nigeria, a strike force reportedly led by longtime South African mercenary Eeben Barlow moved successfully &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/worldnews/africaandindianocean/nigeria/11596210/South-African-mercenaries-secret-war-on-Boko-Haram.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;against the Islamist militant group Boko Haram&lt;/a&gt; in 2015. A company Barlow founded, Executive Outcomes, was credited with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/1999/02/04/opinion/saving-sierra-leone-at-a-price.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;crushing the bloody RUF rebel force&lt;/a&gt; in war-torn Sierra Leone in the 1990s. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;subbuzz subbuzz-image xs-mb4 xs-relative col xs-col-12 xs-z1 md-col-6 xs-mb4 md-mb2 md-pl3 md-float-right subbuzz-image--align-right&quot; data-module=&quot;subbuzz-image&quot;&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;flex xs-flex-column&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;subbuzz__attribution js-subbuzz__attribution xs-text-6 xs-block&quot;&gt;BuzzFeed News&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;subbuzz subbuzz-text xs-mb4 xs-relative&quot; data-module=&quot;subbuzz-text&quot; readability=&quot;71&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But over spaghetti with Dahlan, Golan and Gilmore were offering an extraordinary form of mercenary service. This was not providing security details, nor was it even traditional military fighting or counterinsurgency warfare. It was, both Golan and Gilmore say, targeted killing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gilmore said he doesn’t remember anyone using the word “assassinations” specifically. But it was clear from that first meeting, he said, that this was not about capturing or detaining Al-Islah’s leadership. “It was very specific that we were targeting,” said Gilmore. Golan said he was explicitly told to help “disrupt and destruct” Al-Islah, which he calls a “political branch of a terrorist organization.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He and Gilmore promised they could pull together a team with the right skillset, and quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the weeks after that lunch, they settled on terms. The team would receive $1.5 million a month, Golan and Gilmore told BuzzFeed News. They’d earn bonuses for successful kills — Golan and Gilmore declined to say how much — but they would carry out their first operation at half price to prove what they could do. Later, Spear would also train UAE soldiers in commando tactics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Golan and Gilmore had another condition: They wanted to be incorporated into the UAE Armed Forces. And they wanted their weapons — and their target list — to come from uniformed military officers. That was “for juridical reasons,” Golan said. “Because if the shit hits the fan,” he explained, the UAE uniform and dog tags would mark “the difference between a mercenary and a military man.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dahlan and the UAE government signed off on the deal, Golan and Gilmore said, and Spear Operations Group got to work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;subbuzz subbuzz-image xs-mb4 xs-relative subbuzz-image--outset-both&quot; data-module=&quot;subbuzz-image&quot;&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;flex xs-flex-column&quot; readability=&quot;7.5&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;subbuzz__attribution js-subbuzz__attribution xs-text-6 xs-block&quot;&gt;Courtesy Abraham Golan&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;subbuzz__description&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Standing in front of a UAE military plane are Gilmore (middle left), Golan (middle right), and two soldiers on their mercenary team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;subbuzz subbuzz-text xs-mb4 xs-relative&quot; data-module=&quot;subbuzz-text&quot; readability=&quot;132.49016100179&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Back in the US&lt;/strong&gt;, Golan and Gilmore started rounding up ex-soldiers for the first, proof-of-concept job. Spear Operations Group is a small company — nothing like the security behemoths such as Garda World Security or Constellis — but it had a huge supply of talent to choose from.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A little-known consequence of the war on terror, and in particular the 17 combined years of US warfare in Iraq and Afghanistan, is that the number of special operations forces has more than doubled since 9/11, from 33,000 to 70,000. That’s a vast pool of crack soldiers selected, trained, and combat-tested by the most elite units of the US military, such as the Navy SEALs and Army Rangers. Some special operations reservists are known to engage in for-profit soldiering, said a high-level SEAL officer who asked not to be named. “I know a number of them who do this sort of thing,” he said. If the soldiers are not on active duty, he added, they are not obligated to report what they’re doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the options for special operations veterans and reservists aren’t what they were in the early years of the Iraq War. Private security work, mostly protecting US government officials in hostile environments, lacks the excitement of actual combat and is more “like driving Miss Daisy with an M4” rifle, as one former contractor put it. It also doesn’t pay what it used to. While starting rates for elite veterans on high-end security jobs used to be $700 or $800 a day, contractors said, now those rates have dropped to about $500 a day. Golan and Gilmore said they were offering their American fighters $25,000 a month — about $830 a day — plus bonuses, a generous sum in almost any market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, the Yemen gig crossed into uncharted territory, and some of the best soldiers declined. “It was still gray enough,” Gilmore said, “that a lot of guys were like, ‘Ah, I’m good.’ ”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gilmore himself said he has an imperfect record. During a live-fire training mission he led, back in his Navy days, he says he accidentally shot another SEAL. Gilmore said that’s what prompted him to leave the Navy, in 2011. His last major job before joining Spear was &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.marketwired.com/press-release/montalvo-spirits-appoints-isaac-gilmore-as-chief-business-development-officer-otcqb-tqla-1917210.htm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;as an executive&lt;/a&gt; at an artisanal Tequila company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That stain on his military career, he said, is also what prompted him to take the risk with Spear: He was an outsider, he wasn’t in the reserves, and he didn’t have a pension to worry about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end of 2015, Golan, who led the operation, and Gilmore had cobbled together a team of a dozen men. Three were American special ops veterans, and most of the rest were former French Foreign Legionnaires, who were cheaper: only about $10,000 per month, as Gilmore remembers it, less than half of what he and Golan said they budgeted for their American counterparts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They gathered at a hotel near Teterboro Airport in New Jersey. They were dressed in an assortment of military fatigues, some in camouflage, some in black. Some were bearded and muscled, others tattooed and wiry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it was time to go, they convinced the hotel staff to give them the US flag flying outside, Gilmore said. In a makeshift ceremony, they folded it up into a small triangle and took it with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They also packed a few weeks’ worth of military “meals ready to eat,” body armor, communications gear, and medical equipment. Gilmore said he brought a utility knife with a special crimping tool to prepare the blasting caps on explosives. The team was sure to stock up on whiskey, too — three cases of Basil Hayden’s since it would be impossible to get any alcohol in Yemen, let alone the good stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On December 15, they boarded a chartered Gulfstream G550. Once airborne, Gilmore walked to the cockpit and told the pilots that there was a slight change to their flight plan. After refueling in Scotland, they wouldn’t be flying to Abu Dhabi’s main commercial airport but to a UAE military base in the desert.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;subbuzz subbuzz-image xs-mb4 xs-relative subbuzz-image--outset-both&quot; data-module=&quot;subbuzz-image&quot;&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;flex xs-flex-column&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;subbuzz__attribution js-subbuzz__attribution xs-text-6 xs-block&quot;&gt;Obtained by BuzzFeed News&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;subbuzz__description&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Left: Business cards for Spear Operations Group; Right: Gilmore's dog tags&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;subbuzz subbuzz-text xs-mb4 xs-relative&quot; data-module=&quot;subbuzz-text&quot; readability=&quot;52&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;From that base&lt;/strong&gt;, the mercenaries took a UAE Air Force transport plane to another base in Assab, Eritrea. During that flight, Gilmore recalled, a uniformed Emirati officer briefed them and handed them a hit list — 23 cards with 23 names and 23 faces. Each card featured rudimentary intelligence: the person’s role in Yemeni politics, for example, or grid coordinates for a residence or two.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gilmore said some were members of Al-Islah, some were clerics, and some were out-and-out terrorists — but he conceded he couldn’t be sure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BuzzFeed News has obtained one of the target cards. On it is a man’s name, photograph, telephone number, and other information. At the top right is the insignia of the UAE Presidential Guard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;subbuzz subbuzz-image xs-mb4 xs-relative col xs-col-12 xs-z1 md-col-8 xs-mb4 md-mb2 md-pr3 subbuzz-image--outset-left&quot; data-module=&quot;subbuzz-image&quot;&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;flex xs-flex-column&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;subbuzz__attribution js-subbuzz__attribution xs-text-6 xs-block&quot;&gt;Obtained by BuzzFeed News&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;subbuzz subbuzz-text xs-mb4 xs-relative&quot; data-module=&quot;subbuzz-text&quot; readability=&quot;117.69547325103&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conspicuously absent is why anyone wanted him dead, or even what group he was associated with. The man could not be reached for comment, and it is not known if he is alive or dead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assassinations have historically played a limited part in US warfare and foreign policy. In 1945, “Wild Bill” Donovan, the director of the CIA’s predecessor agency, the OSS, was handed a finalized plan to deploy kill teams across Europe to attack Nazi leaders such as Hitler, Himmler, and Goering, as well as SS officers with a rank of major or above, according to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Wild-Bill-Donovan-Spymaster-Espionage/dp/1416567445/ref=tmm_hrd_swatch_0?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1539032910&amp;amp;sr=1-1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;a biography of Donovan&lt;/a&gt; by Douglas Waller. But the OSS chief got queasy about the “wholesale assassination” project and canceled it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the Cold War, the CIA played a role in plots to assassinate foreign leaders, such as Patrice Lumumba of the Democratic Republic of Congo, Rafael Trujillo of the Dominican Republic, and Ngo Dinh Diem of South Vietnam. Later in the Vietnam War, the US launched the Phoenix program, in which the CIA often teamed up with US military units to “neutralize” — or, critics say, assassinate — Viet Cong leaders. Even so, targeted killings were not a central pillar of US military strategy in Vietnam. And after Congress exposed CIA activities in the 1970s, the US banned assassinations of foreign leaders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then came the war on terror.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under President George W. Bush, the CIA and the military used drones to kill terrorists, and the CIA developed covert assassination capabilities. President Barack Obama halted the agency’s secret assassination program but drastically ramped up the use of drone strikes in Pakistan, Yemen, Afghanistan, and Somalia. Soon the CIA and the military were using the aircraft — piloted remotely using video monitors — to kill people whose names the US didn’t even know, through “signature strikes” based solely on a target’s associations and activities. President Donald Trump has further loosened the rules for drone strikes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But while private contractors often maintain the drones and sometimes even pilot them, there is one action they reportedly cannot take: Only a uniformed officer can push the button that fires the drone’s missile and kills the target.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With organized assassinations having become a routine part of war in the region, the UAE developed its own appetite. The country had begun to flex more military muscle, and by 2015 it had become a major player in the war in Yemen. It quickly targeted Al-Islah, an Islamist political party that won &lt;a href=&quot;https://worldview.stratfor.com/article/uaes-ulterior-motives-yemen&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;more than 20%&lt;/a&gt; of the vote in Yemen’s most recent parliamentary election, held in 2003.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elisabeth Kendall, an expert on Yemen at the University of Oxford, points out that unlike al-Qaeda or other terrorist groups, which try to seize power through violence, Al-Islah participates in the political process. But, she said, the US rationale for drone strikes has legitimized other countries’ pursuit of their own assassinations: “The whole very watery, vague notion of a war on terror has left the door wide open to any regime saying, ‘This is all a war on terror.’ ”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the top of the deck of targets they got from the UAE, Gilmore and Golan said, was Mayo, Al-Islah’s leader in Aden. Mayo had close-cropped hair, wire-rimmed glasses, and a wisp of goatee to go with his mustache. He had spoken out against US drone strikes in Yemen, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/middle_east/in-yemen-us-airstrikes-breed-anger-and-sympathy-for-al-qaeda/2012/05/29/gJQAUmKI0U_story_2.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;telling the Washington Post in 2012&lt;/a&gt; that rather than stopping al-Qaeda they had instead fueled its growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Asked about the ethics and legality of killing unarmed Al-Islah political leaders, as opposed to armed terrorists, Golan responded, “I think this dichotomy is a purely intellectual dichotomy.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;subbuzz subbuzz-pullquote xs-relative col xs-col-12 xs-z1 xs-mb4 md-mb2 md-col-5 md-pl4 md-float-right&quot; data-module=&quot;subbuzz-quote&quot; readability=&quot;5.4271844660194&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;pullquote js-subbuzz__title-text&quot; readability=&quot;27.553398058252&quot;&gt;Got a tip? You can email tips@buzzfeed.com. To learn how to reach us securely, go to &lt;a href=&quot;https://tips.buzzfeed.com&quot;&gt;tips.buzzfeed.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;subbuzz subbuzz-text xs-mb4 xs-relative&quot; data-module=&quot;subbuzz-text&quot; readability=&quot;66&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Golan said he models his assassination business on Israel’s targeted killing program, which has been underway since the country was founded, and which, despite some high-profile errors and embarrassments, he claims is done properly. He argues there are some terrorist enemies so dangerous and implacable — and so difficult to arrest — that assassination is the best solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He insists his team is not a murder squad. As evidence, Golan recounted how, as their mission continued, the UAE provided names with no affiliation to Al-Islah or any group, terrorist or otherwise. Golan said he declined to pursue those individuals, a claim that could not be verified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The people Spear did target, he and Gilmore said, were legitimate because they were selected by the government of the UAE, an ally of the United States that was engaged in a military action supported by the US. Gilmore said that he and Golan told the UAE they would never act against US interests. And Golan claimed that, based on his military experience, he could tell if a target was a terrorist after just a week or two of surveillance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, Gilmore acknowledged that some of the targets may have been people who merely fell out of favor with the ruling family. Referring to the country’s Crown Prince Mohammed bin Zayed, Gilmore said, “There is the possibility that the target would be someone who MBZ doesn’t like. We’d try to make sure that didn’t happen.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;subbuzz subbuzz-image xs-mb4 xs-relative subbuzz-image--outset-both&quot; data-module=&quot;subbuzz-image&quot;&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;flex xs-flex-column&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;subbuzz__attribution js-subbuzz__attribution xs-text-6 xs-block&quot;&gt;Obtained by BuzzFeed News&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;subbuzz subbuzz-text xs-mb4 xs-relative&quot; data-module=&quot;subbuzz-text&quot; readability=&quot;61&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When they reached&lt;/strong&gt; Aden, the mercenaries were issued weapons. They were surprised at the low quality — shitty Chinese assault rifles and RPGs, according to Gilmore and Golan.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At some point, they also received their official designation in the Emirati military. Golan was named a colonel and Gilmore a lieutenant colonel, a heady “promotion” for a man who had been discharged from the Navy as a petty officer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gilmore still has his UAE dog tag, a rectangle of white gold imprinted with his blood type, AB-negative. His name is in English on one side and in Arabic on the other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using sources handed to them by the UAE’s intelligence network, Gilmore said, the team established Mayo’s daily life pattern — the home he lived in, the mosque he prayed at, the businesses he frequented.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Christmas passed with the mercenaries sharing their whiskey and plotting how exactly they should kill Mayo. A raid, a bomb, a sniper? “We had five or six courses of action to go after him,” Gilmore said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;subbuzz subbuzz-pullquote xs-relative col xs-col-12 xs-z1 xs-mb4 md-mb2 md-col-5 md-pr4&quot; data-module=&quot;subbuzz-quote&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Christmas passed with the mercenaries sharing their whiskey and plotting how exactly they should kill Mayo.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;subbuzz subbuzz-text xs-mb4 xs-relative&quot; data-module=&quot;subbuzz-text&quot; readability=&quot;73&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After some quick surveillance of the Al-Islah headquarters, they decided on explosives. Gilmore said he drew the mission plan out on the floor of the tent, with a black Sharpie. It showed the angles of approach, the attack, and, most important, the escape route.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After he briefed his colleagues, Gilmore took out his knife, cut through the tough tent fabric, and burned the mission plan. “I don’t want any of that with my handwriting on it floating around,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two days later, Gilmore recalled, they got the word that Mayo was in his office for a large meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Golan gathered with Gilmore, another ex-SEAL, and a former Delta Force soldier, for the mission. They had left behind their wallets and all identifying information, and they wore an assortment of motley uniforms — Gilmore said he wore a baseball hat and Salomon Speedcross trail-running shoes, with a chest rig full of spare ammunition magazines. All held AK-47s, and one had the bomb loaded with shrapnel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gilmore, Golan, and two others climbed into an armored SUV with a plainclothes Emirati soldier at the wheel. The French Foreign Legion soldiers were in another SUV, which would stop a short distance from the attack site, ready to rush in should the Americans get into a jam. The gates of their base opened and they pulled out onto the nighttime streets of Aden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;subbuzz subbuzz-image xs-mb4 xs-relative xs-mb1&quot; data-module=&quot;subbuzz-image&quot;&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;flex xs-flex-column&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;subbuzz__attribution js-subbuzz__attribution xs-text-6 xs-block&quot;&gt;Provided to BuzzFeed News&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;subbuzz__description&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Golan with a member of his mercenary team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;subbuzz subbuzz-text xs-mb4 xs-relative&quot; data-module=&quot;subbuzz-text&quot; readability=&quot;71&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It’s unclear exactly&lt;/strong&gt; what went wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right before the mercenary reached the front door, carrying the explosive charge meant to kill Mayo, one of his fellow fighters at the back of the SUV opened fire, shooting along the backstreet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a drone high overhead, and the video, obtained by BuzzFeed News, shows gunfire but not what the American is shooting at. The drone video doesn’t show anyone shooting back at the mercenaries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gilmore said he himself fired at someone on the street, but his gun jammed. He said he wasn’t sure who was firing at them. In any case, the mercenary carrying the explosive to the building carried on despite the commotion around him — for a full 20 seconds, the video shows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make their escape, the mercenaries ran into UAE military vehicles. Then suddenly there was an explosion — the bomb on the door — followed by a second, bigger one. The second explosion was the mercenaries’ SUV. Gilmore and Golan say they booby-trapped it to disguise the source of the bomb, confuse Al-Islah, and add to the destruction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The team returned to base without something they all knew they needed. US special operations forces call it positive identification, or “PID” — proof that Mayo was dead. A photo, for example, or DNA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“That caused some problems with Dahlan,” Gilmore recalled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;subbuzz subbuzz-image xs-mb4 xs-relative subbuzz-image--outset-both&quot; data-module=&quot;subbuzz-image&quot;&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;flex xs-flex-column&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;subbuzz__attribution js-subbuzz__attribution xs-text-6 xs-block&quot;&gt;Obtained by BuzzFeed News&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;subbuzz subbuzz-text xs-mb4 xs-relative&quot; data-module=&quot;subbuzz-text&quot; readability=&quot;60.28659160696&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Still, Mayo seemed&lt;/strong&gt; to have vanished. He rarely posted on his &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/anssafaden&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; page, and for a time, Gilmore and Golan said, he wasn’t seen in public.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet Al-Islah didn’t announce his death, as it would when other members got assassinated. The reason, a spokesperson for Al-Islah said in a phone interview, is that Mayo is alive — he had left the building 10 minutes before the attack and as of July was living in Saudi Arabia. No one, the spokesperson said, died in the mercenaries’ assault.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mayo seems to have reemerged in Yemeni politics. In May he was nominated to a post by the president of Yemen, Abed Rabbo Mansour Hadi, according to Charles Schmitz, a specialist on the Middle East and Yemen at Towson University in Maryland. Schmitz said he found a recent photo of Mayo &lt;a href=&quot;http://almasdaronline.com/article/98549&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;standing in a group&lt;/a&gt; with the UN envoy to Yemen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Golan maintains that, at the very least, Mayo was neutralized for a time. “For me it’s a success,” he said, “as long as the guy disappeared.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;subbuzz subbuzz-image xs-mb4 xs-relative subbuzz-image--outset-both&quot; data-module=&quot;subbuzz-image&quot;&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;flex xs-flex-column&quot; readability=&quot;7.5&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;subbuzz__attribution js-subbuzz__attribution xs-text-6 xs-block&quot;&gt;Nasser Awad / Reuters&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;subbuzz__description&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soldiers from the United Arab Emirates stand guard as military equipment is unloaded from a UAE military plane at the airport in Aden, Aug. 12, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;subbuzz subbuzz-text xs-mb4 xs-relative&quot; data-module=&quot;subbuzz-text&quot; readability=&quot;58.719848053181&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Even though it&lt;/strong&gt; failed to kill Mayo, the mercenaries’ bomb attack seems to have ushered in a new phase in the UAE’s war against Al-Islah. “It was the exclamation point that set the tone that Al-Islah was now going to be targeted,” said Schmitz.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Al-Islah spokesperson who spoke to BuzzFeed News recited the date by memory: December 29, 2015. “It was the first attack,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As 2016 progressed, those watching the deteriorating situation in Yemen began to notice that members of Al-Islah, and other clerics in Aden, were dropping dead at an alarming pace. “It does appear to be a targeted campaign,” said Gregory Johnsen of the Arabia Foundation, who in 2016 served on a UN panel investigating the Yemen war. “There have been 25 to 30 assassinations,” he said, though a few appear to be the work of ISIS. (Johnsen used to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.buzzfeed.com/gregorydjohnsen/how-i-escaped-a-kidnapping-attempt-in-yemen&quot;&gt;write&lt;/a&gt; for BuzzFeed News.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“There is a widespread belief on the ground,” said Kendall, the University of Oxford expert, “that the UAE is behind the assassination of Al-Islah officials and activists.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;subbuzz subbuzz-pullquote xs-relative col xs-col-12 xs-z1 xs-mb4 md-mb2 md-col-5 md-pr4&quot; data-module=&quot;subbuzz-quote&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Golan said his team killed several of the dead but refused to give an exact number or names.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;subbuzz subbuzz-text xs-mb4 xs-relative&quot; data-module=&quot;subbuzz-text&quot; readability=&quot;110.8814717477&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When BuzzFeed News read Gilmore the names of some of the dead, he nodded in recognition at two of them — “I could probably recognize their faces” — and said they were among the team’s targets. But he said he hadn’t been involved in killing them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Golan said his team killed several of the dead but refused to give an exact number or names. But after their first semi-botched mission, the mercenaries rebooted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They got rid of the French Foreign Legionnaires, replacing them with Americans. The Emiratis also provided them with better weapons and better equipment, Golan and Gilmore said: C4 explosives, pistols fitted with silencers, and high-end American-made M4 rifles. They were also outfitted with motorbikes they could use to scoot through Aden’s traffic and affix magnetized bombs to cars. All the equipment, they said, came from the UAE military.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gilmore stayed on for only a short time. He said he left Spear in April 2016. He and Golan declined to say why, but Gilmore said he wishes he had been more aggressive in Yemen. “If I could do it over again we would have been less risk-averse,” he said. “We could have done some amazing things — although we also could have done some amazing things and all ended up in jail.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One new member of the team, hired in early 2016, was the veteran of SEAL Team 6, Daniel Corbett, according to three sources and confirmed by photos. Corbett was a superb soldier, say those who know him, and had served multiple combat tours in Afghanistan and Iraq. He was still in the reserves, so the US military could deploy him at any moment; he collected a government salary; and he was supposed to report for monthly drills. And yet he was in Yemen on a private contract to work for a foreign military. It is unclear if he himself was involved in missions to assassinate anyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a mysterious development, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/aramroston/daniel-corbett-navy-seal-jail-serbia-mercenary-yemen&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Corbett is currently in jail in Serbia&lt;/a&gt;, where he is being investigated for illegal handgun possession. The American veteran has been held there since February 2018. Corbett could not be reached, and his lawyer did not respond to calls seeking comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As they went about their work in Yemen, the mercenaries stayed in huts, sleeping in cots. Some carried distinctive weapons for potential close-in fighting. One, according to photographs, carried two knives on his belt that he could draw cross-handed. Another carried a small tomahawk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The team began to develop what Gilmore called “esprit de corps.” They flew a makeshift flag featuring a skull and crossed swords — a kind of Jolly Roger on a black background — and painted that emblem onto their military vehicles and their living quarters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much about the Spear mercenary team remains unknown, and some who participated made clear they have no desire to shed light on what went down. Asked if he’d been deployed in the Yemen mission, one of the Americans replied, “If I was, you know I can’t discuss it.” The former Green Beret who was sucking a lollipop during the mission sent BuzzFeed News a text message: “A big story for you could be a tragic story for the cast of characters; especially if they are good men doing what was right but not necessarily legal.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For his part, Gilmore said he “would have preferred that this stay off the radar.” But he decided to speak to BuzzFeed News because “once this comes out there’s no way that I’m going to stay out of it, so I’d prefer to own it. And I’m not going to try to hide from what I did.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s still,” he said, “some variety of the future of warfare.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gilmore is out of the mercenary business. He has since found himself in another gray-zone line of work, albeit one that’s far less dangerous. He said he’s with a California company that plans to make cannabis oil for vaporizers. ●&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;subbuzz subbuzz__section-divider subbuzz__section-divider--thin xs-block xs-mb4 xs-col-11&quot;/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;subbuzz subbuzz-text xs-mb4 xs-relative&quot; data-module=&quot;subbuzz-text&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jules Darmanin in Paris contributed reporting to this story.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 20:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>georgecmu</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/aramroston/mercenaries-assassination-us-yemen-uae-spear-golan-dahlan</og:url>
<og:image>https://img.buzzfeed.com/buzzfeed-static/static/2018-10/15/21/enhanced/buzzfeed-prod-web-06/original-5957-1539652720-3.jpg?crop=815:427;63,157</og:image>
<og:title>Exclusive: American Mercenaries Went To Yemen To Carry Out Targeted Killings</og:title>
<og:description>“There was a targeted assassination program in Yemen. I was running it. We did it.”</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/aramroston/mercenaries-assassination-us-yemen-uae-spear-golan-dahlan?fbclid=IwAR08TqB-uGvRrRsnylMTMTiHmvuPEdQ0hj0xFSBSH3tT4SN9S3VBNqf4nbA</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>What I loved about Paul Allen</title>
<link>https://www.gatesnotes.com/About-Bill-Gates/Remembering-Paul-Allen?WT.mc_id=10_16_2018_10_PaulAllen_BG-TW_&amp;WT.tsrc=BGTW&amp;linkId=58288095</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.gatesnotes.com/About-Bill-Gates/Remembering-Paul-Allen?WT.mc_id=10_16_2018_10_PaulAllen_BG-TW_&amp;WT.tsrc=BGTW&amp;linkId=58288095</guid>
<description>&lt;div id=&quot;content_0_articlePanel&quot; readability=&quot;127&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul Allen, one of my oldest friends and the first business partner I ever had, died yesterday. I want to extend my condolences to his sister, Jody, his extended family, and his many friends and colleagues around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I met Paul when I was in 7&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; grade, and it changed my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I looked up to him right away. He was two years ahead of me in school, really tall, and proved to be a genius with computers. (Later, he also had a very cool beard, which I could never pull off.) We started hanging out together, especially once the first computer arrived at our school. We spent just about all our free time messing around with any computer we could get our hands on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here we are in school. That’s Paul on the left, our friend Ric Weiland, and me on the right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;494&quot; alt=&quot;Remembering Paul Allen&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; src=&quot;https://www.gatesnotes.com/-/media/Images/Articles/About-Bill-Gates/Remembering-Paul-Allen/paul-allen-memoriam_2018_inline1_800px_v1.jpg?la=en&amp;amp;hash=68A75EDEEA6FFE44CA3E297094A40693E148AC1B&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul foresaw that computers would change the world. Even in high school, before any of us knew what a personal computer was, he was predicting that computer chips would get super-powerful and would eventually give rise to a whole new industry. That insight of his was the cornerstone of everything we did together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, Microsoft would never have happened without Paul. In December 1974, he and I were both living in the Boston area—he was working, and I was going to college. One day he came and got me, insisting that I rush over to a nearby newsstand with him. When we arrived, he showed me the cover of the January issue of &lt;em&gt;Popular Electronics&lt;/em&gt;. It featured a new computer called the Altair 8800, which ran on a powerful new chip. Paul looked at me and said: “This is happening without us!” That moment marked the end of my college career and the beginning of our new company, Microsoft. It happened because of Paul.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the first person I ever partnered with, Paul set a standard that few other people could meet. He had a wide-ranging mind and a special talent for explaining complicated subjects in a simple way. Since I was lucky enough to know him from such a young age, I saw that before the rest of the world did. As a teenager, I was curious about (of all things) gasoline. What did “refining” even mean? I turned to the most knowledgeable person I knew. Paul explained it in a super-clear and interesting way. It was just one of many enlightening conversations we would have over the coming decades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul was cooler than I was. He was really into Jimi Hendrix as a teenager, and I remember him playing &lt;em&gt;Are You Experienced?&lt;/em&gt; for me. I wasn’t experienced at much of anything back then, and Paul wanted to share this amazing music with me. That’s the kind of person he was. He loved life and the people around him, and it showed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sports was another passion that Paul loved to share with his friends. In later years he would take me to see his beloved Portland Trail Blazers and patiently helped me understand everything that was happening on the court.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;494&quot; alt=&quot;Remembering Paul Allen&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; src=&quot;https://www.gatesnotes.com/-/media/Images/Articles/About-Bill-Gates/Remembering-Paul-Allen/paul-allen-memoriam_2018_inline2_800px_v2.jpg?la=en&amp;amp;hash=37AD431C8EDB878B3B3C9790FCBE4275572F29C0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I think about Paul, I remember a passionate man who held his family and friends dear. I also remember a brilliant technologist and philanthropist who wanted to accomplish great things, and did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul deserved more time in life. He would have made the most of it. I will miss him tremendously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;PrevNextTabsHolder&quot; class=&quot;PrevNextTabsHolder&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;PrevNextTabs_PrevTab&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previous Article&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;PrevNextTabs_NextTab&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next Article&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;content_0_articlePrevNextCont&quot; readability=&quot;57&quot;&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;NEXT&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nextPrevText&quot;&gt;Can the Wi-Fi chip in your phone help feed the world?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 18:36:40 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>uknownuser</dc:creator>
<og:description>Bill Gates remembers his friend Paul Allen, a brilliant technologist and philanthropist.</og:description>
<og:image>https://www.gatesnotes.com/-/media/Images/Articles/About-Bill-Gates/Remembering-Paul-Allen/paul-allen-memoriam_2018_1200px_v2.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>What I loved about Paul Allen</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.gatesnotes.com/About-Bill-Gates/Remembering-Paul-Allen</og:url>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.gatesnotes.com/About-Bill-Gates/Remembering-Paul-Allen?WT.mc_id=10_16_2018_10_PaulAllen_BG-TW_&amp;WT.tsrc=BGTW&amp;linkId=58288095</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>China May Have $5.8T in Hidden Debt with ‘Titanic’ Risks</title>
<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-10-16/china-may-have-5-8-trillion-in-hidden-debt-with-titanic-risks</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-10-16/china-may-have-5-8-trillion-in-hidden-debt-with-titanic-risks</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-10-16/china-may-have-5-8-trillion-in-hidden-debt-with-titanic-risks&quot;&gt;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-10-16/china-may-have-5-8-trillion-in-hidden-debt-with-titanic-risks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=18231756&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=18231756&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 333&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 156&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 18:17:55 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>aswaedr</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bloomberg.com/tosv2.html?vid=&amp;uuid=c5b7ea50-d19f-11e8-8c37-6541b02bdac1&amp;url=L25ld3MvYXJ0aWNsZXMvMjAxOC0xMC0xNi9jaGluYS1tYXktaGF2ZS01LTgtdHJpbGxpb24taW4taGlkZGVuLWRlYnQtd2l0aC10aXRhbmljLXJpc2tz</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>GitHub launches Actions, its workflow automation tool</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2018/10/16/github-launches-actions-its-workflow-automation-tool/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2018/10/16/github-launches-actions-its-workflow-automation-tool/</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;speakable-summary&quot;&gt;For the longest time, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; was all about storing source code and sharing it either with the rest of the world or your colleagues. Today, the company, which is in the process of being acquired by Microsoft, is taking a step in a different but related direction by &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.github.com/2018-10-16-future-of-software/&quot;&gt;launching GitHub Actions&lt;/a&gt;. Actions allow developers to not just host code on the platform but also run it. We’re not talking about a new cloud to rival AWS here, but instead about something more akin to a very flexible IFTTT for developers who want to automate their development workflows, whether that is sending notifications or building a full continuous integration and delivery pipeline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a big deal for &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://crunchbase.com/organization/github&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;github&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;. Indeed, Sam Lambert, GitHub’s head of platform, described it to me as “the biggest shift we’ve had in the history of GitHub.” He likened it to shortcuts in iOS — just more flexible. “Imagine an infinitely more flexible version of shortcut, hosted on GitHub and designed to allow anyone to create an action inside a container to augment and connect their workflow.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;breakout aligncenter size-full wp-image-1733557&quot; src=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/IMG_20181016_100903.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;768&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GitHub users can use &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/features/actions&quot;&gt;Actions&lt;/a&gt; to build their continuous delivery pipelines, and the company expects that many will do so. And that’s pretty much the first thing most people will think about when they hear about this new project. GitHub’s own description of Actions in today’s announcement makes definitely fits that bill, too. “Easily build, package, release, update, and deploy your project in any language—on GitHub or any external system—without having to run code yourself,” the company writes. But it’s about more than that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I see CI/CD as one narrow use case of actions. It’s so, so much more,” Lambert stressed. “And I think it’s going to revolutionize DevOps because people are now going to build best in breed deployment workflows for specific applications and frameworks, and those become the de facto standard shared on GitHub. […] It’s going to do everything we did for open source again for the DevOps space and for all those different parts of that workflow ecosystem.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;breakout aligncenter size-full wp-image-1733561&quot; src=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/46967252-9d15c200-d075-11e8-886f-19af1cf545fd.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;577&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That means you can use it to send a text message through Twilio every time someone uses the ‘urgent issue’ tag in your repository, for example. Or you can write a one-line command that searches your repository with a basic grep command. Or really run any other code you want to because all you have to do to turn any code in your repository into an Action is to write a Docker file for it so that GitHub can run it. “As long as there is a Docker file, we can build it, run in and connect it to your workflow,” Lambert explained. If you don’t want to write a Docker file, though, there’s also a visual editor you can use to build your workflow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Corey Wilkerson, GitHub’s head of product engineering also noted, many of these Actions already exist in repositories on GitHub today. And there are now over 96 million of those on GitHub, so that makes for a lot of potential actions that will be available from the start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Actions, which is now in limited public beta, developers can set up the workflow to build, package, release, update and deploy their code without having to run the code themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now developers could host those Actions themselves — they are just Docker containers, after all — but GitHub will also host and run the code for them. And that includes developers on the free open source plan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over time — and Lambert seemed to be in favor of this — GitHub could also allow developers to sell their workflows and Actions through the GitHub marketplace. For now, that’s not an option, but it it’s definitely that’s something the company has been thinking about. Lambert also noted that this could be a way for open source developers who don’t want to build an enterprise version of their tools (and the sales force that goes with that) to monetize their efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While GitHub will make its own actions available to developers, this is an open platform and others in the GitHub community can contribute their own actions, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GitHub will slowly open Actions to developers, starting with daily batches for the time being. You can sign up for access &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/features/actions&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to Actions, GitHub also announced a number of other new features on its platform. As the company stressed during today’s event, it’s mission is to make the life of developers easier — and most of the new features may be small but do indeed make it easier for developers to do their jobs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;breakout aligncenter size-full wp-image-1733542&quot; src=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/IMG_20181016_094559.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;768&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what else is new? GitHub Connect, which connects the silo of GitHub Enterprise with the open source repositories on its public site, is now generally available, for example. GitHub Connect enables new features like unified search, that can search through both the open source code on the site and internal code, as well as a new Unified Business Identity feature that brings together the multiple GitHub Business accounts that many businesses now manage (thanks, shadow IT) under a single umbrella to improve billing, licensing and permissions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company also today launched three new courses in its Learning Lab that make it easier for developers to get started with the service, as well as a business version of Learning Lab for larger organizations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What’s maybe even more interesting for developers whose companies use GitHub Enterprise, though, is that the company will now allow admins to enable a new feature that will display those developers’ work as part of their public profile. Given that GitHub is now the de facto resume for many developers, that’s a big deal. Much of their work, after all, isn’t in open source or in building side projects, but in the day-to-day work at their companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;breakout aligncenter size-full wp-image-1733551&quot; src=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/IMG_20181016_095336.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;768&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other new features the company announced today are pretty much all about security. The new GitHub Security Advisory API, for example, makes it easier for developers to find threads in their code through automatic vulnerability scans, while the new security vulnerability alerts for Java and .NET projects now extend GitHub’s existing alerts to these two languages. If your developers are prone to putting their security tokens into public code, then you can now rest easier since GitHub will now also start scanning all public repositories for known token formats. If it finds one, it’ll alert you and you can set off to create a new one.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 17:08:24 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>moritzplassnig</dc:creator>
<og:title>GitHub launches Actions, its workflow automation tool</og:title>
<og:description>For the longest time, GitHub was all about storing source code and sharing it either with the rest of the world or your colleagues. Today, the company, which is in the process of being acquired by Microsoft, is taking a step in a different but related direction by launching GitHub Actions. Actions …</og:description>
<og:image>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/IMG_20181016_092551.jpg?w=533</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2018/10/16/github-launches-actions-its-workflow-automation-tool/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2018/10/16/github-launches-actions-its-workflow-automation-tool/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>MongoDB switches up its open source license</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2018/10/16/mongodb-switches-up-its-open-source-license/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2018/10/16/mongodb-switches-up-its-open-source-license/</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;speakable-summary&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mongodb.com/&quot;&gt;MongoDB&lt;/a&gt; is a bit miffed that some cloud providers — especially in Asia — are taking its open-source code and offering a hosted commercial version of its database to their users without playing by the open-source rules. To combat this, &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://crunchbase.com/organization/mongodb-inc&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;mongodb-inc&quot;&gt;MongoDB&lt;/a&gt; today announced it has issued a new software license, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mongodb.com/licensing/server-side-public-license&quot;&gt;Server Side Public License&lt;/a&gt; (SSPL), that will apply to all new releases of its MongoDB Community Server, as well as all patch fixes for prior versions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previously, MongoDB used the &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://crunchbase.com/organization/gnu&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;gnu&quot;&gt;GNU&lt;/a&gt; AGPLv3 license, but it has now submitted the SSPL for approval from the Open Source Initiative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For virtually all regular users who are currently using the community server, nothing changes because the changes to the license don’t apply to them. Instead, this is about what MongoDB sees as the misuse of the AGPLv3 license. “MongoDB was previously licensed under the GNU AGPLv3, which meant companies who wanted to run MongoDB as a publicly available service had to open source their software or obtain a commercial license from MongoDB,” the company explains. “However, MongoDB’s popularity has led some organizations to test the boundaries of the GNU AGPLv3.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So while the SSPL isn’t all that different from the GNU GPLv3, with all the usual freedoms to use, modify and redistribute the code (and virtually the same language), the SSPL explicitly states that anybody who wants to offer MongoDB as a service — or really any other software that uses this license — needs to either get a commercial license or open source the service to give back the community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The market is increasingly consuming software as a service, creating an incredible opportunity to foster a new wave of great open source server-side software. Unfortunately, once an open source project becomes interesting, it is too easy for cloud vendors who have not developed the software to capture all of the value but contribute nothing back to the community,” said Eliot Horowitz, the CTO and co-founder of MongoDB, in a statement. “We have greatly contributed to — and benefited from — open source and we are in a unique position to lead on an issue impacting many organizations. We hope this will help inspire more projects and protect open source innovation.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m sure this move will ruffle some feathers. It’s hard to discuss open-source licenses without getting religious about what this movement is all about. And because MongoDB is the commercial entity behind the software and manages outside contributions to the code, it does have a stronger grip on the actual code than other projects that are managed by a large open-source foundation, for example. For some, that alone is anathema to everything they think open source should stand for. For others, it’s simply a pragmatic way to develop software. Either way, though, this will kick off a discussion about how companies like MongoDB manage their open-source projects and how much control they can exert over how their code is used. I, for one, can’t wait to read the discussions on Hacker News today.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 14:05:56 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>zhuxuefeng1994</dc:creator>
<og:title>MongoDB switches up its open-source license</og:title>
<og:description>MongoDB is a bit miffed that some cloud providers — especially in Asia — are taking its open-source code and offering a hosted commercial version of its database to their users without playing by the open-source rules. To combat this, MongoDB today announced it has issued a new software…</og:description>
<og:image>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/GettyImages-903669404.jpg?w=711</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2018/10/16/mongodb-switches-up-its-open-source-license/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2018/10/16/mongodb-switches-up-its-open-source-license/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Alarming study shows massive insect loss</title>
<link>https://www.washingtonpost.com/science/2018/10/15/hyperalarming-study-shows-massive-insect-loss/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.washingtonpost.com/science/2018/10/15/hyperalarming-study-shows-massive-insect-loss/</guid>
<description>&lt;div data-elm-loc=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;inline-content inline-photo inline-photo-normal&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/LabF-N1sgw4O8eTGYehZf3DxgYI=/480x0/arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/PYVRQXBIWREUVHWHEOM5BFUHWY.jpeg&quot; data-hi-res-src=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/nmfwK5o-CEuSYDXv5Iw9kOeiOGo=/545x0/arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/PYVRQXBIWREUVHWHEOM5BFUHWY.jpeg&quot; data-low-res-src=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/LabF-N1sgw4O8eTGYehZf3DxgYI=/480x0/arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/PYVRQXBIWREUVHWHEOM5BFUHWY.jpeg&quot; data-raw-src=&quot;https://arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/PYVRQXBIWREUVHWHEOM5BFUHWY.jpeg&quot; data-threshold=&quot;480&quot; class=&quot;unprocessed&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pb-caption&quot;&gt;The emerald anole, one of the main insect eaters in the Luquillo forest of Puerto Rico. (Brad Lister/PNAS)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;author-sig-line-wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author-sig-line&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author-byline&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author-wrapper&quot; data-authorname=&quot;Ben Guarino&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;author-hover-card&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author-headshot&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/people/ben-guarino/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/sRtAbVvTZtGoZynEk4wVZyrXrVs=/200x200/s3.amazonaws.com/arc-authors/washpost/8b9ee559-3d29-421c-9d83-e18d4c69b1b4.png&quot; class=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;author-name&quot; href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/people/ben-guarino/&quot;&gt;Ben Guarino&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author-bio&quot;&gt;Reporter covering biology, genetics, nature, paleontology and the culture of science&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;author-timestamp&quot; itemprop=&quot;datePublished&quot; content=&quot;2018-10-15T03:00-500&quot;&gt;October 15&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;2&quot;&gt;Insects around the world are in a crisis, according to a small but growing number of long-term studies showing dramatic declines in invertebrate populations. A &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/cgi/doi/10.1073/pnas.1722477115&quot;&gt;new report&lt;/a&gt; suggests that the problem is more widespread than scientists realized. Huge numbers of bugs have been lost in a pristine national forest in Puerto Rico, the study found, and the forest’s insect-eating animals have gone missing, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;3&quot;&gt;In 2014, an international team of biologists estimated that, in the past 35 years, the abundance of invertebrates such as beetles and bees had &lt;a href=&quot;http://science.sciencemag.org/content/345/6195/401.full&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;decreased by 45 percent&lt;/a&gt;. In places where long-term insect data are available, mainly in Europe, insect numbers are plummeting. A study last year showed a 76 percent &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/speaking-of-science/wp/2017/10/18/this-is-very-alarming-flying-insects-vanish-from-nature-preserves/?utm_term=.646ed11d4999&quot;&gt;decrease in flying insects&lt;/a&gt; in the past few decades in German nature preserves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;4&quot;&gt;The latest report, published Monday in the Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences, shows that this startling loss of insect abundance extends to the Americas. The study’s authors implicate climate change in the loss of tropical invertebrates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;5&quot;&gt;“This study in PNAS is a real wake-up call — a clarion call — that the phenomenon could be much, much bigger, and across many more ecosystems,” said &lt;a href=&quot;http://hydrodictyon.eeb.uconn.edu/people/dwagner/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;David Wagner&lt;/a&gt;, an expert in invertebrate conservation at the University of Connecticut who was not involved with this research. He added: “This is one of the most disturbing articles I have ever read.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div data-elm-loc=&quot;6&quot; class=&quot;inline-content inline-video&quot;&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;7&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://science.rpi.edu/biology/faculty/brad-lister&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Bradford&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://science.rpi.edu/biology/faculty/brad-lister&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Lister&lt;/a&gt;, a biologist at Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute in New York, has been studying rain forest insects in Puerto Rico since the 1970s. If Puerto Rico is the island of enchantment — “la isla del encanto” — then its rain forest is “the enchanted forest on the enchanted isle,” he said. Birds and coqui frogs trill beneath a 50-foot-tall emerald canopy. The forest, named El Yunque, is well-protected. Spanish King Alfonso XII claimed the jungle as a 19th-century royal preserve. Decades later, Theodore Roosevelt made it a national reserve, and El Yunque remains the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fs.usda.gov/main/elyunque/about-forest&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;only tropical rain forest&lt;/a&gt; in the National Forest system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;8&quot;&gt;“We went down in ’76, ’77 expressly to measure the resources: the insects and the insectivores in the rain forest, the birds, the frogs, the lizards,” Lister said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;9&quot;&gt;He came back nearly 40 years later, with his colleague Andrés García, an ecologist at the National Autonomous University of Mexico. What the scientists did not see on their return troubled them. “Boy, it was immediately obvious when we went into that forest,” Lister said. Fewer birds flitted overhead. The butterflies, once abundant, had all but vanished.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;10&quot;&gt;García and Lister once again measured the forest’s insects and other invertebrates, a group called arthropods that includes spiders and centipedes. The researchers trapped arthropods on the ground in plates covered in a sticky glue, and raised several more plates about three feet into the canopy. The researchers also swept nets over the brush hundreds of times, collecting the critters that crawled through the vegetation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;11&quot;&gt;Each technique revealed the biomass (the dry weight of all the captured invertebrates) had significantly decreased from 1976 to the present day. The sweep sample biomass decreased to a fourth or an eighth of what it had been. Between January 1977 and January 2013, the catch rate in the sticky ground traps fell 60-fold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;12&quot;&gt;“Everything is dropping,” Lister said. The most common invertebrates in the rain forest — the moths, the butterflies, the grasshoppers, the spiders and others — are all far less abundant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;13&quot;&gt;“Holy crap,” Wagner said of the 60-fold loss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;14&quot;&gt;Louisiana State University entomologist &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lsuagcenter.com/profiles/tschowalter&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Timothy Schowalter&lt;/a&gt;, who is not an author of the recent report, has studied this forest since the 1990s. The new research is consistent with his data, as well as the European biomass studies. “It takes these long-term sites, with consistent sampling across a long period of time, to document these trends,” he said. “I find their data pretty compelling.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;15&quot;&gt;The study authors also trapped anole lizards, which eat arthropods, in the rain forest. They compared these numbers with counts from the 1970s. Anole biomass dropped by more than 30 percent. Some anole species have altogether disappeared from the interior forest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;16&quot;&gt;Insect-eating frogs and birds plummeted, too. Another &lt;a href=&quot;https://luq.lter.network/data/luqmetadata173&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;research team&lt;/a&gt; used mist nets to capture birds in 1990, and again in 2005. Captures fell by about 50 percent. Garcia and Lister analyzed the data with an eye on the insectivores. The ruddy quail dove, which eats fruits and seeds, had no population change. A brilliant green bird called the &lt;a href=&quot;https://neotropical.birds.cornell.edu/Species-Account/nb/species/purtod1/overview&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Puerto Rican tody&lt;/a&gt;, which eats bugs almost exclusively, diminished by 90 percent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;17&quot;&gt;The food web appears to have been obliterated from the bottom. It’s credible that the authors link the cascade to arthropod loss, Schowalter said, because “you have all these different taxa showing the same trends — the insectivorous birds, frogs and lizards — but you don’t see those among seed-feeding birds.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;18&quot;&gt;Lister and Garcia attribute this crash to climate. In the same 40-year period as the arthropod crash, the average high temperature in the rain forest increased by 4 degrees Fahrenheit. The temperatures in the tropics stick to a narrow band. The invertebrates that live there, likewise, are adapted to these temperatures and fare poorly outside them; bugs cannot regulate their internal heat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div data-elm-loc=&quot;19&quot; class=&quot;inline-content inline-video&quot;&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;20&quot;&gt;A recent analysis of climate change and insects, published in August in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://science.sciencemag.org/content/361/6405/916&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;journal Science&lt;/a&gt;, predicts a decrease in tropical insect populations, according to an author of that study, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.uvm.edu/gund/profiles/scott-merrill&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Scott Merrill&lt;/a&gt;, who studies crop pests at the University of Vermont. In temperate regions farther from the equator, where insects can survive a wider range of temperatures, agricultural pests will devour more food as their metabolism increases, Merrill and his co-authors warned. But after a certain thermal threshold, insects will no longer lay eggs, he said, and their internal chemistry breaks down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;21&quot;&gt;The authors of a 2017 study of vanished flying insects in Germany suggested other possible culprits, including pesticides and habitat loss. Arthropods around the globe also have to contend with pathogens and invasive species.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;22&quot;&gt;“It’s bewildering, and I’m scared to death that it’s actually death by a thousand cuts,” Wagner said. “One of the scariest parts about it is that we don’t have an obvious smoking gun here.” A particular danger to these arthropods, in his view, was not temperature but droughts and lack of rainfall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;23&quot;&gt;Lister pointed out that, since 1969, pesticide use has fallen more than 80 percent in Puerto Rico. He does not know what else could be to blame. The study authors used a recent &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/03610918.2015.1122048?journalCode=lssp20&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;analytic method&lt;/a&gt;, invented by a professor of economics at Fordham University, to assess the role of heat. “It allows you to place a likelihood on variable X causing variable Y,” Lister said. “So we did that and then five out of our six populations we got the strongest possible support for heat causing those decreases in abundance of frogs and insects.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;24&quot;&gt;The authors sorted out the effects of weather like hurricanes and still saw a consistent trend, Schowalter said, which makes a convincing case for climate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;25&quot;&gt;“If anything, I think their results and caveats are understated. The gravity of their findings and ramifications for other animals, especially vertebrates, is hyperalarming,” Wagner said. But he is not convinced that climate change is the global driver of insect loss. “The decline of insects in northern Europe precedes that of climate change there,” he said. “Likewise, in New England, some tangible declines began in the 1950s.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;26&quot;&gt;No matter the cause, all of the scientists agreed that more people should pay attention to the bugpocalypse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;27&quot;&gt;“It’s a very scary thing,” Merrill said, that comes on the heels of a “gloomy, gloomy” U.N. report that estimated the world has little more than &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/energy-environment/2018/10/08/world-has-only-years-get-climate-change-under-control-un-scientists-say/?utm_term=.2bc091839d2c&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;a decade left&lt;/a&gt; to wrangle climate change under control. But “we can all step up,” he said, by using more fuel-efficient cars and turning off unused electronics. The Portland, Ore.-based Xerces Society, a nonprofit environmental group that promotes insect conservation, recommends planting a &lt;a href=&quot;https://xerces.org/pollinator-conservation/gardens/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;garden&lt;/a&gt; with native plants that flower throughout the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;28&quot;&gt;“Unfortunately, we have deaf ears in Washington,” Schowalter said. But those ears will listen at some point, he said, because our food supply will be in jeopardy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;29&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2016/02/27/science/decline-of-species-that-pollinate-poses-a-threat-to-global-food-supply-report-warns.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Thirty-five percent&lt;/a&gt; of the world’s plant crops require pollination by bees, wasps and other animals. And arthropods are more than just pollinators. They’re the planet’s wee custodians, toiling away in unnoticed or avoided corners. They chew up rotting wood and eat carrion. “And none of us want to have more carcasses around,” Schowalter said. Wild insects provide $57 billion worth of six-legged labor in the United States each year, according to a 2006 estimate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;30&quot;&gt;The loss of insects and arthropods could further rend the rain forest’s food web, Lister warned, causing plant species to go extinct without pollinators. “If the tropical forests go it will be yet another catastrophic failure of the whole Earth system,” he said, “that will feed back on human beings in an almost unimaginable way.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div data-elm-loc=&quot;31&quot; class=&quot;inline-content inline-video&quot;&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;32&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read more:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;33&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/speaking-of-science/wp/2017/10/18/this-is-very-alarming-flying-insects-vanish-from-nature-preserves/?utm_term=.48d0d82f757a&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;‘This is very alarming!’: Flying insects vanish from nature preserves&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;34&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/speaking-of-science/wp/2017/11/20/these-bizarre-flies-wear-bubbles-like-scuba-suits-to-dive-in-a-toxic-lake/?utm_term=.10ce7c718478&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Watch these bizarre flies dive underwater using bubbles like scuba suits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;35&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/speaking-of-science/wp/2017/10/25/this-bug-is-real-and-now-so-are-your-nightmares/?utm_term=.f4e9903e6208&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;This bug is real, and now so are your nightmares&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 12:46:23 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>dschuetz</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.washingtonpost.com/science/2018/10/15/hyperalarming-study-shows-massive-insect-loss/</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/YBYAUUMjkiLyRRoGUQ_bAjE2JLA=/1484x0/arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/PYVRQXBIWREUVHWHEOM5BFUHWY.jpeg</og:image>
<og:title>‘Hyperalarming’ study shows massive insect loss</og:title>
<og:description>Insects are vanishing even in a pristine tropical forest, and an ecologist calls this &quot;one of the most disturbing articles I have ever read.”</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.washingtonpost.com/science/2018/10/15/hyperalarming-study-shows-massive-insect-loss/?noredirect=on</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>How Exercise Might “Clean” the Alzheimer&amp;#039;s Brain</title>
<link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/how-exercise-might-clean-the-alzheimers-brain1/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/how-exercise-might-clean-the-alzheimers-brain1/</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;mura-region mura-region-loose&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;mura-region-local&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.alz.co.uk/research/WorldAlzheimerReport2015.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;50 million individuals worldwide&lt;/a&gt; ailing from Alzheimer’s disease, the announcements by pharmaceutical giants earlier this year that they will end research on therapeutics were devastating. The news is even more devastating considering projections that 100 million more people will be diagnosed with Alzheimer’s disease across the globe by 2050, all potentially without a medical means to better their quality of life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As it happens, though, the pursuit of a therapeutic has been given a lifeline. &lt;a href=&quot;http://science.sciencemag.org/content/361/6406/eaan8821&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;New research&lt;/a&gt; shows that physical exercise can “clean up” the hostile environments in the brains of Alzheimer’s mice, allowing new nerve cells in the hippocampus, the brain structure involved in memory and learning, to enable cognitive improvements, such as learning and memory. These findings imply that pharmacological agents that enrich the hippocampal environment to boost cell growth and survival might be effective to recuperate brain health and function in human Alzheimer’s disease patients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.annualreviews.org/doi/abs/10.1146/annurev-pathol-020712-163927&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;brain of an individual with Alzheimer’s disease&lt;/a&gt; is a harsh place filled with buildups of harmful nerve cell junk—amyloid plaques and neurofibrillary tangles—and dramatic loss of nerve cells and connections that occur with severe cognitive decline, such as memory loss. Targeting and disrupting this harmful junk, specifically amyloid plaques, to restore brain function has been the basis of many failed clinical trials. This futility has led to a re-evaluation of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/nrneurol.2017.111&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;the amyloid hypothesis&lt;/a&gt;—the central dogma for Alzheimer’s disease pathology based on the toxic accumulation of amyloid plaques.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time, there have been traces of evidence for &lt;a href=&quot;https://content.iospress.com/articles/journal-of-alzheimers-disease/jad091531&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;exercise playing a preventative role in Alzheimer’s disease&lt;/a&gt;, but exactly how this occurs and how to take advantage of it therapeutically has remained elusive. Exercise has been shown to create biochemical changes that fertilize the brain’s environment to mend nerve cell health. Additionally, exercise induces restorative changes relevant to Alzheimer’s disease pathology with improved nerve cell growth and connectivity in the hippocampus, a process called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/nn0399_266&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;adult hippocampal neurogenesis&lt;/a&gt;. For these reasons, the authors Choi et al. explored whether exercise-induced effects and hippocampal nerve cell growth could be utilized for therapeutic purposes in Alzheimer’s disease to restore brain function.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The researchers found that exercised animals from a mouse model of Alzheimer’s had greatly enhanced memory compared to sedentary ones due to improved adult hippocampal neurogenesis and a rise in amounts of a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4746328/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;specific molecule that promotes brain cell growth called BDNF&lt;/a&gt;.  Importantly, they could recover brain function, specifically memory, in mice with Alzheimer’s disease but without exercise by increasing hippocampal cell growth and BDNF levels using a combination of genetic—injecting a virus—and pharmacological means. On the other hand, blocking hippocampal neurogenesis early in Alzheimer’s worsened nerve cell health later in stages, leading to degeneration of the hippocampus and, subsequently, memory function. This provides preclinical proof of concept that a combination of drugs that increase adult hippocampal neurogenesis and BDNF levels could be disease-modifying or prevent Alzheimer’s disease altogether.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this work, things don’t look promising for the amyloid hypothesis—that Alzheimer’s disease is caused by the deposition of amyloid plaques. In this study, it was shown that eliminating amyloid plaques were not to necessary to ameliorate memory defects, which is consistent with evidence that plaques can also be found in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2737680/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;brains of healthy individuals&lt;/a&gt;. On the contrary, we may be looking at a new and improved fundamental theory for Alzheimer’s disease based on promoting a healthier brain environment and adult hippocampal neurogenesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, this inspiring news should be taken with an important caution—&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4070393/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;mouse models of Alzheimer’s are notorious for failing to translate into humans&lt;/a&gt; such that treatments that have worked to remedy mice have failed for humans. Besides, even if these findings translate into humans, it may apply to a fraction of Alzheimer’s individuals with relevant genetic components to the mouse model utilized. Future studies will need to replicate these results in mouse models emulating the range of known Alzheimer’s disease genetic milieus and, more importantly, prove its medical relevance to human disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before translating these findings into human patients, there remains significant research to establish that a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(08)00838-6?_returnURL=https%3A%2F%2Flinkinghub.elsevier.com%2Fretrieve%2Fpii%2FS0092867408008386%3Fshowall%3Dtrue&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;medication or drug could mimic the effects of exercise—exercise mimetics—&lt;/a&gt;by “cleaning up” the brain with BDNF and stimulating neurogenesis to combat Alzheimer’s disease. Currently, the method for administering BDNF to animals in the lab—by direct injection into the brain—is not ideal for use in people, and a hippocampal neurogenesis stimulating compound remains elusive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Future attempts to generate pharmacological means to imitate and heighten the benefits of exercise—exercise mimetics—to increase adult hippocampal neurogenesis in addition to BDNF may someday provide an effective means of improving cognition in people with Alzheimer’s disease. Moreover, increasing neurogenesis in the earliest stages of the disease may protect against neuronal cell death later in the disease, providing a potentially powerful disease-modifying treatment strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 12:03:06 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>extraterra</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>How Exercise Might &quot;Clean&quot; the Alzheimer's Brain</og:title>
<og:description>Hints at potential treatments for age-related dementia and memory loss</og:description>
<og:image>https://static.scientificamerican.com/sciam/cache/file/083C2462-D184-4A1C-8B65542B7925DCDF.jpg</og:image>
<og:url>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/how-exercise-might-clean-the-alzheimers-brain1/</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/how-exercise-might-clean-the-alzheimers-brain1/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ex-Google engineer describing the company&amp;#039;s role in China censorship</title>
<link>https://threader.app/thread/1051725524064591872</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://threader.app/thread/1051725524064591872</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;thread-head&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;pic-user d-inline&quot;&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/@real_vijay&quot;&gt;&lt;img id=&quot;post-img-user&quot; class=&quot;users-thread&quot; src=&quot;https://pbs.twimg.com/profile_images/929948905818570752/GI708xLD.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot; id=&quot;thread-post-start&quot;&gt;1/ Google is working on a new search engine code-named &quot;Dragonfly&quot; that will aid China's effort to censor information from its citizenry.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a former Google engineer I wanted to share some information on what it's like to be inside Google as these decisions are made &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;2/ I previously shared that in 2006 I was an engineer who worked on Google News and was asked to write code to censor new results in China.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I've found some emails from 2006 that shed more light on the censorship requirements of the Chinese state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet tw-align-center&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;3/ The emails I'm presenting came from a mailing list at Google where employees discussed topics on politics and economics. I have formatted the emails for readability and redacted the names of my colleagues, with whom I was debating. The topic was the 2008 Olympics in China. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;4/ The striking fact that I had forgotten about until I rediscovered these emails was that China required Google to censor information both broadly (entire news sections were to be censored) and extremely expeditiously (Google needed to comply with requests within 15 minutes)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;5/ It is very likely that the same censorship requirements will apply to the Dragonfly project that Google is currently working on and perhaps the requirements have become even more stringent given Google's new willingness to comply with the Chinese state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;6/ The other thing I find disturbing, after all these years, is the willingness of my former colleagues to not only comply with the censorship but their enthusiasm in rationalizing it. It is not a coincidence that the rationale they give was the same one management had given them&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;7/ As Blaise Pascal trenchantly observed in Pensées, *power creates opinion*. This is just as true within corporations as it is for national politics. There are benefits to toeing the line, plus obvious disadvantages to dissenting (e.g., risk of being fired).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;8/ My colleagues, although they may have been well intentioned, were just regurgitating the reasons Google's management had given for its first foray into China.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The real problem, then as now, is that management seems to have no moral compass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;9/ For many people there is little difference between what is legal and what is moral. This mindset is especially dangerous when it is held by people in power, such as Google's executives. The mindset is: if it's a legal requirement to censor, then we should do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;10/ The desire to comply becomes even more urgent for executives of large profit-seeking corporations because it gives them access to massive and lucrative markets. Without a strong moral compass, the temptation is far too strong for most of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;11/ As I previously tweeted, Sergey Brin is a notable exception to this temptation, and he is reported to be the reason that Google left China in 2010:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet tw-align-center&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;12/ Unfortunately, Brin's influence in Google's decision making seems to have waned and the new management seems not only willing to be complicit in censorship, but to lie about what it's doing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet tw-align-center&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;13/ I encourage employees of Google who have been asked to work on censored products to stand up against these requests, as I did in 2006, and make it known that Google's willingness to censor is immoral.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can follow &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/real_vijay&quot;&gt;Vijay Boyapati&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;____&lt;br/&gt;Tip: mention &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/threader_app&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;@threader_app&lt;/a&gt; on a Twitter thread with the keyword “compile” to get a link to it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Enjoy Threader? &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?text=Hi%20%40jack%2C%20I%20read%20Twitter%20threads%20on%20%40threader_app&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Tell @jack&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;download-url&quot;&gt;Download &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/threader/id1317519091?mt=8&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Threader&lt;/a&gt; on iOS.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 10:12:06 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>seapunk</dc:creator>
<og:title>A thread written by @real_vijay</og:title>
<og:image>https://threader.app/img/ogthreader.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>1/ Google is working on a new search engine code-named &quot;Dragonfly&quot; that will aid China's effort to censor information from its citizenry. As a former Google engineer I wanted to share some information on what it's like to be inside Google as these decisions are made https://t.co/HAts5wXwsU</og:description>
<og:url>https://threader.app/thread/1051725524064591872</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://threader.app/thread/1051725524064591872</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Concepts to help developers master JavaScript</title>
<link>https://github.com/leonardomso/33-js-concepts</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/leonardomso/33-js-concepts</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;Box-body p-6&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;markdown-body entry-content&quot; itemprop=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;33 Concepts Every JavaScript Developer Should Know&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://makeapullrequest.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/a34cfbf37ba6848362bf2bee0f3915c2e38b1cc1/68747470733a2f2f696d672e736869656c64732e696f2f62616467652f5052732d77656c636f6d652d627269676874677265656e2e7376673f7374796c653d666c61742d737175617265&quot; alt=&quot;PRs Welcome&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/PRs-welcome-brightgreen.svg?style=flat-square&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://opensource.org/licenses/MIT&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/4b5966a2a252ee0f241a1e03b13417178eb4964f/68747470733a2f2f696d672e736869656c64732e696f2f62616467652f6c6963656e73652d4d49542d626c75652e7376673f7374796c653d666c61742d737175617265&quot; alt=&quot;Licence MIT&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/license-MIT-blue.svg?style=flat-square&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This repository was created with the intention of helping developers master their concepts in JavaScript. It is not a requirement, but a guide for future studies. It is based on an article written by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/stephenthecurt&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Stephen Curtis&lt;/a&gt; and you can read it &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@stephenthecurt/33-fundamentals-every-javascript-developer-should-know-13dd720a90d1&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Feel free to contribute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/leonardomso/33-js-concepts#call-stack&quot;&gt;Call Stack&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/leonardomso/33-js-concepts#primitive-types&quot;&gt;Primitive Types&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/leonardomso/33-js-concepts#value-types-and-reference-types&quot;&gt;Value Types and Reference Types&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/leonardomso/33-js-concepts#implicit-explicit-nominal-structuring-and-duck-typing&quot;&gt;Implicit, Explicit, Nominal, Structuring and Duck Typing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/leonardomso/33-js-concepts#-vs--vs-typeof&quot;&gt;== vs === vs typeof&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/leonardomso/33-js-concepts#function-scope-block-scope-and-lexical-scope&quot;&gt;Function Scope, Block Scope and Lexical Scope&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/leonardomso/33-js-concepts#expression-vs-statement&quot;&gt;Expression vs Statement&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/leonardomso/33-js-concepts#iife-modules-and-namespaces&quot;&gt;IIFE, Modules and Namespaces&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/leonardomso/33-js-concepts#message-queue-and-event-loop&quot;&gt;Message Queue and Event Loop&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/leonardomso/33-js-concepts#settimeout-setinterval-and-requestanimationframe&quot;&gt;setTimeout, setInterval and requestAnimationFrame&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/leonardomso/33-js-concepts#javascript-engines&quot;&gt;JavaScript Engines&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/leonardomso/33-js-concepts#bitwise-operators-type-arrays-and-array-buffers&quot;&gt;Bitwise Operators, Type Arrays and Array Buffers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/leonardomso/33-js-concepts#dom-and-layout-trees&quot;&gt;DOM and Layout Trees&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/leonardomso/33-js-concepts#factories-and-classes&quot;&gt;Factories and Classes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/leonardomso/33-js-concepts#this-call-apply-and-bind&quot;&gt;this, call, apply and bind&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/leonardomso/33-js-concepts#new-constructor-instanceof-and-instances&quot;&gt;new, Constructor, instanceof and Instances&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/leonardomso/33-js-concepts#prototype-inheritance-and-prototype-chain&quot;&gt;Prototype Inheritance and Prototype Chain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/leonardomso/33-js-concepts#object.create-and-object.assign&quot;&gt;Object.create and Object.assign&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/leonardomso/33-js-concepts#map-reduce-filter&quot;&gt;map, reduce, filter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/leonardomso/33-js-concepts#pure-functions-side-effects-and-state-mutation&quot;&gt;Pure Functions, Side Effects and State Mutation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/leonardomso/33-js-concepts#closures&quot;&gt;Closures&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/leonardomso/33-js-concepts#high-order-functions&quot;&gt;High Order Functions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/leonardomso/33-js-concepts#recursion&quot;&gt;Recursion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/leonardomso/33-js-concepts#collections&quot;&gt;Collections&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/leonardomso/33-js-concepts#promises&quot;&gt;Promises&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/leonardomso/33-js-concepts#asyncawait&quot;&gt;async/await&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/leonardomso/33-js-concepts#data-structures&quot;&gt;Data Structures&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/leonardomso/33-js-concepts#expensive-operation-and-big-o-notation&quot;&gt;Expensive Operation and Big O Notation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/leonardomso/33-js-concepts#algorithms&quot;&gt;Algorithms&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/leonardomso/33-js-concepts#inheritance-polymorphism-and-code-reuse&quot;&gt;Inheritance, Polymorphism and Code Reuse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/leonardomso/33-js-concepts#design-patterns&quot;&gt;Design Patterns&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/leonardomso/33-js-concepts#partial-applications-currying-compose-and-pipe&quot;&gt;Partial Applications, Currying, Compose and Pipe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/leonardomso/33-js-concepts#clean-code&quot;&gt;Clean Code&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Call Stack&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Articles&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Videos&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/leonardomso/33-js-concepts#table-of-contents&quot;&gt;⬆ back to top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Primitive Types&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Articles&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Videos&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/leonardomso/33-js-concepts#table-of-contents&quot;&gt;⬆ back to top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Value Types and Reference Types&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Articles&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Videos&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/leonardomso/33-js-concepts#table-of-contents&quot;&gt;⬆ back to top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Implicit, Explicit, Nominal, Structuring and Duck Typing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Articles&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/leonardomso/33-js-concepts#table-of-contents&quot;&gt;⬆ back to top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;== vs === vs typeof&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Articles&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Videos&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/leonardomso/33-js-concepts#table-of-contents&quot;&gt;⬆ back to top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Function Scope, Block Scope and Lexical Scope&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Articles&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Videos&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/leonardomso/33-js-concepts#table-of-contents&quot;&gt;⬆ back to top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Expression vs Statement&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Articles&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Videos&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/leonardomso/33-js-concepts#table-of-contents&quot;&gt;⬆ back to top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;IIFE, Modules and Namespaces&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Articles&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Videos&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/leonardomso/33-js-concepts#table-of-contents&quot;&gt;⬆ back to top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Message Queue and Event Loop&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Articles&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Videos&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/leonardomso/33-js-concepts#table-of-contents&quot;&gt;⬆ back to top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;setTimeout, setInterval and requestAnimationFrame&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Articles&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Videos&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/leonardomso/33-js-concepts#table-of-contents&quot;&gt;⬆ back to top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;JavaScript Engines&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Articles&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Videos&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/leonardomso/33-js-concepts#table-of-contents&quot;&gt;⬆ back to top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Bitwise Operators, Type Arrays and Array Buffers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Articles&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Videos&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/leonardomso/33-js-concepts#table-of-contents&quot;&gt;⬆ back to top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;DOM and Layout Trees&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Articles&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Videos&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/leonardomso/33-js-concepts#table-of-contents&quot;&gt;⬆ back to top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Factories and Classes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Articles&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Videos&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/leonardomso/33-js-concepts#table-of-contents&quot;&gt;⬆ back to top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;this, call, apply and bind&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Articles&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;📜 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.codementor.io/niladrisekhardutta/how-to-call-apply-and-bind-in-javascript-8i1jca6jp&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;How-to: call() , apply() and bind() in JavaScript — Niladri Sekhar Dutta&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;📜 &lt;a href=&quot;http://javascriptissexy.com/javascript-apply-call-and-bind-methods-are-essential-for-javascript-professionals/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;JavaScript’s Apply, Call, and Bind Methods are Essential for JavaScript Professionals — Richard Bovell&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;📜 &lt;a href=&quot;https://tylermcginnis.com/this-keyword-call-apply-bind-javascript/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;WTF is this - Understanding the this keyword, call, apply, and bind in JavaScript — Tyler McGinnis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;📜 &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@omergoldberg/javascript-call-apply-and-bind-e5c27301f7bb&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Javascript: call(), apply() and bind() — Omer Goldberg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;📜 &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@ivansifrim/the-differences-between-call-apply-bind-276724bb825b&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;The difference between call / apply / bind — Ivan Sifrim&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;📜 &lt;a href=&quot;https://tech.io/playgrounds/9799/learn-solve-call-apply-and-bind-methods-in-javascript&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;call(), apply() and bind() methods in JavaScript&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;📜 &lt;a href=&quot;https://thenewstack.io/mastering-javascript-callbacks-bind-apply-call/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Mastering 'this' in JavaScript: Callbacks and bind(), apply(), call() — Michelle Gienow&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;📜 &lt;a href=&quot;https://dev.to/kbk0125/javascripts-apply-call-and-bind-explained-by-hosting-a-cookout-32jo&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;JavaScript’s apply, call, and bind explained by hosting a cookout — Kevin Kononenko&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;📜 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eigenx.com/blog/https/mediumcom/eigen-x/how-and-when-to-use-bind-call-and-apply-in-javascript-77b6f42898fb&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;How AND When to use bind, call, and apply in Javascript — Eigen X&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;📜 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hacksparrow.com/javascript-bind-vs-apply-and-call.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;JavaScript .bind() vs .apply() and .call() — Hack Sparrow&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;📜 &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/JavaScript/Reference/Global_Objects/Function/call&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;call() — MDN&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;📜 &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/JavaScript/Reference/Global_objects/Function/bind&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;bind() — MDN&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;📜 &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/JavaScript/Reference/Global_Objects/Function/apply&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;apply() — MDN&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;📜 &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.brew.com.hk/what-is-this-in-javascript/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;What is 'this' in JavaScript? — Daniel Li&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Videos&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/leonardomso/33-js-concepts#table-of-contents&quot;&gt;⬆ back to top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;new, Constructor, instanceof and Instances&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Articles&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/leonardomso/33-js-concepts#table-of-contents&quot;&gt;⬆ back to top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Prototype Inheritance and Prototype Chain&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Articles&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Videos&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/leonardomso/33-js-concepts#table-of-contents&quot;&gt;⬆ back to top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Object.create and Object.assign&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Articles&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Videos&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/leonardomso/33-js-concepts#table-of-contents&quot;&gt;⬆ back to top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;map, reduce, filter&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Articles&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;📜 &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/jsguru/javascript-functional-programming-map-filter-and-reduce-846ff9ba492d&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;JavaScript Functional Programming — map, filter and reduce — Bojan Gvozderac&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;📜 &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@joomiguelcunha/learn-map-filter-and-reduce-in-javascript-ea59009593c4&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Learn map, filter and reduce in Javascript — João Miguel Cunha&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;📜 &lt;a href=&quot;https://danmartensen.svbtle.com/javascripts-map-reduce-and-filter&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;JavaScript’s Map, Reduce, and Filter — Dan Martensen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;📜 &lt;a href=&quot;https://code.tutsplus.com/tutorials/how-to-use-map-filter-reduce-in-javascript--cms-26209&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;How to Use Map, Filter, &amp;amp; Reduce in JavaScript — Peleke Sengstacke&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;📜 &lt;a href=&quot;https://codeburst.io/javascript-learn-to-chain-map-filter-and-reduce-acd2d0562cd4&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;JavaScript — Learn to Chain Map, Filter, and Reduce — Brandon Morelli&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;📜 &lt;a href=&quot;https://codeburst.io/write-beautiful-javascript-with-%CE%BB-fp-es6-350cd64ab5bf&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Javascript data structure with map, reduce, filter and ES6 — Deepak Gupta&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;📜 &lt;a href=&quot;https://hackernoon.com/understanding-map-filter-and-reduce-in-javascript-5df1c7eee464&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Understanding map, filter and reduce in Javascript — Luuk Gruijs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;📜 &lt;a href=&quot;https://hackernoon.com/functional-programming-in-js-map-filter-reduce-pt-5-308a205fdd5f&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Functional Programming in JS: map, filter, reduce (Pt. 5) — Omer Goldberg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;📜 &lt;a href=&quot;https://wsvincent.com/functional-javascript-map-filter-reduce/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;JavaScript: Map, Filter, Reduce — William S. Vincent&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;📜 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sitepoint.com/es6-arrow-functions-new-fat-concise-syntax-javascript/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Arrow Functions: Fat and Concise Syntax in JavaScript — Kyle Pennell&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;📜 &lt;a href=&quot;https://codeburst.io/javascript-arrow-functions-for-beginners-926947fc0cdc&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;JavaScript: Arrow Functions for Beginners — Brandon Morelli&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;📜 &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.freecodecamp.org/when-and-why-you-should-use-es6-arrow-functions-and-when-you-shouldnt-3d851d7f0b26&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;When (and why) you should use ES6 arrow functions — and when you shouldn’t — Cynthia Lee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;📜 &lt;a href=&quot;https://codeburst.io/javascript-learn-understand-arrow-functions-fe2083533946&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;JavaScript — Learn &amp;amp; Understand Arrow Functions — Brandon Morelli&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;📜 &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/podiihq/javascript-arrow-functions-27d4c3334b83&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;(JavaScript )=&amp;gt; Arrow functions — sigu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Videos&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;🎥 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UXiYii0Y7Nw&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Map, Filter and Reduce — Lydia Hallie&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🎥 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vytzLlY_wmU&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Functional JavaScript: Map, forEach, Reduce, Filter — Theodore Anderson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🎥 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qTeeVd8hOFY&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;JavaScript Array superpowers: Map, Filter, Reduce (part I) — Michael Rosata&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🎥 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gIm9xLYudL0&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;JavaScript Array superpowers: Map, Filter, Reduce (part 2) — Michael Rosata&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🎥 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zYBeEPxNSbw&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;JavaScript Higher Order Functions - Filter, Map, Sort &amp;amp; Reduce — Epicop&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🎥 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4qWlqD0yYTU&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;[Array Methods 2/3] .filter + .map + .reduce — CodeWithNick&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🎥 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6sQDTgOqh-I&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Arrow functions in JavaScript - What, Why and How — Fun Fun Function&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/leonardomso/33-js-concepts#table-of-contents&quot;&gt;⬆ back to top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Pure Functions, Side Effects and State Mutation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Articles&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Videos&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/leonardomso/33-js-concepts#table-of-contents&quot;&gt;⬆ back to top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Closures&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Articles&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Videos&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/leonardomso/33-js-concepts#table-of-contents&quot;&gt;⬆ back to top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;High Order Functions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Articles&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Videos&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/leonardomso/33-js-concepts#table-of-contents&quot;&gt;⬆ back to top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Recursion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Articles&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Videos&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/leonardomso/33-js-concepts#table-of-contents&quot;&gt;⬆ back to top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Collections&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Articles&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Videos&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/leonardomso/33-js-concepts#table-of-contents&quot;&gt;⬆ back to top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Promises&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Articles&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Videos&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/leonardomso/33-js-concepts#table-of-contents&quot;&gt;⬆ back to top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;async/await&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Articles&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/leonardomso/33-js-concepts#table-of-contents&quot;&gt;⬆ back to top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Data Structures&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Articles&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Videos&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/leonardomso/33-js-concepts#table-of-contents&quot;&gt;⬆ back to top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Expensive Operation and Big O Notation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Articles&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Videos&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/leonardomso/33-js-concepts#table-of-contents&quot;&gt;⬆ back to top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Algorithms&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Articles&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/leonardomso/33-js-concepts#table-of-contents&quot;&gt;⬆ back to top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Inheritance, Polymorphism and Code Reuse&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Articles&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Videos&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/leonardomso/33-js-concepts#table-of-contents&quot;&gt;⬆ back to top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Design Patterns&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Articles&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/leonardomso/33-js-concepts#table-of-contents&quot;&gt;⬆ back to top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Partial Applications, Currying, Compose and Pipe&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Articles&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Videos&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/leonardomso/33-js-concepts#table-of-contents&quot;&gt;⬆ back to top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Clean Code&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Articles&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/leonardomso/33-js-concepts#table-of-contents&quot;&gt;⬆ back to top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 09:05:21 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>alexgrcs</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars1.githubusercontent.com/u/8030067?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>leonardomso/33-js-concepts</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/leonardomso/33-js-concepts</og:url>
<og:description>📜 33 concepts every JavaScript developer should know. - leonardomso/33-js-concepts</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/leonardomso/33-js-concepts</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>To become a software consultant, avoid letting clients pay you for code (2017)</title>
<link>https://daedtech.com/key-becoming-software-consultant/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://daedtech.com/key-becoming-software-consultant/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, I made an idle threat on Twitter (shown below).  I was thinking of creating some content along the lines of how to go from being a software developer to a software consultant.  People &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.daedtech.com/category/you-asked-for-it/&quot;&gt;ask me&lt;/a&gt; about this all the time, and it makes for an interesting subject.  I was also flattered and encouraged by the enthusiastic response to the tweet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot; readability=&quot;8.3157894736842&quot;&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;I’ve been getting that book writing itch again this week. Thinking about a guide for developers on how to become consultants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Erik Dietrich (@daedtech) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/daedtech/status/877547953652715520&quot;&gt;June 21, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m still mulling over the best delivery mechanism for such a thing.  I could do &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.daedtech.com/book/&quot;&gt;another book&lt;/a&gt;, but I could also do something like a video course or perhaps a series of small courses.  But whatever route I decide to go, I need to chart out the content before doing anything else.  I could go a mile wide and a mile deep on that, but I’d say there’s one sort of fundamental, philosophical key to becoming a software consultant.  So today I’d like to speak about that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Software Consultant, Differentiated&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I won’t bury the lede any further here.  The cornerstone piece of advice I’ll offer is the one upon which I’d build all of the rest of my content.  You probably won’t like it.  Or, you’ll at least probably think it should take a back seat to other pieces of advice like, “be sympathetic” or “ask a lot of questions” or something.  But, no.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t ever let would-be consulting clients pay you for code that you write.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seriously.  That’s the most foundational piece of your journey from software developer to software consultant.  And the reason has everything to do with something that successful consultants come to understand well: positioning.  Now, usually, people talk about &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.marketingteacher.com/positioning/&quot;&gt;positioning in the context of marketing&lt;/a&gt; as differentiating yourself from competitors.  Here, I’m talking about differentiating yourself from what you’re used to doing (and thus obliquely from competitors you should stop bothering to compete with: software developers).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me explain, as I’m wont to do, with narrative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Leonardo Da Vinci: Renaissance Plumber&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By any reckoning, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.history.com/topics/leonardo-da-vinci&quot;&gt;Leonardo Da Vinci&lt;/a&gt; was one of the most impressive humans ever to walk the planet.  Among &lt;a href=&quot;https://learnodo-newtonic.com/leonardo-da-vinci-accomplishments&quot;&gt;his diverse achievements&lt;/a&gt;, he painted the Mona Lisa, designed a tank, and made important strides in human anatomy.  But let’s say that, in a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0096928/&quot;&gt;Bill and Ted&lt;/a&gt;-like &lt;em&gt;deus ex machina&lt;/em&gt;, someone transported him 500 years into the future and brought him to the modern world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even someone as impressive as Leonardo would, no doubt, need a bit of time to get his bearings.  So assume that, as he learned modern language, technology, and culture, he took a job as a plumber.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.daedtech.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/Leonardo-Da-Vinci-as-Plumber.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone wp-image-8967 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://www.daedtech.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/Leonardo-Da-Vinci-as-Plumber.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Leonardo Da Vinci as a plumber to help you understand the difference between software developer and software consultant&quot; width=&quot;1006&quot; height=&quot;1123&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s assume that you happened to have a leaky sink faucet, and you called Leonardo’s plumbing company for help.  They dispatched him forthwith to take a look and to help you out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So Leonardo comes over and, since he’s Leonardo, figures out almost immediately that your supply line has come slightly loose.  He tightens it, and you couldn’t be more pleased with the result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Leonardo, Ignored&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Encouraged by your praise, Leonardo then gets a bit of a twinkle in his eye.  He does some mental arithmetic and tells you that could actually cut down on your water bill by about 15% if you adopted a counter-intuitive way of cleaning off your dishes after meals.  He proceeds to tell you how that would work.  And, while he’s at it, he points out that the painting print on your kitchen wall isn’t a good match for the paint in the room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And do you know what you do in response to the genius of Leonardo Da Vinci teaching you a better dish washing scheme and helping you with your art?  You smile, humor him, and think to yourself, “just fix the sink and get out of here.”  &lt;em&gt;And you’re absolutely right to do that&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why?  Because you have no way of knowing that he’s Leonardo Freakin’ Da Vinci.  You just understand that you hired someone to fix a sink, and that someone is now giving you unsolicited advice about washing your dishes and decorating your house.  You hired him to perform labor, and instead (or in addition to), you’re getting his opinions about your life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Software Developer, Ignored&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone reading this that has spent time as a professional software developer can probably relate to my channeling of Da Vinci.  You understand the better outcomes your company would have if you’d ramp down tech debt.  You can easily see that management’s waterfall ‘methodology’ is ineffective and misery-inducing.  And, while you’re no expert, you even know that the company’s branding and sales strategies are ineffective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You offer constructive feedback, but nobody listens.  You’re Da Vinci, ignored.  And I’m not patronizing you.  You have to be smart to write software for a living, and in every shop I’ve ever visited, the software developers had good ideas that extended far beyond the boundaries of an IDE.  And, usually, management humored them or else flat out ignored them.  You could chalk this up to familiarity breeding contempt, but it’s really the &lt;em&gt;positioning&lt;/em&gt; that I mentioned earlier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Management hired you to perform the labor of writing code.  Your unsolicited opinions are not part of that equation.  Because you’re in high demand, people smile, nod, and humor you.  But they don’t care.  That’s the life of a software developer.  File your suggestions in the little bin, on the ground next to my desk with a “suggestions” label taped over the “trash” label.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Would-Be Software Consultant, Ignored&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s say that you tire of this at some point.  You decide you love the industry and that you love software, but you want more influence.  Management isn’t for you, so “consulting” it is.  Maybe you hang out your shingle to freelance, or maybe you go work for a software “consulting” firm.  &lt;em&gt;Now&lt;/em&gt;, it’ll be different.  &lt;em&gt;Now&lt;/em&gt;, people will listen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then, to your intense frustration, it doesn’t turn out that way.  Even though you have “consultant” in your title and charter, people still humor you and say, “whatever, buddy, just code up the spec.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What gives?  Well, a big part of the problem lies in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.daedtech.com/a-taxonomy-of-software-consultants/&quot;&gt;the dilution of the term “consultant”&lt;/a&gt; in our line of work.  Everyone at your client’s site that doesn’t have a W2 arrangement with that client is a “consultant,” whether they personally advise the CIO or whether they lock themselves in a broom closet and write stored procedures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, to make matters worse, every firm that does custom app dev and calls it consulting positions themselves in an entirely predictable way.  “Oh, heavens no.  Our consultants aren’t just coders — they write code AND provide thought leadership and advice.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s so utterly expected that some clients would probably find it refreshing to hear one of these shops or people say, “nope, we just turn specs into code.”  Thank &lt;em&gt;goodness&lt;/em&gt;.  I finally don’t have to listen to the plumber talk about my choice of wall decorations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Positioning Like You Mean It&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So let’s take an honest look at the software consultant’s situation.  All that “consultant” really tells anyone for sure is that you do work for someone that doesn’t send you a W2.  But, if they play the odds, it tells them that you write code for someone that doesn’t send you a W2 and will offer a lot of opinions, whether anyone wants them or not.  The stock software consultant persona and thus default positioning is then “opinionated, above average developer.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now the people interested in my prospective book or course are people that actually want to &lt;em&gt;be &lt;/em&gt;consultants.  Firms don’t pay consultants for labor (or code); they pay consultants for their opinions.  So, here’s the rub.  If you introduce yourself as a software consultant or someone else introduces you that way, your default positioning is “coder.”  But, to achieve your objective, you need to position yourself as an &lt;em&gt;actual&lt;/em&gt; consultant, getting paid for advice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While many subtle options exist to nudge yourself in that direction, you have one foundational one.  Don’t let your clients pay you to write code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a world where every software developer writing code for another company is a “consultant” you can position yourself as an actual consultant by not writing code for pay.  Nobody confuses you with a pro coder then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Medicine as a Metaphor&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jonathan Stark, of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ditchinghourly.com/&quot;&gt;Ditching Hourly&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://devchat.tv/freelancers//&quot;&gt;Freelancer’s Show&lt;/a&gt;, has a great metaphor to help you understand the positioning concept.  And I’ll use it here to drive home a major differentiation between consulting and laboring (i.e. writing code).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He talks about four phases of solving problems for companies.  Those include diagnosis, prescribing a cure, application of the cure, and re-application of the cure.  Software developers and most so-called software consultants involve themselves almost exclusively in phase three: application.  But that’s a pretty low leverage place to be.  Consultants exist almost exclusively in phases one and two: diagnosing and prescribing.  They let laborers take care of phase three and even lower status laborers take care of phase four.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think of it in terms of other knowledge workers.  You go to the doctor with an ailment, and the doctor figures out the ailment and prescribes medicine.  But if that medicine involves rubbing stuff on the bottom of your feet 5 times per day, he doesn’t also handle that — it’s below his pay grade.  You do that yourself, or you hire a masseuse or something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.daedtech.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/Foot-with-Goo.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-8966&quot; src=&quot;https://www.daedtech.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/Foot-with-Goo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1397&quot; height=&quot;832&quot; srcset=&quot;https://daedtech.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/Foot-with-Goo.jpg 1397w, https://daedtech.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/Foot-with-Goo-300x179.jpg 300w, https://daedtech.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/Foot-with-Goo-768x457.jpg 768w, https://daedtech.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/Foot-with-Goo-1024x610.jpg 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1397px) 100vw, 1397px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you write code as a software “consultant,” you &lt;em&gt;tell&lt;/em&gt; people that you’re in the business of diagnosis and prescription.  But when the rubber meets the road, you spend almost all of your time slathering stuff on people’s feet and talking at length about (“consulting on”) the best ways to slather.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, imagine an industry in which diagnosticians and slatherers alike all called themselves doctors.  When you needed a diagnosis, you’d start to look reflexively for people without goop on their hands in order to tell the difference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Caveats&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First of all, let me clear something up immediately.  I can practically write the comment myself.  Someone is going to read this and say, “well, I’m a consultant that writes code for my clients and they actually asked me whether they should adopt Scrum or not and then listened.”  Yes, I believe that in the same way I believe that management does sometimes listen to staff software developers’ opinions.  It happens.  But it’s a far cry from you being there &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; to tell them whether or not to adopt Scrum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly, you can write code in a consultative capacity.  Coaches and trainers make excellent examples.  Notice that I said not to let people pay you for &lt;em&gt;code&lt;/em&gt; that you write.  Companies don’t pay trainers for the code that they write, but rather for the service of showing their team how to write code.  As a rule of thumb for differentiating, ask yourself whether the client depends on you to code something intended for production.  If the answer is yes, you’re slathering foot goop and not diagnosing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, finally, I won’t dispute that some people may walk this line with more than ephemeral success.  Maybe everywhere they go, they roll up their sleeves and crank code all morning, only to then go into the CIO’s office and provide strategy advice.  I’ve never actually seen that or anything close to it, but it could happen.  Or, maybe even more likely, someone consults for some clients and codes for others.  Whatever the arrangement, some people might succeed in perpetually walking the consultant-coder line.  And, good for them.  But what I &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; tell you is that this is the exception and not the rule.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;There’s an Awful Lot More to Consulting, But Here’s Your Start&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned in early in the post, I could fill a book or course(s) with information about how to succeed as a software consultant.  Going from software developer to software consultant seems kind of straightforward, but that’s really fools’ gold.  It’s superficially easy if you accept the extremely loose definition of consulting, but not if you seriously want to get paid for expert opinions, diagnoses and prescriptions instead of for writing code.  Then you have a good bit of learning and skill acquisition ahead of you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So why, of all things, do I pick avoiding writing code as foundational?  Well, as I’ve said all along, positioning yourself is critical, and that’s your single best piece of positioning.  In order to get paid for diagnosing, you need someone asking you for a diagnosis and not asking you to slather stuff on their foot and just call that diagnosing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there’s an even subtler reason for the emphasis on not coding, as well.  Writing code is satisfying, fun, and &lt;em&gt;extremely&lt;/em&gt; marketable.  And so finding people to pay you to write code is tantalizingly easy.  They need your programming skills so badly, they’ll probably even call you the “CEO of teh codez” if that’s what you want to be called.  You have a ready-made crutch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Refusing to write code for clients means forcibly removing the crutch.  Doing this, you’re like a non-native language speaker that flies to a foreign country and practices learning by immersion.  You have no crutch, and no choice but to figure it out.  You can write code for fun, in your spare time, and to support your practice.  But if you want to get serious about consulting, stop slathering so that you can start diagnosing.  Don’t let ’em pay you for your code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;And, by the way…&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the way, if you liked this post and you're new here, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.daedtech.com/welcome-to-daedtech/&quot;&gt;check out this page&lt;/a&gt; as a good place to start for more content that you might enjoy.  You can also sign up for my mailing list below to check out a free set of chapters from my book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;tve-leads-shortcode tve-tl-anim tl-anim-instant tve-leads-track-shortcode_7177&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;tl-style&quot; id=&quot;tve_38_set&quot; data-state=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;tve-leads-conversion-object&quot; data-tl-type=&quot;shortcode_7177&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;tve_flt&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;tve_editor&quot; class=&quot;tve_shortcode_editor&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;thrv-leads-form-box tve_no_drag tve_no_icons tve_element_hover thrv_wrapper tve_editor_main_content tve_38_set tve_brdr_solid tve_blue tve_empty_dropzone&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;thrv_wrapper thrv_columns tve_clearfix&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;tve_colm tve_tfo tve_df tve_empty_dropzone&quot; readability=&quot;13&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;rft&quot;/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Want more content like this?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sign up for my mailing list, and get about 10 posts' worth of content, excerpted from my latest book as a PDF. (Don't worry about signing up again -- the list is smart enough to keep each email only once.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;tve_colm tve_foc tve_ofo tve_df tve_lst tve_empty_dropzone&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;thrv_wrapper tve_image_caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;tve_image_frame&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;tve_image&quot; src=&quot;https://www.daedtech.com/wp-content/plugins/thrive-leads/editor-templates/_form_css/images/set_38_icon.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;tve_leads_end_content&quot;/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 08:49:58 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>fagnerbrack</dc:creator>
<og:title>The Key to Becoming a Software Consultant</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://daedtech.com/key-becoming-software-consultant/</og:url>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://daedtech.com/key-becoming-software-consultant/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>