<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Exxon knew that fossil fuels were influencing the climate in 1978</title>
<link>https://thecompost.io/articles/exxonknew</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://thecompost.io/articles/exxonknew</guid>
<description>&lt;h2&gt;What's Going On?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Atmospheric CO2 measurements at the Mauna Loa observatory (where CO2 concentration has been measured since the 1950s) &lt;a href=&quot;https://scripps.ucsd.edu/programs/keelingcurve/&quot;&gt;topped 415 ppm last week&lt;/a&gt;, and levels continue to rise steadily. The last time Earth's atmosphere &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.com/news/science-environment-47806440&quot;&gt;had this much carbon&lt;/a&gt;, mastodons, sabre-toothed cats, and giant ground sloths roamed across an iceless Antarctic where beech trees grew. That was 3-5 million years ago, during the Pliocene, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ecowatch.com/carbon-dioxide-climate-change-exxon-2637281941.html&quot;&gt;humans did not yet exist&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://thecompost.s3.us-west-2.amazonaws.com/newsletters/2019-05-20/mlo_full_record.png&quot; alt=&quot;Keeling Curve&quot;/&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Keeling_Curve&quot;&gt;Keeling Curve&lt;/a&gt; | Source: Scripps Institute of Oceanography&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Well That's News...&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not to Exxon. They called this one 40 years ago. Recent investigations by &lt;a href=&quot;https://insideclimatenews.org/news/15092015/Exxons-own-research-confirmed-fossil-fuels-role-in-global-warming&quot;&gt;InsideClimate&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ucsusa.org/sites/default/files/attach/2015/07/The-Climate-Deception-Dossiers.pdf&quot;&gt;The Union of Concerned Scientists&lt;/a&gt; unearthed &lt;a href=&quot;https://insideclimatenews.org/sites/default/files/documents/1982%20Exxon%20Primer%20on%20CO2%20Greenhouse%20Effect.pdf&quot;&gt;internal company documents&lt;/a&gt; from 1982, revealing that Exxon's research team was performing groundbreaking climate research and very clearly understood the consequences of carbon emissions from fossil fuels on the planet. The accuracy of their predictions are chilling — they anticipated (in their &quot;21st Century Study-High Growth Scenario&quot;) that in 2020 atmospheric CO2 levels would fall between 400 and 420 ppm. They also foresaw the accompanying sea level rise, melting of polar ice sheets, change of rainfall patterns, and agricultural failures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://thecompost.s3.us-west-2.amazonaws.com/newsletters/2019-05-20/graph.png&quot; alt=&quot;Exxon Predictions&quot;/&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: InsideClimateNews&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Wow — Give Me The Brief History.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exxon &lt;a href=&quot;https://insideclimatenews.org/news/15092015/Exxons-own-research-confirmed-fossil-fuels-role-in-global-warming&quot;&gt;had a rigorous program&lt;/a&gt; of CO2 sampling and climate modeling going on in the 70s. In 1978 senior scientist James Black gave a company talk where he described the &quot;general scientific agreement&quot; that human-produced CO2 emissions from fossil fuels were influencing the climate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He said, &quot;present thinking holds that man has a time window of five to ten years before the need for hard decisions regarding changes in energy strategies might become critical.&quot; Reminder — that was &lt;strong&gt;1978.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exxon doubled down on their research, and in the early 80s published several papers on climate change in scientific journals, gaining a reputation of &quot;genuine expertise&quot; on the subject. But they stayed cagey on the role of oil on global warming with their shareholders (they're &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vox.com/energy-and-environment/2019/1/7/18172275/supreme-court-exxon-climate-change-massachusetts&quot;&gt;now facing&lt;/a&gt; several lawsuits as a result).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The turning point came in 1988, when NASA climate scientist James Hansen testified before Congress, stating that global warming was well underway and steps must be taken to stop it. Sensing an existential threat to their industry, Exxon &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/exxon-knew-about-climate-change-almost-40-years-ago/&quot;&gt;began a systematic campaign&lt;/a&gt; to sow doubt and confusion about the science behind climate change, spinning a narrative that emphasized its uncertain points. They formed a multinational corporate alliance called the Global Climate Coalition to impede government efforts to cut fossil fuels, and helped prevent the US from signing the international 1997 Kyoto Protocol that would have set limits on emissions. Exxon continues its lobbying, funding of right-wing think tanks, and rhetoric of misinformation today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sounds Like We Have Ourselves A Proper Villain.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No kidding. Unfortunately, Exxon's campaign has largely succeeded. The seeds of doubt they planted from 1988 onward have delayed critical action for decades — half of all the carbon in the atmosphere was released &lt;em&gt;after&lt;/em&gt; 1988.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;All it would've taken is for one prominent fossil fuel CEO to know this was about more than just shareholder profits, and a question about our legacy,&quot; says climate scientist Michael Mann. &quot;But now because of the cost of inaction—what I call the 'procrastination penalty'—we face a far more uphill battle.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2019 23:55:24 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ajhaupt7</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://thecompost.io/articles/exxonknew</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>SerenityOS – a graphical Unix-like OS for x86, with 90s aesthetics</title>
<link>https://github.com/SerenityOS/serenity</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/SerenityOS/serenity</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;Box-body&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;markdown-body entry-content p-5&quot; itemprop=&quot;text&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Graphical Unix-like operating system for x86 computers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;About&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I always wondered what it would be like to write my own operating system, but I never took it seriously. Until now.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Serenity is a love letter to '90s user interfaces, with a custom Unix-like core. It flatters with sincerity by stealing beautiful ideas from various other systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roughly speaking, the goal is a marriage between the aesthetic of late-1990s productivity software and the power-user accessibility of late-2000s *nix. This is a system by me, for me, based on the things I like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you like some of the same things, you are welcome to join the project. It would be great to one day change the above to say &quot;this is a system by us, for us, based on the things we like.&quot; :^)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I regularly post raw hacking sessions and demos on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC3ts8coMP645hZw9JSD3pqQ&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;my YouTube channel&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's also a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.patreon.com/serenityos&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Patreon&lt;/a&gt; if you would like to show some support that way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Screenshot&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awesomekling/serenity/master/Meta/screenshot-d727005.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awesomekling/serenity/master/Meta/screenshot-d727005.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot as of d727005&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Current features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Pre-emptive multitasking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multithreading&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compositing window server&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IPv4 networking with ARP, TCP, UDP and ICMP&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ext2 filesystem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unix-like libc and userland&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shell with pipes and I/O redirection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;mmap()&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;/proc filesystem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Local sockets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pseudoterminals (with /dev/pts filesystem)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Event loop library (LibCore)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;High-level GUI library (LibGUI)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visual GUI design tool&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PNG format support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Text editor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IRC client&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DNS lookup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Desktop games: Minesweeper and Snake&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other stuff I can't think of right now...&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;How do I build and run this?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go into the Toolchain/ directory and run the &lt;strong&gt;BuildIt.sh&lt;/strong&gt; script. Then source the &lt;strong&gt;UseIt.sh&lt;/strong&gt; script to put the i686-pc-serenity toolchain in your $PATH.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you've done both of those, go into the Kernel directory, then run &lt;strong&gt;makeall.sh&lt;/strong&gt;, and if nothing breaks too much, take it for a spin by using &lt;strong&gt;run&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Otherwise, see the older &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/awesomekling/serenity/blob/master/Meta/BuildInstructions.md&quot;&gt;step-by-step guide to building Serenity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;IRC&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come chat in &lt;code&gt;#serenityos&lt;/code&gt; on the Freenode IRC network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Author&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Serenity is licensed under a 2-clause BSD license.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2019 22:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>yankcrime</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars3.githubusercontent.com/u/50811782?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>SerenityOS/serenity</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/SerenityOS/serenity</og:url>
<og:description>Serenity Operating System. Contribute to SerenityOS/serenity development by creating an account on GitHub.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/SerenityOS/serenity</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Playdate – A New Handheld Gaming System</title>
<link>https://play.date/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://play.date/</guid>
<description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;welcome&quot;&gt;Hello. We made a brand new handheld gaming system.&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s yellow. It fits in your pocket. It’s got a beautiful black and white screen. It’s not super cheap, but not super expensive. It includes brand new games from some amazing creators. Plus it has a crank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OK, yeah, let’s back up a little bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;For over 20 years &lt;a href=&quot;https://panic.com&quot;&gt;Panic&lt;/a&gt; has mostly made Mac and iOS software. Twenty years is a long time, and we wanted to try some new things. To make the most of what we have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s why we started publishing games, like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.firewatchgame.com/&quot;&gt;Firewatch&lt;/a&gt; and, soon, &lt;a href=&quot;https://goose.game/&quot;&gt;Untitled Goose Game&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what if we could push ourselves even further? What if we could build something? A real something that you could hold?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was harder than we thought, but it’s here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And it’s called Playdate&lt;span class=&quot;circleR&quot;&gt;®&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.play.date/img/device-interior-80.jpg&quot; width=&quot;1400&quot; height=&quot;788&quot; alt=&quot;Close-up rendering of a Playdate device with its outer case removed and internal components visible.&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;We love video games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We love the places they take us and the feelings they give us. We’ve grown up with them. It sounds silly, but they really mean a lot to us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Playdate is our celebration of the video game.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We reached out to some top game designers, like Keita Takahashi and Zach Gage and Bennett Foddy and Shaun Inman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We showed them Playdate and asked, “Want to make a game for it?”. Then we lost our minds when they said “Yeah!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So Playdate isn’t just the hardware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It’s twelve brand new video games, one each week.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are these games? Here’s the thing: we’d like to keep them a secret until they appear on your Playdate. We want to surprise you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some are short, some long, some are experimental, some traditional. All are fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When your Playdate lights up with a brand new game delivery, we hope you can’t wait to unwrap your gift.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And there’s so much more to come. Playdate is alive with possibilities and surprises, future games and new ways to make them. We’ll have even more to talk about at launch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://play.date/img/nowebgl-demo.png&quot; alt=&quot;A Playdate device with its crank extended and a game onscreen.&quot; width=&quot;527&quot; height=&quot;443&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;crank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We weren’t kidding about the crank.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It flips out from the side, a rotating analog controller that puts a whole new spin on games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some games use the crank exclusively (like &lt;em&gt;Crankin’s Time Travel Adventure&lt;/em&gt;, above.) Some don’t use it at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it’s very fun. Extremely fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the way, the crank came from our friends at &lt;a href=&quot;https://teenage.engineering/&quot;&gt;Teenage Engineering&lt;/a&gt;. They were our partners for Playdate’s design. Isn’t it nice?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2019 22:11:56 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>dombili</dc:creator>
<og:title>Playdate. A New Handheld Gaming System</og:title>
<og:description>It’s yellow. It fits in your pocket. It’s got a beautiful black and white screen. Playdate from Panic is coming soon.</og:description>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>https://play.date/</og:url>
<og:image>https://play.date/social-card.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://play.date/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Amazon shareholders reject facial recognition ban</title>
<link>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-amazon-com-facial-recognition/amazon-shareholders-reject-facial-recognition-ban-as-concern-grows-in-u-s-congress-idUSKCN1SS28I</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.reuters.com/article/us-amazon-com-facial-recognition/amazon-shareholders-reject-facial-recognition-ban-as-concern-grows-in-u-s-congress-idUSKCN1SS28I</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;(Reuters) - Amazon.com Inc said shareholders rejected proposals to curb and audit its facial recognition service on Wednesday, just as members of Congress indicated there was bipartisan support to one day regulate the technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the past year Amazon has found itself at the center of a growing debate over the use of facial recognition by governments, with critics warning of false matches and arrests and proponents arguing it keeps the public safe. Law enforcement in Oregon and Florida have used Amazon’s face and image ID service, known as Rekognition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With support from civil liberties groups, two non-binding proposals on facial recognition made it to the ballot ahead of Amazon’s shareholder meeting on Wednesday. The world’s top online retailer and cloud computing company had tried to stop the votes, but it was effectively overruled by the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first proposal would have made the company stop offering facial recognition to governments unless its board determined sales did not violate civil liberties. A second would have requested a study by September of the extent to which Amazon’s service harmed rights and privacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to an Amazon spokeswoman, the resolutions failed by a wide margin. The vote breakdown will be disclosed at a later point in time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adding to shareholders’ concerns was recent research that showed Amazon’s technology struggled to identify the gender of individuals with darker skin, prompting fears that a faulty technology would put innocent people behind bars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazon has defended its work and said all users must follow the law. It also added a web portal for people to report any abuse of the service &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.awscloud.com/rekognition-abuse.html.&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The proposals faced an uphill battle. Amazon’s board recommended against them, and Jeff Bezos, the company’s chief executive and founder, controls 16 percent of its stock and voting rights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, critics of the technology believed the vote was beneficial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This shareholder intervention should serve as a wake-up call for the company to reckon with the real harms of face surveillance and to change course,” said Shankar Narayan of the American Civil Liberties Union of Washington state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A key congressional committee also met on Wednesday in Washington, D.C., to discuss the civil rights impact of all facial recognition technology, not only Amazon’s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Responding to the shareholder vote, Democratic U.S. Representative Jimmy Gomez said, “that just means that it’s more important that Congress acts.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Republican members of the committee expressed concern about U.S. citizens having their rights violated and their information shared with the likes of the FBI without elected officials’ oversight. A second hearing on the topic is scheduled for June 4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any federal regulation would follow a major decision by San Francisco officials earlier this month to ban city personnel from using the technology. That contrasts with New York, Chicago and Detroit, where law enforcement have reportedly used facial recognition or acquired it with the hope of speeding up post-crime investigations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Image_container&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;LazyImage_container LazyImage_dark&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s2.reutersmedia.net/resources/r/?m=02&amp;amp;d=20190522&amp;amp;t=2&amp;amp;i=1389873097&amp;amp;r=LYNXNPEF4L1MG&amp;amp;w=20&quot; aria-label=&quot;FILE PHOTO: The logo of Amazon is seen at the company logistics centre in Boves, France, May 13, 2019. REUTERS/Pascal Rossignol/File Photo&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;Image_caption&quot;&gt;

&lt;span&gt;FILE PHOTO: The logo of Amazon is seen at the company logistics centre in Boves, France, May 13, 2019. REUTERS/Pascal Rossignol/File Photo&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazon is one of many facial recognition vendors, alongside France's Idemia, Japan's NEC Corp and Microsoft Corp, which has repeatedly called for regulation and said &lt;a href=&quot;https://reut.rs/2IygqgS&quot;&gt;reut.rs/2IygqgS&lt;/a&gt; it turned down sales for human rights concerns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mark Meadows, a Republican, said it was time to start legislating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You’ve now hit the sweet spot that brings progressives and conservatives together,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Attribution_container&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Attribution_attribution&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Attribution_content&quot;&gt;Reporting By Jeffrey Dastin in San Francisco; Editing by Meredith Mazzilli&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;StandardArticleBody_trustBadgeContainer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;StandardArticleBody_trustBadgeTitle&quot;&gt;Our Standards:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;trustBadgeUrl&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thomsonreuters.com/en/about-us/trust-principles.html&quot;&gt;The Thomson Reuters Trust Principles.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2019 21:52:44 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>petethomas</dc:creator>
<og:title>Amazon shareholders reject facial recognition ban as concern grows...</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-amazon-com-facial-recognition-idUSKCN1SS28I</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>Amazon.com Inc said shareholders rejected proposals to curb and audit its facial...</og:description>
<og:image>https://s2.reutersmedia.net/resources/r/?m=02&amp;d=20190522&amp;t=2&amp;i=1389873097&amp;w=1200&amp;r=LYNXNPEF4L1MG</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-amazon-com-facial-recognition/amazon-shareholders-reject-facial-recognition-ban-as-concern-grows-in-u-s-congress-idUSKCN1SS28I</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>PEP 594 – Removing dead batteries from Python&amp;#039;s standard library</title>
<link>https://www.python.org/dev/peps/pep-0594/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.python.org/dev/peps/pep-0594/</guid>
<description>&lt;header class=&quot;article-header&quot;&gt;
&lt;/header&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;abstract&quot; readability=&quot;9.6491228070175&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This PEP proposed a list of standard library modules to be removed from the standard library. The modules are mostly historic data formats and APIs that have been superseded a long time ago, e.g. Mac OS 9 and Commodore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;rationale&quot; readability=&quot;36.889625455751&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back in the early days of Python, the interpreter came with a large set of useful modules. This was often refrained to as &quot;batteries included&quot; philosophy and was one of the corner stones to Python's success story. Users didn't have to figure out how to download and install separate packages in order to write a simple web server or parse email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Times have changed. The introduction of the cheese shop (PyPI), setuptools, and later pip, it became simple and straight forward to download and install packages. Nowadays Python has a rich and vibrant ecosystem of third party packages. It's pretty much standard to either install packages from PyPI or use one of the many Python or Linux distributions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, Python's standard library is piling up cruft, unnecessary duplication of functionality, and dispensable features. This is undesirable for several reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;simple&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;Any additional module increases the maintenance cost for the Python core development team. The team has limited resources, reduced maintenance cost frees development time for other improvements.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Modules in the standard library are generally favored and seen as the de-facto solution for a problem. A majority of users only pick 3rd party modules to replace a stdlib module, when they have a compelling reason, e.g. lxml instead of &lt;cite&gt;xml&lt;/cite&gt;. The removal of an unmaintained stdlib module increases the chances of a community contributed module to become widely used.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A lean and mean standard library benefits platforms with limited resources like devices with just a few hundred kilobyte of storage (e.g. BBC Micro:bit). Python on mobile platforms like BeeWare or WebAssembly (e.g. pyodide) also benefit from reduced download size.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The modules in the PEP have been selected for deprecation because their removal is either least controversial or most beneficial. For example least controversial are 30 years old multimedia formats like &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;sunau&lt;/tt&gt; audio format, which was used on SPARC and NeXT workstations in the late 1980ties. The &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;crypt&lt;/tt&gt; module has fundamental flaws that are better solved outside the standard library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This PEP also designates some modules as not scheduled for removal. Some modules have been deprecated for several releases or seem unnecessary at first glance. However it is beneficial to keep the modules in the standard library, mostly for environments where installing a package from PyPI is not an option. This can be cooperate environments or class rooms where external code is not permitted without legal approval.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;simple&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;The usage of FTP is declining, but some files are still provided over the FTP protocol or hosters offer FTP to upload content. Therefore &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;ftplib&lt;/tt&gt; is going to stay.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;optparse&lt;/tt&gt; and &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;getopt&lt;/tt&gt; module are widely used. They are mature modules with very low maintenance overhead.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;According to David Beazley  the &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;wave&lt;/tt&gt; module is easy to teach to kids and can make crazy sounds. Making a computer generate crazy sounds is powerful and highly motivating exercise for a 9yo aspiring developer. It's a fun battery to keep.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;deprecation-schedule&quot; readability=&quot;16.03738317757&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;id2&quot; readability=&quot;13.936459909228&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This PEP targets Python 3.8. Version 3.8.0 final is scheduled to be released a few months before Python 2.7 will reach its end of lifetime. We expect that Python 3.8 will be targeted by users that migrate to Python 3 in 2019 and 2020. To reduce churn and to allow a smooth transition from Python 2, Python 3.8 will neither raise &lt;cite&gt;DeprecationWarning&lt;/cite&gt; nor remove any modules that have been scheduled for removal. Instead deprecated modules will just be &lt;em&gt;documented&lt;/em&gt; as deprecated. Optionally modules may emit a &lt;cite&gt;PendingDeprecationWarning&lt;/cite&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All deprecated modules will also undergo a feature freeze. No additional features should be added. Bug should still be fixed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;id3&quot; readability=&quot;13.729032258065&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting with Python 3.9, deprecated modules will start issuing &lt;cite&gt;DeprecationWarning&lt;/cite&gt;. The &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.python.org/3/library/parser.html&quot;&gt;parser&lt;/a&gt;  module is removed and potentially replaced with a new module.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All other deprecated modules are fully supported and will receive security updates until Python 3.9 reaches its end of lifetime. Python 3.9.0 will be released about 18 months after 3.8.0 (April 2021?) and most likely be supported for 5 years after the release. The estimated EOL of Python 3.9 is in 2026.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;id4&quot; readability=&quot;9.7037037037037&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 3.10 all deprecated modules will be removed from the CPython repository together with tests, documentation, and autoconf rules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;pep-acceptance-process&quot; readability=&quot;19.243243243243&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3.8.0b1 is scheduled to be release shortly after the PEP is officially submitted. Since it's improbable that the PEP will pass all stages of the PEP process in time, I propose a two step acceptance process that is analogous Python's two release deprecation process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first &lt;em&gt;provisionally accepted&lt;/em&gt; phase targets Python 3.8.0b1. In the first phase no code is changes or removed. Modules are only documented as deprecated. The only exception is the &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.python.org/3/library/parser.html&quot;&gt;parser&lt;/a&gt;  module. It has been documented as deprecated since Python 2.5 and is scheduled for removal for 3.9 to make place for a more advanced parser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final decision, which modules will be removed and how the removed code is preserved, can be delayed for another year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;deprecated-modules&quot; readability=&quot;14.316314107442&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The modules are grouped as data encoding, multimedia, network, OS interface, and misc modules. The majority of modules are for old data formats or old APIs. Some others are rarely useful and have better replacements on PyPI, e.g. Pillow for image processing or NumPy-based projects to deal with audio processing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;1&quot; class=&quot;colwidths-given docutils&quot;&gt;&lt;caption&gt;Table 1: Proposed modules deprecations&lt;/caption&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;&lt;col width=&quot;17%&quot;/&gt;&lt;col width=&quot;17%&quot;/&gt;&lt;col width=&quot;17%&quot;/&gt;&lt;col width=&quot;17%&quot;/&gt;&lt;col width=&quot;33%&quot;/&gt;&lt;/colgroup&gt;&lt;thead valign=&quot;bottom&quot;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th class=&quot;head&quot;&gt;Module&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class=&quot;head&quot;&gt;Deprecated in&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class=&quot;head&quot;&gt;To be removed&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class=&quot;head&quot;&gt;Has expert?&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class=&quot;head&quot;&gt;Replacement&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody valign=&quot;top&quot; readability=&quot;6.5&quot;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;aifc&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;yes (inactive)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;asynchat&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.6&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;yes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;asyncio&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;asyncore&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.6&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;yes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;asyncio&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;audioop&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;yes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;binhex&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;no&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;cgi&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;no&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;cgitb&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;no&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;chunk&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;no&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;crypt&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;yes (inactive)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;bcrypt, argon2cffi, hashlib, passlib&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;formatter&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;no&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;fpectl&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.7&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.7&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;n/a&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;imghdr&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;no&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;filetype, puremagic, python-magic&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;imp&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.4&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;yes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;importlib&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;macpath&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.7&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.8&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;n/a&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;msilib&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;no&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;nntplib&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;no&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;nis&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;no&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;ossaudiodev&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;no&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;parser&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.5&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.9&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;yes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ast, lib2to3.pgen2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;pipes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;no&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;subprocess&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;smtpd&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.4.7&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;3.5.4&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;yes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;aiosmtpd&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;sndhdr&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;no&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;filetype, puremagic, python-magic&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;spwd&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;no&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;python-pam, simplepam&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;sunau&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;no&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;uu&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;no&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;xdrlib&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;no&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;data-encoding-modules&quot; readability=&quot;9.9514925373134&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;binhex&quot; readability=&quot;8.6603773584906&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;toc-backref&quot; href=&quot;https://www.python.org/dev/peps/pep-0594/#id113&quot;&gt;binhex&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.python.org/3/library/binhex.html&quot;&gt;binhex&lt;/a&gt; module encodes and decodes Apple Macintosh binhex4 data. It was originally developed for TSR-80. In the 1980s and early 1990s it was used on classic Mac OS 9 to encode binary email attachments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class=&quot;docutils&quot;&gt;&lt;dt&gt;Module type&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;pure Python&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Deprecated in&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;3.8&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;To be removed in&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;3.10&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Has a designated expert&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;no&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Substitute&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;strong&gt;none&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;uu&quot; readability=&quot;8.8758620689655&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;toc-backref&quot; href=&quot;https://www.python.org/dev/peps/pep-0594/#id114&quot;&gt;uu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.python.org/3/library/uu.html&quot;&gt;uu&lt;/a&gt; module provides uuencode format, an old binary encoding format for email from 1980. The uu format has been replaced by MIME. The uu codec is provided by the binascii module.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class=&quot;docutils&quot;&gt;&lt;dt&gt;Module type&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;pure Python&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Deprecated in&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;3.8&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;To be removed in&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;3.10&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Has a designated expert&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;no&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Substitute&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;strong&gt;none&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;xdrlib&quot; readability=&quot;7.6862745098039&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;toc-backref&quot; href=&quot;https://www.python.org/dev/peps/pep-0594/#id115&quot;&gt;xdrlib&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.python.org/3/library/xdrlib.html&quot;&gt;xdrlib&lt;/a&gt; module supports the Sun External Data Representation Standard. XDR is an old binary serialization format from 1987. These days it's rarely used outside specialized domains like NFS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class=&quot;docutils&quot;&gt;&lt;dt&gt;Module type&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;pure Python&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Deprecated in&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;3.8&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;To be removed in&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;3.10&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Has a designated expert&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;no&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Substitute&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;strong&gt;none&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;networking-modules&quot; readability=&quot;28.354557420204&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;asynchat&quot; readability=&quot;6.1724137931034&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;toc-backref&quot; href=&quot;https://www.python.org/dev/peps/pep-0594/#id125&quot;&gt;asynchat&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.python.org/3/library/asynchat.html&quot;&gt;asynchat&lt;/a&gt; module is build on top of &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.python.org/3/library/asyncore.html&quot;&gt;asyncore&lt;/a&gt;  and has been deprecated since Python 3.6.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class=&quot;docutils&quot;&gt;&lt;dt&gt;Module type&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;pure Python&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Deprecated in&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;3.6&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Removed in&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;3.10&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Has a designated expert&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;yes&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Substitute&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;asyncio&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;asyncore&quot; readability=&quot;14.48608137045&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;toc-backref&quot; href=&quot;https://www.python.org/dev/peps/pep-0594/#id126&quot;&gt;asyncore&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.python.org/3/library/asyncore.html&quot;&gt;asyncore&lt;/a&gt; module was the first module for asynchronous socket service clients and servers. It has been replaced by asyncio and is deprecated since Python 3.6.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;asyncore&lt;/tt&gt; module is also used in stdlib tests. The tests for &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;ftplib&lt;/tt&gt;, &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;logging&lt;/tt&gt;, &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;smptd&lt;/tt&gt;, &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;smtplib&lt;/tt&gt;, and &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;ssl&lt;/tt&gt; are partly based on &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;asyncore&lt;/tt&gt;. These tests must be updated to use asyncio or threading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class=&quot;docutils&quot;&gt;&lt;dt&gt;Module type&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;pure Python&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Deprecated in&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;3.6&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Removed in&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;3.10&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Has a designated expert&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;yes&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Substitute&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;asyncio&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;cgi&quot; readability=&quot;13.755376344086&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;toc-backref&quot; href=&quot;https://www.python.org/dev/peps/pep-0594/#id127&quot;&gt;cgi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.python.org/3/library/cgi.html&quot;&gt;cgi&lt;/a&gt; module is a support module for Common Gateway Interface (CGI) scripts. CGI is deemed as inefficient because every incoming request is handled in a new process. &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.python.org/dev/peps/pep-0206&quot;&gt;PEP 206&lt;/a&gt; considers the module as &lt;em&gt;designed poorly and are now near-impossible to fix&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several people proposed to either keep the cgi module for features like &lt;cite&gt;cgi.parse_qs()&lt;/cite&gt; or move &lt;cite&gt;cgi.escape()&lt;/cite&gt; to a different module. The functions &lt;cite&gt;cgi.parse_qs&lt;/cite&gt; and &lt;cite&gt;cgi.parse_qsl&lt;/cite&gt; have been deprecated for a while and are actually aliases for &lt;cite&gt;urllib.parse.parse_qs&lt;/cite&gt; and &lt;cite&gt;urllib.parse.parse_qsl&lt;/cite&gt;. The function &lt;cite&gt;cgi.quote&lt;/cite&gt; has been deprecated in favor of &lt;cite&gt;html.quote&lt;/cite&gt; with secure default values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class=&quot;docutils&quot;&gt;&lt;dt&gt;Module type&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;pure Python&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Deprecated in&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;3.8&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;To be removed in&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;3.10&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Has a designated expert&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;no&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Substitute&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;strong&gt;none&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;cgitb&quot; readability=&quot;14.585635359116&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;toc-backref&quot; href=&quot;https://www.python.org/dev/peps/pep-0594/#id128&quot;&gt;cgitb&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.python.org/3/library/cgitb.html&quot;&gt;cgitb&lt;/a&gt; module is a helper for the cgi module for configurable tracebacks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;cgitb&lt;/tt&gt; module is not used by any major Python web framework (Django, Pyramid, Plone, Flask, CherryPy, or Bottle). Only Paste uses it in an optional debugging middleware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class=&quot;docutils&quot;&gt;&lt;dt&gt;Module type&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;pure Python&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Deprecated in&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;3.8&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;To be removed in&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;3.10&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Has a designated expert&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;no&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Substitute&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;strong&gt;none&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;smtpd&quot; readability=&quot;10.699453551913&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;toc-backref&quot; href=&quot;https://www.python.org/dev/peps/pep-0594/#id129&quot;&gt;smtpd&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.python.org/3/library/smtpd.html&quot;&gt;smtpd&lt;/a&gt; module provides a simple implementation of a SMTP mail server. The module documentation marks the module as deprecated and recommends &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;aiosmtpd&lt;/tt&gt; instead. The deprecation message was added in releases 3.4.7, 3.5.4, and 3.6.1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class=&quot;docutils&quot;&gt;&lt;dt&gt;Module type&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;pure Python&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Deprecated in&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.4.7&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;3.5.4&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;3.6.1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;To be removed in&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;3.10&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Has a designated expert&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;yes&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Substitute&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;aiosmtpd&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;nntplib&quot; readability=&quot;16.474226804124&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;toc-backref&quot; href=&quot;https://www.python.org/dev/peps/pep-0594/#id130&quot;&gt;nntplib&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.python.org/3/library/nntplib.html&quot;&gt;nntplib&lt;/a&gt; module implements the client side of the Network News Transfer Protocol (nntp). News groups used to be a dominant platform for online discussions. Over the last two decades, news has been slowly but steadily replaced with mailing lists and web-based discussion platforms. Twisted is also &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://twistedmatrix.com/trac/ticket/9405&quot;&gt;planning&lt;/a&gt; to deprecate NNTP support and &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/greenbender/pynntp&quot;&gt;pynnt&lt;/a&gt; hasn't seen any activity since 2014. This is a good indicator that the public interest in NNTP support is declining.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;nntplib&lt;/tt&gt; tests have been the cause of additional work in the recent past. Python only contains client side of NNTP. The tests connect to external news server. The servers are sometimes unavailble, too slow, or do not work correctly over IPv6. The situation causes flaky test runs on buildbots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class=&quot;docutils&quot;&gt;&lt;dt&gt;Module type&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;pure Python&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Deprecated in&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;3.8&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;To be removed in&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;3.10&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Has a designated expert&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;no&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Substitute&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;strong&gt;none&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;operating-system-interface&quot; readability=&quot;19.603498542274&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;crypt&quot; readability=&quot;9.7056483691329&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;toc-backref&quot; href=&quot;https://www.python.org/dev/peps/pep-0594/#id132&quot;&gt;crypt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.python.org/3/library/crypt.html&quot;&gt;crypt&lt;/a&gt; module implements password hashing based on &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;crypt(3)&lt;/tt&gt; function from &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;libcrypt&lt;/tt&gt; or &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;libxcrypt&lt;/tt&gt; on Unix-like platform. The algorithms are mostly old, of poor quality and insecure. Users are discouraged to use them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;simple&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;The module is not available on Windows. Cross-platform application need an alternative implementation any way.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only DES encryption is guarenteed to be available. DES has an extremely limited key space of 2**56.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MD5, salted SHA256, salted SHA512, and Blowfish are optional extension. SSHA256 and SSHA512 are glibc extensions. Blowfish (bcrypt) is the only algorithm that is still secure. However it's in glibc and therefore not commonly available on Linux.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Depending on the platform, the &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;crypt&lt;/tt&gt; module is not thread safe. Only implementations with &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;crypt_r(3)&lt;/tt&gt; are thread safe.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The module was never useful to interact with system user and password databases. On BSD, macOS, and Linux, all user authentication and password modification operations must go through PAM (pluggable authentication module), see &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.python.org/3/library/spwd.html&quot;&gt;spwd&lt;/a&gt;  deprecation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;dl class=&quot;docutils&quot;&gt;&lt;dt&gt;Module type&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;C extension + Python module&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Deprecated in&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;3.8&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;To be removed in&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;3.10&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Has a designated expert&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;yes, but expert is currently inactive.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Substitute&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://pypi.org/project/bcrypt/&quot;&gt;bcrypt&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://pypi.org/project/passlib/&quot;&gt;passlib&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://pypi.org/project/argon2-cffi/&quot;&gt;argon2cffi&lt;/a&gt;, hashlib module (PBKDF2, scrypt)&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;macpath&quot; readability=&quot;7.4741784037559&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;toc-backref&quot; href=&quot;https://www.python.org/dev/peps/pep-0594/#id133&quot;&gt;macpath&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.python.org/3/library/macpath.html&quot;&gt;macpath&lt;/a&gt; module provides Mac OS 9 implementation of os.path routines. Mac OS 9 is no longer supported&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class=&quot;docutils&quot;&gt;&lt;dt&gt;Module type&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;pure Python&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Deprecated in&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;3.7&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Removed in&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;3.8&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Has a designated expert&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;n/a&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Substitute&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;strong&gt;none&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;nis&quot; readability=&quot;12.83368869936&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;toc-backref&quot; href=&quot;https://www.python.org/dev/peps/pep-0594/#id134&quot;&gt;nis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.python.org/3/library/nis.html&quot;&gt;nis&lt;/a&gt; module provides NIS/YP support. Network Information Service / Yellow Pages is an old and deprecated directory service protocol developed by Sun Microsystems. It's designed successor NIS+ from 1992 never took off. For a long time, libc's Name Service Switch, LDAP, and Kerberos/GSSAPI are considered a more powerful and more secure replacement of NIS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class=&quot;docutils&quot;&gt;&lt;dt&gt;Module type&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;C extension&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Deprecated in&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;3.8&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;To be removed in&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;3.10&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Has a designated expert&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;no&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Substitute&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;strong&gt;none&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;spwd&quot; readability=&quot;19.045161290323&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;toc-backref&quot; href=&quot;https://www.python.org/dev/peps/pep-0594/#id135&quot;&gt;spwd&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.python.org/3/library/spwd.html&quot;&gt;spwd&lt;/a&gt; module provides direct access to Unix shadow password database using non-standard APIs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In general it's a bad idea to use the spwd. The spwd circumvents system security policies, it does not use the PAM stack, and is only compatible with local user accounts, because it ignores NSS. The use of the &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;spwd&lt;/tt&gt; module for access control must be consider a &lt;em&gt;security bug&lt;/em&gt;, as it bypasses PAM's access control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further more the &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;spwd&lt;/tt&gt; module uses the &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;http://man7.org/linux/man-pages/man3/shadow.3.html&quot;&gt;shadow(3)&lt;/a&gt; APIs. Functions like &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;getspnam(3)&lt;/tt&gt; access the &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;/etc/shadow&lt;/tt&gt; file directly. This is dangerous and even forbidden for confined services on systems with a security engine like SELinux or AppArmor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class=&quot;docutils&quot;&gt;&lt;dt&gt;Module type&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;C extension&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Deprecated in&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;3.8&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;To be removed in&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;3.10&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Has a designated expert&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;no&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Substitute&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://pypi.org/project/python-pam/&quot;&gt;python-pam&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://pypi.org/project/simplepam/&quot;&gt;simpleplam&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;misc-modules&quot; readability=&quot;20.314462809917&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;formatter&quot; readability=&quot;6.4084507042254&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;toc-backref&quot; href=&quot;https://www.python.org/dev/peps/pep-0594/#id137&quot;&gt;formatter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.python.org/3/library/formatter.html&quot;&gt;formatter&lt;/a&gt; module is an old text formatting module which has been deprecated since Python 3.4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class=&quot;docutils&quot;&gt;&lt;dt&gt;Module type&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;pure Python&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Deprecated in&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;3.4&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;To be removed in&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;3.10&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Has a designated expert&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;no&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Substitute&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;em&gt;n/a&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;imp&quot; readability=&quot;7.5959595959596&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;toc-backref&quot; href=&quot;https://www.python.org/dev/peps/pep-0594/#id138&quot;&gt;imp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.python.org/3/library/imp.html&quot;&gt;imp&lt;/a&gt; module is the predecessor of the &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.python.org/3/library/importlib.html&quot;&gt;importlib&lt;/a&gt; module. Most functions have been deprecated since Python 3.3 and the module since Python 3.4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class=&quot;docutils&quot;&gt;&lt;dt&gt;Module type&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;C extension&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Deprecated in&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;3.4&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;To be removed in&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;3.10&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Has a designated expert&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;yes, experts have deprecated the module&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Substitute&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;importlib&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;msilib&quot; readability=&quot;13.706293706294&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;toc-backref&quot; href=&quot;https://www.python.org/dev/peps/pep-0594/#id139&quot;&gt;msilib&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.python.org/3/library/msilib.html&quot;&gt;msilib&lt;/a&gt; package is a Windows-only package. It supports the creation of Microsoft Installers (MSI). The package also exposes additional APIs to create cabinet files (CAB). The module is used to facilitate distutils to create MSI installers with &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;bdist_msi&lt;/tt&gt; command. In the past it was used to create CPython's official Windows installer, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft is slowly moving away from MSI in favor of Windows 10 Apps (AppX) as new deployment model .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class=&quot;docutils&quot;&gt;&lt;dt&gt;Module type&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;C extension + Python code&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Deprecated in&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;3.8&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;To be removed in&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;3.10&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Has a designated expert&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;no&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Substitute&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;strong&gt;none&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;parser&quot; readability=&quot;18.770623742455&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;toc-backref&quot; href=&quot;https://www.python.org/dev/peps/pep-0594/#id140&quot;&gt;parser&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.python.org/3/library/parser.html&quot;&gt;parser&lt;/a&gt; module provides an interface to Python’s internal parser and byte-code compiler. The stdlib has superior ways to interact with the parse tree. From Python 2.5 onward, it's much more convenient to cut in at the Abstract Syntax Tree (AST) generation and compilation stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;parser&lt;/tt&gt; module causes additional work. It's C code that must be kept in sync with any change to Python's grammar and internal parser. Pablo wants to remove the parser module and promote lib2to3's pgen2 instead .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most importantly the presence of the &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;parser&lt;/tt&gt; module makes it harder to switch to something more powerful than a LL(1) parser . Since the &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;parser&lt;/tt&gt; module is documented as deprecated since Python 2.5 and a new parsing technology is planned for 3.9, the &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;parser&lt;/tt&gt; module is scheduled for removal in 3.9.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class=&quot;docutils&quot;&gt;&lt;dt&gt;Module type&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;C extension&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Deprecated in&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;3.8, documented as deprecated since &lt;strong&gt;2.5&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;To be removed in&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.9&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Has a designated expert&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;yes, experts have deprecated the module.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Substitute&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;ast, lib2to3.pgen2&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;pipes&quot; readability=&quot;8.7247706422018&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;toc-backref&quot; href=&quot;https://www.python.org/dev/peps/pep-0594/#id141&quot;&gt;pipes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.python.org/3/library/pipes.html&quot;&gt;pipes&lt;/a&gt; module provides helpers to pipe the input of one command into the output of another command. The module is built on top of &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;os.popen&lt;/tt&gt;. Users are encouraged to use the subprocess module instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class=&quot;docutils&quot;&gt;&lt;dt&gt;Module type&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;pure Python&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Deprecated in&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;3.8&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;To be removed in&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;3.10&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Has a designated expert&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;no&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Substitute&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;subprocess module&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;removed-modules&quot; readability=&quot;6.7582417582418&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;fpectl&quot; readability=&quot;9.3965517241379&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.python.org/3.6/library/fpectl.html&quot;&gt;fpectl&lt;/a&gt; module was never built by default, its usage was discouraged and considered dangerous. It also required a configure flag that caused an ABI incompatibility. The module was removed in 3.7 by Nathaniel J. Smith in &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://bugs.python.org/issue29137&quot;&gt;bpo-29137&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class=&quot;docutils&quot;&gt;&lt;dt&gt;Module type&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;C extension + CAPI&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Deprecated in&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;3.7&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Removed in&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;3.7&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Has a designated expert&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;n/a&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Substitute&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;strong&gt;none&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;modules-to-keep&quot; readability=&quot;34.590846524432&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some modules were originally proposed for deprecation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;1&quot; class=&quot;colwidths-given docutils&quot;&gt;&lt;caption&gt;Table 2: Withdrawn deprecations&lt;/caption&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;&lt;col width=&quot;25%&quot;/&gt;&lt;col width=&quot;25%&quot;/&gt;&lt;col width=&quot;50%&quot;/&gt;&lt;/colgroup&gt;&lt;thead valign=&quot;bottom&quot;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th class=&quot;head&quot;&gt;Module&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class=&quot;head&quot;&gt;Deprecated in&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class=&quot;head&quot;&gt;Replacement&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody valign=&quot;top&quot; readability=&quot;2.5&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;colorsys&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;colormath, colour, colorspacious, Pillow&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;fileinput&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;argparse&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;getopt&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;argparse, optparse&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;lib2to3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;optparse&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;argparse&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;wave&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;colorsys&quot; readability=&quot;22.089171974522&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.python.org/3/library/colorsys.html&quot;&gt;colorsys&lt;/a&gt; module defines color conversion functions between RGB, YIQ, HSL, and HSV coordinate systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Walter Dörwald, Petr Viktorin, and others requested to keep &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;colorsys&lt;/tt&gt;. The module is useful to convert CSS colors between coordinate systems. The implementation is simple, mature, and does not impose maintenance overhead on core development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The PyPI packages &lt;em&gt;colormath&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;colour&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;colorspacious&lt;/em&gt; provide more and advanced features. The Pillow library is better suited to transform images between color systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class=&quot;docutils&quot;&gt;&lt;dt&gt;Module type&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;pure Python&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Has a designated expert&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;no&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Substitute&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://pypi.org/project/colormath/&quot;&gt;colormath&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://pypi.org/project/colour/&quot;&gt;colour&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://pypi.org/project/colorspacious/&quot;&gt;colorspacious&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://pypi.org/project/Pillow/&quot;&gt;Pillow&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;fileinput&quot; readability=&quot;12.416458852868&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.python.org/3/library/fileinput.html&quot;&gt;fileinput&lt;/a&gt; module implements a helpers to iterate over a list of files from &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;sys.argv&lt;/tt&gt;. The module predates the optparser and argparser module. The same functionality can be implemented with the argparser module.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several core developers expressed their interest to keep the module in the standard library, as it is handy for quick scripts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class=&quot;docutils&quot;&gt;&lt;dt&gt;Module type&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;pure Python&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Has a designated expert&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;no&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;lib2to3&quot; readability=&quot;9.3140794223827&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.python.org/3/library/2to3.html&quot;&gt;lib2to3&lt;/a&gt; package provides the &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;2to3&lt;/tt&gt; command to transpile Python 2 code to Python 3 code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The package is useful for other tasks besides porting code from Python 2 to 3. For example &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://pypi.org/project/black/&quot;&gt;black&lt;/a&gt;  uses it for code reformatting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class=&quot;docutils&quot;&gt;&lt;dt&gt;Module type&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;pure Python&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Has a designated expert&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;no&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;getopt&quot; readability=&quot;12.501597444089&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.python.org/3/library/getopt.html&quot;&gt;getopt&lt;/a&gt; module mimics C's getopt() option parser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although users are encouraged to use argparse instead, the getopt module is still widely used. The module is small, simple, and handy for C developers to write simple Python scripts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class=&quot;docutils&quot;&gt;&lt;dt&gt;Module type&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;pure Python&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Has a designated expert&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;no&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Substitute&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;argparse&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;optparse&quot; readability=&quot;9.36&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.python.org/3/library/optparse.html&quot;&gt;optparse&lt;/a&gt; module is the predecessor of the argparse module.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although it has been deprecated for many years, it's still too widely used to remove it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class=&quot;docutils&quot;&gt;&lt;dt&gt;Module type&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;pure Python&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Deprecated in&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;3.2&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Has a designated expert&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;yes&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Substitute&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;argparse&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;wave&quot; readability=&quot;18.442666666667&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.python.org/3/library/wave.html&quot;&gt;wave&lt;/a&gt; module provides support for the WAV sound format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The module is not deprecated, because The WAV format is still relevant these days. The &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;wave&lt;/tt&gt; module is also used in education, e.g. to show kids how to make noise with a computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The module uses one simple function from the &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.python.org/3/library/audioop.html&quot;&gt;audioop&lt;/a&gt;  module to perform byte swapping between little and big endian formats. Before 24 bit WAV support was added, byte swap used to be implemented with the &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;array&lt;/tt&gt; module. To remove &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;wave&lt;/tt&gt;'s dependency on the &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;audioop&lt;/tt&gt;, the byte swap function could be either be moved to another module (e.g. &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;operator&lt;/tt&gt;) or the &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;array&lt;/tt&gt; module could gain support for 24 bit (3 byte) arrays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class=&quot;docutils&quot;&gt;&lt;dt&gt;Module type&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;pure Python (depends on &lt;em&gt;byteswap&lt;/em&gt; from &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.python.org/3/library/audioop.html&quot;&gt;audioop&lt;/a&gt;  C extension)&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Has a designated expert&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;no&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;future-maintenance-of-removed-modules&quot; readability=&quot;54.908835904628&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main goal of the PEP is to reduce the burden and workload on the Python core developer team. Therefore removed modules will not be maintained by the core team as separate PyPI packages. However the removed code, tests and documentation may be moved into a new git repository, so community members have a place from which they can pick up and fork code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A first draft of a &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/tiran/legacylib&quot;&gt;legacylib&lt;/a&gt; repository is available on my private Github account. The modules could be made available on PyPI. The Python core team will not publish or maintain the packages. It is my hope that members of the Python community will adopt, maintain, and perhaps improve the deprecated modules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's my hope that some of the deprecated modules will be picked up and adopted by users that actually care about them. For example &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;colorsys&lt;/tt&gt; and &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;imghdr&lt;/tt&gt; are useful modules, but have limited feature set. A fork of &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;imghdr&lt;/tt&gt; can add new features and support for more image formats, without being constrained by Python's release cycle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the modules are in pure Python and can be easily packaged. Some depend on a simple C module, e.g. &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.python.org/3/library/audioop.html&quot;&gt;audioop&lt;/a&gt;  and &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.python.org/3/library/crypt.html&quot;&gt;crypt&lt;/a&gt; . Since &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.python.org/3/library/audioop.html&quot;&gt;audioop&lt;/a&gt;  does not depend on any external libraries, it can be shipped in as binary wheels with some effort. Other C modules can be replaced with ctypes or cffi. For example I created &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/tiran/legacycrypt&quot;&gt;legacycrypt&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;_crypt&lt;/tt&gt; extension reimplemented with a few lines of ctypes code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;discussions&quot;&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;simple&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;Elana Hashman and Nick Coghlan suggested to keep the &lt;em&gt;getopt&lt;/em&gt; module.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Berker Peksag proposed to deprecate and removed &lt;em&gt;msilib&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Brett Cannon recommended to delay active deprecation warnings and removal of modules like &lt;em&gt;imp&lt;/em&gt; until Python 3.10. Version 3.8 will be released shortly before Python 2 reaches end of lifetime. A delay reduced churn for users that migrate from Python 2 to 3.8.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Brett also came up with the idea to keep lib2to3. The package is useful for other purposes, e.g. &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://pypi.org/project/black/&quot;&gt;black&lt;/a&gt; uses it to reformat Python code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At one point, distutils was mentioned in the same sentence as this PEP. To avoid lengthy discussion and delay of the PEP, I decided against dealing with distutils. Deprecation of the distutils package will be handled by another PEP.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multiple people (Gregory P. Smith, David Beazley, Nick Coghlan, ...) convinced me to keep the &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.python.org/3/library/wave.html&quot;&gt;wave&lt;/a&gt;  module. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gregory P. Smith proposed to deprecate &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.python.org/3/library/nntplib.html&quot;&gt;nntplib&lt;/a&gt; . &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Andrew Svetlov mentioned the &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;socketserver&lt;/tt&gt; module is questionable. However it's used to implement &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;http.server&lt;/tt&gt; and &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;xmlrpc.server&lt;/tt&gt;. The stdlib doesn't have a replacement for the servers, yet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;update-history&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;update-1&quot;&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;simple&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;Deprecate &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.python.org/3/library/parser.html&quot;&gt;parser&lt;/a&gt;  module&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.python.org/3/library/fileinput.html&quot;&gt;fileinput&lt;/a&gt;  module&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Elaborate why &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.python.org/3/library/crypt.html&quot;&gt;crypt&lt;/a&gt;  and &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.python.org/3/library/spwd.html&quot;&gt;spwd&lt;/a&gt;  are dangerous and bad&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve sections for &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.python.org/3/library/cgitb.html&quot;&gt;cgitb&lt;/a&gt; , &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.python.org/3/library/colorsys.html&quot;&gt;colorsys&lt;/a&gt; , &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.python.org/3/library/nntplib.html&quot;&gt;nntplib&lt;/a&gt; , and &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.python.org/3/library/smtpd.html&quot;&gt;smtpd&lt;/a&gt;  modules&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.python.org/3/library/colorsys.html&quot;&gt;colorsys&lt;/a&gt; , &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.python.org/3/library/crypt.html&quot;&gt;crypt&lt;/a&gt; , &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.python.org/3/library/imghdr.html&quot;&gt;imghdr&lt;/a&gt; , &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.python.org/3/library/sndhdr.html&quot;&gt;sndhdr&lt;/a&gt; , and &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.python.org/3/library/spwd.html&quot;&gt;spwd&lt;/a&gt;  sections now list suitable substitutions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mention that &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;socketserver&lt;/tt&gt; is going to stay for &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;http.server&lt;/tt&gt; and &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;xmlrpc.server&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The future maintenance section now states that the deprecated modules may be adopted by Python community members.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;update-2&quot;&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;simple&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;Keep &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;colorsys&lt;/tt&gt; module&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add experts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Redirect discussions to discuss.python.org&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;copyright&quot; readability=&quot;5.9672131147541&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This document has been placed in the public domain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/python/peps/blob/master/pep-0594.rst&quot;&gt;https://github.com/python/peps/blob/master/pep-0594.rst&lt;/a&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2019 21:36:25 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jorshman</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:title>PEP 594 -- Removing dead batteries from the standard library</og:title>
<og:description>The official home of the Python Programming Language</og:description>
<og:image>https://www.python.org/static/opengraph-icon-200x200.png</og:image>
<og:url>https://www.python.org/dev/peps/pep-0594/</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.python.org/dev/peps/pep-0594/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Google and Binomial Open-Source Basis Universal Texture Format</title>
<link>https://opensource.googleblog.com/2019/05/google-and-binomial-partner-to-open.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://opensource.googleblog.com/2019/05/google-and-binomial-partner-to-open.html</guid>
<description>Today, Google and Binomial are excited to announce that we have partnered to open source &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/binomialLLC/basis_universal&quot;&gt;the Basis Universal texture codec&lt;/a&gt; to improve the performance of transmitting images on the web and within desktop and mobile applications, while maintaining GPU efficiency. This release fills an important gap in the graphics compression ecosystem and complements earlier work in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/google/draco&quot;&gt;Draco geometry compression&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;p&gt;The Basis Universal texture format is 6-8 times smaller than JPEG on the GPU, yet is a similar storage size as JPEG – making it a great alternative to current GPU compression methods that are inefficient and don’t operate cross platform – and provides a more performant alternative to JPEG/PNG. It creates compressed textures that work well in a variety of use cases - games, virtual &amp;amp; augmented reality, maps, photos, small-videos, and more!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Without a universal texture format, developers are left with 2 options:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Use GPU formats and take the storage size hit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use other formats that have reduced storage size but couldn't compete with the GPU performance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Maintaining so many different GPU formats is a burden on the whole ecosystem, from GPU manufacturers to software developers to the end user who can’t get a great cross platform experience. We’re streamlining this with one solution that has built-in flexibility (like optional higher quality modes) but is much easier on everyone to improve and maintain.&lt;p&gt;How does it all work? Compress your image using the encoder, choosing the quality settings that make sense for your project (you can also submit multiple images for small videos or optimization purposes, just know they’ll share the same color palette). Insert the transcoder code before rendering, which will turn the intermediary format into the GPU format your computer can read. The image stays compressed throughout this process, even on your GPU!  Instead of needing to decode and read the whole image, the GPU will read only the parts it needs. Enjoy the performance benefits!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table align=&quot;center&quot; cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;tr-caption-container&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-lrBsY8-mRTY/XOMlO8iXJHI/AAAAAAAAAOI/c2uOtvac6bMAFIrCNp7X4w61gHqgUTfzACLcBGAs/s1600/Google%2BOpen%2BSource%2BBlog%2B-%2BBinomial%2BUniversal%2Btextures.png&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;864&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1152&quot; src=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-lrBsY8-mRTY/XOMlO8iXJHI/AAAAAAAAAOI/c2uOtvac6bMAFIrCNp7X4w61gHqgUTfzACLcBGAs/s1600/Google%2BOpen%2BSource%2BBlog%2B-%2BBinomial%2BUniversal%2Btextures.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tr-caption&quot;&gt;Basis Universal can efficiently target the most common GPU formats&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
Google and Binomial will be working together to continue to support, maintain and add features, so &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/binomialLLC/basis_universal&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;check back frequently&lt;/a&gt; for the latest. This initial release of Basis Universal transcodes into the following GPU formats: PVRTC1 opaque, ETC1, ETC2 basic alpha, BC1-5, and BC7 opaque. Over the coming months more functionality will be added including BC7 transparent, ASTC opaque and alpha, PVRTC1 transparent, and higher quality BC7/ASTC.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;table align=&quot;center&quot; cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;tr-caption-container&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;578&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1600&quot; src=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-yAF7gCE6XhE/XOMliKLdQRI/AAAAAAAAAOQ/B60E_sPWCAgkKxvK6Tw5t7km-YvsubPCgCLcBGAs/s1600/Screenshot%2B2019-05-14%2Bat%2B5.08.45%2BPM.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tr-caption&quot;&gt;Basis Universal improves GPU memory usage over .jpeg and .png&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
With this partnership, we hope to see adoption of the transcoder in all major browsers to make performant cross-platform compressed textures accessible to everyone via the WebGL API, and the forthcoming WebGPU API. In addition to opening up the possibility of seamless integration into pipelines, everyone now has access to the state of the art compressor, which will also be open sourced.&lt;p&gt;We look forward to seeing what people do with Basis Universal now that it's open sourced. Check out the code and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/BinomialLLC/basis_universal/tree/master/webgl&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;demo&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/binomialLLC/basis_universal&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;, let us know what you think, and how you plan to use it! Currently, Basis Universal transcoders are available in C++ and WebAssembly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By Stephanie Hurlburt, Binomial and Jamieson Brettle, Chrome Media&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2019 18:33:46 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jasondavies</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://opensource.googleblog.com/2019/05/google-and-binomial-partner-to-open.html</og:url>
<og:title>Google and Binomial Partner to Open-Source Basis Universal Texture Format</og:title>
<og:description>The latest news from Google on open source releases, major projects, events, and student outreach programs.</og:description>
<og:image>https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-lrBsY8-mRTY/XOMlO8iXJHI/AAAAAAAAAOI/c2uOtvac6bMAFIrCNp7X4w61gHqgUTfzACLcBGAs/w1200-h630-p-k-no-nu/Google%2BOpen%2BSource%2BBlog%2B-%2BBinomial%2BUniversal%2Btextures.png</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://opensource.googleblog.com/2019/05/google-and-binomial-partner-to-open.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>US cosmetics are full of chemicals banned by Europe</title>
<link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2019/may/22/chemicals-in-cosmetics-us-restricted-eu</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2019/may/22/chemicals-in-cosmetics-us-restricted-eu</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;drop-cap&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;drop-cap__inner&quot;&gt;A&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; brief but telling piece of legislation was put forward in Connecticut in January. Just three lines in length, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cga.ct.gov/2019/TOB/s/pdf/2019SB-00075-R00-SB.PDF&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;bill&lt;/a&gt; calls for any cosmetics in the state to “meet the chemical safety standards established by the European Union”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The move, unlikely to be made law, is the latest signal of mounting anguish over the enfeebled regulation of everyday products in the US compared with European countries. Across a span of cosmetics, including makeup, toothpaste and shampoo, to items ranging from household cleaners to fruit juice to cheese, hundreds of potentially harmful ingredients banned in the EU are legally allowed in the US.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://interactive.guim.co.uk/embed/2019/05/toxic-america/v31/embed.html&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;toxic america embed&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Many Americans are unaware that they are absorbing untested and unsafe chemicals in their products,” said Alex Bergstein, a state senator who put forward the Connecticut legislation. Bergstein was previously the chair of the Mount Sinai Children’s Environmental health center.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Generally, the EU has got it right. In the US we have a strong favouritism towards companies and manufacturers, to the extent that public health and the environment is being harmed. The pendulum has swung in an extreme way and it’s really going to take a general awakening by the public.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The disparity in standards between the EU and US has grown to the extent it touches almost every element of most Americans’ lives. In &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.beautybyearth.com/over-1000-toxic-ingredients-banned-in-europe-but-not-in-us/&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;cosmetics alone&lt;/a&gt;, the EU has banned or restricted more than 1,300 chemicals while the US has outlawed or curbed just 11.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s possible to find formaldehyde, a known carcinogen banned in EU-sold cosmetics, in US hair-straightening treatments and nail polish. Parabens, linked to reproductive problems, are ruled out in the EU but not the US, where they lurk in skin and hair products. Coal tar dyes can be found in Americans’ eyeshadow, years after they were banned in the EU and Canada.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;element element-pullquote element--supporting&quot;&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;pullquote-paragraph&quot;&gt;Many Americans are unaware that they are absorbing untested and unsafe chemicals in their products&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;footer&gt;&lt;cite class=&quot;pullquote-cite&quot;&gt;Alex Bergstein&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/footer&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;“In the US it’s really a buyer beware situation,” said Janet Nudelman, director of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.safecosmetics.org/&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Campaign for Safe Cosmetics&lt;/a&gt;. “Cosmetics companies can use any raw material that they like and there’s no way to know if they are safe before they reach the shelves. The contrast with the EU is stark and troubling.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the heart of the EU’s approach is what as known as its &lt;a href=&quot;https://echa.europa.eu/regulations/reach/understanding-reach&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Reach (Registration, Evaluation, Authorisation and Restriction of Chemicals)&lt;/a&gt; laws which require manufacturers to prove to regulators that a product is safe before it can be used. The US has similar rules for new chemicals entering the market but no such precautionary principles for the thousands of potential toxins already in use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This means that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thrillist.com/health/nation/8-food-additives-banned-in-europe-that-are-legal-in-the-united-states&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;certain&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.chicagotribune.com/business/ct-artificial-food-coloring-0626-biz-20160624-story.html&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;dyes&lt;/a&gt; used in cheese, chocolates and juice are restricted in some European countries such as the UK – where a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/17825405&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;2007 study&lt;/a&gt; found some artificial colors and preservatives are linked to increased hyperactivity in children – but not the US. Atrazine is the most widely used herbicide in the US but has been banned in Europe since 2003 due to concerns it pollutes water. Lead-based paints were banned in much of Europe before the second world war but it took the US until 1978 to follow suit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;u-responsive-ratio&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;gu-image&quot; itemprop=&quot;contentUrl&quot; alt=&quot;Products such as shampoo and conditioner contain potentially harmful ingredients that are banned in the EU but legally allowed in the US.&quot; src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/59762356501c09bec4083d665cfafecd2c56c55b/0_384_5760_3456/master/5760.jpg?width=300&amp;amp;quality=85&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;fit=max&amp;amp;s=4aaca0a70a17248d140ab1eb864a17b9&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

Products such as shampoo and conditioner contain potentially harmful ingredients that are banned in the EU but legally allowed in the US. Photograph: Graham Turner/The Guardian
&lt;p&gt;Asbestos exposure has long been known to cause deaths and illnesses but the substance is still not banned in the US. The Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) attempted to do so in 1989 only to be overturned by the federal court following a backlash from manufacturers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The clout of powerful industry interests, combined with a regulatory system that demands a high level of proof of harm before any action is taken, has led to the American public being routinely exposed to chemicals that have been rubbed out of the lives of people in countries such as the UK, Germany and France.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“When the asbestos ban got overturned the EPA got nervous about banning anything,” said Molly Jacobs, a senior researcher at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.uml.edu/research/lowell-center/&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Lowell Center for Sustainable Production&lt;/a&gt;. “That was the last time the EPA sought very strict restrictions on industrial chemicals. The EU definitely has stronger policies.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of the more than 40,000 chemicals on the market in the US, the EPA &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/epa-only-restricts-9-chemicals-2016-2&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;has only banned six&lt;/a&gt;, including polychlorinated biphenyls (known as PCBs) which are linked to cancers, certain aerosol sprays blamed for the hole in the ozone layer and dioxins, used as an ingredient in Agent Orange, which the US sprayed during the Vietnam war.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under a 1976 law called the Toxic Substances Control Act (TSCA) the EPA has the power to limit chemicals, but critics say it is severely flawed. The act largely focuses on new potential toxins and even then &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ewg.org/enviroblog/2016/05/will-congress-protect-americans-untested-chemicals&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;gives the EPA just 90 days&lt;/a&gt; to work out if new products pose a risk before they hit the market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A 2016 amendment known as the Lautenberg Act required the EPA to evaluate all potentially risky chemicals, but progress on this backlog has often appeared painfully slow. “The EPA is playing catchup, and under this administration things aren’t moving very fast at all,” said Jacobs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The EPA recently listed 40 chemicals to be assessed for review, including asbestos, formaldehyde and trichloroethylene, which is used in refrigeration and can cause damage to the nervous system and liver. Andrew Wheeler, administrator of the EPA, said the agency was committed to the “successful and timely implementation” of the Lautenberg Act.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details data-snippet-id=&quot;bc3be0ed-944a-4f30-b04f-57a92e9d31ea&quot; data-snippet-type=&quot;qanda&quot; class=&quot;atom atom--snippet atom--snippet--qanda&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;atom--snippet__label&quot;&gt;Q&amp;amp;A&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;atom--snippet__headline&quot;&gt;What is the Toxic America series?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;button class=&quot;atom__button atom__button--large atom__button--rounded atom--snippet__handle&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;is-on&quot;&gt; Show&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;is-off&quot;&gt; Hide&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/button&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__body&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The American public is routinely exposed to toxic chemicals that have long been banned in countries such as the UK, Germany and France. If they’re deemed harmful in those countries, why not in the US?&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From pesticides in our produce to toxic dyes in cosmetics, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/series/toxic-america&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Toxic America&lt;/a&gt; is an ambitious new series to investigate the health risks from exposure to chemicals in our everyday lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project will:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Hold politicians, the Trump administration, the EPA and the FDA accountable for any regulatory rollbacks and failures keep dangerous chemicals out of products and off of store shelves&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Offer advice on how to navigate the supermarket and make food choices to reduce your exposure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Look at potential everyday dangers in our homes, from flame retardants in the sofa to carcinogens in dry cleaning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explore how plastic pollution is impacting human health&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Report on threats to our drinking water supply&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deliver rigorous, accessible, scientific reporting that explains what we know about how the chemicals in our environment are impacting our health and raises public awareness about this issue&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reader support protects The Guardian’s independence and ensures our in-depth environmental journalism remains open to all. Our editorial independence allows us to fight for transparency and accountability – and deliver the facts with clarity. Please help us reach our goal by &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.theguardian.com/us/contribute/toxicamerica&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline js-acquisition-link&quot;&gt;contributing today&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;footer class=&quot;atom--snippet__footer&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__feedback&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Was this helpful?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__ack&quot; hidden=&quot;&quot; aria-role=&quot;alert&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot;&gt;Thank you for your feedback.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/footer&gt;&lt;/details&gt;&lt;p&gt;But while the process has lagged, deaths have mounted. More than &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.edf.org/health/methylene-chloride-paint-strippers-ban-falls-short&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;50 deaths&lt;/a&gt; in the US since the 1980s have been linked to methylene chloride, a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cdc.gov/mmwr/preview/mmwrhtml/mm6107a2.htm&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;lethal&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/2222600&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;ingredient&lt;/a&gt; of paint stripper that has been banned in the EU. The EPA recently got around to banning the chemical from consumer use after a group of retailers voluntarily removed it from shelves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It will still be allowed for commercial use, however. “I am deeply disappointed that the EPA has decided to weaken its proposed ban on methylene chloride,” said Wendy Hartley, whose 21-year-old son Kevin died two years ago while using paint stripper on a bathtub, even after receiving training and wearing a protective mask. Hartley is one of two mothers &lt;a href=&quot;https://saferchemicals.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/saferchemicals.org_vpirg_et_al_v_wheeler_complaint.pdf&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;who are suing the EPA&lt;/a&gt; claiming that their sons died while using the paint stripper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Workers who use methylene chloride will now be left unprotected and at risk of health issues or death. I will continue my fight until the EPA does its job.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But even within the Trump administration, characterized by its zeal for deregulation, there is frustration that regulators have not been able to intervene as strongly as their EU counterparts. The Food and Drug Administration (FDA) recently found asbestos in Claire’s cosmetics but could do little when the company refused to recall the products. Claire’s subsequently withdrew the eyeshadows and compact powders &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fda.gov/Safety/Recalls/ucm633237.htm&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;voluntarily&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;element element-pullquote element--supporting&quot;&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;pullquote-paragraph&quot;&gt;Consumers have to realize they have the power to become more vocal and demand change&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;footer&gt;&lt;cite class=&quot;pullquote-cite&quot;&gt;Alex Bergstein&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/footer&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;Scott Gottlieb, the departing FDA commissioner, said the episode showed that cosmetics regulations unchanged since 1938 are “outdated” and need to be overhauled to ensure public health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“To be clear, there are currently no legal requirements for any cosmetic manufacturer marketing products to American consumers to test their products for safety,” Gottlieb &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fda.gov/NewsEvents/Newsroom/PressAnnouncements/ucm632736.htm&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt;. “This means that ultimately a cosmetic manufacturer can decide if they’d like to test their product for safety and register it with the FDA.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In lieu of any new laws, consumer advocates want federal agencies to act more aggressively and defy chemical industry lobbyists. They concede, however, a more likely recourse is an upwelling of public outrage at the risks faced in mundanities such as applying makeup or eating lunch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I’m hoping for dramatic changes in our politics but there’s little chance of that,” said Bergstein. “The federal government is barely functioning, so consumers have to realize they have the power to become more vocal and demand change. The awareness is still not there, though.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article has been updated to correct the date of the Lautenberg Act&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2019 16:21:28 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>gpresot</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2019/may/22/chemicals-in-cosmetics-us-restricted-eu</og:url>
<og:description>A long list of potentially harmful ingredients banned in the EU are legally allowed in the US due to historically relaxed regulations</og:description>
<og:image>https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/0d94de224c83b51b59044f957a2e807b0e75a77e/0_0_5644_3386/master/5644.jpg?width=1200&amp;height=630&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=crop&amp;overlay-align=bottom%2Cleft&amp;overlay-width=100p&amp;overlay-base64=L2ltZy9zdGF0aWMvb3ZlcmxheXMvdGctZGVmYXVsdC5wbmc&amp;s=27154847b11ca04f313d6455aa6fac19</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>US cosmetics are full of chemicals banned by Europe – why?</og:title>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2019/may/22/chemicals-in-cosmetics-us-restricted-eu</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Show HN: Scar – Static websites with HTTPS, a global CDN, and custom domains</title>
<link>https://github.com/cloudkj/scar</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/cloudkj/scar</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;Box-body&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;markdown-body entry-content p-5&quot; itemprop=&quot;text&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tired of reading outdated blog posts or combing through verbose AWS documentation just to figure out how to deploy your blog? Deploying static websites on AWS shouldn't be so &lt;em&gt;scar&lt;/em&gt;y.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SCAR&lt;/strong&gt; is a deployment stack that make it easy for you to deploy a static website with a custom domain, SSL, and a CDN. All you need is an AWS account to get started in three simple steps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Quick Start&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;1. Launch a new stack using the AWS console to create all the required resources&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://console.aws.amazon.com/cloudformation/home?region=us-east-1#/stacks/new?stackName=SCAR&amp;amp;templateURL=https://s3.amazonaws.com/cloudkj/scar_base_template.json&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/210bb3bfeebe0dd2b4db57ef83837273e1a51891/68747470733a2f2f73332e616d617a6f6e6177732e636f6d2f636c6f7564666f726d6174696f6e2d6578616d706c65732f636c6f7564666f726d6174696f6e2d6c61756e63682d737461636b2e706e67&quot; alt=&quot;Launch stack&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/cloudformation-examples/cloudformation-launch-stack.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;2. Update the settings at your domain registrar to use the Route 53 name servers&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find the name servers from your newly created &lt;a href=&quot;https://console.aws.amazon.com/route53/home?#hosted-zones:&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Route 53 hosted zone&lt;/a&gt;, then update the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/cloudkj/scar#name-server-settings&quot;&gt;name server settings at your registrar&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;3. Validate the domain for your new &lt;a href=&quot;https://console.aws.amazon.com/acm/home&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;ACM certificate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find and expand the details of the certificate for your domain in the AWS console, then click the &lt;em&gt;&quot;Create record in Route 53&quot;&lt;/em&gt; buttons in the two prompts for validation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;That's all, folks!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use the &lt;a href=&quot;https://console.aws.amazon.com/cloudformation/home&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;CloudFormation&lt;/a&gt; console to check the status of the stack. Once it has been created, navigate to your given domain, and you should see the SCAR welcome page. You can now upload the contents of your website directly with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://s3.console.aws.amazon.com/s3/home&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;S3 console&lt;/a&gt;, or use the &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/cli/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;AWS CLI&lt;/a&gt; for programmatic control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Stack&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/cloudkj/scar/blob/master/src/cloudformation/scar_base_template.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/cloudkj/scar/raw/master/src/cloudformation/scar_base_template.png&quot; alt=&quot;SCAR stack&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SCAR&lt;/strong&gt; is a deployment stack for static websites running entirely on AWS, using &lt;strong&gt;S&lt;/strong&gt;3, &lt;strong&gt;C&lt;/strong&gt;loudFront, &lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt;mazon Certificate Manager, and &lt;strong&gt;R&lt;/strong&gt;oute 53. For a given domain such as &lt;code&gt;example.com&lt;/code&gt;, the default SCAR stack will create the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Two S3 buckets, one for storing the contents of your static website (&lt;code&gt;www.example.com&lt;/code&gt;) and another for redirecting requests for the apex domain (&lt;code&gt;example.com&lt;/code&gt;) to the &lt;code&gt;www&lt;/code&gt; subdomain.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Two CloudFront distributions, one for each S3 bucket.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One ACM public SSL/TLS certificate for both &lt;code&gt;example.com&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;*.example.com&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One Route 53 hosted zone, with an &lt;code&gt;A&lt;/code&gt; record for each CloudFront distribution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The behavior for the default SCAR stack is to redirect all requests for the apex domain to the &lt;code&gt;www&lt;/code&gt; subdomain, and to redirect all &lt;code&gt;http&lt;/code&gt; requests to &lt;code&gt;https&lt;/code&gt;. All content will be stored in and served out of the &lt;code&gt;www&lt;/code&gt; S3 bucket.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additional stacks with slight variations from the default stack are also available:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;Behavior&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Default&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;WWW-&amp;gt;Apex&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Apex only&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Apex domain requests&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Redirect to &lt;code&gt;www&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;www&lt;/code&gt; subdomain requests&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Redirect to apex domain&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;N/A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;http&lt;/code&gt; requests&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Redirect to &lt;code&gt;https&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Redirect to &lt;code&gt;https&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Redirect to &lt;code&gt;https&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://console.aws.amazon.com/cloudformation/home?region=us-east-1#/stacks/new?stackName=SCAR&amp;amp;templateURL=https://s3.amazonaws.com/cloudkj/scar_base_template.json&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/210bb3bfeebe0dd2b4db57ef83837273e1a51891/68747470733a2f2f73332e616d617a6f6e6177732e636f6d2f636c6f7564666f726d6174696f6e2d6578616d706c65732f636c6f7564666f726d6174696f6e2d6c61756e63682d737461636b2e706e67&quot; alt=&quot;Launch stack&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/cloudformation-examples/cloudformation-launch-stack.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;(Coming Soon)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;(Coming Soon)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Name Server Settings&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Development&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TODO:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Additional templates for bare domain only, www-&amp;gt;root&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;See if there's a way to use same set of name servers for Route 53 zone to avoid having to always look up name servers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Include certificate validation using CNAME DNS record as part of template. Until official CloudFormation support, potential solutions:
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add custom resource to delete the CNAME DNS record used for validation in Route 53 hosted zone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Copyright © 2019&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2019 14:56:42 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>cloudkj</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars1.githubusercontent.com/u/227462?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>cloudkj/scar</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/cloudkj/scar</og:url>
<og:description>Deploy static websites in seconds - with HTTPS, a global CDN, and custom domains. - cloudkj/scar</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/cloudkj/scar</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Implementing a Convolutional Neural Network from Scratch in Python</title>
<link>https://victorzhou.com/blog/intro-to-cnns-part-1/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://victorzhou.com/blog/intro-to-cnns-part-1/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;There’s been a lot of buzz about Convolution Neural Networks (CNNs) in the past few years, especially because of how they’ve revolutionized the field of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Computer_vision&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Computer Vision&lt;/a&gt;. In this post, we’ll build on a basic background knowledge of neural networks and &lt;strong&gt;explore what CNNs are, understand how they work, and build a real one from scratch&lt;/strong&gt; (using only &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.numpy.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;numpy&lt;/a&gt;) in Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This post assumes only a basic knowledge of neural networks&lt;/strong&gt;. My &lt;a href=&quot;https://victorzhou.com/blog/intro-to-neural-networks/&quot;&gt;introduction to Neural Networks&lt;/a&gt; covers everything you’ll need to know, so you might want to read that first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ready? Let’s jump in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-motivation&quot;&gt;1. Motivation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A classic use case of CNNs is to perform image classification, e.g. looking at an image of a pet and deciding whether it’s a cat or a dog. It’s a seemingly simple task - &lt;strong&gt;why not just use a normal Neural Network?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;reason-1-images-are-big&quot;&gt;Reason 1: Images are Big&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Images used for Computer Vision problems nowadays are often 224x224 or larger. Imagine building a neural network to process 224x224 color images: including the 3 color channels (RGB) in the image, that comes out to 224 x 224 x 3 = &lt;strong&gt;150,528&lt;/strong&gt; input features! A typical hidden layer in such a network might have 1024 nodes, so we’d have to train 150,528 x 1024 = &lt;strong&gt;150+ million weights for the first layer alone&lt;/strong&gt;. Our network would be &lt;em&gt;huge&lt;/em&gt; and nearly impossible to train.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not like we need that many weights, either. The nice thing about images is that we know &lt;strong&gt;pixels are most useful in the context of their neighbors&lt;/strong&gt;. Objects in images are made up of small, &lt;em&gt;localized&lt;/em&gt; features, like the circular iris of an eye or the square corner of a piece of paper. Doesn’t it seem wasteful for &lt;em&gt;every&lt;/em&gt; node in the first hidden layer to look at &lt;em&gt;every&lt;/em&gt; pixel?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;reason-2-positions-can-change&quot;&gt;Reason 2: Positions can change&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you trained a network to detect dogs, you’d want it to be able to a detect a dog &lt;em&gt;regardless of where it appears in the image&lt;/em&gt;. Imagine training a network that works well on a certain dog image, but then feeding it a slightly shifted version of the same image. The dog would not activate the same neurons, so &lt;strong&gt;the network would react completely differently!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll see soon how a CNN can help us mitigate these problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-dataset&quot;&gt;2. Dataset&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this post, we’ll tackle the “Hello, World!” of Computer Vision: the &lt;a href=&quot;http://yann.lecun.com/exdb/mnist/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;MNIST&lt;/a&gt; handwritten digit classification problem. It’s simple: given an image, classify it as a digit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-image&quot; alt=&quot;Sample images from the MNIST dataset&quot; title=&quot;Sample images from the MNIST dataset&quot; src=&quot;https://victorzhou.com/static/16ddab2ee3bcd9e22d96f267e473a2f4/262c7/mnist-examples.png&quot; srcset=&quot;/static/16ddab2ee3bcd9e22d96f267e473a2f4/52d5c/mnist-examples.png 175w, /static/16ddab2ee3bcd9e22d96f267e473a2f4/1bae2/mnist-examples.png 350w, /static/16ddab2ee3bcd9e22d96f267e473a2f4/262c7/mnist-examples.png 594w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 594px) 100vw, 594px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt; Sample images from the MNIST dataset&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each image in the MNIST dataset is 28x28 and contains a centered, grayscale digit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Truth be told, a normal neural network would actually work just fine for this problem. You could treat each image as a 28 x 28 = 784-dimensional vector, feed that to a 784-dim input layer, stack a few hidden layers, and finish with an output layer of 10 nodes, 1 for each digit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This would only work because the MNIST dataset contains &lt;strong&gt;small&lt;/strong&gt; images that are &lt;strong&gt;centered&lt;/strong&gt;, so we wouldn’t run into the aforementioned issues of size or shifting. Keep in mind throughout the course of this post, however, that &lt;strong&gt;most real-world image classification problems aren’t this easy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enough buildup. Let’s get into CNNs!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;3-convolutions&quot;&gt;3. Convolutions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are Convolutional Neural Networks?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They’re basically just neural networks that use &lt;strong&gt;Convolutional layers&lt;/strong&gt;, a.k.a. Conv layers, which are based on the mathematical operation of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Convolution&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;convolution&lt;/a&gt;. Conv layers consist of a set of &lt;strong&gt;filters&lt;/strong&gt;, which you can think of as just 2d matrices of numbers. Here’s an example 3x3 filter:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://victorzhou.com/vertical-sobel-687f9b9f24fc4f9a50b30e8a1f4d3686.svg&quot;/&gt;A 3x3 filter&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can use an input image and a filter to produce an output image by &lt;strong&gt;convolving&lt;/strong&gt; the filter with the input image. This consists of&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Overlaying the filter on top of the image at some location.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Performing &lt;strong&gt;element-wise multiplication&lt;/strong&gt; between the values in the filter and their corresponding values in the image.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Summing up all the element-wise products. This sum is the output value for the &lt;strong&gt;destination pixel&lt;/strong&gt; in the output image.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Repeating for all locations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;8.4831081081081&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Side Note: We (along with many CNN implementations) are technically actually using &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cross-correlation&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;cross-correlation&lt;/a&gt; instead of convolution here, but they do almost the same thing. I won’t go into the difference in this post because it’s not that important, but feel free to look this up if you’re curious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That 4-step description was a little abstract, so let’s do an example. Consider this tiny 4x4 grayscale image and this 3x3 filter:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://victorzhou.com/media/cnn-post/convolve-example-1.svg&quot;/&gt;A 4x4 image (left) and a 3x3 filter (right)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The numbers in the image represent pixel intensities, where 0 is black and 255 is white. We’ll convolve the input image and the filter to produce a 2x2 output image:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://victorzhou.com/media/cnn-post/example-output.svg&quot;/&gt;A 2x2 output image&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To start, lets overlay our filter in the top left corner of the image:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://victorzhou.com/media/cnn-post/convolve-example-2.svg&quot;/&gt;Step 1: Overlay the filter (right) on top of the image (left)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, we perform element-wise multiplication between the overlapping image values and filter values. Here are the results, starting from the top left corner and going right, then down:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;Image Value&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Filter Value&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Result&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;50&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;80&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;31&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;62&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;33&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-33&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;90&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
Step 2: Performing element-wise multiplication.
&lt;p&gt;Next, we sum up all the results. That’s easy enough:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;katex-display&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;62−33=2962 - 33 = \boxed{29}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;6&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mbin&quot;&gt;−&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mrel&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-t vlist-t2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord boxpad&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;9&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-s&quot;&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, we place our result in the destination pixel of our output image. Since our filter is overlayed in the top left corner of the input image, our destination pixel is the top left pixel of the output image:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://victorzhou.com/media/cnn-post/convolve-output-1.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We do the same thing to generate the rest of the output image:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://victorzhou.com/convolve-output-69b4c1dd078ee363317bb8fa323eaace.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;31-how-is-this-useful&quot;&gt;3.1 How is this useful?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s zoom out for a second and see this at a higher level. What does convolving an image with a filter do? We can start by using the example 3x3 filter we’ve been using, which is commonly known as the vertical &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sobel_operator&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Sobel filter&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://victorzhou.com/media/cnn-post/vertical-sobel.svg&quot;/&gt;The vertical Sobel filter&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s an example of what the vertical Sobel filter does:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-image&quot; alt=&quot;lenna vertical&quot; title=&quot;An image convolved with the vertical Sobel filter&quot; src=&quot;https://victorzhou.com/static/44a1ff59f9a2c7f62cf9f56a8398efd0/a8200/lenna%2Bvertical.png&quot; srcset=&quot;/static/44a1ff59f9a2c7f62cf9f56a8398efd0/52d5c/lenna%2Bvertical.png 175w, /static/44a1ff59f9a2c7f62cf9f56a8398efd0/1bae2/lenna%2Bvertical.png 350w, /static/44a1ff59f9a2c7f62cf9f56a8398efd0/a8200/lenna%2Bvertical.png 700w, /static/44a1ff59f9a2c7f62cf9f56a8398efd0/8ff1e/lenna%2Bvertical.png 800w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 700px) 100vw, 700px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt; An image convolved with the vertical Sobel filter&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, there’s also a horizontal Sobel filter:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://victorzhou.com/media/cnn-post/horizontal-sobel.svg&quot;/&gt;The horizontal Sobel filter&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-image&quot; alt=&quot;lenna horizontal&quot; title=&quot;An image convolved with the horizontal Sobel filter&quot; src=&quot;https://victorzhou.com/static/342e8364a392ac2cbcd4ecc7b9aacaa1/a8200/lenna%2Bhorizontal.png&quot; srcset=&quot;/static/342e8364a392ac2cbcd4ecc7b9aacaa1/52d5c/lenna%2Bhorizontal.png 175w, /static/342e8364a392ac2cbcd4ecc7b9aacaa1/1bae2/lenna%2Bhorizontal.png 350w, /static/342e8364a392ac2cbcd4ecc7b9aacaa1/a8200/lenna%2Bhorizontal.png 700w, /static/342e8364a392ac2cbcd4ecc7b9aacaa1/8ff1e/lenna%2Bhorizontal.png 800w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 700px) 100vw, 700px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt; An image convolved with the horizontal Sobel filter&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See what’s happening? &lt;strong&gt;Sobel filters are edge-detectors&lt;/strong&gt;. The vertical Sobel filter detects vertical edges, and the horizontal Sobel filter detects horizontal edges. The output images are now easily interpreted: a bright pixel (one that has a high value) in the output image indicates that there’s a strong edge around there in the original image.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can you see why an edge-detected image might be more useful than the raw image? Think back to our MNIST handwritten digit classification problem for a second. A CNN trained on MNIST might look for the digit 1, for example, by using an edge-detection filter and checking for two prominent vertical edges near the center of the image. In general, &lt;strong&gt;convolution helps us look for specific localized image features&lt;/strong&gt; (like edges) that we can use later in the network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;32-padding&quot;&gt;3.2 Padding&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember convolving a 4x4 input image with a 3x3 filter earlier to produce a 2x2 output image? Often times, we’d prefer to have the output image be the same size as the input image. To do this, we add zeros around the image so we can overlay the filter in more places. A 3x3 filter requires 1 pixel of padding:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://victorzhou.com/media/cnn-post/padding.svg&quot;/&gt;A 4x4 input convolved with a 3x3 filter to produce a 4x4 output using same padding&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is called &lt;strong&gt;“same” padding&lt;/strong&gt;, since the input and output have the same dimensions. Not using any padding, which is what we’ve been doing and will continue to do for this post, is sometimes referred to as &lt;strong&gt;“valid” padding&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;33-conv-layers&quot;&gt;3.3 Conv Layers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that we know how image convolution works and why it’s useful, let’s see how it’s actually used in CNNs. As mentioned before, CNNs include &lt;strong&gt;conv layers&lt;/strong&gt; that use a set of filters to turn input images into output images. A conv layer’s primary parameter is the &lt;strong&gt;number of filters&lt;/strong&gt; it has.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For our MNIST CNN, we’ll use a small conv layer with 8 filters as the initial layer in our network. This means it’ll turn the 28x28 input image into a 26x26x8 output &lt;strong&gt;volume&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://victorzhou.com/media/cnn-post/cnn-dims-1.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reminder: The output is 26x26x8 and not 28x28x8 because we’re using &lt;strong&gt;valid padding&lt;/strong&gt;, which decreases the input’s width and height by 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each of the 4 filters in the conv layer produces a 26x26 output, so stacked together they make up a 26x26x8 volume. All of this happens because of 3 &lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;×\times&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;×&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; 3 (filter size) &lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;×\times&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;×&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; 8 (number of filters) = &lt;strong&gt;only 72 weights&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;34-implementing-convolution&quot;&gt;3.4 Implementing Convolution&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time to put what we’ve learned into code! We’ll implement a conv layer’s feedforward portion, which takes care of convolving filters with an input image to produce an output volume. For simplicity, we’ll assume filters are always 3x3 (which is not true - 5x5 and 7x7 filters are also very common).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s start implementing a conv layer class:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;python&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;language-python&quot;&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-python&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; numpy &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; np

&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token class-name&quot;&gt;Conv3x3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
  

  &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;__init__&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;self&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; num_filters&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
    self&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;num_filters &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; num_filters

    
    
    self&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;filters &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; np&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;random&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;randn&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;num_filters&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;9&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;Conv3x3&lt;/code&gt; class takes only one argument: the number of filters. In the constructor, we store the number of filters and initialize a random filters array using NumPy’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.scipy.org/doc/numpy/reference/generated/numpy.random.randn.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;randn()&lt;/a&gt; method.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;8.1486486486486&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: Diving by 9 during the initialization is more important than you may think. If the initial values are too large or too small, training the network will be ineffective. To learn more, read about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.quora.com/What-is-an-intuitive-explanation-of-the-Xavier-Initialization-for-Deep-Neural-Networks&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Xavier Initialization&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, the actual convolution:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;python&quot; readability=&quot;26&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;language-python&quot;&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-python&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token class-name&quot;&gt;Conv3x3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
  

  &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;iterate_regions&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;self&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; image&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;token triple-quoted-string string&quot;&gt;'''
    Generates all possible 3x3 image regions using valid padding.
    - image is a 2d numpy array
    '''&lt;/span&gt;
    h&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; w &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; image&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;shape

    &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; i &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token builtin&quot;&gt;range&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;h &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; j &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token builtin&quot;&gt;range&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;w &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
        im_region &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; image&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;i&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;i &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; j&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;j &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;yield&lt;/span&gt; im_region&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; i&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; j

  &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;forward&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;self&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token builtin&quot;&gt;input&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;token triple-quoted-string string&quot;&gt;'''
    Performs a forward pass of the conv layer using the given input.
    Returns a 3d numpy array with dimensions (h, w, num_filters).
    - input is a 2d numpy array
    '''&lt;/span&gt;
    h&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; w &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token builtin&quot;&gt;input&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;shape
    output &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; np&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;zeros&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;h &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; w &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; self&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;num_filters&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; im_region&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; i&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; j &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; self&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;iterate_regions&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token builtin&quot;&gt;input&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;gatsby-highlight-code-line&quot;&gt;      output&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;i&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; j&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; np&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token builtin&quot;&gt;sum&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;im_region &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; self&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;filters&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; axis&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; output&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-python&quot;&gt;iterate_regions&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt; is a helper &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.python.org/moin/Generators&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;generator&lt;/a&gt; method that yields all valid 3x3 image regions for us. This will be useful for implementing the backwards portion of this class later on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The line of code that actually performs the convolutions is highlighted above. Let’s break it down:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;We have &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;im_region&lt;/code&gt;, a 3x3 array containing the relevant image region.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We have &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;self.filters&lt;/code&gt;, a 3d array.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We do &lt;code class=&quot;language-python&quot;&gt;im_region &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; self&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;filters&lt;/code&gt;, which uses numpy’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.scipy.org/doc/numpy/user/basics.broadcasting.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;broadcasting&lt;/a&gt; feature to element-wise multiply the two arrays. The result is a 3d array with the same dimension as &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;self.filters&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.scipy.org/doc/numpy/reference/generated/numpy.sum.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;np.sum()&lt;/a&gt; the result of the previous step using &lt;code class=&quot;language-python&quot;&gt;axis&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;, which produces a 1d array of length &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;num_filters&lt;/code&gt; where each element contains the convolution result for the corresponding filter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We assign the result to &lt;code class=&quot;language-python&quot;&gt;output&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;i&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; j&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;, which contains convolution results for pixel &lt;code class=&quot;language-python&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;i&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; j&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt; in the output.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The sequence above is performed for each pixel in the output until we obtain our final output volume! Let’s give our code a test run:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;python&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;language-python&quot;&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-python&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; mnist
&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; conv &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; Conv3x3



train_images &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; mnist&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;train_images&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
train_labels &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; mnist&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;train_labels&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

conv &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; Conv3x3&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
output &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; conv&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;forward&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;train_images&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;print&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;output&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;shape&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looks good so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: in our &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;Conv3x3&lt;/code&gt; implementation, we assume the input is a &lt;strong&gt;2d&lt;/strong&gt; numpy array for simplicity, because that’s how our MNIST images are stored. This works for us because we use it as the first layer in our network, but most CNNs have many more Conv layers. If we were building a bigger network that needed to use &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;Conv3x3&lt;/code&gt; multiple times, we’d have to make the input be a &lt;strong&gt;3d&lt;/strong&gt; numpy array.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;4-pooling&quot;&gt;4. Pooling&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neighboring pixels in images tend to have similar values, so conv layers will typically also produce similar values for neighboring pixels in outputs. As a result, &lt;strong&gt;much of the information contained in a conv layer’s output is redundant&lt;/strong&gt;. For example, if we use an edge-detecting filter and find a strong edge at a certain location, chances are that we’ll also find relatively strong edges at locations 1 pixel shifted from the original one. However, &lt;strong&gt;these are all the same edge!&lt;/strong&gt; We’re not finding anything new.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pooling layers solve this problem. All they do is reduce the size of the input it’s given by (you guessed it) &lt;em&gt;pooling&lt;/em&gt; values together in the input. The pooling is usually done by a simple operation like &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;max&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;min&lt;/code&gt;, or &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;average&lt;/code&gt;. Here’s an example of a Max Pooling layer with a pooling size of 2:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://victorzhou.com/pool-ac441205fd06dc037b3db2dbf05660f7.gif&quot;/&gt;Max Pooling (pool size 2) on a 4x4 image to produce a 2x2 output&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To perform &lt;em&gt;max&lt;/em&gt; pooling, we traverse the input image in 2x2 blocks (because pool size = 2) and put the &lt;em&gt;max&lt;/em&gt; value into the output image at the corresponding pixel. That’s it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pooling divides the input’s width and height by the pool size&lt;/strong&gt;. For our MNIST CNN, we’ll place a Max Pooling layer with a pool size of 2 right after our initial conv layer. The pooling layer will transform a 26x26x8 input into a 13x13x8 output:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://victorzhou.com/media/cnn-post/cnn-dims-2.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;41-implementing-pooling&quot;&gt;4.1 Implementing Pooling&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll implement a &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;MaxPool2&lt;/code&gt; class with the same methods as our conv class from the previous section:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;python&quot; readability=&quot;30&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;language-python&quot;&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-python&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; numpy &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; np

&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token class-name&quot;&gt;MaxPool2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
  

  &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;iterate_regions&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;self&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; image&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;token triple-quoted-string string&quot;&gt;'''
    Generates non-overlapping 2x2 image regions to pool over.
    - image is a 2d numpy array
    '''&lt;/span&gt;
    h&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; w&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; _ &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; image&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;shape
    new_h &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; h &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;//&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;
    new_w &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; h &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;//&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; i &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token builtin&quot;&gt;range&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;new_h&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; j &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token builtin&quot;&gt;range&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;new_w&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
        im_region &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; image&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;i &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;i &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;j &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;j &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;yield&lt;/span&gt; im_region&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; i&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; j

  &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;forward&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;self&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token builtin&quot;&gt;input&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;token triple-quoted-string string&quot;&gt;'''
    Performs a forward pass of the maxpool layer using the given input.
    Returns a 3d numpy array with dimensions (h / 2, w / 2, num_filters).
    - input is a 3d numpy array with dimensions (h, w, num_filters)
    '''&lt;/span&gt;
    h&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; w&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; num_filters &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token builtin&quot;&gt;input&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;shape
    output &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; np&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;zeros&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;h &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;//&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; w &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;//&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; num_filters&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; im_region&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; i&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; j &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; self&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;iterate_regions&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token builtin&quot;&gt;input&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;gatsby-highlight-code-line&quot;&gt;      output&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;i&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; j&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; np&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;amax&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;im_region&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; axis&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; output&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This class works similarly to the &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;Conv3x3&lt;/code&gt; class we implemented previously. The critical line is again highlighted: to find the max from a given image region, we use &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.scipy.org/doc/numpy/reference/generated/numpy.amax.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;np.amax()&lt;/a&gt;, numpy’s array max method. We set &lt;code class=&quot;language-python&quot;&gt;axis&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt; because we only want to maximize over the first two dimensions, height and width, and not the third, &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;num_filters&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s test it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;python&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;language-python&quot;&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-python&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; mnist
&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; conv &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; Conv3x3
&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; maxpool &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; MaxPool2



train_images &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; mnist&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;train_images&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
train_labels &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; mnist&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;train_labels&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

conv &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; Conv3x3&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
pool &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; MaxPool2&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

output &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; conv&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;forward&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;train_images&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
output &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; pool&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;forward&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;output&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;print&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;output&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;shape&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our MNIST CNN is starting to come together!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;5-softmax&quot;&gt;5. Softmax&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To complete our CNN, we need to give it the ability to actually make predictions. We’ll do that by using the standard final layer for a multiclass classification problem: the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Softmax_function&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Softmax&lt;/a&gt; layer, a standard fully-connected (dense) layer that uses the softmax activation function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;5.2258064516129&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reminder: fully-connected layers have every node connected to every output from the previous layer. We used fully-connected layers in my &lt;a href=&quot;https://victorzhou.com/blog/intro-to-neural-networks/&quot;&gt;intro to Neural Networks&lt;/a&gt; if you need a refresher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Softmax turns arbitrary real values into &lt;em&gt;probabilities&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. The math behind it is pretty simple: given some numbers,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Raise &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/E_(mathematical_constant)&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;e&lt;/a&gt; (the mathematical constant) to the power of each of those numbers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sum up all the exponentials (powers of &lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;ee&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;e&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;). This result is the denominator.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use each number’s exponential as its numerator.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;Probability=NumeratorDenominator\text{Probability} = \frac{\text{Numerator}}{\text{Denominator}}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord text&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;Probability&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mrel&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mfrac&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-t vlist-t2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sizing reset-size6 size3 mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord text mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mtight&quot;&gt;Denominator&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sizing reset-size6 size3 mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord text mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mtight&quot;&gt;Numerator&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-s&quot;&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;Written more fancily, Softmax performs the following transform on &lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;nn&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;n&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; numbers &lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;x1…xnx_1 \ldots x_n&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;msupsub&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-t vlist-t2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sizing reset-size6 size3 mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mtight&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-s&quot;&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;minner&quot;&gt;…&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;msupsub&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-t vlist-t2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sizing reset-size6 size3 mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault mtight&quot;&gt;n&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-s&quot;&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;katex-display&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;s(xi)=exi∑j=1nexjs(x_i) = \frac{e^{x_i}}{\sum_{j=1}^n e^{x_j}}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;s&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mopen&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;msupsub&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-t vlist-t2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sizing reset-size6 size3 mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault mtight&quot;&gt;i&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-s&quot;&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mclose&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mrel&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mfrac&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-t vlist-t2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mop&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mop op-symbol small-op&quot;&gt;∑&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;msupsub&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-t vlist-t2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sizing reset-size6 size3 mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault mtight&quot;&gt;j&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mrel mtight&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mtight&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sizing reset-size6 size3 mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault mtight&quot;&gt;n&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-s&quot;&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;e&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;msupsub&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-t&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sizing reset-size6 size3 mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault mtight&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;msupsub&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-t vlist-t2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sizing reset-size3 size1 mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault mtight&quot;&gt;j&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-s&quot;&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;e&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;msupsub&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-t&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sizing reset-size6 size3 mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault mtight&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;msupsub&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-t vlist-t2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sizing reset-size3 size1 mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault mtight&quot;&gt;i&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-s&quot;&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-s&quot;&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The outputs of the Softmax transform are always in the range &lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;[0,1][0, 1]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mopen&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mpunct&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mclose&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; and add up to 1. Hence, they’re &lt;strong&gt;probabilities&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s a simple example using the numbers -1, 0, 3, and 5:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;katex-display&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;Denominator=e−1+e0+e3+e5=169.87\begin{aligned} \text{Denominator} &amp;amp;= e^{-1} + e^0 + e^3 + e^5 \\ &amp;amp;= \boxed{169.87} \\ \end{aligned}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mtable&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;col-align-r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-t vlist-t2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord text&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;Denominator&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-s&quot;&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;col-align-l&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-t vlist-t2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mrel&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;e&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;msupsub&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-t&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sizing reset-size6 size3 mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mtight&quot;&gt;−&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mtight&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mbin&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;e&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;msupsub&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-t&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sizing reset-size6 size3 mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mtight&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mbin&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;e&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;msupsub&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-t&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sizing reset-size6 size3 mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mtight&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mbin&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;e&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;msupsub&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-t&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sizing reset-size6 size3 mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mtight&quot;&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mrel&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-t vlist-t2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord boxpad&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;6&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;9&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;7&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-s&quot;&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-s&quot;&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;xx&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;exe^x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;e&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;msupsub&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-t&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sizing reset-size6 size3 mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault mtight&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Probability (&lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;ex169.87\frac{e^x}{169.87}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mfrac&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-t vlist-t2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sizing reset-size6 size3 mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mtight&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mtight&quot;&gt;6&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mtight&quot;&gt;9&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mtight&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mtight&quot;&gt;8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mtight&quot;&gt;7&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sizing reset-size6 size3 mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault mtight&quot;&gt;e&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;msupsub&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-t&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sizing reset-size3 size1 mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault mtight&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-s&quot;&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;-1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.368&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.002&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.006&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;20.09&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.118&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;148.41&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.874&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;51-usage&quot;&gt;5.1 Usage&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll use a softmax layer with &lt;strong&gt;10 nodes, one representing each digit,&lt;/strong&gt; as the final layer in our CNN. Each node in the layer will be connected to every input. After the softmax transformation is applied, &lt;strong&gt;the digit represented by the node with the highest probability&lt;/strong&gt; will be the output of the CNN!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://victorzhou.com/media/cnn-post/cnn-dims-3.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;52-cross-entropy-loss&quot;&gt;5.2 Cross-Entropy Loss&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might have just thought to yourself, &lt;span class=&quot;emph-special&quot;&gt;why bother transforming the outputs into probabilities? Won’t the highest output value always have the highest probability?&lt;/span&gt; If you did, you’re absolutely right. &lt;strong&gt;We don’t actually need to use softmax to predict a digit&lt;/strong&gt; - we could just pick the digit with the highest output from the network!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What softmax really does is help us &lt;strong&gt;quantify how sure we are of our prediction&lt;/strong&gt;, which is useful when training and evaluating our CNN. More specifically, using softmax lets us use &lt;strong&gt;cross-entropy loss&lt;/strong&gt;, which takes into account how sure we are of each prediction. Here’s how we calculate cross-entropy loss:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;katex-display&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;L=−ln⁡(pc)L = -\ln(p_c)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;L&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mrel&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;−&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mop&quot;&gt;ln&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mopen&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;p&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;msupsub&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-t vlist-t2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sizing reset-size6 size3 mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault mtight&quot;&gt;c&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-s&quot;&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mclose&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;where &lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;cc&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;c&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; is the correct class (in our case, the correct digit), &lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;pcp_c&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;p&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;msupsub&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-t vlist-t2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sizing reset-size6 size3 mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault mtight&quot;&gt;c&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-s&quot;&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; is the predicted probability for class &lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;cc&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;c&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, and &lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;ln⁡\ln&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mop&quot;&gt;ln&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_logarithm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;natural log&lt;/a&gt;. As always, a lower loss is better. For example, in the best case, we’d have&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;katex-display&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;pc=1,L=−ln⁡(1)=0p_c = 1, L = -\ln(1) = 0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;p&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;msupsub&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-t vlist-t2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sizing reset-size6 size3 mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault mtight&quot;&gt;c&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-s&quot;&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mrel&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mpunct&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;L&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mrel&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;−&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mop&quot;&gt;ln&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mopen&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mclose&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mrel&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a more realistic case, we might have&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;katex-display&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;pc=0.8,L=−ln⁡(0.8)=0.223p_c = 0.8, L = -\ln(0.8) = 0.223&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;p&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;msupsub&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-t vlist-t2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sizing reset-size6 size3 mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault mtight&quot;&gt;c&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-s&quot;&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mrel&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mpunct&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;L&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mrel&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;−&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mop&quot;&gt;ln&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mopen&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mclose&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mrel&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll be seeing cross-entropy loss again later on in this post, so keep it in mind!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;53-implementing-softmax&quot;&gt;5.3 Implementing Softmax&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You know the drill by now - let’s implement a &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;Softmax&lt;/code&gt; layer class:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;python&quot; readability=&quot;17&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;language-python&quot;&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-python&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; numpy &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; np

&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token class-name&quot;&gt;Softmax&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
  

  &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;__init__&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;self&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; input_len&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; nodes&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
    
    self&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;weights &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; np&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;random&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;randn&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;input_len&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; nodes&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; input_len
    self&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;biases &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; np&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;zeros&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;nodes&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

  &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;forward&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;self&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token builtin&quot;&gt;input&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;token triple-quoted-string string&quot;&gt;'''
    Performs a forward pass of the softmax layer using the given input.
    Returns a 1d numpy array containing the respective probability values.
    - input can be any array with any dimensions.
    '''&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;token builtin&quot;&gt;input&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token builtin&quot;&gt;input&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;flatten&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

    input_len&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; nodes &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; self&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;weights&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;shape

    totals &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; np&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;dot&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token builtin&quot;&gt;input&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; self&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;weights&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; self&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;biases
    exp &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; np&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;exp&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;totals&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; exp &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; np&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token builtin&quot;&gt;sum&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;exp&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; axis&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s nothing too complicated here. A few highlights:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;We &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.scipy.org/doc/numpy/reference/generated/numpy.ndarray.flatten.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;flatten()&lt;/a&gt; the input to make it easier to work with, since we no longer need its shape.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.scipy.org/doc/numpy/reference/generated/numpy.dot.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;np.dot()&lt;/a&gt; multiplies &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;input&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;self.weights&lt;/code&gt; element-wise and then sums the results.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.scipy.org/doc/numpy/reference/generated/numpy.exp.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;np.exp()&lt;/a&gt; calculates the exponentials used for Softmax.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;We’ve now completed the entire forward pass of our CNN! Putting it together:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;python&quot; readability=&quot;22&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;language-python&quot;&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-python&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; mnist
&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; numpy &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; np
&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; conv &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; Conv3x3
&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; maxpool &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; MaxPool2
&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; softmax &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; Softmax



test_images &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; mnist&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;test_images&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;1000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;
test_labels &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; mnist&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;test_labels&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;1000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;

conv &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; Conv3x3&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;                  
pool &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; MaxPool2&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;                  
softmax &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; Softmax&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;13&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;13&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; 

&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;forward&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;image&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; label&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;token triple-quoted-string string&quot;&gt;'''
  Completes a forward pass of the CNN and calculates the accuracy and
  cross-entropy loss.
  - image is a 2d numpy array
  - label is a digit
  '''&lt;/span&gt;
  
  
  out &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; conv&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;forward&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;image &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;255&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;0.5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  out &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; pool&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;forward&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;out&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  out &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; softmax&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;forward&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;out&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

  
  loss &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;np&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;log&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;out&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;label&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  acc &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; np&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;argmax&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;out&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; label &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;else&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;

  &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; out&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; loss&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; acc

&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;print&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;'MNIST CNN initialized!'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

loss &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;
num_correct &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; i&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;im&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; label&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token builtin&quot;&gt;enumerate&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token builtin&quot;&gt;zip&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;test_images&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; test_labels&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
  
  _&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; l&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; acc &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; forward&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;im&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; label&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  loss &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;+=&lt;/span&gt; l
  num_correct &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;+=&lt;/span&gt; acc

  
  &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; i &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;%&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;100&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;99&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;print&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;'[Step %d] Past 100 steps: Average Loss %.3f | Accuracy: %d%%'&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;%&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;i &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; loss &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;100&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; num_correct&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    loss &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;
    num_correct &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Running &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;cnn.py&lt;/code&gt; gives us output similar to this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;text&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;MNIST CNN initialized!
[Step 100] Past 100 steps: Average Loss 2.302 | Accuracy: 11%
[Step 200] Past 100 steps: Average Loss 2.302 | Accuracy: 8%
[Step 300] Past 100 steps: Average Loss 2.302 | Accuracy: 3%
[Step 400] Past 100 steps: Average Loss 2.302 | Accuracy: 12%&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This makes sense: with random weight initialization, you’d expect the CNN to be only as good as random guessing. Random guessing would yield 10% accuracy (since there are 10 classes) and a cross-entropy loss of &lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;−ln⁡(0.1)=2.302{-\ln(0.1)} = 2.302&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;−&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mop&quot;&gt;ln&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mopen&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mclose&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mrel&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, which is what we get!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Want to try or tinker with this code yourself? &lt;a href=&quot;https://repl.it/@vzhou842/A-CNN-from-scratch-Part-1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Run this CNN in your browser&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; It’s also available on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/vzhou842/cnn-from-scratch/tree/master&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;6-conclusion&quot;&gt;6. Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s the end of this introduction to CNNs! In this post, we&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Motivated why CNNs might be more useful for certain problems, like image classification.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduced the &lt;strong&gt;MNIST&lt;/strong&gt; handwritten digit dataset.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learned about &lt;strong&gt;Conv layers&lt;/strong&gt;, which convolve filters with images to produce more useful outputs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Talked about &lt;strong&gt;Pooling layers&lt;/strong&gt;, which can help prune everything but the most useful features.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implemented a &lt;strong&gt;Softmax&lt;/strong&gt; layer so we could use &lt;strong&gt;cross-entropy loss&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;There’s still much more that we haven’t covered yet, such as how to actually train a CNN. &lt;strong&gt;Part 2 of this CNN series will do a deep-dive on training a CNN&lt;/strong&gt;, including deriving gradients and implementing backprop. &lt;a href=&quot;http://eepurl.com/gf8JCX&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Subscribe to my newsletter&lt;/a&gt; if you want to get an email when Part 2 comes out (soon)!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re eager to see a trained CNN in action: this &lt;a href=&quot;https://keras.io/examples/mnist_cnn/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;example Keras CNN&lt;/a&gt; trained on MNIST achieves &lt;strong&gt;99.25%&lt;/strong&gt; accuracy. CNNs are powerful!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2019 14:46:34 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>vzhou842</dc:creator>
<og:title>CNNs, Part 1: An Introduction to Convolutional Neural Networks - victorzhou.com</og:title>
<og:description>A simple guide to what CNNs are, how they work, and how to build one from scratch in Python.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:image>https://victorzhou.com/media/cnn-post/cnn-dims-3.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://victorzhou.com/blog/intro-to-cnns-part-1/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>IQ rates are dropping in many developed countries</title>
<link>https://www.nbcnews.com/think/opinion/iq-rates-are-dropping-many-developed-countries-doesn-t-bode-ncna1008576</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nbcnews.com/think/opinion/iq-rates-are-dropping-many-developed-countries-doesn-t-bode-ncna1008576</guid>
<description>&lt;section class=&quot;mb7&quot; readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;time data-test=&quot;timestamp__datePublished&quot; class=&quot;relative z-1&quot; itemprop=&quot;datePublished&quot; content=&quot;2019-05-22T08:31:00.000Z&quot; datetime=&quot;Wed May 22 2019 08:31:00 GMT+0000 (UTC)&quot;&gt;May 22, 2019, 8:31 AM UTC&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By Evan Horowitz&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;People are getting dumber. That's not a judgment; it's a global fact. In a host of leading nations, IQ scores &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencealert.com/iq-scores-falling-in-worrying-reversal-20th-century-intelligence-boom-flynn-effect-intelligence&quot;&gt;have started to decline&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Though there are legitimate questions about the relationship between &lt;a href=&quot;https://theconversation.com/the-iq-test-wars-why-screening-for-intelligence-is-still-so-controversial-81428&quot;&gt;IQ and intelligence&lt;/a&gt;, and broad recognition that success depends as much on &lt;a href=&quot;https://qz.com/work/1233940/angela-duckworth-explains-grit-is-the-key-to-success-and-self-confidence/&quot;&gt;other virtues like grit&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.guilford.com/books/Contemporary-Intellectual-Assessment/Flanagan-McDonough/9781462535781&quot;&gt;IQ tests in use&lt;/a&gt; throughout the world today really do seem to capture something meaningful and durable. Decades of research have shown that individual IQ scores predict things such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0160289606000171&quot;&gt;educational achievement&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/19234402&quot;&gt;longevity&lt;/a&gt;. More broadly, the average IQ score of a country is linked to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.weforum.org/agenda/2015/12/why-your-nations-iq-matters-more-than-your-own/&quot;&gt;economic growth&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/21537056&quot;&gt;scientific innovation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;container___1unUn mv8 smallContainer___VvWON mt2-m&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text___2iNlR ma0 mt6 f8 lh-none founders-cond&quot;&gt;Even children born to high-IQ parents are slipping down the IQ ladder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;So if IQ scores are really dropping, that could not only mean 15 more seasons of the Kardashians, but also the potential end of progress on all these other fronts, ultimately leading to fewer scientific breakthroughs, stagnant economies and a general dimming of our collective future.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;As yet, the United States hasn’t hit this IQ wall — despite what you may be tempted to surmise from the current state of the political debate. But don’t rush to celebrate American exceptionalism: If IQs are dropping in other advanced countries but not here, maybe that means we’re not really an advanced country (&lt;a href=&quot;https://qz.com/879092/the-us-doesnt-look-like-a-developed-country/&quot;&gt;too much poverty&lt;/a&gt;, too little &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.peoplespolicyproject.org/2018/03/26/the-u-s-spends-far-too-little-on-social-welfare/&quot;&gt;social support&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Or — just as troubling — if we are keeping up with the Joneses (or Johanssons and Jacques) in terms of national development, that means we are likely to experience similarly plummeting IQs in the near future. At which point, the U.S. will face the same dangers of intellectual and economic stagnation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://secure.nbcnews.com/optin/think/newsletter?icid=ed_npd_nn_nn_tk-win_181016&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;SIGN UP FOR THE THINK WEEKLY NEWSLETTER HERE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;If we want to prevent America from suffering this fate, we’d better figure out why IQs are dropping elsewhere. But it’s uncharted territory. Until recently, IQ scores only moved in one direction: up. And if you're thinking, &quot;Isn't the test set up so that 100 is always the average IQ?,&quot; that's only true because researchers rescale the tests to correct for improving raw scores. (Also, congrats, that’s the kind of critical thinking we don’t want to lose!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;These raw scores have been rising on a variety of standard IQ tests for &lt;a href=&quot;https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1745691615577701&quot;&gt;over half a century&lt;/a&gt;. That may sound odd if you think of IQ as largely hereditary. But current IQ tests are designed to measure &lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.scientificamerican.com/beautiful-minds/what-do-iq-tests-test-interview-with-psychologist-w-joel-schneider/?redirect=1&quot;&gt;core cognitive skills&lt;/a&gt; such as short-term memory, problem-solving speed and visual processing, and rising scores show that these cognitive capabilities can actually be &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0160289618300904&quot;&gt;sharpened by environmental factors&lt;/a&gt; such as higher-quality schools and more demanding workplaces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;related related--relatedContent related___2RfEH single___1bpFv dn-print&quot; data-test=&quot;related&quot;&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;For a while, rising IQ scores seemed like clear evidence of social progress, palpable proof that humanity was getting steadily smarter — and might even be able to boost brainpower indefinitely. Scholars called it the &quot;Flynn effect,&quot; in homage to J.R. Flynn, the researcher who recognized its full sweep and import.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;These days, however, &lt;a href=&quot;https://pdf.sciencedirectassets.com/272071/1-s2.0-S0160289617X0007X/1-s2.0-S0160289617302787/main.pdf?x-amz-security-token=AgoJb3JpZ2luX2VjEOf%2F%2F%2F%2F%2F%2F%2F%2F%2F%2FwEaCXVzLWVhc3QtMSJHMEUCIFxVZykALebxgKzmTAIeHJlkTmU96qKlb4uKdSsRYUy%2FAiEAqayZJ%2FIbFuc0fo6cMhy6vStTCkXpp44fYy98mf0gtQ8q4wMI4P%2F%2F%2F%2F%2F%2F%2F%2F%2F%2FARACGgwwNTkwMDM1NDY4NjUiDJ4YqaOZU3y33JCYmyq3A3lArkT0Q74uNuuP3UFR1YpenDeQxYuFcRUJ0JqtChddAe1fEWPRi4DbLqZbZvE3tCFsejoiybU8v2VcdQJWyHFH%2Bedx0rYkINhETAgQ%2Bd8HOEzGuiyrm7a61MsO1cwx7RD8D9K5Nkoh6BNmYOLtFt%2B84gp%2Bdwfs0UZvaYV6gI1g04Rpd0iGOvoJT0nS1DGHiOwq2AxN%2F9Vc3u5%2FaWzQtk5ilcMsV21hzywDOLfO1H53wYml776tzTkR3%2B6qb90H29s424USZNJdZ1lLpGO1049RtI682gvar%2FhoLQGcWsnDY9dCcGwIB4QSHQ%2Bz951x%2BM6DfT4JO2OLwCqJII6%2FhC%2FAopeEhBBxgtR%2BQWXF2Hu6uts8yo9I98WpziBNKeuqp%2B5fz8%2BFTMH0lmAmsyWwQv4NCoWKuDDGKtOkeQdY4XH0AsBLyjmVMXRFojTndwuxXGNHIrJ0bP7GihgN9W%2Bk%2Fhh6fqUa%2Fs%2BB6zGbcFEw5dREjal6%2FLSPH%2F09v22b6kDM3fTw%2B%2BdLA6CZ2Ypw%2BUOC%2FL6MnnokplNCE0Jt%2FrzSlBK9ruTS08sTja%2BtDwqa3fRou2AWYJ0PWlkwvInt5gU6tAEz%2FGfInN8NlS0YWPGiVuSrfnpFHFJIdF6zKEMQuihgSqZN8OPOJol4zRM3Lthc38QBGcg72LBbyQI1adqR3eAV0BFbAfvT09mHzff4R7%2BqA1xT%2BJKzu9i2W%2F%2BEs25wHyeLUwFh9He6RBenw4OnBcKC9dK7v9ipTXDjWiO63Ut6FUTtHhjNFxwy0nsfESzNKoU8inE3Fepidan1DAuo2KRZ7ikYagM3ZsdcLOmCnID%2FOOz5SaA%3D&amp;amp;AWSAccessKeyId=ASIAQ3PHCVTY7XVYDE45&amp;amp;Expires=1557877759&amp;amp;Signature=WqQHbQY%2FGYMyFNBr2GX%2FHC96Uuc%3D&amp;amp;hash=29940b44fb521b16b8c86b891eda72f67296d7e8bc9b175877823a9736aca741&amp;amp;host=68042c943591013ac2b2430a89b270f6af2c76d8dfd086a07176afe7c76c2c61&amp;amp;pii=S0160289617302787&amp;amp;tid=spdf-4ac2916d-db8d-40d7-a685-53cf35e0fe94&amp;amp;sid=53bc8c3a543de845664a6d51292a9b656853gxrqa&amp;amp;type=client&quot;&gt;Flynn himself concedes&lt;/a&gt; that &quot;the IQ gains of the 20th century have faltered.&quot; A range of studies using a variety of well-established &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gwern.net/docs/iq/2016-dutton.pdf&quot;&gt;IQ tests and metrics&lt;/a&gt; have found declining scores across Scandinavia, Britain, Germany, France and Australia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Details vary from study to study and from place to place given the available data. &lt;a href=&quot;http://differentialclub.wdfiles.com/local--files/assigned-topics-iq/End%20of%20Flynn%20effect%202004.pdf&quot;&gt;IQ shortfalls in Norway&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://psycnet.apa.org/record/2008-01547-005&quot;&gt;Denmark appear in longstanding tests&lt;/a&gt; of military conscripts, whereas information about &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.iapsych.com/iqmr/fe/LinkedDocuments/dutton2015.pdf&quot;&gt;France is based&lt;/a&gt; on a smaller sample and a different test. But the broad pattern has become clearer: Beginning around the turn of the 21st century, many of the most economically advanced nations began experiencing some kind of decline in IQ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;inlineVideo___3ZAlE&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;pt4 pl4 pr8 pt5-m pl6-m pr9-m info___3BGcG&quot;&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;infoText___2xq7T f2 ttu mt3&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;date___2i7u0&quot;&gt;May 22, 2018&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;02:40&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;One potential explanation was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gwern.net/docs/iq/2016-dutton.pdf&quot;&gt;quasi-eugenic&lt;/a&gt;. As in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0387808/&quot;&gt;the movie “Idiocracy,”&lt;/a&gt; it was suggested that average intelligence is being pulled down because lower-IQ families are having more children (&quot;dysgenic fertility&quot; is the technical term). Alternatively, widening immigration might be bringing less-intelligent newcomers to societies with otherwise higher IQs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;However, a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pnas.org/content/pnas/115/26/6674.full.pdf&quot;&gt;2018 study of Norway&lt;/a&gt; has punctured these theories by showing that IQs are dropping not just across societies but within families. In other words, the issue is not that educated Norwegians are increasingly outnumbered by lower-IQ immigrants or the children of less-educated citizens. Even children born to high-IQ parents are slipping down the IQ ladder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Some environmental factor — or collection of factors — is causing a drop in the IQ scores of parents and their own children, and older kids and their younger siblings. One leading explanation is that the rise of lower-skill &lt;a href=&quot;https://fredblog.stlouisfed.org/2018/08/the-rise-of-the-service-economy/&quot;&gt;service jobs&lt;/a&gt; has made work &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.com/news/magazine-31556802&quot;&gt;less intellectually demanding&lt;/a&gt;, leaving IQs to atrophy as people flex their brains less.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;container___1unUn mv8 smallContainer___VvWON mt2-m&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text___2iNlR ma0 mt6 f8 lh-none founders-cond&quot;&gt;One leading explanation is that the rise of lower-skill service jobs has made work less intellectually demanding, leaving IQs to atrophy as people flex their brains less.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;There are also other possibilities, largely untested, such as global warming &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/does-global-warming-make-food-less-nutritious/?redirect=1&quot;&gt;making food less nutritious&lt;/a&gt; or information-age devices &lt;a href=&quot;https://health.clevelandclinic.org/science-clear-multitasking-doesnt-work/&quot;&gt;sapping our ability to focus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Ultimately, it’d be nice to pin down the precise reason IQ scores are dropping before we’re too stupid to figure it out, especially as these scores really do seem connected to &lt;a href=&quot;https://mason.gmu.edu/~gjonesb/IQandNationalProductivity.pdf&quot;&gt;long-term productivity and economic success&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;lastMarkupItem&quot;&gt;And while we might be able to compensate with skills besides intelligence, like determination or passion, in a world where IQ scores continue to fall — and where the drop expands to places like the United States — there’s also a bleaker scenario: a global intelligence crisis that undermines humanity's problem-solving capacity and leaves us ill-equipped to tackle the complex challenges posed by AI, global warming and developments we have yet to imagine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;articleBylineContainer mt8&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;articleByline byline___2NGv_ noImage___3G0GY pt3 pb2&quot; readability=&quot;34&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;articleByline__name name___32ZJk founders-mono f3 lh-title ls-tight pt1 pt4-m ml9 ml0-m ml0-print&quot;&gt;Evan Horowitz&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;articleByline__social social___kAOJV f2 mt2 mt4-m ml9 ml0-m dn-print&quot; data-test=&quot;article-byline__social&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;articleByline__bio bio___3q2CD publico-txt f2 lh-copy mt3 mt0-m ml9-m&quot;&gt;Evan Horowitz is the director of research communication at FCLT Global, a financial think thank. The views expressed here are his own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2019 13:10:44 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>onetimemanytime</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nbcnews.com/think/opinion/iq-rates-are-dropping-many-developed-countries-doesn-t-bode-ncna1008576</og:url>
<og:title>Opinion | Many developed countries are getting dumber, and the U.S. is likely next</og:title>
<og:description>An intelligence crisis could undermine our problem-solving capacities and dim the prospects of the global economy.</og:description>
<og:image>https://media1.s-nbcnews.com/j/newscms/2019_21/2865616/190521-brain-iq-think-cs-456p_a579caeb49b55338447cdc5b80c70199.nbcnews-fp-1200-630.jpg</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nbcnews.com/think/opinion/iq-rates-are-dropping-many-developed-countries-doesn-t-bode-ncna1008576</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>