<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Students learn more effectively from print textbooks than screens, study says</title>
<link>http://www.businessinsider.com/students-learning-education-print-textbooks-screens-study-2017-10</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.businessinsider.com/students-learning-education-print-textbooks-screens-study-2017-10</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;KonaFilter image-container float_right&quot;&gt;
&lt;div data-post-image=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;image on-image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://static6.businessinsider.com/image/59a03c7d79bbfd1d008b4a6d-480/trade-in-used-textbooks-and-get-up-to-80-of-their-value-in-an-amazon-gift-card.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;trade in used textbooks and get up to 80 of their value in an amazon gift card&quot; width=&quot;480&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;source-only&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;source&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;ShutterStock&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today's students see themselves as &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.emeraldinsight.com/doi/pdfplus/10.1108/10748120110424816&quot;&gt;digital natives&lt;/a&gt;, the first generation to grow up surrounded by technology like smartphones, tablets and e-readers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teachers, parents and policymakers certainly acknowledge the growing influence of technology and have responded in kind. We've seen &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/2017/03/28/microsoft-google-and-facebook-see-billions-in-future-of-education.html&quot;&gt;more investment in classroom technologies&lt;/a&gt;, with students now equipped with school-issued iPads and access to e-textbooks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.leginfo.ca.gov/pub/09-10/bill/sen/sb_0001-0050/sb_48_bill_20090825_enrolled.html&quot;&gt;2009&lt;/a&gt;, California passed a law requiring that all college textbooks be available in electronic form by 2020; in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flsenate.gov/Session/Bill/2011/2120/BillText/er/HTML&quot;&gt;2011&lt;/a&gt;, Florida lawmakers passed legislation requiring public schools to convert their textbooks to digital versions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given this trend, teachers, students, parents and policymakers might assume that students' familiarity and preference for technology translates into better learning outcomes. But we've found that's not necessarily true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As researchers in learning and text comprehension, our recent work has focused on the differences between reading print and digital media. While new forms of classroom technology like digital textbooks are more accessible and portable, it would be wrong to assume that students will automatically be better served by digital reading simply because they prefer it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Speed – at a cost&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our work has revealed a significant discrepancy. Students said they preferred and performed better when reading on screens. But their actual performance tended to suffer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, from our &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0034654317722961&quot;&gt;review of research done since 1992&lt;/a&gt;, we found that students were able to better comprehend information in print for texts that were more than a page in length. This appears to be related to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.co.twosides.info/download/To_Scroll_or_Not_to_Scroll_Scrolling_Working_Memory_Capacity_and_Comprehending_Complex_Texts.pdf&quot;&gt;disruptive effect&lt;/a&gt; that scrolling has on comprehension. We were also surprised to learn that few researchers tested different levels of comprehension or documented reading time in their studies of printed and digital texts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To explore these patterns further, we conducted &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/00220973.2016.1143794?journalCode=vjxe20&quot;&gt;three studies&lt;/a&gt; that explored college students' ability to comprehend information on paper and from screens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students first rated their medium preferences. After reading two passages, one online and one in print, these students then completed three tasks: Describe the main idea of the texts, list key points covered in the readings and provide any other relevant content they could recall. When they were done, we asked them to judge their comprehension performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Across the studies, the texts differed in length, and we collected varying data (e.g., reading time). Nonetheless, some key findings emerged that shed new light on the differences between reading printed and digital content:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;4.5&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students overwhelming preferred to read digitally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reading was significantly faster online than in print.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students judged their comprehension as better online than in print.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paradoxically, overall comprehension was better for print versus digital reading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The medium didn't matter for general questions (like understanding the main idea of the text).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But when it came to specific questions, comprehension was significantly better when participants read printed texts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;KonaFilter image-container display-table&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span data-post-image=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;image on-image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://static6.businessinsider.com/image/57b62306db5ce953008b79c6-2000/gettyimages-125675111.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;students&quot; data-mce-source=&quot;Getty Images/Sean Gallup&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;source-only&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;source&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Getty Images/Sean Gallup&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Placing print in perspective&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From these findings, there are some lessons that can be conveyed to policymakers, teachers, parents and students about print's place in an increasingly digital world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Consider the purpose&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all read for many reasons. Sometimes we're looking for an answer to a very specific question. Other times, we want to browse a newspaper for today's headlines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we're about to pick up an article or text in a printed or digital format, we should keep in mind why we're reading. There's likely to be a difference in which medium works best for which purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other words, there's no &quot;one medium fits all&quot; approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Analyze the task&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most consistent findings from our research is that, for some tasks, medium doesn't seem to matter. If all students are being asked to do is to understand and remember the big idea or gist of what they're reading, there's &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/00220973.2016.1143794?journalCode=vjxe20&quot;&gt;no benefit in selecting one medium over another&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But when the reading assignment demands more engagement or deeper comprehension, students &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/00220973.2016.1143794?journalCode=vjxe20&quot;&gt;may be better off reading print&lt;/a&gt;. Teachers could make students aware that their ability to comprehend the assignment may be influenced by the medium they choose. This awareness could lessen the discrepancy we witnessed in students' judgments of their performance vis-à-vis how they actually performed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;KonaFilter image-container display-table&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span data-post-image=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;image on-image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://static3.businessinsider.com/image/543fd7a3eab8ea2612f582d1-1200/classroom%20students%20teacher%20ipad.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Classroom Students Teacher iPad&quot; data-mce-source=&quot;REUTERS/Eric Gaillard&quot; data-mce-caption=&quot;Elementary school children use electronic tablets on the first day of class in the new school year in Nice, September 3, 2013.&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caption-source&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Elementary school children use electronic tablets on the first day of class in the new school year in Nice, September 3, 2013.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;source&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;REUTERS/Eric Gaillard&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Slow it down&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our third experiment, we were able to create meaningful profiles of college students based on the way they read and comprehended from printed and digital texts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among those profiles, we found a select group of undergraduates who actually comprehended better when they moved from print to digital. What distinguished this atypical group was that they actually read slower when the text was on the computer than when it was in a book. In other words, they didn't take the ease of engaging with the digital text for granted. Using this select group as a model, students could possibly be taught or directed to fight the tendency to glide through online texts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Something that can't be measured&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There may be &lt;a href=&quot;http://community.aiim.org/blogs/dennis-kempner/2013/11/18/go-green-and-save-green-economic--ecologic-benefits-of-going-paperless&quot;&gt;economic and environmental reasons&lt;/a&gt; to go paperless. But there's clearly something important that would be lost with print's demise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our academic lives, we have books and articles that we regularly return to. The dog-eared pages of these treasured readings contain lines of text etched with questions or reflections. It's difficult to imagine a similar level of engagement with a digital text. There should probably always be a place for print in students' academic lives – no matter how technologically savvy they become.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, we realize that the march toward online reading will continue unabated. And we don't want to downplay the many conveniences of online texts, which include breadth and speed of access.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rather, our goal is simply to remind today's digital natives – and those who shape their educational experiences – that there are significant costs and consequences to discounting the printed word's value for learning and academic development.&lt;/p&gt;



</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 20:41:34 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ALee</dc:creator>
<og:title>A new study shows that students learn way more effectively from print textbooks than screens</og:title>
<og:description>Students told researchers they preferred and performed better when reading on screens. But their actual performance tended to suffer.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>http://www.businessinsider.com/students-learning-education-print-textbooks-screens-study-2017-10</og:url>
<og:image>http://static6.businessinsider.com/image/59e2c4d4d4e9201f008b567b-1190-625/a-new-study-shows-that-students-learn-way-more-effectively-from-print-textbooks-than-screens.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.businessinsider.com/students-learning-education-print-textbooks-screens-study-2017-10</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>New law bans California employers from asking applicants their prior salary</title>
<link>http://m.sfgate.com/business/networth/article/New-law-bans-California-employers-from-asking-12274431.php</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://m.sfgate.com/business/networth/article/New-law-bans-California-employers-from-asking-12274431.php</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;California employers can no longer ask job applicants about their prior salary and — if applicants ask — must give them a pay range for the job they are seeking, under a new state law that takes effect Jan. 1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://leginfo.legislature.ca.gov/faces/billTextClient.xhtml?bill_id=201720180AB168&quot;&gt;AB168&lt;/a&gt;, signed Thursday by Gov. Jerry Brown, applies to all public- and private-sector California employers of any size.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal is to narrow the gender wage gap. If a woman is paid less than a man doing the same job and a new employer bases her pay on her prior salary, gender discrimination can be perpetuated, the bill’s backers say.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year, the state passed &lt;a href=&quot;https://leginfo.legislature.ca.gov/faces/billCompareClient.xhtml?bill_id=201520160AB1676&quot;&gt;a weaker law&lt;/a&gt; that said prior compensation, by itself, cannot justify any disparity in compensation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new bill goes further by prohibiting employers, “orally or in writing, personally or through an agent,” from asking about an applicant’s previous pay. However, if the applicant “voluntarily and without prompting” provides this information, the employer may use it “in determining the salary for that applicant.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Delaware, Massachusetts and Oregon have passed similar laws that take effect later this year or next, said attorney Ben Ebbink of Fisher &amp;amp; Phillips in Sacramento. Philadelphia passed one that was supposed to take effect in May but is being challenged in court. New York City and San Francisco have similar ordinances that take effect Oct. 31 and July 1, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The San Francisco ordinance also prevents employers in the city from releasing a current or former employee’s salary without consent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most employers ask about an applicant’s previous salary in interviews or applications. Some online applications cannot be submitted until a prior salary is entered. Multistate employers will have to decide whether they want to remove that question from all applications or come up with different versions for use where it’s outlawed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If more cities and states ban the salary question, at some point “employers will reach a tipping point” and stop asking anyone, Ebbink said. But we’re not there yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The California law applies to jobs within the state, but “I think there is an argument that it would apply” to employers soliciting Californians for jobs out of state, Ebbink said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bill, sponsored by Assemblywoman Susan Eggman, D-Stockton, had bipartisan support. Two of its co-authors are Republicans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A long list of employers and groups representing them opposed it. The San Jose Unified School District said it needs to attract and retain educators and “in order to (do) so, it needs the ability to ask applicants about their salary history.” The Western States Trucking Association said it “effectively eliminates an employer’s ability to negotiate wage, as well as creates a new reason to sue.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bill was &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sfchronicle.com/bayarea/article/Jerry-Brown-signs-job-protection-tampon-bills-12273817.php&quot;&gt;one of nine&lt;/a&gt; that Brown signed Thursday designed to help women and children. One of them, SB63, will let mothers and fathers working for employers with 20 to 49 employees take 12 weeks of unpaid, job-protected leave to care for a newborn or newly adopted child or foster child. Businesses with 50 or more workers already had to provide this. The leave can be taken in two-week increments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brown did not sign another workplace bill, &lt;a href=&quot;https://leginfo.legislature.ca.gov/faces/billNavClient.xhtml?bill_id=201720180AB1209&quot;&gt;AB1209,&lt;/a&gt; that would require employers with 500 or more employees in California to collect certain information on gender wage differentials and submit it to the secretary of state by July 1, 2020, and biennially thereafter. The secretary of state would publish it on a website. That bill was more controversial than the two workplace bills he did sign, Ebbink said. The fact that he did not sign it has led to speculation that he may veto it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A bill that would give California public school teachers and other employees six weeks of paid maternity &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sfchronicle.com/business/networth/article/California-teachers-other-school-employees-could-12243454.php&quot;&gt;also still awaits&lt;/a&gt; his signature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kathleen Pender is a San Francisco Chronicle columnist. Email: &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:kpender@sfchronicle.com&quot;&gt;kpender@sfchronicle.com&lt;/a&gt; Twitter: &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/kathpender&quot;&gt;@kathpender&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 19:26:52 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ssaxena80</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>New law bans California employers from asking applicants their prior salary</og:title>
<og:description>California employers can no longer ask job applicants about their prior salary and — if applicants ask — must give them a pay range for the job they are seeking, under a new&amp;hellip;</og:description>
<og:url>http://www.sfgate.com/business/networth/article/New-law-bans-California-employers-from-asking-12274431.php</og:url>
<og:image>http://ww4.hdnux.com/photos/66/30/37/14256071/5/premium_gallery_landscape.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://m.sfgate.com/business/networth/article/New-law-bans-California-employers-from-asking-12274431.php</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>75% decline over 27 years in total flying insect biomass in protected areas</title>
<link>http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;abstract toc-section&quot; readability=&quot;20&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Global declines in insects have sparked wide interest among scientists, politicians, and the general public. Loss of insect diversity and abundance is expected to provoke cascading effects on food webs and to jeopardize ecosystem services. Our understanding of the extent and underlying causes of this decline is based on the abundance of single species or taxonomic groups only, rather than changes in insect biomass which is more relevant for ecological functioning. Here, we used a standardized protocol to measure total insect biomass using Malaise traps, deployed over 27 years in 63 nature protection areas in Germany (96 unique location-year combinations) to infer on the status and trend of local entomofauna. Our analysis estimates a seasonal decline of 76%, and mid-summer decline of 82% in flying insect biomass over the 27 years of study. We show that this decline is apparent regardless of habitat type, while changes in weather, land use, and habitat characteristics cannot explain this overall decline. This yet unrecognized loss of insect biomass must be taken into account in evaluating declines in abundance of species depending on insects as a food source, and ecosystem functioning in the European landscape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;articleinfo&quot; readability=&quot;144.21102791014&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Citation:&lt;/strong&gt; Hallmann CA, Sorg M, Jongejans E, Siepel H, Hofland N, Schwan H, et al. (2017) More than 75 percent decline over 27 years in total flying insect biomass in protected areas. PLoS ONE12(10): e0185809. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Editor:&lt;/strong&gt; Eric Gordon Lamb, University of Saskatchewan, CANADA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Received:&lt;/strong&gt; July 28, 2017; &lt;strong&gt;Accepted:&lt;/strong&gt; September 19, 2017; &lt;strong&gt;Published:&lt;/strong&gt; October 18, 2017&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Copyright:&lt;/strong&gt; © 2017 Hallmann et al. This is an open access article distributed under the terms of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/&quot;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution License&lt;/a&gt;, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data Availability:&lt;/strong&gt; All relevant data are within the paper and its Supporting Information files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Funding:&lt;/strong&gt; CH and EJ were supported by the Netherlands Organization for Scientific Research (NWO grants 840.11.001 and 841.11.007), and NH by the Triodos Foundation. The investigations of the Entomological Society Krefeld and its members are spread over numerous individual projects at different locations and in different years. Grants and permits that have made this work possible are listed below: Bezirksregierungen Düsseldorf &amp;amp; Köln, BfN - Bundesamt für Naturschutz, Land Nordrhein-Westfalen - Europäische Gemeinschaft ELER, Landesamt für Agrarordnung Nordrhein-Westfalen, Landesamt für Natur, Umwelt und Verbraucherschutz Nordrhein-Westfalen, Landesamt für Umwelt Brandenburg, Landesamt für Umwelt Rheinland-Pfalz, LVR - Landschaftsverband Rheinland, Naturschutzbund Deutschland, Nordrhein-Westfalen Stiftung, RBN Bergischer Naturschutzverein, RVR - Regionalverband Ruhr, SGD Nord Rheinland-Pfalz, Universitäten Bonn, Duisburg-Essen &amp;amp; Köln, Untere Landschaftsbehörden: Kreis Düren, Kreis Heinsberg, Kreis Kleve, Kreis Viersen, Kreis Wesel &amp;amp; AGLW, Stadt Düsseldorf, Stadt Köln, Stadt Krefeld, Rheinisch Bergischer Kreis, Rhein Kreis Neuss &amp;amp; Rhein-Sieg-Kreis. Members of the Entomological Society Krefeld and cooperating botanists and entomologists that were involved in the empirical investigations are greatly acknowledged: U.W. Abts, F. Bahr, A. Bäumler, D. &amp;amp; H. Beutler, P. Birnbrich, U. Bosch, J. Buchner, F. Cassese, K. Cölln, A.W. Ebmer, R. Eckelboom, B. Franzen, M. Grigo, J. Günneberg, J. Gusenleitner, K. Hamacher, F. Hartfeld, M. Hellenthal, J. Hembach, A. Hemmersbach, W. Hock, V. Huisman-Fiegen, J. Illmer, E. Jansen, U. Jäckel, F. Koch, M. Kreuels, P. Leideritz, I. Loksa, F. B. Ludescher, F. J. Mehring, G. Milbert, N. Mohr, P. Randazzo, K. Reissmann, S. Risch, B. Robert, J. de Rond, U. Sandmann, S. Scharf, P. Scherz, J. Schiffer, C. Schmidt, O. &amp;amp; W. Schmitz, B. P. &amp;amp; W. Schnell, J. L. Schönfeld, E. Schraetz, M. Schwarz, R. Seliger, H. W. Siebeneicher, F. &amp;amp; H. Sonnenburg W. J. S. &amp;amp; P. Sorg, A. Ssymank, H. Sticht, M. Weithmann, W. Wichard and H. Wolf.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Competing interests:&lt;/strong&gt; The authors have declared that no competing interests exist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;section1&quot; class=&quot;section toc-section&quot; readability=&quot;50.204255319149&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Loss of insects is certain to have adverse effects on ecosystem functioning, as insects play a central role in a variety of processes, including pollination [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref001&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref002&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;], herbivory and detrivory [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref003&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref004&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;], nutrient cycling [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref004&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;] and providing a food source for higher trophic levels such as birds, mammals and amphibians. For example, 80% of wild plants are estimated to depend on insects for pollination [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref002&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;], while 60% of birds rely on insects as a food source [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref005&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;]. The ecosystem services provided by wild insects have been estimated at $57 billion annually in the USA [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref006&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;]. Clearly, preserving insect abundance and diversity should constitute a prime conservation priority.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Current data suggest an overall pattern of decline in insect diversity and abundance. For example, populations of European grassland butterflies are estimated to have declined by 50% in abundance between 1990 and 2011 [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref007&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;]. Data for other well-studied taxa such as bees [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref008&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;–&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref014&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;14&lt;/a&gt;] and moths [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref015&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;15&lt;/a&gt;–&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref018&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;18&lt;/a&gt;] suggest the same trend. Climate change, habitat loss and fragmentation, and deterioration of habitat quality have been proposed as some of the prime suspects responsible for the decline [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref009&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;9&lt;/a&gt;–&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref011&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;11&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref013&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;13&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref018&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;18&lt;/a&gt;–&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref022&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;22&lt;/a&gt;]. However, the number of studies on insect trends with sufficient replication and spatial coverage are limited [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref010&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;10&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref023&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;23&lt;/a&gt;–&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref025&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;25&lt;/a&gt;] and restricted to certain well-studied taxa. Declines of individual species or taxa (e.g. [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref007&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref026&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;26&lt;/a&gt;]) may not reflect the general state of local entomofauna [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref027&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;27&lt;/a&gt;]. The total insect biomass would then be a better metric for the status of insects as a group and its contribution to ecosystem functioning, but very few studies have monitored insect biomass over an extensive period of time [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref028&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;28&lt;/a&gt;]. Hence, to what extent total insect biomass has declined, and the relative contribution of each proposed factor to the decline, remain unresolved yet highly relevant questions for ecosystem ecology and conservation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here, we investigate total aerial insect biomass between 1989 and 2016 across 96 unique location-year combinations in Germany, representative of Western European low-altitude nature protection areas embedded in a human-dominated landscape (&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.s006&quot;&gt;S1 Fig&lt;/a&gt;). In all years we sampled insects throughout the season (March through October), based on a standardized sampling scheme using Malaise traps. We investigated rate of decline in insect biomass, and examined how factors such as weather, habitat and land use variables influenced the declines. Knowledge on the state of insect biomass, and it’s direction over time, are of broad importance to ecology and conservation, but historical data on insect biomass have been lacking. Our study makes a first step into filling this gap, and provides information that is vital for the assessment of biodiversity conservation and ecosystem health in agricultural landscapes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;section2&quot; class=&quot;section toc-section&quot; readability=&quot;66.657132312235&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Materials and methods&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;section1&quot; class=&quot;section toc-section&quot; readability=&quot;90.917844595147&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Data&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;section1&quot; class=&quot;section toc-section&quot; readability=&quot;92.598004505954&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Biomass data.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Biomass data were collected and archived using a standardized protocol across 63 unique locations between 1989 and 2016 (resulting in 96 unique location-year combinations) by the Entomological Society Krefeld. The standardized protocol of collection has been originally designed with the idea of integrating quantitative aspects of insects in the status assessment of the protected areas, and to construct a long-term archive in order to preserve (identified and not-identified) specimens of local diversity for future studies. In the present study, we consider the total biomass of flying insects to assess the state of local entomofauna as a group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All trap locations were situated in protected areas, but with varying protection status: 37 locations are within Natura2000 sites, seven locations within designated Nature reserves, nine locations within Protected Landscape Areas (with funded conservation measures), six locations within Water Protection Zones, and four locations of protected habitat managed by Regional Associations. For all location permits have been obtained by the relevant authorities, as listed in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.s001&quot;&gt;S1 Appendix&lt;/a&gt;. In our data, traps located in nutrient-poor heathlands, sandy grasslands, and dune habitats provide lower quantities of biomass as compared to nutrient nutrient-rich grasslands, margins and wastelands. As we were interested in whether the declines interact with local productivity, traps locations were pooled into 3 distinct habitat clusters, namely: nutrient-poor heathlands, sandy grassland, and dunes (habitat cluster 1, n = 19 locations, &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone-0185809-g001&quot;&gt;Fig 1A&lt;/a&gt;), nutrient-rich grasslands, margins and wasteland (habitat cluster 2, n = 41 locations, &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone-0185809-g001&quot;&gt;Fig 1B&lt;/a&gt;) and a third habitat cluster that included pioneer and shrub communities (n = 3 locations).&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Most locations (59%, n = 37) were sampled in only one year, 20 locations in two years, five locations in three years, and one in four years, yielding in total 96 unique location-year combinations of measurements of seasonal total flying insect biomass. Our data do not represent longitudinal records at single sites, suitable to derive location specific trends (e.g. [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref028&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;28&lt;/a&gt;]). Prolonged trapping across years is in the present context (protected areas) deemed undesirable, as the sampling process itself can negatively impact local insect stocks. However, the data do permit an analysis at a higher spatial level, i.e. by treating seasonal insect biomass profiles as random samples of the state of entomofauna in protected areas in western Germany.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Malaise traps were deployed through the spring, summer and early autumn. They operated continuously (day and night), and catches were emptied at regular intervals, on average every 11.2 days (sd = 6.3). We collected in total 1503 trap samples, with an average of 16 (4–35) successive catches per location-year combination (&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone-0185809-t001&quot;&gt;Table 1&lt;/a&gt;). Between 1989 and 2016, a total of 53.54kg of invertebrates have been collected and stored, over a total trap exposure period of 16908 days, within an average of 176 exposure days per location-year combination. Malaise traps are known to collect a much wider diversity of insect species (e.g. [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref029&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;29&lt;/a&gt;–&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref031&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;31&lt;/a&gt;]) as compared to suction traps (e.g. [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref028&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;28&lt;/a&gt;]) and are therefore considered superior as a method of collecting flying insects. On the basis of partial assessments, we can assume that the total number of insects included in 53.54 kg biomass represents millions of individuals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;figure&quot; data-doi=&quot;10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.t001&quot; readability=&quot;12.445623342175&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-box&quot;&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;Click for larger image&quot; href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/figure/image?size=medium&amp;amp;id=info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.t001&quot; data-doi=&quot;info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809&quot; data-uri=&quot;info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.t001&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/figure/image?size=inline&amp;amp;id=info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.t001&quot; alt=&quot;thumbnail&quot; class=&quot;thumbnail&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Table 1.&lt;/span&gt; Overview of malaise-trap samples sizes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For each year, the number of locations sampled, the number of location re-sampled, total number of samples, as well as mean and standard deviation of exposure time at the trap locations (in days) are presented.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption_object&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.t001&quot;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.t001&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sampling was standardized in terms of trap construction, size and design (identical parts), colors, type of netting and ground sealing, trap orientation in the field as well as slope at the trap location. Hence none of the traps differed in any of these field aspects. Our trap model was similar to the bi-colored malaise trap model by Henry Townes [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref032&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;32&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref033&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;33&lt;/a&gt;]. The traps, collecting design, and accompanying methods of biomass measurement as designed and applied by the Entomological Society Krefeld are described elsewhere [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref034&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;34&lt;/a&gt;–&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref036&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;36&lt;/a&gt;] and in &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.s002&quot;&gt;S2 Appendix&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trap catches were stored in 80% ethanol solution, prior to weighing, and total insect biomass of each catch (bottle) was obtained based on a standardized measurement protocol by first subtracting fluid content. In order to optimally preserve samples for future species determination, the insects were weighed in an alcohol-wet state. First, the alcohol concentration in the vessels was stabilized to 80%, while this concentration was controlled with an areometer over a period of at least two days. In order to obtain biomass per sample with sufficient accuracy and comparability, the measuring process was fixed using a standardized protocol [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref034&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;34&lt;/a&gt;]. For this purpose the insects of a sample were poured onto a stainless steel sieve (10cm diameter) of 0.8 mm mesh width. This sieve is placed slightly obliquely (30 degrees) over a glass vessel. The skew position accelerates the first runoff of alcohol and thus the whole measuring procedure. The drop sequence is observed with a stopwatch. When the time between two drops has reached 10 seconds for the first time, the weighing process is performed with a laboratory scale. For the determination of the biomass, precision scales and analytical scales from Mettler company were used with an accuracy of at least 0.1g and controlled with calibrated test weights at the beginning of a new weighing series. In a series of 84 weightings of four different samples repeating this measurement procedure, an average deviation from the mean value of the measurement results of 0.4 percent was observed (unpublished results).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;section2&quot; class=&quot;section toc-section&quot; readability=&quot;59.493012674683&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Weather data.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Climate change is a well-known factor responsible for insect declines [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref015&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;15&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref018&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;18&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref021&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;21&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref037&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;37&lt;/a&gt;]. To test if weather variation could explain the observed decline, we included mean daily temperature, precipitation and wind speed in our analysis, integrating data from 169 weather stations [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref038&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;38&lt;/a&gt;] located within 100km to the trap locations. We examined temporal trends in each weather variable over the course of the study period to assess changes in climatic conditions, as a plausible explanation for insect decline. Estimates of each weather variable at the trap locations were obtained by interpolation of each variable from the 169 climate stations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We initially considered mean daily air temperature, precipitation, cloud cover, relative air moisture content, wind speed, and sunshine duration. However, only temperature, precipitation and wind speed were retained for analysis, as the other variables were significantly correlated with the selected variables [R(temperature, cover) = −43.2%, R(temperature, sunshine) = 53.4%, R(precipitation, moisture) = −47.3%] and because we wanted to keep the number of covariates as low as possible. Additionally, we calculated the number of frost days and the sum of precipitation in the months November- February preceding a sampling season. We used spatio-temporal geostatistical models [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref039&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;39&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref040&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;40&lt;/a&gt;] to predict daily values for each weather variable to each trap location. Amongst other methods, the geostatistical approach is considered a superior interpolation method in order to derive weather variables to trap locations [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref041&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;41&lt;/a&gt;]. Uncertainty in interpolated variables such as wind speed is usually associated with altitude differences. However, as our trap locations are all situated in lowland areas with little altitude variation, we do not expect a large error in our interpolations at trap locations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We decomposed the daily values of each weather variable into a long-term average trend (between years), a mean seasonal trend, and a yearly seasonal anomaly component (&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.s007&quot;&gt;S2 Fig&lt;/a&gt;), modeled using regression splines [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref042&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;42&lt;/a&gt;] while controlling for altitude of weather stations. The remaining residual daily values of each station were further modeled using a spatio-temporal covariance structure. For example, temperature &lt;em&gt;T&lt;/em&gt;, on given day &lt;em&gt;t&lt;/em&gt;, of a given year &lt;em&gt;k&lt;/em&gt; at a given trap location &lt;em&gt;s&lt;/em&gt; is modeled as: &lt;span class=&quot;equation&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/file?type=thumbnail&amp;amp;id=info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.e001&quot; class=&quot;inline-graphic&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;note&quot;&gt;(1)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; where &lt;em&gt;f&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sub&gt;&lt;em&gt;k&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;(&lt;em&gt;k&lt;/em&gt;) is the long-term trend over the years (a thin plate regression spline), &lt;em&gt;f&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sub&gt;&lt;em&gt;t&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;(&lt;em&gt;t&lt;/em&gt;) the mean seasonal trend within years (a penalized cyclic cubic regression spline), &lt;em&gt;r&lt;/em&gt;(&lt;em&gt;k&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;t&lt;/em&gt;) the mean residual seasonal component, which measures annual anomaly in mean daily values across selected stations, and &lt;em&gt;a&lt;/em&gt; is the linear coefficient for the altitude &lt;em&gt;h&lt;/em&gt; effect. The spatio-temporal covariance structure &lt;em&gt;C&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sub&gt;&lt;em&gt;s&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;t&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;, fitted independently to the residuals of each weather variable model, allowed us to deal with lack of independence between daily weather data within and between stations, as well as to interpolate to trap locations using kriging. Altitude of trap locations was extracted from a digital elevation models at 90m resolution [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref043&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;43&lt;/a&gt;].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;section3&quot; class=&quot;section toc-section&quot; readability=&quot;25.676427525622&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Land use data.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Land use variables (and changes therein) were derived from aerial photographs [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref044&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;44&lt;/a&gt;] taken within two distinct time periods (between 1989–1994, and between 2012–2015), and allowed us to characterize land use composition at surroundings of the traps, as well as changes over time. We distinguished cover of forests, agricultural areas, natural grassland, and surface water. For each trap location, aerial photographs were manually processed, polygons extracted and categorized, and their surface area calculated with a radius of 200 meter. Preliminary analysis of the relationship between log biomass and landuse variables, on a subset of the trap locations, indicated that land use elements at 200m radius better predicted insect biomass than elements at 500 and 1000m radius, similar to findings elsewhere for wild bees [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref045&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;45&lt;/a&gt;]. Land use variables were measured at a coarse temporal resolution, but fortunately cover the temporal span of insect sampling. To link the cover of a given land use variable to the insect biomass samples in a particular year, we interpolated coverage between the two time points to the year of insect sampling using generalized linear models with a binomial error distribution, a logit link, and an estimated dispersion parameter. Mean distributions of land use at each of the two time points are depicted in &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.s008&quot;&gt;S3A &amp;amp; S3B Fig&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;section4&quot; class=&quot;section toc-section&quot; readability=&quot;20.826556543837&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Habitat data.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plant inventories were conducted in the immediate surroundings (within 50m) of the trap, in the same season of insect sampling. These data permitted the assessment of plant species richness (numbers of herbs, shrubs and trees) and environmental conditions based on average Ellenberg values [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref046&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;46&lt;/a&gt;–&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref048&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;48&lt;/a&gt;], as well as changes therein over time. Each Ellenberg indicator (we considered nitrogen, pH, light, temperature and moisture) was averaged over all species for each location-year combination. We examined annual trends in each of the above-mentioned variables in order to uncover potential structural changes in habitat characteristics over time. Species richness was analyzed using mixed-effects generalized linear models [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref049&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;49&lt;/a&gt;] with a random intercept for trap location and assuming a Poisson distribution for species richness, and a normal distribution for mean Ellenberg indicator values. Although a Poisson distribution fitted tree and shrub species adequately, (residual deviance/ degree of freedom = 0.94 and 1.04 respectively), severe overdispersion was found for herb species richness (residual deviance/ degree of freedom = 2.16). Trend coefficients of richness over time between a Poisson mixed effects model and a negative binomial model were comparable but differed in magnitude (Poisson GLMM: −0.034 (se = 0.003), vs NB GLMM −0.027 (se = 0.006)). Although the fit is not perfect in the case of herb richness, we believe our trend adequately describes direction of change over time. Mean changes in plant species richness are depicted in &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.s008&quot;&gt;S3C Fig&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;section2&quot; class=&quot;section toc-section&quot; readability=&quot;43.900938086304&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Insect biomass model&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The temporal resolution of the trap samples (accumulated over several days) is not directly compatible with the temporal distribution of the weather data (daily values). Additionally, variable exposure intervals between trap samples is expected to induce variation in trapped biomass between samples, and hence induce heteroscedasticity. Furthermore, biomass data can numerically only be positive on the real line, and we require a model to reflect this property of the data. Because of the unequal exposure intervals however, log-transforming the response would be inappropriate, because we require the sum of daily values after exponentiation, rather that the exponent of the sum of log-daily biomass values. In order to indirectly relate biomass to daily weather variables, to account for the variation in time exposure intervals over which biomass was accumulated in the samples, and to respect the non-negative nature of our data, we modeled the biomass of each catch as the sum of the expected (but unobserved) latent daily biomass. The mass &lt;em&gt;m&lt;/em&gt; of each sample &lt;em&gt;j&lt;/em&gt;, at site &lt;em&gt;s&lt;/em&gt; in year &lt;em&gt;k&lt;/em&gt;, is assumed to be distributed normally about the sum of the latent expected daily mass (&lt;em&gt;z&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sub&gt;&lt;em&gt;t&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;s&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;k&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;), with variance &lt;span class=&quot;inline-formula&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/file?type=thumbnail&amp;amp;id=info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.e002&quot; class=&quot;inline-graphic&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span class=&quot;equation&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/file?type=thumbnail&amp;amp;id=info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.e003&quot; class=&quot;inline-graphic&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;note&quot;&gt;(2)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; subject to &lt;span class=&quot;inline-formula&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/file?type=thumbnail&amp;amp;id=info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.e004&quot; class=&quot;inline-graphic&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt; where &lt;em&gt;τ&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt; and &lt;em&gt;τ&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; mark the exposure interval (in days) of biomass collection of each sample &lt;em&gt;j&lt;/em&gt;. The latent daily biomass itself is represented by a log normal distribution, in which coefficients for covariates, random effects and residual variance are all represented on the log scale. In turn, daily biomass is modeled as &lt;span class=&quot;equation&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/file?type=thumbnail&amp;amp;id=info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.e005&quot; class=&quot;inline-graphic&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;note&quot;&gt;(3)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;equation&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/file?type=thumbnail&amp;amp;id=info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.e006&quot; class=&quot;inline-graphic&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;note&quot;&gt;(4)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; where &lt;em&gt;c&lt;/em&gt; is a global intercept, &lt;strong&gt;X&lt;/strong&gt; a design matrix of dimensions n×p (number of samples × number of covariates; see Model analysis below), &lt;em&gt;β&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sub&gt;&lt;em&gt;x&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; the corresponding vector of coefficients that measure the weather, habitat and land use effects, and &lt;em&gt;log&lt;/em&gt;(&lt;em&gt;λ&lt;/em&gt;) a mean annual population growth rate parameter. The random term (&lt;em&gt;u&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sub&gt;&lt;em&gt;s&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;) denotes the location-specific random effect assumed to be distributed normally about zero &lt;span class=&quot;inline-formula&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/file?type=thumbnail&amp;amp;id=info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.e007&quot; class=&quot;inline-graphic&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. The exponentiation of the right hand side of &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.e005&quot;&gt;Eq (3)&lt;/a&gt; ensures expected values to be positive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The expected residual variance of each sample &lt;span class=&quot;inline-formula&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/file?type=thumbnail&amp;amp;id=info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.e008&quot; class=&quot;inline-graphic&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, is expressed as the sum of variances of daily biomass values (&lt;span class=&quot;inline-formula&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/file?type=thumbnail&amp;amp;id=info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.e009&quot; class=&quot;inline-graphic&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;equation&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/file?type=thumbnail&amp;amp;id=info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.e010&quot; class=&quot;inline-graphic&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;note&quot;&gt;(5)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The variances of daily biomass should respect the non-negative nature of the data as well. Additionally, we are interested in being able to compare the residual variance with the random effects variance, and this requires them to be on the same scale. Therefore, we expressed the variance of the daily biomass as a function of the variance of the logarithm of the daily biomass. Using the method of moments: &lt;span class=&quot;equation&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/file?type=thumbnail&amp;amp;id=info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.e011&quot; class=&quot;inline-graphic&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;note&quot;&gt;(6)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; where &lt;em&gt;v&lt;/em&gt; represents the residual variance of daily log-biomass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;section3&quot; class=&quot;section toc-section&quot; readability=&quot;101.72614107884&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Analysis&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We developed a series of models each consisting of a set of explanatory variables that measure aspects of climate, land use and local habitat characteristics. Significant explanatory variables in these models were combined into a final model, which was then reduced to exclude insignificant effects. An overview of which covariates were included in each model is given in &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone-0185809-t002&quot;&gt;Table 2&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Weather effects explored were daily temperature, precipitation and wind speed, as well as the number of frost days and sum of precipitation in the preceding winter. Habitat effects explored tree and herb species richness, as well as average Ellenberg values for nitrogen, pH, light, temperature and moisture, per location-year combination. Land use effects explored the fractions of agricultural area, forest, grass, and surface water in a radius of 200m around the plot location.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parameter values are obtained by the use of Markov chain Monte Carlo (MCMC) methods by the aid of JAGS (Just Another Gibbs Sampler [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref050&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;50&lt;/a&gt;]) invoked through R [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref051&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;51&lt;/a&gt;] and the R2Jags package [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref052&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;52&lt;/a&gt;]. JAGS model scripts are given in &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.s003&quot;&gt;S1 Code&lt;/a&gt;, while data are given in &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.s004&quot;&gt;S1&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.s005&quot;&gt;S2&lt;/a&gt; Dataset. For each model, we ran 3 parallel chains each consisting of 24000 iterations (first 4000 discarded), and kept every 10&lt;sup&gt;&lt;em&gt;th&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; value as a way to reduce within chain autocorrelation. We used vague priors for all parameters, with uniform distributions for the residual and random effect variance components, and flat normal distributions (with very high variance) for all other parameters. Covariates in &lt;strong&gt;X&lt;/strong&gt; were standardized prior to model fitting, with the exception of year (values 1–26), and land use variables (proportions within 0–1 range).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For all models, we computed the Deviance Information Criterion [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref053&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;53&lt;/a&gt;] (DIC) as well as the squared correlation coefficient (R&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;) between observed and mean posterior estimates of biomass on the log scale. Results are given in &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone-0185809-t003&quot;&gt;Table 3&lt;/a&gt;. Parameter convergence was assessed by the potential scale reduction factor [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref054&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;54&lt;/a&gt;] (commonly &lt;span class=&quot;inline-formula&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/file?type=thumbnail&amp;amp;id=info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.e012&quot; class=&quot;inline-graphic&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;), that measures the ratio of posterior distributions between independent MCM chains (in all models, all parameters attained values below 1.02). For all models, we confirmed that the posterior distribution of the trend coefficient did not confound any other variable by plotting the relevant posterior samples and computing pairwise correlation coefficients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;figure&quot; data-doi=&quot;10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.t003&quot; readability=&quot;13&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-box&quot;&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;Click for larger image&quot; href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/figure/image?size=medium&amp;amp;id=info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.t003&quot; data-doi=&quot;info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809&quot; data-uri=&quot;info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.t003&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/figure/image?size=inline&amp;amp;id=info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.t003&quot; alt=&quot;thumbnail&quot; class=&quot;thumbnail&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Table 3.&lt;/span&gt; Results for 7 models ranked by Deviance Information Criterion (DIC).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For each model, the number of parameters, the Deviance Information Criterion, the effective number of parameters (pD), calculated &lt;em&gt;R&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; and difference in DIC units between each model and the model with lowest ΔDIC. See &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone-0185809-t002&quot;&gt;Table 2&lt;/a&gt; for covariates included in each model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption_object&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.t003&quot;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.t003&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our basic model included habitat cluster (3 levels), a quadratic effect for day number, an annual trend coefficient measuring the rate of biomass change, and the interactions between the annual trend coefficient and the day number variables. Next we developed 3 models each consisting of either weather variables (&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.s011&quot;&gt;S1 Table&lt;/a&gt;), land use variables (&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.s012&quot;&gt;S2 Table&lt;/a&gt;), or habitat variables. Because interactions between the annual rate of change and land use variables seemed plausible, a fourth model was developed to include these interactions (&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.s013&quot;&gt;S3 Table&lt;/a&gt;). Finally, all significant variables were combined into our final model (&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone-0185809-t004&quot;&gt;Table 4&lt;/a&gt;), which included effects of an annual trend coefficient, season (linear and quadratic effect of day number), weather (temperature, precipitation, number of frost days), land use (cover of grassland and water, as well as interaction between grassland cover and trend), and habitat (number of herb and tree species as well as Ellenberg temperature).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;figure&quot; data-doi=&quot;10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.t004&quot; readability=&quot;11.409952606635&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-box&quot;&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;Click for larger image&quot; href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/figure/image?size=medium&amp;amp;id=info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.t004&quot; data-doi=&quot;info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809&quot; data-uri=&quot;info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.t004&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/figure/image?size=inline&amp;amp;id=info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.t004&quot; alt=&quot;thumbnail&quot; class=&quot;thumbnail&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Table 4.&lt;/span&gt; Posterior parameter estimates of the final mixed effects model of daily insect biomass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For each included variable, the corresponding coefficient mean, standard deviation and 95% credible intervals are given. P-values were calculated empirically based on posterior distributions of coefficients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption_object&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.t004&quot;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.t004&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our estimate of decline is based on our basic model, from which we can derive seasonal estimates of daily biomass for any given year. The basic model includes only a temporal (annual and seasonal effects, as well as interactions) and a basic habitat cluster distinction (additive effects only) as well as a random trap location effect. We here report the annual trend coefficient, as well as a weighted estimate of decline that accounts for the within season differences in biomass decline. The weighted insect biomass decline was estimated by projecting the seasonal biomass (1-April to 30-October) for years 1989 and 2016 using coefficients our basic model, and then dividing the summed (over the season) biomass of 2016 by the summed biomass over 1989.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using our final model, we assessed the relative contribution (i.e. net effect) of the explanatory variables to the observed decline, both combined and independently. To this aim we projected the seasonal daily biomass for the years 1989 and 2016 twice: first we kept covariates at their mean values during the early stages of the study period, and second we allowed covariate values to change according to the observed mean changes (see &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.s007&quot;&gt;S2&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.s008&quot;&gt;S3&lt;/a&gt; Figs). Difference in the total biomass decline between these two projections are interpreted as the relative contribution of the explanatory variables to the decline. The marginal (i.e. independent) effects of each covariate were calculated by projecting biomass increase/decline as result of the observed temporal developments in each variable separately, and expressing it as percentual change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our data provide repetitions across years for only a subset of locations (n = 26 out of 63). As such, spatial variation in insect biomass may confound the estimated trend. To verify that this is not the case, we fitted our basic model (but excluding the day number and year interaction to avoid overparameterization) to the subset of our data that includes only locations that were sampled in more than one year. Seasonal profiles of daily biomass values are depicted in &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.s009&quot;&gt;S4 Fig&lt;/a&gt;. Finally, we reran our basic model for the two (of the three) habitat clusters (for which sufficient data existed; see Biomass Data) separately in order to compare the rate of decline between them (&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.s010&quot;&gt;S5 Fig&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;section3&quot; class=&quot;section toc-section&quot; readability=&quot;123.62892194116&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Results&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following corrections for seasonal variation and habitat cluster (basic model, see &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#sec002&quot;&gt;Materials and methods&lt;/a&gt;), the annual trend coefficient of our basic model was significantly negative (annual trend coefficient = −0.063, sd = 0.002, i.e. 6.1% annual decline). Based on this result, we estimate that a major (up to 81.6% [79.7–83.4%]) decline in mid-summer aerial insect biomass has taken place since 1989 (&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone-0185809-g002&quot;&gt;Fig 2A&lt;/a&gt;). However, biomass loss was more prominent in mid-summer as compared to the start and end of the season (&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone-0185809-g003&quot;&gt;Fig 3A&lt;/a&gt;), indicating that the highest losses occur when biomass is highest during the season (&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone-0185809-g002&quot;&gt;Fig 2B&lt;/a&gt;). As such, a seasonally weighted estimate (covering the period 1-April to 30-October; see methods) results in an overall 76.7% [74.8–78.5%] decline over a 27 year period. The pattern of decline is very similar across locations that were sampled more than once (&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone-0185809-g004&quot;&gt;Fig 4&lt;/a&gt;), suggesting that the estimated temporal decline based on the entire dataset is not confounded by the sampling procedure. Re-estimation of the annual decline based on 26 locations that have been sampled in more than one year (&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.s009&quot;&gt;S4 Fig&lt;/a&gt;), revealed a similar rate of decline (76.2%[73.9–78.3%]).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;figure&quot; data-doi=&quot;10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.g002&quot; readability=&quot;13.807327001357&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-box&quot;&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;Click for larger image&quot; href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/figure/image?size=medium&amp;amp;id=info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.g002&quot; data-doi=&quot;info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809&quot; data-uri=&quot;info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.g002&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/figure/image?size=inline&amp;amp;id=info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.g002&quot; alt=&quot;thumbnail&quot; class=&quot;thumbnail&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Fig 2.&lt;/span&gt; Temporal distribution of insect biomass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(A) Boxplots depict the distribution of insect biomass (gram per day) pooled over all traps and catches in each year (n = 1503). Based on our final model, the grey line depicts the fitted mean (+95% posterior credible intervals) taking into account weather, landscape and habitat effects. The black line depicts the mean estimated trend as estimated with our basic model. (B) Seasonal distribution of insect biomass showing that highest insect biomass catches in mid summer show most severe declines. Color gradient in both panels range from 1989 (blue) to 2016 (orange).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption_object&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.g002&quot;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.g002&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;figure&quot; data-doi=&quot;10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.g003&quot; readability=&quot;14.628453038674&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-box&quot;&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;Click for larger image&quot; href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/figure/image?size=medium&amp;amp;id=info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.g003&quot; data-doi=&quot;info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809&quot; data-uri=&quot;info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.g003&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/figure/image?size=inline&amp;amp;id=info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.g003&quot; alt=&quot;thumbnail&quot; class=&quot;thumbnail&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Fig 3.&lt;/span&gt; Seasonal decline and phenology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(A) Seasonal decline of mean daily insect biomass as estimated by independent month specific log-linear regressions (black bars), and our basic mixed effects model with interaction between annual rate of change and a quadratic trend for day number in season. (B), Seasonal phenology of insect biomass (seasonal quantiles of biomass at 5% intervals) across all locations revealing substantial annual variation in peak biomass (solid line) but no direction trend, suggesting no phenological changes have occurred with respect to temporal distribution of insect biomass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption_object&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.g003&quot;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.g003&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;figure&quot; data-doi=&quot;10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.g004&quot; readability=&quot;11.690721649485&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-box&quot;&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;Click for larger image&quot; href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/figure/image?size=medium&amp;amp;id=info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.g004&quot; data-doi=&quot;info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809&quot; data-uri=&quot;info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.g004&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/figure/image?size=inline&amp;amp;id=info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.g004&quot; alt=&quot;thumbnail&quot; class=&quot;thumbnail&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Fig 4.&lt;/span&gt; Temporal distribution of insect biomass at selected locations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(A) Daily biomass (mean ±1 se) across 26 locations sampled in multiple years (see &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.s009&quot;&gt;S4 Fig&lt;/a&gt; for seasonal distributions). (B) Distribution of mean annual rate of decline as estimated based on plot specific log-linear models (annual trend coefficient = −0.053, sd = 0.002, i.e. 5.2% annual decline).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption_object&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.g004&quot;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.g004&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Insect biomass was positively related to temperature and negatively to precipitation (&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.s011&quot;&gt;S1 Table&lt;/a&gt;). Including lagged effects of weather revealed no effect of either number of frost days, or winter precipitation, on the biomass in the next season (&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.s011&quot;&gt;S1 Table&lt;/a&gt;). The overall model fit improved as compared to our basic model (R&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; = 65.4%, &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone-0185809-t003&quot;&gt;Table 3&lt;/a&gt;), explaining within and between year variation in insect biomass, but not the overall decline (log(&lt;em&gt;λ&lt;/em&gt;) = −0.058, sd = 0.002). Over the course of the study period, some temporal changes occurred in the means of the weather variables (&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.s007&quot;&gt;S2 Fig&lt;/a&gt;), most notably an increase by 0.5°C in mean temperature and a decline 0.2 m/sec in mean wind speed. Yet, these changes either do not have an effect on insect biomass (e.g. wind speed) either are expected to positively affected insect biomass (e.g. increased temperature). Furthermore, a phenological shift with peak biomass earlier in the season could have resulted in lower biomass in the mid-season (&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone-0185809-g003&quot;&gt;Fig 3A&lt;/a&gt;), but this does not appear to be the case as none of the seasonal distribution quantiles in biomass showed any temporal trend (&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone-0185809-g003&quot;&gt;Fig 3B&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was substantial variation in trapped insect biomass between habitat clusters (see &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#sec002&quot;&gt;Materials and methods&lt;/a&gt;), with nutrient-rich grasslands, margins and wasteland containing 43% more insect biomass than nutrient-poor heathland, sandy grassland, and dunes. Yet, the annual rate of decline was similar, suggesting that the decline is not specific to certain habitat types (&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.s010&quot;&gt;S5 Fig&lt;/a&gt;). To further characterize trap locations, we used past (1989–1994) and present (2012–2015) aerial photographs and quantified land use cover within 200m around the trap locations. On average, cover of arable land decreased, coverage of forests increased, while grassland and surface water did not change much in extent over the last three decades (&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.s008&quot;&gt;S3 Fig&lt;/a&gt;). Overall, adding land use variables alone did not lead to a substantial improvement of the model fit (R&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; = 61.3%, &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone-0185809-t003&quot;&gt;Table 3&lt;/a&gt;), nor did it affect the annual trend coefficient (log(&lt;em&gt;λ&lt;/em&gt;) = −0.064, sd = 0.002). While presence of surface water appeared to significantly lower insect biomass, none of the other variables were significantly related to biomass. However, including interactions between the annual trend coefficient and land use variables increased the model fit slightly (&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone-0185809-t003&quot;&gt;Table 3&lt;/a&gt;), and revealed significant interactions for all variables except coverage of surface water (&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.s012&quot;&gt;S2 Table&lt;/a&gt;). These interactions, which were retained in our final model (&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone-0185809-t004&quot;&gt;Table 4&lt;/a&gt;), revealed higher rates of decline where coverage of grassland was higher, while lower declines where forest and arable land coverage was higher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hypothesized that successional changes in plant community [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref055&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;55&lt;/a&gt;] or changes in environmental conditions [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref009&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;9&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref018&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;18&lt;/a&gt;], could have affected the local insect biomass, and hence explain the decline. Plant species inventories that were carried out in the immediate vicinity of the traps and in the same season of trapping, revealed that species richness of trees, shrubs and herbs declined significantly over the course of the study period (&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.s008&quot;&gt;S3 Fig&lt;/a&gt;). Including species richness in our basic model, i.e. number of tree species and log number of herb species, revealed significant positive and negative effects respectively on insect biomass, but did not affect the annual trend coefficient (&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.s013&quot;&gt;S3 Table&lt;/a&gt;), explaining some variation between locations rather than the annual trend coefficient. Moreover, and contrary to expectation, trends in herb species richness were weakly negatively correlated with trends in insect biomass, when compared on per plot basis for plots sampled more than once. Ellenberg values of plant species provide a reliable indicator for the environmental conditions such as pH, nitrogen, and moisture [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref046&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;46&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref047&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;47&lt;/a&gt;]. Around trap locations, mean indicators (across all locations) were stable over time, with changes in the order of less than 2% over the course of the study period. Adding these variables to our basic model revealed a significant positive effect of nitrogen and light, and a significant negative effect of Ellenberg temperature on insect biomass, explaining a major part of the variation between the habitat types. However, Ellenberg values did not affect the insect biomass trend coefficient (log(&lt;em&gt;λ&lt;/em&gt;) = −0.059, sd = 0.003, &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.s013&quot;&gt;S3 Table&lt;/a&gt;) and only marginally improved the model fit (R&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; = 61.9%, &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone-0185809-t003&quot;&gt;Table 3&lt;/a&gt;). All habitat variables were considered in our final model (&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone-0185809-t004&quot;&gt;Table 4&lt;/a&gt;), with the exception of of pH and moisture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our final model, based on including all significant variables from previous models, revealed a higher trend coefficient as compared to our basic model (log(&lt;em&gt;λ&lt;/em&gt;) = −0.081, sd = 0.006, &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone-0185809-t004&quot;&gt;Table 4&lt;/a&gt;), suggesting that temporal developments in the considered explanatory variables counteracted biomass decline to some degree, leading to an even more negative coefficient for the annual trend. The marginal net effect of changes in each covariate over time (see Analysis), showed a positive contribution to biomass growth rate of temporal developments in arable land, herb species richness, and Ellenberg Nitrogen, while negative effects of developments of tree species richness and forest coverage (&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone-0185809-g005&quot;&gt;Fig 5&lt;/a&gt;). For example, the negative effect of arable land on biomass (&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone-0185809-t004&quot;&gt;Table 4&lt;/a&gt;), in combination with a decrease in coverage of arable land (&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.s008&quot;&gt;S3 Fig&lt;/a&gt;), have resulted in a net positive effect for biomass (&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone-0185809-g005&quot;&gt;Fig 5&lt;/a&gt;). Projections of our final model, while fixing the coefficient for the temporal annual trend log(&lt;em&gt;λ&lt;/em&gt;) to zero, suggest insect biomass would have remained stable, or even increased by approximately 8% (mean rate = 1.075, 0.849–1.381) over the course of the study period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;figure&quot; data-doi=&quot;10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.g005&quot; readability=&quot;10.166259168704&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-box&quot;&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;Click for larger image&quot; href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/figure/image?size=medium&amp;amp;id=info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.g005&quot; data-doi=&quot;info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809&quot; data-uri=&quot;info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.g005&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/figure/image?size=inline&amp;amp;id=info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.g005&quot; alt=&quot;thumbnail&quot; class=&quot;thumbnail&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Fig 5.&lt;/span&gt; Marginal effects of temporal changes in considered covariates on insect biomass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each bar represents the rate of change in total insect biomass, as the combined effect of the relevant coefficient (&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone-0185809-t004&quot;&gt;Table 4&lt;/a&gt;) and the temporal development of each covariate independently (&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.s007&quot;&gt;S2&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.s008&quot;&gt;S3&lt;/a&gt; Figs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption_object&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.g005&quot;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.g005&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;section4&quot; class=&quot;section toc-section&quot; readability=&quot;92.907498805923&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Discussion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our results document a dramatic decline in average airborne insect biomass of 76% (up to 82% in midsummer) in just 27 years for protected nature areas in Germany. This considerably exceeds the estimated decline of 58% in global abundance of wild vertebrates over a 42-year period to 2012 [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref056&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;56&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref057&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;57&lt;/a&gt;]. Our results demonstrate that recently reported declines in several taxa such as butterflies [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref007&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref025&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;25&lt;/a&gt;–&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref027&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;27&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref058&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;58&lt;/a&gt;], wild bees [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref008&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;–&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref014&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;14&lt;/a&gt;] and moths [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref015&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;15&lt;/a&gt;–&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref018&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;18&lt;/a&gt;], are in parallel with a severe loss of total aerial insect biomass, suggesting that it is not only the vulnerable species, but the flying insect community as a whole, that has been decimated over the last few decades. The estimated decline is considerably more severe than the only comparable long term study on flying insect biomass elsewhere [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref028&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;28&lt;/a&gt;]. In that study, 12.2m high suction traps were deployed at four locations in the UK over the time period 1973–2002, and showed a biomass decline at one of the four sites only. However, the sampling designs differ considerably between the two studies. Suction traps mainly target high-flying insects, and in that study the catches were largely comprised of flies belonging to the Bibionidae family. Contrary, malaise traps as used in the present study target insects flying close to the ground surface (up to 1 meter), with a much wider diversity of taxa. Future investigations should look into how biomass is distributed among insect species, and how species trends contribute to the biomass decline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although the present dataset spans a relatively large number of years (27) and sites (63), the number of repetitions (i.e. multiple years of seasonal distributions at the same locations) was lower (n = 26). We are however confident that our estimated rate of decline in total biomass resembles the true rate of decline, and is not an artifact of site selection. Firstly, our basic model (including an annual rate of decline) outperformed the null-model (without an annual rate of decline; ΔDIC = 822.62 units; &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone-0185809-t003&quot;&gt;Table 3&lt;/a&gt;), while at the same time, between-plot variation (i.s. &lt;em&gt;σ&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sub&gt;&lt;em&gt;site&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;) and residual variation (&lt;em&gt;v&lt;/em&gt;) decreased by 44.3 and 9.7% respectively, after incorporating an annual rate of decline into the models. Secondly, using only data from sites at which malaise traps were operating in at least two years, we estimated a rate of decline similar to using the full dataset (&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone-0185809-g004&quot;&gt;Fig 4&lt;/a&gt;), with the pattern of decline being congruent across locations (&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.s009&quot;&gt;S4 Fig&lt;/a&gt;). Taken together, there does not seem to be evidence that spatial variation (between sites) in this dataset forms a confounding factor to the estimated temporal trend, and conclude that our estimated biomass decline is representative for lowland protected areas in west Germany.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In light of previously suggested driving mechanisms, our analysis renders two of the prime suspects, i.e. landscape [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref009&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;9&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref018&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;18&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref020&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;20&lt;/a&gt;] and climate change [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref015&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;15&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref018&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;18&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref021&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;21&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref037&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;37&lt;/a&gt;], as unlikely explanatory factors for this major decline in aerial insect biomass in the investigated protected areas. Habitat change was evaluated in terms of changes in plant species composition surrounding the standardized trap locations, and in plant species characteristics (Ellenberg values). Land use changes was evaluated in terms of proportional surface changes in aerial photographs, and not for example changes in management regimes. Given the major decline in insect biomass of about 80%, much stronger relationships would have been expected if changes in habitat and land use were the driving forces, even with the somewhat crude parameters that were at our disposal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The decline in insect biomass, being evident throughout the growing season, and irrespective of habitat type or landscape configuration, suggests large-scale factors must be involved. While some temporal changes in climatic variables in our study area have taken place, these either were not of influence (e.g. wind speed), or changed in a manner that should have increased insect biomass (e.g temperature). However, we have not exhaustively analysed the full range of climatic variables that could potentially impact insect biomass. For example prolonged droughts, or lack of sunshine especially in low temperatures might have had an effect on insect biomass [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref059&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;59&lt;/a&gt;–&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref062&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;62&lt;/a&gt;]. Agricultural intensification [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref017&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;17&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref020&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;20&lt;/a&gt;] (e.g. pesticide usage, year-round tillage, increased use of fertilizers and frequency of agronomic measures) that we could not incorporate in our analyses, may form a plausible cause. The reserves in which the traps were placed are of limited size in this typical fragmented West-European landscape, and almost all locations (94%) are enclosed by agricultural fields. Part of the explanation could therefore be that the protected areas (serving as insect sources) are affected and drained by the agricultural fields in the broader surroundings (serving as sinks or even as ecological traps) [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref001&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref063&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;63&lt;/a&gt;–&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref065&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;65&lt;/a&gt;]. Increased agricultural intensification may have aggravated this reduction in insect abundance in the protected areas over the last few decades. Whatever the causal factors responsible for the decline, they have a far more devastating effect on total insect biomass than has been appreciated previously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The widespread insect biomass decline is alarming, ever more so as all traps were placed in protected areas that are meant to preserve ecosystem functions and biodiversity. While the gradual decline of rare insect species has been known for quite some time (e.g. specialized butterflies [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref009&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;9&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref066&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;66&lt;/a&gt;]), our results illustrate an ongoing and rapid decline in total amount of airborne insects active in space and time. Agricultural intensification, including the disappearance of field margins and new crop protection methods has been associated with an overall decline of biodiversity in plants, insects, birds and other species in the current landscape [&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref020&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;20&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref027&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;27&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809#pone.0185809.ref067&quot; class=&quot;ref-tip&quot;&gt;67&lt;/a&gt;]. The major and hitherto unrecognized loss of insect biomass that we report here for protected areas, adds a new dimension to this discussion, because it must have cascading effects across trophic levels and numerous other ecosystem effects. There is an urgent need to uncover the causes of this decline, its geographical extent, and to understand the ramifications of the decline for ecosystems and ecosystem services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;section5&quot; class=&quot;section toc-section&quot; readability=&quot;36.658322580645&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Supporting information&lt;/h2&gt;







&lt;div class=&quot;supplementary-material&quot; readability=&quot;13.648293963255&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;siTitle title-small&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/file?type=supplementary&amp;amp;id=info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.s007&quot;&gt;S2 Fig.&lt;/a&gt; Temporal variation in weather variables.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;preSiDOI&quot;&gt;Annual means (A-C), daily means (D-F), and mean daily residual values (G-I) of temperature, precipitation and wind speed respectively. In all panels, black lines depict data while blue and red lines represent long term and seasonal fitted means of the variables, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;siDoi&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.s007&quot;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.s007&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;postSiDOI&quot;&gt;(PDF)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;supplementary-material&quot; readability=&quot;12.843657817109&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;siTitle title-small&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/file?type=supplementary&amp;amp;id=info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.s008&quot;&gt;S3 Fig.&lt;/a&gt; Land use and plant species richness changes.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;preSiDOI&quot;&gt;Mean land use in 1989–1994 (A) and 2012–2014 (B), based on aerial photograph analysis at 63 protected areas show a decrease of arable land and an increase in forested area over the past 25 years. (C) Changes in plants species richness for herbs (black) shrubs (red) and trees (blue). Annual means as well as mean trends are depicted in the corresponding colors. Linear trends are based on generalized linear mixed effects models with a Poisson error distribution and a random intercept effect for location. Note, zero values for tree and shrub species not depicted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;siDoi&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.s008&quot;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.s008&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;postSiDOI&quot;&gt;(PDF)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;supplementary-material&quot; readability=&quot;9.6254416961131&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;siTitle title-small&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/file?type=supplementary&amp;amp;id=info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.s009&quot;&gt;S4 Fig.&lt;/a&gt; Seasonal profiles of daily biomass across 26 locations.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;preSiDOI&quot;&gt;For each location, different colors represent different years, with time color-coded from green (1989) to red (2016). X-axis represents day number (January 1 = 0).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;siDoi&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.s009&quot;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.s009&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;postSiDOI&quot;&gt;(PDF)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;supplementary-material&quot; readability=&quot;16.619178082192&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;siTitle title-small&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/file?type=supplementary&amp;amp;id=info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.s010&quot;&gt;S5 Fig.&lt;/a&gt; Daily biomass of insects over time for two habitat clusters.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;preSiDOI&quot;&gt;Boxplots depict the distribution of insect biomass pooled over all traps and catches in each year at trap locations in nutrient-poor heathland, sandy grassland, and dunes (A), and in nutrient-rich grasslands, margins and wasteland (B). Grey lines depict the fitted mean (+95% posterior credible intervals), while the black lines the mean estimated trend. Estimated annual decline amounts to 7.5%(6.6–8.4) for habitat cluster 1, as compared to 5.2% (4.8–5.5) habitat cluster 2. Models fitted independently for each habitat location. Color gradient in all panels range from 1989 (blue) to 2016 (orange).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;siDoi&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.s010&quot;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.s010&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;postSiDOI&quot;&gt;(PDF)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;supplementary-material&quot; readability=&quot;10.951086956522&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;siTitle title-small&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/file?type=supplementary&amp;amp;id=info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.s011&quot;&gt;S1 Table.&lt;/a&gt; Posterior parameter estimates of the mixed effects model including weather variables.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;preSiDOI&quot;&gt;For each included variable, the corresponding coefficient posterior mean, standard deviation and 95% credible intervals are given. P-values are calculated empirically based on posterior distributions of coefficients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;siDoi&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.s011&quot;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.s011&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;postSiDOI&quot;&gt;(PDF)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;supplementary-material&quot; readability=&quot;11.046632124352&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;siTitle title-small&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/file?type=supplementary&amp;amp;id=info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.s012&quot;&gt;S2 Table.&lt;/a&gt; Posterior parameter estimates of the mixed effects model including land use variables and interactions.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;preSiDOI&quot;&gt;For each included variable, the corresponding coefficient posterior mean, standard deviation and 95% credible intervals are given. P-values are calculated empirically based on posterior distributions of coefficients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;siDoi&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.s012&quot;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.s012&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;postSiDOI&quot;&gt;(PDF)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;supplementary-material&quot; readability=&quot;10.951086956522&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;siTitle title-small&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/file?type=supplementary&amp;amp;id=info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.s013&quot;&gt;S3 Table.&lt;/a&gt; Posterior parameter estimates of the mixed effects model including habitat variables.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;preSiDOI&quot;&gt;For each included variable, the corresponding coefficient posterior mean, standard deviation and 95% credible intervals are given. P-values are calculated empirically based on posterior distributions of coefficients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;siDoi&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.s013&quot;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.s013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;postSiDOI&quot;&gt;(PDF)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section toc-section&quot; readability=&quot;95&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Acknowledgments&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CH and EJ were supported by the Netherlands Organization for Scientific Research (NWO grants 840.11.001 and 841.11.007), and NH by the Triodos Foundation. The investigations of the Entomological Society Krefeld and its members are spread over numerous individual projects at different locations and in different years. Grants and permits that have made this work possible are listed below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bezirksregierungen Düsseldorf &amp;amp; Köln, BfN—Bundesamt für Naturschutz, Land Nordrhein-Westfalen—Europäische Gemeinschaft ELER, Landesamt für Agrarordnung Nordrhein-Westfalen, Landesamt für Natur, Umwelt und Verbraucherschutz Nordrhein-Westfalen, Landesamt für Umwelt Brandenburg, Landesamt für Umwelt Rheinland-Pfalz, LVR—Landschaftsverband Rheinland, Naturschutzbund Deutschland, Nordrhein-Westfalen Stiftung, RBN—Bergischer Naturschutzverein, RVR—Regionalverband Ruhr, SGD Nord Rheinland-Pfalz, Universitäten Bonn, Duisburg-Essen &amp;amp; Köln, Untere Landschaftsbehörden: Kreis Düren, Kreis Heinsberg, Kreis Kleve, Kreis Viersen, Kreis Wesel &amp;amp; AGLW, Stadt Düsseldorf, Stadt Köln, Stadt Krefeld, Rheinisch Bergischer Kreis, Rhein Kreis Neuss &amp;amp; Rhein-Sieg-Kreis. Members of the Entomological Society Krefeld and cooperating botanists and entomologists that were involved in the empirical investigations are greatly acknowledged: U.W. Abts, F. Bahr, A. Bäumler, D. &amp;amp; H. Beutler, P. Birnbrich, U. Bosch, J. Buchner, F. Cassese, K. Cölln, A.W. Ebmer, R. Eckelboom, B. Franzen, M. Grigo, J. Günneberg, J. Gusenleitner, K. Hamacher, F. Hartfeld, M. Hellenthal, J. Hembach, A. Hemmersbach, W. Hock, V. Huisman-Fiegen, J. Illmer, E. Jansen, U. Jäckel, F. Koch, M. Kreuels, P. Leideritz, I. Loksa, F. B. Ludescher, F. J. Mehring, G. Milbert, N. Mohr, P. Randazzo, K. Reissmann, S. Risch, B. Robert, J. de Rond, U. Sandmann, S. Scharf, P. Scherz, J. Schiffer, C. Schmidt, O. &amp;amp; W. Schmitz, B. P. &amp;amp; W. Schnell, J. L. Schönfeld, E. Schraetz, M. Schwarz, R. Seliger, H. W. Siebeneicher, F. &amp;amp; H. Sonnenburg W. J. S. &amp;amp; P. Sorg, A. Ssymank, H. Sticht, M. Weithmann, W. Wichard and H. Wolf.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;toc-section&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;references&quot;&gt;&lt;li id=&quot;ref1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;1.&lt;/span&gt;  Öckinger E, Smith HG. Semi-natural grasslands as population sources for pollinating insects in agricultural landscapes. Journal of Applied Ecology. 2007;44(1):50–59.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;2.&lt;/span&gt;  Ollerton J, Winfree R, Tarrant S. How many flowering plants are pollinated by animals? Oikos. 2011;120(3):321–326.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref3&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;3.&lt;/span&gt;  Mattson WJ, Addy ND. Phytophagous insects as regulators of forest primary production. Science. 1975;190(4214):515–522.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref4&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;4.&lt;/span&gt;  Yang LH, Gratton C. Insects as drivers of ecosystem processes. Current Opinion in Insect Science. 2014;2:26–32.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref5&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;5.&lt;/span&gt;  Morse H D. The insectivorous bird as an adaptive strategy. Annual Review of Ecology and Systematics. 1971; p. 177–200.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref6&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;6.&lt;/span&gt;  Losey JE, Vaughan M. The economic value of ecological services provided by insects. Bioscience. 2006;56(4):311–323.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref7&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;7.&lt;/span&gt;  van Swaay C, van Strien A, Harpke A, Fontaine B, Stefanescu C, Roy D, et al. The European grassland butterfly indicator: 1990–2011. EEA Technical Reports. 2013;11.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref8&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;8.&lt;/span&gt;  Goulson D, Lye GC, Darvill B. Decline and conservation of bumble bees. Annual Review of Entomology. 2008;53:191–208. pmid:17803456
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref9&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;9.&lt;/span&gt;  Nilsson SG, Franzen M, Jönsson E. Long-term land-use changes and extinction of specialised butterflies. Insect Conservation and Diversity. 2008;1(4):197–207.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref10&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;10.&lt;/span&gt;  Winfree R, Aguilar R, Vázquez DP, LeBuhn G, Aizen MA. A meta-analysis of bees’ responses to anthropogenic disturbance. Ecology. 2009;90(8):2068–2076. pmid:19739369
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref11&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;11.&lt;/span&gt;  Potts SG, Biesmeijer JC, Kremen C, Neumann P, Schweiger O, Kunin WE. Global pollinator declines: trends, impacts and drivers. Trends in Ecology and Evolution. 2010;25(6):345–353. pmid:20188434
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref12&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;12.&lt;/span&gt;  Ilyinykh A. Analysis of the causes of declines in Western Siberian outbreaks of the nun moth &lt;em&gt;Lymantria monacha&lt;/em&gt;. BioControl. 2011;56(2):123–131.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref13&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;13.&lt;/span&gt;  Ollerton J, Erenler H, Edwards M, Crockett R. Extinctions of aculeate pollinators in Britain and the role of large-scale agricultural changes. Science. 2014;346(6215):1360–1362. pmid:25504719
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref14&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;14.&lt;/span&gt;  Woodcock BA, Isaac NJ, Bullock JM, Roy DB, Garthwaite DG, Crowe A, et al. Impacts of neonicotinoid use on long-term population changes in wild bees in England. Nature Communications. 2016;7:12459. pmid:27529661
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref15&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;15.&lt;/span&gt;  Conrad KF, Woiwod IP, Perry JN. Long-term decline in abundance and distribution of the garden tiger moth (&lt;em&gt;Arctia caja&lt;/em&gt;) in Great Britain. Biological Conservation. 2002;106(3):329–337.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref16&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;16.&lt;/span&gt;  Conrad KF, Warren MS, Fox R, Parsons MS, Woiwod IP. Rapid declines of common, widespread British moths provide evidence of an insect biodiversity crisis. Biological Conservation. 2006;132(3):279–291.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref17&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;17.&lt;/span&gt;  Fox R. The decline of moths in Great Britain: a review of possible causes. Insect Conservation and Diversity. 2013;6(1):5–19.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref18&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;18.&lt;/span&gt;  Fox R, Oliver TH, Harrower C, Parsons MS, Thomas CD, Roy DB. Long-term changes to the frequency of occurrence of British moths are consistent with opposing and synergistic effects of climate and land-use changes. Journal of Applied Ecology. 2014;51(4):949–957. pmid:25954052
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref19&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;19.&lt;/span&gt;  Brändle M, Amarell U, Auge H, Klotz S, Brandl R. Plant and insect diversity along a pollution gradient: understanding species richness across trophic levels. Biodiversity &amp;amp; Conservation. 2001;10(9):1497–1511.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref20&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;20.&lt;/span&gt;  Benton TG, Bryant DM, Cole L, Crick HQ. Linking agricultural practice to insect and bird populations: a historical study over three decades. Journal of Applied Ecology. 2002;39(4):673–687.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref21&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;21.&lt;/span&gt;  Morecroft M, Bealey C, Howells O, Rennie S, Woiwod I. Effects of drought on contrasting insect and plant species in the UK in the mid-1990s. Global Ecology and Biogeography. 2002;11(1):7–22.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref22&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;22.&lt;/span&gt;  Biesmeijer JC, Roberts S, Reemer M, Ohlemüller R, Edwards M, Peeters T, et al. Parallel declines in pollinators and insect-pollinated plants in Britain and the Netherlands. Science. 2006;313(5785):351–354. pmid:16857940
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref23&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;23.&lt;/span&gt;  Fuentes-Montemayor E, Goulson D, Park KJ. The effectiveness of agri-environment schemes for the conservation of farmland moths: assessing the importance of a landscape-scale management approach. Journal of Applied Ecology. 2011;48(3):532–542.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref24&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;24.&lt;/span&gt;  Dirzo R, Young HS, Galetti M, Ceballos G, Isaac NJ, Collen B. Defaunation in the Anthropocene. Science. 2014;345(6195):401–406. pmid:25061202
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref25&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;25.&lt;/span&gt;  Thomas JA. Butterfly communities under threat. Science. 2016;353(6296):216–218. pmid:27418487
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref26&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;26.&lt;/span&gt;  Habel JC, Segerer A, Ulrich W, Torchyk O, Weisser WW, Schmitt T. Butterfly community shifts over 2 centuries. Conservation Biology. 2015; p. 754–762.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref27&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;27.&lt;/span&gt;  Thomas JA, Telfer MG, Roy DB, Preston CD, Greenwood J, Asher J, et al. Comparative losses of British butterflies, birds, and plants and the global extinction crisis. Science. 2004;303(5665):1879–1881. pmid:15031508
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref28&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;28.&lt;/span&gt;  Shortall CR, Moore A, Smith E, Hall MJ, Woiwod IP, Harrington R. Long-term changes in the abundance of flying insects. Insect Conservation and Diversity. 2009;2(4):251–260.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref29&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;29.&lt;/span&gt;  Bosch U, Hock W, Schwan H. Naturkundliche Untersuchungen zum Naturschutzgebiet Die Spey—III. Nachgewiesene Schmetterlinge (Macrolepidoptera). Natur am Niederrhein (NF). 1994;9(1):40–52.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref30&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;30.&lt;/span&gt;  Schmidt C, Robert B. Naturkundliche Untersuchungen zum Naturschutzgebiet Die Spey—VI. Die Köcherfliegen (Insecta, Trichoptera). Natur am Niederrhein (NF). 1995;10(2):62–68.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref31&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;31.&lt;/span&gt;  Hellenthal M, Ssymank A. Schwebfliegen (Diptera, Syrphidae) des Wahnbachtals im Bergischen Land (Nordrhein-Westfalen, Deutschland). Volucella. 2007;8:219–236.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref32&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;32.&lt;/span&gt;  Townes H. A light-weight Malaise trap. Entomological News. 1972;83:239–247.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref33&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;33.&lt;/span&gt;  Matthews RW, Matthews JR. Malaise traps: the Townes model catches more insects. Contributions of the American Entomological Institute. 1983;20:428–432.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref34&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;34.&lt;/span&gt;  Schwan H, Sorg M, Stenmans W. Naturkundliche Untersuchungen zum Naturschutzgebiet Die Spey (Stadt Krefeld, Kreis Neuss)—I. Untersuchungsstandorte und Methoden. Natur am Niederrhein (NF). 1993;8(1):1–13.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref35&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;35.&lt;/span&gt;  Sorg M. Entomophage Insekten des Versuchsgutes Höfchen (BRD, Burscheid).- Teil 1. Aphidiinae (Hymenoptera, Braconidae). Pflanzenschutz-Nachrichten Bayer. 1990;43(1/2):29–45.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref36&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;36.&lt;/span&gt;  Sorg M, Schwan H, Stenmans W, Müller A. Ermittlung der Biomassen flugaktiver Insekten im Naturschutzgebiet Orbroicher Bruch mit Malaise Fallen in den Jahren 1989 und 2013. Mitteilungen aus dem Entomologischen Verein Krefeld. 2013;2013(1):1–5.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref37&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;37.&lt;/span&gt;  Fliszkiewicz M, Giejdasz K, Wasielewski O, Krishnan N. Influence of winter temperature and simulated climate change on body mass and fat body depletion during diapause in adults of the Solitary bee, &lt;em&gt;Osmia rufa&lt;/em&gt; (Hymenoptera: Megachilidae). Environmental Entomology. 2012;41(6):1621–1630. pmid:23321111
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref38&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;38.&lt;/span&gt; Deutscher Wetterdienst. Recent and historical daily NKDZ climate station data; 2015. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.deutscher-wetterdienst.de&quot;&gt;http://www.deutscher-wetterdienst.de&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref39&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;39.&lt;/span&gt;  Cressie N. Statistics for spatial data: Wiley series in probability and statistics. Wiley-Interscience New York. 1993;15:16.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref40&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;40.&lt;/span&gt;  Pebesma EJ. Multivariable geostatistics in S: the gstat package. Computers &amp;amp; Geosciences. 2004;30(7):683–691.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref41&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;41.&lt;/span&gt;  Luo W, Taylor M, Parker S. A comparison of spatial interpolation methods to estimate continuous wind speed surfaces using irregularly distributed data from England and Wales. International Journal of Climatology. 2008;28(7):947–959.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref42&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;42.&lt;/span&gt;  Wood SN. Thin plate regression splines. Journal of the Royal Statistical Society: Series B (Statistical Methodology). 2003;65(1):95–114.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref43&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;43.&lt;/span&gt; Jarvis A, Reuter HI, Nelson A, Guevara E. Hole-filled seamless SRTM data V4, International Centre for Tropical Agriculture (CIAT); 2008. &lt;a href=&quot;http://srtm.csi.cgiar.org&quot;&gt;http://srtm.csi.cgiar.org&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref44&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;44.&lt;/span&gt; TIM-online. Karten NRW; 2016. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tim-online.nrw.de/tim-online/initParams.do&quot;&gt;http://www.tim-online.nrw.de/tim-online/initParams.do&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref45&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;45.&lt;/span&gt;  Steffan-Dewenter I, Münzenberg U, Bürger C, Thies C, Tscharntke T. Scale-dependent effects of landscape context on three pollinator guilds. Ecology. 2002;83(5):1421–1432.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref46&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;46.&lt;/span&gt;  Ellenberg H. Zeigerwerte der Gefäßpflanzen Mitteleuropas. Scripta Geobotanica 9. Goltze, Göttingen. 1974;.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref47&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;47.&lt;/span&gt;  Ellenberg H, Weber HE, Düll R, Wirth V, Werner W, Paulißen D, et al. Zeigerwerte von pflanzen in Mitteleuropa. E. Goltze; 1992.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref48&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;48.&lt;/span&gt;  Hennekens SM, Schaminée JH. TURBOVEG, a comprehensive data base management system for vegetation data. Journal of vegetation science. 2001;12(4):589–591.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref49&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;49.&lt;/span&gt;  Bates D, Mächler M, Bolker B, Walker S. Fitting Linear Mixed-Effects Models Using lme4. Journal of Statistical Software. 2015;67(1):1–48.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref50&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;50.&lt;/span&gt; Plummer M, et al. JAGS: A program for analysis of Bayesian graphical models using Gibbs sampling. In: Proceedings of the 3rd International Workshop on Distributed Statistical Computing. vol. 124. Vienna; 2003. p. 125.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref51&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;51.&lt;/span&gt; R Core Team. R: A Language and Environment for Statistical Computing; 2015. Available from: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.R-project.org/&quot;&gt;https://www.R-project.org/&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref52&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;52.&lt;/span&gt; Su YS, Yajima M. R2jags: Using R to Run JAGS; 2015. Available from: &lt;a href=&quot;http://CRAN.R-project.org/package=R2jags&quot;&gt;http://CRAN.R-project.org/package=R2jags&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref53&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;53.&lt;/span&gt;  Spiegelhalter DJ, Best NG, Carlin BP, Van Der Linde A. Bayesian measures of model complexity and fit. Journal of the Royal Statistical Society: Series B (Statistical Methodology). 2002;64(4):583–639.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref54&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;54.&lt;/span&gt;  Gelman A, Rubin DB. Inference from iterative simulation using multiple sequences. Statistical Science. 1992; p. 457–472.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref55&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;55.&lt;/span&gt;  Brown VK. Insect herbivores and plant succession. Oikos. 1985;44:17–22.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref56&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;56.&lt;/span&gt; WWF International. Living Planet Report 2016: Risk and resilience in a new era. Gland, Switzerland. 2016;.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref57&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;57.&lt;/span&gt;  Ceballos G, Ehrlich PR, Dirzo R. Biological annihilation via the ongoing sixth mass extinction signaled by vertebrate population losses and declines. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences. 2017; p. 201704949.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref58&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;58.&lt;/span&gt;  Kuussaari M, Heliölä J, Pöyry J, Saarinen K. Contrasting trends of butterfly species preferring semi-natural grasslands, field margins and forest edges in northern Europe. Journal of Insect Conservation. 2007;11(4):351–366.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref59&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;59.&lt;/span&gt;  Dennis RL, Sparks TH. Climate signals are reflected in an 89 year series of British Lepidoptera records. European Journal of Entomology. 2007;104(4):763.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref60&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;60.&lt;/span&gt;  Grüebler MU, Morand M, Naef-Daenzer B. A predictive model of the density of airborne insects in agricultural environments. Agriculture, Ecosystems &amp;amp; Environment. 2008;123(1):75–80.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref61&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;61.&lt;/span&gt;  Ewald JA, Wheatley CJ, Aebischer NJ, Moreby SJ, Duffield SJ, Crick HQ, et al. Influences of extreme weather, climate and pesticide use on invertebrates in cereal fields over 42 years. Global Change Biology. 2015;21(11):3931–3950. pmid:26149473
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref62&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;62.&lt;/span&gt;  McDermott Long O, Warren R, Price J, Brereton TM, Botham MS, Franco A. Sensitivity of UK butterflies to local climatic extremes: which life stages are most at risk? Journal of Animal Ecology. 2017;86(1):108–116. pmid:27796048
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref63&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;63.&lt;/span&gt;  Battin J. When good animals love bad habitats: ecological traps and the conservation of animal populations. Conservation Biology. 2004;18(6):1482–1491.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref64&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;64.&lt;/span&gt;  Gilroy JJ, Sutherland WJ. Beyond ecological traps: perceptual errors and undervalued resources. Trends in Ecology and Evolution. 2007;22(7):351–356. pmid:17416438
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref65&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;65.&lt;/span&gt;  Furrer RD, Pasinelli G. Empirical evidence for source—sink populations: a review on occurrence, assessments and implications. Biological Reviews. 2016;91:782–795. pmid:26010659
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref66&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;66.&lt;/span&gt;  Warren M, Hill J, Thomas J, Asher J, Fox R, Huntley B, et al. Rapid responses of British butterflies to opposing forces of climate and habitat change. Nature. 2001;414(6859):65–69. pmid:11689943
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ref67&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;order&quot;&gt;67.&lt;/span&gt;  Hallmann CA, Foppen RP, van Turnhout CA, de Kroon H, Jongejans E. Declines in insectivorous birds are associated with high neonicotinoid concentrations. Nature. 2014;511:341–343. pmid:25030173
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 19:17:24 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>kawera</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809</og:url>
<og:title>More than 75 percent decline over 27 years in total flying insect biomass in protected areas</og:title>
<og:description>Global declines in insects have sparked wide interest among scientists, politicians, and the general public. Loss of insect diversity and abundance is expected to provoke cascading effects on food webs and to jeopardize ecosystem services. Our understanding of the extent and underlying causes of this decline is based on the abundance of single species or taxonomic groups only, rather than changes in insect biomass which is more relevant for ecological functioning. Here, we used a standardized protocol to measure total insect biomass using Malaise traps, deployed over 27 years in 63 nature protection areas in Germany (96 unique location-year combinations) to infer on the status and trend of local entomofauna. Our analysis estimates a seasonal decline of 76%, and mid-summer decline of 82% in flying insect biomass over the 27 years of study. We show that this decline is apparent regardless of habitat type, while changes in weather, land use, and habitat characteristics cannot explain this overall decline. This yet unrecognized loss of insect biomass must be taken into account in evaluating declines in abundance of species depending on insects as a food source, and ecosystem functioning in the European landscape.</og:description>
<og:image>http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/figure/image?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809.g005&amp;size=inline</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185809</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>AlphaGo Zero: Learning from scratch</title>
<link>https://deepmind.com/blog/alphago-zero-learning-scratch/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://deepmind.com/blog/alphago-zero-learning-scratch/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;It is able to do this by using a novel form of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reinforcement_learning&quot;&gt;reinforcement learning&lt;/a&gt;, in which AlphaGo Zero becomes its own teacher. The system starts off with a neural network that knows nothing about the game of Go. It then plays games against itself, by combining this neural network with a powerful search algorithm. As it plays, the neural network is tuned and updated to predict moves, as well as the eventual winner of the games.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This updated neural network is then recombined with the search algorithm to create a new, stronger version of AlphaGo Zero, and the process begins again. In each iteration, the performance of the system improves by a small amount, and the quality of the self-play games increases, leading to more and more accurate neural networks and ever stronger versions of AlphaGo Zero.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This technique is more powerful than previous versions of AlphaGo because it is no longer constrained by the limits of human knowledge. Instead, it is able to learn tabula rasa from the strongest player in the world: AlphaGo itself.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It also differs from previous versions in other notable ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;AlphaGo Zero only uses the black and white stones from the Go board as its input, whereas previous versions of AlphaGo included a small number of hand-engineered features.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It uses one neural network rather than two. Earlier versions of AlphaGo used a “policy network” to select the next move to play and a ”value network” to predict the winner of the game from each position. These are combined in AlphaGo Zero, allowing it to be trained and evaluated more efficiently.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AlphaGo Zero does not use “rollouts” - fast, random games used by other Go programs to predict which player will win from the current board position. Instead, it relies on its high quality neural networks to evaluate positions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;All of these differences help improve the performance of the system and make it more general. But it is the algorithmic change that makes the system much more powerful and efficient.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 17:05:24 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>stablemap</dc:creator>
<og:title>AlphaGo Zero: Learning from scratch | DeepMind</og:title>
<og:url>https://deepmind.com/blog/alphago-zero-learning-scratch/</og:url>
<og:description>We introduce AlphaGo Zero, the latest evolution of AlphaGo, the first computer program to defeat a world champion at the ancient Chinese game of Go. Zero is even more powerful and is arguably the strongest Go player in history. Previous versions of AlphaGo initially trained on thousands of human amateur and professional games to learn how to play Go. AlphaGo Zero skips this step and learns to play simply by playing games against itself, starting from completely random play. In doing so, it quickly surpassed human level of play and defeated the previously published champion-defeating version of AlphaGo by 100 games to 0.</og:description>
<og:image>https://storage.googleapis.com/deepmind-live-cms/images/AlphaGoZero-Illustration-Square.width-600.jpg</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://deepmind.com/blog/alphago-zero-learning-scratch/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Dollar General Hits a Gold Mine in Rural America</title>
<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2017-10-11/dollar-general-hits-a-gold-mine-in-rural-america</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2017-10-11/dollar-general-hits-a-gold-mine-in-rural-america</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;section-break&quot;&gt;On a Friday in April, Bob Tharp, the mayor of Decatur, Ark., takes me to see what used to be the commercial heart of his town. There isn’t much to look at beyond the husk of a Walmart Express: 12,000 square feet of cinder block painted in different shades of brown. The glass doors are locked, as they’ve been for 14 months. “For so many people in this town, to have to see this empty building every day, they couldn’t drive by without getting tears in their eyes,” Tharp recalls. The store had opened on a frigid morning in January 2015, just days into his mayorship. “Pinch yourself and it is true,” he’d posted on Facebook the night before. For the first time in a decade, the 1,788 residents could buy groceries in town.﻿﻿ But the reprieve was short. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2016-01-15/wal-mart-to-shut-hundreds-of-stores-including-express-locations&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;following January&lt;/a&gt;, word came from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/quote/WMT:US&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot;&gt;Wal-Mart Stores Inc.&lt;/a&gt;’s corporate headquarters, 18 miles to the east in Bentonville, that within the month the store would be closed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You rascals!” Tharp remembers telling the executive who called to deliver the news. “You come to these small towns, and you build these stores, and you cause all the mom and pops to close down, and now you’re the only ones left standing, and you want to go home? Why would you do that to our community?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;lazy-img-319030575&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/inAp35JPRTds/v1/60x-1.jpg&quot; data-native-src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/inAp35JPRTds/v1/-1x-1.jpg&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img__image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mayor Tharp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photographer: Terry A. Ratzlaff for Bloomberg Businessweek&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Walmart Express had been a pilot store, the smallest ever for the world’s largest retailer, designed to test whether a national brand with major supply-chain advantages could wrest a profit from towns long considered too sparsely populated. The answer, it seemed, was no: The company closed more than 100 stores across Arkansas and other southeastern states that day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tharp did what he could to turn things around, putting out calls to urge a grocer, or any retailer, to move into the vacant building. He found no takers for a year, until at last, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/quote/DG:US&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot;&gt;Dollar General Corp.&lt;/a&gt;, which had operated a smaller store on the outskirts of Decatur’s downtown since 2001, agreed to relocate to Main Street—and start offering fresh meat, fruit, and vegetables.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Decatur store is one of 1,000 Dollar Generals opening this year as part of the $22 billion chain’s plan to expand rapidly in poor, rural communities where it has come to represent not decline but economic resurgence, or at least survival. The company’s aggressively plain yellow-and-black logo is becoming the small-town corollary to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/quote/SBUX:US&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot;&gt;Starbucks Corp.&lt;/a&gt;’s two-tailed green mermaid. (Although you can spot her on canned iced coffee at Dollar General, too.) Already, there are 14,000 one-story cinder block Dollar Generals in the U.S.—outnumbering by a few hundred the coffee chain’s domestic footprint. Fold in the second-biggest dollar chain, Dollar Tree, and the number of stores, 27,465, exceeds the 22,375 outlets of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/quote/CVS:US&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot;&gt;CVS&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/quote/RAD:US&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot;&gt;Rite Aid&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/quote/WBA:US&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot;&gt;Walgreens&lt;/a&gt; combined. And the little-box player is fully expecting to turn profits where even narrow-margin colossus Walmart failed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;section-break&quot;&gt;Later in the morning, after I meet with Tharp, I join Linda Martin, a Decatur alderwoman, to do a little shopping at the existing Dollar General. First we swing by the slaughterhouse on Main Street, owned by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/quote/3889556Z:US&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot;&gt;Simmons Foods Inc.&lt;/a&gt;, the main local employer, where rows of chickens sit in five reeking semitrailers outside. Then we head to the crest of a big hill a half-mile south and park under the massive Dollar General sign.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re greeted inside the 7,300-square-foot store by a foot-tall chocolate bunny, one of a number of items sitting on a clearance table marked 25 percent off. Easter was last Sunday, so the bunny can be ours for $3.75. Pastel-colored single-stem roses are available for $1.50, and 12-pack cartons of Mountain Dew are stacked, without price tags, under the table. Deeper in, stuffed shelves reach almost to the ceiling, resembling a Walmart in the days when Sam Walton’s “Stack ’em high, watch ’em fly” edict reigned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next to an endcap arrayed with no-contract cell phones, the assistant store manager, Debbie Schmidt, is tidying an unruly rack of knit stretch pants and tank tops, some actually priced at $1. (Dollar General hasn’t technically been a dollar store for decades, and only a quarter of its products sell for that amount today.) Schmidt is a cheerful presence, and though she’s preparing to pack up the store for the big move to the former Walmart site in two days, she isn’t too busy to greet each customer by name. “These people are not in here one time a day; they are in here three and four times a day,” she says. Formerly, she managed wire transfers at the Walmart Express, and she says she found out she was losing her job, along with 29 others, from the news teams who showed up in the parking lot. “Everyone was crying,” she recalls. “Employees and customers, they were heartbroken. We were family.” She worked for a while at a Walmart in Bentonville, but “it was nothing like it was here,” she says. “We’re just closer here. We all know each other.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;pullquote&quot; data-align=&quot;center&quot; readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;passage&quot;&gt;“Essentially what the dollar stores are betting on in a large way is that we are going to have a permanent underclass in America”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;Martin and I peer inside the refrigerated coolers at the entrance, which have triangular yellow stickers on each corner reading “Putting Healthy Food Within Reach, SNAP &amp;amp; EBT accepted here.” Inside are packets of Eckrich Deli Bologna ($2), Ore-Ida Tater Tots ($2), and 12-ounce bottles of Red Diamond sweet tea ($1). In another cooler, Martin finds the green Michelina’s-brand frozen meals she heats up for lunch at her weekly quilting group. She glances in dismay at the price tag of the Mediterranean Chicken Pasta—$1.50—then marches to the register, explaining to the cashier that she recently bought one for $1 at a Dollar General in Coal Hill, two hours away. That’s also the price, she says, at the Bentonville Walmart. “They’re so good,” the cashier sympathizes, blaming the store’s supplier for the extra 50¢. “I’m not going to pay $1.50 when I can go to Walmart and get it for $1,” Martin tells me later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;lazy-img-319033980&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/iCZ0BTHMPtwQ/v6/60x-1.png&quot; data-native-src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/iCZ0BTHMPtwQ/v6/-1x-1.png&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img__image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like many rural towns, Decatur once fed itself and shared its bounty with the rest of America. At the turn of the 20th century, it had a tomato cannery and exported peaches, apples, strawberries, and beans by the boxcar from a downtown train depot. A population of 245 in 1915 supported two grocery stores and four general stores. But in the 1930s, blight outbreaks and insect invasions largely wiped out local orchards. The depot is now a museum where antique bushel baskets and poplar harvest crates hang from the ceiling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By 1962 there was one grocery store left, serving a population of 400. Small-scale chicken farms had replaced the orchards, and poultry was the town’s economic engine, thanks largely to Lloyd Peterson, who employed almost half the working population at his chicken farm, research facility, and plant (the one Simmons Foods now owns). Meanwhile, 22 miles away, in Rogers, Ark., Sam Walton opened his first Walmart, and the era of big-box retail began. Walton later wrote in his autobiography that his strategy was to “put good-sized discount stores into little one-horse towns which everybody else was ignoring.” He apparently didn’t think Decatur reached even one-horse status. Peterson, a hunting buddy of Walton’s, asked his friend many times to open a Walmart there, but Walton’s response was always the same: “Lloyd, that dog just doesn’t hunt.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;lazy-img-319030358&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/i2oJ7tiuROCQ/v1/60x-1.jpg&quot; data-native-src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/i2oJ7tiuROCQ/v1/-1x-1.jpg&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img__image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The vacant interior of the original Dollar General in Decatur. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photographer: Terry A. Ratzlaff for Bloomberg Businessweek&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So Peterson finally opened his own version, in 1983, called Decatur Discount, just where the Walmart Express, and now Dollar General, would later appear—the past 40 years of global economic trends playing out in retail form on a single concrete lot. Peterson’s 17,000-square-foot Walmart clone was as much a form of charitable largesse as an attempt to make money. The store did sell some food, but most people still bought groceries from the local mom and pop, which cycled through three owners. Walmart’s growing portfolio of Supercenters and Sam’s Clubs in Bentonville was hard for local stores to compete with. “We couldn’t get a supplier to give us a good deal on anything,” recalls Michael Wilkins, whose family was the last to run a locally owned grocer in Decatur. “In Northwest Arkansas, Walmart dominated everything.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2001, observing its population of 1,314, a national retailer finally started paying attention to Decatur, but it wasn’t Walmart. Instead, Dollar General’s yellow sign went up atop the hill. The new chain in town had similar roots to Walmart—established in 1955 in Springfield, Ky. (population 2,000)—but relied even more on low-income shoppers and recessions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That made it a good fit for Decatur, where chicken hasn’t delivered much prosperity. The town’s median household income is just under $35,000, and the poverty rate is 32 percent, more than twice the national average; one out of every five people needs federal help to buy food. Workers at the Simmons plant, many of whom are Latino immigrants, say they earn as little as $8.50 an hour slaughtering and cleaning carcasses in grueling eight-hour shifts. (Simmons says wages start at $11.50 an hour.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For them, and for longtime residents such as Martin and Tharp, the Dollar General has meant a place to buy laundry detergent, shaving cream, and other basics much cheaper than the local operations could manage. It wasn’t selling milk or eggs at first, but within a few years it was—and accepting food assistance cards. Wilkins gave up his business in 2006. Twelve people lost their jobs, and Decatur was now in line with two of the U.S. Department of Agriculture’s criteria for food deserts: It’s both a low-income community with limited food access and a rural area 10 miles from the nearest supermarket. In 2010, Peterson’s heirs closed the pharmacy inside Decatur General (the renamed Decatur Discount), the only one in town; two years later they shut down the rest of the store, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;section-break&quot;&gt;About a year ago, as stores were going under across the nation, Garrick Brown, director for retail research at the commercial real estate company Cushman &amp;amp; Wakefield, was searching for bright spots in the industry. For five years running, he realized, a dollar store had opened once every four and a half hours, an average of more than five a day. “They see a need and are aggressively racing to meet that need for low-cost goods in places that are food deserts,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dollar General’s sales per square foot have risen steadily in recent years, to $229, but they’re still far below the industry average of $325 and less than half of Walmart’s. Their gross profit margins were 30.9 percent over the last five years, though, compared with 25.1 percent at Walmart. The dollar chain doesn’t carry the big-ticket purchases—bikes, appliances—that Walmart does. It thrives mostly on selling low-ticket items and basics, such as toilet paper, that help shoppers on tight budgets get through the week. At Dollar General, a package of eight Pop-Tarts is $2, or 25¢ a tart. At Walmart, shoppers can buy the same eight-pack, but more often they save by spending $9.98 for a bulk package of 48—only 20¢ a tart. Dollar General doesn’t offer much bulk. A Dollar General store also has lower startup costs; it spends as little as $250,000 for a new store, vs. the more than $15 million Walmart puts into a new Supercenter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;lazy-img-319030685&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/iPzaE5Y1UCGQ/v1/60x-1.jpg&quot; data-native-src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/iPzaE5Y1UCGQ/v1/-1x-1.jpg&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img__image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Local resident Carol Daniel watches the musical acts at the annual Decatur BBQ Blues &amp;amp; Bluegrass Festival. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photographer: Terry A. Ratzlaff for Bloomberg Businessweek&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company declined to comment for this story, but in March 2016, Chief Executive Officer Todd Vasos outlined the chain’s “2020 Vision” for 125 investors gathered at a hotel in Nashville, south of the headquarters in suburban Goodlettsville, Tenn. (Shareholders include T. Rowe Price Associates, the Singapore sovereign wealth fund GIC, BlackRock, and Vanguard Group.) The presentation detailed a site-selection strategy focused on small towns, dubbed “Anytown, USA.” Then Jim Thorpe, Dollar General’s chief merchandising officer at the time, defined the core customer for the investors: “Our Best Friends Forever”—an extremely cash-strapped demographic, with a household income less than $35,000, and reliant on government assistance, that shops at Dollar General to “stretch budgets.” Thorpe said these BFFs represented 21 percent of the chain’s shoppers and 43 percent of its sales. His final slide touted a goal of increasing sales 50 percent, to $30 billion, by 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are really only two ways brick-and-mortar retailers can meet such a grand goal: open hundreds of stores or, much harder, radically increase same-store sales. Vasos’s presentation included a map that looks similar to an epidemiological forecast, with yellow and green dots spreading like a pox. The yellow dots represented the chain’s 12,483 existing stores. The 13,000 green dots were the “remaining opportunities”—some in low-income urban neighborhoods, but most in small and very small towns. There’s almost no white space east of the Mississippi, except for the tip of Maine and southernmost end of Florida. The Rust Belt is overflowing with green dots piled upon yellow, and the Eastern Seaboard is almost exclusively green.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;lazy-img-319034140&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/iqdcGzLhsfr8/v2/60x-1.jpg&quot; data-native-src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/iqdcGzLhsfr8/v2/-1x-1.jpg&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img__image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Decatur High School cheerleaders during a parade for the festival. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photographer: Terry A. Ratzlaff for Bloomberg Businessweek&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dollar General’s chief rival, Dollar Tree Inc., which also owns Family Dollar, has a plan that’s almost as ambitious. In a recent Securities and Exchange Commission filing, Dollar Tree indicated that it believes the U.S. market can support 10,000 Dollar Trees and 15,000 Family Dollars. That’s almost 11,000 more stores than its current 14,500, though it isn’t putting a timeline on the expansion. In August, Randy Guiler, vice president for investor relations at Dollar Tree, told me it would “determine each year what our pace of growth will be.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It reminds me of a craps table,” Brown, the commercial real estate analyst, says. “Essentially what the dollar stores are betting on in a large way is that we are going to have a permanent underclass in America. It’s based on the concept that the jobs went away, and the jobs are never coming back, and that things aren’t going to get better in any of these places.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dollar chains do provide jobs of their own, of course. The chain employs about 121,000 people nationwide and has said it will hire 10,000 more employees this year. But those jobs will be or are mostly low-wage. Salaried managers can earn about $40,000, but they often work long hours without overtime pay. These few positions won’t make much of a dent in the fortunes of communities such as Decatur. The only new employment opportunities in the foreseeable future, other than at the larger Dollar General, are on the grim, hazardous industrial meat lines at Simmons. The company recently announced plans to build an expanded factory 2 miles outside town by 2019 and close part of the existing one. Tharp doesn’t know if the city will lose its water and sewer contract with Simmons and is worried about the potential loss of tax revenue for the schools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;section-break&quot;&gt;Inside the city building, an old schoolhouse, Mayor Tharp, wearing a shirt with his name embroidered on one side and a paw print of the town’s bulldog mascot on the other, takes a seat at a wide wooden table with Jaeger Bauer, an 11-year-old from Cub Scout Pack 3410. Bauer is earning his merit badge in citizenship. He opens the discussion by expressing concern about how much energy the town’s digital library sign uses. “The city should buy a solar panel,” he suggests. After Tharp promises to check into it, Bauer asks what being mayor involves. Tharp explains that he had a rough start to his tenure. “I was purely aggravated and angry with Walmart,” he says. “But we have to forgive and forget and move on.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a touchy subject. Like many townspeople, the Bauers survive on a paycheck from Walmart. They moved to the area from Texas 12 years ago, when Jaeger’s dad was hired for an IT position at the Bentonville headquarters. His mother, Brandi, who home-schools her two children, still talks nostalgically about the year she was able to “shop locally at our company.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;lazy-img-319040894&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/iInAz9vpdwao/v5/60x-1.jpg&quot; data-native-src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/iInAz9vpdwao/v5/-1x-1.jpg&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img__image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Standing for a portrait after shopping at the Dollar General in Decatur (clockwise from top left): Steven Hoover; Peggy Beal; Charlotte Berry; “Bump” Steel; Caitlin Moore, Bret Russow, and Chris Yancey; Ashley Holmes and her daughter Aurora.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photographer: Terry A. Ratzlaff for Bloomberg Businessweek&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tharp explains to Jaeger that he’d called Walmart every two weeks after the store closed. At first the company suggested he put a flea market in the space. “I told them I don’t need another flea market. The town’s outcry was, ‘Find us something like Walmart, but with a pharmacy.’ ” When he tried soliciting other retailers, Walmart’s asking price, $1.2 million, was too high. Over the summer of 2016, Dollar General had made a deal to buy 41 shuttered Expresses, but the Decatur store was excluded from it. Tharp kept asking Walmart to lower the price, and by February, Dollar General closed on the Decatur property for $425,000. Even so, Tharp still can’t bring himself to shop at Walmart regularly. His wife canceled their Sam’s Club membership.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later that day, I meet with Deborah Foresee, the school nurse at Decatur Northside Elementary, who explains that even before the Walmart Express closed, many families were struggling to stretch their food budget; the cost of gas to make the drive to Bentonville or another town with a supermarket is significant. The school relies on grants and donations to help feed students—districtwide, 79.3 percent qualify for a free or reduced-price lunch. After Walmart closed, Foresee heard about students eating processed meals almost exclusively and sometimes nothing at all. “So many of these families were doing ramen noodles or anything that they can buy in big packages and store for long periods,” she says. In response, Foresee introduced a rash of initiatives: providing dinner during after-school activities, handing out fresh fruit three days a week, a snack-pack program on Fridays. “We make sure every kid who needs it gets food,” she says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;lazy-img-319034046&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/izCcZ.6Nln7U/v2/60x-1.jpg&quot; data-native-src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/izCcZ.6Nln7U/v2/-1x-1.jpg&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img__image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The festival parade traveling north on Main Street. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photographer: Terry A. Ratzlaff for Bloomberg Businessweek&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elizabeth Racine, a professor of public health at the University of North Carolina at Charlotte, is among the few academics who closely study dollar-store chains. In 2010 she was asked by the county health department to study Charlotte food deserts, and she soon noticed how many dollar stores were in these areas. “It’s not the kind of store a dietitian would love,” Racine says. She describes feeling bombarded when she first walked into a Family Dollar—chips, rows of candy, coolers of soda—and wondering how places so filled with unhealthful food could possibly be authorized to take food assistance cards. “I’ve come around,” she says. “I appreciate that they are willing to operate in low-income places because so many other stores aren’t willing to go there.” They may not be selling fresh fruit and vegetables, but they do offer some healthier staples, such as frozen meats, brown rice, 10-percent-whole-wheat bread, and dried beans. She calls them the Whole Foods of Charlotte’s food deserts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soon enough the Whole Foods of American food deserts could be Whole Foods itself. This summer, the USDA rolled out a pilot program to let food assistance card recipients order their groceries online. Ten companies signed on, including Walmart and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/quote/AMZN:US&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot;&gt;Amazon.com Inc.&lt;/a&gt;, which recently spent $13.7 billion to acquire &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/quote/WFM:US&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot;&gt;Whole Foods Market Inc.&lt;/a&gt;—but no dollar-store chains. The program could open the door for the big players to go back into very small towns in a way that lets them avoid the traditional overhead problems. But it could take a while. Dollar General’s rural geography has an insulating effect, writes Brandon Fletcher, an analyst at Sanford C. Bernstein, in his May report, “DG: The revolution of rural America has not been televised,” arguing it will be decades before Walmart and Amazon develop “a truly rural solution to disrupt the important role Dollar General plays in rural American life.” That might be why the dollar chains haven’t developed e-commerce strategies. Dollar General didn’t start selling online until 2011, and Family Dollar still doesn’t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;lazy-img-319030188&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/iwlTgusacJZc/v1/60x-1.jpg&quot; data-native-src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/iwlTgusacJZc/v1/-1x-1.jpg&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img__image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sunrise over state Route 102 leading out of Decatur.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photographer: Terry A. Ratzlaff for Bloomberg Businessweek&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;section-break&quot;&gt;On June 3, a little before 7 a.m., Tharp puts a red ribbon and a pair of giant golden scissors with blue handles and “City of Decatur” engraved on the top blade in the back seat of his car. Then he drives down to Main Street—along with half the town, it seems—to celebrate the new Dollar General. The line started forming at 6 a.m., and when the doors open shortly after Tharp arrives, it stretches almost across the street to the farmers co-op. The first 100 adults in line receive $10 gift bags; the first 200 get goody bags with plastic Dollar General cups and samples of Tide. There are hot dogs, and Tony the Tiger shows up for photos with the kids. After the ribbon-cutting and some introductions by the local management team at Dollar General, Tharp takes a deep breath and addresses the crowd. “We have a store,” he says, “that’s here to stay.”&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 16:29:26 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>trevin</dc:creator>
<og:description>In the poorest towns, where even Wal-Mart failed, the little-box player is turning a profit.</og:description>
<og:image>https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/i8dRTgsgs6sA/v0/1200x630.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>Dollar General Hits a Gold Mine in Rural America</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2017-10-11/dollar-general-hits-a-gold-mine-in-rural-america</og:url>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2017-10-11/dollar-general-hits-a-gold-mine-in-rural-america</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Documenting the Web together</title>
<link>https://blogs.windows.com/msedgedev/2017/10/18/documenting-web-together-mdn-web-docs</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blogs.windows.com/msedgedev/2017/10/18/documenting-web-together-mdn-web-docs</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Today, we’re excited to share some big news for developers around the world wide web: We’re committing our resources towards making MDN Web Docs the best place to go for web API reference. To kick things off, today we started redirecting over 7,700 MSDN pages to corresponding topics in the MDN web docs library powered by Mozilla.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In conjunction with similar commitments from &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.mozilla.org/blog/2017/10/18/mozilla-brings-microsoft-google-w3c-samsung-together-create-cross-browser-documentation-mdn&quot;&gt;Mozilla&lt;/a&gt;, Google, the W3C, and Samsung, we’re teaming up to make MDN Web Docs the best place for web developers to learn and share information about building for the open web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-21730&quot; src=&quot;https://winblogs.azureedge.net/win/2017/10/5f06918f73070fef4068d1ad24847b8f.png&quot; alt=&quot;Illustrations showing the Microsoft and MDN Web Docs logos surrounding a handshake icon&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;450&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;15&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MDN is a core part of Mozilla’s overarching mission: to ensure the Internet is a global public resource, open and accessible to all. We believe providing web developers the best possible information will enable them to deliver great web experiences that adhere to established standards and work across platforms and devices. We are excited to have Microsoft, Google, The W3C, and Samsung on board as we continue on our journey to make MDN the premiere resource for developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;— Ali Spivak, Head of Developer Ecosystem at Mozilla&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/MDN/MDN_Product_Advisory_Board/Members&quot;&gt;Representatives&lt;/a&gt; from each of these organizations will also be serving on the &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/MDN/MDN_Product_Advisory_Board/Members&quot;&gt;MDN Product Advisory Board&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, a committee dedicated to making MDN your definitive place for useful, unbiased, browser-agnostic documentation for current and emerging standards-based web technologies. The MDN Product Advisory Board is also looking for active individuals from the web community to serve on the board. If you’re interested, &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/MDN/MDN_Product_Advisory_Board/Members&quot;&gt;find more details&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;em&gt;MDN web docs&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Web docs should just work for everyone&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Redirecting our API reference library to MDN is the next step towards consolidating our compatibility info in the same place you probably already frequent for general web documentation. Earlier this year, we began the effort to backfill the MDN browser &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/MDN/Contribute/Structures/Compatibility_tables&quot;&gt;Compatibility tables&lt;/a&gt; with a column representing the Microsoft Edge browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over 5000 MDN edits later, the entire web API surface of Microsoft Edge (as of the 10/2017 &lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.windows.com/windowsexperience/2017/10/17/whats-new-windows-10-fall-creators-update/#zdURfPb34hBRFT3W.97&quot;&gt;Windows 10 Fall Creators Update&lt;/a&gt;, Build 16299) is now documented on MDN, and will continue to be kept up-to-date with each new release of Windows and our EdgeHTML browser engine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_21727&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; readability=&quot;7.4285714285714&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-21727&quot; src=&quot;https://winblogs.azureedge.net/win/2017/10/39e80306e30b7211f93a4ffabbce08e5.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screen capture showing a sample Browser Compatibility Table from MDN Web Docs&quot; width=&quot;678&quot; height=&quot;246&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Example of a &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/API/Pointer_Lock_API#Browser_compatibility&quot;&gt;Browser compatibility table on MDN Web Docs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of our guiding principles in developing Microsoft Edge is that end users should never have to worry about which sites work in which browsers. This philosophy—”&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.windows.com/msedgedev/2014/11/11/living-on-the-edge-our-next-step-in-helping-the-web-just-work/&quot;&gt;the Web should just work for everyone&lt;/a&gt;“—led to our choice to &lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.windows.com/msedgedev/2015/06/17/building-a-more-interoperable-web-with-microsoft-edge/#pM4fSdjFWdI7PP0G.97&quot;&gt;target the “interoperable intersection” of web APIs&lt;/a&gt; in our browser engineering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just like with end users, we think it’s well overdue for developers to have a simpler view of web standards documentation. Developers shouldn’t have to chase down API documentation across standards bodies, browser vendors, and third parties—there should be a single, canonical source which is community-maintained and supported by all major vendors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For these reasons we’re all-in on making MDN the home of web standards documentation. Not only is MDN a veritable encyclopedia and thriving community of all things web development, it’s also an institution in itself–a living monument to our collective history—as web developers and enthusiasts, web standards advocates, and browser engineers–of developing the web forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Documenting the web forward&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MDN was founded &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MDN_Web_Docs&quot;&gt;over 10 years ago in 2005&lt;/a&gt; as the Mozilla Developer Center and later become known as the Mozilla Developer Network. Just as the Mozilla Organization was &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mozilla_Foundation&quot;&gt;founded out of Netscape&lt;/a&gt;, the Mozilla Developer Center grew from the original Netscape Navigator browser docs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, the Internet Explorer Developer Center was first published online from the Microsoft Developer Network (MSDN) several years before that in the late 90s to help introduce and showcase Dynamic HTML (“DHTML”), Microsoft’s precursor to the modern DOM and CSS object model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_21736&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; readability=&quot;25.00826446281&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-21736&quot; src=&quot;https://winblogs.azureedge.net/win/2017/10/8659e49978661d1616499c2c472e9e8e.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screen capture of Microsoft Internet Explorer Developer Center on MSDN Online, circa 2000. Courtesy of the Internet Archive Wayback Machine&quot; width=&quot;813&quot; height=&quot;443&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Microsoft Internet Explorer Developer Center on MSDN Online, circa 2000. Courtesy of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://web.archive.org/web/20001110003800/msdn.microsoft.com/ie&quot;&gt;Internet Archive Wayback Machine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast forward to the modern web platform of today. The competing Netscape and Internet Explorer browsers from the bygone era of the early web are now subjects of tech archaeology, not site compatibility testing. From the final releases of IE &lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.windows.com/msedgedev/2015/05/06/a-break-from-the-past-part-2-saying-goodbye-to-activex-vbscript-attachevent/&quot;&gt;culminating with the birth of Microsoft Edge&lt;/a&gt;, we replaced earlier Microsoft technologies with emerging industry standards–the modern DOM and ECMAScript standards for DHTML and VBScript, HTML5 for ActiveX, a common browser extension model for Browser Helper Objects (“BHOs”).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through all this change, MDN has grown up alongside the web, and today has over 34,500 documents, 6 million monthly users and 20,500 contributors. From its initial Netscape product docs, the breadth and depth of MDN’s content has radically expanded to encompass the state of the art of modern web development—so much so that recently the site was &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.mozilla.org/opendesign/future-mdn-focus-web-docs/&quot;&gt;restructured and rebranded&lt;/a&gt; to reflect MDN’s commitment to being a browser-neutral community resource. We are excited to join Mozilla, Google, The W3C, and Samsung in making MDN our home for web standards documentation and dedicated to helping it grow even further to meet your needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will continue to maintain Microsoft- and Windows-focused documentation on Microsoft Docs (&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.microsoft.com/microsoft-edge&quot;&gt;docs.microsoft.com/microsoft-edge&lt;/a&gt;), including Windows-specific test guidance, information on the Edge DevTools, and upcoming details about Progressive Web Apps in the Windows Store. And you’ll still find the latest Microsoft Edge status, changelogs, and news at our Microsoft Edge Developer site (&lt;a href=&quot;https://dev.microsoftedge.com&quot;&gt;dev.microsoftedge.com&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please join us in supporting and contributing to MDN web docs! We’re all building this Web together; let’s document our hard work!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Erika Doyle Navara, Senior Dev Writer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;post-modified&quot;&gt;Updated October 18, 2017 6:12 am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 15:56:59 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>marvinpinto</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Documenting the Web together - Microsoft Edge Dev Blog</og:title>
<og:description>Today, we’re excited to share some big news for developers around the world wide web: We’re committing our resources towards making MDN Web Docs the best place to go for web API reference. To kick things off, today we started redirecting over 7,700 MSDN pages to corresponding topics in the MDN web docs library powered …</og:description>
<og:url>https://blogs.windows.com/msedgedev/2017/10/18/documenting-web-together-mdn-web-docs/</og:url>
<og:image>https://winblogs.azureedge.net/win/2017/10/5f06918f73070fef4068d1ad24847b8f.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blogs.windows.com/msedgedev/2017/10/18/documenting-web-together-mdn-web-docs/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why You Can Focus in a Coffee Shop but Not in Your Open Office</title>
<link>https://hbr.org/2017/10/why-you-can-focus-in-a-coffee-shop-but-not-in-your-open-office</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://hbr.org/2017/10/why-you-can-focus-in-a-coffee-shop-but-not-in-your-open-office</guid>
<description>&lt;div readability=&quot;40&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;text-gray-light mbn mt-large2&quot;&gt;Executive Summary&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surveys have shown that workers’ primary complaint with open or cubicle-filled offices is the unwanted noise. However, recent research suggests it’s not the noise itself that’s the problem. Two recent studies have found that the right level of ambient noise triggers our minds to think more creatively. And one of those studies found no difference between people working in a very noisy environment (the equivalent of a motorcycle engine revving) and people working in total silence. Taken together, the lesson here is that the ideal space for focused work is not about freedom from noise, but about freedom from &lt;em&gt;interruption&lt;/em&gt;. Finding a space you can hide away in, regardless of how noisy it is, may be the best strategy for making sure you get the important work done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;115.99714285714&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;mbn pbn&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2017/10/oct17-18-andrew-neel-unsplash-218073.jpg&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 48em) 55.7291667vw, 97.3924381vw&quot; srcset=&quot;/resources/images/article_assets/2017/10/oct17-18-andrew-neel-unsplash-218073-300x169.jpg 300w, /resources/images/article_assets/2017/10/oct17-18-andrew-neel-unsplash-218073-1024x576.jpg 1024w, /resources/images/article_assets/2017/10/oct17-18-andrew-neel-unsplash-218073-500x281.jpg 500w, /resources/images/article_assets/2017/10/oct17-18-andrew-neel-unsplash-218073-383x215.jpg 383w, /resources/images/article_assets/2017/10/oct17-18-andrew-neel-unsplash-218073-383x215.jpg 383w, /resources/images/article_assets/2017/10/oct17-18-andrew-neel-unsplash-218073-500x281.jpg 500w, /resources/images/article_assets/2017/10/oct17-18-andrew-neel-unsplash-218073-700x394.jpg 700w, /resources/images/article_assets/2017/10/oct17-18-andrew-neel-unsplash-218073-850x478.jpg 850w, /resources/images/article_assets/2017/10/oct17-18-andrew-neel-unsplash-218073-1200x675.jpg 1200w, /resources/images/article_assets/2017/10/oct17-18-andrew-neel-unsplash-218073.jpg 1200w&quot; alt=&quot;oct17-18-andrew-neel-unsplash-218073&quot; width=&quot;1200&quot; height=&quot;675&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-185107&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;andrew neel/unsplash&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few years ago, during a media interview for one of my books, my interviewer said something I still ponder often. Ranting about the level of distraction in his open office, he said, “That’s why I have a membership at the coworking space across the street — so I can focus.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I fully support the backlash against open offices, the comment struck me as odd. After all, coworking spaces &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; typically use an open office layout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I recently came across a series of studies examining the effect of sound on the brain that reveals why his strategy works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&quot;https://hbr.org/2013/11/research-cubicles-are-the-absolute-worst&quot;&gt;previous research&lt;/a&gt;, we know that workers’ primary problem with open or cubicle-filled offices is the unwanted noise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;max-width-700&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full mvn pvm has-border-top has-border-bottom wp-image-31865&quot; src=&quot;https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2013/11/everyonecanhear.gif&quot; srcset=&quot;/resources/images/article_assets/2013/11/everyonecanhear-278x300.gif 278w, /resources/images/article_assets/2013/11/everyonecanhear-32x32.gif 32w, /resources/images/article_assets/2013/11/everyonecanhear.gif 580w&quot; alt=&quot;everyonecanhear&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 48em) 55.7291667vw, 97.3924381vw&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But new research shows that it may not be the sound itself that distracts us…it may be &lt;em&gt;who&lt;/em&gt; is making it. In fact, some level of office banter in the background might actually benefit our ability to do creative tasks, provided we don’t get drawn into the conversation. Instead of total silence, the ideal work environment for creative work has a little bit of background noise. That’s why you might focus really well in a noisy coffee shop, but barely be able to concentrate in a noisy office.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jstor.org/stable/10.1086/665048&quot;&gt;One study&lt;/a&gt;, published in the Journal of Consumer Research, found that the right level of ambient noise triggers our minds to think more creatively. The researchers, led by Ravi Mehta of the University of Illinois Urbana-Champaign, examined various levels of noise on participants as they completed tests of creative thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Participants were randomized into four groups and everyone was asked to complete a Remote Associates Test (a commonly used measurement that judges creative thinking by asking test-takers to find the relationship between a series of words that, as first glance, appear unrelated). Depending on the group, participants were exposed to various noise levels in the background, from total silence to 50 decibels, 70 decibels, and 85 decibels. The differences between most of the groups were statistically insignificant; however, the participants in the 70 decibels group (those exposed to a level of noise similar to background chatter in a coffee shop) significantly outperformed the other groups. Since the effects were small, this may suggest that our creative thinking doesn’t differ that much in response to total silence and 85 decibels of background noise — the equivalent of a loud garbage disposal or a quiet motorcycle. Since none of us presumably want to work next to a garbage disposal or motorcycle, I found this surprising.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But since the results at 70 decibels were significant, the study also suggests that the &lt;em&gt;right&lt;/em&gt; level of background noise — not too loud and not total silence — may actually boost one’s creative thinking ability. The right level of background noise may disrupt our normal patterns of thinking just enough to allow our imaginations to wander, without making it impossible to focus. This type of “distracted focus” appears to be the optimal state for working on creative tasks. As the authors write, “Getting into a relatively noisy environment may trigger the brain to think abstractly, and thus generate creative ideas.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.brikbase.org/content/sound-creativity-correlating-brainwave-psychometric-changes-workplace-acoustics&quot;&gt;another study&lt;/a&gt;, researchers used frontal lobe electroencephalographic (EEG) machines to study the brain waves of participants as they completed tests of creativity while exposed to various sound environments. The researchers found statistically significant changes in creativity scores and a connection between those scores and certain brain waves. As in the previous study, a certain level of white noise proved the ideal background sound for creative tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So why do so many of us hate our open offices? The quiet chatter of colleagues and the gentle thrum of the HVAC &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; help us focus. The problem may be that, in our offices, we can’t stop ourselves from getting drawn into others’ conversations or from being interrupted while we’re trying to focus. Indeed, the EEG researchers found that face-to-face interactions, conversations, and other disruptions negatively affect the creative process. By contrast, a coworking space or a coffee shop provides a certain level of ambient noise while also providing freedom from interruptions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taken together, the lesson here is that the ideal space for focused work is not about freedom from noise, but about freedom from interruption. Finding a space you can hide away in, regardless of how noisy it is, may be the best strategy for making sure you get the important work done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 13:02:53 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>apress</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:image>https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2017/10/oct17-18-andrew-neel-unsplash-218073.jpg</og:image>
<og:url>https://hbr.org/2017/10/why-you-can-focus-in-a-coffee-shop-but-not-in-your-open-office</og:url>
<og:description>Research suggests the problem isn’t the noise, but the interruptions.</og:description>
<og:title>Why You Can Focus in a Coffee Shop but Not in Your Open Office</og:title>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://hbr.org/2017/10/why-you-can-focus-in-a-coffee-shop-but-not-in-your-open-office</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>It Takes Just $1k to Track Someone&amp;#039;s Location with Mobile Ads</title>
<link>https://www.wired.com/story/track-location-with-mobile-ads-1000-dollars-study</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.wired.com/story/track-location-with-mobile-ads-1000-dollars-study</guid>
<description>&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;247&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lede&quot; data-reactid=&quot;248&quot;&gt;When you consider&lt;/span&gt; the nagging privacy risks of online advertising, you may find comfort in the thought of a vast, abstract company like Pepsi or Nike viewing you as just one data point among millions. What, after all, do you have to hide from Pepsi? And why should that corporate megalith care about &lt;em data-reactid=&quot;250&quot;&gt;your&lt;/em&gt; secrets out of countless potential Pepsi drinkers? But an upcoming study has dissipated that delusion. It shows that ad-targeting can not only track you at the personal, individual level but also that it doesn't take a corporation's resources to seize upon that surveillance tool—just time, determination, and about a thousand dollars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;252&quot;&gt;A team of security-focused researchers from the University of Washington has demonstrated just how deeply even someone with modest resources can exploit mobile advertising networks. An advertising-savvy spy, they've shown, can spend just a grand to track a target's location with disturbing precision, learn details about them like their demographics and what apps they have installed on their phone, or correlate that information to make even more sensitive discoveries—say, that a certain twentysomething man has a gay dating app installed on his phone and lives at a certain address, that someone sitting next to the spy at a Starbucks took a certain route after leaving the coffee shop, or that a spy's spouse has visited a particular friend's home or business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;253&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;em data-reactid=&quot;255&quot;&gt;Regular people&lt;/em&gt;, not just impersonal, commercially motivated merchants or advertising networks, can exploit the online advertising ecosystem to extract private information about &lt;em data-reactid=&quot;257&quot;&gt;other people&lt;/em&gt;, such as people that they know or that live nearby,&quot; reads the &lt;a href=&quot;https://adint.cs.washington.edu/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-reactid=&quot;259&quot;&gt;study, titled &quot;Using Ad Targeting for Surveillance on a Budget,&quot;&lt;/a&gt; which will be presented at the Workshop on Privacy in the Electronic Society in Dallas later this month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;261&quot;&gt;The University of Washington researchers didn't exploit a bug or loophole in mobile advertising networks so much as reimagine the motivation and resources of an ad buyer to show how those networks' intentional tracking features allow relatively cheap, highly targeted spying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One test subject's commute across Seattle that the researchers tracked with ads in the app Talkatone. The dotted lines show the subject's real path, while the red dots show where the ads were delivered to the subject's phone to reveal his or her workplace, bus stop, home and local coffee shop. (The subject's actual home location has been somewhat obscured for privacy.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;cite class=&quot;caption-component__credit&quot; data-reactid=&quot;268&quot;&gt;University of Washington&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;269&quot;&gt;&quot;If you want to make the point that advertising networks should be more concerned with privacy, the bogeyman you usually pull out is that big corporations know so much about you. But people don't really care about that,&quot; says University of Washington researcher Paul Vines. &quot;But the potential person using this information isn't some large corporation motivated by profits and constrained by potential lawsuits. It can be a person with relatively small amounts of money and very different motives.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;272&quot;&gt;The research team used 10 Moto G Android phones for testing, a mobile banner ad they created, and a website that served as the landing page if someone clicked on the ad. Then they spent the minimum $1,000 deposit to place orders with a so-called demand-side platform—think Facebook, Google AdWords, MediaMath, Centro, Simpli.fi, and others—that allows ad buyers to specify criteria like where their ad appears, for which unique phone identifiers, and in which apps. (They declined to reveal which specific DSP they tested, arguing that nothing about that platform was more intrusive than many others in the industry.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;273&quot;&gt;They then used that DSP to place a geographic grid of location-targeted ad buys around a 3-mile-square section of Seattle, which for their tests they set to appear on the popular ad-supported calling and texting app Talkatone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;274&quot;&gt;Every time a target phone had Talkatone open near one of the coordinates the researchers had set on their grid of ad buys, the ad would appear on it, the researchers would be charged 2 cents, and they'd receive confirmation from the DSP of approximately where, when, and on which phone the ad had been shown. With that method, they they were able to follow their test phones' locations within a range of about 25 feet any time the phone user left an app open in one location for about 4 minutes or opened it twice in the same location during that time span. They registered just a 6-minute delay in the ad network's real-time reporting of the phone's location. Following a human test subject carrying each test phone over seven days, they were able to easily identify the person's home and work address, based on where their target stopped. (See the map above.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;277&quot;&gt;&quot;You’re using whether or not your ad gets served as an oracle to tell you whether or not an event happened: that this particular device was at this location,&quot; Vines says. They note that the DSP they used never flagged their behavior as unusual or cut off their account for attempting targeted surveillance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;278&quot;&gt;That tracking method has a couple of serious limitations. The target would have to have a certain app open on their phone at the time they're being tracked, so that the ad can appear. And to track a specific phone, any ad-buying spy would have to know a unique identifier of the target phone, known as a mobile advertising ID, or MAID.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;279&quot;&gt;But to get around the first of those limitations, a spy could buy ads against a range of popular apps in the hope that one of them would show the ad. And for the second, the researchers suggest a variety of ways to obtain that MAID, including placing an &quot;active-content&quot; ad that uses javascript to pull the MAID from a phone at a certain location, then use that identifier to continue to track the phone with normal ads. Perhaps more simply, they point out, MAIDs can also be intercepted by someone on the same Wi-Fi network as the target phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;280&quot;&gt;&quot;It’s not a particularly high bar to entry for a very, very highly targeted attack,&quot; says Adam Lee, a professor at the University of Pittsburgh who reviewed the University of Washington study.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;inset-left-component inset-left-component--pullquote&quot; data-reactid=&quot;283&quot; readability=&quot;9.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;inset-left&quot; class=&quot;inset-left-component__el&quot; data-reactid=&quot;284&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;285&quot;&gt;'It’s not a particularly high bar to entry for a very, very highly targeted attack.'&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;inset-left&quot; class=&quot;inset-left-component__el&quot; data-reactid=&quot;286&quot;&gt;Adam Lee, University of Pittsburgh&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;287&quot;&gt;A domestic abuser could, for instance, obtain a spouse's MAID from their home network, and then use it to closely track him or her by placing ads in apps he or she uses frequently. A person on a laptop at a nearby table at Starbucks could steal your MAID when you connect your phone to Wi-Fi, or a coworker could do the same in the office, and then either could receive periodic pings of your location whenever you see an ad they've placed. Or an ad buyer could use active-content ads to gather the MAIDs of the people at a specific location, like a protest, or users of a potentially sensitive app like gay-dating apps or religious apps—plus other demographics provided by ad networks—and then track those targets' movements. (The researchers found that their DSP did in fact allow them to place location-based ads on the most popular gay-hookup app, Grindr, though they didn't test whether it implemented other protections to prevent continuous location tracking of users. Grindr didn't immediately respond to WIRED's request for comment on the researchers' work.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;288&quot;&gt;Even without obtaining a MAID, some broader spying remains possible. The researchers say they were able to count the number of people with the Grindr app or the Muslim-focused app Quran Reciter installed at a target location without knowing any unique identifiers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;289&quot;&gt;There's no simple fix for the targeted surveillance that mobile ad networks enable, the Washington researchers say, without reducing ad networks' fine-grained tracking ability in general. But they hope that their findings will at least draw attention to the surveillance capabilities of ad networks, beyond the amorphous notion of companies gathering data about users en masse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;290&quot;&gt;&quot;This is so easy and it's industrywide,&quot; says Tadayoshi Kohno, a computer science professor at the University of Washington who worked on the study. &quot;We want to enable a broader conversation about the risks of online advertising when &lt;em data-reactid=&quot;292&quot;&gt;anyone&lt;/em&gt; can become the adversary.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;294&quot;&gt;DSPs could, perhaps, attempt to detect and block advertising that's targeted at the individual level or that seems designed specifically to track a particular user. More ad networks need to collect MAIDs over encrypted connections, protecting them from interception, they say. And more experimental tools like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/2016/06/apples-differential-privacy-collecting-data/&quot; data-reactid=&quot;296&quot;&gt;differential privacy&lt;/a&gt; could make it possible to collect data from large groups of users while masking the sensitive details of any one person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;298&quot;&gt;And in the meantime, for users who'd rather not become a target of that individualized ad-spying? Perhaps consider which ad-supported apps you use, when you use them, and what they reveal about you. It may be worthwhile to pay for the premium version of that gay-hookup app rather than allow it to be populated with ads that can potentially track your sexual orientation &lt;em data-reactid=&quot;300&quot;&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; location. Every ad that you see on your smartphone, after all, can in some sense see you too—and so can the unknown entity that paid for it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 12:33:23 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>AndrewDucker</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>It Takes Just $1,000 to Track Someone's Location With Mobile Ads</og:title>
<og:description>University of Washington researchers have shown just how cheaply spies can exploit ad networks for fine-grained, individualized surveillance.</og:description>
<og:image>https://media.wired.com/photos/59e69fb7f572231fe56c38ef/191:100/pass/TrackerAds-FeatureArt.jpg</og:image>
<og:url>https://www.wired.com/story/track-location-with-mobile-ads-1000-dollars-study/</og:url>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.wired.com/story/track-location-with-mobile-ads-1000-dollars-study</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Napa.js: A multi-threaded JavaScript runtime</title>
<link>https://github.com/Microsoft/napajs</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/Microsoft/napajs</guid>
<description>&lt;h3&gt;README.md&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;markdown-body entry-content&quot; itemprop=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://travis-ci.org/Microsoft/napajs&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/3d1754084d3414d75ce69ead4492f63eb25b203c/68747470733a2f2f7472617669732d63692e6f72672f4d6963726f736f66742f6e6170616a732e7376673f6272616e63683d6d6173746572&quot; alt=&quot;Build Status for Linux/MacOS&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://travis-ci.org/Microsoft/napajs.svg?branch=master&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://ci.appveyor.com/project/napajs/napajs&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/3116baa5de0fa01f9a9f88b754a90e0da2ec6cd5/68747470733a2f2f63692e6170707665796f722e636f6d2f6170692f70726f6a656374732f7374617475732f6769746875622f4d6963726f736f66742f6e6170616a733f6272616e63683d6d6173746572267376673d74727565&quot; alt=&quot;Build Status for Windows&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://ci.appveyor.com/api/projects/status/github/Microsoft/napajs?branch=master&amp;amp;svg=true&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npmjs.com/package/napajs&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/f4d28049d0750c9f4d8a974b90585fca9b45ab67/68747470733a2f2f62616467652e667572792e696f2f6a732f6e6170616a732e737667&quot; alt=&quot;npm version&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://badge.fury.io/js/napajs.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npmjs.com/package/napajs&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/5dce060ec79a5516b06a739c5046df129c3da761/68747470733a2f2f696d672e736869656c64732e696f2f6e706d2f646d2f6e6170616a732e737667&quot; alt=&quot;Downloads&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/npm/dm/napajs.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Napa.js is a multi-threaded JavaScript runtime built on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/v8/v8&quot;&gt;V8&lt;/a&gt;, which was originally designed to develop highly iterative services with non-compromised performance in Bing. As it evolves, we find it useful to complement &lt;a href=&quot;https://nodejs.org&quot;&gt;Node.js&lt;/a&gt; in CPU-bound tasks, with the capability of executing JavaScript in multiple V8 isolates and communicating between them. Napa.js is exposed as a Node.js module, while it can also be embedded in a host process without Node.js dependency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Install the latest stable version:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;npm install napajs
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other options can be found in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Microsoft/napajs/wiki/build-napa.js&quot;&gt;Build Napa.js&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Quick Start&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-js&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; napa &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;require&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;napajs&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;);
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; zone1 &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;napa&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;zone&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;create&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;zone1&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, { workers&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;} );

&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;//&lt;/span&gt; Broadcast code to all 4 workers in 'zone1'.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;zone1&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;broadcast&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;console.log(&quot;hello world&quot;);&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;);

&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;//&lt;/span&gt; Execute an anonymous function in any worker thread in 'zone1'.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;zone1&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;execute&lt;/span&gt;(
    (&lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;text&lt;/span&gt;) &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; {
        &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; text;
    }, 
    [&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;hello napa&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;])
    .&lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;then&lt;/span&gt;((&lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;result&lt;/span&gt;) &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; {
        &lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;console&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;log&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;result&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;value&lt;/span&gt;);
    });
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More examples:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Multi-threaded JavaScript runtime&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Node.js compatible module architecture with NPM support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;API for object transportation, object sharing and synchronization across JavaScript threads&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;API for pluggable logging, metric and memory allocator&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Distributed as a Node.js module, as well as supporting embed scenarios&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Documentation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can contribute to Napa.js in following ways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project has adopted the &lt;a href=&quot;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/&quot;&gt;Microsoft Open Source Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;. For more information see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/faq/&quot;&gt;Code of Conduct FAQ&lt;/a&gt; or contact &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:opencode@microsoft.com&quot;&gt;opencode@microsoft.com&lt;/a&gt; with any additional questions or comments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/article&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 11:27:38 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>rimher</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars2.githubusercontent.com/u/6154722?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>Microsoft/napajs</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/Microsoft/napajs</og:url>
<og:description>napajs - Napa.js: a multi-threaded JavaScript runtime</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/Microsoft/napajs</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Selling My Bootstrapped SaaS Business</title>
<link>https://www.indiehackers.com/@tylertringas/selling-my-bootstrapped-saas-business-26c8406e1d</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.indiehackers.com/@tylertringas/selling-my-bootstrapped-saas-business-26c8406e1d</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;medium-insert-images medium-insert-images-full&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://storage.googleapis.com/indie-hackers.appspot.com/articles/1N9ZPzh8xNWZ3qGHXaPBWv2kDIJ3/@tylertringas%7C26c8406e1d/map-desk-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Five years ago I built and launched the first version of a SaaS app on a single flight from San Francisco to Buenos Aires. Slowly and steadily, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.storemapper.co/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Storemapper&lt;/a&gt; grew into a healthy location-independent business for one person and then later a small dedicated remote team. At parties, I would describe it as, “not a startup; a healthy growing internet small business.” This year, almost exactly five years after launching, I sold the business for what, to someone growing up middle class in Florida, is a life-changing amount of money that will enable all kinds of exciting new projects and adventures. From start to finish, it has been an exciting ride. With the sale concluded, I wanted to share as much as I could about the process of building a business that can be sold and how I sold it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s always a risk that these posts turn into a 5,000-word humblebrag. But I really do think it’s worth a read because, unlike most business acquisition stories, which often feel like an out of the blue stroke of good luck, the way that I sold Storemapper feels very replicable for other entrepreneurs. When I spoke to someone two years ago about what it would look like if I ever sold the business I would say, “I’m not trying to sell it now, but if I ever did it would probably look this…” And six months ago I would tell a few folks privately, “I think that one of the people I met recently might be the one to buy Storemapper and if they do it will probably go like this…” And, then basically when it all went down it looked more or less like… that. There wasn’t some single huge stroke of good luck, though of course, I got lucky in the little ways that every successful business has to. An excellent outcome, but also a perfectly reasonable and achievable one that I think can serve as something of a template for other bootstrapped entrepreneurs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a long and detailed post. I had so many questions going&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;First the obvious: why sell your software business?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The past two years of my life have been pretty amazing due in no small part to owning my own SaaS business. Two years ago, my girlfriend and I set off on a year backpacking around the world: driving the coasts of Croatia, South Africa, and New Zealand; going on safari in the Serengeti and practicing yoga in Bali; diving in Fiji and soaking up the Mediterranean lifestyle in an apartment in Barcelona. Throughout the process, thanks primarily to an awesome remote team, Storemapper was able to keep running and growing even as I took long stretches of time off the grid (hiking Mt. Kilimanjaro or rock climbing in El Potrero Chico). Last year we moved back to Washington, DC and I felt like I was living the dream: being able to afford to live in a world-class city while still maintaining complete control over my time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did warn you this might come out humble-braggy. But it’s important to highlight that none of the normal pressures to sell a business were present. I wasn’t burned out, on the contrary life was pretty good and running Storemapper only took about 10 hours per week of my time and attention. I wasn’t crunched for cash; Storemapper was profitable and I was saving away the bulk of the profits each month. So in light of that, why sell the business? Here was my thought process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Running the numbers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From a purely financial perspective, owning your own stable, profitable SaaS business is incredible. Unlike the wild seasonal swings of running an e-commerce store or the feast-or-famine revenues of selling books or info-products, once you have a reasonably large SaaS customer base you tend to have predictable revenues, stable costs and a low risk of any of that changing dramatically month to month. Say the business is already profitable and in one month you add $1,000 in new monthly subscribers. You keep that $1,000. You can have a reasonable expectation that next month you will also get most of that $1,000 and so on for the foreseeable future. On top of that, the value of your SaaS business is a multiple of that number so that extra $1,000 in subscriptions may have added $36,000 or more to the total value of your business. If your business is solid and predictable and you “run the numbers” on selling &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; month versus six months from now you will typically arrive at the conclusion that you could keep the business, pocket the six months of extra profit &lt;em&gt;and then&lt;/em&gt; sell the business for &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; than you could this month. Essentially the very positive math of operating SaaS will never lead you to conclude that you should sell your business just yet. A spreadsheet will almost always tell you to hold the SaaS and reconsider selling it in six months and it will generally be correct.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unless of course, it all blows up somewhere in those six months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that’s the key consideration. When you estimate “how will my SaaS business be doing in 6-12 months” the answer is very bi-modal. There’s a very very large chance that it’s doing a bit better and a very small but non-zero chance the whole thing blows up in some unforeseen way. At least that was my estimate at the time and that’s why a key financial decision for me to sell the business was diversification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Diversification and peace of mind&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an entrepreneur, the risks and rewards of your financial future are extremely concentrated. In my case, as Storemapper succeeded I had slowly wound down freelancing and other sources of income so that I was 100% reliant on Storemapper revenues for income. There wasn’t a lot to complain about there. Business was good and I was still saving much of what I made from Storemapper, which is more than I can say for the last paycheck I ever had. But I sat down and did a detailed visualization of what it would be like for some &lt;em&gt;black swan&lt;/em&gt; event to force me to completely shut down Storemapper. Even though it seemed extremely unlikely I found that my loss aversion was pretty high. I’d been working on Storemapper for five years and I really wanted to lock in a solid win. One of the most important skills for a poker player is knowing when to end a big run and take chips off the table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leaving aside a “strategic acquisition offer” for ludicrous amounts of money (more on that later), most of the time the financial spreadsheet of selling your business doesn’t add up to a convincing case to sell. Almost everyone will end up selling for non-financial reasons like getting burned out or bored, badly needing the money or a million other reasons other than “I did the math.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diversification felt like one of the better reasons to sell a business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I felt at the time that the benefits of diversification, reducing my overall risk, outweighed the opportunity cost of the potential money I could earn by continuing to run the business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But okay, this is getting a bit boring…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Momentum for other projects&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diversification was honestly just the line of thinking that allowed me to rationalize selling Storemapper. The real driver was largely non-financial. I have often pointed out that Storemapper was a means to an end, not necessarily a passion project. I have always said that I did not want my legacy to be the King of Store Locators. Building Storemapper was a way for me to learn a ton about building and running a business and a way to achieve financial freedom. That’s not meant as an insult by the way. Crafting a great product that works well and makes customers happy can be extremely fulfilling. But I felt it was important, to be honest with myself about what my motivations were and over time, once Storemapper became financially successful, those motivations changed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As soon as Storemapper reached a point of providing me a full-time income I began optimizing to reduce my time requirements, rather than trying to maximize revenue and growth. I started looking for another project a bit further up the hierarchy of needs. A little over a year ago I found it and started working part-time with the team at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.maptia.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Maptia&lt;/a&gt;. After working with the team for nearly a year, while still running Storemapper, &lt;a href=&quot;https://tylertringas.com/joining-maptia/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;I knew&lt;/a&gt; Maptia was where I wanted to really put my focus and energy. Even though Storemapper was as close to a Four Hour Work Week business as I think is really feasible, it still takes up quite a bit of your background thought processes and mental bandwidth. I never seriously considered selling Storemapper until I had some next thing that I knew I wanted to throw myself into. I think Derek Sivers calls this the &lt;a href=&quot;https://sivers.org/tarzan&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Tarzan approach&lt;/a&gt; of waiting until you grab hold of the next “vine” before you let go of the last one. I’m not sure I would have gone through with the deal if I didn’t have a clue what the next thing would be, but the prospect of really building momentum for projects that I wanted to invest more time and energy into was the main reason for selling the business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s why earlier this year, after five years of telling people flatly “No” when they asked if I would sell Storemapper, I started to become open to the idea. Ultimately the prospect of shifting my whole focus and energy into new projects was what motivated me to close the deal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m also finding that the increased bandwidth, and of course the cash, from selling the business has built momentum for other projects like &lt;a href=&quot;https://tylertringas.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;my blog&lt;/a&gt;, angel investing, which I will probably dabble in once I formulate a real strategy for it, and a few other ideas kicking around. Having a finite chunk of money and no income, rather than an open-ended income stream, has been a surprisingly good kick in the butt to start some more ambitious projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;So, let’s talk about the actual process&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of people wanted to know about the actual nuts and bolts of selling a business so here are a few FAQs. The answers are, um, a little on the dry side so if you’re not fascinated by the nitty-gritty of how to execute a sale, skip to the next section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How did you find the buyer, or did they find you?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being &lt;a href=&quot;https://tylertringas.com/storemapper/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;transparent&lt;/a&gt; and making the business visible by blogging, tweeting and podcasting, brought a number of potential buyers to my inbox. I would estimate at least 50-75 people have emailed me over five years. A good chunk emailed in response to a single post on the NYC Ruby Meetup group, entitled “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.meetup.com/NYC-rb/messages/57549452/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;UnSexy, Profitable SaaS business for sale or partner&lt;/a&gt;,” where I briefly considered selling the business about a year after it launched. I’ve been amazed at how years later that single post continued to generate random inbound interest. Initially, I took quite a number of calls, primarily out of curiosity and a huge number of those inquiries were complete wastes of time. There is a large pool of buyers out there scanning the web looking for distressed or under-valued properties trying to pick up things for a steal. If I wanted to sell Storemapper for 6x &lt;em&gt;monthly&lt;/em&gt; profits I could have had 20 offers in a day. But most inquiries were not serious buyers willing to pay a reasonable multiple for a profitable SaaS business. A few offers during that stretch were legitimate and I almost considered selling, but then I ran the numbers and decided to keep the business. Good thing too since the business grew by more than 20x in the next four years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;medium-insert-images medium-insert-images-inline&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://tylertringas.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/Screenshot-2017-09-29-11.02.02-768x733.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;https://tylertringas.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/Screenshot-2017-09-29-11.02.02-768x733.png 768w, https://tylertringas.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/Screenshot-2017-09-29-11.02.02-300x286.png 300w, https://tylertringas.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/Screenshot-2017-09-29-11.02.02-1024x977.png 1024w, https://tylertringas.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/Screenshot-2017-09-29-11.02.02.png 1582w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 768px) 100vw, 768px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I kid you not this post, by uh “user 1.”, brought in at least 30 pretty serious inquiries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In March of this year, I went to my first &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.microconf.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;MicroConf&lt;/a&gt;, a conference dedicated to bootstrapped software businesses, which is where I met Kevin from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sureswiftcapital.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;SureSwift Capital&lt;/a&gt;. In the follow-up to MicroConf I had discussions with three serious potential buyers and, somewhat by coincidence, I was connected with two more potential buyers around the same time. These were either individuals that I knew I had sold businesses before or who had raised a fund dedicated to buying businesses like mine. Serious buyers, not just someone poking around looking for something on the cheap. Over the subsequent months, I made a concerted effort to schedule calls and keep each one of the discussions moving forward at roughly the same pace. Two of the discussions pretty quickly concluded as not viable but the other three progressed to either a verbal offer or a letter of intent (more on that below) and one became the deal with SureSwift that concluded about five months after initially meeting Kevin at MicroConf.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How did the initial discussion go? What did you disclose?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While none of them lead to a deal, taking those calls from early inquiries in 2013 was helpful to me in understanding the kinds of questions a potential buyer might ask and help me to think through what I would and wouldn’t like to disclose on an initial call. Some people might play this process very close their chest, asking a potential buyer to sign an NDA and only disclosing the bare minimum information. I had already taken the path of disclosing a huge amount of Storemapper’s financial info, even going so far as to post a live public dashboard with figures like revenue growth, churn and customer lifetime value. So I didn’t really have much to hide. This simplified the process substantially. In an initial call, I was able to summarize the publicly available info and give an overview of our costs and profitability (which were not public) which is more than enough for a buyer to make an initial assessment of whether they are seriously interested and even to discuss preliminary pricing for a deal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How did you discuss pricing?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you ask around at conferences or find the right blog posts you’ll learn about a metric called Seller Discretionary Earnings (SDE) or Seller Discretionary Income (SDI). I first heard these terms from Thomas Smale, who runs a brokerage focusing on bootstrapped businesses like mine. Essentially it is the profitability of the business, but adding back in things like the owner’s salary and various other expenses that make sense (from a tax perspective) to charge to the business but that wouldn’t be a cost the new owner would be obliged to pay. Most discussions of pricing are framed as a combination of two components: the SDE and the multiple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simple example: the business has a top line revenue of $200k. After operating costs like employees, your email marketing software and other SaaS you use for the business and servers, you’re left with $90k. You add another $20k of expenses to your business like your cell phone bill, your annual Macbook Pro upgrade and so on, then you pay yourself the remaining $70k as a salary. Your SDE would be the $90k and a reasonable valuation of the business would be some multiple of that $90k.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the default approach for discussing pricing is to agree on the business’s SDE and then haggle over the multiple. This approach seems sensible, and it probably works well if you are working with a broker with a very rigorous and well-tested methodology for what does and doesn’t count for SDE, but I really did not like it as a communication tool. The problem is that is can still be very difficult to pin down all the edges cases that affect SDE. For example, an SDE is an annual number, spanning 12 months… but which 12 months? Is it the previous (or “trailing”) 12 months? But a fast-growing business that added 50% of its customers in the last quarter and a totally flat-lined business could have the same trailing twelve months SDE, while the former would clearly be much more valuable. What if a deal takes 6 months to close, which is not uncommon, does the SDE update every month automatically or is it frozen at some point in negotiations? Why not use a forward-looking 12 months? When fellow founders ask “what’s the MRR of your business?” we are usually referring to the current level of subscriptions, but current MRR isn’t something that shows up in the historical bookkeeping; you have to calculate it across all your current subscribers. If you’re looking forward do you factor in churn? What about expected growth? Is it a 12-month forecast (what you really expect to happen) or a 12-month pro forma (current customers minus churn plus expansion MRR)? What expenses really are excluded from SDE? Does that $6,000 marketing experiment you ran 11 months ago and then abandoned count against you? Should you wait 2 months until it gets pushed out of the trailing 12 months metric? And so on, and so on…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much like when you are pitching a client on how many “hours” a project will take, the multiple is just a polite proxy for what both parties are really thinking about: the actual amount of money being exchanged. Once I started taking the idea of selling the business very seriously I explained why I felt the “multiple” discussion was a problematic proxy and just moved to speaking in whole dollar amounts. If we close in the next X months, my price is Y. I recommend this approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the day, the valuation of a business is where the buyer’s willingness to pay and the seller’s willingness to sell overlap. The SDE + Multiple framing is just a way to attempt to simplify communication, but I think just speaking in whole dollar amounts is more direct and sensible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So how does the process actually kick off?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my case, I had a few preliminary calls with buyers. I was very transparent about the business since I already had nothing to hide. In the initial calls, we didn’t explicitly discuss a sale price, although we did allude to a range of multiples just to make sure we were on the same general page about deal size.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For my part, I was also interviewing each potential buyer about the non-monetary factors. Most importantly, what did they plan to do with the business and would there be opportunities for my team? But also making sure they seemed technically competent so that the handover wouldn’t become a giant headache. I asked a few of them for references that I could speak to from people they had worked with or other companies they had acquired. It’s a perfectly reasonable request and is immensely helpful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you generally feel that this could be a serious buyer, the next step is for the buyer to prepare a &lt;em&gt;letter of intent&lt;/em&gt; (LOI). An LOI is a legal document with no legal weight whatsoever… or at least that is my perspective, I am not a lawyer. The goal of it is for the buyer to start to put some details in writing about what they are willing to offer for the business and to lay out the terms of how you will approach &lt;em&gt;due diligence&lt;/em&gt;. Due diligence is the process where the buyer really starts to dig into the details of the company and it will vary enormously from buyer to buyer. In the LOI you will typically describe the timeline for due diligence and the buyer may ask for a period of exclusivity, say 30-60 days, in which they will conduct due diligence and you will agree not to talk to other buyers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You do not have to agree to exclusivity.&lt;/em&gt; As soon as you get an LOI from a serious buyer you can and should immediately begin looking for another buyer. Having a strong backup buyer is the absolute best way to ensure you get a good deal and have a strong negotiating position all the way to the end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the LOI and through due diligence you are still mostly operating on good faith. Nobody has any legal obligation to buy or sell and both parties can still walk away or radically change the deal terms. But once due diligence is over, the next step is the important one. After due diligence is when you will start preparing the final documents that are actually legally binding. In Storemapper’s case, it was an &lt;em&gt;asset purchase agreement&lt;/em&gt; where I agreed to sell all of the operating assets to SureSwift Capital. Tax and legal considerations will determine whether the buyer wants to acquire the entire corporate entity (LLC, corporation, etc) or just the assets, but an asset sale seems to be by far the most common. So in my case after the sale, I was left still owning the empty shell of an LLC and bank accounts associated with Storemapper. Which is totally fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This document is the legally binding one where you want to make sure you get all the tax and legal advice you need before signing. Then you sign it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do you actually conclude the sale?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is by far the most common question I’ve gotten but it has a pretty simple answer. The asset purchase agreement will more or less lay out the terms. You will use an &lt;em&gt;escrow agent&lt;/em&gt;, a law firm or dedicated escrow firm. Both the buyer and seller sign a simple document with the escrow agent who then accepts a wire transfer from the buyer. The escrow agent then confirms to you that they have the money in their account and you start a pre-defined process of handing over control of the assets of the business. Once things like the domain, the servers, and various passwords are handed over, the buyer has a short period of time to review them and make sure you haven’t been completely misleading them. Then they give the escrow agent the thumbs up, and the escrow agent releases the money to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then you have sold your business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our case, this process was incredibly smooth for two reasons. First, SureSwift has acquired a number of businesses already and provided a very comprehensive list of things to prepare for the day of, much of which I would not have thought of on my own. Second, at Storemapper we often use platforms rather than hand-crafting our own solutions. For example, handing over control of the app was a matter of two clicks on Heroku, but it would be a different story if Storemapper was running on some artisanal private server co-located with every other software project I’d ever started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Did you use a broker?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end, I did not. I know several entrepreneurs who used brokers and recommend it highly. I have met a few brokers in this space who seem very smart and who I really considered working with. Here’s the main reason why you might not want to use a broker and why I ultimately didn’t. I was an opportunistic seller, not a motivated one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brokers will argue that they are totally aligned with your interest because their fee is a percentage of the deal size, so they are incentivized to get you the best deal possible. On a single deal basis that is true, but on an organizational level, a brokerage is not incentivized to get each client the absolute best possible deal they can. They are incentivized to create maximum liquidity in the marketplace. As an organization, they will earn far more if every deal takes half as long, so they do twice as many deals than if they take an unlimited amount of time and get every client a (let’s say hypothetically) 30% better offer. As a seller that 30% could be a massive difference but for the broker it’s better to just get more deals done. I’m not saying any of them would be deceptive or deny this, just that brokers are much better suited for motivated sellers who definitely want to get the business sold in a reasonable timeframe. I’ll go into this later, but my whole strategy for selling the business was to put myself in a position where I &lt;em&gt;didn’t have&lt;/em&gt; to sell; where I would be perfectly happy to run the business myself for another year or five years if the deal wasn’t exactly what I wanted. This is not a good client for a broker and a good broker will tell you as much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want a reasonable deal on a reasonable timeline, get a broker. If you want a phenomenal deal, you may &lt;em&gt;still&lt;/em&gt; want a broker if you feel like having someone walk you through the process is worth the fee. But I did not use one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So do you just walk away as soon as the deal closes?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, almost all deals like this have a transition period where you are still involved with the business and slowly handover all the responsibilities to the buyer’s team. 3-6 months seems to be pretty normal. In my case, the first 30 days or so after the sale were exactly the same as the previous 30 days, where I was still managing the day to day as I had before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How I chose SureSwift&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had never heard of SureSwift Capital until I met Kevin at MicroConf in Las Vegas, but they ended up being the ideal acquirer for Storemapper. I’ll walk through the reasons I chose them, not because I’m contractually obligated to compliment them now, but because I think the reasoning, which goes beyond just the price of the deal, is pretty broadly applicable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;A very important feature, in some regards, simply because it’s somewhat rare in the bootstrapped or Micro-SaaS market, is that SureSwift is a long-term player. They have raised a fund to go out and acquire lots of bootstrapped profitable businesses like mine. They had closed on quite a few deals before buying Storemapper and I knew they intended to close on many more after. This means they have reputational skin in the game. Throughout the process I could talk to founders they have acquired businesses from before and I knew that if they tried to completely screw me over, then they wouldn’t be able to acquire more businesses in the future. This is a huge point of differentiation from a solo buyer, using their own money, who might only acquire one business per decade and not be that concerned about their reputation. SureSwift needs to maintain an impeccable reputation in the market or else they would not be able to deploy the capital they raised. As a first time seller there is a constant feeling of being at an informational disadvantage and having someone with long-term skin in the game really helps balance that fear.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It was a great opportunity for the Storemapper team. A big part of Storemapper’s enterprise value was that the small and awesome team mostly ran it entirely on their own. It was important to me that after an acquisition they would have lots of opportunities and also not be pressured into making drastic changes. SureSwift offered exactly that. They manage a portfolio of software businesses and were equally happy to have the employees stay exactly in their current roles at Storemapper or to expand their roles across the portfolio. It’s hard to overstate how important those assurances have been for a smooth closing and transition.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They had a competent team in place to accept the business. Throughout the acquisition process I also made sure to counter-interview the buyers to try to find out how well they would likely manage the handover. Were they used to working with highly remote/distributed teams? Did they have people in place who understood the tech stack we used? Even if they made a higher offer I really was not interested in selling Storemapper to an organization with a CTO who only codes in .NET and who wants to get everybody on the phone every other day for a two hour check-in.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lastly, they had similar priorities on what was and wasn’t important in the transaction. A classic move from a potential buyer, that I’ve experienced in other businesses, is to make all kinds of assurances about how interested they are very early on in the discussion and then at the very end of the deal process the lawyers and accountants dig in with a million nit-picky irrelevant quibbles; then they come back with a ridiculous low ball offer. This was &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; how SureSwift operated. I more or less asked this point blank and then verified by speaking to other founders that had been through the process with them, that they really did focus on the key important metrics and didn’t sweat the small stuff.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;What made Storemapper sell-able&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kevin from SureSwift is probably better equipped to answer precisely why it made sense for them to buy Storemapper, but I think it’s worth my taking a stab at why I think it was a sell-able business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many things that are required, being necessary but not sufficient, of a sell-able business but only one thing makes a buyer want to buy your business: they need to see an opportunity. Entrepreneurs sometimes adopt a strange language when discussing acquisitions that seems to assume that acquirers are just out there as a natural part of the world, and if they create a “good business” someone &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; want to buy it. But acquirers of all kinds are not simply walking around looking to pay full market price to take over good businesses. They need to see an opportunity. Either they need to feel they are getting a good deal on the business by paying below what it’s worth, or they need to see a pathway to the business performing much better under their ownership. The first one, deal hunters or vultures, are by far the dominant mentality of potential acquirers because it’s the easiest and simplest way to make sure an acquisition is a good investment. As a potential seller you want to sniff out quickly if someone is just poking around looking for distressed assets and move. The best reason for a business to be sell-able is for the buyer to see an opportunity for the business to flourish under their ownership and be a worthwhile investment even when paying full market value for the business; a true win-win. Here are a few examples of good reasons for a buyer to want to buy your business:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Budget dynamics&lt;/strong&gt;: there is a well known budget dynamic in large SaaS businesses that they often lose money when they grow quickly. If you spend $50 to get a customer for your $40 ebook, you’re doing it wrong. But it’s perfectly rational to spend $50 to acquire a customer who subscribes to your $10/month SaaS plan, who then stays paying for 24 months. But in this case you actually lose money in the short-term, the faster you grow the faster you rack up losses even when your business is doing great. A small bootstrapped startup might not have the budget to sustain this but a well-funded acquirer might be perfectly happy to plow money into customer acquisition, growing the enterprise value of the business quickly, even if it means short-term losses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Customer synergies:&lt;/strong&gt; an acquirer may have a product that is complementary to an overlapping customer base. They may be able to cross-sell their product to your customers and vice versa, reducing their customer acquisition costs and creating up-sell opportunities. Cross-selling and up-selling are immensely more efficient than finding completely new customers so an acquirer may see buying your business as a far more effective use of funds than burning through the same money on marketing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cost synergies:&lt;/strong&gt; less fun than the others but still common. An acquirer may have a team or overhead that allows them to run your product for much less than you currently do. This doesn’t always have to be the “chop shop” strategy where they would fire some of your employees to cut costs. For example Storemapper never got very involved in paid Facebook or Adwords ads primarily because we just weren’t big enough to justify having a full time person dedicated to managing it. A larger acquirer might be able to amortize the cost of a smart marketer across a larger business.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Core competencies:&lt;/strong&gt; businesses as they grow often require different core competencies. A very early stage business needs to be able to connect deeply with customers’ needs and iterate quickly to achieve product-market fit. A more mature business may no longer need to iterate quickly but rather scale up its existing activities. These can be completely different skillsets that different owners excel at, which can make a business sell-able under the right circumstances.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Any one of these, or hopefully several plus others I haven’t mentioned, creates the seed of an opportunity to buy/sell a business. However there are a many other factors that, in combination with an opportunity, make a business sell-able. Ultimately it is the buyers’ opinions on these that matter, but here is my take on the key factors to making your business sell-able.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;An awesome team:&lt;/strong&gt; first and foremost is building a team that can keep the business growing without you. Too often founders want to insinuate themselves into every part of the business, making the entire structure dependent on their engaged focus. Instead you want to build a team and a product that are self-sufficient without you. A buyer can’t possibly learn exactly how active you are day-to-day before a sale, so a great team gives them confidence that the whole thing won’t collapse after you walk away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Predictable, diversified revenue base:&lt;/strong&gt; the reason for being of a business is to generate revenue but not all revenue is created equal when it comes to buying and selling a business. A buyer is buying your revenue streams and different revenue streams have different degrees of risk to a buyer. Obviously customers with recurring subscriptions are more valuable than one-off purchasers. But also customers that have been paying for 30 months continuously are more valuable than a customer who subscribed last month. A customer base made up of a diverse group of “boring” businesses is better than a customer base composed entirely of fidget spinner manufacturers. $10,000 per month composed of 1,000 companies paying $10 is more robust than two companies paying $5,000. The more predictable and diversified the revenue base, the more sell-able the business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Documentation and processes:&lt;/strong&gt; basically a business needs to have its shit together to be sell-able. Buyers can to some extent be choosy and they can and should pass on buying a great business that will be a nightmare to run. Having thorough documentation and good internal processes may not really increase the value of your business per se, but not having them can be a deal-breaker to an acquirer. You want them to be impressed by how painless it will be to take over operating the business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an incomplete list but I believe some combination of all of these factors lead to Storemapper being a very sell-able business. It had an awesome team who had mostly been with the company for more than two years and who managed the day to day business without me having to be involved. The examples of me going completely offline for 10 days in Tanzania and Fiji really drove this home. It had great documentation and processes and a solid predictable, customer base with recurring low-churn revenue. It was also very easy to see how a buyer with different skillsets could invest time, money or even just more focus to really increase the already growing revenue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Lessons on how to sell a bootstrapped SaaS business&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Built-Sell-Creating-Business-Without/dp/1591845823/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1506625929&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=built+to+sell&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Built to Sell&lt;/a&gt; is an essential read for every entrepreneur. It lays out clearly and simply some of the key counter-intuitive features of selling a business versus running a business. Here are some of the most salient lessons from that book and elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Run your business to sell it, before you want to sell it&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can’t emphasize this enough. If you think you will ever want to sell your business, the time to start preparing is now. Don’t wait until you are actually ready to sell it. Making a business sell-able requires systematically making small or big decisions differently and optimizing for certain qualities in your business that can’t be bolted on last minute or even over the course of a few months. Your business will be sold on a track record, every selling point about your business will be greatly enhanced by being able to point to 48 consecutive months of that same thing. Through some combination of books and blog posts I was fortunate enough to internalize this lesson early on and acted accordingly. It turns out that creating a sell-able business is also very similar to running a lifestyle business, focusing on taking yourself out of the day to day and optimizing to recapture your time and freedom. The process of removing yourself from a business is also a big part of making that business sell-able.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Focus on financial, not strategic acquirers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First let’s differentiate between the two broad categories of potential buyers of a business: strategic and financial acquirers. A strategic acquisition is the kind you hear most about in the news: Facebook buying Instagram, Google buying Nest. Strategic acquisitions can be driven by a variety of motivations such as buying a competitor before they grow too large or a proprietary piece of intellectual property. The reasons can be varied but the common thread is that the actual finances of the business are a secondary concern. In a strategic acquisition, businesses can be purchased&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s the definitional difference but here is the key difference between the two kinds of acquisitions: a strategic acquisition is mostly about getting lucky whereas a financial acquisition can be engineered by a founder. In both instances you have to run a great company, but beyond that there isn’t much you can do to increase your odds of a bolt from the blue strategic acquisition offer for 25x times your revenue. But you can structure your business in such a way that it is highly attractive to financial acquirers and greatly increase your odds of a successful transaction. Learn what makes a successful financial acquisition from this post and elsewhere. Get a sense of what the very high end of a financial acquisition might look like and shoot for that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Acquisition offers are a hidden benefit of radical transparency&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I joined the radical transparency train after being inspired by and learning a ton from the founders of Buffer, Baremetrics, Keen, Patrick McKenzie and many more. I felt at the time that being transparent even with the financial metrics of the business added an appropriate level of credibility and was helpful to readers. Over time, as copycat apps started popping up, I began to question whether being so transparent was really a good idea, although they never made a material dent in the business. However being public about the numbers behind Storemapper certainly increased the number of acquisition inquiries I received over the years. People knew the revenue and growth and could immediately tell whether Storemapper was roughly in the range of businesses they were looking for. Between that and reading my transparent blogging about the strategy and challenges, we only needed to briefly discuss the costs and profitability before they would have enough information to credibly make an initial offer. This hugely accelerated the speed at which I could have acquisition discussions. Having multiple buyers involved at the same time really helped me feel confident to press forward with the deal. In the end transparency definitely was a big net benefit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Go to conferences&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one is pretty self-explanatory but despite all the blogging and sporadic inbound interest in Storemapper, I only reached a critical mass of serious acquisition offers after attending my first Micro-Conf in Las Vegas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How to get the best deal possible&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously I have only sold one business, so this isn’t some proven methodology for selling businesses that I’ve honed over years. But, I’m synthesizing advise I got from other founders and that I felt generally worked well for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be an opportunistic seller&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The absolute most important factor in getting a great deal in a sale is not &lt;em&gt;having&lt;/em&gt; to sell. All of the work here happens well before the sale. Craft your business in a way that you would be perfectly happy to run it indefinitely. Get your work/life balance in order and your stress level under control. Go into a sale process with the idea that if you don’t get exactly the offer you want, you are 100% willing to just wait it out and run your business for another year. Running yourself into the ground, getting burned out or bored of your business, or falling into a cash crunch, or any other situation where you really &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt; to sell the business is an excellent way to get lured into accepting a low-ball offer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be aggressive and ready to walk&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not having to sell allows you adopt an aggressive ‘take it or leave it’ attitude to a sale negotiation. You want to be extremely polite, nobody wants to buy a business from a jerk, but continually remind the buyer, “look if we’re not on the same page here, no big deal, let’s just save each other some time and move on.” Smart buyers can sense if you are a really motivated seller and can use all kinds of tactics, waiting until the last minute of negotiations when you have already invested a lot of time and energy into the deal, to try to gain last minute leverage. The sale process can be long and grueling. With every hour you spend working on a deal, your brain starts to become more and more committed to getting the deal done. You start envisioning your life post-sale before it closes. But, that is a sunk cost fallacy. Throughout the process I repeatedly made myself sit down and visualize the process of walking away from the whole deal if necessary and that gave me the confidence to stand my ground, from actually turning down a pretty big offer to holding firm on several small points, to get the best deal I think was reasonably possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have multiple offers in parallel&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being aggressive and ready to walk away from one particular negotiation is made immensely easier if you have multiple offers on the table. It’s important to make an effort to develop those offers at roughly the same time. From the time you meet a buyer to the time you have a firm offer may be many months. When you’re in late-stage negotiations, having another firm vaguely interested in talking about an acquisition is not nearly as useful as having three LOIs in the same week. You can view each thread with a buyer as a conversion funnel and try to keep as many conversations moving forward in parallel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Purposefully under-optimize&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first few recommendation are all about the seller’s mindset, but it’s important not to neglect the buyer’s psychology. One thing I would recommend is to purposefully under-optimize certain aspects of your business. A business that is fully optimized in every aspect, with the juice wrung out of every possible avenue of improvement, is not actually attractive to a buyer. They want to see areas where they can come in and bring their own skills and resources to quickly accelerate the business. For example, I really do not understand paid search advertising (Google Adwords, Facebook, etc) so I purposefully put almost no effort into it as a customer acquisition channel for Storemapper. I would highlight that fact to buyers saying, “Despite the fact that revenue is growing well, I have put almost no effort in paid ads, if you have an Adwords guru on staff, I’m sure they can fire up a profitable paid advertising funnel in no time to further increase growth.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Build a narrative for the buyer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the day buyers need to tell themselves a story about acquiring your business. If they have raised outside funding and have partners or a board, they need to be able to tell that story to defend their investment to their partners. If they are a solo buyer they still need to tell that story to their spouse or to themselves. Almost everything in this post was part of an explicit narrative that I built and gave to potential buyers. For me it looked something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I’ve been running this business for five years. It’s profitable, growing and has product-market fit. I have a great team who handle most of the day to day operations so I’m perfectly willing to run it indefinitely. However, because I’ve run this with a lifestyle business approach, certain aspects are very under-optimized and its still performing well below its full potential. The right buyer, who I, and more importantly my team, would like working with, could pay a comparatively high price for the business and still generate a very strong return on investment.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Build your own narrative and sell that story to the buyer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wow, thanks for hanging in there all the way to the end. If you have any follow-up questions, fire them at me &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/tylertringas&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;. If you are little earlier on in the Micro-SaaS process, feel free to check out my ebook &lt;a href=&quot;https://tylertringas.com/micro-saas-ebook/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Building Micro-SaaS Businesses&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 08:17:16 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>AlikhanPeleg</dc:creator>
<og:description>Five years ago I built and launched the first version of a SaaS app on a single flight from San Francisco to Buenos Aires. Slowly and steadily, Storemappe…</og:description>
<og:image>https://storage.googleapis.com/indie-hackers.appspot.com/articles/1N9ZPzh8xNWZ3qGHXaPBWv2kDIJ3/@tylertringas%7C26c8406e1d/map-desk-2.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>Selling My Bootstrapped SaaS Business – Indie Hackers</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.indiehackers.com/@tylertringas/selling-my-bootstrapped-saas-business-26c8406e1d</og:url>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.indiehackers.com/@tylertringas/selling-my-bootstrapped-saas-business-26c8406e1d</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>