<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Instagram’s Co-Founders Said to Step Down from Company</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/09/24/technology/instagram-cofounders-resign.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2018/09/24/technology/instagram-cofounders-resign.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div readability=&quot;47.883847549909&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot; readability=&quot;41.466424682396&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;SAN FRANCISCO — Kevin Systrom and Mike Krieger, the co-founders of the photo-sharing app Instagram, have resigned and plan to leave the company in the coming weeks, adding to the challenges facing Instagram’s parent company, Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Mr. Systrom, Instagram’s chief executive, and Mr. Krieger, the chief technical officer, notified Instagram’s leadership team and Facebook on Monday of their decision to leave, said people with direct knowledge of the matter, who spoke on condition of anonymity because they were not authorized to discuss the matter publicly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Mr. Systrom and Mr. Krieger did not give a reason for stepping down, according to the people, but said they planned to take time off after leaving Instagram. Mr. Systrom, 34, and Mr. Krieger, 32, have known each other since 2010, when they met and transformed a software project built by Mr. Systrom into what eventually became Instagram, which now has more than one billion users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://instagram-press.com/blog/2018/09/24/statement-from-kevin-systrom-instagram-co-founder-and-ceo/&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;In a statement&lt;/a&gt; late Monday, Mr. Systrom said he and Mr. Krieger were “ready for our next chapter,” and hinted that they would create something new.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;42.817699115044&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot; readability=&quot;36.573451327434&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“We’re planning on taking some time off to explore our curiosity and creativity again,” Mr. Systrom said. “Building new things requires that we step back, understand what inspires us and match that with what the world needs; that’s what we plan to do.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Mark Zuckerberg, Facebook’s chief executive, praised the Instagram founders in a statement and said that he wished them “all the best and I’m looking forward to seeing what they build next.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The departures raise questions about Instagram’s future at a time when Facebook faces its most sustained set of crises in its 14-year history. For much of the past two years, critics have railed against Facebook for being &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/03/17/us/politics/cambridge-analytica-trump-campaign.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;careless with user data&lt;/a&gt; and for &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/02/17/technology/indictment-russian-tech-facebook.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;not preventing foreign interference&lt;/a&gt; across its network of more than two billion people. The issues have started taking a toll on Facebook’s business, with the company &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/07/25/technology/facebook-revenue-scandals.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;saying in July&lt;/a&gt; that growth in digital advertising sales and in the number of its users had slowed down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Against those problems, Instagram has been one of the &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/06/27/business/dealbook/instagram-facebook.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;jewels of Facebook&lt;/a&gt;. The social network &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://dealbook.nytimes.com/2012/04/09/facebook-buys-instagram-for-1-billion/&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;acquired Instagram in 2012&lt;/a&gt; for $1 billion, when the photo-sharing site was used by around 30 million people. Since then, Instagram’s reach has ballooned and it has widely been seen as &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/04/26/technology/why-instagram-is-becoming-facebooks-next-facebook.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;one of Facebook’s most successful acquisitions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Facebook has lost other founders of businesses it has acquired. In April, Jan Koum, a Facebook board member and a founder of WhatsApp, the messaging app that the social network purchased in 2014, &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/04/30/technology/whatsapp-facebook-jan-koum.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;said he was leaving&lt;/a&gt;. Mr. Koum had grown increasingly concerned about Facebook’s position on user data in recent years, people with knowledge of the situation said at the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;35&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot; readability=&quot;15&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;In Silicon Valley, reaction to the Instagram founders’ resignation was swift.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“Wow,” tweeted John Lilly, a venture capitalist at Greylock, calling the exits “a real moment.” He added, “What an impact they’ve had on all of us.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;45.135514018692&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot; readability=&quot;35.711615487316&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Instagram was founded in 2010 and at first was a location check-in app called Burbn. Mr. Krieger, an enthusiastic user of Burbn, met Mr. Systrom at a Stanford University fellowship program and they decided to work together. Eventually, Burbn was retooled and renamed Instagram.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Instagram became popular in Silicon Valley almost immediately. The app heavily emphasized the use of a smartphone camera as iPhones were being widely adopted, turning everyday people into amateur photographers. Mr. Systrom and Mr. Krieger popularized photo filters and camera lenses, spurring a wave of copycat apps for the iPhone and Android-based smartphones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The duo worked out of a small office in the South Park neighborhood of San Francisco. Instagram spent a lot of money in its early years just trying to keep its app online as its servers struggled under the constant stream of new user sign-ups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Instagram eventually caught the eye of Mr. Zuckerberg, who realized how powerful Instagram’s nascent photo-sharing network would become, and saw the wealth of photo-sharing activity across his own social network. Mr. Zuckerberg handled the negotiations with Mr. Systrom and Mr. Krieger largely on his own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Facebook purchased Instagram for $1 billion in cash and stock (though the final cost was closer to &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1326801/000132680112000006/fb-9302012x10q.htm&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;$715 million&lt;/a&gt; because the stock on which part of the deal was based declined in value). It was Facebook’s biggest acquisition to date, and came a month before the social network’s initial public offering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;47.990006246096&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot; readability=&quot;42.113678950656&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“For years, we’ve focused on building the best experience for sharing photos with your friends and family,” Mr. Zuckerberg wrote in a blog post about the deal. “Now, we’ll be able to work even more closely with the Instagram team to also offer the best experiences for sharing beautiful mobile photos with people based on your interests.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The deal immediately turned Mr. Systrom and Mr. Krieger into millionaires many times over. Instagram has since been valued at 100 times that $1 billion acquisition price by Bloomberg Intelligence, a sizable return on investment on paper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Facebook went on to purchase Parse, a service that provided tools for mobile developers, and Oculus, a virtual reality hardware start-up, branching into new areas beyond the original social network. Mr. Zuckerberg also &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://dealbook.nytimes.com/2014/02/19/facebook-to-buy-messaging-start-up/&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;spent $19 billion to buy WhatsApp&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;But Instagram remained Mr. Zuckerberg’s main success story. As Facebook saw a threat in young people departing the network for Snapchat, a rival photo-sharing network, Instagram was quick to shift and recreate one of Snapchat’s key features of online stories. Since then, Instagram has surged further in popularity, while Snapchat’s growth has been inconsistent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The departures of Mr. Systrom and Mr. Krieger create uncertainty around the app. It is unclear who will lead the company on the founders’ departures, and if that person can continue Instagram’s longstanding success streak. Marne Levine, who was previously Instagram’s chief operating officer, left her role at Instagram earlier this month to return to Facebook and lead partnerships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;28.219230769231&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;css-14rhwhm&quot; readability=&quot;8.2722513089005&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Follow Mike Isaac on Twitter: &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/MikeIsaac&quot;&gt;@MikeIsaac&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interested in All Things Tech?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/newsletters/signup/TU&quot;&gt;Get the Bits newsletter&lt;/a&gt; delivered to your inbox weekly for the latest from Silicon Valley and the technology industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-3glrhn&quot; readability=&quot;7.2727272727273&quot;&gt;A version of this article appears in print on , on Page B1 of the New York edition with the headline: Co-Founders Of Instagram Are Departing The Company&lt;span&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytreprints.com/&quot;&gt;Order Reprints&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/pages/todayspaper/index.html&quot;&gt;Today’s Paper&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/subscriptions/Multiproduct/lp8HYKU.html?campaignId=48JQY&quot;&gt;Subscribe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2018 01:53:58 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>garretruh</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/09/24/technology/instagram-cofounders-resign.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Instagram’s Co-Founders to Step Down From Company</og:title>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/09/25/business/25instagram1/25instagram1-facebookJumbo.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>Kevin Systrom and Mike Krieger, Instagram’s co-founders, resigned from the photo app on Monday. Their exits add to the challenges facing Facebook, which owns the app.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/09/24/technology/instagram-cofounders-resign.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Police forcing me to install Jingwang spyware app, how to minimize impact?</title>
<link>https://security.stackexchange.com/questions/194353/police-forcing-me-to-install-jingwang-spyware-app-how-to-minimize-impact</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://security.stackexchange.com/questions/194353/police-forcing-me-to-install-jingwang-spyware-app-how-to-minimize-impact</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;This is a tricky one. It goes without saying, but it's also a dangerous one. Attempting to circumvent these restrictions and getting caught doing so will potentially cause a lot of legal trouble. If they throw people in jail for refusing to install the app, I wouldn't want to figure out what they do to people circumventing the app restrictions. It is especially relevant because even experts in tech security have gotten caught by their governments despite extensive safeguards (&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ross_Ulbricht&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;the founder of Silk Road is a great example and is now serving a life sentence&lt;/a&gt;). Granted, evading this app is most likely a much less serious &quot;crime&quot;, but the Chinese government isn't exactly known for lenience here. So while I would like to answer your question, please don't take this as me suggesting that you actually do any of this. I consider myself a tech-expert, but I still wouldn't do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, to answer your question, you have a few options. I won't bother mentioning the &quot;Get a second phone&quot; option because you've already ruled that out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some options for &quot;dual booting&quot; android phones. I don't have any examples to immediately link to (software suggestions are off topic here anyway) but there are options. If you can get your phone to dual boot then you can install the tracking software on one ROM and then do all your personal stuff on the other. You may need to put some basic information on the ROM with the tracking app installed just so you don't raise too many flags.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course there are still risks here: risks that they might reboot your phone and notice, risks that they might realize you have a completely different system installed next to the tracked one, and the simple risk that you would go out and about and forget to reboot into the &quot;tracked&quot; system, allowing a police officer to find and install the tracking app on your &lt;em&gt;actual&lt;/em&gt; system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If this app creates enough bad press it is possible that anti-tracking apps or hacked versions of this app may start floating around that try to automatically protect you from it. I would not expect there to be any general tools already available that would protect you from this, so this is something that would simply take lots of googling or (perhaps) requests to the right people. This has a major downside that unless you are an expert at reverse engineering, there isn't much to do to make this happen. It's also hard to estimate what the risks of detection are. That will obviously vary wildly depending on the skill level of the person who put it together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Depending on your level of technological know-how you might be able to put something together yourself (note: this is not for novices). Based on what I know and my experience in this area, I'm going to try to summarize some details about what a server-spoofing measure might look like. Again, I'm not summarizing this because I think you should do it, but because understanding how things like this operate can be generally informative and also help understand the risks there-in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Built-in security&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, we need to understand how this spying app might secure itself. From all information available so-far, the answer is &quot;it doesn't&quot;. This is a pretty simple conclusion to come to because the app communicates exclusively through http. It is very easy to intercept http requests, either from the device itself (if your phone is rooted) or with network sniffing tools on a computer attached to the same network as the device. Most likely it is also very possible to easily figure out how the app authenticates itself with the end-server and how the end-server authenticates itself with the app. In all likelihood there is no authentication in either direction, which means that spoofing requests in either direction is trivially easy. This might be hard to believe (given that a country like China sets aside lots of resources to invasive technology like this), but the reality is that if the people who developed this app wanted to secure it from outside tampering, using HTTPS for transit would be the very first step to perform. It is cheap, easy, and very effective. The lack of HTTPS means that it is &lt;strong&gt;very&lt;/strong&gt; likely that there is no actual security in this ecosystem, which is a plus for anyone trying to evade it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sniff all traffic coming out of this app to determine what requests/responses it makes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the first step. By watching the traffic leaving this app (which can be easily intercepted in the network itself since there is no SSL encryption) you can figure out what requests it sends to the destination server and what responses it expects back. Understanding the underlying API is critical, but easy due to the lack of encryption. This will also let you know if there is any authentication happening in either direction. If there is, you can at least see the full request and responses, so you can most likely figure out how to spoof it. It is possible that there is some hard-to-reverse-engineer authentication going back and forth, but again, given the lack of basic encryption, I doubt there is any such thing built in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure out if the app is talking to a domain name or IP address&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The destination server the app is talking to is either found via a DNS lookup or has its IP address hard-coded in the app. In the event of the former you can edit the DNS for your android phone to repoint it to a different server, including one running on your phone. In the event of a hard-coded IP address you will similarly have to redirect all traffic to that IP address to your local android phone (presumably you can do this with Android - you can with other operating systems, but you would definitely have to root your phone).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Setup a replacement server&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You then setup a local server that responds to all requests just like the server did in your initial spoofing. You would have to get this server to run on your phone itself, that way it is always available. This doesn't necessarily have to be complicated (although that depends on how detailed the actual server interaction is), as you don't actually care about keeping any data on hand. You just need to make sure that you provide valid responses to all requests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Risks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;The app may auto-update itself (although your mock-server may make this impossible) and point to new domains/ip addresses, suddenly removing your protections&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If there is an auto-update functionality and your end up unintentionally killing it (which would be good per point #1 above), a police officer may notice that it is not properly updated, flag you for &quot;extra&quot; checking, and discover what you are doing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They may do server-side tracking and discover what you are doing because they don't find any data on their end for your particular IMEI (because your mock-server acts like a black-hole and sucks up everything). Even if you send spoofed requests there will be easy ways for them to determine that (imagine the police copy a blacklisted image to your phone and discover that the app doesn't block/report it)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They may have root-checking in the app itself, which will cause you problems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was trying for a longer list but that is really what it all boils down to. Short of not carrying around a phone or purchasing a separate one, these are about your only options. For reference, I haven't gone into details about the server spoofing because I think you're necessarily going to go out and do it. If anything, I've gone through it because it gives opportunity to talk through the risks in more detail, and those should make it clear that &lt;strong&gt;there are a lot of risks&lt;/strong&gt;. Even if you find a solution from someone, they have to deal with all of these same risks (or ones like it). Right now this app sounds like it is poorly executed and easily fooled, but depending on how much the Chinese government decides it cares, that could change very quickly. At that point in time not getting caught basically turns into a cat-and-mouse game with the Chinese government, and that isn't realistically something that someone can continue to win for an extended period of time. There are a lot of risks, so &lt;strong&gt;tread lightly&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 19:18:02 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>sebazzz</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>https://security.stackexchange.com/questions/194353/police-forcing-me-to-install-jingwang-spyware-app-how-to-minimize-impact</og:url>
<og:image>https://cdn.sstatic.net/Sites/security/img/apple-touch-icon@2.png?v=497726d850f9</og:image>
<og:title>Police forcing me to install Jingwang spyware app, how to minimize impact?</og:title>
<og:description>Chinese police are forcing whole cities to install an Android spyware app Jingwang Weishi. They are stopping people in the street and detaining those who refuse to install it. Knowing that I may be</og:description>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://security.stackexchange.com/questions/194353/police-forcing-me-to-install-jingwang-spyware-app-how-to-minimize-impact</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Am I logged in or not? GDPR case study on the example of Chrome browser change</title>
<link>https://blog.lukaszolejnik.com/am-i-logged-in-or-not-gdpr-case-study-on-the-example-of-chrome-browser-change/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.lukaszolejnik.com/am-i-logged-in-or-not-gdpr-case-study-on-the-example-of-chrome-browser-change/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;It is surprisingly difficult to find realistic, interesting and creative privacy case studies. It is perhaps even more difficult in the case of major software. There are no proper motivations for making this kind of work public (&lt;em&gt;employees often paid to do some kind of work in-house; their compensation typically containing a demotivating NDA&lt;/em&gt;). Finding the right angle is also often difficult. I have some experience in this sphere, both in terms of technology (&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.lukaszolejnik.com/battery-status-readout-as-a-privacy-risk/&quot;&gt;battery case study&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.lukaszolejnik.com/w3c-web-bluetooth-api-privacy/&quot;&gt;Web Bluetooth privacy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.lukaszolejnik.com/privacy-of-london-tube-wifi-tracking/&quot;&gt;London Tube wifi tracking&lt;/a&gt;) and from a regulatory point of view (&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.lukaszolejnik.com/everything-you-should-know-about-gdpr-fines/&quot;&gt;technical overview of GDPR fines&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.lukaszolejnik.com/is-gdpr-recharging-cookie-notice-popups/&quot;&gt;not surprising observation of an imminent outcome of GDPR&lt;/a&gt;). Today, I’ll do both at the same time, though more on the second aspect (GDPR).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With growing pace of cloud services development and Internet of Things, ordinary users are increasingly at odds with understanding of how technology works; vendors must be aware of it. The lines between what is local (desktop computer, smartphone), and what is remote (cloud system; someone else’s computer) are getting softer. While about two years ago, I &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.lukaszolejnik.com/w3c-web-bluetooth-api-privacy/&quot;&gt;remarked how a web mechanism called ‘Web Bluetooth’&lt;/a&gt; makes the lines between the local devices and the cloud possibly blurred, today we’re seeing another example: local (desktop, smartphone) and cloud. Well designed user interfaces are of particular concern.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The latest release of a major web browser drops another stone here. Starting with Chrome 69, when you log into a Google service (GMail, or so), Google Chrome is effectively logging you into the browser. It looks like that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.lukaszolejnik.com/content/images/2018/09/R2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This change apparently “solves” the &lt;em&gt;hypothetical issue&lt;/em&gt; of user confusion: “&lt;em&gt;am I logged into the system or into the browser?&lt;/em&gt;” (and at the same time is creating others). Logging in is made “&lt;em&gt;consistent&lt;/em&gt;” among the web and the browser. While some people are finding it problematic and confusing (e.g. &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/chrome/forum/AAAAP1KN0B0n4hbwpgOxkM/?hl=en&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/chrome/comments/9hk9zs/please_help_chrome_signed_in_automatically_did_it/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;), let’s trust Google Chrome has thought it through well. We can trust Google, as Chrome is the most secure browser out there, and maybe the feature will allow to better tailor ads in the future. There are good reasons for using the browser. Let’s assume the feature is needed. The problem lies elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;suddenchange&quot;&gt;Sudden change&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For some reason, the information about this change is not reflected in the official &lt;a href=&quot;https://chromereleases.googleblog.com/2018/09/stable-channel-update-for-desktop.html&quot;&gt;release notes of Chrome 69&lt;/a&gt;, nor in the note &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.blog.google/products/chrome/redesigning-chrome-interview-chromes-lead-designer/&quot;&gt;lauding the user interface upgrade&lt;/a&gt;. The change simply appeared to come out of the blue. Things work very different than, say, in Chrome 68 (&lt;em&gt;released 2018-07-24&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;privacypolicyissue&quot;&gt;Privacy Policy issue&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/privacy/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome privacy policy&lt;/a&gt; “&lt;em&gt;signed-in Chrome mode&lt;/em&gt;” works differently than the &lt;em&gt;basic&lt;/em&gt; (non-signed) mode. Accordingly “your personal browsing data is saved on Google's servers and synced with your account. This type of information can include: Browsing history, Bookmarks, Tabs, Passwords and Autofill information, Other browser settings, like installed extensions”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In line with privacy policy, this could be the case. However, &lt;strong&gt;data synchronisation appears not to happen by default in practice&lt;/strong&gt; (as also confirmed &lt;a href=&quot;https://ha.x0r.be/posts/chrome-is-a-google-service/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;). It seems &lt;em&gt;this behavior is not accounted by the privacy policy&lt;/em&gt;, which means either the policy is obsolete (and needs to be updated, which suggests potential issues in the internal privacy program, and possibly the priorities), or the mechanic may be subject to change in future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;userinterfaceconfusion&quot;&gt;User Interface confusion&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is indeed a justified concern that currently browser sign-ins happen without the user knowledge (in advance), awareness, or consent. This may well be seen as regression in terms of privacy user interface (while I do not intend to argue that this is a proof of privacy being a 2nd-class citizen), not least touching the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Principle_of_least_astonishment&quot;&gt;principle of least surprise&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a dramatic change in mechanics like that, you could imagine, for example, displaying of an information to the user upon first launch of an updated browser. This has not happened with Chrome 69, which means that a the change of the operating method for a key technology has been made abruptly, for millions of users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;mistakensynchronisation&quot;&gt;Mistaken synchronisation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, during testing I was successful at &lt;strong&gt;deliberately-inadvertently&lt;/strong&gt; synchronising my settings to the cloud, simply by clicking on “sync”, where I could click “undo”, but the information page encouraged me to first look into the settings. However, by clicking on “settings” I was unable to click “undo” - the user interface happily assumed that yes, in fact I wanted to first upload my data. And suddenly, instead of “Last time synced in 2017” I saw the following: “Last time synced on Today”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.lukaszolejnik.com/content/images/2018/09/S3.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Subsequently, I clicked “delete” of course. &lt;em&gt;Note: I tested that on Canary version.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;disablebydefault&quot;&gt;Disable by default&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It looks like setting a special flag &lt;em&gt;chrome://flags#account-consistency&lt;/em&gt; to “&lt;em&gt;Disabled&lt;/em&gt;” might solve the case for concerned users. The flag is quite oddly documented.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.lukaszolejnik.com/content/images/2018/09/set3.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a fascinating example for a GDPR case study. However, I will not go into details whether GDPR articles concerning consent were affected in this case. &lt;strong&gt;Consent is overrated&lt;/strong&gt;. Instead, I focus on two less known, but specialised items.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;dataprotectionimpactassessment&quot;&gt;Data Protection Impact Assessment&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Article 35 of GDPR requires making an assessment taking into account the “&lt;em&gt;fundamental rights and freedoms&lt;/em&gt;” (privacy one of them) of an individual. I previously wrote about making of DPIAs (&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.lukaszolejnik.com/guidelines-to-data-protection-impact-assessment/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;). Now, I am not sure Chrome has a DPIA at all. Projects made prior to GDPR do not need to have one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, &lt;strong&gt;data protection impact assessment&lt;/strong&gt; (DPIA) must be updated when &lt;strong&gt;significant changes&lt;/strong&gt; in the system are introduced. In this case, pre-GDPR projects effectively need to have one made (if not having one). While I do not want to debate whether Chrome releases 67 and 68 introduced such changes, I would say version 69 may have &lt;strong&gt;crossed the threshold&lt;/strong&gt;. If a Data Protection Authority decides there is a need to see the DPIA, it can formally request the vendor to deliver the document. GDPR says that an infringement in relation to a DPIA requirements are in the award region of 10 000 000 EUR, or to 2 % of the total worldwide annual turnover (whichever higher).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;dataprotectionbydesign&quot;&gt;Data Protection by Design&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is another interesting superpower introduced by GDPR. Software needs to be designed with consideration of data protection - by design and by default. The particular Article 25 of GDPR is rarely seriously and meaningfully discussed in practice, not least because probably still almost nobody actually knows what the “data protection by design” even means. However, infringement entails a comparable award (20M or 2%) as in the case of DPIA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The case of Chrome login discussed here might be one of the best examples for a case study&lt;/strong&gt;. It is high impact (lots of users), concerns expectations and defaults, and is about changing how things work. Clarity of user interface, what the user expects, and what actually happens - are the key elements. I am afraid there may be an issue here. Yet, perhaps Google has designed the new login feature well, considering the user privacy under the hood, but not accounting in the user interface. However, we are unable to know about this of course - it is not explained anywhere (no information in the release log). The possible best place where one can find it could be the data protection impact assessment (previous point).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It would therefore be very interesting if Chrome made its DPIA public&lt;/strong&gt;. That would not only allow to clarify the above mentioned points. That would also be an interesting and trust-building move. I often advise organisations to make their privacy impact assessment public. I believe doing so might be do good for everyone, in this particular case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hope you liked this little tech-GDPR exercise. Interested in technical high-level analyses on privacy &amp;amp; cyber, including international norms, regulations, and policy? Feel free to reach out: me@lukaszolejnik.com&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 18:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>krahmakt</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Am I logged in or not? GDPR case study on the example of Chrome browser change</og:title>
<og:description>It is surprisingly difficult to find realistic, interesting and creative privacy case studies. It is perhaps even more difficult in the case of major software. There are no proper motivations for making this kind of work public (employees often paid to do some kind of work in-house; their compensation typically</og:description>
<og:url>http://blog.lukaszolejnik.com/am-i-logged-in-or-not-gdpr-case-study-on-the-example-of-chrome-browser-change/</og:url>
<og:image>http://blog.lukaszolejnik.com/content/images/2018/09/Screen-Shot-2018-09-23-at-20.19.55-1.png</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.lukaszolejnik.com/am-i-logged-in-or-not-gdpr-case-study-on-the-example-of-chrome-browser-change/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Zoho.com CEO says domain with 40M users suspended for abuse complaint</title>
<link>https://twitter.com/svembu/status/1044265646739996673</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://twitter.com/svembu/status/1044265646739996673</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;It does not seem like they banned and asked later, according to that conversation. It appears as if they alerted, and no response was given, so they then banned. Regardless, the urgency you took is well appreciated. Is there any metrics on your side for a quantifiable outage?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 17:55:18 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>achynet</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://mobile.twitter.com/svembu/status/1044265646739996673</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Myst at 25: How it changed gaming, created addicts, and made enemies</title>
<link>https://www.fastcompany.com/90240345/myst-at-25-how-it-changed-gaming-created-addicts-and-made-enemies</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.fastcompany.com/90240345/myst-at-25-how-it-changed-gaming-created-addicts-and-made-enemies</guid>
<description>&lt;div readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just a few days ago, as Hurricane Florence approached my home in North Carolina, I popped a disc into my 1990s Atari Jaguar CD gaming console. A familiar animated logo popped onto the screen, and I found myself transported back to a world I knew well decades ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;ad-wrapper ad-wrapper--mobileparallax_1&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ad-wrapper--ad-unit-wrap&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;advertisement&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ad-wrapper ad-wrapper--native_mid_article_inject&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ad-wrapper--ad-unit-wrap&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;advertisement&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;61.414350112697&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was &lt;em&gt;Myst&lt;/em&gt;, the groundbreaking point-and-click adventure game that Brøderbund published in its first incarnation–for the Mac–25 years ago today, on September 24, 1993. I personally happened to have first played &lt;em&gt;Myst&lt;/em&gt; on the most obscure platform possible, the Jaguar, but that made it no less of a transformational experience at the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;Myst&lt;/em&gt;, you explore an ornately detailed island that leads to other vaguely Victorian sci-fi worlds (called ages) created by a character named Atrus. You’re presented with lushly detailed screens—punctuated by animations—depicting the scene around you, and can point and click your way through puzzles that feel woven perfectly into the tapestry of the game. Despite its largely static nature, its groundbreaking pre-rendered visuals (which many people called photorealistic at the time) made &lt;em&gt;Myst&lt;/em&gt; feel like the first convincing virtual reality experience, at least in the sense of feeling physically present in a fictional world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-90240477 size-large lazyload&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;525&quot; height=&quot;394&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 525px) 100vw, 525px&quot; data-src=&quot;https://images.fastcompany.net/image/upload/w_596,c_limit,q_auto:best,f_auto/wp-cms/uploads/2018/09/i-myst-night.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;em&gt;Myst’s&lt;/em&gt; world was static and mysterious, but gorgeous by the standards of the mid-1990s. [Image: Cyan Worlds, Inc.]I invited my daughters, aged 6 and 8, to join me in exploring the lush alien world while the rains encircled our house. They took copious illustrated notes and offered suggestions as we played. Despite growing up with much flashier animated graphics, they were still sucked in by the classic world of &lt;em&gt;Myst&lt;/em&gt;. As we collaborated over puzzles played out on vintage machinery, my older daughter said, “People back then must have been incredibly creative to make something like this.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed they were.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The creators of &lt;em&gt;Myst&lt;/em&gt;, brothers Rand and Robyn Miller, along with a small team at their Washington state-based firm Cyan, were no strangers to innovation. The company had previously developed the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.filfre.net/2016/10/the-manhole/&quot;&gt;first-ever game released on CD-ROM for a personal computer&lt;/a&gt; (in this case, a Macintosh), &lt;em&gt;The Manhole&lt;/em&gt;, in 1989. They followed that children’s title with other whimsical point-and-click words crafted in &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2012/05/25-years-of-hypercard-the-missing-link-to-the-web/&quot;&gt;HyperCard&lt;/a&gt;, Apple’s Mac-based hypertext environment that presaged the World Wide Web. Creativity came naturally to the Millers, and &lt;em&gt;Myst&lt;/em&gt; was the natural next step in the refinement of their art.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-90240476 size-full lazyload&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;512&quot; height=&quot;342&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 512px) 100vw, 512px&quot; data-src=&quot;https://images.fastcompany.net/image/upload/w_596,c_limit,q_auto:best,f_auto/wp-cms/uploads/2018/09/i-myst-vector.jpg&quot;/&gt;Four years before &lt;em&gt;Myst&lt;/em&gt;, the Miller brothers’ &lt;em&gt;The Manhole&lt;/em&gt; couldn’t yet offer the same sort of visual splendor. [Image: Cyan Worlds, Inc.]Even 25 years later, the emergence of &lt;em&gt;Myst&lt;/em&gt; still represents a watershed moment in the development of computer video games. It’s an achievement on par, I think, with the launch of &lt;em&gt;Pong&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Super Mario Bros.&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Tetris&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Myst&lt;/em&gt; expanded the art form, expanded the market, and challenged assumptions. It also made a lot of people happy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ad-wrapper ad-wrapper--mobilerectangle_1&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ad-wrapper--ad-unit-wrap&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;advertisement&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;53.299957573186&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like most classic works, &lt;em&gt;Myst&lt;/em&gt; has proven commercially timeless. After the Mac launch in September 1993, an IBM PC version launched the following February, and the game’s popularity quickly spread by word of mouth. Within a year, glowing reviews of the title began appearing in mainstream newspapers, and &lt;em&gt;Myst’s&lt;/em&gt; sales skyrocketed, making it a high-profile success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since then, the game has appeared on at least 12 different platforms, most recently including iOS and Nintendo 3DS. Across all releases, consumers have purchased &lt;em&gt;Myst&lt;/em&gt; over 6 million times; for several years it held the title of highest-selling PC game of all time (until the equally groundbreaking &lt;em&gt;The Sims&lt;/em&gt; came along). Over the dozen years following its release, it also inspired four sequels. And last May, Cyan completed &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/1252280491/myst-25th-anniversary-collection&quot;&gt;a &lt;em&gt;Myst&lt;/em&gt; 25th anniversary Kickstarter campaign&lt;/a&gt; with more than $2.8 million in crowdfunded proceeds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;525&quot; height=&quot;295&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/IL4mfS_d2U0?feature=oembed&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Beloved–to a point&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite &lt;em&gt;Myst’s&lt;/em&gt; enduring popularity, its reputation is surprisingly mixed for such an iconic game. At launch, people immediately loved it. Just &lt;a href=&quot;https://groups.google.com/forum/#!search/Myst$201993/comp.sys.mac.games/uQnemAXaYA4/JyasFn7CDukJ&quot;&gt;search the Usenet archives over on Google&lt;/a&gt;, and you’ll find players who enjoyed it so much that when the game crashed repeatedly on their Macs they kept on plowing through it, soaking in every second of the experience. Reviewers for major newspapers and magazines &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/1994/12/04/arts/a-new-art-form-may-arise-from-the-myst.html&quot;&gt;cited &lt;em&gt;Myst&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; as evidence that computer gaming had finally attained artistic maturity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The traditional gaming press was not as easily swayed, and some editorials derided the title for its simplicity and lack of action. (“Finally attained?” I can imagine them asking in their heads; they considered computer games an artform form all along.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Often, the needling of &lt;em&gt;Myst&lt;/em&gt; gets far more specific. In my years of reporting on the history of electronic games, I have encountered more than one industry developer who has blamed &lt;em&gt;Myst&lt;/em&gt; for the death of everything they loved about adventure games in the early 1990s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-90240478 size-large lazyload&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;525&quot; height=&quot;397&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 525px) 100vw, 525px&quot; data-src=&quot;https://images.fastcompany.net/image/upload/w_596,c_limit,q_auto:best,f_auto/wp-cms/uploads/2018/09/i-myst-boat.jpg&quot;/&gt;[Image: Cyan Worlds, Inc.]While developing a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pcworld.com/article/158850/best_pc_games.html&quot;&gt;list&lt;/a&gt; of the “Ten Greatest PC Games Ever” for &lt;em&gt;PCWorld&lt;/em&gt; back in 2009, I sought a quote from a famous game developer for just about every game included. When I looked around for a developer willing to praise &lt;em&gt;Myst&lt;/em&gt;, I found none. In fact, Al Lowe, creator of Sierra’s classic graphical adventure game &lt;em&gt;Leisure Suit Larry&lt;/em&gt; (1987), &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vintagecomputing.com/index.php/archives/1150/vcg-anthology-developers-cite-the-best-pc-games-of-all-time-2008&quot;&gt;went out of his way to explain why he didn’t like it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ad-wrapper ad-wrapper--mobilerectangle_2&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ad-wrapper--ad-unit-wrap&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;advertisement&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;67&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I never understood the excitement about &lt;em&gt;Myst&lt;/em&gt;,” Lowe told me. “There were always many other games that were more interesting, exciting, subtle and funny, with better logic and puzzles. I grew to resent its success while better games struggled for recognition.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s true that adventure titles developed by people like Lowe suffered for attention while &lt;em&gt;Myst&lt;/em&gt; soaked up the limelight. That must have been very difficult to accept for companies like Sierra, which had a proven formula for adventure games in franchises such as &lt;em&gt;Leisure Suit Larry&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;King’s Quest&lt;/em&gt;. Suddenly, that approach wasn’t so hot anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prior to &lt;em&gt;Myst&lt;/em&gt;, if you said “adventure game,” a PC owner might see images of a title from that firm or LucasArts, another company that crafted some of the most well-respected adventure titles of the ’80s and ’90s. Think &lt;em&gt;Monkey’s Island&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Indiana Jones and the Fate of Atlantis&lt;/em&gt;: third-person view, inventory, copious dialog (often funny), lots of characters, constant peril, verb-based interface. &lt;em&gt;Myst&lt;/em&gt; did away with all of that. It was Spartan, lonely, calm, and low-stakes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-90240479 size-large lazyload&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;525&quot; height=&quot;439&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 525px) 100vw, 525px&quot; data-src=&quot;https://images.fastcompany.net/image/upload/w_596,c_limit,q_auto:best,f_auto/wp-cms/uploads/2018/09/i-myst-bed.jpg&quot;/&gt;[Image: Cyan Worlds, Inc.]Along with violating the existing rules of adventure games, &lt;em&gt;Myst&lt;/em&gt; was also the ultimate anti-arcade game. Everything gaming had taught itself to be since 1972 was thrown out the window. There were no lives, no dying, no score, and no time limit. No physical agility or reflexes were required. The only pressure was that which you imposed upon yourself to solve the puzzles and complete the storyline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a game so seemingly simple, &lt;em&gt;Myst&lt;/em&gt; was astonishingly hard to copy. After it became wildly successful, it was not long before other developers tried to replicate Cyan’s recipe. In general, they failed, and many &lt;em&gt;Myst&lt;/em&gt;-like adventure games suffered poorly at the hands of reviewers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;525&quot; height=&quot;394&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/94pzx_9LkVI?feature=oembed&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agustín Cordes, the creator of one of my favorite adventure games, 2006’s &lt;em&gt;Scratches&lt;/em&gt;, sometimes tangles with me about &lt;em&gt;Myst&lt;/em&gt; on Twitter. He admits it was important, but still laments its impact on the adventure game market. “I do believe the overwhelming saturation of &lt;em&gt;Myst&lt;/em&gt; clones led to an adventure game fatigue,” he says. “It didn’t help they were so shamefully similar to each other, featuring sterile worlds, obscure puzzles based on trial and error, and close to no narrative design.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ad-wrapper ad-wrapper--mobileparallax_2&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ad-wrapper--ad-unit-wrap&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;advertisement&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;62&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tim Schafer, a veteran game designer responsible for LucasArts classics such as &lt;em&gt;Day of the Tentacle&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Grim Fandango&lt;/em&gt;, says that he never saw &lt;em&gt;Myst&lt;/em&gt; as a threat to LucasArts’ way of life; instead, he saw the sunny side of its impact on the market. “We didn’t really think of &lt;em&gt;Myst&lt;/em&gt; as competition because it was such a different type of game to us,” Schafer says. “If anything we thought it would make more people buy computers and CD-ROM drives and see games as more than just hyperviolent shooters.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-90240478 size-large lazyload&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;525&quot; height=&quot;397&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 525px) 100vw, 525px&quot; data-src=&quot;https://images.fastcompany.net/image/upload/w_596,c_limit,q_auto:best,f_auto/wp-cms/uploads/2018/09/i-myst-boat.jpg&quot;/&gt;[Image: Cyan Worlds, Inc.]Speaking of hyperviolence, &lt;em&gt;Myst&lt;/em&gt; debuted in a gaming era typified by &lt;em&gt;Mortal Kombat&lt;/em&gt;, which was known for its intensity and gore. It seemed everything leading up to &lt;em&gt;Myst&lt;/em&gt; involved ramping up gaming’s intensity, including the first-person shooter games that followed. The launch of &lt;em&gt;Myst&lt;/em&gt; was like hitting a steam release valve; a peaceful break from the visceral and often bloody action of the era.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And one of the period’s most archetypal violent shooters, &lt;em&gt;Doom&lt;/em&gt;, launched in December 1993 — just a few months after Myst. &lt;em&gt;Doom’s&lt;/em&gt; success propelled first-person shooters into mainstream consciousness, and like &lt;em&gt;Myst&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Doom&lt;/em&gt; spawned a horde of copycat titles. These two games rode in like twin horsemen of a PC gaming apocalypse, shifting fashions and styles in gaming dramatically for the remainder of the decade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-90240472 size-full lazyload&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;544&quot; height=&quot;333&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 544px) 100vw, 544px&quot; data-src=&quot;https://images.fastcompany.net/image/upload/w_596,c_limit,q_auto:best,f_auto/wp-cms/uploads/2018/09/i-myst-ribs.jpg&quot;/&gt;[Image: Cyan Worlds, Inc.]
&lt;p&gt;Curious about the interplay of those two titles, I asked John Romero, co-creator of &lt;em&gt;Doom&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Quake&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Wolfenstein 3D&lt;/em&gt;, how he feels about &lt;em&gt;Myst&lt;/em&gt; and its impact on the industry. “When &lt;em&gt;Myst&lt;/em&gt; came out, I was floored to see it unseat &lt;em&gt;Wolfenstein 3D&lt;/em&gt; from the top of the Usenet 100 weekly list,” he says. “We couldn’t believe that a game with static screens was actually so popular, and ignored most of the conventions of adventure games of the era.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Romero strikes an understanding tone on the appeal of the game. “There is a huge market for players who like to go on an adventure and read a good story, so there is definitely a place for those kinds of games. But we looked at &lt;em&gt;Doom&lt;/em&gt; as the beginning of a new era of action gaming that was super exciting.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lost in the usual criticism of &lt;em&gt;Myst&lt;/em&gt; as a genre killer is the fact that success in business is not usually a zero-sum game. One company can “win” a sales race while second place still does astonishingly well. &lt;em&gt;Myst&lt;/em&gt; may have been #1 on the charts for a while in the late 1990s, but radically different #2 sellers like &lt;em&gt;Quake&lt;/em&gt; still sold in phenomenal quantities. And while LucasArts-style games may have fallen by the wayside for a time, it wasn’t the death of the adventure genre.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ad-wrapper ad-wrapper--mobilerectangle_3&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ad-wrapper--ad-unit-wrap&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;advertisement&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;42.09565807327&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, if you squinted the right way, you could see that adventure games had survived, even if they had changed form. As Romero points out, “&lt;em&gt;CSI&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Nancy Drew&lt;/em&gt;, and all of the murder mystery types of adventure games kept the genre alive for a long time. Now you can see &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Puzzle_video_game#Hidden_object_game&quot;&gt;hidden-object games&lt;/a&gt; as expanding the realm of the adventure.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-90240644 lazyload&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;525&quot; height=&quot;428&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 525px) 100vw, 525px&quot; data-src=&quot;https://images.fastcompany.net/image/upload/w_596,c_limit,q_auto:best,f_auto/wp-cms/uploads/2018/09/Benjs-Daughter-Myst-Notes_Sept_2018_2.jpg&quot;/&gt;Notes by one of the author’s daughters about &lt;em&gt;Myst&lt;/em&gt;, a game created long before she was born. [Image: Courtesy of Benj Edwards]In &lt;em&gt;Myst’s&lt;/em&gt; heyday, the concept of “&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Casual_game&quot;&gt;casual games&lt;/a&gt;” had not yet solidified, but now it’s okay to make games that take it easy. We’re used to a world with bajillion-sellers like &lt;em&gt;Bejeweled&lt;/em&gt;, one-finger smartphone and tablet games that we digest at our own pace, and quieter adventure experiences like &lt;em&gt;Gone Home&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Dear Esther&lt;/em&gt;–games that put the pot on simmer rather than full boil. What if &lt;em&gt;Myst&lt;/em&gt; was, in fact, the world’s first breakout causal game? The first adventure roasted in a slow-cooker?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Maybe that’s the key to the stunning success behind &lt;em&gt;Myst&lt;/em&gt;,” reflects Cordes. “It came up with the winning formula of casual and then mobile games… in 1993.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You could say that &lt;em&gt;Myst&lt;/em&gt; was ahead of its time, but more than that, it &lt;em&gt;created&lt;/em&gt; its time, giving birth to the idea that it can be fun to play games at your own pace. Casual or otherwise, for my kids, it doesn’t matter what you call it. 25 years later, &lt;em&gt;Myst&lt;/em&gt; is still a compelling treat for the senses–even in the middle of a hurricane.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ad-wrapper ad-wrapper--native_recommendationlink&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ad-wrapper--ad-unit-wrap&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;advertisement&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 16:24:32 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>johnshades</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>“Myst” at 25: How it changed gaming, created addicts, and made enemies</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.fastcompany.com/90240345/myst-at-25-how-it-changed-gaming-created-addicts-and-made-enemies</og:url>
<og:description>In 1993, the atmospheric CD-ROM game became a beloved megahit–but not everybody was happy with its influence on the game industry.</og:description>
<og:image>https://images.fastcompany.net/image/upload/w_1280,f_auto,q_auto,fl_lossy/wp-cms/uploads/2018/09/p-1-myst-25th-an.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.fastcompany.com/90240345/myst-at-25-how-it-changed-gaming-created-addicts-and-made-enemies</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Police that collect more in fees and fines are less effective at solving crime</title>
<link>https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/monkey-cage/wp/2018/09/24/want-your-police-department-to-collect-more-fines-it-will-solve-fewer-crimes/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/monkey-cage/wp/2018/09/24/want-your-police-department-to-collect-more-fines-it-will-solve-fewer-crimes/</guid>
<description>&lt;div data-elm-loc=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;inline-content inline-photo inline-photo-normal&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/aVhSKnMo7aGeD31D6lJBVrTvJps=/311x0/arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/YVSTG4ZOXQ7OJESX2FAZ6NKZTY.jpg&quot; data-hi-res-src=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/tN9UFS2nTtWaZiTxwl27Ti3iGOM=/960x0/arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/YVSTG4ZOXQ7OJESX2FAZ6NKZTY.jpg&quot; data-low-res-src=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/aVhSKnMo7aGeD31D6lJBVrTvJps=/311x0/arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/YVSTG4ZOXQ7OJESX2FAZ6NKZTY.jpg&quot; data-raw-src=&quot;https://arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/YVSTG4ZOXQ7OJESX2FAZ6NKZTY.jpg&quot; data-threshold=&quot;311&quot; class=&quot;unprocessed&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pb-caption&quot;&gt;Protesters march in Ferguson, Mo., in August 2014 after the shooting of Michael Brown, an unarmed black 18-year-old. (Jeff Roberson/AP)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;author-sig-line-wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author-sig-line&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author-byline multiple&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author-wrapper&quot; data-authorname=&quot;Rebecca Goldstein&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author-info&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;by-lbl&quot;&gt;By&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;author-name&quot;&gt;Rebecca Goldstein&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;byline-divider-comma&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author-wrapper&quot; data-authorname=&quot;Michael Sances&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author-info&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;author-name&quot;&gt;Michael Sances&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;byline-divider-lbl&quot;&gt;and&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author-wrapper&quot; data-authorname=&quot;Hye Young You&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author-info&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;author-name&quot;&gt;Hye Young You&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;author-timestamp&quot; itemprop=&quot;datePublished&quot; content=&quot;2018-09-24T05:00-500&quot;&gt;September 24 at 5:00 AM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Alongside the Black Lives Matter movement in the past several years, civil rights advocates have begun pointing out that the way municipalities collect fees and fines often &lt;u&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usccr.gov/pubs/2017/Statutory_Enforcement_Report2017.pdf&quot;&gt;disproportionately&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt; &lt;u&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://faculty.washington.edu/kbeckett/articles/AJS.pdf&quot;&gt;affects&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt; low-income communities of color, especially when those communities &lt;u&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.journals.uchicago.edu/doi/abs/10.1086/691354&quot;&gt;aren’t well represented in local governments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt;. In 2015, as a follow-up to investigations of police bias in Ferguson, Mo., the Civil Rights Division of the Justice Department released the &lt;u&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.justice.gov/sites/default/files/opa/press-releases/attachments/2015/03/04/ferguson_police_department_report.pdf&quot;&gt;Ferguson report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt;, which painstakingly documents how the police department in that city relied overwhelmingly on fees and fines collected from people in ways that “both reflect and exacerbate existing racial bias.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;2&quot;&gt;But here’s another result of fee and fine enforcement that has never before been measured: Police departments that collect more in fees and fines are less effective at solving crimes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 data-elm-loc=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here’s how we did our research&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;4&quot;&gt;We document this relationship in a &lt;u&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/pdf/10.1177/1078087418791775&quot;&gt;recent article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt;. We started with detailed municipal finance data for 2007 and 2012 from the two most recent survey years of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.census.gov/programs-surveys/cog/data.html&quot;&gt;Census of Governments&lt;/a&gt;, a Census Bureau survey that collects detailed revenue and expenditure data from cities and towns. We combined that with crime clearance data for those same years from the FBI’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ucrdatatool.gov/&quot;&gt;Uniform Crime Reporting Program&lt;/a&gt;, which collects crime and policing data from law enforcement agencies nationwide. We could then examine whether departments that are successful at bringing in more municipal revenue are also effective at investigating crime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;5&quot;&gt;Examining nearly 6,000 cities’ finance and crime data for each of the two studied years, we find a strong link between revenue collection and clearance rates. Police departments in cities that collect a greater share of their revenue from fees, fines and civilly forfeited assets have significantly lower rates of solving violent and property crimes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;6&quot;&gt;We suspect that this comes simply from how these police departments focus their time and resources. Departments that need to collect fee and fine revenue shift their officers away from investigatory work. That’s especially true in smaller cities, where we found an especially clear link: Higher revenue from fees and fines meant fewer violent crimes solved. Cities with smaller departments and fewer resources are less likely to have specialized investigators, so when patrol officers are collecting revenue, they’re not investigating more serious crimes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 data-elm-loc=&quot;7&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here’s an example of how it works&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;8&quot;&gt;Let’s imagine a city of 50,000 people — call it Middletown — where the per capita income, racial demographics, crime rate and similar variables are the same as the state averages. Nationally, on average, municipalities bring in 2 percent of their revenue from fees and fines. If Middletown’s police department collected only about 1 percent of its revenue from fees and fines, our model predicts it would solve 53 percent of its violent crimes and 32 percent of its property crimes. But if Middletown’s police department instead collected 3 percent of its revenue from fees and fines, our model predicts that clearance rates would fall to 41 percent for violent crimes and 16 percent for property crimes. That’s a stark drop of 12 and 16 percentage points, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;9&quot;&gt;Some communities have a saying: “The police are never there when you need them and always there when you don’t.” Our findings help explain this adage. In cities where police are collecting revenue, communities are at once &lt;em&gt;overpoliced&lt;/em&gt; — because they are charged with more fines and fees — and &lt;em&gt;underpoliced&lt;/em&gt; — because serious crimes in their areas are less likely to be solved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;10&quot;&gt;This dynamic of simultaneous overpolicing and underpolicing reduces the community’s trust in policing and in government more generally. For many citizens, police interactions may be &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.annualreviews.org/doi/abs/10.1146/annurev-polisci-060415-093825&quot;&gt;their only contact with any government official&lt;/a&gt;. If citizens see the police in particular and the government in general as exploiting them for revenue, they are unlikely to see either as allies in keeping their communities safe. Low clearance rates, especially for violent crimes, reduce public trust in the police and in government as a whole — leading them not to cooperate with either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;11&quot;&gt;A good example of this in popular literature is Jill Leovy’s “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.penguinrandomhouse.com/books/100077/ghettoside-by-jill-leovy/9780385529990/&quot;&gt;Ghettoside&lt;/a&gt;,” which focuses on homicide policing in Los Angeles. A &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2017/3/1/14777612/trump-crime-certainty-severity&quot;&gt;vicious circle&lt;/a&gt; can emerge when police cannot or do not solve crimes, especially violent ones. Communities lose trust in the police, making it less likely that they’ll help the police solve crimes, which, in turn, increases the number of unsolved crimes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;12&quot;&gt;Almost 40 years ago, James Q. Wilson’s “&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hup.harvard.edu/catalog.php?isbn=9780674932111&quot;&gt;Varieties of Police&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hup.harvard.edu/catalog.php?isbn=9780674932111&quot;&gt;Beh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hup.harvard.edu/catalog.php?isbn=9780674932111&quot;&gt;avior&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hup.harvard.edu/catalog.php?isbn=9780674932111&quot;&gt;”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; described different “styles” of policing that departments develop. Some are aggressive, some not. Some are more courteous, some not. Some focus mostly on crime, while some take a broader view of their work. Our research shows that a municipality’s revenue approach can shape its police department’s style. When police are also revenue collectors, that shapes how citizens, especially poor citizens of color, relate to and perceive them. But it also reverberates in other ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;13&quot;&gt;Policing practices may be far more interconnected than observers have realized, with each policy choice reverberating in unexpected directions. Reforming institutions so that municipal governments rely less on fines and fees may also help improve police effectiveness and improve  public safety.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;14&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read more:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;15&quot; class=&quot;interstitial-link&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;[&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/monkey-cage/wp/2016/07/25/does-more-policing-lead-to-less-crime-or-just-more-racial-resentment/&quot;&gt;Does more policing lead to less crime — or just more racial resentment?&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;16&quot; class=&quot;interstitial-link&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;[&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/monkey-cage/wp/2018/08/29/we-gathered-data-on-every-confirmed-line-of-duty-police-killing-of-a-civilian-in-2014-and-2015-heres-what-we-found&quot;&gt;We gathered data on every confirmed, line-of-duty police killing of a civilian in 2014 and 2015. Here’s what we found.&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;17&quot; class=&quot;interstitial-link&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;[&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/monkey-cage/wp/2017/12/05/how-racial-diversity-makes-police-forces-better/&quot;&gt;How racial diversity makes police forces better&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;18&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://rebeccasgoldstein.com/&quot;&gt;Rebecca Goldstein&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;is a doctoral candidate in the department of government at Harvard University.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;19&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.memphis.edu/polisci/people/faculty_and_staff/sancesprofile.php&quot;&gt;Michael Sances&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;is an assistant professor in the department of political science at the University of Memphis.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;20&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://hyeyoungyou.com/&quot;&gt;Hye Young You&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;is an assistant professor in the Wilf Family Department of Politics at New York University.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 15:18:08 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>part997</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/monkey-cage/wp/2018/09/24/want-your-police-department-to-collect-more-fines-it-will-solve-fewer-crimes/</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/soppmi1gLYVL0GL_tNUCzYWUEnA=/1484x0/arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/326VZCWLXIY5FLCEEJ3RMJZRWM.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>Analysis | What happens to police departments that collect more fines? They solve fewer crimes.</og:title>
<og:description>That's a recipe for mistrust, resentment -- and still more unsolved crimes.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/monkey-cage/wp/2018/09/24/want-your-police-department-to-collect-more-fines-it-will-solve-fewer-crimes/?noredirect=on</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>If You&amp;#039;re Not Writing a Program, Don&amp;#039;t Use a Programming Language [video]</title>
<link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Fq5EQBFLEC8</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Fq5EQBFLEC8</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;eow-description&quot; class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Leslie Lamport: &quot;If You're Not Writing a Program, Don't Use a Programming Language&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Algorithms are not programs. They can and should be written with math rather than programming languages or pseudo-languages. This applies to many more algorithms than the ones taught in algorithm courses.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This video is also available on another stream:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/redirect?v=Fq5EQBFLEC8&amp;amp;redir_token=2ipcen-9w5SIny1ZOK1wP0lPerB8MTUzNzk0ODg4M0AxNTM3ODYyNDgz&amp;amp;q=http%3A%2F%2Fhitsmediaweb.h-its.org%2FMediasite%2FPlay%2Fabdee6c8696a48288ce8c3e004c50cd41d%3FplayFrom%3D13826%26autoStart%3Dfalse%26popout%3Dtrue&amp;amp;event=video_description&quot; class=&quot;yt-uix-sessionlink&quot; data-sessionlink=&quot;itct=CDUQ6TgYACITCMKJqJjY1d0CFVjbxAodS28Gvyj4HUivoKyKgYiR1xY&quot; data-target-new-window=&quot;True&quot; data-url=&quot;/redirect?v=Fq5EQBFLEC8&amp;amp;redir_token=2ipcen-9w5SIny1ZOK1wP0lPerB8MTUzNzk0ODg4M0AxNTM3ODYyNDgz&amp;amp;q=http%3A%2F%2Fhitsmediaweb.h-its.org%2FMediasite%2FPlay%2Fabdee6c8696a48288ce8c3e004c50cd41d%3FplayFrom%3D13826%26autoStart%3Dfalse%26popout%3Dtrue&amp;amp;event=video_description&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://hitsmediaweb.h-its.org/Mediasi...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;More information to the Heidelberg Laureate Forum:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Website: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/redirect?v=Fq5EQBFLEC8&amp;amp;redir_token=2ipcen-9w5SIny1ZOK1wP0lPerB8MTUzNzk0ODg4M0AxNTM3ODYyNDgz&amp;amp;q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.heidelberg-laureate-forum.org%2F&amp;amp;event=video_description&quot; class=&quot;yt-uix-sessionlink&quot; data-sessionlink=&quot;itct=CDUQ6TgYACITCMKJqJjY1d0CFVjbxAodS28Gvyj4HUivoKyKgYiR1xY&quot; data-target-new-window=&quot;True&quot; data-url=&quot;/redirect?v=Fq5EQBFLEC8&amp;amp;redir_token=2ipcen-9w5SIny1ZOK1wP0lPerB8MTUzNzk0ODg4M0AxNTM3ODYyNDgz&amp;amp;q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.heidelberg-laureate-forum.org%2F&amp;amp;event=video_description&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://www.heidelberg-laureate-forum....&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Facebook: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/redirect?v=Fq5EQBFLEC8&amp;amp;redir_token=2ipcen-9w5SIny1ZOK1wP0lPerB8MTUzNzk0ODg4M0AxNTM3ODYyNDgz&amp;amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2FHeidelbergLaureateForum&amp;amp;event=video_description&quot; class=&quot;yt-uix-sessionlink&quot; data-sessionlink=&quot;itct=CDUQ6TgYACITCMKJqJjY1d0CFVjbxAodS28Gvyj4HUivoKyKgYiR1xY&quot; data-target-new-window=&quot;True&quot; data-url=&quot;/redirect?v=Fq5EQBFLEC8&amp;amp;redir_token=2ipcen-9w5SIny1ZOK1wP0lPerB8MTUzNzk0ODg4M0AxNTM3ODYyNDgz&amp;amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2FHeidelbergLaureateForum&amp;amp;event=video_description&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://www.facebook.com/HeidelbergLa...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Twitter: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/redirect?v=Fq5EQBFLEC8&amp;amp;redir_token=2ipcen-9w5SIny1ZOK1wP0lPerB8MTUzNzk0ODg4M0AxNTM3ODYyNDgz&amp;amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Ftwitter.com%2Fhlforum&amp;amp;event=video_description&quot; class=&quot;yt-uix-sessionlink&quot; data-sessionlink=&quot;itct=CDUQ6TgYACITCMKJqJjY1d0CFVjbxAodS28Gvyj4HUivoKyKgYiR1xY&quot; data-target-new-window=&quot;True&quot; data-url=&quot;/redirect?v=Fq5EQBFLEC8&amp;amp;redir_token=2ipcen-9w5SIny1ZOK1wP0lPerB8MTUzNzk0ODg4M0AxNTM3ODYyNDgz&amp;amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Ftwitter.com%2Fhlforum&amp;amp;event=video_description&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://twitter.com/hlforum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Flickr: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/redirect?v=Fq5EQBFLEC8&amp;amp;redir_token=2ipcen-9w5SIny1ZOK1wP0lPerB8MTUzNzk0ODg4M0AxNTM3ODYyNDgz&amp;amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.flickr.com%2Fhlforum&amp;amp;event=video_description&quot; class=&quot;yt-uix-sessionlink&quot; data-sessionlink=&quot;itct=CDUQ6TgYACITCMKJqJjY1d0CFVjbxAodS28Gvyj4HUivoKyKgYiR1xY&quot; data-target-new-window=&quot;True&quot; data-url=&quot;/redirect?v=Fq5EQBFLEC8&amp;amp;redir_token=2ipcen-9w5SIny1ZOK1wP0lPerB8MTUzNzk0ODg4M0AxNTM3ODYyNDgz&amp;amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.flickr.com%2Fhlforum&amp;amp;event=video_description&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://www.flickr.com/hlforum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;More videos from the HLF: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/LaureateForum&quot; class=&quot;yt-uix-sessionlink&quot; data-sessionlink=&quot;itct=CDUQ6TgYACITCMKJqJjY1d0CFVjbxAodS28Gvyj4HUivoKyKgYiR1xY&quot; data-url=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/LaureateForum&quot;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/user/Laureate...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Blog: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/redirect?v=Fq5EQBFLEC8&amp;amp;redir_token=2ipcen-9w5SIny1ZOK1wP0lPerB8MTUzNzk0ODg4M0AxNTM3ODYyNDgz&amp;amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Fscilogs.spektrum.de%2Fhlf%2F&amp;amp;event=video_description&quot; class=&quot;yt-uix-sessionlink&quot; data-sessionlink=&quot;itct=CDUQ6TgYACITCMKJqJjY1d0CFVjbxAodS28Gvyj4HUivoKyKgYiR1xY&quot; data-target-new-window=&quot;True&quot; data-url=&quot;/redirect?v=Fq5EQBFLEC8&amp;amp;redir_token=2ipcen-9w5SIny1ZOK1wP0lPerB8MTUzNzk0ODg4M0AxNTM3ODYyNDgz&amp;amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Fscilogs.spektrum.de%2Fhlf%2F&amp;amp;event=video_description&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://scilogs.spektrum.de/hlf/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 15:02:30 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>azhenley</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Fq5EQBFLEC8</og:url>
<og:title>6th HLF – Lecture: Leslie Lamport</og:title>
<og:image>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/Fq5EQBFLEC8/maxresdefault.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>Leslie Lamport: &quot;If You're Not Writing a Program, Don't Use a Programming Language&quot; Algorithms are not programs. They can and should be written with math rat...</og:description>
<og:type>video.other</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Fq5EQBFLEC8</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Show HN: A new protocol for packet radio including ECDSA and compression</title>
<link>https://github.com/brannondorsey/chattervox</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/brannondorsey/chattervox</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;Box-body p-6&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;markdown-body entry-content&quot; itemprop=&quot;text&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://travis-ci.com/brannondorsey/chattervox&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/82b91c95bc576e065cc6e69873e1c9de22d00902/68747470733a2f2f7472617669732d63692e636f6d2f6272616e6e6f6e646f727365792f63686174746572766f782e7376673f6272616e63683d6d6173746572&quot; alt=&quot;Travis CI Build Image&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://travis-ci.com/brannondorsey/chattervox.svg?branch=master&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://coveralls.io/github/brannondorsey/chattervox?branch=master&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/18c32a8e5d5f224934b7dda4f3be0c5fd9165f1d/68747470733a2f2f636f766572616c6c732e696f2f7265706f732f6769746875622f6272616e6e6f6e646f727365792f63686174746572766f782f62616467652e7376673f6272616e63683d6d6173746572&quot; alt=&quot;Coverage Status&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://coveralls.io/repos/github/brannondorsey/chattervox/badge.svg?branch=master&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An AX.25 packet radio chat protocol with support for digital signatures and binary compression. Like IRC over radio waves 📡.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chattervox implements a minimal &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/brannondorsey/chattervox#the-protocol&quot;&gt;packet radio protocol&lt;/a&gt; on top of AX.25 that can be used with a terminal node controller (TNC) like &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/wb2osz/direwolf&quot;&gt;Direwolf&lt;/a&gt; to transmit and receive digitally signed messages using audio frequency shift keying modulation (AFSK). In the United States, it's illegal to broadcast encrypted messages on amateur radio frequencies. Chattervox respects this law, while using elliptic curve cryptography and digital signatures to protect against message spoofing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With amateur packet radio anyone can pretend to be anyone else. With Chattervox, you can be sure you're chatting with the person you intend to. For more information, check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/brannondorsey/chattervox/blob/master/FAQ.md&quot;&gt;FAQ&lt;/a&gt; or the discussion about chattervox on &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=18058031&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;hackernews&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE&lt;/strong&gt; (September 24th, 2018): Please understand that this software is in &lt;strong&gt;beta&lt;/strong&gt; and I ask for your patience until development stabilizes. While I'm very excited to see that interest in the project is high, It's quite unexpected and I have spent very little time testing the software (aside from automated tests). If you have a problem, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/brannondorsey/chattervox/issues&quot;&gt;please submit a detailed issue&lt;/a&gt; and I'll have a look. I'll be writing a tutorial explaining how to get up and running with chattervox very soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/brannondorsey/chattervox/blob/master/.images/baofeng.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/brannondorsey/chattervox/raw/master/.images/baofeng.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Baofeng UV-5R Linux setup&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chattervox requires a linux computer and a serial connection to a TNC to send and receive AX.25 packets. I recommend using &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/wb2osz/direwolf&quot;&gt;Direwolf&lt;/a&gt;, a popular software TNC which can be run on the same computer hosting the &lt;code&gt;chattervox&lt;/code&gt; application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You'll also need a radio and a cable to connect the microphone and speaker from the radio to your linux machine. I recommend the following equipment, especially if you're on a budget:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;$24 Baofeng UV-5R 4-watt radio. This is the absolute best radio you can buy for that price.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;$18 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/BTECH-APRS-K1-Interface-APRSDroid-Compatible/dp/B01LMIBAZW&amp;amp;keywords=btech+aprs+cable&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BTech APRS cable&lt;/a&gt; (3.5mm TRRS to 3.5mm and 2.5mm audio cable)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can also make the cable yourself if you prefer. Check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://books.vvvvvvaria.org/read/41/pdf&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;this zine&lt;/a&gt; for instructions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, to operate legally on amateur radio frequencies, you'll need an amateur radio license.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Download&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Binary downloads are available for Linux x64 and x86 architectures on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/brannondorsey/chattervox/releases&quot;&gt;releases page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have &lt;code&gt;npm&lt;/code&gt;, that is the preferred method of install as it allows for the easiest upgrade to the latest version. If you prefer to &quot;build&quot; it from Typescript source and run it as a Node.js app, you can do that as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;NPM&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
npm install --cli -g chattervox@latest 
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Source&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt; clone the repo&lt;/span&gt;
git clone https://github.com/brannondorsey/chattervox
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;cd&lt;/span&gt; chattervox

&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt; download dependencies&lt;/span&gt;
npm install

&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt; transpile the src/*.ts typescript files to build/*.js&lt;/span&gt;
npm run build

&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt; run chattervox from source to opening the chat room&lt;/span&gt;
node build/main.js chat
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Usage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt; open the chat room&lt;/span&gt;
chattervox chat

&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt; generate a new public/private key pair, and use it as your default signing key&lt;/span&gt;
chattervox genkey --make-signing

&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt; add a friend's public key to your keyring, so that chattervox can verify their messages&lt;/span&gt;
chattervox addkey KC3LZO 0489a1d94d700d6e45508d12a4eb9be93386b5b30feb2b4aa07836398781e3d444e04b54a6e01cf752e54ef423770c00a6

&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt; remove a friend's public key if it has become compromised &lt;/span&gt;
chattervox removekey KC3LZO 0489a1d94d700d6e45508d12a4eb9be93386b5b30feb2b4aa07836398781e3d444e04b54a6e01cf752e54ef423770c00a6

&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt; print all keys in your keyring&lt;/span&gt;
chattervox showkey
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;usage: chattervox [-h] [-v] [--config CONFIG]
                  {chat,showkey,addkey,removekey,genkey} ...

An AX.25 ham radio chat protocol with support for digital signatures
and binary compression.

Optional arguments:
  -h, --help            Show this help message and exit.
  -v, --version         Show program's version number and exit.
  --config CONFIG, -c CONFIG
                        Path to config file (default: ~/.chattervox/config.json)

subcommands:
  {chat,showkey,addkey,removekey,genkey}
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Protocol&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The chattervox packet is primitive and straightforward. It contains a simple header, an optional ECDSA digital signature, and a message payload that can be in plaintext or compressed. As of packet version 1, the protocol is connectionless. There is only one type of packet and there is no mechanism for delivery confirmation (think of it like UDP). It is expected to be transported via AX.25 Unnumbered Information (UI) packets, which the chattervox program relies on for sender and recipient information, as no such fields exists in the packet itself to conserve space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The protocol may be amended in the future to add new features, however, its simplicity should not be seen as a weakness. The goal of chattervox is singular: &lt;strong&gt;Add cryptographic verifiability to text-based radio communication.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Chattervox Protocol v1 Packet&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;Byte Offset&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;# of Bits&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Name&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Value&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;0x0000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;16&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Magic Header&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0x7a39&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A constant two-byte value used to identify chattervox packets.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;0x0002&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Version Byte&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Number&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A protocol version number between 1-255.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;0x0003&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Unused Flag Bits&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Null&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Reserved for future use.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;0x0003&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Digital Signature Flag&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Bit&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A value of 1 indicates that the message contains a ECDSA digital signature.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;0x0003&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Compression Flag&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Bit&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A value of 1 indicates that the message payload is compressed.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;[0x0004]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;[8]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;[Signature Length]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Number&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The length in bytes of the digital signature. This field is only included if the Digital Signature Flag is set.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;[0x0004 or 0x0005]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;[0-2048]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;[Digital Signature]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Bytes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The ECDSA digital signature created using a SHA256 hash of the message contents and the sender's private key.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;0x0004-0x104&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0-∞&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Message&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Bytes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The packet's UTF-8 message payload. If the Compression Flag is set the contents of this buffer is a &lt;a href=&quot;https://nodejs.org/api/zlib.html#zlib_zlib_deflateraw_buffer_options_callback&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;raw DEFLATE buffer&lt;/a&gt; containing the UTF-8 message.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;[] indicates an optional field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;TypeScript chattervox client&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This repository serves as the first implementation of the protocol. The &lt;code&gt;chattervox&lt;/code&gt; command-line tool acts as a client to send and receive chattervox packets in combination with a TNC. This implementation creates a new ECDSA keypair the first time it's run and includes a digital signature for each message (so long as there remains a &lt;code&gt;signingKey&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code&gt;~/.chattervox/config.json&lt;/code&gt;). Each message is temporarily compressed by the client before it's sent in an attempt to measure the efficiency of the DEFLATE compression algorithm. If the compressed version is smaller than the uncompressed version, the compressed buffer is used as the message payload and the compression bit is set in the chattervox packet. If the plaintext version is smaller, no compression is used and the original message text is used as the payload.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 14:36:53 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>braxxox</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars2.githubusercontent.com/u/3193533?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>brannondorsey/chattervox</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/brannondorsey/chattervox</og:url>
<og:description>📡 An AX.25 packet radio chat protocol with support for digital signatures and binary compression. Like IRC over radio waves. 〰 - brannondorsey/chattervox</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/brannondorsey/chattervox</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>YubiKey 5 Series with New NFC and FIDO2 Passwordless Features</title>
<link>https://www.yubico.com/2018/09/introducing-the-yubikey-5-series-with-new-nfc-and-fido2-passwordless-features/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.yubico.com/2018/09/introducing-the-yubikey-5-series-with-new-nfc-and-fido2-passwordless-features/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Today, we are announcing some exciting news that we know you’ve all been waiting for. The 5th generation YubiKey has arrived!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;780&quot; height=&quot;424&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Y7jMarlnxac&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Our new YubiKey 5 Series is comprised of four multi-protocol security keys, including two much anticipated new features: FIDO2 / WebAuthn and NFC (near field communication).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The YubiKey 5 Series is the industry’s first set of multi-protocol security keys to support&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.yubico.com/solutions/fido2/&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;FIDO2&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w3.org/TR/webauthn/&quot;&gt;WebAuthn&lt;/a&gt;, the open authentication standard that Yubico helped to pioneer, along with Microsoft and others. All leading platforms and browsers have either made support or are engaged in this standards work, expanding authentication choices using authentication devices, such as a YubiKey, with or without a username and password. Each key in the YubiKey 5 series supports: FIDO2 / WebAuthn, FIDO U2F, PIV (smart card), OpenPGP, Yubico OTP, OATH-TOTP, OATH-HOTP, and challenge-response.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;With the new YubiKey 5 series, Yubico provides a solution that not only works for today’s authentication scenarios, but into tomorrow’s, helping to bridge the gap from existing solutions to a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.yubico.com/2018/04/yubico-and-microsoft-introduce-passwordless-login/&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;future of passwordless login&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;. Users will receive the same trusted security, ease of use, and durability expected from a YubiKey, but will now have the added option of passwordless logins using FIDO2:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_386137&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-386137 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://www.yubico.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/Screen-Shot-2018-09-13-at-3.52.07-PM.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;281&quot; height=&quot;459&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Authentication options with the YubiKey 5 Series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Single-Factor Authentication (Passwordless) with the YubiKey 5 Series – &lt;/strong&gt;The YubiKey 5 security keys can be used alone for strong single-factor authentication, requiring no username or password to login — just tap or touch to authenticate.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Second-Factor Authentication with the YubiKey 5 Series – &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;Used alongside a username and password, the YubiKey 5 series offers a strong second factor of authentication. This is the YubiKey integration that exists today with services like Google, Twitter, and Facebook, and it is most familiar to our users.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multi-Factor Authentication (Passwordless + PIN + Touch) with the YubiKey 5 Series – &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;The YubiKey 5 series can be used in conjunction with a PIN for user verification. In this case, the PIN unlocks the device locally and touch is still required for the YubiKey to perform the authentication.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;With this expanded choice of authentication modes, developers choosing to add support for the YubiKey will have the option to choose the authentication model that best suits their use cases and customers. Implementation resources for all of the YubiKey-supported protocols can be found on the&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.yubico.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Yubico Developer website&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;or through the&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.yubico.com/why-yubico/for-developers/developer-program/&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Yubico Developer Program mailing list&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Another much anticipated feature added with the YubiKey 5 series, is the addition of NFC to the YubiKey 5 NFC device, allowing for a seamless and secure tap-and-go experience with mobile devices or external NFC readers.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_386133&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption alignright&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-386133 size-medium&quot; src=&quot;https://www.yubico.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/YK5_NFC_Keychain-444x296.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;444&quot; height=&quot;296&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.yubico.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/YK5_NFC_Keychain-444x296.jpg 444w, https://www.yubico.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/YK5_NFC_Keychain-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.yubico.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/YK5_NFC_Keychain-1030x687.jpg 1030w, https://www.yubico.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/YK5_NFC_Keychain-1500x1000.jpg 1500w, https://www.yubico.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/YK5_NFC_Keychain-705x470.jpg 705w, https://www.yubico.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/YK5_NFC_Keychain-450x300.jpg 450w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 444px) 100vw, 444px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;YubiKey 5 NFC&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Combining the security and usability features of FIDO2 passwordless authentication and tap-and-go NFC provides an optimal user experience, and drastically improves security and productivity. This is especially beneficial in fast-paced, dispersed working environments within sectors such as financial services, healthcare, and retail point-of-sale (POS). FIDO2 is the first open standard authentication protocol that can take tap-and-go authentication to the masses.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The YubiKey 5 Series includes: YubiKey 5 NFC, YubiKey 5 Nano, YubiKey 5C, and YubiKey 5C Nano. To determine the key that is best for you, please reference the online&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.yubico.com/products/yubikey-hardware/compare-yubikeys/&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;comparison chart&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, or take our&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.yubico.com/quiz/&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;YubiKey quiz&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Beginning today, YubiKey 5 Series security keys are available for purchase exclusively at Yubico.com.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.yubico.com/store/&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Shop our store&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, and be one of the first to own a YubiKey 5!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 11:06:10 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ofrzeta</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Introducing the YubiKey 5 Series with New NFC and FIDO2 Passwordless Features | Yubico</og:title>
<og:description>Today, Yubico announced the availability of its new YubiKey 5 Series, the industry’s first set of multi-protocol security keys to support FIDO2 / WebAuthn for the future of passwordless logins.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.yubico.com/2018/09/introducing-the-yubikey-5-series-with-new-nfc-and-fido2-passwordless-features/</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.yubico.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/yk5-blog-header-green.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.yubico.com/2018/09/introducing-the-yubikey-5-series-with-new-nfc-and-fido2-passwordless-features/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Self-solving Rubik&amp;#039;s Cube</title>
<link>https://media.dmm-make.com/item/4462/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://media.dmm-make.com/item/4462/</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;dtl-main-img&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.dmm-make.com/item/4462/mainImage1994606812&quot; alt=&quot;全自動ルービックキューブ　Self Solving Rubik's Cube&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;box-info&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;icon-makers&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://media.dmm-make.com/maker/4387/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.dmm-make.com/maker/4387/image-small&quot; alt=&quot;Human Controller&quot; class=&quot;img-circle&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;txt-area&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;name&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://media.dmm-make.com/maker/4387/&quot;&gt;Human Controller (ID4387)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;time&quot;&gt;2018/09/17&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;favo&quot; title=&quot;お気に入り/リスト登録&quot; data-ng-controller=&quot;addListController&quot; data-ng-click=&quot;show()&quot; data-fav-count=&quot;4462&quot;&gt;0&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;share clearfix&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;facebook&quot;&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;twitter&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/share&quot; class=&quot;twitter-share-button&quot; data-lang=&quot;ja&quot; data-url=&quot;https://media.dmm-make.com/item/4462/&quot; data-count=&quot;none&quot;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;hatena&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://b.hatena.ne.jp/entry/https://media.dmm-make.com/item/4462/&quot; class=&quot;hatena-bookmark-button&quot; data-hatena-bookmark-title=&quot;DMM.make&quot; data-hatena-bookmark-layout=&quot;standard-balloon&quot; data-hatena-bookmark-lang=&quot;ja&quot; title=&quot;このエントリーをはてなブックマークに追加&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://b.hatena.ne.jp/images/entry-button/button-only@2x.png&quot; alt=&quot;このエントリーをはてなブックマークに追加&quot; width=&quot;20&quot; height=&quot;20&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;https://youtu.be/xCoH2AORcEQ&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;dtl-img-area&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.dmm-make.com/item/4462/236873/image&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;dtl-img-area&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.dmm-make.com/item/4462/236874/image&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;dtl-img-area&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.dmm-make.com/item/4462/236875/image&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://youtu.be/7WXclH8OubA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;dtl-img-area&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.dmm-make.com/item/4462/236871/image&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;dtl-img-area&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.dmm-make.com/item/4462/236872/image&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;dtl-img-area&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.dmm-make.com/item/4462/236901/image&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;dtl-img-area&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.dmm-make.com/item/4462/236908/image&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;dtl-img-area&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.dmm-make.com/item/4462/236866/image&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;dtl-img-area&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.dmm-make.com/item/4462/236867/image&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;dtl-img-area&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.dmm-make.com/item/4462/236868/image&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;dtl-img-area&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.dmm-make.com/item/4462/236869/image&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;dtl-img-area&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.dmm-make.com/item/4462/236893/image&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://youtu.be/cExtbByvAEw&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;refererd-report&quot; readability=&quot;9.2156862745098&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;参考にしてくれた記事&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;no-repeat&quot;&gt;記事が登録されていません。&lt;br/&gt;この記事を参考にして、&lt;span&gt;新しく記事を投稿しよう！&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;btn-area&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;well&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://media.dmm-make.com/item/edit/?ref=4462&quot; class=&quot;btn btn-primary&quot;&gt;投稿する&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;box-detail-bottom&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;share clearfix&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;facebook&quot;&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;twitter&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/share&quot; class=&quot;twitter-share-button&quot; data-lang=&quot;ja&quot; data-url=&quot;https://media.dmm-make.com/item/4462/&quot; data-count=&quot;none&quot;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;hatena&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://b.hatena.ne.jp/entry/https://media.dmm-make.com/item/4462/&quot; class=&quot;hatena-bookmark-button&quot; data-hatena-bookmark-title=&quot;DMM.make&quot; data-hatena-bookmark-layout=&quot;standard-balloon&quot; data-hatena-bookmark-lang=&quot;ja&quot; title=&quot;このエントリーをはてなブックマークに追加&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://b.hatena.ne.jp/images/entry-button/button-only@2x.png&quot; alt=&quot;このエントリーをはてなブックマークに追加&quot; width=&quot;20&quot; height=&quot;20&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 11:04:28 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>murkle</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://media.dmm-make.com/item/4462/</og:url>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:title>全自動ルービックキューブ　Self Solving Rubik&amp;#039;s Cube by Human Controller - DMM.make</og:title>
<og:image>https://img.dmm-make.com/item/4462/mainImage1994606812</og:image>
<og:description>全自動ルービックキューブ　Self Solving Rubik&amp;#039;s Cube</og:description>
<dc:language>ja</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://media.dmm-make.com/item/4462/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>