<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Sonos is spying on me (and you)</title>
<link>https://blog.gingerlime.com/2020/sonos-is-spying-on-me-and-you/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.gingerlime.com/2020/sonos-is-spying-on-me-and-you/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I recently decided to get a wireless speaker for our Kitchen. Sonos seems like an obvious choice these days. The sound quality and aesthetics were very appealing. So I ordered a Sonos One SL speaker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of sound quality and looks, I was very pleased. I’m not an audiophile but the sound quality seemed superb and the speaker just looks fantastic. A very clean and unassuming look.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-image&quot;&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; width=&quot;768&quot; height=&quot;1024&quot; src=&quot;https://blog.gingerlime.com/assets/IMG_6571-1-768x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-2644&quot; srcset=&quot;https://blog.gingerlime.com/assets/IMG_6571-1-768x1024.jpg 768w, https://blog.gingerlime.com/assets/IMG_6571-1-225x300.jpg 225w, https://blog.gingerlime.com/assets/IMG_6571-1.jpg 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 706px) 89vw, (max-width: 767px) 82vw, 740px&quot;/&gt;what’s hiding underneath ?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As I later discovered, a dirty beast hides under the cool exterior.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;more-2630&quot;/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My concerns started to grow almost immediately as I was setting up the new speaker. I downloaded the app, and started the setup process, soon to realize that I need to register with my email just to set up the device on my network… And of course, I had to accept the terms and conditions …. hmmm… ok, I guess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-image&quot;&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; src=&quot;https://blog.gingerlime.com/assets/IMG_92F6A34207E1-1-576x1024.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-2640&quot; width=&quot;236&quot; height=&quot;420&quot; srcset=&quot;https://blog.gingerlime.com/assets/IMG_92F6A34207E1-1-576x1024.jpeg 576w, https://blog.gingerlime.com/assets/IMG_92F6A34207E1-1-169x300.jpeg 169w, https://blog.gingerlime.com/assets/IMG_92F6A34207E1-1.jpeg 750w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 236px) 100vw, 236px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-image&quot;&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; src=&quot;https://blog.gingerlime.com/assets/IMG_31E9A893CD62-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-2642&quot; width=&quot;203&quot; height=&quot;361&quot; srcset=&quot;https://blog.gingerlime.com/assets/IMG_31E9A893CD62-1.png 375w, https://blog.gingerlime.com/assets/IMG_31E9A893CD62-1-169x300.png 169w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 203px) 100vw, 203px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was then asked to allow sharing my location as well, which raised another alarm bell. &lt;strong&gt;Why does my speaker need my location?&lt;/strong&gt; I’m not 100% sure, but if I recall, I had to allow it to access my location, or else I couldn’t continue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the device was finally set up, I went through the settings, to explore and see what else is there. I was rather disappointed to find that &lt;strong&gt;“Additional usage data” was turned on by default&lt;/strong&gt;. I live in Europe, and I thought that the EU regulations should prevent this kind of behaviour. They should explicitly ask my permission to track my usage, especially if it isn’t necessary for the device to function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could opt-out of it luckily, but it didn’t feel right to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What data is Sonos collecting, and why?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Digging into the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sonos.com/en/legal/privacy&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;Sonos privacy policy&lt;/a&gt; made my hair stand…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-group has-black-color has-cyan-bluish-gray-background-color has-text-color has-background&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-group__inner-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Functional Data:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This data is absolutely necessary for your Sonos Product or Service, including Sonos Radio, to perform its basic functions in a secure way and &lt;strong&gt;you will not be able to opt out from this data collection, sharing, and/or processing&lt;/strong&gt; if you want to continue to use your Sonos Products.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We collect:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Registration data.&lt;/strong&gt; This data includes your email address, location, language preference, Product serial number, IP address, and Sonos account login information (as described above).&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;System data.&lt;/strong&gt; This data includes things like Product type, controller device type, controller operating system, software version, content source (audio line in), signal input (e.g. whether your TV outputs a specific audio signal such as Dolby to your Sonos system), information about WiFi antennas, system settings (such as equalisation or stereo pair), Product orientation, names of the music service(s) you added/enabled on your Sonos product, the names you have given your Sonos Product in different rooms, whether your Product has been tuned using Sonos Trueplay technology, system performance metrics (e.g. the temperature of your Product or WiFi signal strength) and error information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(emphasis not mine)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this is &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; the data that you &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;cannot&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; opt-out of. The data &lt;strong&gt;absolutely necessary to perform basic functions.&lt;/strong&gt; And in case you wonder why they track this data, here’s what the privacy policy says&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-group has-cyan-bluish-gray-background-color has-background&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-group__inner-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why we collect Functional Data:&lt;/strong&gt; We collect this information to help ensure that your Products are working properly, to provide you with customer support, to honour your audio preferences, and to guide product improvement and customer support decisions. We also collect this information to guide product improvement and customer support decisions which is &lt;strong&gt;our legitimate interest&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;emphasis mine… we’ll go back to what &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;legitimate interest&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; actually means later on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure what basic functions for a speaker might be, that they require to share so much data with Sonos. And if this not enough, there’s also the (optional) Usage data that Sonos happily collects, by default, without asking for permission&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-group&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-group__inner-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-group has-cyan-bluish-gray-background-color has-background&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-group__inner-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Additional Usage Data:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to improve your experience with Sonos Products and to offer better, personalised Sonos Products and Services, including Sonos Radio, that meet the needs and expectations of our customers, we collect the following Additional Usage Data. The processing of this information is in our legitimate interest as further set out below (under Why). You can opt out of sharing this data by following the steps listed &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sonos.com/en/legal/privacy#data-opt-out&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We collect:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Performance Information.&lt;/strong&gt; This includes things like the temperature of your Product, WiFi information like signal strength, how often you use music services you have connected to your Sonos system (including, for some services, your login username, but not password), information about how often you use the Sonos app versus other control mechanisms, flow of interactions within the Sonos app, how often you use the physical controls on the unit, the flow of interactions within the Sonos app, duration of Sonos Product use, and, as required for certain Services, location-based data using GPS (or similar technology, where available) and crowdsourced WiFi access points and cell tower locations collected from your third party device when the Sonos app is in use.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Activity Information.&lt;/strong&gt; This includes duration of music service use, Product or room grouping information, command information (such as play, pause, change volume, or skip tracks), information about playlist or station container data including listening history (‘Recently Played’), and Sonos playlist or Sonos favourites information; each correlated to individual Sonos Products and your interactions with them. If you enable voice control or use Sonos Radio, we will additionally collect information about track data when using those features.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;wp-block-quote&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why:&lt;/strong&gt; We collect this information so that we can help ensure Sonos Products are functioning properly, provide a personalised experience for our customers, determine what types of Product or feature improvements would please our customers most, and to help predict potential problems with Sonos Products. Additionally, to provide Sonos Radio, we collect location-based information for licensing and reporting purposes. &lt;strong&gt;Collecting this data is our legitimate interest&lt;/strong&gt; to support a user-friendly experience that meets your needs and help you with issues you may experience. It is your choice if you want us to collect this information, and therefore you can opt out of sharing this data by following the steps listed &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sonos.com/en/legal/privacy#rights-choices&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; personalisation services (e.g. Recently Played), Sonos Radio, Voice Control, and Direct Control functionality require Additional Usage Data to function. If you decide to use any of these features and/or Services, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sonos.com/en/legal/privacy#additional-data&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;Additional Usage Data&lt;/a&gt; becomes functional. You can always clear all Recently Played by following the instructions in the Sonos app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, the legitimate interest emphasis is mine…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you read their privacy policy further, you could spot the real incentives and potential uses of the data, but I won’t dive into it here. I do recommend reading it though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;(il)legitimate interest&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what is this all about? Well, if you’re familiar with the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), you might guess the answer. I’m not a lawyer, so without going into too much detail, here’s my brief understanding of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First off, the GDPR is the regulation that aims to protect the privacy of all EU citizens. It’s meant to reduce privacy invasive practices, force companies to protect private data, and encourage companies to treat private data with care and respect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what’s “legitimate interest”, and why is it important?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Essentially, companies aren’t simply allowed to store any customer data they want. They need a “good reason” to do so. Or in other words, they need to have a legitimate interest in storing such data. Otherwise, they’re simply not allowed to store it at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So now, can I just ask someone who accesses my website “What’s your home address”? and store it, if they give it to me. I need to have a real reason to ask for this address. It can be my legitimate interest to ask it if, for example, I’m going to send you a free gift. I obviously can’t send you a gift without knowing your address.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can imagine, “legitimate interest” can be interpreted in many different ways. Is it legitimate interest to ask for an email address in order to send marketing emails? well, actually it might be. There’s no black and white answer here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Putting it to the test&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are &lt;a href=&quot;https://ico.org.uk/for-organisations/guide-to-data-protection/guide-to-the-general-data-protection-regulation-gdpr/legitimate-interests/what-is-the-legitimate-interests-basis/#balancing_test&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;3 tests for “legitimate interest”&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-group&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-group__inner-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-group has-luminous-vivid-amber-background-color has-background&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-group__inner-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Purpose test&lt;/strong&gt; – is there a legitimate interest behind the processing?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Necessity test&lt;/strong&gt; – is the processing necessary for that purpose?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Balancing test&lt;/strong&gt; – is the legitimate interest overridden by the individual’s interests, rights or freedoms?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst Sonos tries very hard to meet those first two tests with their policies (but in my opinion, have a very weak position there), I think it clearly fails the balancing test. Sonos blatantly violates its customer privacy by excessively tracking, analysing and making use of very detailed information about them. They capture their listening preferences, their location, neighbouring Wifi access points and lots more. And worse of all, they do it without asking for explicit consent. It’s all hidden in the privacy policy, and set to expose all this data by default.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What’s the &lt;strong&gt;purpose&lt;/strong&gt; of collecting all this data? Sonos claims that their purpose is “[To] help ensure Sonos Products are functioning properly, provide a personalised experience for our customers, determine what types of Product or feature improvements would please our customers most, and to help predict potential problems with Sonos Products”. This seems fairly clear as a purpose. Still rather widespread and invasive, but there’s a purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But is collecting all this data &lt;strong&gt;necessary&lt;/strong&gt; to meet this purpose? I don’t think so. I think they collect far too detailed information, and they could meet the same purpose with far less data, or by using non-private / anonymised data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example: how does the IP address of the customer help with any of those stated purposes? Or why do they need to map neighbouring Wifi access points? I guess Sonos would claim something along the lines of “if a customer has a problem, these details help us support this customer and troubleshoot the problem”. But then is it &lt;strong&gt;necessary&lt;/strong&gt; to collect this data constantly, even when there are no problems?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To drive product decisions and understand usage trends, they can collect data that’s been anonymised and still be able to improve features. In my mind, most of this collection is &lt;strong&gt;unnecessary&lt;/strong&gt;. Rather than collect all this data indiscriminately and bundle all those purposes together, each purpose and data collection should be examined individually. The necessity argument easily breaks if you look at individual purposes and the data being collected to fulfill the specific purpose. Do they need to collect all this &lt;strong&gt;personal&lt;/strong&gt; data about me to determine what feature improvements would please their customers most? I don’t think so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s a quick data point to you, Sonos: &lt;strong&gt;I’m not pleased by your excessive data collection&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And finally, let’s look at whether this &lt;strong&gt;excessive collection overrides the individual’s interests, rights and freedoms&lt;/strong&gt;. I think the answer is as clear as day. &lt;strong&gt;The Sonos speaker works totally fine, even without an Internet connection&lt;/strong&gt;. It meets the criteria of most customers who buy a speaker: it plays music via Wifi. The data collection that Sonos does isn’t primarily to help their customers. It’s to help Sonos learn more about its customers, sell aggregate data, and advertise to its customers. I’m pretty sure that if you ask a Sonos customer whether they want a “personalized experience” from their Sonos speaker, they will look back at you with a confused look on their faces… It’s a speaker. It plays what I ask it to play… If I buy a speaker, do I want it to manipulate me with ads based on my listening preferences? No. Can a reasonable person even imagine that so much data about their usage is being collected, by default, when they buy a speaker? absolutely not. This is far from balanced. It weighs heavily in Sonos’ interests, and those do not align with the interests of its customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I therefore find it very hard to believe that Sonos can really meet the legitimate interest tests. They are clearly using “legitimate interests” in the privacy policy language to protect themselves against a potential GDPR claim. However, I think it’s a thin veil, and they clearly fail to balance the privacy needs of their customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What can you do about it?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a few things I think we should collectively do to stop this kind of practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the practical/technical level: try to block Sonos from collecting data about you. This requires some technical knowledge unfortunately, so most people won’t be able to do much. But even if you’re not technical, you can still do a lot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Opt-out of Additional data usage&lt;/strong&gt;: this is a super-simple thing you can do inside your Sonos app to reduce the amount of data you share with Sonos.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t connect your Sonos to 3rd party services:&lt;/strong&gt; Sonos would encourage you to give it access to your Spotify account, Amazon, Apple or any other 3rd party music service. You don’t actually need it in most cases. You can use the music service directly, and just play it on your Sonos speaker as a destination (e.g. using Airplay).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Block Sonos from accessing the internet:&lt;/strong&gt; many routers allow you to block individual IP or MAC addresses from accessing the internet. Beyond the initial setup, your Sonos speaker can work fine without an internet connection. If you can and know how to, block it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use a privacy-blocking DNS product or service:&lt;/strong&gt; For example: &lt;a href=&quot;https://pi-hole.net/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;Pi-hole&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://nextdns.io/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;Nextdns&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&quot;https://adguard.com/en/adguard-home/overview.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;Adguard home&lt;/a&gt; all offer options to block your Sonos (and many other privacy-invasive apps and services) from sending personal data, without affecting other functionality.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Complain to Sonos about it&lt;/strong&gt;: let them know that you’re unhappy. If they truly look at ways of pleasing their customers, they should collect some data that &lt;strong&gt;this practice makes their customers unhappy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/reform/rights-citizens/redress/what-should-i-do-if-i-think-my-personal-data-protection-rights-havent-been-respected_en&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;File a GDPR complaint&lt;/a&gt;: if you are a EU citizen or live in Europe. You should be protected by the GDPR. The more complaints about Sonos, the higher the chances of the regulators taking action against Sonos and forcing them to stop those practices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Become a member to &lt;a href=&quot;https://noyb.eu/en/support-us&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;support NYOB&lt;/a&gt;. This is a non-profit privacy-focused organization that helps fight against privacy violations. Disclaimer: I am a member, and I’m in discussion with one of their lawyers to promote some privacy initiatives. Other than promoting their cause, I have nothing to gain (financial or otherwise) from endorsing them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2020 17:18:45 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>gingerlime</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.gingerlime.com/2020/sonos-is-spying-on-me-and-you/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why I left my tenured academic job</title>
<link>https://reyammer.io/blog/2020/10/03/the-good-the-bad-and-the-bye-bye-why-i-left-my-tenured-academic-job/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://reyammer.io/blog/2020/10/03/the-good-the-bad-and-the-bye-bye-why-i-left-my-tenured-academic-job/</guid>
<description>&lt;time datetime=&quot;2020-10-03T09:00:00+0200&quot; class=&quot;post-date&quot;&gt;Sat, Oct 3, 2020&lt;/time&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RSS:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://reyammer.io/blog/index.xml&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://reyammer.io/rss.png&quot; width=&quot;23px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/reyammer/status/1311338230139232258&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;news is out&lt;/a&gt;: I left France, I'm no longer a professor at EURECOM, I joined the Malware Research Team at CISCO Talos, and I moved to beautiful Vienna. Big change :-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been a professor for a bit more than three years, but I have had contrasting feelings about the &quot;prof job&quot; for a long time (even before finishing my PhD), it took me a couple of years to realize that I would eventually have needed to move on, and it took even more (mental) effort to actually make the call and leave. Despite being &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; excited for what's next, oh boy, this was tough :-) But independently of the concrete next step, it was time to move on. Even if Talos realizes the mistake and kicks me out next week, I'm still confident that moving on was the right call.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Especially when it comes to take big decisions, I tend to obsess about trying to stay rational, and I spent years collecting notes on the various pros/cons. Many of these thoughts often started surfacing as &quot;feeling something is not right&quot;, without consciously understanding what was going on. But by keep thinking and writing notes down, patterns of thoughts started to emerge and I was eventually able to pinpoint some more defined thoughts on what kept me on the current job and what pushed me to change. Once these reasons were clear, it was much easier to take the decision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a very long blog post, and I don't expect more than a very few people to actually read it. I wrote it mostly for selfish reasons: before changing to a new life, I wanted to wrap up all these notes in something more structured. I can't be certain I took a good decision, but systematizing these thoughts allowed me to move on with enough confidence to know I'm likely making a step forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that being said, I know that someone may be actually interested in hearing these thoughts and my experience. When I was a PhD student and I needed to take the notorious academia vs. industry decision, I would have paid big bucks to read more thoughts on the various pros/cons. One of the stupidest things you can do is to take big decisions based on what other people do and think, but reading about other people's thought process has helped me a lot. It is time I do my part.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The target audience for this post is, other than myself, PhD students / postdocs that are about to decide what to do next and junior profs that somehow feel that &quot;something is wrong&quot;. I also expect some senior academics and industry people to read this post, but I guess they will find themselves skipping directly to the academic rant part and mostly agree with much I have to say :-) Anyways, I tried to stay away from the &quot;very known things&quot; (e.g., 👀-level BS when writing proposals, generally &quot;more limited&quot; immediate impact of your work, different compensation level, etc.), and I tried to focus on thoughts I have not seen much discussed around (at least not in this depth).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, if you feel clueless and you want to hear more from an equivalently clueless random dude on the Internet, here we are :-) If you think this is &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; blog post that will make everything clear, I have a bad news for you: it's all about tradeoffs and in my opinion there is no clear-cut winner. And, unfortunately, the problem with tradeoffs and balancing many aspects is that figuring out which one to weigh more is yet another very personal decision in its own way. So, you will not find any answer in this post and you will eventually need to figure this thing out on your own, but I hope this will help you forming your own opinion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post is organized in three parts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mandatory disclaimer: I have no idea what I'm talking about, and these are personal takes/opinions anyways. Unless you are a bad person, please don't take anything personal. Please feel free to reach out, ping me on twitter, or shoot me an email: I'm of course happy to share more thoughts if you have any question. And if you disagree with something, bring it on! I love to argue, especially with people with strong and different opinions :-)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;part-1-the-good-mdash-what-pushed-me-to-keep-the-job&quot;&gt;Part 1: The Good — What pushed me to keep the job&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I discuss why I left, I want to touch on what pushed me to keep the job. I want to make sure it's a balanced post despite the upcoming mega rant, so that my overall opinion is more closely reflected. And I really don't want to discourage anyone to take this path, I still think it is a great one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that some of my &quot;reasons to stay&quot; are good, but some are bad. Also note that many of these refer to my personal situation at EURECOM, working in the field of systems security, and not all these points can be generalized to all universities. As they say, your mileage may vary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;its-a-very-good-job&quot;&gt;It's a very good job&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first pros is... 🥁: &quot;it's a very good job&quot;. At first, I was shocked to find out that it's an actual job. When I joined this prof thingy I thought that this would be a &quot;job&quot; (note the double quotes). But, while it's true that you don't have a direct boss that tells you what to do, at the end of the day you need to deliver, and you actually work very hard: If your PhD students are in trouble or you teaching sucks, you will run into problems. This doesn't necessarily mean &quot;they kick out&quot;, but if you value being a professional (and I do), failing at your core tasks will make you feel bad, even without additional pressure from your superior, and even if you have tenure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now that we got this &quot;it's an actual job&quot; out of the way, I can tell you: it's a very good one. There is &lt;em&gt;a lot&lt;/em&gt; of freedom in what you do and how you structure your time. Research-wise I felt very free (but you eventually work on what your students like to work on — as it should be), and the department values the right things (I've heard some BS in other schools where, in the context of systems security research, they pressure you to &quot;publish more journal papers...&quot; 🤦‍♂️). I really like teaching and mentoring, and there were many opportunities to do so. They let me create and teach my own class on mobile security, &lt;a href=&quot;https://mobisec.reyammer.io&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;MOBISEC&lt;/a&gt;, and the teaching load is overall very low (1 or 1.5 classes per year). I love playing CTFs and I was even &lt;em&gt;encouraged&lt;/em&gt; to spend time and push for NOPS, the EURECOM CTF team (after winning &lt;a href=&quot;https://ctftime.org/event/647&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;HXP CTF 2018&lt;/a&gt; and after being referred to as &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/j0taw78tCYs?t=968&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;probably a top team&lt;/a&gt;&quot; we are mostly enjoying our eternal and well-deserved glory).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The environment is extremely relaxed, informal, and friendly. You are surrounded by top-skilled colleagues and humans, from MS students to profs. I felt in a family from day 1. Last very good point: since in France positions come with tenure, there were not even problems in terms of pre-tenure stress, a real luxury. And on this aspect, EURECOM delivered: I never felt any sort of pressure (but: I did work my ass off... so if you stop doing anything, bad things may happen :-)).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[BTW, EURECOM is frantically trying to replace me, you should apply :-)]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;you-are-surrounded-by-students&quot;&gt;You are surrounded by students&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I took my decision to remain in academia, my top reason was for teaching and mentorship. Probably the best perk of the job is that you are surrounded by people eager to learn, from MS to PhD students to postdocs. It is extremely fulfilling and rewarding. Working with my students has been the highlight of my time at EURECOM, from traditional teaching, to suffering through the various rejections, to celebrating defeats of Reviewer #2, to cluelessly getting CTF-close in many stego CTF challenges. I feel very lucky that during these years we found enough interesting ideas that we enjoyed working on together, and that my next job will allow me to keep advising them until they graduate. As a prof, I believe the net output of my work is to see students becoming independent researchers, not the actual papers — I can't wait to see the bright careers I'm sure they will have :-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;i-have-deep-respect-for-the-role-of-profs-in-society-and-it-felt-great-to-be-one&quot;&gt;I have deep respect for the role of &quot;profs&quot; in society, and it felt great to be one&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I somehow have a profound admiration for the role that professors have in society and that had in my life. For their hard work, knowledge, passion, patience, and ultimately their service to the community. I'm referring to all teachers and mentors (from elementary schools to universities), who spend their life helping others, while at the same time often being asked to do many useless things and being massively underpaid. I admire and deeply respect these efforts: my most sincere thank you to all past, present, and future profs!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, to be frank, it felt great to be one. I have been in love with the idea of being a prof for many years. In part, I think it is because some of the people who impacted me the most are professors, and I wanted to do my part in helping others. And after all the uncertainties that one has during a PhD, I think I was even more in love with the idea of having finally found my place in society. [Narrator: LOL, this clueless dude did not find his place. [Answer to narrator: But I've surely found it &lt;em&gt;now&lt;/em&gt;!!1!]]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overcoming all these positive emotions and feelings attached to this job was likely the biggest challenge I faced in coming to terms with the several problems and cons I did have during these three years. As mentioned, I have no intention to give up on this teaching/mentoring thing (taking the time for this long blog post is part of this!), but it will surely not be the same thing. I'm very grateful I had a chance to try this job out. Thanks to all who made it possible, from family to advisors, colleagues, and students ❤️. I owe you big time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Of course, being a prof does not necessarily make you a smart or great person. Some profs I know are some of the dumbest people I have ever met (by far) and they would not survive one day in the real world. And some profs I know are the most asshole, selfish, egomaniac, and delusional humans I have ever heard of (Are you pushing your students to stay in the lab until 10PM, work during the weekends, and have no paid vacation? ✔️ Do you treat your students like cheap labor whose only task is to implement your visionary research plan (LOL)? ✔️ Do you come up with ridiculous excuses to put yourself as first author even when the student did all the work? ✔️ Do you engage in sexist/homophobic/racist behavior of any form? ✔️ Huge congrats, you are a terrible person and a disgrace for the academic community. No matter how many papers you have or whether you have a wikipedia page or a statue that looks like you, the only place I have for you is on my shit list 💩📝. You think you are one of them? Shoot me an email with your achievements and let's find out! 😈)]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;many-of-my-friends-are-academics-i-will-miss-them--&quot;&gt;Many of my friends are academics, I will miss them :-(&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[OK, this is likely less rational than it should be.]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been part of the academic circus for about 10 years, which is a significant portion of my adult life. I do have very good friends in industry, but in terms of numbers, I of course have many more friends in academia. And one non-obvious aspect that made my decision difficult was the fear of losing contact with these friends if I had to make the move. Most of my friends do not live where I live, but I thought I at least would have a chance to catch up at various conferences or when serving in PCs. Leaving academia, these occasions will likely be less frequent. Sadness ensues :-( Being more rational, I don't think this will be a huge problem, and moving to industry I'll be significantly richer anyways and I can even pay for conferences without having to write grant proposals ;-) But still, you get the point: I fear I'll miss my buddies even more than I do now. We'll see how it goes. :/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-social-pressure-a-very-bad-reason-to-stay&quot;&gt;The social pressure (a &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; bad reason to stay!)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It took me a lot of time to admit this to myself, but here it is: the social pressure &quot;you are crazy if you leave a tenured prof job&quot; is real, and I think it affected me as well. I perceive the prof job as very prestigious, and for a while it was insane to even consider leaving it. When people, from students who foolishly challenge you at ping pong to uber drivers, ask you &quot;So, what do you do?&quot; and you can answer &quot;I'm a professor&quot; without lying, well, that feels very cool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here there are other variants of &quot;the pressure&quot;: &quot;after a PhD, the smart kids become profs&quot; or &quot;you want to make your advisor proud? then become a prof&quot;. Nobody said these things to me explicitly, but I need to admit I felt them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Needless to say, &lt;em&gt;these are absolutely bad reasons to stick with the job&lt;/em&gt;. But even if I've always recognized these reasons as bad ones, actually &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; getting rid of them and avoiding that they clutter your mind when taking decisions, well, that has been a real challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You want to be a real &quot;smart kid&quot;? You want to make your advisor proud? Great: then find something you truly like and stick to it! If &quot;making your advisor proud&quot; == &quot;become a prof no matter what&quot;, then your advisor is likely a dumbass (please let me know so that I can update my list).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an advisor myself, I just wish for my students to find something they truly like and be the best possible version of themselves. I would personally be &lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt; prouder of a student who has the chance of being a prof but says &quot;fuck it&quot; and starts cultivating tomatoes vs. a student that sticks to the prof job just because it's cool or prestigious (I'm not kidding, and I would envy him/her a bit).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, let me tell you: The prof job is a job like any other. Yes, it's competitive to get a position, but the vast majority of the smartest people are very far from being academics, and I can assure you that some profs are very, very dumb. So, this prof thingy is not a very good filter for smartness anyways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And don't get fooled by the &quot;I'm good at this, so I must do this&quot; or &quot;I was born to be a professor&quot;. Really, chances are that you are not &quot;too good&quot; to &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; be a professor. The key question is: do you like it or not? Don't get trapped by some weird stories that many academics push forward. There are many more good candidates than open positions. Nobody is irreplaceable. And if you think you are, stop being delusional. You are not. Which is good news! You do not owe anything to anyone, and you have the freedom to start enjoying your life the way you want!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have friends who I believe are stuck with the prof job and torturing themselves with this pre-tenure madness just because it's cool. I'm convinced this &quot;the job is prestigious&quot; is making many smart humans losing many years of their lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If any of these thoughts sounds somehow familiar, maybe it's time for you to sound the alarm bell. If you need some wise words as a wake-up call, here is the best I could come up (don't worry, I wrote them before leaving the job, so they come out of infallible prof wisdom):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;14&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our days on this planet are counted. And the days of whoever you are trying to impress are counted as well. So what's the point? Really, it's not worth it, life is too short, and you get only one. Find something you like, regardless of how prestigious it is, strive to be the best version of yourself, and enjoy the ride! 💥&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;part-2-the-bad-mdash-what-pushed-me-to-leave-the-job&quot;&gt;Part 2: The Bad — What pushed me to leave the job&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;🔥🔥🔥🔥🔥🔥🔥🔥🔥🔥🔥🔥🔥🔥🔥🔥&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LET THE MEGA RANT BEGIN&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;🔥🔥🔥🔥🔥🔥🔥🔥🔥🔥🔥🔥🔥🔥🔥🔥&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many things I don't like about academia, and they are definitively too many to fit even in a mega blog post like this. But since I do not think it would be particularly useful to aim for a comprehensive list of the problems, and since a lot of people already rant about academic issues, this post is more about some aspects for which I did not find much discussion online (at least not in this depth), and a bit on the &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt;, in my very personal opinion, some things are as bad and as frustrating as they are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also discuss a bit how, even with a tenured position, I was not really able to ignore (some of) these problems. This may very well be a personal failure rather than a &quot;it's not possible to ignore them&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once again, please keep in mind that this is a personal blog post, and it does not have any pretense other than being a &quot;clean&quot; snapshot of my thoughts — especially for the last two aspects I discuss, some people may consider them a &quot;pro&quot; rather than a &quot;con&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;publish-or-perish-the-incentives-are-fucked-not-good&quot;&gt;Publish or perish: the incentives are &lt;del&gt;&lt;del&gt;fucked&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/del&gt; &quot;not good&quot;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The academic community has profoundly perverse incentives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am a firm believer in using incentives as a proxy to determine the health of a community: incentives are what motivate people to do what they do, and they are the basis to select who should move to the next step of their career, whether they are PhD students on the academic job market or whether they are profs trying to get to a higher level of the academic food chain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biggest incentive that personally affected me the most is the &lt;em&gt;absolutely insane and unhealthy obsession for publishing&lt;/em&gt;. You heard about the &quot;publish or perish&quot;? Yeah, it's real. I initially thought &quot;tenure can save me from this&quot;, but I don't think it does (more on this later).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Publications are not the only aspect that count, but I believe they have a disproportionate amount of importance for an academic career (at all stages), especially when compared to the net value that some &quot;papers&quot; actually contribute to society and the overall research field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe this papers' insanity is the root cause of many problems we have, and it ultimately distracts from what should really matter — expanding our knowledge and sharing our successes and failures with the community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think these incentives are the root cause of a number of problems, which I discuss next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Weirdly enough, while I really don't like this system, I do have profound respect for most of its members. Please don't take anything of this personally — it's a systemic issue. I'm guilty as anyone else and I'm definitively part of the problem.]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h4 id=&quot;problem-1-we-write-papers-that-do-not-deserve-to-be-written&quot;&gt;Problem 1: We write papers that do not deserve to be written&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The obsession of having to write a full academic paper about &lt;em&gt;everything&lt;/em&gt; causes us to spend &lt;em&gt;so much time&lt;/em&gt; writing papers that sometimes barely qualify even for the &quot;quick blog post&quot; bar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe this has a net &lt;em&gt;negative&lt;/em&gt; overall contribution for the community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may ask: How can an additional paper hurt?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For each peer-reviewed paper, there is an insane amount of overhead to actually write it, going through (often multiple rounds of) reviews, preparing the presentation, attending the conference, etc. The community also spends significant time, by reviewing the paper, discussing it, etc. That's &lt;em&gt;a lot&lt;/em&gt; of time and resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, you could tell me &quot;but there is value in writing a well-structured academic paper&quot;. Yes, there may be value. But &quot;there is value in X&quot; != &quot;it makes sense to do X&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is this &quot;value&quot; really balancing the insane amount of time we lose to make that happen? Is there really a net positive overall contribution for the community? &lt;em&gt;Is it worth it?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think we seldom ask ourselves this question, and I think in many cases the answer is &quot;no&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or, more precisely, I think the incentives are set to actually make it &quot;worth it&quot;, but for the wrong reasons. I'm criticizing that often &quot;it's worth it&quot; to write papers for the mere sake of publishing papers and padding our CVs, and not because we &lt;em&gt;truly&lt;/em&gt; believe it's worth doing so to share our knowledge with the community in the most effective way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, there are unreasonable people that exploit these tricks, and there are entire conferences and journals whose mere existence is justified and sustained by this publishing obsession. And as long as the incentives remain the same, and as long as we have &quot;pokemon venues&quot; (&quot;going to catch/accept them all&quot;, got it?), people will still lose time writing these papers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Combine this obsession with crazy schemes of &quot;collaborations&quot;... and you can see CVs with 60+ papers published &lt;em&gt;in a year&lt;/em&gt; (More than one per week... let that sink.)]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is definitively possible to avoid the super shitty venues and it is possible to focus on the bigger ones where the quality is definitively higher... but with me getting old(er), however, my (&lt;em&gt;very subjective!&lt;/em&gt;) bar for &quot;it is worth writing a full academic paper for X and fight to death to get it accepted somewhere&quot; is getting higher and higher :-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Note: I of course do not let these personal thoughts interfere with my judgment when I serve on PCs. If I feel a paper is above the bar (which is very relative depending on the venue), then I surely fight for acceptance, even if I may not agree that it was worth it to do the effort to write the paper in the first place. Actually, when the paper has been already written and submitted, sometimes by being positive and accepting &quot;marginal&quot; papers we are saving the authors and the community a lot of time.]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that being said, there are a couple of categories of papers that, in my opinion, we should not lose (much) time writing and submitting, but for which the incentives push us to write and submit anyways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Category A: good projects that did not work out&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's say you had a great project idea, but it did not work out. Now, in general, negative results may have value, and it may be worth sharing them. You could write a negative result paper (I think they are valuable). But wait, most conferences don't like those! Shit. So what do you do? You could write a blog post — as detailed as you want, no page limits, etc. you are the boss! — and move on with life with something better? But wait, blog posts &quot;don't count&quot; (more on this later). And in many environments, &quot;no paper&quot; == &quot;I completely lost my time from the eyes of the public&quot;...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;... and that's what pushes us to write full academic papers even for projects that were objectively a failure: we go on a quest to twist reality to sell something as &quot;this is great/novel&quot;, to respin the negative results as &quot;some positive results&quot;, and to build a convincing story around them. And what does it this usually lead to? Oversellings and overclaims, which the academic community is often accused of (and rightfully so).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We lose &lt;em&gt;so much time&lt;/em&gt; fine-tuning every single sentence of our papers to make sure to have a chance to win the peer-review lottery (and these papers are usually submitted many times before getting accepted, losing even more time of the overall community). But since &quot;publishing papers&quot; is so important, these aspects are now a normal and accepted part of the deal. Argh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Category B: bad projects&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are then some projects that should not even be started... But that are rewarded anyways by the current incentives, as long as they are publishable!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two variants that seem to be recurring:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Variant 1: &quot;there is no paper on this topic&quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mario: We could work on XYZ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luigi: Mmm... but what would be the point? Isn't XYZ obvious? Doesn't everyone know?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mario: Yeah... but I didn't see any &lt;em&gt;peer-reviewed&lt;/em&gt; paper on this, it could be publishable! 🤩&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luigi: 👀&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don't get me wrong, there definitively are well-explored areas of works that would benefit a lot from a systematic overview that an academic paper can provide (I'm a big fan of Oakland's SoKs). I just get mad when I hear people pushing forward a &quot;paper idea&quot; with the &lt;em&gt;sole&lt;/em&gt; argument of &quot;there is no peer-reviewed paper on this&quot;. The real question should be: &quot;would a paper on topic XYZ be a big-enough contribution to the community that makes my time well spent, regardless of its &quot;peer-reviewed&quot; status?&quot; Asking this question? HERESY!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Variant 2: &quot;it's a step forward&quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mario: We could work on a new defense mechanism XYZ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luigi: Mmm... but that looks easily bypassable in all realistic threat models... and it feels very brittle anyways...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mario: Don't be so negative. Remember that scientific progress is incremental by nature. XYZ is a step forward, so it could be publishable (and &lt;em&gt;thus&lt;/em&gt; it's worth working on it) 🕶️.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luigi: 🤯&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Note: &quot;new defense mechanism&quot; is just an example, I've seen this variant even with ridiculous attack papers.]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once again, don't get me wrong: I'm all in favor of supporting people who &lt;em&gt;truly&lt;/em&gt; believe they got an idea that, against all odds, may eventually be successful in the long-term future — this definitively fits in my &quot;great research&quot; bucket! But I often see papers for which I'm ready to bet that even the authors themselves don't believe their proposal would actually work in practice or be relevant/valuable in the real world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm upset that we often hide ourselves behind the &quot;we do a step forward&quot; or the &quot;it could be useful in 100 years&quot; arguments just to find an excuse to work on ideas that even ourselves don't believe in, other than believing in the vastly more important &quot;it could be publishable&quot; aspect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please, I beg you: the next time you start a project or start writing a full-fledge academic paper on something that did not work out as expected, ask yourself: is it &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; worth it to spend so much time on that? And is it worth it asking the community to lose time on it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I'm quite confident that in most cases, the answer would be: worth it 'for the science'&quot;? No. Worth it for my career (or for the career of my students)? Yeah, sorry :/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a direct consequence of this point, conferences — even so-called &lt;em&gt;top&lt;/em&gt; conferences — are overwhelmed with submissions, most of which have really marginal contributions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marginal contributions are great and valuable, but is it really worth it to write 12+ pages for a result that could be summarized in a couple of paragraphs? And is it really worth it to ask 3/4 reviewers (for each conference the paper is submitted to!) to write a full-fledge review on that? And is it really worth it to have PC discussions, rebuttals, re-submissions? And once these papers get accepted (at maybe a minor conference), is it really worth it to organize conferences and have 20-minute presentations on these contributions?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once again, we sometimes hide ourselves behind the &quot;there is value&quot; and we forget that this value should be balanced vs. the efforts it requires and time we lose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h4 id=&quot;problem-2-we-optimize-papers-for-the-referee-not-for-the-intended-audience&quot;&gt;Problem 2: We optimize papers for the referee, not for the (intended) audience&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With &quot;too many submissions&quot; comes the problem of not enough experts to properly cover all submissions in all research areas. Chances are that your paper will be reviewed by someone less expert than you are in your particular area, or someone who is completely clueless. If you consider that this someone may also be very tired by the insane PC load (and that's understandable), and that it's much easier to reject a paper than to accept it, and that systems security folks seem particularly nasty... well, this game sucks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what do we do when the game sucks but we &lt;em&gt;must&lt;/em&gt; play it anyways? We adapt to the rules of the game and we optimize for the only thing that matters: paper acceptance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of just writing papers for our &quot;real&quot; target audience (the community), we go all-in with &quot;defensive writing&quot; and we start iper-optimizing every single sentence to make sure it can't possibly be misunderstood even by the dumbest reader. Papers can't just be &quot;clear&quot; for a benign reader: they need to be bulletproof against capricious people who are ready to reject things for random reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe it's just me, but I personally spend an &lt;em&gt;enormous&lt;/em&gt; part of my writing time for these optimizations. Same goes for the time spent in teaching and providing feedback over these aspects. Now, is defensive writing a good skill to acquire? Yes, I think so. But does it make sense that we are forced to use it for every single paper. No, I think it's madness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a mismatch between the &quot;whoever needs to say 'accept'&quot; and the real target audience. We lose so much time optimizing for the &quot;wrong&quot; readers. And I hate it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And you know what I'm most upset about? That I actually &lt;em&gt;love&lt;/em&gt; writing. For example, I truly enjoyed writing this blog post, and I really missed writing just for the sake of organizing some thoughts and speaking my mind. Unfortunately, I can't say the same thing for most research papers I wrote so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wish we could write academic papers with the candor of, say, &lt;a href=&quot;http://phrack.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;phrack&lt;/a&gt; articles. After 10 years of academic writing, I find myself enjoying that &quot;direct&quot; style so much, regardless of the topic I'm reading about: &quot;here is what I got, here is what I had in mind but didn't have time to try / didn't work, and here is all my code / etc. so that you can start playing on this as well&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wishful thinking, I know...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h4 id=&quot;problem-3-we-move-away-from-potentially-very-cool-stuff&quot;&gt;Problem 3: We move away from (potentially) very cool stuff&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my naive mind, academia would provide a &quot;low-risk&quot; environment and safety nets for academics to work on &quot;high risk&quot; projects, or on projects that may be very valuable but may not necessarily lead to a short-term impact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current incentives are not aligned with this spirit, and we find ourselves, once again, needing to optimize for the wrong things: papers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've seen many making the argument that, yes, pre-tenure, that's exactly the case: the only focus should be to publish and get tenure. And thus many make the argument: &quot;tenure is there exactly to allow academics to work on high risk projects&quot;. I understand this argument, but I don't buy it. In most cases, profs are too busy to do the actual research, and that's why they get PhD students and postdocs to do the research for them. PhD students and postdocs have much more time than profs, but guess what they don't have? Tenure. And the cycle begins: it's again very risky to work on risky projects, maybe not for the prof, but for the students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it becomes difficult (and maybe immoral?) to try to convince students to work on project X when we know it may not lead to a publication, or when we know it may take a very long time to see the light. Considering that PhDs are 3-year long in many European countries... well, that sucks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another variant of the same problem: Given a project X, the rule of thumb is to do enough work to get to a good paper, but not (significantly) more. Once the paper is accepted, &quot;that's it&quot;. There is no incentive to keep working on it or to maintain a tool. Unless you have enough material for another paper, it's better to move on. And having &quot;enough&quot; material for a follow up is usually tricky, because the &quot;novelty&quot; factor is gone. (BTW, this triggers another unhealthy optimization: &quot;maybe it's better to leave some results out of paper #1 so that I have more material for a potential paper #2?&quot;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One potential trick to escape from this madness would be to get tenure and then have only very few students so that you have time to do the &quot;big shot&quot; research yourself. But not many students usually lead to not many papers, which leads to not many grants, which, in some schools, leads to higher teaching load / committee work (AFAIK, that's &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; the case at EURECOM), which leads to less free time. Argh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that this does not categorically prevent academics to do great work — some groups definitively do amazing stuff! But these groups do that &lt;em&gt;despite&lt;/em&gt; the current incentives, not thanks to them. And when the incentives don't align with what should be the overall goal, well, that makes me sad, doubly so when thinking that these incentives are some self-imposed &quot;counting papers&quot; madness... and for what? Padding our CVs? Seriously, what's the point?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h4 id=&quot;problem-4-non-peer-reviewed-resources-are-often-unjustly-dismissed&quot;&gt;Problem 4: Non-peer-reviewed resources are often unjustly dismissed&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's so competitive to publish in peer-reviewed venues and it takes so much time that we somehow feel entitled to unjustly dismiss non-peer-reviewed resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A classic example when dealing with related work? &quot;Oh, but that's just a blog post.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This mentality gets me mad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's true, many blog post &quot;just&quot; propose an idea and &quot;just&quot; scratch the surface of a given topic. But some blog posts are &lt;em&gt;solid&lt;/em&gt; work and they are more thorough and more fairly evaluated than many peer-reviewed publications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I get mad when we judge existing resources merely based on the &quot;peer-reviewed&quot; vs. &quot;non-peer-reviewed&quot; status. The question should be &quot;is this good work?&quot;, not &quot;on which platform has this been published?&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wish we would start valuing resources for what they actually are and for what we actually think of them. Does &quot;resource-published-on-napkin&quot; offer a systematic exploration of problem X? Does it fully solve the problem? Is it properly evaluated? Does it have a good comparison with related work?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the answer is &quot;yes&quot; to all these questions, why shouldn't it count as much as a normal paper? &quot;Peer-reviewed&quot; should be useful to act as a filter. But once you read a blog post and you think it's good, then it should be considered as a good resource, independently from how it was published.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I'll tell what you would hear in academic circles: &quot;it's not fair, publishing blog posts is much easier, they don't need to go through the crazy peer-review process, etc.&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Funny thing? I agree. It's not fair to compete against them. If only we would stop being obsessed with this &quot;not peer-reviewed =&amp;gt; doesn't count&quot; madness... If only even &lt;em&gt;our&lt;/em&gt; blog posts would start counting more... oh wait.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We somehow ended up using the &quot;peer-reviewed&quot; bit as a proxy for &quot;is this good work?&quot;, when we ourselves know that the process is deeply flawed, with so many false positives, false negatives, and various degrees of randomness. It's a very sad state of affairs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[A quick parenthesis on arxiv. A while ago I accidentally (👼) started a mega flame on arxiv vs. not arxiv. Let me clarify once for all: my intent was to bring up the problem that some people follow the spirit of double blind and some people just follow &quot;what's written in the CFP&quot;, which technically allow them to publish on arxiv and talk to journalists to hype it up (thus deanonymizing themselves). I don't know what's the best way to combine blind reviews and arxiv, but, in principle, I really like arxiv and the freedom it grants you. Big fan!]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;tenure-does-not-save-you-from-the-publishing-pressure&quot;&gt;Tenure does not save you from the publishing pressure&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, did I discover the problems above only recently? No, I was aware of most of them before joining the prof job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I thought: French positions come with tenure, I'll do what I want!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, I genuinely thought that, LOL. I thought I would be free from the insane publishing pressure. But that's not really the case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first problem is that I want to be professional. If I'm hired to do job X, I want to do job X. I don't want to keep the job &quot;to scam the system&quot;. If the job is about publishing academic papers, then I want to deliver. I don't like it? Then I should move on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second (and more pressing) problem: I chose this job for mentoring students. And what do students need to successfully defend their PhD and have a chance to aim at an academic career? Papers. So many papers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I guess you see where I'm going with this: I personally don't care that much about papers anymore, but I do profoundly care about the success of my students. I was super lucky to have two advisors who cared for me, and I want to do my part.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so here I am, getting stuck playing the reviewers lottery game over and over again, deadline after deadline, CCS rebuttal after CCS rebuttal. It's very different than when I was a PhD student myself. Working hard with students, getting papers accepted, making sure the presentation is top-notch, etc.: it's actually fun and it's great to see progress and share successes together. But rejections still hurt, especially the pointless ones. They hurt in a very different way than when I was a student, but they do hurt. It could be that I feel this pressure particularly because of the short &quot;3-year PhD&quot; that we have in France, but I'm not sure. [For reference, I started actually publishing around my 2.5th year (out of 6-year PhD). It takes time to skill up.]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In sum: if you chose academia for the students, I think it's very difficult to &quot;get out of the system&quot;. It's a different game and it's not terrible as when you are PhD student, but the game never ends, and the &quot;pressure&quot; doesn't leave you alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;too-many-tasks-no-time-for-tech-stuff&quot;&gt;Too many tasks, no time for tech stuff&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &quot;work freedom&quot; is real, but not in the way you may expect. You have a lot of flexibility in deciding on what to work on as research subject. But during these three years I have always felt as &quot;always too busy&quot;. There is an incredible high number of different tasks to juggle, and I feel I spent most of my time playing &quot;catching up&quot; rather than enjoying what I was doing. And I need to admit that, sometimes, the &quot;advertised academic freedom&quot; felt like a lie. I managed to do some technical work for papers during my first year or so, but I needed to work crazy hours to juggle all the tasks. I think I can do it. And it's cool to be able to do it. But I don't enjoy the unhealthy juggling anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I realized I'm the most happy when I can take a hard technical problem and go all-in trying to solve it. I deeply miss the luxury of focusing. Now, I understand that when people progress in their career, the focus and tech portion of the job is usually reduced. I get that, and that's OK. All I need is just a decent tradeoff — and this prof job really doesn't look like it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More in general, with all the tasks and the weird incentives (for you and the students), this job ends up being &quot;about tech&quot;, but not a &quot;tech job&quot;. Most of these tasks are &lt;em&gt;about&lt;/em&gt; technical stuff, but they rarely are actual technical tasks. Nowadays I find myself spending hours discussing (very interesting!) technical things with students or reviewing papers about technical things, but I don't see much technical stuff myself anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And between the many tasks and mostly non-technical nature, I found it challenging to keep up with the gritty tech details I used to like the most. I know that some colleagues work 60/70/80 hours per week to keep up with everything. But I categorically refuse to accept that to stay up-to-date with the tech knowledge I'm passionate about I need to work that much. (If you manage to stay up to date without working that much, respect!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I value work/life balance, I have a life outside my job, and I have no intention to give that up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I think, with time, my interests are changing. I love more and more building things and engineering, even if there is no paper at the end (!!!). Unfortunately, as a prof, the time you are expected to spend in this direction is very very low (so far I used my &quot;DEFCON CTF org&quot; card many times to justify investing time in &quot;tech stuff&quot;, but that doesn't last forever :-)). My bet is that I'll be happier with a job that incentives me to dig deeper on technical stuff, rather than just scratching the surface and change as soon as there is paper (if any). The academic job does not look like such a job — luckily my next one seems a pretty good fit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess that by moving to industry I will be learning many more things, but the number of public works/papers with my name on it will likely be much lower. So be it: I prefer to know many things, than being known by many people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;so-much-travelling-not-a-fan-anymore&quot;&gt;So much travelling, not a fan anymore&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used to enjoy travelling, but I think I burned out. The combination of attending various conferences, giving talks, serving on PCs, going to PI meetings for grants, and my long-distance relationship really took a toll on my quality of life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then COVID hit and I got stuck at home for six months. You know what? I really enjoyed it. The biggest pro of having a calm life? After years of failed attempts, I finally managed to establish many new healthy habits: I started eating in a healthier way, I lost 10kg+ (and I was not particularly overweight), started new hobbies, and I've managed to study two new languages every single day for more than six months (no, don't worry, French is not one of them :-)). I look forward to go back to the occasional trips, but having the &quot;I'm at home&quot; as the new norm is absolutely fantastic. Yeah, I'm getting old 👴.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-location&quot;&gt;The location&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last of my main issues: the location. This is tricky... many universities are in some random places in the middle of nowhere... Eurecom is on the beautiful French riviera... And yet, I'm finding ways to complain... oh well :-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This really is about personal taste. There are many people that love the area (for many good reasons), but it turns out it is not for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many nice &quot;nature&quot;-related things to explore (which are great!), but I prefer a bigger city with more balanced &quot;life&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One other problem I had is that I don't speak French, and I never took the time to learn it. As long as you stay around the school or in other &quot;tech places&quot;, everyone speaks English and it's all good. But when you need to do &quot;normal life stuff&quot;... yeah, you may be able to survive without knowing French, but you will have a tough time. (I saved myself because my mom and my brother both speak French very well, but I have no idea how I would have bootstrapped my life there without them. &amp;lt;3)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last aspect I was worried about: the so-called &quot;French attitude&quot;. Truth be told: the vast majority of French people I interacted with are actually super nice and helpful :-) BUT: if you need to send/receive a package or if you need to open a bank account: &lt;em&gt;RUN&lt;/em&gt;. A farewell message to Chronopost and BNP: from the core of my heart, I hope one day you will experience the arrogance, the profound unprofessional attitude, and your overall torture-level customer service that you seem to be proud of. May all your baguettes turn out curved and burned!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;part-3-the-bye-bye-mdash-the-decision-to-leave&quot;&gt;Part 3: The bye bye — The decision to leave&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;... and after three years of thinking about the pros and cons, it's time for me to move on :-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a very difficult decision to take and I spent an enormous time thinking about it (not as much time as shortening CCS rebuttals into the words limit, but quite close). I have last few additional thoughts from my introspective journey on how I approached this decision and how and why I eventually decided to leave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;life-freedom-vs-work-freedom&quot;&gt;Life freedom vs. work freedom&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One important aspect for me has always been to find a good location. French riviera didn't cut it, and Vienna seems a &quot;good&quot; alternative... (&quot;#1 city in livability world-wide&quot;-level &quot;good&quot;). I'm also extremely lucky to have found a very smart, beautiful, and unrealistically patient woman, and I have always been absolutely against the idea of taking &quot;one way&quot; decisions (as in &quot;decisions that only optimize for one of the two&quot;). Staying in Vienna looks like a great fit for both us, for many reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have always aimed at &quot;work freedom&quot; to be more free in life and enjoy it more. But &quot;work freedom&quot; lately started clashing with &quot;life freedom&quot;, and I picked the latter. Having the best job to then be somehow limited in life serves no purpose (again, that's my subjective opinion). This was enough for me to decide to leave — the other reasons (cons of the current job / pros of the future one) just made it much simpler.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;industry-vs-academia-it-is-not-a-black--white-choice&quot;&gt;Industry vs. academia: it is not a black / white choice&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Industry vs. academia decision is not as black / white as I once thought. There are many alternatives and shades out there. For example, I primarily chose the academic path for teaching and mentoring... but is academia really the only choice if you want to contribute on teaching/mentoring? Of course not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With time passing, &quot;traditional profs&quot; have less and less &quot;exclusive access&quot; to vast pools of smart students. Examples? I started learning &quot;security stuff&quot; with blog posts from &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/corelanc0d3r&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;@corelanc0d3r&lt;/a&gt; (around 2009/2010), not in university. And I learned most of the things I know from public online resources. Another example closer to me is about my MOBISEC class: Each year I had around 50 students in class, but by putting everything publicly online I've reached more students in 2 years than I would have reached with 1000 years of traditional teaching. Sure, the &quot;impact&quot; I have on these online students is much less &quot;deep&quot; than when you have them in class, but some of these online students (whom I have never met) did actually end up reaching out for suggestions/advice (even outside mobile security... and I love it! Please keep these random emails coming :-)). And that's how the &quot;tradeoff&quot; keyword kicks in: it does not need to be black and white.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And in this direction, I have great plans for the future. First off, watch this space for some MOBISEC announcement :-) Second: I have so many blog posts in the pipeline for a wide range of topics, from whether to do a PhD, to advices for PhD students, to how to pick a good research topic, or a very long list of technical/CTF-related things I've collected notes about. I also plan to keep serving in some PCs, time permitting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is &lt;em&gt;my&lt;/em&gt; way of finding a personal tradeoff between the two worlds I like, but I'm sure there are many others. Find what you like and try to make it fit in the current position you have! And if it doesn't work for you, well, yeah, maybe it's time to move on to something else :-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;in-our-field-industry-looks-damn-attractive&quot;&gt;In our field, industry looks damn attractive&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Confession: I have secretly (?) envied my industry friends for many years, and not for their money. I envied them because they could seemingly have some work/life balance and at the same time spend their time on something technical and used &quot;for real&quot;. There are many jobs in industry that I consider exceptionally interesting. In academia, in those occasions in which we do something that &lt;em&gt;may&lt;/em&gt; be useful, we often need to hope that someone else &quot;picks it up&quot; and builds something on top of it... and even if that happens, in most cases you will never know if something changed specifically thanks to your work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's not about being able to brag. It's about saying &quot;OK, I spent so much time on X, and that was useful&quot;. For several things for Android, I have seen some things getting fixed and some permissions on the &quot;deprecation path&quot;. What is also thanks to my work? I guess so? I would pay big bucks to know it was. Again, it is not about bragging, it's about knowing that my work did have value. I found this aspect quite frustrating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the industry side, I would expect that I would feel my work to be more directly useful, even if my name will not be there when the thing goes public (if it ever goes public). And again, so be it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last: I have been told there is a lot of BS in industry as well, and I think (?) I'm ready to deal with it. If industry manages to win against some BS I've seen for some European proposals or Reviewer #2 madness, wow, &quot;Respect&quot;. :-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;final-thoughts-on-taking-big-decisions&quot;&gt;Final thoughts on taking big decisions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried to make the tone of this blog post &quot;light&quot;... but it was a tough decision and I had some rough years while figuring these things out. The trickiest point for me was the feeling of getting stuck and overwhelmed by the SO many orthogonal aspects to balance when taking such a decision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent a lot of time trying to figure out which specific combination of them would have been my ideal one. I think that's a good exercise, but my suggestion is to be more pragmatic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of exploring the full combinatorial space of possibilities, the vast majority of which are only available in an ideal world, I suggest you to start from some concrete instances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is what I would suggest: 1) list the aspects for which you are not very flexible; 2) list the aspects that are important but for which you are flexible, and the ones that are very minor points; 3) look around and try to find &lt;em&gt;concrete&lt;/em&gt; possibilities. That is, instead of exploring the entire combinatorial space, try to find 3/4/5/6 reasonable candidates: it will be much easier to choose &quot;just among them&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other thing you can do is to read about other people's experiences. The good news is that there are a lot of resources on the topic, and some of them are really helpful and offer in-depth perspective. If I need to pick one, I would suggest you to check the blog posts from Matt Welsh. Many of the things he wrote ringed very true, and I envied him when he found the guts to leave his tenured position at Harvard (!!!). These are some of his interesting blog posts (among many others): &lt;a href=&quot;https://matt-welsh.blogspot.com/2010/05/secret-lives-of-professors.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Secret Lives of Professors&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://matt-welsh.blogspot.com/2010/11/why-im-leaving-harvard.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Why I'm Leaving Harvard&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://matt-welsh.blogspot.com/2014/08/the-fame-trap.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Fame Trap&lt;/a&gt;. I somehow felt he was right when I was reading about these things many years ago, but I wanted to try this prof job myself... and it turns out he was definitively right on many things... I guess lesson learnt: always trust the advice of a prof, infinite wisdom FTW! :P&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But kidding apart, it's very difficult to take these decisions especially because you don't have much data about them. So, my general advice is: are you in doubt? Do you think you may like it? GO AND TRY! If I could go back to 3 years ago, I would totally and surely do it again. Unless you are absolute sure that, for example, you hate teaching, nobody can really tell you if you would be a good fit. Worst case, you can quit after few years. Really, nothing is forever...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Best of luck for your decisions, and enjoy the journey! ... and as &quot;the dude&quot; would say, take it easy :-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arevuar!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#GTFO &lt;img src=&quot;https://reyammer.io/blog/assets/gtfo.gif&quot; alt=&quot;gtfo&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2020 16:22:27 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>adamnemecek</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://reyammer.io/blog/2020/10/03/the-good-the-bad-and-the-bye-bye-why-i-left-my-tenured-academic-job/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Algorithm discovers how six molecules could evolve into life’s building blocks</title>
<link>https://www.chemistryworld.com/news/algorithm-discovers-how-six-simple-molecules-could-evolve-into-lifes-building-blocks/4012505.article</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.chemistryworld.com/news/algorithm-discovers-how-six-simple-molecules-could-evolve-into-lifes-building-blocks/4012505.article</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;An organic synthesis algorithm has mapped out the thousands of reactions that might have converted abiotic compounds into the building blocks of life more than 3.5 billion years ago. Starting off with six simple precursors, the program discovered many known as well as 24 entirely new pathways to prebiotic molecules, and showed how catalytic and self-replicating systems might emerge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite hundreds of demonstrations that various organic reactions can take place under the conditions on early Earth, the scientific community still only has a piecemeal understanding of how the building blocks of life emerged. That’s because the number of possible combinations of these reactions is so large that the number of molecules generated quickly jumps into the tens of thousands. While synthesising and analysing so many compounds is difficult, it could in principle be sorted using a computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, researchers have done just that. A team led by &lt;a href=&quot;http://grzybowski-group.net/&quot;&gt;Bartosz Grzybowski&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.researchgate.net/scientific-contributions/2078762041-Sara-Szymkuc&quot;&gt;Sara Szymkuć&lt;/a&gt; from the Polish Academy of Sciences encoded all 500 known prebiotic reactions and a feedstock of six precursors – water, hydrogen cyanide, ammonia, hydrogen sulfide, nitrogen and methane – into open-use platform &lt;a href=&quot;https://tol.allchemy.net/&quot;&gt;Allchemy&lt;/a&gt;. The algorithm then used encoded mechanistic chemistry rules to produce a map of their combinations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Running the program for seven generations, each time combining the generated molecules with what came before, the researchers ended up with almost 35,000 compounds including 50 biotic ones. The program was able to find many prebiotic syntheses previously described in the literature, for example 10 pathways leading to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.chemistryworld.com/1010237.article&quot;&gt;DNA component adenine&lt;/a&gt;. But it also discovered 24 entirely new pathways to biotic compounds – more than 20 of which the team experimentally validated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;inline_image image_size_full&quot; data-attachment=&quot;508159&quot; data-sequence=&quot;2&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;picture&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;A network of circles connected by lines representing the program's output of finding new pathways to biotic molecules. Each dot represents a compound and each line a reaction.&quot; src=&quot;data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAAMAAAACCAQAAAA3fa6RAAAADklEQVR42mNkAANGCAUAACMAA2w/AMgAAAAASUVORK5CYII=&quot; data-src=&quot;https://d2cbg94ubxgsnp.cloudfront.net/Pictures/480xany/1/5/9/508159_wolos2009251_600082.jpg&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1023px) 100vw, 780px&quot; data-srcset=&quot;https://d2cbg94ubxgsnp.cloudfront.net/Pictures/480xany/1/5/9/508159_wolos2009251_600082.jpg 480w,https://d2cbg94ubxgsnp.cloudfront.net/Pictures/600xany/1/5/9/508159_wolos2009251_600082.jpg 600w,https://d2cbg94ubxgsnp.cloudfront.net/Pictures/780xany/1/5/9/508159_wolos2009251_600082.jpg 780w&quot; class=&quot; lazyload&quot; width=&quot;1485&quot; height=&quot;1263&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As well as that, more complex systems such as reaction cycles and micelles began to emerge. One molecule generated, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chemspider.com/Chemical-Structure.8557.html&quot;&gt;iminodiacetic acid&lt;/a&gt;, can complex with metals such as manganese to act as a catalyst. ‘You can take it through a cycle and it can potentially reproduce two copies of itself for one cycle. In experiment, we showed this auto-amplification. What this teaches us is that this self-replication emerges chemically,’ says Grzybowski.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the reasons computer programs are better at finding these pathways than humans, explains Szymkuć, is that ‘people aren’t accustomed, when designing something, to incorporate a step, which degrades a molecule, and that’s necessary for the cycle.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the vast majority of reaction combinations led to abiotic compounds – molecules that were never incorporated into living systems. Analysis showed that the molecules that became the building blocks of life were more soluble in water and more thermodynamically stable. ‘The chosen ones had a balanced number of hydrogen bond donors and acceptors,’ Grzybowski adds. ‘When you think about it, this makes perfect sense – think about DNA. Nature chose molecules that are more likely to be fitting into a larger architecture, to build these kinds of supramolecular assemblies.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‘This is an incredible piece of work,’ says &lt;a href=&quot;https://erastova.xyz/&quot;&gt;Valentina Erastova&lt;/a&gt; who investigates origin of life chemistry with computational methods at the University of Edinburgh, UK. ‘We have a bit of a limitation in that this has to be based upon our discovered reactions. There are still reactions we haven’t been exploring as much that will be related to minerals and surfaces, which could be catalytic. That would be very interesting to look into… we can’t take this map as an absolute map.’&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2020 16:21:50 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>gmays</dc:creator>
<og:title>Algorithm discovers how six simple molecules could evolve into life’s building blocks</og:title>
<og:type>Article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.chemistryworld.com/news/algorithm-discovers-how-six-simple-molecules-could-evolve-into-lifes-building-blocks/4012505.article</og:url>
<og:description>Program shows how micelles, catalysts and self-replicating chemical systems emerge from abiotic precursors</og:description>
<og:image>https://d2cbg94ubxgsnp.cloudfront.net/Pictures/2000x2000fit/1/5/8/508158_gettyimages534853313_732571.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.chemistryworld.com/news/algorithm-discovers-how-six-simple-molecules-could-evolve-into-lifes-building-blocks/4012505.article</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Running a Unix-like OS on a home-built CPU with a home-built C compiler</title>
<link>https://fuel.edby.coffee/posts/how-we-ported-xv6-os-to-a-home-built-cpu-with-a-home-built-c-compiler/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://fuel.edby.coffee/posts/how-we-ported-xv6-os-to-a-home-built-cpu-with-a-home-built-c-compiler/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been two years since I started working as a software engineer. I sometimes tell my colleagues about a student project I did in my junior year of university, and it’s so well-received that I’m writing this post. &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, let me ask you a question. Have you ever designed your own ISA, built a processor of that ISA on FPGA, and built a compiler for it? Furthermore, have you run an operating system on that processor? Actually, we have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this post, I’m going to talk about my undergraduate days in 2015, our four months of building a home-built CPU of a home-built RISC ISA, building a home-built C toolchain, and porting Xv6, a Unix-like OS, to that CPU.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;cpu-experiment-at-the-university-of-tokyo&quot;&gt;CPU Experiment at the University of Tokyo&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was all done as a student experiment project called CPU Experiment. So, let’s start with what is CPU experiment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CPU experiment is a little famous exercise held in the winter of the junior year in my department, the Department of Information Science at the University of Tokyo. In the experiment, students are divided into groups of four or five students. Each group designs an own CPU architecture, implements it on an FPGA, builds an OCaml subset compiler for that CPU, and then runs a given ray-tracing program on the CPU. Typically, one or two people are responsible for each of the CPU, FPU, CPU simulator and compiler. I was in charge of the CPU in my group, Group 6.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This exercise is well known for the high expectation of self learning. The instructor only asks the students to “take this ray-tracing program written in OCaml and run it on your CPU implemented on an FPGA”, and the class ends. He/she doesn’t tell much about the concrete steps of how to write CPU and compilers. The students learn for themselves how to embody the general knowledge of CPUs and compilers learned in previous lectures to the level of real circuits and code. Well, this is a very tough exercise, but very exciting and educational.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;lets-run-operating-system-on-our-own-cpu&quot;&gt;Let’s run Operating System on our own CPU.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As some of you may have noticed, I didn’t talk about operating system at all. I’ll add a little explanation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Typically, the experiment proceeds as follows. First, you make a CPU that works reliably, no matter how slow it is. If you can make a working CPU and successfully run the ray-tracing program, you can earn the credit of the experiment. After that, your team has a free time. The traditional way to spend this free time is to further speed up their CPU. In past experiments, students have made out-of-order CPU, VLIEW CPU, multi-core CPU, or even superscalar CPU, which is amazing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, some teams put more energy into doing fun such as running games or playing music by connecting a speaker with their CPU. Group 6, to which I belonged, was a group of such people who loved entertainment, and we decided to run an OS as our team goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result of other groups showing interest in this idea, a joint group of about 8 people, Group X, was formed, and their goal was “Let’s run an OS on our own CPU!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although I was in charge of creating a CPU in Group 6, this time I chose to be the leader of the OS team in the Group X. So this post is written primarily from the perspective of the OS team, but of course I also introduce the overall group’s results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;xv6&quot;&gt;Xv6&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the OS to be ported, we chose Xv6, a simple Unix v6-inspired OS created by MIT for educational purposes. Xv6 is written in ANSI C, unlike Unix v6, and it runs on x86. Xv6 is an educational OS, so its features are a bit poor, but it has sufficient features as a simple Unix-like OS. You can find more information of Xv6 on &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Xv6&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mit-pdos/xv6-public&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;the GitHub repository&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;challenges&quot;&gt;Challenges&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In porting xv6, there are a lot of challenges on the software side alone because we were trying to create everything from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. C Compiler and tool chain for Xv6&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the CPU experiment, we usually create an ML compiler. Naturally, you can’t compile C codes of Xv6.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. What kind of CPU features required for operating system?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Privilege protections? Virtual address? Interrupt? Yes, we had overall understanding of what operating system does by lectures, but we didn’t have solid enough understanding to explain what specific CPU features could make that happen at that time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. What about the simulator?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had a simulator made in the core part of CPU experiment, but it was a simple one that executes one instruction by instruction, and there was no interruption or no virtual address conversion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Low portability of xv6&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Xv6 was not very portable. For example, it assumes the &lt;code&gt;char&lt;/code&gt; is 1 byte and &lt;code&gt;int&lt;/code&gt; is 4 bytes, and manipulates the stack heavily. Well, the name “Xv6” I guess comes from x86 and Unix “v6”, so it’s kind of natural.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had a lot of concerns, but started the Group X’s OS porting project in December.&lt;br/&gt;From here I’m going to write about what we did in roughly chronological order. It’s a little bit long, so if you want to look at our final products quickly, &lt;a href=&quot;https://fuel.edby.coffee/posts/how-we-ported-xv6-os-to-a-home-built-cpu-with-a-home-built-c-compiler/#march---xv6-runs&quot;&gt;please jump to March&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;late-november---starting-the-compiler&quot;&gt;Late November - Starting the compiler&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first problem that we saw the answer to was the compiler and tool chain. To be surprise, our decision was to build the C89 compiler from scratch. To be honest, I hadn’t imagined that we would choose this way. I remember I talked with Yuichi, who became in charge of CPU of Group X, about doing a gcc or llvm port at first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, one of the team members, Keiichi, suddenly said he had written a C compiler and showed us a prototype of a compiler with a simple parser and emitter. It seemed more fun to write the toolchain from scratch, so we decided to write a compiler by ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yuichi and Wataru from Group 3, who had already finished the core part of the experiment that year, joined Keiichi, and the Group X compiler team was born. We later named our compiler Ucc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;mid-december---the-os-team-is-up&quot;&gt;Mid-December - The OS team is up!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the beginning of December, I completed my CPU, and Group 6 completed the core part of the CPU experiment. So, we moved on to the fun part, Group X’s OS porting task. At this time, myself and Shohei from Group 6 started working in Group X and became the OS team. Masayoshi joined it at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;core-part-of-the-experiment-writing-a-cpu&quot;&gt;Core part of the experiment: Writing a CPU&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the way, I guess not so many software engineers have ever written a CPU, so let me talk a little bit about making a CPU as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nowadays, making a CPU doesn’t mean wiring every single jump wire on a breadboard; you write the circuitry in Hardware Description Language. Then you synthesize that HDL into a real circuit using Vivado or Quartus. This process is called logic synthesis, not compilation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HDL and programming language are similar but different. Think of it like writing a function that maps the signal state of registers to another signal state, triggered by a clock or input signal. If you want to experience real reactive programming, I suggest you try writing an HDL. Please also remember to write HDLs, always worrying about whether the signal propagation of the HDLs you write really ends up in one clock. Otherwise, the behavior of your circuits would be incomprehensible to humans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hardest part of the actual development was that this logic synthesis took a ridiculous amount of time. It was not uncommon for us to have to wait up to 30 minutes after starting the synthesis, so once I started the synthesis, I was often playing Smash Bros. Melee with the other CPU guys who were also waiting for the synthesis to finish. FYI, my character was Sheik.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;late-december-to-mid-january---learn-by-porting-xv6-to-mips&quot;&gt;Late December to mid-January - Learn by porting Xv6 to MIPS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We began to find the answer to “What kind of CPU features required for operating system?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the OS team was born, we started weekly rounds of Xv6 source code reading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time, I started porting Xv6 to MIPS. This was partly to learn how an OS works at the implementation level, and partly because there appeared to be no Xv6 port to MIPS. I completed the port until the process scheduler started in about a week. I did a lot of research on MIPS during this porting process, and on x86 to understand how xv6 works. Thanks to that, I understood mechanisms around interrupts and MMU at the implementation level. At this stage I got a solid understanding of the CPU functionality required for Xv6.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, in mid-January, we worked hard to compile the entire Xv6 code by commenting out the various parts. As a result, Xv6 on the simulator of our homebrew architecture showed the first message of the boot sequence,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;xv6...
cpu0: starting...
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time, this meant that by this time Ucc had already grown enough to compile most of xv6, which was awesome.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;february---our-cpu-gaia-was-born&quot;&gt;February - our CPU, GAIA was born!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the MIPS port, I completed the initialization of the PIC, which was a real pain, and also completed the implementation of the interrupt handler. As a result, the porting of Xv6 to MIPS was completed until just before the first user program started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on this experience, I made the draft specifications of the interrupt and virtual address translation for our homebrew CPU. In order to keep it simple, we decided to omit hardware privilege mechanisms like Ring protection. For virtual address translation, we decided to use a hardware page-walking method, just like x86. It may seem difficult to implement in hardware, but we thought it was cheaper if we sacrificed the speed and omit TLB implementation. After all, Yuichi made an excellent CPU core later, and it installed TLB from the beginning though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yuichi completed the overall design of the ISA of our CPU. He named our CPU GAIA. In typical CPU experiment projects, we don’t implement interrupt nor MMU. However, Yuichi started to implement them for Xv6, based on the refactored version of the CPU of Group 3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll note the weekly records as the rapid progress begins from then on!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;1st-week&quot;&gt;1st Week&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of just commenting boot sequences out, Masayoshi started implementing actual initialization of our CPU, and Shohei rewrote the x86 assembly of Xv6 into our homebrew architecture’s. I added interrupt simulation capability to our simulator which Wataru had made in the core part of CPU experiments, and also completed support for virtual address translation. This gave the simulator enough functionality to run the OS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;2nd-week&quot;&gt;2nd Week&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I made a primitive linker for our architecture to assemble Xv6 and its binary blobs. Shohei was working on implementation of the interrupt handler, which was a tough part. Interrupts are hard to understand, hard to figure out the flow, hard to debug, and hard to develop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I ported Xv6 to MIPS, I had GDB, so it was rather OK, but our own simulator didn’t have any debug features, so it must have been very difficult to debug. Shohei couldn’t bear the difficulty of debugging, so he added a disassembler and a debug dump function to the simulator. After this, the simulator’s debugging features were rapidly upgraded by the OS team, and finally the simulator grew to look like the following picture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://fuel.edby.coffee/images/simulator.png&quot; width=&quot;600&quot;/&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;3rd-week&quot;&gt;3rd Week&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overcoming various difficulties, the porting of Xv6 was advanced, but Xv6 still did not work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Especially, the specification of Ucc that &lt;code&gt;char&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;int&lt;/code&gt; are both 32 bits caused a lot of troubles. That was not Ucc’s fault. Actually, the C specification only requires &lt;code&gt;sizeof(char) == 1&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;sizeof(char) &amp;lt;= sizeof(int)&lt;/code&gt;, so this was legal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, xv6 is written for x86, so it assumes &lt;code&gt;sizeof(int) == 4&lt;/code&gt; and adds constants to the value of the pointer, which caused a lot of inconsistencies. Because the bug created by this was so hard to find and the amount was also large, it was decided to ask Ucc to make &lt;code&gt;char&lt;/code&gt; 8 bits after all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After delegating the char 32-bit problem to the Ucc team, I wrote the initialization of paging of the first entry stage, and tried to get the interrupts to work properly by trial and error.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bottom line is that we worked hard to fix the challenge #4, “Low portability of Xv6”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;february-2728&quot;&gt;February 27,28&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I reread the slack, I can see that a lot of progress was made on this day. After the Ucc team very quickly finished the change to make &lt;code&gt;char&lt;/code&gt; 8-bit, we worked hard on a lot of debugging. Finally, our first user program &lt;code&gt;init&lt;/code&gt; worked!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that, we made more and more progress in porting the user process applications that I hadn’t yet gotten to in the port to MIPS. On the way, many bugs that were hard to reproduce or inadequacies in the interrupt specification were found and fixed, , but we got over it somehow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One interesting errata we fixed is the cache alias issue. GAIA CPU chose a virtual address instead of a physical address as the cache index. This is because it allows you to skip the virtual address translation to look up caches. However, due to that, we found that inconsistency happened between caches, because multiple caches of virtual addresses could point to the same single physical address. When the cache of one virtual address was updated, the caches of other virtual addresses pointing to the same physical address were not updated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This bug was hard to fix on the hardware side at low cost, so we fixed it by introducing “Page Coloring” in our Xv6. This introduces “color” for each cache line, and allocates pages so that virtual addresses pointing to the same physical address will always get the same color. This means virtual addresses pointing to the same physical address will always have only one cache. This allowed Xv6 to ensure that GAIA never had multiple caches which shared the same physical address.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;march---xv6-runs&quot;&gt;March - Xv6 Runs!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On 1st, the xv6 port is complete. xv6 was now running on the simulator…!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://fuel.edby.coffee/images/xv6runs.png&quot; width=&quot;600&quot;/&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;there-should-be-no-shortage-of-entertainment&quot;&gt;There should be no shortage of entertainment&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Originally, the Xv6 port was meant to be fun, and since Xv6 started working on the simulator, we worked hard to add a lot more fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First of all, a mini curses is created by Masayoshi in about 4 hours and the &lt;code&gt;sl&lt;/code&gt; command run on our Xv6.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://fuel.edby.coffee/images/sl.png&quot; width=&quot;600&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Shohei kind of wanted to do a Minesweeper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://fuel.edby.coffee/images/minesweeper.png&quot; width=&quot;600&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;During this period, Yuichi completed the implementation of the CPU of the Group X. The real CPU ran much faster than the simulator, which made the game easier to play and develop. At this time, a very high quality application, 2048, was created.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://fuel.edby.coffee/images/2048.png&quot; width=&quot;600&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;This 2048 was very high quality. Yuichi played with it all the time. Incidentally, the 2048 uses non-line buffering input, but xv6 originally did not have this feature. To support this feature, &lt;code&gt;ioctl&lt;/code&gt; was added as a &lt;code&gt;devsw&lt;/code&gt; action in addition to &lt;code&gt;read&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;write&lt;/code&gt;, and new &lt;code&gt;termios&lt;/code&gt;-related features to control &lt;code&gt;ICANON&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;echo&lt;/code&gt; were added. So the only Xv6 that can play 2048 with such a high degree of completeness is the one on GAIA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the way, for a V6-inspired Xv6, I guess adding &lt;code&gt;gtty&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;stty&lt;/code&gt; system calls is a more Unix V6-like approach. However, I adopted &lt;code&gt;ioctl&lt;/code&gt; because Xv6 doesn’t have the concept of tty, and because &lt;code&gt;ioctl&lt;/code&gt; was introduced in the next version, V7, which is close in history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, as something a little cooler, Xv6-GAIA has a small assembler made by Keiichi. Also it has a mini vi that Shohei made. Guess what you can do with these two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://fuel.edby.coffee/images/vi.png&quot; width=&quot;600&quot;/&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://fuel.edby.coffee/images/as.png&quot; width=&quot;600&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s interactive programming on an FPGA! This is a pretty impressive demo for a CPU experiment, which usually doesn’t include any interactive program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-greatest-demo&quot;&gt;The greatest demo&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The original task of the CPU experiment was “Run the given ray-tracing program on your homebrew CPU”. Now that you’ve got an operating system running on your CPU, you know what you’re supposed to do, right? We decided to run the ray-tracing program “on the OS “on our own CPU. We had a few bugs, but we managed to finish it an hour before the final presentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://fuel.edby.coffee/images/minrt.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, we did what every student in the history of our department has probably joked at least once: Run an operating system on a CPU, and ran the ray-tracing program on top of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;looking-back-from-2020&quot;&gt;Looking back from 2020&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I’ve written so far is essentially a rewrite of my own blog post I wrote in 2015. While reading it now, I can see a lot of my technical inexperience at the time, what we did then is definitely exciting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the way, you can see what our Xv6 looked like at that time on your browser right now from &lt;a href=&quot;https://nullpo-head.github.io/emcc-gaia-simu/xv6.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; ! After the CPU experiment, I ported our GAIA simulator to JavaScript by Emscripten. Let’s try our &lt;code&gt;sl&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;minesweeper&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;2048&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;terminal&quot; tabindex=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;xv6...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;cpu0: starting&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;init: starting sh&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me also tell you that the porting of Xv6 to MIPS, which wasn’t finished at the time of the CPU experiment, was finished a month after the experiment. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/nullpo-head/xv6-mips&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;GitHub repository is here&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After we posted a blog post about the Group X challenge in 2015, later generations of students continued to take on new challenges around OS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2018, some students ran their own OS on top of a home-built CPU, and in 2019, a group of students ran their own OS while adopting RISC-V for their home-built CPU ISA. In addition, the group in 2020 finally ran Linux on top of a homebrew CPU that also adopted RISC-V as its ISA.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:3&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m sure there will be many more stories in the future, so everyone please look forward to them. Personally, I look forward to someone running Linux on their own ISA someday, or running a VM on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reinventing the wheel is generally said to be something to be avoided, but there’s quite a bit to learn from actually doing it. It made me realize that I didn’t understand it as well as I could implement it from scratch. Plus, I recommend it to you because, above all, it’s fun to die for!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s the end of the story of our CPU experiment. If you’re interested in reinventing the exciting wheel, please try building a CPU or porting an OS to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, I would like to summarize the members of the Group X.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2020 16:17:23 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>abc_tkys</dc:creator>
<og:title>How we ran a Unix-like OS (Xv6), on our home-built CPU with our home-built C compiler</og:title>
<og:description>It’s been two years since I started working as a software engineer. I sometimes tell my colleagues about a student project I did in my junior year of university, and it’s so well-received that I’m writing this post. 1 Now, let me ask you a question. Have you ever designed your own ISA, built a processor of that ISA on FPGA, and built a compiler for it? Furthermore, have you run an operating system on that processor?</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://fuel.edby.coffee/posts/how-we-ported-xv6-os-to-a-home-built-cpu-with-a-home-built-c-compiler/</og:url>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://fuel.edby.coffee/posts/how-we-ported-xv6-os-to-a-home-built-cpu-with-a-home-built-c-compiler/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Shapez.io: open-source base building game inspired by Factorio</title>
<link>https://shapez.io/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://shapez.io/</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://shapez.io/&quot;&gt;https://shapez.io/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24678720&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24678720&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 275&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 83&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2020 13:01:34 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>smusamashah</dc:creator>
<og:title>shapez.io</og:title>
<og:description>shapez.io is a fun factory base building game about combining shapes</og:description>
<og:url>https://shapez.io/</og:url>
<og:image>https://shapez.io/og_thumb.png</og:image>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://shapez.io/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>French bar owners arrested for offering free WiFi but not keeping logs</title>
<link>https://www.cozyit.com/french-bar-owners-arrested-for-offering-free-wifi-but-not-keeping-logs/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.cozyit.com/french-bar-owners-arrested-for-offering-free-wifi-but-not-keeping-logs/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;At least five bar owners in Grenoble, France have been arrested for providing WiFi at their businesses without keeping logs. The bar owners were arrested under a 2006 law that technically classifies WiFi hotspot providing establishments as ISPs, and requires them to store one year’s worth of logs or connection records for anti-terrorism purposes. This requirement is in place even if the WiFi network is password protected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The law No. 2006-64 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bfmtv.com/economie/des-patrons-de-bars-en-garde-a-vue-a-cause-du-wi-fi-offert-a-leurs-clients_AN-202009290142.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;extends&lt;/a&gt; the traditional ISP logging requirements “to all persons who, in respect of an activity primary or secondary professional, offer the public a connection allowing on-line communication via network access, including free of charge.” Violating this crime means that the owner of a small cafe that offers WiFi to patrons could face up to one year in prison and up to a 75,000 euro fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;All businesses in France providing WiFi to the public are required to log&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That all public WiFi hotspots in France are required by law to be logging shouldn’t be too surprising. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bfmtv.com/economie/des-patrons-de-bars-en-garde-a-vue-a-cause-du-wi-fi-offert-a-leurs-clients_AN-202009290142.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;BFM Business&lt;/a&gt; noted that most large providers of free WiFi like hotels, conference centers, airports, and such do so with business packages that include this logging. However, it seems that most people aren’t aware that even small businesses like bars, cafes, nightclubs, and restaurants that offer WiFi to their patrons are faced with these logging requirements. One of the arrested bar owners noted that the relevant organization, Umih, never noted this requirement when renewing his license:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Nobody, not even the professionals of Umih who provide compulsory training as part of a license IV resumption, to me never said I should keep this history.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In response to questions by BFM Business, Umih admitted that the training doesn’t mention WiFi logging but noted that Umih members should have known about this important requirement because it was mentioned in a newsletter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If anything, this piece of dystopian news highlights the state of surveillance in France and the desperate need for online privacy there, as well. Small business owners in France need to make sure that they are in compliance with the laws; similarly, public WiFi users in France need to make sure they never connect without a VPN.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2020 12:59:22 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>seigando</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>French bar owners arrested for offering free WiFi but not keeping logs - CozyIT</og:title>
<og:description>At least five bar owners in Grenoble, France have been arrested for providing WiFi at their businesses without keeping logs. The bar owners were arrested under a 2006 law that technically classifies WiFi hotspot providing establishments as ISPs, and requires them to store one year’s worth of logs or connection records for anti-terrorism purposes. This […]</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.cozyit.com/french-bar-owners-arrested-for-offering-free-wifi-but-not-keeping-logs/</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.cozyit.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/French-bar-owners-arrested-for-not-keeping-logs-on-their-public-WiFi.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.cozyit.com/french-bar-owners-arrested-for-offering-free-wifi-but-not-keeping-logs/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Internet&amp;#039;s Own Boy: The Story of Aaron Swartz (2014) [video]</title>
<link>https://youtube.com/watch?v=M85UvH0TRPc</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://youtube.com/watch?v=M85UvH0TRPc</guid>
<description>&lt;div id=&quot;player&quot; class=&quot;skeleton flexy&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div id=&quot;player-wrap&quot;&gt;
        
            &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- end of chunk --&gt;&lt;ytd-app disable-upgrade=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;ytd-masthead id=&quot;masthead&quot; slot=&quot;masthead&quot; class=&quot;shell  chunked&quot; disable-upgrade=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;svg id=&quot;menu-icon&quot; class=&quot;external-icon&quot; preserveaspectratio=&quot;xMidYMid meet&quot;&gt;&lt;g id=&quot;menu&quot; class=&quot;yt-icons-ext&quot; viewbox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot;&gt;&lt;path d=&quot;M3 18h18v-2H3v2zm0-5h18v-2H3v2zm0-7v2h18V6H3z&quot;/&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;masthead-logo&quot; slot=&quot;masthead-logo&quot;&gt;  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;svg id=&quot;yt-logo-svg&quot; class=&quot;external-icon&quot; viewbox=&quot;0 0 200 60&quot;&gt;&lt;g id=&quot;yt-logo&quot; viewbox=&quot;0 0 200 60&quot; preserveaspectratio=&quot;xMidYMid meet&quot;&gt;&lt;g&gt;&lt;path fill=&quot;#FF0000&quot; d=&quot;M63,14.87c-0.72-2.7-2.85-4.83-5.56-5.56C52.54,8,32.88,8,32.88,8S13.23,8,8.32,9.31&amp;#10;            c-2.7,0.72-4.83,2.85-5.56,5.56C1.45,19.77,1.45,30,1.45,30s0,10.23,1.31,15.13c0.72,2.7,2.85,4.83,5.56,5.56&amp;#10;            C13.23,52,32.88,52,32.88,52s19.66,0,24.56-1.31c2.7-0.72,4.83-2.85,5.56-5.56C64.31,40.23,64.31,30,64.31,30&amp;#10;            S64.31,19.77,63,14.87z&quot;/&gt;&lt;polygon fill=&quot;#FFFFFF&quot; points=&quot;26.6,39.43 42.93,30 26.6,20.57&quot;/&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;g&gt;&lt;g id=&quot;youtube-paths&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill=&quot;#282828&quot; d=&quot;M92.69,48.03c-1.24-0.84-2.13-2.14-2.65-3.91c-0.52-1.77-0.79-4.12-0.79-7.06v-4&amp;#10;              c0-2.97,0.3-5.35,0.9-7.15c0.6-1.8,1.54-3.11,2.81-3.93c1.27-0.82,2.94-1.24,5.01-1.24c2.04,0,3.67,0.42,4.9,1.26&amp;#10;              c1.23,0.84,2.13,2.15,2.7,3.93c0.57,1.78,0.85,4.16,0.85,7.12v4c0,2.94-0.28,5.3-0.83,7.08c-0.55,1.78-1.45,3.09-2.7,3.91&amp;#10;              c-1.24,0.82-2.93,1.24-5.06,1.24C95.65,49.29,93.93,48.87,92.69,48.03z M99.66,43.71c0.34-0.9,0.52-2.37,0.52-4.4v-8.59&amp;#10;              c0-1.98-0.17-3.42-0.52-4.34c-0.34-0.91-0.95-1.37-1.82-1.37c-0.84,0-1.43,0.46-1.78,1.37c-0.34,0.91-0.52,2.36-0.52,4.34v8.59&amp;#10;              c0,2.04,0.16,3.51,0.49,4.4c0.33,0.9,0.93,1.35,1.8,1.35C98.71,45.06,99.31,44.61,99.66,43.71z&quot;/&gt;&lt;path fill=&quot;#282828&quot; d=&quot;M188.16,37.13v1.39c0,1.77,0.05,3.09,0.16,3.98c0.1,0.88,0.32,1.53,0.65,1.93&amp;#10;              c0.33,0.4,0.84,0.61,1.53,0.61c0.93,0,1.57-0.36,1.91-1.08c0.34-0.72,0.53-1.92,0.56-3.6l5.35,0.31&amp;#10;              c0.03,0.24,0.04,0.57,0.04,0.99c0,2.55-0.7,4.45-2.09,5.71c-1.39,1.26-3.36,1.89-5.91,1.89c-3.06,0-5.2-0.96-6.43-2.88&amp;#10;              c-1.23-1.92-1.84-4.88-1.84-8.9v-4.81c0-4.14,0.64-7.15,1.91-9.06c1.27-1.9,3.45-2.85,6.54-2.85c2.13,0,3.76,0.39,4.9,1.17&amp;#10;              c1.14,0.78,1.94,1.99,2.41,3.64c0.46,1.65,0.7,3.93,0.7,6.83v4.72H188.16z M188.95,25.53c-0.31,0.39-0.52,1.03-0.63,1.91&amp;#10;              c-0.11,0.88-0.16,2.23-0.16,4.02v1.98h4.54v-1.98c0-1.77-0.06-3.11-0.18-4.02c-0.12-0.91-0.34-1.56-0.65-1.93&amp;#10;              c-0.31-0.37-0.8-0.56-1.46-0.56C189.75,24.94,189.26,25.14,188.95,25.53z&quot;/&gt;&lt;path fill=&quot;#282828&quot; d=&quot;M77.59,36.61l-7.06-25.49h6.16l2.47,11.55c0.63,2.85,1.09,5.27,1.39,7.28h0.18&amp;#10;              c0.21-1.44,0.67-3.85,1.39-7.24l2.56-11.6h6.16L83.7,36.61v12.23h-6.11V36.61z&quot;/&gt;&lt;path fill=&quot;#282828&quot; d=&quot;M126.45,21.28v27.55h-4.85l-0.54-3.37h-0.13c-1.32,2.55-3.3,3.82-5.93,3.82c-1.83,0-3.18-0.6-4.05-1.8&amp;#10;              c-0.87-1.2-1.3-3.07-1.3-5.62V21.28h6.2v20.23c0,1.23,0.13,2.11,0.4,2.63c0.27,0.52,0.72,0.79,1.35,0.79&amp;#10;              c0.54,0,1.06-0.16,1.55-0.49c0.49-0.33,0.86-0.75,1.1-1.26V21.28H126.45z&quot;/&gt;&lt;path fill=&quot;#282828&quot; d=&quot;M158.27,21.28v27.55h-4.85l-0.54-3.37h-0.13c-1.32,2.55-3.3,3.82-5.93,3.82c-1.83,0-3.18-0.6-4.05-1.8&amp;#10;              c-0.87-1.2-1.3-3.07-1.3-5.62V21.28h6.2v20.23c0,1.23,0.13,2.11,0.4,2.63c0.27,0.52,0.72,0.79,1.35,0.79&amp;#10;              c0.54,0,1.06-0.16,1.55-0.49c0.49-0.33,0.86-0.75,1.1-1.26V21.28H158.27z&quot;/&gt;&lt;path fill=&quot;#282828&quot; d=&quot;M143.31,16.11h-6.16v32.72h-6.07V16.11h-6.16v-4.99h18.38V16.11z&quot;/&gt;&lt;path fill=&quot;#282828&quot; d=&quot;M178.8,25.69c-0.38-1.74-0.98-3-1.82-3.78c-0.84-0.78-1.99-1.17-3.46-1.17c-1.14,0-2.2,0.32-3.19,0.97&amp;#10;              c-0.99,0.64-1.75,1.49-2.29,2.54h-0.05l0-14.52h-5.98v39.11h5.12l0.63-2.61h0.13c0.48,0.93,1.2,1.66,2.16,2.2&amp;#10;              c0.96,0.54,2.02,0.81,3.19,0.81c2.1,0,3.64-0.97,4.63-2.9c0.99-1.93,1.48-4.95,1.48-9.06v-4.36&amp;#10;              C179.36,29.84,179.17,27.43,178.8,25.69z M173.11,36.93c0,2.01-0.08,3.58-0.25,4.72c-0.16,1.14-0.44,1.95-0.83,2.43&amp;#10;              c-0.39,0.48-0.91,0.72-1.57,0.72c-0.51,0-0.98-0.12-1.42-0.36c-0.43-0.24-0.79-0.6-1.06-1.08V27.71&amp;#10;              c0.21-0.75,0.57-1.36,1.08-1.84c0.51-0.48,1.06-0.72,1.66-0.72c0.63,0,1.12,0.25,1.46,0.74c0.34,0.49,0.58,1.33,0.72,2.49&amp;#10;              c0.13,1.17,0.2,2.83,0.2,4.99V36.93z&quot;/&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;svg id=&quot;yt-logo-red-svg&quot; class=&quot;external-icon&quot; viewbox=&quot;0 0 98 24&quot;&gt;&lt;g id=&quot;yt-logo-red&quot; viewbox=&quot;0 0 98 24&quot; preserveaspectratio=&quot;xMidYMid meet&quot;&gt;&lt;g&gt;&lt;path fill=&quot;#FF0000&quot; d=&quot;M28.4,5.12c-0.34-1.24-1.31-2.2-2.55-2.52C23.62,2,14.68,2,14.68,2S5.75,2,3.52,2.6&amp;#10;            C2.29,2.93,1.33,3.89,1,5.12C0.59,7.39,0.39,9.69,0.4,12c-0.01,2.31,0.19,4.61,0.6,6.88c0.33,1.23,1.29,2.19,2.52,2.52&amp;#10;            C5.75,22,14.68,22,14.68,22s8.93,0,11.16-0.6c1.24-0.32,2.22-1.28,2.56-2.52c0.41-2.27,0.61-4.57,0.6-6.88&amp;#10;            C29.01,9.69,28.81,7.39,28.4,5.12z&quot;/&gt;&lt;polygon fill=&quot;#FFFFFF&quot; points=&quot;11.83,16.29 19.25,12 11.83,7.71&quot;/&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;g id=&quot;youtube-red-paths&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill=&quot;#282828&quot; d=&quot;M41.67,8.35V9c0,3.45-1.53,5.48-4.88,5.48h-0.51v6h-2.74V3.42h3.49C40.22,3.42,41.67,4.77,41.67,8.35z&amp;#10;            M38.79,8.6c0-2.49-0.45-3.09-2-3.09h-0.51v7h0.47c1.47,0,2-1.06,2-3.37L38.79,8.6z&quot;/&gt;&lt;path fill=&quot;#282828&quot; d=&quot;M48.14,7.83L48,11.08c-1.17-0.24-2.13-0.08-2.6,0.69v8.78h-2.67V8h2.17l0.24,2.71h0.1c0.28-2,1.2-3,2.39-3&amp;#10;            C47.8,7.73,47.98,7.77,48.14,7.83z&quot;/&gt;&lt;path fill=&quot;#282828&quot; d=&quot;M51.27,15.25v0.63c0,2.21,0.12,3,1.06,3s1.1-0.69,1.12-2.12l2.43,0.14c0.18,2.7-1.23,3.9-3.61,3.9&amp;#10;            c-2.9,0-3.76-1.9-3.76-5.35v-2.23c0-3.64,1-5.41,3.84-5.41s3.64,1.51,3.64,5.29v2.15H51.27z M51.27,12.67v0.9h2.06v-0.89&amp;#10;            c0-2.3-0.16-3-1-3s-1,0.67-1,3L51.27,12.67z&quot;/&gt;&lt;path fill=&quot;#282828&quot; d=&quot;M70.02,11.1v9.46H67.2v-9.25c0-1-0.27-1.53-0.88-1.53c-0.54,0.02-1.02,0.34-1.25,0.82&amp;#10;            c0.01,0.17,0.01,0.34,0,0.51v9.46h-2.79v-9.26c0-1-0.27-1.53-0.88-1.53c-0.53,0.02-1,0.33-1.23,0.8v10H57.4V8h2.23l0.25,1.59l0,0&amp;#10;            c0.51-1.12,1.63-1.85,2.86-1.86c1.05-0.07,1.98,0.67,2.16,1.7c0.55-1.01,1.61-1.65,2.76-1.66C69.4,7.78,70.02,9,70.02,11.1z&quot;/&gt;&lt;path fill=&quot;#282828&quot; d=&quot;M71.4,4.83c0-1.35,0.49-1.74,1.53-1.74s1.53,0.45,1.53,1.74s-0.47,1.74-1.53,1.74S71.4,6.22,71.4,4.83z&amp;#10;            M71.59,8h2.7v12.56h-2.7V8z&quot;/&gt;&lt;path fill=&quot;#282828&quot; d=&quot;M83.5,8v12.56h-2.2L81.05,19h-0.06c-0.46,1.08-1.53,1.77-2.7,1.74c-1.67,0-2.43-1.06-2.43-3.37V8h2.82&amp;#10;            v9.19c0,1.1,0.23,1.55,0.8,1.55c0.52-0.02,0.98-0.33,1.2-0.8V8H83.5z&quot;/&gt;&lt;path fill=&quot;#282828&quot; d=&quot;M97.8,11.1v9.46h-2.82v-9.25c0-1-0.27-1.53-0.88-1.53c-0.54,0.02-1.02,0.34-1.25,0.82&amp;#10;            c0.01,0.17,0.01,0.34,0,0.51v9.46h-2.79v-9.26c0-1-0.27-1.53-0.88-1.53c-0.53,0.02-1,0.33-1.23,0.8v10h-2.81V8h2.26l0.24,1.59l0,0&amp;#10;            c0.51-1.12,1.63-1.85,2.86-1.86c1.04-0.07,1.97,0.64,2.17,1.66c0.55-0.99,1.6-1.61,2.73-1.62C97.15,7.78,97.8,9,97.8,11.1z&quot;/&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;country-code&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;masthead-skeleton-icons&quot; slot=&quot;masthead-skeleton&quot;/&gt;&lt;/ytd-masthead&gt;&lt;a slot=&quot;guide-links-primary&quot; href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/about/&quot;&gt;About&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a slot=&quot;guide-links-primary&quot; href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/about/press/&quot;&gt;Press&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a slot=&quot;guide-links-primary&quot; href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/about/copyright/&quot;&gt;Copyright&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a slot=&quot;guide-links-primary&quot; href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/t/contact_us&quot;&gt;Contact us&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a slot=&quot;guide-links-primary&quot; href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/creators/&quot;&gt;Creators&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a slot=&quot;guide-links-primary&quot; href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/ads/&quot;&gt;Advertise&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a slot=&quot;guide-links-primary&quot; href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/youtube&quot;&gt;Developers&lt;/a&gt;

      &lt;a slot=&quot;guide-links-secondary&quot; href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/t/terms&quot;&gt;Terms&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a slot=&quot;guide-links-secondary&quot; href=&quot;https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/&quot;&gt;Privacy&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a slot=&quot;guide-links-secondary&quot; href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/about/policies/&quot;&gt;Policy &amp;amp; Safety&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a slot=&quot;guide-links-secondary&quot; href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/howyoutubeworks?utm_campaign=ytgen&amp;amp;utm_source=ythp&amp;amp;utm_medium=LeftNav&amp;amp;utm_content=txt&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fhowyoutubeworks%3Futm_source%3Dythp%26utm_medium%3DLeftNav%26utm_campaign%3Dytgen&quot;&gt;How YouTube works&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a slot=&quot;guide-links-secondary&quot; href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/new&quot;&gt;Test new features&lt;/a&gt;

      

      &lt;div id=&quot;copyright&quot; slot=&quot;copyright&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;© 2020 Google LLC&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;/ytd-app&gt;&lt;!-- end of chunk --&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;watch-page-skeleton&quot; class=&quot;watch-skeleton &quot;&gt;
    &lt;div id=&quot;container&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div id=&quot;related&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;autoplay skeleton-light-border-bottom&quot;&gt;
          
            &lt;div class=&quot;video-skeleton&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;video-details&quot;&gt;
      
      &lt;div class=&quot;details flex-1&quot;&gt;
        
        
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;video-skeleton&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;video-details&quot;&gt;
      
      &lt;div class=&quot;details flex-1&quot;&gt;
        
        
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

            &lt;div class=&quot;video-skeleton&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;video-details&quot;&gt;
      
      &lt;div class=&quot;details flex-1&quot;&gt;
        
        
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

            &lt;div class=&quot;video-skeleton&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;video-details&quot;&gt;
      
      &lt;div class=&quot;details flex-1&quot;&gt;
        
        
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

            &lt;div class=&quot;video-skeleton&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;video-details&quot;&gt;
      
      &lt;div class=&quot;details flex-1&quot;&gt;
        
        
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

            &lt;div class=&quot;video-skeleton&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;video-details&quot;&gt;
      
      &lt;div class=&quot;details flex-1&quot;&gt;
        
        
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

            &lt;div class=&quot;video-skeleton&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;video-details&quot;&gt;
      
      &lt;div class=&quot;details flex-1&quot;&gt;
        
        
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

            &lt;div class=&quot;video-skeleton&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;video-details&quot;&gt;
      
      &lt;div class=&quot;details flex-1&quot;&gt;
        
        
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

            &lt;div class=&quot;video-skeleton&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;video-details&quot;&gt;
      
      &lt;div class=&quot;details flex-1&quot;&gt;
        
        
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

            &lt;div class=&quot;video-skeleton&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;video-details&quot;&gt;
      
      &lt;div class=&quot;details flex-1&quot;&gt;
        
        
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div id=&quot;info-container&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div id=&quot;primary-info&quot; class=&quot;skeleton-light-border-bottom&quot;&gt;
          
          &lt;div id=&quot;info&quot;&gt;
            
            
            &lt;div id=&quot;menu&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
            &lt;/div&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div id=&quot;secondary-info&quot; class=&quot;skeleton-light-border-bottom&quot;&gt;
          &lt;div id=&quot;top-row&quot;&gt;
            &lt;div id=&quot;video-owner&quot; class=&quot;flex-1&quot;&gt;
              
              &lt;div id=&quot;upload-info&quot; class=&quot;flex-1&quot;&gt;
                
                
              &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
            
          &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

    &lt;link rel=&quot;canonical&quot; href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=M85UvH0TRPc&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;alternate&quot; media=&quot;handheld&quot; href=&quot;https://m.youtube.com/watch?v=M85UvH0TRPc&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;alternate&quot; media=&quot;only screen and (max-width: 640px)&quot; href=&quot;https://m.youtube.com/watch?v=M85UvH0TRPc&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;theme-color&quot; content=&quot;#ff0000&quot;/&gt;&lt;title&gt;The Internet's Own Boy: The Story of Aaron Swartz - YouTube&lt;/title&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;title&quot; content=&quot;The Internet's Own Boy: The Story of Aaron Swartz&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;description&quot; content=&quot;More free documentaries: http://documentarystorm.com The Internet's Own Boy follows the story of programming prodigy and information activist Aaron Swartz. F...&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;keywords&quot; content=&quot;aaron swarz, The Internet's Own Boy: The Story Of Aaron Swartz (Film), Aaron Swartz (Organization Founder), Creative Commons, RSS, reddit, documentary, full ...&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;shortlink&quot; href=&quot;https://youtu.be/M85UvH0TRPc&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;alternate&quot; href=&quot;android-app://com.google.android.youtube/http/www.youtube.com/watch?v=M85UvH0TRPc&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;alternate&quot; href=&quot;ios-app://544007664/vnd.youtube/www.youtube.com/watch?v=M85UvH0TRPc&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;alternate&quot; type=&quot;application/json+oembed&quot; href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/oembed?format=json&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3DM85UvH0TRPc&quot; title=&quot;The Internet's Own Boy: The Story of Aaron Swartz&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;alternate&quot; type=&quot;text/xml+oembed&quot; href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/oembed?format=xml&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3DM85UvH0TRPc&quot; title=&quot;The Internet's Own Boy: The Story of Aaron Swartz&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;image_src&quot; href=&quot;https://i.ytimg.com/vi/M85UvH0TRPc/maxresdefault.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:site_name&quot; content=&quot;YouTube&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:url&quot; content=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=M85UvH0TRPc&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:title&quot; content=&quot;The Internet's Own Boy: The Story of Aaron Swartz&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:image&quot; content=&quot;https://i.ytimg.com/vi/M85UvH0TRPc/maxresdefault.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:image:width&quot; content=&quot;1280&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:image:height&quot; content=&quot;720&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:description&quot; content=&quot;More free documentaries: http://documentarystorm.com The Internet's Own Boy follows the story of programming prodigy and information activist Aaron Swartz. F...&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;al:ios:app_store_id&quot; content=&quot;544007664&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;al:ios:app_name&quot; content=&quot;YouTube&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;al:ios:url&quot; content=&quot;vnd.youtube://www.youtube.com/watch?v=M85UvH0TRPc&amp;amp;feature=applinks&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;al:android:url&quot; content=&quot;vnd.youtube://www.youtube.com/watch?v=M85UvH0TRPc&amp;amp;feature=applinks&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;al:android:app_name&quot; content=&quot;YouTube&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;al:android:package&quot; content=&quot;com.google.android.youtube&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;al:web:url&quot; content=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=M85UvH0TRPc&amp;amp;feature=applinks&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:type&quot; content=&quot;video.other&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:video:url&quot; content=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/M85UvH0TRPc&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:video:secure_url&quot; content=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/M85UvH0TRPc&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:video:type&quot; content=&quot;text/html&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:video:width&quot; content=&quot;1280&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:video:height&quot; content=&quot;720&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:video:tag&quot; content=&quot;aaron swarz&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:video:tag&quot; content=&quot;The Internet's Own Boy: The Story Of Aaron Swartz (Film)&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:video:tag&quot; content=&quot;Aaron Swartz (Organization Founder)&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:video:tag&quot; content=&quot;Creative Commons&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:video:tag&quot; content=&quot;RSS&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:video:tag&quot; content=&quot;reddit&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:video:tag&quot; content=&quot;documentary&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:video:tag&quot; content=&quot;full movie&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:video:tag&quot; content=&quot;technology&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:video:tag&quot; content=&quot;Internet&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:video:tag&quot; content=&quot;Entrepreneur (Profession)&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:video:tag&quot; content=&quot;Documentary (TV Genre)&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;fb:app_id&quot; content=&quot;87741124305&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:card&quot; content=&quot;player&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:site&quot; content=&quot;@youtube&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:url&quot; content=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=M85UvH0TRPc&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:title&quot; content=&quot;The Internet's Own Boy: The Story of Aaron Swartz&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:description&quot; content=&quot;More free documentaries: http://documentarystorm.com The Internet's Own Boy follows the story of programming prodigy and information activist Aaron Swartz. F...&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:image&quot; content=&quot;https://i.ytimg.com/vi/M85UvH0TRPc/maxresdefault.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:app:name:iphone&quot; content=&quot;YouTube&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:app:id:iphone&quot; content=&quot;544007664&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:app:name:ipad&quot; content=&quot;YouTube&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:app:id:ipad&quot; content=&quot;544007664&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:app:url:iphone&quot; content=&quot;vnd.youtube://www.youtube.com/watch?v=M85UvH0TRPc&amp;amp;feature=applinks&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:app:url:ipad&quot; content=&quot;vnd.youtube://www.youtube.com/watch?v=M85UvH0TRPc&amp;amp;feature=applinks&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:app:name:googleplay&quot; content=&quot;YouTube&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:app:id:googleplay&quot; content=&quot;com.google.android.youtube&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:app:url:googleplay&quot; content=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=M85UvH0TRPc&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:player&quot; content=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/M85UvH0TRPc&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:player:width&quot; content=&quot;1280&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:player:height&quot; content=&quot;720&quot;/&gt;
  
  
  

      
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2020 12:37:57 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>tosh</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=M85UvH0TRPc</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The mystery of why one ant species goes after larger foes (2018)</title>
<link>https://www.nationalgeographic.com/animals/2018/11/ants-head-hunters-attack-trap-jaw-enemies-nests/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nationalgeographic.com/animals/2018/11/ants-head-hunters-attack-trap-jaw-enemies-nests/</guid>
<description>&lt;span itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot; class=&quot;clearfix&quot;&gt;Scientists are beginning to solve a mystery involving three ants: A headhunter, a formidable biter, and a kidnapper.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot; class=&quot;clearfix&quot;&gt;For 60 years, scientists have known that one species of small, rust-colored ant known as &lt;em&gt;Formica archboldi&lt;/em&gt; likes to decorate its nests with skulls, or head cases, of several kinds of trap-jaw ants.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot; class=&quot;clearfix&quot;&gt;This is bizarre, because trap-jaw ants come equipped with potent stingers and gigantic mandibles that can snap closed like a beartrap. These massive mouthparts come with some special features, such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.nationalgeographic.com/2015/05/150513-ants-animals-science-insects-trap-jaw/&quot;&gt;allowing the insects to catapult to freedom when facing attack&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot; class=&quot;clearfix&quot;&gt;Diminutive &lt;em&gt;F. archboldi&lt;/em&gt; ants, native to Florida and surrounding states, nevertheless succeed in taking them down and nabbing their heads—but how?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot; class=&quot;clearfix&quot;&gt;“Something weird was going on but no one had looked into it yet,” until now, says &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.adrianalansmith.com/&quot;&gt;Adrian Smith&lt;/a&gt;, a research biologist at North Carolina State University.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot; class=&quot;clearfix&quot;&gt;In a new &lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s00040-018-0675-y&quot;&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; published in the journal &lt;em&gt;Insectes Sociaux,&lt;/em&gt; Smith has shown that &lt;em&gt;F. archboldi&lt;/em&gt; subdues its quarry with quick, highly efficient sprays of toxic acid.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot; class=&quot;clearfix&quot;/&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot; class=&quot;clearfix&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-hover-control--hover-only enlarge-button&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;enlarge-button__icons icon&quot;/&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;hide-from-mobile&quot;&gt;View Images&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2020 12:06:47 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>tosh</dc:creator>
<og:title>These ants decorate their homes with the heads of their enemies</og:title>
<og:description>We’re beginning to understand how and why one species goes after larger foes—and it may have something to do with evading kidnapper ants.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.nationalgeographic.com/animals/2018/11/ants-head-hunters-attack-trap-jaw-enemies-nests/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:image>https://www.nationalgeographic.com/content/dam/animals/2018/11/ant-collects-skulls/01-ant-collects-skull-formica-archboldi.ngsversion.1543318203486.adapt.1900.1.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nationalgeographic.com/animals/2018/11/ants-head-hunters-attack-trap-jaw-enemies-nests/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why American cities can’t keep up with infrastructure maintenance (2017)</title>
<link>https://www.strongtowns.org/journal/2017/1/9/the-real-reason-your-city-has-no-money</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.strongtowns.org/journal/2017/1/9/the-real-reason-your-city-has-no-money</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Lafayette, Louisiana, has a population of around 125,000. That makes it about the 200th largest city in the country; not really big but not really all that small either. It has a unique culture and geography, but the layout and design of the city are very ordinary American. Get outside of the core downtown and surrounding neighborhoods to visit the strip malls, big box stores and residential subdivisions and Lafayette looks like any other city you'll pass through.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;I stress its unremarkable nature not to denigrate it in any way -- I love the city and I have a special fondness for the people of Lafayette -- but to help connect you, the reader, to a shared plight. Except for a small handful of North American cities -- literally five or less -- Lafayette provides an insight into why your city has no money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Problems have solutions. Predicaments have outcomes. What is happening in Lafayette is not a problem; it's a predicament.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Along with my good friends and colleagues &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.urban-three.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Joe Minicozzi and Josh McCarty of Urban 3&lt;/a&gt;, I was invited to work with the city of Lafayette to help them get a handle on why they could not keep up with infrastructure maintenance. Through a strange path, the city had found itself with a lawyer turned newspaper reporter -- a really sharp guy named &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.strongtowns.org/journal/2016/1/27/podcast-kevin-blanchard&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Kevin Blanchard&lt;/a&gt; -- as their public works director. Questions that prior directors had found inconvenient to ask were now front and center.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Like most cities, Lafayette had the written reports detailing an enormously large backlog of infrastructure maintenance. At current spending rates, roads were going bad faster than they could be repaired. With aggressive tax increases, the rate of failure could be slowed, but not reversed. The story underground was even worse. Ironically, this news had historically been the rationale for building even more infrastructure (theory: this is a problem that we'll grow our way out of). That didn't make sense to Kevin or to the city's mayor, a guy named Joey Durel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Joe, Josh and I interviewed all the city's department heads and key staff. We gathered as much data as we could (they had a lot). We analyzed and then mapped out all of the city's revenue streams by parcel. We then did the same for all of the city's expenses. This was the most comprehensive geographic analysis of a city's finances that I've ever seen completed. When we finished, we had a three dimensional map showing what parts of the city generated more revenue than expense (in business terms, this would be called profit) and what parts of the city generated more expense than revenue (again, in business terms, this is considered a loss).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Here's that map. In accounting terms, green equals profit and red equals loss. The higher the block goes, the larger the amount of profit/loss. If you have a sense of the basic layout of North American cities post World War II, you can figure out pretty easily what is going on here.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2020 10:24:12 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>lifeisstillgood</dc:creator>
<og:title>The Real Reason Your City Has No Money — Strong Towns</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.strongtowns.org/journal/2017/1/9/the-real-reason-your-city-has-no-money</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>Problems have solutions. Predicaments have outcomes. We're in a predicament.</og:description>
<og:image>http://static1.squarespace.com/static/53dd6676e4b0fedfbc26ea91/54b6c509e4b062126976d942/58746371a5790a4103e7a35e/1563901949802/Screen+Shot+2018-03-06+at+3.22.35+PM.png?format=1500w</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.strongtowns.org/journal/2017/1/9/the-real-reason-your-city-has-no-money</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Reddit’s About page doesn&amp;#039;t include Aaron Swartz as a founder</title>
<link>https://www.reddit.com/r/WatchRedditDie/comments/j4fsi1/reddit_rewrites_history_by_excluding_aaron_swartz/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.reddit.com/r/WatchRedditDie/comments/j4fsi1/reddit_rewrites_history_by_excluding_aaron_swartz/</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;_1qeIAgB0cPwnLhDF9XSiJM&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;_12FoOEddL7j_RgMQN0SNeU&quot;&gt;The reddit admins have insisted on a unique, higher standard that often comes with secret, bad faith rules for the WatchRedditDie community. They want to ban us, but they're obsessed with manufacturing reasons beforehand. As such, we must initially filter all comments and posts before manually approving them. Please be patient as this often takes time.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;_1qeIAgB0cPwnLhDF9XSiJM&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;_12FoOEddL7j_RgMQN0SNeU&quot;&gt;This is why you often can't see comments.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;_1qeIAgB0cPwnLhDF9XSiJM&quot;&gt;If you want to go somewhere where you don't have to be treated like little children, try &lt;a href=&quot;https://ruqqus.com/&quot; class=&quot;_3t5uN8xUmg0TOwRCOGQEcU&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow ugc&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Ruqqus&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.ruqqus&quot; class=&quot;_3t5uN8xUmg0TOwRCOGQEcU&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow ugc&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;_1qeIAgB0cPwnLhDF9XSiJM&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;_7s4syPYtk5hfUIjySXcRE&quot;&gt;I am a bot, and this action was performed automatically. Please&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/message/compose/?to=/r/WatchRedditDie&quot; class=&quot;_3t5uN8xUmg0TOwRCOGQEcU&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow ugc&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;_7s4syPYtk5hfUIjySXcRE&quot;&gt;contact the moderators of this subreddit&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em class=&quot;_7s4syPYtk5hfUIjySXcRE&quot;&gt;if you have any questions or concerns.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2020 09:07:13 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>DeusExMachina</dc:creator>
<og:title>r/WatchRedditDie - Reddit Rewrites History By Excluding Aaron Swartz</og:title>
<og:type>image</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.reddit.com/r/WatchRedditDie/comments/j4fsi1/reddit_rewrites_history_by_excluding_aaron_swartz/</og:url>
<og:description>9,061 votes and 433 comments so far on Reddit</og:description>
<og:image>https://external-preview.redd.it/z0w8p-CvRzDByGmDexxUgIKaIl1gS4kBF_x1NlfxD4c.jpg?auto=webp&amp;s=1ed36fa5b7db02b1102c596c44dac80e67a4de9e</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.reddit.com/r/WatchRedditDie/comments/j4fsi1/reddit_rewrites_history_by_excluding_aaron_swartz/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>