<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Harder programming questions do a worse job of predicting outcomes</title>
<link>https://triplebyte.com/blog/interview-questions-are-too-hard-and-too-short</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://triplebyte.com/blog/interview-questions-are-too-hard-and-too-short</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;tl;dr Programming interview questions can feel unnecessarily difficult. Sometimes they actually are. And this isn't just because they make interviews excessively stressful. Our data shows that harder programming questions actually do a &lt;strong&gt;worse&lt;/strong&gt; job of predicting final outcomes than easier ones.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Programming under time pressure is difficult.&lt;/strong&gt; This is especially true during interviews. A coding exercise that would seem simple under normal circumstances somehow becomes a formidable challenge under the bright lights of an interview room. Stress hormones cloud your thinking during interviews (even though, sadly, neither fight nor flight is an effective response to a menacing programming problem). And it can almost feel like the questions are designed to be perversely difficult. I actually think this is more than just a feeling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interview questions are designed to be hard.&lt;/strong&gt; Because the cost of hiring a bad engineer is so much higher than the cost of rejecting a good engineer, companies are incentivized to set a high bar. And for most companies that means asking hard questions. Intuitively this makes sense because harder questions seem like they should result in a more rigorous screening process. But intuition turns out to be a poor guide here. &lt;strong&gt;Our data shows that harder questions are actually less predictive than relatively easy ones.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hard questions do filter out bad engineers, but they also filter out good engineers&lt;/strong&gt; (that is, they have a high false-negative rate). Easy questions, in contrast, produce fewer false-negatives but more false-positives (since more engineers get them right, including some bad ones). Balancing these two signals is the core problem you face when selecting the optimal difficulty level for interview questions. Companies—seeking to avoid false positives at all cost—tend to skew towards the harder end of this spectrum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, &lt;strong&gt;whether or not a candidate answers a question correctly is not the only source of signal during an interview.&lt;/strong&gt; You can also evaluate their process by, for example, observing how long it takes them to finish, how clean their code is, and how much they struggle while finding a solution. Our analysis shows that this second source of signal (process) is almost as predictive as the first (correctness).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But there is an additional trade-off here.&lt;/strong&gt; The questions that carry the most process signal are significantly easier than the questions that carry the most correctness signal. The reason for this becomes clear when you distill process down to how much a candidate struggles while finding a solution (the aspect of process most directly related to question difficulty). If a question is hard enough to carry a strong correctness signal, then all candidates will struggle with it (even those who eventually answer it correctly). So struggle will carry no signal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conversely, questions that carry a strong process signal will be easy enough for most candidates to answer them correctly, thus having little to offer in terms of correctness signal. An optimally difficult question is one that balances process and correctness to extract the maximum signal from the combination of these two factors (which may not be the peak signal for either).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We interviewed thousands of engineers and scored their answers along multiple dimensions, including process and correctness, and compared these scores with later performance. And, after regression analysis (looking at both process and correctness signal) our data showed that the most predictive questions were actually much easier than we expected (and easier than the questions that many companies ask).&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harder questions ultimately filter out too many qualified candidates to be optimal. So, if you want to make your hiring process more accurate, you should probably ask easier questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to state clearly, however, that this doesn't mean you should lower the bar and pass more people. &lt;strong&gt;Asking easier questions doesn't necessarily mean making your interviews easier.&lt;/strong&gt; The difficulty level of the questions you ask and where you set your decision-threshold are independent decisions. You can still implement an extremely rigorous hiring process by asking relatively easy questions and evaluating them demandingly. Our finding is simply that easier questions provide more signal. But what you do with that signal is up to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Easier interview questions are also less stressful, which is an important advantage. Stress causes candidates to under-perform. But, on the other hand, when candidates are more comfortable, they perform their true best, which actually makes interviews more predictive. I think that interviewers tend to under-estimate the effects of stress on candidates while over-estimating their own abilities. When you're the one asking the questions, it's easy to forget how hard it is to get much real programming done in 30-60 minutes. To counter this bias, we've adopted a rule at Triplebyte stating that interviewers have to give candidates 3X as much time to answer a question as they think it would take to solve it themselves. Usually this works out to be the right amount of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Easier questions are beneficial for another important reason. They allow you to fit more content into your interviews. This means you can use longer, multi-part problems which have compounding benefits in terms of prediction. You can ask questions that ramp up in difficulty over time, and these &lt;strong&gt;longer, real-world questions are more predictive than their shorter and harder cousins.&lt;sup id=&quot;ref1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://triplebyte.com/blog/interview-questions-are-too-hard-and-too-short#fn1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is partly because longer questions serve as better proxies for real-life programming. Production programming involves working with a relatively large codebase over a long period of time, and longer questions just do a better job of approximating this reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, longer questions allow you to offer hints when a candidate gets stuck. I think this is vital because even strong engineers can get tripped up at some point during a coding problem. Asking longer questions gives candidates the chance to recover from errors and show off their skills later on during an exercise. &lt;strong&gt;A single misstep shouldn't ruin an entire interview.&lt;/strong&gt; Finally, being able to offer help makes interviews less stressful which, again, results in more accurate outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Companies can get stuck in a vicious cycle when it comes to question difficulty.&lt;/strong&gt; They start out asking questions that are already too hard and too short, which leads them to make sub-optimal hiring decisions based off noisy signals. When they experience poor outcomes, they may attempt to correct by making their process even more rigorous (which generally means asking even harder questions). But this only makes their interviews less accurate. And so on. Both companies and candidates are hurt by this cycle. I see companies missing out on talent and candidates missing out on jobs—and everyone getting more stressed than they need to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope interviewers will embrace this finding. Not only can it make their work more accurate, but easier as well. It's much less time intensive to come up with straightforward, multi-step problems than perversely difficult short challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, here's our advice, if you actually want to make your interviews more accurate, you probably need to start asking easier programming questions. This doesn't mean lowering the bar. It just means getting a better signal so you can hire the right people.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you decide to ask easier questions during programming interviews, or find this post helpful in some other way, I'd love to hear from you! Email me at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:charlie@triplebyte.com&quot;&gt;charlie@triplebyte.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;fn1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;em&gt;“The best predictor of how someone will perform in a job is a work sample test (29 percent). This entails giving candidates a sample piece of work, similar to that which they would do in the job, and assessing their performance at it.”&lt;/em&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/2015/04/hire-like-google/&quot;&gt;(Wired Magazine)&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://triplebyte.com/blog/interview-questions-are-too-hard-and-too-short#ref1&quot; title=&quot;Jump back to footnote 1 in the text.&quot;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 18:04:09 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Harj</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Programming Interview Questions Are Too Hard and Too Short</og:title>
<og:description>tl;dr Programming interview questions can feel unnecessarily difficult. Sometimes they actually are. And this isn't just because they make interviews excessively stressful. Our data shows that harder programming questions actually do a worse job of predicting final outcomes than easier ones.</og:description>
<og:url>https://triplebyte.com/blog/interview-questions-are-too-hard-and-too-short</og:url>
<og:image>https://d25hn4jiqx5f7l.cloudfront.net/blog-posts/og_images/og/37_1550272508.png?1550272508</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://triplebyte.com/blog/interview-questions-are-too-hard-and-too-short</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>A faster, more efficient cryptocurrency</title>
<link>http://news.mit.edu/2019/vault-faster-more-efficient-cryptocurrency-0124</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://news.mit.edu/2019/vault-faster-more-efficient-cryptocurrency-0124</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;region region-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;block-system-main&quot; class=&quot;block block-system&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-article-content field-type-text-long field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MIT researchers have developed a new cryptocurrency that drastically reduces the data users need to join the network and verify transactions — by up to 99 percent compared to today’s popular cryptocurrencies. This means a much more scalable network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cryptocurrencies, such as the popular Bitcoin, are networks built on the blockchain, a financial ledger formatted in a sequence of individual blocks, each containing transaction data. These networks are decentralized, meaning there are no banks or organizations to manage funds and balances, so users join forces to store and verify the transactions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But decentralization leads to a scalability problem. To join a cryptocurrency, new users must download and store all transaction data from hundreds of thousands of individual blocks. They must also store these data to use the service and help verify transactions. This makes the process slow or computationally impractical for some.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a paper being presented at the Network and Distributed System Security Symposium next month, the MIT researchers introduce Vault, a cryptocurrency that lets users join the network by downloading only a fraction of the total transaction data. It also incorporates techniques that delete empty accounts that take up space, and enables verifications using only the most recent transaction data that are divided and shared across the network, minimizing an individual user’s data storage and processing requirements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In experiments, Vault reduced the bandwidth for joining its network by 99 percent compared to Bitcoin and 90 percent compared to Ethereum, which is considered one of today’s most efficient cryptocurrencies. Importantly, Vault still ensures that all nodes validate all transactions, providing tight security equal to its existing counterparts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Currently there are a lot of cryptocurrencies, but they’re hitting bottlenecks related to joining the system as a new user and to storage. The broad goal here is to enable cryptocurrencies to scale well for more and more users,” says co-author Derek Leung, a graduate student in the Computer Science and Artificial Intelligence Laboratory (CSAIL).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joining Leung on the paper are CSAIL researchers Yossi Gilad and Nickolai Zeldovich, who is also a professor in the Department of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science (EECS); and recent alumnus Adam Suhl ’18.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vaulting over blocks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each block in a cryptocurrency network contains a timestamp, its location in the blockchain, and fixed-length string of numbers and letters, called a “hash,” that’s basically the block’s identification. Each new block contains the hash of the previous block in the blockchain. Blocks in Vault also contain up to 10,000 transactions — or 10 megabytes of data — that must all be verified by users. The structure of the blockchain and, in particular, the chain of hashes, ensures that an adversary cannot hack the blocks without detection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New users join cryptocurrency networks, or “bootstrap,” by downloading all past transaction data to ensure they’re secure and up to date. To join Bitcoin last year, for instance, a user would download 500,000 blocks totaling about 150 gigabytes. Users must also store all account balances to help verify new users and ensure users have enough funds to complete transactions. Storage requirements are becoming substantial, as Bitcoin expands beyond 22 million accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers built their system on top of a new cryptocurrency network called Algorand — invented by Silvio Micali, the Ford Professor of Engineering at MIT — that’s secure, decentralized, and more scalable than other cryptocurrencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With traditional cryptocurrencies, users compete to solve equations that validate blocks, with the first to solve the equations receiving funds. As the network scales, this slows down transaction processing times. Algorand uses a “proof-of-stake” concept to more efficiently verify blocks and better enable new users join. For every block, a representative verification “committee” is selected. Users with more money — or stake — in the network have higher probability of being selected. To join the network, users verify each certificate, not every transaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But each block holds some key information to validate the certificate immediately ahead of it, meaning new users must start with the first block in the chain, along with its certificate, and sequentially validate each one in order, which can be time-consuming. To speed things up, the researchers give each new certificate verification information based on a block a few hundred or 1,000 blocks behind it — called a “breadcrumb.” When a new user joins, they match the breadcrumb of an early block to a breadcrumb 1,000 blocks ahead. That breadcrumb can be matched to another breadcrumb 1,000 blocks ahead, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The paper title is a pun,” Leung says. “A vault is a place where you can store money, but the blockchain also lets you ‘vault’ over blocks when joining a network. When I’m bootstrapping, I only need a block from way in the past to verify a block way in the future. I can skip over all blocks in between, which saves us a lot of bandwidth.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Divide and discard&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To reduce data storage requirements, the researchers designed Vault with a novel “sharding” scheme. The technique divides transaction data into smaller portions — or shards — that it shares across the network, so individual users only have to process small amounts of data to verify transactions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To implement sharing in a secure way, Vault uses a well-known data structure called a binary Merkle tree. In binary trees, a single top node branches off into two “children” nodes, and those two nodes each break into two children nodes, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Merkle trees, the top node contains a single hash, called a root hash. But the tree is constructed from the bottom, up. The tree combines each pair of children hashes along the bottom to form their parent hash. It repeats that process up the tree, assigning a parent node from each pair of children nodes, until it combines everything into the root hash. In cryptocurrencies, the top node contains a hash of a single block. Each bottom node contains a hash that signifies the balance information about one account involved in one transaction in the block. The balance hash and block hash are tied together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To verify any one transaction, the network combines the two children nodes to get the parent node hash. It repeats that process working up the tree. If the final combined hash matches the root hash of the block, the transaction can be verified. But with traditional cryptocurrencies, users must store the entire tree structure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Vault, the researchers divide the Merkle tree into separate shards assigned to separate groups of users. Each user account only ever stores the balances of the accounts in its assigned shard, as well as root hashes. The trick is having all users store one layer of nodes that cuts across the entire Merkle tree. When a user needs to verify a transaction from outside of their shard, they trace a path to that common layer. From that common layer, they can determine the balance of the account outside their shard, and continue validation normally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Each shard of the network is responsible for storing a smaller slice of a big data structure, but this small slice allows users to verify transactions from all other parts of network,” Leung says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, the researchers designed a novel scheme that recognizes and discards from a user’s assigned shard accounts that have had zero balances for a certain length of time. Other cryptocurrencies keep all empty accounts, which increase data storage requirements while serving no real purpose, as they don’t need verification. When users store account data in Vault, they ignore those old, empty accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr id=&quot;separator-comments&quot;/&gt;&lt;section&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 15:13:02 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>salvadormon</dc:creator>
<og:image>http://news.mit.edu/sites/mit.edu.newsoffice/files/styles/og/public/images/2019/MIT-Vault-Cryptocurrency.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>A faster, more efficient cryptocurrency</og:title>
<og:description>Design reduces by 99 percent the data users need to join the network and verify transactions.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>http://news.mit.edu/2019/vault-faster-more-efficient-cryptocurrency-0124</og:url>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://news.mit.edu/2019/vault-faster-more-efficient-cryptocurrency-0124</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Magic Lantern</title>
<link>https://www.magiclantern.fm/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.magiclantern.fm/</guid>
<description>&lt;h2&gt;Supported cameras:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;5D Mark II, 5D Mark III, 6D, 7D, 50D, 60D, 500D/T1i, 550D/T2i, 600D/T3i, 650D/T4i, 700D/T5i, 1100D/T3, EOS M.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;In progress:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;70D, 100D/SL1, 1200D/T5, 450D/XSi.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;5D3 1.3.4, 7D 2.0.6, 550D 1.1.0, EOS M 2.0.3.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;(downloads available, feedback and/or help needed)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Porting started:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;EOS M2, 1300D/T6 (Hello World running)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;80D (proof of concept), 750D, 5DS (can run code alongside Canon firmware)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;760D, 5D Mark IV, 7D Mark II, 77D, 200D, 800D, 6D Mark II (ROM dumpers available)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Old versions only:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;5D classic&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Emulation available (&lt;a href=&quot;https://bitbucket.org/hudson/magic-lantern/src/qemu/contrib/qemu/&quot;&gt;QEMU&lt;/a&gt;):&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;With GUI: 5D2, 5D3, 6D, 40D, 50D, 60D, 70D, 450D, 500D, 550D, 600D, 650D, 700D, 100D, 1000D, 1100D, 1200D, 1300D, EOS M, EOS M2.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;No GUI, file I/O works, still usable for porting ML: 80D, 750D, 760D, EOS M3.&lt;/h4&gt;
Very limited: 5D, 5DS, 5D4, 7D, 7D2, 400D, EOS M5, EOS M10.

&lt;h2&gt;ROM dumpers:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;5D4, 7D2, 80D, 750D, 760D, 1300D, EOS M2, 200D, 800D, 77D, 6D Mark II.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;EOS M3, EOS M5, EOS M6, EOS M10 (CHDK).&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;All other models already running ML.&lt;/h4&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 12:27:49 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>chris_overseas</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.magiclantern.fm/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>I took 50,000 images of the night sky to make an 81 Megapixel image of the moon</title>
<link>https://www.reddit.com/r/space/comments/arer0k/i_took_nearly_50000_images_of_the_night_sky_to/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.reddit.com/r/space/comments/arer0k/i_took_nearly_50000_images_of_the_night_sky_to/</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;OP used an &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 hnLHXO&quot; href=&quot;https://astronomy-imaging-camera.com/product/asi224mc&quot;&gt;ASI224MC&lt;/a&gt; for the Moon exposures for this image. This is a camera which uses a similar sensor compared to your average DSLR, but it is smaller and has no moving parts, capable of taking dozens to hundreds of frames per second depending on what resolution you use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;The software for capture, stacking, and processing is all free, thankfully. Firecapture is a popular capture software - as the ASI224MC has no viewfinder it relies on laptop control for operation. Autostakkert!2 is a popular stacking software (it aligns the Moon for each image and averages the pixel values), and either Registax or Photoshop can be used for sharpening afterwards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;As for stacking, our atmosphere distorts incoming light, such as Moonlight. You can see this effect on a hot day when you look across a parking lot, the air will shimmer. This is compounded by the fact that even when the Moon is directly overhead, you are still looking through roughly 100 miles of air. The method then used to pick out those millisecond-long moments where the Moon is actually sharp and in focus is called Lucky Imaging, and it is why OP takes so many frames. For planetary imaging 50,000 is not too uncommon, though you can get decent enough results with as little as a few hundred with a calm atmosphere free of dust. As an example, I took &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 hnLHXO&quot; href=&quot;https://www.astrobin.com/full/351168/0/?nc=user&quot;&gt;this mosaic&lt;/a&gt; with the same camera OP used, using a total of about 100,000 frames, but spread through about 55 panels since my telescope is comparable to a ~2000mm lens (and since the camera sensor is so small, it only picks up a portion of that field of view). Click &quot;full resolution&quot; at your own peril, for those on mobile devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;The other advantage of stacking multiple images is noise reduction. Cameras have some amount of random noise in each frame, which is the grainy effect you often see in darker images. Astrophotography is all about signal-to-noise ratios, with the primary goal being to increase this ratio through varying methods of noise reduction, such as image stacking. The great thing about random noise is that you can get rid of most of it by stacking about 40 images, with some decreasing benefit using higher numbers of images. Obviously 50,000 would reduce it to tiny levels, but in the case of planetary imaging, which uses very short exposures, the main advantage of stacking is to get around the atmospheric blurring. &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 hnLHXO&quot; href=&quot;https://www.cloudynights.com/uploads/monthly_07_2018/post-273658-0-74013300-1530665326.jpg&quot;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt; is an example of the benefits of stacking I found online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;Capturing the night sky via long exposure is another animal. Long exposure introduces not only random noise, but some heat-related noise caused by the camera taking so long for each exposure. This can be partially reduced through stacking (for long exposure, we use a free software called Deep Sky Stacker, which will identify and align images to detected stars), but also benefits from calibration images called Darks. These are exposures identical to the ones you took of the night sky except with the lens cap on. Using this method, you can capture only the camera noise, which is subtracted from each image of the night sky before then stacking them together. In this manner, you can remove the predictable noise as well as the random noise for a clean image.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;Also in the case of night sky long exposure, you will require a tracking mount. For bright objects like the Moon or planets, you can get away with using a manually-driven telescope, but since the Earth rotates, the stars will move during the exposure and thus require a tracking mount to counteract this. Widefield lenses (14mm or so) can get away with static tripod imaging since the stars don't noticeably move as fast, but anything 50mm or beyond will likely require a tracking mount for decent imaging.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 12:18:20 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>sohkamyung</dc:creator>
<og:title>r/space - I took nearly 50,000 images of the night sky to make an 81 Megapixel image of Tuesday's moon. Uncompressed image linked in the comments. [OC]</og:title>
<og:type>image</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.reddit.com/r/space/comments/arer0k/i_took_nearly_50000_images_of_the_night_sky_to/</og:url>
<og:description>160,059 votes and 3,752 comments so far on Reddit</og:description>
<og:image>https://preview.redd.it/d1aehdnbq0h21.jpg?auto=webp&amp;s=90682669f090293cf1c26361777b71cab7967775</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.reddit.com/r/space/comments/arer0k/i_took_nearly_50000_images_of_the_night_sky_to/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The shady economics of ‘buy one, get one free’ deals</title>
<link>https://thehustle.co/are-buy-one-get-one-free-deals-worth-it/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://thehustle.co/are-buy-one-get-one-free-deals-worth-it/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;In commerce, a single phrase wields the power of a thousand salespeople.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;It can turn even the most rational consumers into crazed lunatics who stand in 3-hour-long lines to save $3 and punch each other in the face over pieces of&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/local/public-safety/man-arrested-at-a-virginia-restaurant-during-a-cheesecake-giveaway/2018/12/05/9c088874-f8c1-11e8-8339-9aeda8decca3_story.html?noredirect=on&amp;amp;utm_term=.147c59de3953&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;cheesecake&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;We’re talking, of course, about ‘buy one, get one free.’&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Deep down, most of us understand that nothing is truly free. Corporations don’t offer us deals out the goodness of their hearts — they do it because it’s great for business. Sometimes, these promotions can even be flat out deceptive.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;So why does the allure of ‘free’ hold us captive? And are these deals even worth it?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The hypnotic power of ‘free’&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Let’s imagine you’re hankering for a treat and you are offered a choice: A Hershey’s Kiss for $0.01, or a much higher-quality Lindt truffle for $0.15&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;. Which would you go with?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;In his book&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Predictably-Irrational-Revised-Expanded-Decisions/dp/0061353248&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Predictably Irrational&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, behavioral economist Dan Ariely ran this exact&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://web.mit.edu/ariely/www/MIT/Papers/zero.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;experiment&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;and found that 73% of folks chose the pricier Lindt. But when he changed the price of the Hershey’s Kiss from $0.01 to&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;free&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span&gt;, 69% opted for the Kiss.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The introduction of that one word —&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;free&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;— entirely reversed the outcome of the study.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_12519&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; readability=&quot;34&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-12519&quot; src=&quot;https://thehustle.co/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/chocos2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;2500&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;When a ‘free’ option is introduced, it completely changes our decision-making process; example via Dan Ariely (visual: Zachary Crockett / The Hustle)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;When confronted with a purchasing choice, we typically run a quick internal&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.investopedia.com/terms/c/cost-benefitanalysis.asp&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;cost-benefit analysis&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, weighing potential satisfaction/joy against price.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;But Ariely concluded that when the word ‘free’ is introduced, it not only decreases the cost but makes us believe the&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;benefits&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;of the free item are higher. Suddenly, that mediocre Hershey’s Kiss is the finest chocolate known to mankind.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;As a result, we fall victim to the&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://market.subwiki.org/wiki/Zero_price_effect&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;zero price effect&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, a phenomenon whereby our demand for an item dramatically increases when it is free.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;For example, most of us would never purchase a low-quality, ill-fitting t-shirt at a store for $15. But when that same t-shirt is free,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/howardcamerik/status/524413860313587712&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;launched&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;from a cannon at the ballpark, we’re willing to&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2016/01/31/sports/why-sports-fans-risk-life-and-limb-for-a-rolled-up-t-shirt.html&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;break bones&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;and spill $12 beers to get our grubby hands on it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;“The moment something involves ‘free,’ we get overly excited,”&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GrHJMfysrlk&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;explains&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;Ariely, “and we no longer think rationally.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Retailers are well aware of this — and for more than a century, they’ve taken advantage of our lunacy by enlisting a promotion known as the BOGO.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BOGO-nomics&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;We’ve all seen it flashing across&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=i3A1TT3kwIY&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;TV screens&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, splayed across e-commerce landing pages, and pinned to sweaters at clothing stores:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;BUY ONE, GET ONE FREE!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;While the origins of this infamous promotion are unclear,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;The Hustle&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;traced it back to newspaper clippings from as far back as 1908.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_12520&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; readability=&quot;34&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-12520&quot; src=&quot;https://thehustle.co/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/bogo-ads.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;2500&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Buy one, get one free ads in the Barder County Index, Kansas (1908)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Largely marketed toward women, these early ads offered 2-for-1 wool dresses. In these early days of price opacity, the first dress would be marked up to cover the cost of both.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Today, these offers, affectionately called ‘BOGO’ by the corporations that peddle them, make up an estimated&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://openaccess.city.ac.uk/16301/1/BOGOF.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;80% of all ‘free’ promotions&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;. A whopping 93% of all shoppers have used a BOGO — and&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.wiser.com/how-buy-one-get-one-can-improve-your-sales/&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;66%&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;of them say it’s their favorite type of discount.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;For retailers, BOGO deals are extremely effective: They allow for the profitable liquidation of low-quality inventory under the guise of “doing something nice” for loyal consumers.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Let’s say a retailer has a surplus of jeans that cost them $20 per pair and carry a “suggested retail price” of $100 (they never&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;actually&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;sell at this price). If they run a standard 50%-off sale, they make a $30 profit ($50 – $20). With a BOGO, they offload two products instead of one and walk away with the same profit per pair.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_12521&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; readability=&quot;33&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-12521&quot; src=&quot;https://thehustle.co/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/50off.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;2500&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;A buy one, get one free is a glorified 50% sale (visual: Zachary Crockett / The Hustle)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Shoppers&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.academia.edu/7427586/EFFECTIVENESS_OF_SALES_PROMOTIONAL_TOOLS_A_STUDY_ON_DISCOUNT_PRICE_OFF_AND_BUY_ONE_GET_ONE_FREE_OFFERS_IN_BRANDED_APPAREL_RETAIL_INDUSTRY_IN_GUJARAT&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;like these deals&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;because, on paper, they seem to offer a second product totally free, at no extra cost. But according to an&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.quora.com/How-does-a-firm-benefit-from-the-Buy-one-get-one-free-or-BOGOF-scheme&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;industry insider&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, the goods we typically get in a BOGO deal are “low-demand, non-efficient, lacking in quality and/or close to the expiration date.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;“The BOGO is one of these quasi-legitimate — maybe not-so-legitimate — deals that rely on consumers not paying a lot of attention to what they’re doing,” Mark Cohen, Director of Retail Studies at Columbia University’s School of Business, tells me.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;“Buyers see ‘free’ and find it to be incredibly compelling without really doing the math.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The math is simple: What you’re really getting with a BOGO deal is a 50% discount off of the manufacturer’s suggested retail price (MSRP). And oftentimes, this price is artificially marked up to begin with.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why ‘free’ deals usually aren’t as good as they seem&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Bonnie Patton is the Executive Director of&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.truthinadvertising.org/&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Truth In Advertising&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, a nonprofit that aims to regulate deceptive advertising and false marketing. On a daily basis, she receives a “barrage of alerts” from the public on shady ‘buy one, get one free’ promotions.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Patton tells me there are several reasons BOGOs often aren’t as good as they seem:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_12522&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-12522&quot; src=&quot;https://thehustle.co/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/things.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;2500&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Visual: Zachary Crockett / The Hustle&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;A common tactic with shady BOGO deals is that the retailer will simply make the first item more expensive. You might, for instance, see a deal where you buy one shirt for $40 and get one free — but it’s possible that the true price of the shirt is $20, and you’re merely buying 2 at list price.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;According to&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.consumerreports.org/shopping-retail/when-are-sales-too-good-to-be-true/&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Consumer Reports&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, there have been at least 150 lawsuits against more than 80 retailers over misleading ‘free’ promotions in the past few years. Some of the more notable BOGO examples (links to court cases below):&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.truthinadvertising.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/Anderson-v-Burger-King-Corp-settlement-agreement.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Burger King&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;offered a BOGO Croissan’wich deal but charged a higher price ($3.15) for the sandwich than it regularly cost ($2.16).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.truthinadvertising.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/Kautsky-v-MyPillow-complaint.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MyPillow&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;offered BOGO deal on their pillows, but really just doubled the price of the first pillow.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.leagle.com/decision/infdco20180503f83&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;VIsionWorks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;offered a BOGO on eyeglasses, but it turned out they’d increased the price of the first pair by ~40%.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.truthinadvertising.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/Akinmeji-v-Jos-A-Bank-notice-of-removal.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jos. A. Bank&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; offered BOGO deals on clothing but inflated the cost of the original item (i.e. a suit that would typically sell for $600 was sold, as a part of the “deal,” for $800).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_12523&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-12523&quot; src=&quot;https://thehustle.co/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/mypillow.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;2500&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Claims from a 2017 lawsuit against MyPillow (via Truth in Advertising)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;“Retailers are often as guilty as you can get with manipulating price of an item,” says Cohen. “You’re often charged a price that nobody has ever paid; anything that’s free is just carved off the regular price.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Another misconception with buy one, get one free deals is that your&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;total utility&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;(satisfaction or happiness) is higher since you paid less for two items than you would’ve at list price.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;This makes sense if the item is something you know you’ll eventually use (like toothpaste), but BOGO deals are more typically applied to goods like expirable food, or clothing.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;But we often forget about a little something called the&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.investopedia.com/terms/l/lawofdiminishingutility.asp&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;law of diminishing marginal utility&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Simply put, this law states that the utility we get from an item decreases with each subsequent item.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;If we get a 2-for-1 pizza deal, for instance, the first slice is going to give us tremendous joy. The second slice, a little less. By the time we get to the second pizza, we’re bloated and the benefits of eating it have dramatically declined.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_12524&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-12524&quot; src=&quot;https://thehustle.co/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/pizza2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;2500&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Visual: Zachary Crockett / The Hustle&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://openaccess.city.ac.uk/16301/1/BOGOF.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Studies&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;have shown that consumers will buy two of something when the word ‘free’ is involved, even when they only need one — and the second item often ends up in the trash. If we walk into a store intending to buy one carton of milk, but encounter a BOGO deal and buy 2 cartons, we’ll almost invariably waste that second carton.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;So unless you encounter a BOGO deal on something you already planned on buying 2 of (and have an actionable use for), it’s generally not worth it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Too good to be true&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Of course, the BOGO deal isn’t the only ‘free’ promotion retailers use to amp up our consumption.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Most online clothing brands offer ‘free’ shipping, with the catch that you have to meet a minimum purchase amount (often $100) to qualify. Some&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.invespcro.com/blog/free-shipping/&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;58%&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;of consumers will add additional items to their cart — often things they didn’t originally intend to purchase — just to “save” $5 to $10 on handling fees.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;On platforms like Amazon, free shipping is often&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/business/archive/2014/11/theres-no-such-thing-as-free-shipping/383234/&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;factored&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;into the price of the item: A coffee mug that usually sells for $10 + $3 S&amp;amp;H will go for $13, with FREE shipping. We’re far more likely to buy the mug with the latter pricing model, even though we’re paying the exact same amount for it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_12525&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-12525&quot; src=&quot;https://thehustle.co/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/book.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;2500&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Visual: Zachary Crockett / The Hustle&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Another common tactic is giving an item (say, a book) away for free, but burying the original cost in the shipping fees. If the book typically costs $15, the seller might throw out a “GENEROUS ONE-TIME FREE OFFER!” and advertise the book at no cost (besides, of course, the $15-20 shipping in the fine print).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Aided by the psychological hypnotism of ‘free,’ these strategies result in increased sales at no additional burden to retailers.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;“At the end of the day, we’re motivated by a variety of things to sustain us: Air, water, food, shelter, sex… and&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;price&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span&gt;,” says Cohen. “But people forget the old adage: If it’s too good to be true, it probably is.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Share and discuss&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;br clear=&quot;all&quot;/&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;6.44&quot;&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;8.28&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://thehustle.co/&quot; onclick=&quot;ga('send', 'event', 'nav', 'advertorial', 'ps');&quot;&gt;Sign up here&lt;/a&gt; for our daily news email to get all the non-political news you never knew you needed. All it takes is 5 minutes and BOOM, you're smarter.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br clear=&quot;all&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 08:51:19 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>zzaner</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Are 'buy one, get one free deals' worth it?</og:title>
<og:description>Free deals can turn even the most rational consumer into a crazed lunatic. But are they as good as they seem to be?</og:description>
<og:url>https://thehustle.co/are-buy-one-get-one-free-deals-worth-it/</og:url>
<og:image>https://thehustle.co/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/share-1.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://thehustle.co/are-buy-one-get-one-free-deals-worth-it/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>How the US has hidden its empire</title>
<link>https://www.theguardian.com/news/2019/feb/15/the-us-hidden-empire-overseas-territories-united-states-guam-puerto-rico-american-samoa</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.theguardian.com/news/2019/feb/15/the-us-hidden-empire-overseas-territories-united-states-guam-puerto-rico-american-samoa</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;drop-cap&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;drop-cap__inner&quot;&gt;T&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;here aren’t many historical episodes more firmly lodged in the United States’s national memory than the attack on Pearl Harbor. It is one of only a few events that many people in the country can put a date to: 7 December 1941, the “date which will live in infamy,” as Franklin D Roosevelt put it. Hundreds of books have been written about it – the Library of Congress holds more than 350. And Hollywood has made movies, from the critically acclaimed From Here to Eternity, starring Burt Lancaster, to the critically derided Pearl Harbor, starring Ben Affleck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what those films don’t show is what happened next. Nine hours after Japan attacked the territory of Hawaii, another set of Japanese planes came into view over another US territory, the Philippines. As at Pearl Harbor, they dropped their bombs, hitting several air bases, to devastating effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The attack on Pearl Harbor was just that – an attack. Japan’s bombers struck, retreated and never returned. Not so in the Philippines. There, the initial air raids were followed by more raids, then by invasion and conquest. Sixteen million Filipinos – US nationals who saluted the stars and stripes and looked to FDR as their commander in chief – fell under a foreign power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contrary to popular memory, the event familiarly known as “Pearl Harbor” was in fact an all-out lightning strike on US and British holdings throughout the Pacific. On a single day, the Japanese attacked the US territories of Hawaii, the Philippines, Guam, Midway Island and Wake Island. They also attacked the British colonies of Malaya, Singapore and Hong Kong, and they invaded Thailand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first, “Pearl Harbor” was not the way most people referred to the bombings. “Japs bomb Manila, Hawaii” was the headline in one New Mexico paper; “Japanese Planes Bomb Honolulu, Island of Guam” in another in South Carolina. Sumner Welles, FDR’s undersecretary of state, described the event as “an attack upon Hawaii and upon the Philippines”. Eleanor Roosevelt used a similar formulation in her radio address on the night of 7 December, when she spoke of Japan “bombing our citizens in Hawaii and the Philippines”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was how the first draft of FDR’s speech went, too: it presented the event as a “bombing in Hawaii and the Philippines”. Yet Roosevelt toyed with that draft all day, adding things in pencil, crossing other bits out. At some point he deleted the prominent references to the Philippines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why did Roosevelt demote the Philippines? We don’t know, but it’s not hard to guess. Roosevelt was trying to tell a clear story: Japan had attacked the US. But he faced a problem. Were Japan’s targets considered “the United States”? Legally, they were indisputably US territory. But would the public see them that way? What if Roosevelt’s audience didn’t care that Japan had attacked the Philippines or Guam? Polls taken slightly before the attack show that few in the continental US supported a military defense of those remote territories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roosevelt no doubt noted that the Philippines and Guam, although technically part of the US, seemed foreign to many. Hawaii, by contrast, was more plausibly “American”. Although it was a territory rather than a state, it was closer to North America and significantly whiter than the others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet even when it came to Hawaii, Roosevelt felt a need to massage the point. So, on the morning of his speech, he made another edit. He changed it so that the Japanese squadrons had bombed not the “island of Oahu”, but the “American island of Oahu”. Damage there, Roosevelt continued, had been done to “American naval and military forces”, and “very many American lives” had been lost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An American island, where American lives were lost – that was the point he was trying to make. If the Philippines was being rounded down to foreign, Hawaii was being rounded up to “American”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One reporter in the Philippines described the scene in Manila as the crowds listened to Roosevelt’s speech on the radio. The president spoke of Hawaii and the many lives lost there. Yet he only mentioned the Philippines, the reporter noted, “very much in passing”. Roosevelt made the war “seem to be something close to Washington and far from Manila”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was not how it looked from the Philippines, where air-raid sirens continued to wail. “To Manilans the war was here, now, happening to us,” the reporter wrote. “And we have no air-raid shelters.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;section-rule&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;drop-cap&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;drop-cap__inner&quot;&gt;H&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;awaii, the Philippines, Guam – it wasn’t easy to know how to think about such places, or even what to call them. At the turn of the 20th century, when many were acquired (Puerto Rico, the Philippines, Guam, American Samoa, Hawaii, Wake), their status was clear. They were, as Theodore Roosevelt and Woodrow Wilson unabashedly called them, colonies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That spirit of forthright imperialism didn’t last. Within a decade or two, after passions had cooled, the c-word became taboo. “The word colony must not be used to express the relationship which exists between our government and its dependent peoples,” an official admonished in 1914. Better to stick with a gentler term, used for them all: territories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet a striking feature of the overseas territories was how rarely they were even discussed. The maps of the country that most people had in their heads didn’t include places such as the Philippines. Those mental maps imagined the US to be contiguous: a union of states bounded by the Atlantic, the Pacific, Mexico and Canada.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is how most people envision the US today, possibly with the addition of Alaska and Hawaii. The political scientist Benedict Anderson called it the “logo map”, meaning that if the country had a logo, this shape would be it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;u-responsive-ratio&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;gu-image&quot; itemprop=&quot;contentUrl&quot; alt=&quot;The US logo map - conterminous lower 48 states&quot; src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/c5086ec4135a39e4bf56ab4cf36a81775ae43cab/981_136_5970_3583/master/5970.jpg?width=300&amp;amp;quality=85&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;fit=max&amp;amp;s=c81a85394c4844df42eed9f714a876d8&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

The US ‘logo map’
&lt;p&gt;The problem with the logo map, however, is that it isn’t right. Its shape does not match the country’s legal borders. Most obviously, the logo map excludes Hawaii and Alaska, which became states in 1959 and now appear on virtually all published maps of the country. But it is also missing Puerto Rico, which, although not a state, has been part of the country since 1899. When have you ever seen a map of the US that had Puerto Rico on it? Or American Samoa, Guam, the US Virgin Islands, the Northern Marianas or any of the other smaller islands that the US has annexed over the years?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1941, the year Japan attacked, a more accurate picture would have been this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;u-responsive-ratio&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;gu-image&quot; itemprop=&quot;contentUrl&quot; alt=&quot;The ‘Greater United States’ map&quot; src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/f1bd4765deea1d47ea54416dd5e12babe70660a8/60_363_9973_5629/master/9973.jpg?width=300&amp;amp;quality=85&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;fit=max&amp;amp;s=2e6d367e12c26793efde9c4a635b4696&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

A map of the ‘Greater United States’ as it was in 1941
&lt;p&gt;What this map shows is the country’s full territorial extent: the “Greater United States”, as some at the turn of the 20th century called it. In this view, the place normally referred to as the US – the logo map – forms only a part of the country. A large and privileged part, to be sure, yet still only a part. Residents of the territories often call it the “mainland”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On this to-scale map, Alaska isn’t shrunken down to fit into a small inset, as it is on most maps. It is the right size – ie, huge. The Philippines, too, looms large, and the Hawaiian island chain – the whole chain, not just the eight main islands shown on most maps – if superimposed on the mainland would stretch almost from Florida to California.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This map also shows territory at the other end of the size scale. In the century before 1940, the US claimed nearly 100 uninhabited islands in the Caribbean and the Pacific. Some claims were forgotten in time – Washington could be surprisingly lax about keeping tabs. The 22 islands included here are the ones that appeared in official tallies (the census or other governmental reports) in the 1940s. I have represented them as clusters of dots in the bottom left and right corners, although they are so small that they would be invisible if they were drawn to scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The logo map is not only misleading because it excludes large colonies and pinprick islands alike. It also suggests that the US is a politically uniform space: a union, voluntarily entered into, of states standing on equal footing with one another. But that is not true, and it has never been true. From its founding until the present day, the US has contained a union of American states, as its name suggests. But it has also contained another part: not a union, not states and (for most of its history) not wholly in the Americas – its territories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is more, a lot of people have lived in that other part. According to the census count for the inhabited territories in 1940, the year before Pearl Harbor, nearly 19 million people lived in the colonies, the great bulk of them in the Philippines. That meant slightly more than one in eight of the people in the US lived outside of the states. For perspective, consider that only about one in 12 was African American. If you lived in the US on the eve of the second world war, in other words, you were more likely to be colonised than black.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My point here is not to weigh forms of oppression against one another. In fact, the histories of African Americans and colonised peoples are tightly connected (and sometimes overlapping, as for the African-Caribbeans in Puerto Rico and the US Virgin Islands). The racism that had pervaded the country since slavery also engulfed the territories. Like African Americans, colonial subjects were denied the vote, deprived of the rights of full citizens, called racial epithets, subjected to dangerous medical experiments and used as sacrificial pawns in war. They, too, had to make their way in a country where some lives mattered and others did not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What getting the Greater United States in view reveals is that race has been even more central to US history than is usually supposed. It hasn’t just been about black and white, but about Filipino, Hawaiian, Samoan and Chamoru (from Guam), too, among other identities. Race has not only shaped lives, but also the country itself – where the borders went, who has counted as “American”. Once you look beyond the logo map, you see a whole new set of struggles over what it means to inhabit the US.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;section-rule&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;drop-cap&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;drop-cap__inner&quot;&gt;L&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;ooking beyond the logo map, however, could be hard for mainlanders. The national maps they used rarely showed the territories. Even the world atlases were confusing. During the second world war, Rand McNally’s Ready Reference Atlas of the World – like many other atlases at the time – listed Hawaii, Alaska, Puerto Rico and the Philippines as “foreign”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A class of seventh-grade girls at the Western Michigan College Training School in Kalamazoo scratched their heads over this. They had been trying to follow the war on their maps. How, they wondered, could the attack on Pearl Harbor have been an attack on the US if Hawaii was foreign? They wrote to Rand McNally to inquire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Although Hawaii belongs to the United States, it is not an integral part of this country,” the publisher replied. “It is foreign to our continental shores, and therefore cannot logically be shown in the United States proper.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The girls were not satisfied. Hawaii is not an integral part of this country? “We believe this statement is not true,” they wrote. It is “an alibi instead of an explanation”. Further, they continued, “we feel that the Rand McNally atlas is misleading and a good cause for the people of outlying possessions to be embarrassed and disturbed”. The girls forwarded the correspondence to the Department of the Interior and asked for adjudication. Of course, the seventh-graders were right. As an official clarified, Hawaii was, indeed, part of the US.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet the government could be just as misleading as Rand McNally on this score. Consider the census: according to the constitution, census takers were required to count only the states, but they had always counted the territories, too. Or, at least, they had counted the continental territories. The overseas territories were handled differently. Their populations were noted, but they were otherwise excluded from demographic calculations. Basic facts about how long people lived, how many children they had, what races they were – these were given for the mainland alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The maps and census reports that mainlanders saw presented them with a selectively cropped portrait of their country. The result was profound confusion. “Most people in this country, including educated people, know little or nothing about our overseas possessions,” concluded a governmental report written during the second world war. “As a matter of fact, a lot of people do not know that we have overseas possessions. They are convinced that only ‘foreigners’, such as the British, have an ‘empire’. Americans are sometimes amazed to hear that we, too, have an ‘empire’.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;section-rule&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;drop-cap&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;drop-cap__inner&quot;&gt;T&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;he proposition that the US is an empire is less controversial today. The case can be made in a number of ways. The dispossession of Native Americans and relegation of many to reservations was pretty transparently imperialist. Then, in the 1840s, the US fought a war with Mexico and seized a third of it. Fifty years later, it fought a war with Spain and claimed the bulk of Spain’s overseas territories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Empire isn’t just landgrabs, though. What do you call the subordination of African Americans? Starting in the interwar period, the celebrated US intellectual WEB Du Bois argued that black people in the US looked more like colonised subjects than like citizens. Many other black thinkers, including Malcolm X and the leaders of the Black Panthers, have agreed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or what about the spread of US economic power abroad? The US might not have physically conquered western Europe after the second world war, but that didn’t stop the French from complaining of “coca-colonisation”. Critics there felt swamped by US commerce. Today, with the world’s business denominated in dollars, and McDonald’s in more than 100 countries, you can see they might have had a point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;u-responsive-ratio&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;gu-image&quot; itemprop=&quot;contentUrl&quot; alt=&quot;Flags on top of the fortress in Old San Juan in Puerto Rico.&quot; src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/bab76f7bf2ce94f6cbd844b34da5f0c1ded98157/0_0_3767_2521/master/3767.jpg?width=300&amp;amp;quality=85&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;fit=max&amp;amp;s=9a4e735066d08234bec849ac35911570&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

Flags on top of the fortress in Old San Juan in Puerto Rico. Photograph: Anton Gorbov/Alamy
&lt;p&gt;Then there are the military interventions. The years since the second world war have brought the US military to country after country. The big wars are well-known: Korea, Vietnam, Iraq, Afghanistan. But there has also been a constant stream of smaller engagements. Since 1945, US armed forces have been deployed abroad for conflicts or potential conflicts 211 times in 67 countries. Call it peacekeeping if you want, or call it imperialism. But clearly this is not a country that has kept its hands to itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet among all the talk of empire, one thing that often slips from view is actual territory. Yes, many would agree that the US is or has been an empire, for all the reasons above. But how much can most people say about the colonies themselves? Not, I would wager, very much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is not as if the information isn’t out there. Scholars, many working from the sites of empire themselves, have assiduously researched this topic for decades. The problem is that their works have been sidelined – filed, so to speak, on the wrong shelves. They are there, but as long as we have the logo map in our heads, they will seem irrelevant. They will seem like books about foreign countries. The confusion and shoulder-shrugging indifference that mainlanders displayed at the time of Pearl Harbor hasn’t changed much at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;section-rule&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;drop-cap&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;drop-cap__inner&quot;&gt;I&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; will confess to having made this conceptual filing error myself. Although I studied US foreign relations as a doctoral student and read countless books about “American empire” – the wars, the coups, the meddling in foreign affairs – nobody ever expected me to know even the most elementary facts about the territories. They just didn’t feel important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t until I travelled to Manila, researching something else entirely, that it clicked. To get to the archives, I would travel by “jeepney”, a transit system originally based on repurposed US army jeeps. I boarded in a section of Metro Manila where the streets are named after US colleges (Yale, Columbia, Stanford, Notre Dame), states and cities (Chicago, Detroit, New York, Brooklyn, Denver), and presidents (Jefferson, Van Buren, Roosevelt, Eisenhower). When I would arrive at my destination, the Ateneo de Manila University, one of the country’s most prestigious schools, I would hear students speaking what sounded to my Pennsylvanian ears to be virtually unaccented English. Empire might be hard to make out from the mainland, but from the sites of colonial rule themselves, it is impossible to miss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Philippines is not a US territory any more; it got its independence after the second world war. Other territories, although they were not granted independence, received new statuses. Puerto Rico became a “commonwealth”, which ostensibly replaced a coercive relationship with a consenting one. Hawaii and Alaska, after some delay, became states, overcoming decades of racist determination to keep them out of the union.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet today, the US continues to hold overseas territory. Besides Guam, American Samoa, the Northern Mariana Islands, Puerto Rico, the US Virgin Islands and a handful of minor outlying islands, the US maintains roughly 800 overseas military bases around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None of this, however – not the large colonies, small islands, or military bases – has made much of a dent on the mainland mind. One of the truly distinctive features of the US’s empire is how persistently ignored it has been. This is, it is worth emphasising, unique. The British weren’t confused as to whether there was a British empire. They had a holiday, Empire Day, to celebrate it. France didn’t forget that Algeria was French. It is only the US that has suffered from chronic confusion about its own borders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason is not hard to guess. The country perceives itself to be a republic, not an empire. It was born in an anti-imperialist revolt and has fought empires ever since, from Hitler’s Thousand-Year Reich and the Japanese empire to the “evil empire” of the Soviet Union. It even fights empires in its dreams. Star Wars, a saga that started with a rebellion against the Galactic Empire, is one of the highest-grossing film franchises of all time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;element element-rich-link element--thumbnail element-rich-link--not-upgraded&quot; data-component=&quot;rich-link&quot; data-link-name=&quot;rich-link-1 | 1&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;rich-link&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;rich-link__container&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;rich-link__header&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;rich-link__title&quot;&gt;Unlearning the myth of American innocence&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;This self-image of the US as a republic is consoling, but it is also costly. Most of the cost has been paid by those living in the colonies and around the military bases. The logo map has relegated them to the shadows, which are a dangerous place to live. At various times, the inhabitants of the US empire have been shot, shelled, starved, interned, dispossessed, tortured and experimented on. What they haven’t been, by and large, is seen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The logo map carries a cost for mainlanders, too. It gives them a truncated view of their own history, one that excludes part of their country. It is an important part. The overseas parts of the US have triggered wars, brought forth inventions, raised up presidents and helped define what it means to be “American”. Only by including them in the picture do we see a full portrait of the country – not as it appears in its fantasies, but as it actually is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;How to Hide an Empire: A Short History of the Greater United States by Daniel Immerwahr will be published by Bodley Head on 28 February. Buy it at&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://guardianbookshop.com/how-to-hide-an-empire-9781847923981.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline in-body-link--immersive&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;guardianbookshop.com&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;bullet&quot;&gt;•&lt;/span&gt; Follow the Long Read on Twitter at &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/@gdnlongread&quot; title=&quot;&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline in-body-link--immersive&quot;&gt;@gdnlongread&lt;/a&gt;, or sign up to the long read weekly email &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/info/ng-interactive/2017/may/05/sign-up-for-the-long-read-email&quot; title=&quot;&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline in-body-link--immersive&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 04:27:52 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>unmole</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://www.theguardian.com/news/2019/feb/15/the-us-hidden-empire-overseas-territories-united-states-guam-puerto-rico-american-samoa</og:url>
<og:description>The long read: The United States likes to think of itself as a republic, but it holds territories all over the world – the map you always see doesn’t tell the whole story</og:description>
<og:image>https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/5f61e45ae68b368a85b96d37151b287c76b83b8f/773_625_8622_5174/master/8622.jpg?width=1200&amp;height=630&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=crop&amp;overlay-align=bottom%2Cleft&amp;overlay-width=100p&amp;overlay-base64=L2ltZy9zdGF0aWMvb3ZlcmxheXMvdGctZGVmYXVsdC5wbmc&amp;s=2c45f1f0d3745bd16b7e4214a2f9ef06</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>How the US has hidden its empire</og:title>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.theguardian.com/news/2019/feb/15/the-us-hidden-empire-overseas-territories-united-states-guam-puerto-rico-american-samoa</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Cache Eviction: When Are Randomized Algorithms Better Than LRU? (2014)</title>
<link>http://danluu.com/2choices-eviction/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://danluu.com/2choices-eviction/</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;meta charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;/&gt;&lt;title&gt;Caches: LRU v. random&lt;/title&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;viewport&quot; content=&quot;width=device-width,initial-scale=1&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;icon&quot; href=&quot;data:;base64,=&quot;/&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot; readability=&quot;217.75126732004&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Caches: LRU v. random&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once upon a time, my &lt;a href=&quot;http://pages.cs.wisc.edu/~sohi/&quot;&gt;computer architecture professor&lt;/a&gt; mentioned that using a random eviction policy for caches really isn't so bad. That random eviction isn't bad can be surprising -- if your cache fills up and you have to get rid of something, choosing the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mathcs.emory.edu/~cheung/Courses/355/Syllabus/9-virtual-mem/LRU-replace.html&quot;&gt;least recently used (LRU)&lt;/a&gt; is an obvious choice, since you're more likely to use something if you've used it recently. If you have a tight loop, LRU is going to be perfect as long as the loop fits in cache, but it's going to cause a miss every time if the loop doesn't fit. A random eviction policy degrades gracefully as the loop gets too big.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In practice, on real workloads, random tends to do worse than other algorithms. But what if we take two random choices and just use LRU between those two choices?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the relative miss rates we get for SPEC CPU with a Sandy Bridge-like cache (&lt;a href=&quot;http://danluu.com/3c-conflict/&quot;&gt;8-way associative&lt;/a&gt;, 64k, 256k, and 2MB L1, L2, and L3 caches, respectively). These are ratios (algorithm miss rate : random miss rate); lower is better. Each cache uses the same policy at all levels of the cache.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;Policy&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;L1 (64k)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;L2 (256k)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;L3 (2MB)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;2-random&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.91&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.93&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.95&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;FIFO&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.96&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.97&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.02&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;LRU&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.90&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.90&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.97&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;random&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;Random and FIFO are both strictly worse than either LRU or 2-random. LRU and 2-random are pretty close, with LRU edging out 2-random for the smaller caches and 2-random edging out LRU for the larger caches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To see if anything odd is going on in any individual benchmark, we can look at the raw results on each sub-benchmark. The L1, L2, and L3 miss rates are all plotted in the same column for each benchmark, below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://danluu.com/images/2choices-eviction/sandy-bridge-miss.png&quot; alt=&quot;Cache miss rates for Sandy Bridge-like cache&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we might expect, LRU does worse than 2-random when the miss rates are high, and better when the miss rates are low.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, it's not clear if 2-random is beating LRU in L3 cache miss rates because it does better when the caches are large or because it does better because it's the third level in a hierarchical cache. Since a cache line that's being actively used in L1 or L2 isn't touched in L3, an eviction can happen from the L3 (which forces an eviction of both the L1 and L2) since, as far as the L3 is concerned, that line hasn't been used recently. This makes it less obvious that LRU is a good eviction policy for L3 cache.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To separate out the effects, let's look at the relative miss rates for a non-hierarchical (single level) vs. hierarchical caches at various sizes. For the hierarchical cache, the L1 and L2 sizes are as above, 64k and 256k, and only the L3 cache size varies. Below, we've got the geometric means of the ratios of how each policy does (over all SPEC sub-benchmarks, compared to random eviction). A possible downside to this metric is that if we have some very low miss rates, those could dominate the mean since small fluctuations will have a large effect on the ratio, but we can look the distribution of results to see if that's the case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://danluu.com/images/2choices-eviction/sweep-sizes-mean-ratios.png&quot; alt=&quot;Cache miss ratios for cache sizes between 64K and 16M&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://danluu.com/images/2choices-eviction/sweep-sizes-mean-ratios-l3.png&quot; alt=&quot;L3 cache miss ratios for cache sizes between 512K and 16M&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sizes below 512k are missing for the hierarchical case because of the 256k L2 -- we're using an inclusive L3 cache here, so it doesn't really make sense to have an L3 that's smaller than the L2. Sizes above 16M are omitted because cache miss rates converge when the cache gets too big, which is uninteresting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at the single cache case, it seems that LRU works a bit better than 2-random for smaller caches (lower miss ratio is better), 2-random edges out LRU as the cache gets bigger. The story is similar in the hierarchical case, except that we don't really look at the smaller cache sizes where LRU is superior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comparing the two cases, the results are different, but similar enough that it looks our original results weren't only an artifact of looking at the last level of a hierarchical cache.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below, we'll look at the entire distribution so we can see if the mean of the ratios is being skewed by tiny results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://danluu.com/images/2choices-eviction/sweep-sizes-miss.png&quot; alt=&quot;L3 cache miss ratios for cache sizes between 512K and 16M&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://danluu.com/images/2choices-eviction/sweep-sizes-miss-l3.png&quot; alt=&quot;L3 cache miss ratios for cache sizes between 512K and 16M&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It looks like, for a particular cache size (one column of the graph), the randomized algorithms do better when miss rates are relatively high and worse when miss rates are relatively low, so, if anything, they're disadvantaged when we just look at the geometric mean -- if we were to take the arithmetic mean, the result would be dominated by the larger results, where 2 random choices and plain old random do relatively well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From what we've seen of the mean ratios, 2-random looks fine for large caches, and from what we've seen of the distribution of the results, that's despite 2-random being penalized by the mean ratio metric, which makes it seem pretty good for large caches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, it's common to implement pseudo-LRU policies because LRU can be too expensive to be workable. Since 2-random requires having at least as much information as LRU, let's take a look at what happens we use pseudo 2-random (approximately 80% accurate), and pseudo 3-random (a two-level tournament, each level of which is approximately 80% accurate).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since random and FIFO are clearly not good replacement policies, I'll leave them out of the following graphs. Also, since the results were similar in the single cache as well as multi-level cache case, we can just look at the results from the more realistic multi-level cache case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://danluu.com/images/2choices-eviction/sweep-sizes-mean-ratios-l3-pseudo.png&quot; alt=&quot;L3 cache miss ratios for cache sizes between 512K and 16M&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since pseudo 2-random acts like random 20% of the time and 2-random 80% of the time, we might expect it to fall somewhere between 2-random and random, which is exactly what happens. A simple tweak to try to improve pseudo 2-random is to try pseudo 3-random (evict the least recently used of 3 random choices). While that's still not quite as good as true 2-random, it's pretty close, and it's still better than LRU (and pseudo LRU) for caches larger than 1M.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The one big variable we haven't explored is the set associativity. To see how LRU compares with 2-random across different cache sizes let's look at the LRU:2-random miss ratio (higher/red means LRU is better, lower/green means 2-random is better).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://danluu.com/images/2choices-eviction/sweep-sizes-assocs-mean-ratios.png&quot; alt=&quot;Cache miss ratios for cache sizes between 64K and 16M with associativities between and 64&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On average, increasing associativity increases the difference between the two policies. As before, LRU is better for small caches and 2-random is better for large caches. Associativities of 1 and 2 aren't shown because they should be identical for both algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's still a combinatorial explosion of possibilities we haven't tried yet. One thing to do is to try different eviction policies at different cache levels (LRU for L1 and L2 with 2-random for L3 seems promising). Another thing to do is to try this for different types of caches. I happened to choose CPU caches because it's easy to find simulators and benchmark traces, but in today's “put a cache on it” world, there are a lot of other places 2-random can be applied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For any comp arch folks, from this data, I suspect that 2-random doesn't keep up with adaptive policies like DIP (although it might -- it's in the right ballpark, but it was characterized on a different workload using a different simulator, so it's not 100% clear). However, A pseudo 2-random policy can be implemented that barely uses more resources than pseudo-LRU policies, which makes this very cheap compared to DIP. Also, we can see that pseudo 3-random is substantially better than pseudo 2-random, which indicates that k-random is probably an improvement over 2-random for the k. Some k-random policy might be an improvement over DIP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So we've seen that this works, but why would anyone think to do this in the first place? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.eecs.harvard.edu/~michaelm/postscripts/handbook2001.pdf&quot;&gt;The Power of Two Random Choices: A Survey of Techniques and Results by Mitzenmacher, Richa, and Sitaraman&lt;/a&gt; has a great explanation. The mathematical intuition is that if we (randomly) throw n balls into n bins, the maximum number of balls in any bin is &lt;code&gt;O(log n / log log n)&lt;/code&gt; with high probability, which is pretty much just &lt;code&gt;O(log n)&lt;/code&gt;. But if (instead of choosing randomly) we choose the least loaded of k random bins, the maximum is &lt;code&gt;O(log log n / log k)&lt;/code&gt; with high probability, i.e., even with two random choices, it's basically &lt;code&gt;O(log log n)&lt;/code&gt; and each additional choice only reduces the load by a constant factor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This turns out to have all sorts of applications; things like &lt;a href=&quot;http://brooker.co.za/blog/2012/01/17/two-random.html&quot;&gt;load balancing&lt;/a&gt; and hash distribution are natural fits for the balls and bins model. There are also a lot of applications that aren't obviously analogous to the balls and bins model, like &lt;a href=&quot;http://citeseerx.ist.psu.edu/showciting?cid=1042246&quot;&gt;circuit routing&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.math.cmu.edu/math/mathcolloquium.php?SeminarSelect=522&quot;&gt;Erdős–Rényi&lt;/a&gt; graphs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Thanks to Jan Elder and Mark Hill for making dinero IV freely available, to Aleksandar Milenkovic for providing SPEC CPU traces, and to Carl Vogel, James Porter, Peter Fraenkel, Katerina Barone-Adesi, Jesse Luehrs, Lea Albaugh, and Kevin Lynagh for advice on plots and plotting packages, to Mindy Preston for finding a typo in the acknowledgments, to Lindsey Kuper for pointing out some terminology stuff, to Tom Wenisch for suggesting that I check out CMP$im for future work, and to Leah Hanson for extensive comments on the entire post.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 04:26:44 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>zwliew</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://danluu.com/2choices-eviction/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Muscle memory discovery ends &amp;#039;use it or lose it&amp;#039; dogma</title>
<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2019/01/190125084106.htm</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2019/01/190125084106.htm</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;first&quot;&gt;The old adage &quot;use it or lose it&quot; tells us: if you stop using your muscles, they'll shrink. Until recently, scientists thought this meant that nuclei -- the cell control centers that build and maintain muscle fibers -- are also lost to sloth.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;text&quot; readability=&quot;125&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But according to a review published in &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Physiology&lt;/em&gt;, modern lab techniques now allow us to see that nuclei gained during training persist even when muscle cells shrink due to disuse or start to break down. These residual 'myonuclei' allow more and faster growth when muscles are retrained -- suggesting that we can &quot;bank&quot; muscle growth potential in our teens to prevent frailty in old age. It also suggests that athletes who cheat and grow their muscles with steroids may go undetected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Our biggest cells are in our muscles, and they're all fused together&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Syncytium. Sounds like a neo-noir comic book series. It's actually a special type of tissue in your body, where cells are fused together extra close -- so close, that they behave a like a giant single cell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Heart, bone and even placenta are built on these networks of cells,&quot; says Lawrence Schwartz, Professor of Biology at the University of Massachusetts. &quot;But by far our biggest cells -- and biggest syncytia -- are our muscles.&quot; Like the Sin City series, it appeared at first that everything was black and white with syncytia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Muscle growth is accompanied by the addition of new nuclei from stem cells to help meet the enhanced synthetic demands of larger muscle cells,&quot; explains Schwartz. &quot;This led to the assumption that a given nucleus controls a defined volume of cytoplasm -- so that when a muscle shrinks or 'atrophies' due to disuse or disease, the number of myonuclei decreases.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A muscle can gain nuclei, but never loses them&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This assumption long seemed valid, with many researchers reporting the presence of disintegrating nuclei in muscle tissue during atrophy induced by inactivity, injury or paralysis. But modern cell-type-specific dyes and genetic markers have shown that the dying nuclei other researchers had detected were in fact inflammatory and other cells recruited to atrophic muscle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new evidence paints a very different picture of muscle syncytium.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Two independent studies -- one in rodents and the other in insects -- have demonstrated that nuclei are not lost from atrophying muscle fibers, and even remain after muscle death has been initiated.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This suggest that once a nucleus has been acquired by a muscle fiber, it belongs to the muscle syncytium -- probably for life. But Schwartz, for one, is unsurprised by the new findings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Muscles get damaged during extreme exercise, and often have to weather changes in food availability and other environmental factors that lead to atrophy. They wouldn't last very long giving up their nuclei in response to every one of these insults.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&quot;Use it or lose it -- until you use it again&quot;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since myonuclei are the synthetic engine of muscle fibers, retaining them should enable muscle size and strength to recover more quickly after one of these insults, and help to explain the phenomenon of 'muscle memory'.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;It is well documented in the field of exercise physiology that it is far easier to reacquire a certain level of muscle fitness through exercise than it was to achieve it the first place, even if there has been a long intervening period of detraining. In other word, the phrase &quot;use it or lose it&quot; is might be more accurately articulated as 'use it or lose it, until you work at it again'.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As such, the findings have important implications beyond understanding muscle biology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Informing public health policy, the discovery that myonuclei are retained indefinitely emphasizes the importance of exercise in early life. During adolescence muscle growth is enhanced by hormones, nutrition and a robust pool of stem cells, making it an ideal period for individuals to &quot;bank&quot; myonuclei that could be drawn upon to remain active in old age.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The findings also support frequent drugs testing for competitive athletes, with permanent bans for proven steroid cheats since they will benefit from the steroids long after their use has ended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Anabolic steroids produce a permanent increase in users' capacity for muscle development. In keeping with this, studies show that mice given testosterone acquire new myonuclei that persist long after the steroid use ends.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;story_source&quot; readability=&quot;29&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Story Source:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Materials provided by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.frontiersin.org&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Frontiers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Note: Content may be edited for style and length.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2019 23:14:17 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>prostoalex</dc:creator>
<og:title>Muscle memory discovery ends 'use it or lose it' dogma</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2019/01/190125084106.htm</og:url>
<og:description>Exercise physiologists agree: muscle memory is real. But how are these 'memories' stored? A review has a simple answer: nuclei gained during training persist even when muscle cells shrink due to disuse or start to break down. This means we can 'bank' nuclei in our youth to prevent frailty in old age -- and makes steroid use in competitive sport a perfect but irredeemable crime.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2019/01/190125084106.htm</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>LD_PRELOAD: The Hero We Need and Deserve</title>
<link>https://blog.jessfraz.com/post/ld_preload/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.jessfraz.com/post/ld_preload/</guid>
<description>&lt;h2&gt;LD_PRELOAD: The Hero We Need and Deserve&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sunday, February 17, 2019&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m a huge, HUGE, fan of &lt;code&gt;LD_PRELOAD&lt;/code&gt; let me tell you… oh wait it’s my blog so I’m going to. Where do I begin…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About three years ago, I wrote a blog post about the &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.jessfraz.com/post/top-10-favorite-ldflags/&quot;&gt;10 &lt;code&gt;LDFLAGS&lt;/code&gt; I love&lt;/a&gt;. After writing the post, I realized I should have made the number odd because I think that is part of BuzzFeed’s “click algorithm.” But more seriously, I realized just how many people on the internet you can upset when you don’t include &lt;code&gt;LD_PRELOAD&lt;/code&gt; in your favorite &lt;code&gt;LDFLAGS&lt;/code&gt; post. I am going to take the time right now to make one thing very clear, VERY CLEAR, listen closely: &lt;code&gt;LD_PRELOAD&lt;/code&gt; IS NOT A FLAG. It is an environment variable. Wake up sheeple! Phew!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that’s out of the way, we can continue… I love &lt;code&gt;LD_PRELOAD&lt;/code&gt;. I love it so much I am devoting this entire blog post to professing my undying love for it. So here we go…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;background&quot;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those who don’t know what &lt;code&gt;LD_PRELOAD&lt;/code&gt; is: &lt;a href=&quot;https://xkcd.com/1053/&quot;&gt;TODAY IS YOUR LUCKY DAY!&lt;/a&gt; &lt;code&gt;LD_PRELOAD&lt;/code&gt; allows you to override symbols in any library by specifying your new function in a shared object.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you run &lt;code&gt;LD_PRELOAD=/path/to/my/free.so /bin/mybinary&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;/path/to/my/free.so&lt;/code&gt; is loaded &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt; any other library, including libc. When &lt;code&gt;mybinary&lt;/code&gt; is executed, it uses your custom function for &lt;code&gt;free&lt;/code&gt;. PRETTY FREAKING AWESOME RIGHT!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.jessfraz.com/img/kronk.gif&quot; alt=&quot;kronk&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FEEL THE POWER! Okay, so moving on…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;fun-times-on-the-internet&quot;&gt;Fun Times on the Internet&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One night, I’m just hanging around in my apartment, laying on my couch, and I think “oh I’m going to ask the Internet what they’ve done with &lt;code&gt;LD_PRELOAD&lt;/code&gt;.” This is how most of my tweets start for what it’s worth. So I asked…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot; readability=&quot;6.3879781420765&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;yo internet nerds, tell me all the ways you've done dirty things with LD_PRELOAD…. I need them…. for… science…&lt;/p&gt;
— jessie frazelle 👩🏼‍🚀 (@jessfraz) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jessfraz/status/1087468414707343362?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;January 21, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This tweet blew up in THE BEST WAY! I got some really cool responses I will highlight below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-conversation=&quot;none&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot; readability=&quot;3.030303030303&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Not mine but my favorite: &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/zljcn70pmh&quot;&gt;https://t.co/zljcn70pmh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
— ダデイさま (@leifwalsh) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/leifwalsh/status/1087496833058914304?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;January 21, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-conversation=&quot;none&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot; readability=&quot;6.3959390862944&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;$ FORCE_PID=42 LD_PRELOAD=./getpid.so bash -c 'echo $$'&lt;br/&gt;42&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For forcing specific bad ssh key generation when the RNG was busted…&lt;/p&gt;
— 𝙺𝚎𝚎𝚜 𝙲𝚘𝚘𝚔 (@kees_cook) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/kees_cook/status/1094391729422123008?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;February 10, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-conversation=&quot;none&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot; readability=&quot;4.8695652173913&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;i didn't use this but dropbox recently stopped working on non-ext4 filesystems and there's this LD_PRELOAD hack to make it work anyway &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/DqRL12FNMk&quot;&gt;https://t.co/DqRL12FNMk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
— 🔎Julia Evans🔍 (@b0rk) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/b0rk/status/1087478518534098945?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;January 21, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-conversation=&quot;none&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot; readability=&quot;3.3197969543147&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Intercept readline calls to add undo to any interpreter that uses readline&lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/M44lDMaeFy&quot;&gt;https://t.co/M44lDMaeFy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/aoeldkK4X6&quot;&gt;https://t.co/aoeldkK4X6&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/w84O715eQG&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/w84O715eQG&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
— Thomas Ballinger (@ballingt) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ballingt/status/1087473790227951616?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;January 21, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-conversation=&quot;none&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot; readability=&quot;4.741935483871&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;We actually mention this in an academic paper! &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/qg5ac6vXx7&quot;&gt;https://t.co/qg5ac6vXx7&lt;/a&gt; We used LD_PRELOAD to interpose on the OnStar software modem audio interface.&lt;/p&gt;
— Karl (@supersat) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/supersat/status/1087472112611282945?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;January 21, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-conversation=&quot;none&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot; readability=&quot;6.0353356890459&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;I wrote a silly hack that let you mount an app’s objc runtime as a filesystem so you could easily browse the class hierarchy. It could be inserted via dyld. Here is a screenshot of the Finder browsing the runtime. &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/zyYxSsGaoS&quot;&gt;https://t.co/zyYxSsGaoS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
— Bill Bumgarner (@bbum) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/bbum/status/1087556645473796096?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;January 22, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-conversation=&quot;none&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot; readability=&quot;6.4285714285714&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;enabling rapid-fire railguns in quake3 rocket arena by hooking gettimeofday() via LD_PRELOAD, enable/disable by hooking strstr() and using console commands&lt;/p&gt;
— HD Moore (@hdmoore) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hdmoore/status/1087470884896628737?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;January 21, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-conversation=&quot;none&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot; readability=&quot;4.7351351351351&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;I made a thing to disable SSL certificate verification in a bunch of popular applications/libraries 😈&lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/jMWQtbl0Kb&quot;&gt;https://t.co/jMWQtbl0Kb&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
— Dаvіd Вucһаnаn (@David3141593) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/David3141593/status/1087469585798959105?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;January 21, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This isn’t all of them but isn’t the internet utterly awesome! You can poke through the thread more and find ones you love as well. But let’s move on to some mad science…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;science&quot;&gt;SCIENCE&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, not the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/S.C.I.E.N.C.E.&quot;&gt;Incubus album&lt;/a&gt;… but my science experiment that I did with &lt;code&gt;LD_PRELOAD&lt;/code&gt;. My friend, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/grepory&quot;&gt;@grepory&lt;/a&gt;, and I came up with this absolutely insane idea for “kernelless”. Yeah, it’s a joke making fun of all the other “-less”s. But ours was special, m’kay. He even made a dope website for it, &lt;a href=&quot;http://kernelless.cloud/&quot;&gt;kernelless.cloud&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the way we were going to implement this in a mad science way would be as “Cloud Native Syscalls.” Let me tell you about the “Cloud Native Syscalls”…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;cloud-native-syscalls&quot;&gt;Cloud Native Syscalls&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first part of the “Cloud Native Syscalls” architecture consists of a daemon on a cloud VM which has a network endpoint accepting incoming syscalls and their arguments. The daemon then performs these syscalls, almost in a code execution as a service type way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To use “Cloud Native Syscalls”, you compile your binary with the library as follows: &lt;code&gt;LD_PRELOAD=/path/to/my/cloudnativesyscalls.so /bin/ls&lt;/code&gt;. This ensures that all your syscalls when you run &lt;code&gt;ls&lt;/code&gt; on &lt;em&gt;your host&lt;/em&gt; are actually performed in the cloud and sent to the daemon described above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.jessfraz.com/img/nuts.gif&quot; alt=&quot;nuts&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;F’king nuts right… I know. We are working on our A-round don’t worry. It’s truly revolutionary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways, that was our little science experiment. Hope you liked it, or at least enjoyed all the other people’s fun hacks. :) Keep &lt;code&gt;LD_PRELOAD&lt;/code&gt;ing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.jessfraz.com/img/everyday-im-ld-preloading.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;everyday-im-ld-preloading&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2019 22:54:48 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ingve</dc:creator>
<og:title>LD_PRELOAD: The Hero We Need and Deserve</og:title>
<og:url>https://blog.jessfraz.com/post/ld_preload/</og:url>
<og:image>/img/share.png</og:image>
<og:description>A summary of my undying love for LD_PRELOAD.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.jessfraz.com/post/ld_preload/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>WireGuard for MacOS</title>
<link>https://lists.zx2c4.com/pipermail/wireguard/2019-February/003853.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://lists.zx2c4.com/pipermail/wireguard/2019-February/003853.html</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;title&gt;WireGuard for macOS&lt;/title&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;Index&quot; href=&quot;index.html&quot; /&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;made&quot; href=&quot;mailto:wireguard%40lists.zx2c4.com?Subject=Re%3A%20WireGuard%20for%20macOS&amp;amp;In-Reply-To=%3CCAHmME9qjTJbWYVr9cToXpfnshGkppcqVS5%3DiVzqsrjS%2Bv_aF%2Bw%40mail.gmail.com%3E&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;robots&quot; content=&quot;index,nofollow&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta http-equiv=&quot;Content-Type&quot; content=&quot;text/html; charset=utf-8&quot; /&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;Previous&quot; href=&quot;003891.html&quot; /&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;Next&quot; href=&quot;003881.html&quot; /&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body bgcolor=&quot;#FFFFFF&quot; id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot; readability=&quot;44.785804816223&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jason A. Donenfeld&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:wireguard%40lists.zx2c4.com?Subject=Re%3A%20WireGuard%20for%20macOS&amp;amp;In-Reply-To=%3CCAHmME9qjTJbWYVr9cToXpfnshGkppcqVS5%3DiVzqsrjS%2Bv_aF%2Bw%40mail.gmail.com%3E&quot; title=&quot;WireGuard for macOS&quot;&gt;Jason at zx2c4.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sat Feb 16 02:26:20 CET 2019&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;pre&gt;
Hey everyone,

After many months of hard work, Roopesh, Eric, and I are pleased to
announce an initial version of WireGuard for macOS:

&lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/wireguard/id1451685025?ls=1&amp;amp;mt=12&quot;&gt;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/wireguard/id1451685025?ls=1&amp;amp;mt=12&lt;/a&gt;

This is built from the same code base as our existing iOS app and
makes use of Apple's Network Extension API to provide native
integration into the operating system's networking stack. The
application lives in the status bar, and after importing a
configuration, the ordinary System Preferences networking item may
also be used to control each tunnel. Because it uses these deep
integration APIs, we're only allowed to distribute the application
using the macOS App Store (whose rejections, appeals, and eventual
acceptance made for quite the stressful saga over the last week and a
half). Compared to the current CLI integration, we expect the
WireGuard experience using this app to be excellent.

For curious folks without a Mac (or without the patience to cajole KVM
into booting macOS), I've assembled a few screenshots:
&lt;a href=&quot;https://data.zx2c4.com/wireguard-for-macos-screenshots-february-2019/&quot;&gt;https://data.zx2c4.com/wireguard-for-macos-screenshots-february-2019/&lt;/a&gt;

This is new software, and there will certainly be problems. Don't
hesitate to email &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.zx2c4.com/mailman/listinfo/wireguard&quot;&gt;team at wireguard.com&lt;/a&gt; directly with bugs as you
encounter them.

Enjoy!

Regards,
Jason

PS: Because people will inevitably ask: yes, a Windows client is on
its way, and it will have a very similar interface to this macOS one.
We're taking the long and careful route, writing a new TUN driver for
Windows 7+ called &quot;Wintun&quot; that we expect to be safer and faster than
the current popular OpenVPN TUN driver, and also suitable for all
projects, not just for WireGuard. We already have packets flowing and
things generally work well, but polish will require a bit of patience.
If you'd like to help and have an appetite for NDIS drivers, Win32 GUI
programming, or Go, please do get in touch.
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.zx2c4.com/mailman/listinfo/wireguard&quot;&gt;More information about the WireGuard mailing list&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2019 20:46:52 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>helper</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://lists.zx2c4.com/pipermail/wireguard/2019-February/003853.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>