<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Explaining copyright broke the YouTube copyright system</title>
<link>https://www.law.nyu.edu/centers/engelberg/news/2020-03-04-youtube-takedown</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.law.nyu.edu/centers/engelberg/news/2020-03-04-youtube-takedown</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;This is a story about how the most sophisticated copyright filter in the world prevented us from explaining copyright law. It doesn’t involve &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vox.com/the-goods/2020/2/4/21112444/renegade-tiktok-song-dance&quot;&gt;TikTok dance moves&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Qj2Xald7NYQ&quot;&gt;nuanced 90s remixes featuring AOC&lt;/a&gt;. No, it involves a debate at a law school conference over how and when one song can infringe the copyright of another and how exactly one proves in a courtroom if the accused song is “substantially similar” enough to be deemed illegal. In the end, because it was blocked by one of the music companies who owns the song, it also became a textbook study in how fair use still suffers online and what it takes to pushback when a video is flagged. A copyright riddle wrapped up in an algorithmic enigma, symbolic of the many current content moderation dilemmas faced by online platforms today.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to watch the video it is available &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UVQTz65Bq70&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. If you prefer to listen to it you can subscribe to the Engelberg Center Live Events podcast &lt;a href=&quot;https://engelberg-center-live.simplecast.com&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.  And if you are curious about how new European laws about copyright filtering may impact this sort of situation in the future both inside and outside of Europe, you might be interested in our upcoming conference examining online copyright liability &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/a-new-global-copyright-order-tickets-94197983705&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;A New Global Copyright Order?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on April 20, 2020. You can find out more information about that conference &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/a-new-global-copyright-order-tickets-94197983705&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Video&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/UVQTz65Bq70&quot; width=&quot;560&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The video in question was a recording of the “Proving Similarity” panel, which was part of the Engelberg Center’s Proving IP symposium in May of 2019.  The panel, which was moderated by Professor &lt;a href=&quot;https://law.vanderbilt.edu/bio/joseph-fishman&quot;&gt;Joseph Fishman&lt;/a&gt;, featured presentations and discussions by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www2.jfmusicservices.com/&quot;&gt;Judith Finell&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://sandywilbur.com/&quot;&gt;Sandy Wilbur&lt;/a&gt;.  Ms. Finell and Ms. Wilbur were the musicologist experts for the opposing parties in the high profile Blurred Lines copyright infringement case. In that case the estate of Marvin Gaye accused Robin Thicke and Pharrell Williams of infringing on Gaye’s song “Got to Give it Up” when they wrote the hit song “Blurred Lines.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The primary purpose of the panel was to have these two musical experts explain to the largely legal audience how they analyze and explain songs in copyright litigation.  The panel opened with each expert giving a presentation about how they approach song analysis.  These presentations included short clips of songs, both in their popular recorded version and versions stripped down to focus on specific musical elements.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Takedown&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In June of 2019, a video of the panel was posted to the NYU School of Law youtube page.  In August of 2019 a new version of the video was posted.  The audio track of the new video was identical to the first. However, more legible versions of the presentation slides were inserted in order to make it easier for viewers to read them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike the first video, this second video was flagged by YouTube’s Content ID system for multiple claims of infringement:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div data-embed-button=&quot;media_entity_embed&quot; data-entity-embed-display=&quot;entity_reference:media_thumbnail&quot; data-entity-type=&quot;media&quot; data-entity-uuid=&quot;c200be61-f95b-45ca-9244-1f6b07dd39d7&quot; data-langcode=&quot;en&quot; class=&quot;embedded-entity&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.law.nyu.edu/sites/default/files/YTTakedown1.png&quot; width=&quot;678&quot; height=&quot;529&quot; alt=&quot;Image of songs matched to the video by content ID&quot; typeof=&quot;foaf:Image&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The video used clips of the songs in question to illustrate specific points about how they were analyzed in the context of copyright infringement litigation.  As such, we were confident that our use of the songs were covered by fair use and disputed the claims using YouTube’s internal system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shortly thereafter we received notice that the rightsholder was rejecting our dispute on multiple songs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div data-embed-button=&quot;media_entity_embed&quot; data-entity-embed-display=&quot;entity_reference:media_thumbnail&quot; data-entity-type=&quot;media&quot; data-entity-uuid=&quot;153ac9a3-49a8-43e5-9682-14cf5c990c66&quot; data-langcode=&quot;en&quot; class=&quot;embedded-entity&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.law.nyu.edu/sites/default/files/YTTakedown2.png&quot; width=&quot;1532&quot; height=&quot;1010&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot of email informing us that our challenge had been rejected&quot; typeof=&quot;foaf:Image&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Decision and the Question&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still confident that our uses were covered by fair use, we researched the YouTube &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/youtube/answer/2807684?hl=en&quot;&gt;counternotification process&lt;/a&gt;.  We discovered that if we continued to challenge the accusation of infringement and lost, our video would be subject to &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/youtube/answer/2814000&quot;&gt;copyright strikes&lt;/a&gt;.  If the account was subject to multiple strikes its ability to live stream could be restricted or the account could be terminated.  While our colleagues in the communications department were highly supportive of our efforts, they were concerned that one misstep could wipe NYU Law’s entire YouTube presence off the internet.&lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt;In deciding how we could continue to press our case, one question was unclear.  Our single video was subject to multiple copyright infringement claims.  If we failed to prevail, would that mean that the account was subject to one copyright strike because all of the claims were against a single video, or multiple strikes tied to each claim against the single video?  As there were four remaining claims against our video, and three claims could result in the termination of the account, the distinction was highly relevant to us. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div data-embed-button=&quot;media_entity_embed&quot; data-entity-embed-display=&quot;entity_reference:media_thumbnail&quot; data-entity-type=&quot;media&quot; data-entity-uuid=&quot;94c86f69-c1ec-42dc-bc7a-bef4133a5e9a&quot; data-langcode=&quot;en&quot; class=&quot;embedded-entity&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.law.nyu.edu/sites/default/files/YTTakedown3.png&quot; width=&quot;665&quot; height=&quot;518&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot of appeal process screen&quot; typeof=&quot;foaf:Image&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, we still do not know the answer to that question.  &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/youtube/answer/6300781?hl=en&quot;&gt;This page&lt;/a&gt; seems like the closest to one having an answer, but it does not provide one to our specific question.  We tried using the ‘Was this helpful?’ link at the bottom to get additional information, but YouTube did not respond. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Resolution&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This would have been a dead end for most users.  Unable to understand how the already opaque dispute resolution process might impact the status of their account, they would have to decide if it was worth gambling their entire YouTube account on the chances that their some combination of YouTube and the rightsholder would recognize their fair use claim.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since we are the center at NYU Law focused on technology and innovation, it was not a dead end for us.  We reached out to YouTube through private channels to try to get clarity around the copyright strike rules.  While we never got that clarity, some weeks later we were informed that the claims against our video had been removed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Takeaway&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What lessons can be learned from this process?  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, it highlights how challenging it can be for users with strong counter-arguments to dispute an allegation of infringement by large rightsholders.  The Engelberg Center is home to some of the top technology and intellectual property scholars in the world, as well as people who have actually operated the notice and takedown processes for large online platforms.  We had legal confidence in our position that would cost an average user tens of thousands of dollars (if not more) to obtain.  Even all of those advantages were not enough to allow us to effectively resolve this dispute.  Instead, we had to also rely on our personal networks to trigger a process - one that is still unclear - that resulted in the accusations being removed.  This is not a reasonable expectation to place on average users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, it highlights the imperfect nature of automated content screening and the importance of process when automation goes wrong.  A system that assumes any match to an existing work is infringement needs a robust process to deal with the situations where that is not the case.  Our original counterclaim included a clear explanation of the nature of the video and the reasons for using the clips.  It is hard to imagine someone with any familiarity with copyright law watching the video, reviewing our claim, and then summarily rejecting it.  Nonetheless, that is what happened.  No matter how much automation allows you to scale, the system will still require informed and fair human review at some point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Third, it highlights the costs of things going wrong. The YouTube copyright enforcement system is likely the most expensive and sophisticated copyright enforcement system ever created.  If even this system has these types of flaws, it is likely that the systems  set up by smaller sites will be even less perfect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nonetheless, we are happy that the video has been restored.  You can watch it - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=efH7O5NgvUQ&amp;amp;list=PLJkLD_s9pYaa8pXexCK7Q7ZRGhn3Dc7Ud&quot;&gt;along with all of the other videos from Proving IP&lt;/a&gt; - on the NYU Law YouTube channel. You can also listen to the audio from it and all of the Engelberg Center’s events by &lt;a href=&quot;https://engelberg-center-live.simplecast.com&quot;&gt;subscribing to our live events podcast&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, Europe has recently passed legislation designed to oblige more websites to implement automated copyright filters.  Our event &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/a-new-global-copyright-order-tickets-94197983705&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;A New Global Copyright Order?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on April 20 will examine how that legislation will impact Europe and the worldwide conversation around copyright law.  We hope to see you there.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2020 19:59:11 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>pulisse</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.law.nyu.edu/centers/engelberg/news/2020-03-04-youtube-takedown</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Highest French court reclassifies Uber drivers as employees</title>
<link>https://www.courdecassation.fr/IMG/20200304_arret_uber_communique_eng.pdf?</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.courdecassation.fr/IMG/20200304_arret_uber_communique_eng.pdf?</guid>
<description>&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.courdecassation.fr/IMG/20200304_arret_uber_communique_eng.pdf?&quot;&gt;Download PDF&lt;/a&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2020 18:46:24 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Aissen</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.courdecassation.fr/IMG/20200304_arret_uber_communique_eng.pdf?</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Waymo Via</title>
<link>https://waymo.com/waymo-via/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://waymo.com/waymo-via/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Since 2017, the Waymo Driver has been learning to drive large Class 8 trucks in much the same way a human driver would, after years of driving passenger cars. Many of the principles are the same, but things like braking, turning, and checking for blind spots are quite different with a fully-loaded truck and trailer. We’re currently testing our fleet of trucks in California and Arizona, and we’ll soon expand to Texas and New Mexico in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re also extending the Waymo Driver to help with local delivery around town. In fact, we’ve already launched a few pilot programs in the Phoenix area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No matter what you’re transporting or where it’s headed, Waymo Via will have you covered.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2020 18:07:50 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>partingshots</dc:creator>
<og:title>Waymo Via – Waymo</og:title>
<og:url>https://waymo.com/waymo-via/</og:url>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:image>https://waymo.com/static/images/waymo-via/splash.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://waymo.com/waymo-via/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Google Kubernetes Engine is introducing a cluster management fee on June 6</title>
<link>https://cloud.google.com/kubernetes-engine/pricing</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://cloud.google.com/kubernetes-engine/pricing</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;This page explains pricing for worker nodes and cluster management in Google Kubernetes Engine (GKE).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting June 6, 2020, GKE clusters will accrue a management fee of $0.10 per cluster per hour, irrespective of cluster size or topology. One &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/kubernetes-engine/docs/concepts/types-of-clusters&quot;&gt;zonal cluster&lt;/a&gt; per billing account is free. GKE cluster management fees do not apply to &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/anthos/gke&quot;&gt;Anthos GKE&lt;/a&gt; clusters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To demonstrate our commitment to superior performance, we are also introducing a Service Level Agreement (SLA) that's financially backed with a guaranteed availability of 99.95% for &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/kubernetes-engine/docs/concepts/types-of-clusters&quot;&gt;regional clusters&lt;/a&gt; and 99.5% for &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/kubernetes-engine/docs/concepts/types-of-clusters&quot;&gt;zonal clusters&lt;/a&gt; running a version of GKE available through the &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/kubernetes-engine/docs/release-notes-stable&quot;&gt;Stable&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/kubernetes-engine/docs/concepts/release-channels&quot;&gt;release channel&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This SLA also covers clusters that follow the &lt;a href=&quot;https://kubernetes.io/docs/setup/release/version-skew-policy/&quot; class=&quot;external&quot;&gt;Kubernetes Open Source Software (OSS) version skew policy&lt;/a&gt; and clusters that use the default version offered in the Stable channel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;note&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;span&gt;The new SLA will be available on June 6, 2020.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;free_cluster&quot;&gt;Free cluster&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GKE provides each billing account one &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/kubernetes-engine/docs/concepts/types-of-clusters&quot;&gt;zonal cluster&lt;/a&gt; for free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;pricing_for_cluster_management&quot;&gt;Pricing for cluster management&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting June 6, 2020, GKE will charge a cluster management fee of $0.10 per cluster per hour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;pricing_for_worker_nodes&quot;&gt;Pricing for worker nodes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GKE uses Compute Engine instances for &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/kubernetes-engine/docs/concepts/cluster-architecture#nodes&quot;&gt;worker nodes in the cluster&lt;/a&gt;. You are billed for each of those instances according to &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/compute/pricing&quot;&gt;Compute Engine's pricing&lt;/a&gt;, until the nodes are deleted. Compute Engine resources are billed on a per-second basis with a one-minute minimum usage cost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;pricing_calculator&quot;&gt;Pricing calculator&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can use the &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/products/calculator#tab=container&quot;&gt;Google Cloud pricing calculator&lt;/a&gt; to estimate your monthly GKE charges, including cluster management fees and worker node pricing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2020 17:20:56 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>agoell</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:title>Pricing  |  Kubernetes Engine Documentation  |  Google Cloud</og:title>
<og:url>https://cloud.google.com/kubernetes-engine/pricing</og:url>
<og:image>https://cloud.google.com/images/social-icon-google-cloud-1200-630.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://cloud.google.com/kubernetes-engine/pricing</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The neuroinvasive potential of SARS-CoV2</title>
<link>https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/32104915</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/32104915</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Following the severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus (SARS-CoV) and Middle East respiratory syndrome coronavirus (MERS-CoV), another highly pathogenic coronavirus named SARS-CoV-2 (previously known as 2019-nCoV) emerged in December 2019 in Wuhan, China, and rapidly spreads around the world. This virus shares highly homological sequence with SARS-CoV, and causes acute, highly lethal pneumonia (COVID-19) with clinical symptoms similar to those reported for SARS-CoV and MERS-CoV. The most characteristic symptom of COVID-19 patients is respiratory distress, and most of the patients admitted to the intensive care could not breathe spontaneously. Additionally, some COVID-19 patients also showed neurologic signs such as headache, nausea and vomiting. Increasing evidence shows that coronavriruses are not always confined to the respiratory tract and that they may also invade the central nervous system inducing neurological diseases. The infection of SARS-CoV has been reported in the brains from both patients and experimental animals, where the brainstem was heavily infected. Furthermore, some coronaviruses have been demonstrated able to spread via a synapse-connected route to the medullary cardiorespiratory center from the mechano- and chemoreceptors in the lung and lower respiratory airways. In light of the high similarity between SARS-CoV and SARS-CoV2, it is quite likely that the potential invasion of SARS-CoV2 is partially responsible for the acute respiratory failure of COVID-19 patients. Awareness of this will have important guiding significance for the prevention and treatment of the SARS-CoV-2-induced respiratory failure. (229 words) This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;copyright&quot;&gt;This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2020 17:02:19 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>processing</dc:creator>
<og:image>http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/coreutils/img/pubmed256blue.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/32104915</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Malawi legalises the growing, selling and export of cannabis</title>
<link>https://africafeeds.com/2020/02/27/malawi-legalises-the-growing-selling-and-export-of-cannabis/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://africafeeds.com/2020/02/27/malawi-legalises-the-growing-selling-and-export-of-cannabis/</guid>
<description>&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;.2crddg9ex5e.3.0.0.1.0.$lx-commentary.$lx-commentary.2.0.1.1:$post-5e57fe374958db067adf010b.0.3.0.0:$post_1&quot;&gt;Malawi has joined the list of &lt;a href=&quot;https://africafeeds.com/2018/04/30/zimbabwe-charges-50k-for-license-to-cultivate-cannabis/&quot;&gt;southern African&lt;/a&gt; countries that have legalised the growing, selling and export of cannabis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;.2crddg9ex5e.3.0.0.1.0.$lx-commentary.$lx-commentary.2.0.1.1:$post-5e57fe374958db067adf010b.0.3.0.0:$post_1&quot;&gt;But the country still restricts the legalization of cannabis for personal use, unlike in South Africa where the courts allowed for cannabis for personal use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;.2crddg9ex5e.3.0.0.1.0.$lx-commentary.$lx-commentary.2.0.1.1:$post-5e57fe374958db067adf010b.0.3.0.0:$post_1&quot;&gt;Per the latest changes to the country’s laws, cannabis will be used to make medicines and hemp fibres.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;.2crddg9ex5e.3.0.0.1.0.$lx-commentary.$lx-commentary.2.0.1.1:$post-5e57fe374958db067adf010b.0.3.0.0:$post_1&quot;&gt;Hemp fibres are used to make clothes, biofuel, paper and other products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;.2crddg9ex5e.3.0.0.1.0.$lx-commentary.$lx-commentary.2.0.1.1:$post-5e57fe374958db067adf010b.0.3.0.0:$post_1&quot;&gt;Malawi depends heavily on tobacco trade but the Cannabis sales could supplement that and boost its revenue streams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p data-reactid=&quot;.2crddg9ex5e.3.0.0.1.0.$lx-commentary.$lx-commentary.2.0.1.1:$post-5e57fe374958db067adf010b.0.3.0.0:$post_1&quot;&gt;Southern African countries, including Zambia, Lesotho and Zimbabwe, have all relaxed their rules on growing cannabis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many for instance in South Africa who consider legalizing Cannabis use as dangerous for the population especially young people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Zimbabwe legalized the cultivation of Cannabis, it offered license to individuals and companies willing to grow the substance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$50 000 is what it takes for people to acquire the licence to grow the plant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Growers will also be required to pay an annual return fee of $15,000 while an application to renew a producer’s licence will cost $20,000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A licence to also conduct research on cannabis has been set at $5,000 while an application for renewal of a licence to conduct research on cannabis will cost $2,500.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If one wants an application for variation or amendment of a licence, that would also cost $2,500 and an application for import or export licence will cost $5,000 and if you want an inspection licence you have to pay $2 500.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It appears many countries in Africa have started considering decriminalizing the growing of the plant due to its economic gains.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source: Africafeeds.com&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2020 16:07:44 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>edward</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Malawi legalises the growing, selling and export of cannabis - Africa Feeds</og:title>
<og:description>Malawi has joined the list of southern African countries that have legalised the growing, selling and export of cannabis. But the country still restricts the legalization of cannabis for personal use, unlike in South Africa where the courts allowed for cannabis for personal use. Per the latest changes to the country’s laws, cannabis will be …</og:description>
<og:url>https://africafeeds.com/2020/02/27/malawi-legalises-the-growing-selling-and-export-of-cannabis/</og:url>
<og:image>https://africafeeds.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/cannabis.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://africafeeds.com/2020/02/27/malawi-legalises-the-growing-selling-and-export-of-cannabis/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Show HN: Monitoror – Unified monitoring wallboard</title>
<link>https://monitoror.com</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://monitoror.com</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Monitor &lt;strong&gt;server status&lt;/strong&gt; by pinging them, check a port to ensure that something is listening behind, &lt;strong&gt;display your CI state&lt;/strong&gt;, and follow its progress live.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most &lt;strong&gt;popular services&lt;/strong&gt; like Jenkins, GitHub, Azure DevOps, Travis CI, ... are &lt;strong&gt;already supported&lt;/strong&gt;. Feel free to &lt;a class=&quot;c-underlined&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/monitoror/monitoror/issues&quot;&gt;request new features&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;c-button c-button--ghost&quot; href=&quot;https://monitoror.com/documentation/#tile-definitions&quot;&gt;Discover all tiles types &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2020 13:13:23 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>alex_d</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://monitoror.com/assets/images/opengraph.png</og:image>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:title>Monitoror — Unified monitoring wallboard</og:title>
<og:url>https://monitoror.com</og:url>
<og:description>Monitoror is a wallboard monitoring app to monitor server status; monitor CI builds progress or even display critical values</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://monitoror.com/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Spot the Drowning Child (2015)</title>
<link>http://spotthedrowningchild.com/#</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://spotthedrowningchild.com/#</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;http://spotthedrowningchild.com/#&quot;&gt;http://spotthedrowningchild.com/#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=22482731&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=22482731&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 600&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 343&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2020 10:57:47 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>vinnyglennon</dc:creator>
<og:title>Spot The Drowning Child</og:title>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>http://spotthedrowningchild.com/</og:url>
<og:image>http://spotthedrowningchild.com/Aimanness_Photography_drowning.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>Can you spot the drowning child in this crowded wave pool? An interactive public service announcement. To the untrained eye, drowning can look just like swimming. The Instinctive Drowning Response is frequently missed, even by people nearby.</og:description>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://spotthedrowningchild.com/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Farmers are hacking their tractors because of a repair ban (2018) [video]</title>
<link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=F8JCh0owT4w</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=F8JCh0owT4w</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;eow-description&quot; class=&quot;&quot;&gt;When it comes to repair, farmers have always been self reliant. But the modernization of tractors and other farm equipment over the past few decades has left most farmers in the dust thanks to diagnostic software that large manufacturers hold a monopoly over.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this episode of State of Repair, Motherboard goes to Nebraska to talk to the farmers and mechanics who are fighting large manufacturers like John Deere for the right to access the diagnostic software they need to repair their tractors.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;WATCH NEXT: The Pinball Doctors, the Last Arcade Technicians in NYC - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/redirect?v=F8JCh0owT4w&amp;amp;redir_token=ra6OYvjSNu9OK2qqc646C6Pmvyp8MTU4MzQ1NjQ5MkAxNTgzMzcwMDky&amp;amp;event=video_description&amp;amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Fvice.video%2F2DRls2X&quot; class=&quot;yt-uix-sessionlink&quot; data-sessionlink=&quot;itct=CCwQ6TgYACITCP2LlJ-RgugCFa5ATAgdNVwJ3UiMn8HR9NCQ4Rc&quot; data-url=&quot;/redirect?v=F8JCh0owT4w&amp;amp;redir_token=ra6OYvjSNu9OK2qqc646C6Pmvyp8MTU4MzQ1NjQ5MkAxNTgzMzcwMDky&amp;amp;event=video_description&amp;amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Fvice.video%2F2DRls2X&quot; data-target-new-window=&quot;True&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://vice.video/2DRls2X&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Subscribe to MOTHERBOARD: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/redirect?v=F8JCh0owT4w&amp;amp;redir_token=ra6OYvjSNu9OK2qqc646C6Pmvyp8MTU4MzQ1NjQ5MkAxNTgzMzcwMDky&amp;amp;event=video_description&amp;amp;q=http%3A%2F%2Fbit.ly%2FSubscribe-To-MOTHERBOARD&quot; class=&quot;yt-uix-sessionlink&quot; data-sessionlink=&quot;itct=CCwQ6TgYACITCP2LlJ-RgugCFa5ATAgdNVwJ3UiMn8HR9NCQ4Rc&quot; data-url=&quot;/redirect?v=F8JCh0owT4w&amp;amp;redir_token=ra6OYvjSNu9OK2qqc646C6Pmvyp8MTU4MzQ1NjQ5MkAxNTgzMzcwMDky&amp;amp;event=video_description&amp;amp;q=http%3A%2F%2Fbit.ly%2FSubscribe-To-MOTHERBOARD&quot; data-target-new-window=&quot;True&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://bit.ly/Subscribe-To-MOTHERBOARD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Follow MOTHERBOARD&lt;br/&gt;Facebook: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/redirect?v=F8JCh0owT4w&amp;amp;redir_token=ra6OYvjSNu9OK2qqc646C6Pmvyp8MTU4MzQ1NjQ5MkAxNTgzMzcwMDky&amp;amp;event=video_description&amp;amp;q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2Fmotherboardtv&quot; class=&quot;yt-uix-sessionlink&quot; data-sessionlink=&quot;itct=CCwQ6TgYACITCP2LlJ-RgugCFa5ATAgdNVwJ3UiMn8HR9NCQ4Rc&quot; data-url=&quot;/redirect?v=F8JCh0owT4w&amp;amp;redir_token=ra6OYvjSNu9OK2qqc646C6Pmvyp8MTU4MzQ1NjQ5MkAxNTgzMzcwMDky&amp;amp;event=video_description&amp;amp;q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2Fmotherboardtv&quot; data-target-new-window=&quot;True&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/motherboardtv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Twitter: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/redirect?v=F8JCh0owT4w&amp;amp;redir_token=ra6OYvjSNu9OK2qqc646C6Pmvyp8MTU4MzQ1NjQ5MkAxNTgzMzcwMDky&amp;amp;event=video_description&amp;amp;q=http%3A%2F%2Ftwitter.com%2Fmotherboard&quot; class=&quot;yt-uix-sessionlink&quot; data-sessionlink=&quot;itct=CCwQ6TgYACITCP2LlJ-RgugCFa5ATAgdNVwJ3UiMn8HR9NCQ4Rc&quot; data-url=&quot;/redirect?v=F8JCh0owT4w&amp;amp;redir_token=ra6OYvjSNu9OK2qqc646C6Pmvyp8MTU4MzQ1NjQ5MkAxNTgzMzcwMDky&amp;amp;event=video_description&amp;amp;q=http%3A%2F%2Ftwitter.com%2Fmotherboard&quot; data-target-new-window=&quot;True&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://twitter.com/motherboard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Tumblr: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/redirect?v=F8JCh0owT4w&amp;amp;redir_token=ra6OYvjSNu9OK2qqc646C6Pmvyp8MTU4MzQ1NjQ5MkAxNTgzMzcwMDky&amp;amp;event=video_description&amp;amp;q=http%3A%2F%2Fmotherboardtv.tumblr.com%2F&quot; class=&quot;yt-uix-sessionlink&quot; data-sessionlink=&quot;itct=CCwQ6TgYACITCP2LlJ-RgugCFa5ATAgdNVwJ3UiMn8HR9NCQ4Rc&quot; data-url=&quot;/redirect?v=F8JCh0owT4w&amp;amp;redir_token=ra6OYvjSNu9OK2qqc646C6Pmvyp8MTU4MzQ1NjQ5MkAxNTgzMzcwMDky&amp;amp;event=video_description&amp;amp;q=http%3A%2F%2Fmotherboardtv.tumblr.com%2F&quot; data-target-new-window=&quot;True&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://motherboardtv.tumblr.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Instagram: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/redirect?v=F8JCh0owT4w&amp;amp;redir_token=ra6OYvjSNu9OK2qqc646C6Pmvyp8MTU4MzQ1NjQ5MkAxNTgzMzcwMDky&amp;amp;event=video_description&amp;amp;q=http%3A%2F%2Finstagram.com%2Fmotherboardtv&quot; class=&quot;yt-uix-sessionlink&quot; data-sessionlink=&quot;itct=CCwQ6TgYACITCP2LlJ-RgugCFa5ATAgdNVwJ3UiMn8HR9NCQ4Rc&quot; data-url=&quot;/redirect?v=F8JCh0owT4w&amp;amp;redir_token=ra6OYvjSNu9OK2qqc646C6Pmvyp8MTU4MzQ1NjQ5MkAxNTgzMzcwMDky&amp;amp;event=video_description&amp;amp;q=http%3A%2F%2Finstagram.com%2Fmotherboardtv&quot; data-target-new-window=&quot;True&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://instagram.com/motherboardtv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;More videos from the VICE network: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/redirect?v=F8JCh0owT4w&amp;amp;redir_token=ra6OYvjSNu9OK2qqc646C6Pmvyp8MTU4MzQ1NjQ5MkAxNTgzMzcwMDky&amp;amp;event=video_description&amp;amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.fb.com%2Fvicevideo&quot; class=&quot;yt-uix-sessionlink&quot; data-sessionlink=&quot;itct=CCwQ6TgYACITCP2LlJ-RgugCFa5ATAgdNVwJ3UiMn8HR9NCQ4Rc&quot; data-url=&quot;/redirect?v=F8JCh0owT4w&amp;amp;redir_token=ra6OYvjSNu9OK2qqc646C6Pmvyp8MTU4MzQ1NjQ5MkAxNTgzMzcwMDky&amp;amp;event=video_description&amp;amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.fb.com%2Fvicevideo&quot; data-target-new-window=&quot;True&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://www.fb.com/vicevideo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2020 10:23:55 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>seanalltogether</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=F8JCh0owT4w</og:url>
<og:title>Tractor Hacking: The Farmers Breaking Big Tech's Repair Monopoly</og:title>
<og:image>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/F8JCh0owT4w/maxresdefault.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>When it comes to repair, farmers have always been self reliant. But the modernization of tractors and other farm equipment over the past few decades has left...</og:description>
<og:type>video.other</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=F8JCh0owT4w</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Post YC Depression</title>
<link>https://www.bmaho.com/articles/post-yc-depression</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bmaho.com/articles/post-yc-depression</guid>
<description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5e4afca13c3a77d3eb3fe8f4/5e5e8c0550f1ab92d7546bca_Frame%203%20(1).png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;It had been a long time since I'd seen them. In fact, it had been a long time since I’d seen anyone...&lt;/h3&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Every New Years, my friends and I do the same thing. We cook. We eat. We drink. We reflect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We reflect on the stories of the past year—that time we threw up on the couch, that time we became born-again-virgins from involuntary abstinence, that time we fell in-and-out of love with our real-estate broker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This New Years was no different. We cooked. We ate. We drank. Then it was time to reflect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Around the table we went. My neck turning and chair swiveling as we listened to one another’s stories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually, the necks turned and the chairs swiveled towards me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I cried.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2.5 years ago, I started a company. Six months in, we applied to Y Combinator and got accepted into the Summer 2018 batch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5e4afca13c3a77d3eb3fe8f4/5e5eacda0a8a0f2bef2e7478_Frame%205.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
My face 5 mins after we had gotten accepted
&lt;p&gt;Even as a pubescent and rotund-tween, getting into YC was my dream. I'd lay in my twin bed, with my J-Bieber-Esque haircut, and stare at the teal painted walls thinking of a day like this; the day we'd get called to the big-leagues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We packed everything and left our lives in New York City for Silicon Valley—the place I had read about for a decade. The place where the giants were born. Apple. Facebook. Google. Airbnb. Stripe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to be a giant...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can't remember much from our 8 months in California. Every day was the same degree of sunny and warm. Every day we took the same loop around our ticky-tacky neighborhood. We were Bill Murray in “Groundhog Day” sans jokes or love interests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We lived in a place called Sunnyvale. A land solely comprised of strip-malls and one-story suburban ranches. For two, 27-year olds, it was a hot destination—and by hot I mean bad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5e4afca13c3a77d3eb3fe8f4/5e5eacf5c6b037b79a6e0bda_Frame%206.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But we embraced the burbs and saw its boring monotony as a blessing. Being in a place where our main source of surprise was walking the aisles at Safeway meant that we could work—and work endlessly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;80 hour weeks. 90 hour weeks. 100 hour weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We worked. We ate. We worked. We ate too much. We worked. We gained weight. We worked. We stopped going to the gym. We worked...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shortly after YC had ended, a noise from my phone blasted—I was awake. I yanked the metal-beaded drawstring to open the flapping plastic slats. Outside, all I saw was fog, and inside, all I smelled was smoke. The forest fires north of Oakland had blown their nasty-asses to Sunnyvale. It was unsafe to breathe outside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The earth was burning and I was burnt-out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like all high-functioning and healthy adults, we stocked up on 2 XL Pineapple Pizzas from Dominos (plus cinna-stix cause we're not fucking heathens) and proceeded to watch all 5 Twilight films...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3 months later, as the tears streamed down, my heartbeat pressed against my vocal chords—rendering me speechless (I'm an ugly crier).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I looked at the people surrounding me. Their turnt necks, their swiveIed chairs. I was with friends. I had not seen them (or basically anyone else) for 8 months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This involuntary surge of tears shook me out of my current state. It was like my body needed to show me what was really going on. Before that moment, I wanted to believe I could handle the rise and grind of a &quot;real&quot; entrepreneur. I wanted to believe I could be like the greats; the ones who slept on factory floors and removed all &quot;distractions&quot; that got in their way.  I wanted to believe I could sustain the insane hours and &quot;hustle&quot; forever...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I couldn't. I was alone. I was sad. And I needed to make a change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the Twilight/Cry-Gate (aka rock-bottom), I've struggled with what it means to be an entrepreneur. Everyday, I'm inundated with headlines reading: &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fastcompany.com/90466041/farmgirl-flowers-ceo-christina-stembel-normally-sleeps-just-4-hours-per-night?partner=rss&amp;amp;utm_source=facebook.com&amp;amp;utm_medium=social&amp;amp;utm_campaign=rss+fastcompany&amp;amp;utm_content=rss&amp;amp;fbclid=IwAR3VwYPDfuhFVJKbL-rpQXR-HlV2dY6CaOoWhSzfa_-24MQEOu9pcLGnwzY&quot;&gt;Farmgirl Flowers CEO Christina Stembel normally sleeps just 4 hours per night&lt;/a&gt;,&quot; and fucking Gary Vaynerchuk videos telling me to hustle till I become a swamp monster who eats toe-nails to survive (or this garbarge-poster he's selling for $90 that reads &quot;Eat shit for 48 months. Eat Caviar for the rest of your life&quot;). I'm sure Gary and Chrstina are great and all—but also fuck-off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5e4afca13c3a77d3eb3fe8f4/5e5ead0e7266237cb499380e_Frame%207.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only recently, have a select few started to promote less destructive lifestyles for founders:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Alexis Ohanian, the founder of Reddit, who coined the term &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://qz.com/work/1458073/reddit-co-founder-alexis-ohanian-is-taking-a-stand-against-hustle-porn/&quot;&gt;Hustle Porn&lt;/a&gt;,&quot; rejects the &quot;idea that unless you are suffering, grinding, working every hour of every day, you’re not working hard enough.&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DHH and Jason Fried, the founders of Basecamp, with their book &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://basecamp.com/books/calm&quot;&gt;It Doesn't Have to Be Crazy at Work&lt;/a&gt;&quot; speak about how &quot;the answer isn’t more hours, it’s less bullshit. Less waste, not more production. And far fewer things that induce distraction, always-on anxiety, and stress.&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Investors like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/alexkonrad/2018/09/10/vc-firm-pledges-1-percent-to-founder-health/#5b2535572ec1&quot;&gt;Felicis Ventures&lt;/a&gt; are committing &quot;1% on top of every check the firm writes in non-dilutive capital earmarked for “founder development” in coaching and mental health.&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;And this shift in mindset is needed. Early last year, an article from Techcrunch came out titled: &quot;Investors and Entrepreneurs need to address the mental health crisis in startups.&quot; In this post, they cited that Founders are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;2X more likely to suffer from depression&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;6X more likely to suffer from ADHD&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3X more likely to suffer from substance abuse&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;10X more likely to suffer from bi-polar disorder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2X more likely to have psychiatric hospitalization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2X more likely to have suicidal thoughts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Crazy. Surprising? No. But fucking crazy...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's been a year since we moved back to NYC from California. A year since that New Years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To this day, I don't know what's needed to create a &quot;successful&quot; company. When we worked 100 hour weeks, our business was not booming. We didn't have millions of users and revenue was not shooting out our asses. In the midst of the business flailing, I loved that I could at least say we were working constantly. It felt like the only &quot;positive&quot; metric that showed we were true &quot;entrepreneurs.&quot; But shortly after I told our one insignificant stat, I'd be back at my desk. Typing on my loud-ass keyboard. Getting nowhere. With no one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast-forward to today, some things have changed and some have remained the same. I still sit at my desk and make ears bleed with my decibel-shattering keyboard. Yet, I am no longer alone. I eat dinner with friends, I workout at the gym, I participate in a shuffleboard league, I go on terrible first-dates, I host weekly Bachelor viewing parties (fuck pilot-pete), I see my family, I live a life outside of my startup. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wish I could say this new lifestyle has led to a booming business. In reality, it hasn’t yet - but it’s clear my decisions are better. I think before I act. I take time before making rash decisions or upsetting my teammates. By taking better care of myself, I can now take better care of the business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And don’t get me wrong, this thing is still my baby; something I'm constantly thinking about and working on. However, I now know it's not everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I simply cannot get all of life's meaning from starting a tech company...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wrote this article for myself and for other founders like me. Too often, we hear stories that make us feel like shit—written by people that want us to think they're crushing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, we're not crushing it. But, I'm having fun building this business again. I'm staying healthy and enjoying other areas of my life. Ones that don't revolve around hitting KPIs or whatever fuck-all nonsense is being pushed out there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're going through something similar or have a story to share, I'd love to hear it and I think others would too.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2020 07:24:04 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>takinola</dc:creator>
<og:title>Post YC Depression</og:title>
<og:description>It had been a long time since I'd seen them. In fact, it had been a long time since I’d seen anyone...</og:description>
<og:image>https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5e4afca13c3a77d3eb3fe8f4/5e5e8c0550f1ab92d7546bca_Frame%203%20(1).png</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bmaho.com/articles/post-yc-depression</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>