<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Plastic recycling is a problem consumers can&amp;#039;t solve</title>
<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/view/articles/2018-06-27/plastic-recycling-is-a-problem-consumers-can-t-solve</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bloomberg.com/view/articles/2018-06-27/plastic-recycling-is-a-problem-consumers-can-t-solve</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lede-media-image__caption caption&quot;&gt;Single-stream recycling was such a nice idea.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;148.75088857982&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Americans were not set up for success in recycling plastics. Even before China &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/01/11/world/china-recyclables-ban.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;stopped accepting plastic refuse from abroad&lt;/a&gt;, 91 percent of potentially recyclable plastic in the U.S. ended up in landfills – or worse, in the oceans. Europe does a little better, with only 70 percent getting tossed.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Why such terrible rates? Partly because some changes that were supposed to make recycling simpler ended up making it almost impossible.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;University of Georgia engineering professor Jenna Jambeck said that indeed, part of the reason China is now refusing to process American and European plastic is that so many people tossed waste into the wrong bin, resulting in a contaminated mix difficult or impossible to recycle.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;In a paper published last week in &lt;a href=&quot;http://advances.sciencemag.org/content/4/6/eaat0131&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;Science Advances,&lt;/a&gt; she and her colleagues calculated that between now and 2030, 111 million metric tons of potentially recyclable plastic will be diverted from Chinese plants into landfills.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Jambeck said that China used to turn a profit by importing the stuff from American and European recycling bins and turning it into useful material. But as other countries attempted to simplify things for consumers with “single stream” recycling – think of one big blue bin for paper, plastic, metal and glass – the material reaching China became too contaminated with nonrecyclable items. The instructions to put everything in one bin seemed appealing but made it much easier to do recycling wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plastic matters because it takes centuries to degrade, and there’s a lot of it. Jambeck has estimated that the world has produced more than 8 billion metric tons since the 1950s. To help grasp this quantity, paleontologist Jan Zalasiewicz has estimated that this is enough to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/view/articles/2016-04-13/scientists-of-the-future-will-have-one-word-for-the-present-plastics&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;wrap our entire planet in cling wrap&lt;/a&gt;. Others have calculated that it would make &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/energy-environment/wp/2018/06/20/a-giant-wave-of-plastic-garbage-could-flood-the-u-s-in-10-years-a-study-says/?utm_term=.1d920ff38f0b&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;four mountains the size of Everest&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&quot;http://science.sciencemag.org/content/347/6223/768&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; Jambeck led in 2015 calculated that about 8 million metric tons of plastic garbage is added to our already polluted oceans each year, killing sea birds, turtles, marine mammals and other creatures. Some breaks down into particles that infuse the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2017/feb/14/sea-to-plate-plastic-got-into-fish&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;fish and shellfish people eat&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How did things go so wrong? I posed the question to Princeton University historian Edward Tenner, author of the new book &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Efficiency-Paradox-What-Data-Cant/dp/1400041392&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;The Efficiency Paradox&lt;/a&gt;,&quot; as well as a classic on unintended consequences, &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Why-Things-Bite-Back-Consequences/dp/0679747567&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;Why Things Bite Back&lt;/a&gt;.&quot; He wrote back that single-stream recycling has burdened us with a heavy cognitive load:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This very morning I finally found out how to treat a milk carton with a plastic spout. What about film-protected take-out coffee cups? Toothpaste tubes? Only after your message did I pay any attention to the Wikipedia article on resin codes – and I, like you, am a science and technology writer!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, trash has become complicated, with products that used to come in cans now in combinations of cardboard and plastic. And then there’s the brain-draining complexity of yogurt tubs – one of the items, along with dirty take-out containers, that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/05/29/climate/recycling-wrong-mistakes.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;The New York Times&lt;/a&gt; said Americans are recycling incorrectly. I put on my reading glasses and studied a carton of Greek yogurt. I discovered all sorts of mysterious symbols, which may have something to do with the lack of GMOs or gluten.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were explicit instructions not to put this product in your freezer, which I might have guessed to be the case, but not much help with the container disposal. A tiny, barely perceptible resin code was stamped on the bottom. It was a 5, I think, which means it’s polypropylene, and is accepted as recyclable in some communities and not others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Making efficient systems work can be surprisingly inefficient for the human mind, at least for mine,” said Tenner. “It's easy to do the 'right thing' only to discover you've made it more difficult to protect the environment.” It's not just a few of us messing up: Remember that 111 million metric tons of plastic headed to Chinese landfills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well-intentioned recyclers probably aren’t the worst offenders; one Waste Management executive &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/05/29/climate/recycling-landfills-plastic-papers.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;quoted in The Times&lt;/a&gt; said he had seen &quot;everything from Christmas lights to animal carcasses to artillery shells.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While there ought to be a fine for the carcasses and Christmas lights, for the most part the answer to contaminated recycling streams is not to keep berating consumers over getting Resin Code 5 wrong, but to commit to advancing clean plastic technology. Even if consumer participation in recycling were 100 percent, we wouldn’t be close to recycling 100 percent of the material, said chemical engineer Megan Robertson, who co-wrote a piece in &lt;a href=&quot;http://science.sciencemag.org/content/358/6365/870&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;Science&lt;/a&gt; last November on the future of plastics recycling. Much consumer waste is simply not recyclable, often because it combines materials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given what scientists already know how to do, the future could bring a greener, more fool-proof system. Right now, she said, she and other scientists are starting to develop ways to recycle mixtures of plastics – a tough job because many plastics repel one another like oil and water. One of the reasons China imported recycling was that it was possible there to hire cheap labor to sort the different plastic types by hand. (Worth noting: Over that same span in which recycling streams have become more contaminated, labor in China has also become &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/view/articles/2018-05-21/china-must-grow-its-shrinking-workforce-to-keep-up&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;scarcer and more expensive&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;inline-newsletter&quot; data-state=&quot;ready&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another problem is that nearly all current “recyclable” plastics can’t go back into packaging but get a second life as a handbag or lawn chair before settling into landfills as their final resting place. They’re not really recycled so much as “downcycled.” The other author of the Science paper, Jamie Garcia of IBM Research, has invented a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ibm.com/blogs/think/2018/04/47262/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;new kind of plastic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;u&gt;,&lt;/u&gt; which can be recycled back into the same kinds of containers hundreds of times. Adopting such a material would require a new approach at recycling facilities, and in the short term could cost more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Curing the plastic problem is a lot like fighting cancer. Even if everyone stopped smoking, there would still be cancer. And even if we all figure out whether our municipalities accept yogurt containers, plastic waste will still pollute the environment. Compliance won't be a cure until innovations from the lab set us up for success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;disclaimer&quot; readability=&quot;6.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;news-rsf-informative-disclaimer&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This column does not necessarily reflect the opinion of the editorial board or Bloomberg LP and its owners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;news-rsf-contact-author&quot;&gt;To contact the author of this story:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/Person&quot;&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;name&quot;&gt;Faye Flam&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:fflam1@bloomberg.net&quot;&gt;fflam1@bloomberg.net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;news-rsf-contact-editor&quot;&gt;To contact the editor responsible for this story:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/Person&quot;&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;name&quot;&gt;Philip Gray&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:philipgray@bloomberg.net&quot;&gt;philipgray@bloomberg.net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:52:24 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>danso</dc:creator>
<og:description>Even if you put everything into the right blue bins, a lot of plastics will end up in landfills and the ocean. Consumers can't solve this problem.</og:description>
<og:image>https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/iGTpDYuy0cMs/v1/1200x800.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>The Recycling Game Is Rigged Against You</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.bloomberg.com/view/articles/2018-06-27/plastic-recycling-is-a-problem-consumers-can-t-solve</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bloomberg.com/view/articles/2018-06-27/plastic-recycling-is-a-problem-consumers-can-t-solve</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Google ups its Linux Foundation membership to the $500,000/year Platinum level</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2018/06/27/google-ups-its-linux-foundation-membership-to-the-500000-year-platinum-level/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2018/06/27/google-ups-its-linux-foundation-membership-to-the-500000-year-platinum-level/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/google/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;google&quot;&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt; has long been a member of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linuxfoundation.org/membership/members/&quot;&gt;Linux&lt;/a&gt; Foundation, but at the relatively low Silver level. Today, the company is stepping up its commitment by becoming a Platinum sponsor — the highest level of membership the open-source nonprofit organization currently offers. Silver membership for large corporations run just under $100,000 per year, while Platinum sponsors pay $500,000. As part of this move, Sarah Novotny, Google’s head of open-source strategy for the Google Cloud Platform, is joining the Linux Foundation board of directors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this, Google joins AT&amp;amp;T, Cisco, Fujitsu, Hitachi, Huawei, IBM, Intel, Microsoft, NEC, Oracle, Qualcomm, Samsung and VMware as a Platinum member, but it’s worth remembering that the Linux Foundation now has more than 800 members at all levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Google is one of the biggest contributors to and supporters of open source in the world, and we are thrilled that they have decided to increase their involvement in The Linux Foundation,” said Jim Zemlin, the executive director of the Linux Foundation, in today’s announcement. “We are honored that Sarah Novotny, one of the leading figures in the open source community, will join our board – she will be a tremendous asset.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google notes that it has released and contributed to more than 10,000 open-source projects to date, including Linux Foundation-managed projects like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cloudfoundry.org/&quot;&gt;Cloud Foundry&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://nodejs.org/&quot;&gt;Node.js&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cncf.io/&quot;&gt;Cloud Native Computing Foundation&lt;/a&gt; (the project behind the Kubernetes container orchestration service) and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openapis.org/&quot;&gt;Open API Initiative&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To some degree, it’s a bit of a surprise that Google remained a Silver member for so long, given its extensive involvement with various open-source software projects and ecosystems over the years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Open source is an essential part of Google’s culture, and we’ve long recognized the potential of open ecosystems to grow quickly, be more resilient and adaptable in the face of change, and create better software” said Novotny. “The Linux Foundation is a fixture in the open source community. By working closely with the organization, we can better engage with the community-at-large and continue to build a more inclusive ecosystem where everyone can benefit.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:44:11 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mikece</dc:creator>
<og:title>Google ups its Linux Foundation membership to the $500,000/year Platinum level</og:title>
<og:description>Google has long been a member of the Linux Foundation, but at the relatively low Silver level. Today, the company is stepping up its commitment by becoming a Platinum sponsor — the highest level of membership the open-source nonprofit organization currently offers. Silver membership for large…</og:description>
<og:image>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/GettyImages-932459182-1.jpg?w=600</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2018/06/27/google-ups-its-linux-foundation-membership-to-the-500000-year-platinum-level/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2018/06/27/google-ups-its-linux-foundation-membership-to-the-500000-year-platinum-level/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Surface Book 2 is everything the MacBook Pro should be</title>
<link>https://char.gd/blog/2018/the-surface-book-2-is-everything-the-macbook-pro-should-be-and-then-some</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://char.gd/blog/2018/the-surface-book-2-is-everything-the-macbook-pro-should-be-and-then-some</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I've been hunting for a &lt;a href=&quot;https://char.gd/blog/2017/why-i-left-mac-for-windows-apple-has-given-up&quot;&gt;great MacBook Pro replacement since early 2017&lt;/a&gt; and while I've been happy with my switch to a desktop machine at home, it's been an interesting journey trying to find something that's on the same all-around hardware and software experience on the laptop side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the past year I've spent time with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://char.gd/blog/2017/the-razer-blade-a-killer-macbook-pro-replacement&quot;&gt;Razer Blade&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://char.gd/blog/2018/ive-finally-found-a-macbook-replacement-that-doesnt-suck&quot;&gt;Dell XPS 15&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://char.gd/blog/2017/a-startup-made-a-better-laptop-than-anyone-else-could&quot;&gt;Eve V&lt;/a&gt;, which are all stellar machines, but I didn't quite feel at home yet. These are fantastic machines that do the job well, but always left something wanting, which I figured I'd need to settle for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm back to say I was wrong, and I've found a machine that not only matches Apple's standard of hardware quality, but goes far beyond it to demonstrate how a laptop of the &lt;em&gt;future&lt;/em&gt; should work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That machine is the 15-inch Surface Book 2 and somehow Microsoft has made the 2-in-1 that Apple should've been building all along, to the same level of quality I'd expect from anyone other than Microsoft. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've used the Surface Book 2 as my daily computer for three months now and it's consistently blown me away with how well considered it is across the board, how great the software works and has completely converted me into the touchscreen laptop camp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm not your typical reviewer but rather a person who needs more out of their machines than most. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm a software developer and UX writer who spends my days either in a text editor or building and debugging PHP applications (including &lt;a href=&quot;https://char.gd/recharged&quot;&gt;my own&lt;/a&gt;) in an IDE. I needed a machine that could offer enough power to get shit done, but is lightweight and flexible enough to do other things, like watch movies and do some light gaming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't want a serious gaming monstrosity, I just desired something that can do the job well, had great build quality &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; could run the Unix-based tools I need to use to get through the day while offering reasonable battery life. It's a tall order, but should be feasible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While a touch screen, ink-compatibility and other things weren't really on my list, the Surface Book came onto my radar when it was first released a few years back by just how sheer adaptable it is. &lt;em&gt;That&lt;/em&gt; was a laptop of the future, and it looked promising, but at the time only came in a 13-inch version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Microsoft introduced the larger 15-inch version in late 2017 with a 6GB GTX 1060 graphics card, my interest was piqued: could this be the Mac-quality alternative I was looking for? At the time, it wasn't available in Europe at the time so I went with the XPS 15. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a recent trip to the US, however, I decided to get one to try it out and see if it lives up to the hype. Here's the very long-winded detail of how I fell in love with a convertible, and why I’m now using it as my daily driver.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;High quality hardware&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://char.gd/assets/_featured/day_to_day.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Surface Book 2 is one of the cleanest, beautiful pieces of hardware design I’ve seen in recent times, and I love that hardware is getting &lt;em&gt;weird &lt;/em&gt;again in all sorts of ways. Microsoft deserves more kudos for pulling this off, because it's fabulous to look at and still functional without compromising on the aesthetic.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the hinge aesthetic itself on this laptop might be incredibly divisive, I really love the element of quirkiness it adds — personality for a laptop design language that’s traditionally been made up of boring rectangles. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The body itself is encased in magnesium that's satisfying to touch and stands out from anything I've used before it. The casing is never too cold to the touch while feeling soft, and doesn’t get finger goop all over it like the Dell XPS 15 did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It feels premium in the hand, but sturdy enough to last, and doesn't feel cheap. There's no flimsy bits at all, just end-to-end metal, without logos or stickers to tarnish it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Display &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://char.gd/assets/DSCF7141.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hands down, the screen is one of the best in the industry and lives up to what you'd hope only out of a Retina display, while still pushing the boundaries. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The display is able to produce rich colors, a ton of brightness and looks &lt;em&gt;fricking great. &lt;/em&gt;If you care about pixels as much as I do, and you want to get as high resolution for working on the go as possible, look no further, but it gets better.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One reason I had interest in this device in the first place was the 3240 x 2160 resolution, which is a quirky 3:2 in a world of wide, vertically-limited 16:9 aspect ratio laptops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such a resolution, however, is far better than your average laptop for one big reason: you get a bunch more vertical screen real estate to play with, which I love, because I spend most of my day working on this thing, not watching widescreen movies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The vertical space on a MacBook or XPS is always extremely limited to the point that I’d always preferred putting the dock on the left of the screen to scrape out as much as possible, so using the Surface Book 2 is like stepping into a room with incredibly high ceilings for the first time: liberating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 15-inch size of the screen works incredibly well in practice, surprisingly in tablet mode, because it's like a slightly oversized piece of A4 paper. That said, if you thought that the iPad Pro looked stupid big, you're now in oversized clipboard territory. Yeah, it’s stupid big, but the size of the canvas lends itself to taking detailed notes, drawing doodles or sketching out diagrams with enough space to really use it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first the size made me embarrassed to use tablet mode public, but then I got to the point where it just felt freeing: enough space to actually do the pen justice, and certainly enough to fall in love with it over, say, a Wacom tablet if you happen to be an illustrator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keyboard / trackpad&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://char.gd/assets/_featured/DSCF7130.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;The biggest stumbling point for PC makers has traditionally been the trackpad and keyboard, which are often either disappointing or downright deal breakers for those looking to switch away from a MacBook. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bar is high because Apple's been good at this for &lt;em&gt;years &lt;/em&gt;and most PC makers' trackpads would trigger accidental scrolls, taps or even just outright barely work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am &lt;em&gt;incredibly&lt;/em&gt; skeptical of any PC for that reason, but was pleasantly surprised by how &lt;em&gt;not &lt;/em&gt;terrible the trackpad and keyboard are. In fact, it was surprising to me that the trackpad is beyond great in practice. It just works, the way you'd expect, and I'm happy to have nothing else to say there. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s the first time I’ve found Apple-level trackpad quality on any other machine and it’s just delightful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If, like me, you're coming from the Macbook Pro with the butterfly keyboard, I promise that typing on this thing is salve for your butterfly-keyboard wounds: it’s got a perfect amount of travel, feels comfortable to use and doesn’t sound like you’re typing on a hollow piece of wood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other words, I’m really convinced that Microsoft finally nailed the combination of hardware and software needed to make a laptop that wasn’t infuriating to use. Input is so key to getting this right, and the combination is finally reaching the bar that's been consistently missed for years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Surface Book 2 might be a bold convertible, but it’s not hindered by compromises like crappy text input — it’s a damn delight to use on a daily basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No dongle required&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://char.gd/assets/DSCF7078.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;For connectivity, if you’re comparing to the MacBook Pro the Surface Book 2 is basically a home-run: you get two USB 3.0 ports, a Magsafe charger (!), a USB-C port (which can also be used for charging), &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; an SD slot. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other words, it’s perfect, and you can basically stop with the dongle hellscape that is 2018 with the Surface Book, because it solves it by just being pragmatic. What Microsoft has done with the combination of ports here is refreshing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There's a magnetic charging port &lt;/strong&gt;which does a lot more than just charge: it's also able to be used for connectivity. Add a Surface Dock, which uses the same port and you'll get charging, displays, networking and more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Having a native SD slot was something I'd actually missed, so having it back is even better for those occasions where you need to quickly offload a card.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;audio jack is at the top right of the screen &lt;/strong&gt;which is an adjustment because it means your cable will be suspended from the right of your display. This is necessary so you can still listen to audio in tablet mode.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The charging ports are &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; inexplicably on the right-hand side of the base, where every other laptop in existence has it on the left-side — this results in an annoying wire floating around right next to your mouse if you don't arrange it carefully.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Split it up&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://char.gd/assets/_featured/DSCF7139.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the Surface Book 2's marketing angles is that it's a full-on computer with a wild secret superpower: it's a full-on tablet too. All you need to do is push a button on the top right of the keyboard to eject the screen, and &lt;em&gt;boom,&lt;/em&gt; you've got a tablet computer without giving up any of the conveniences of your full computer.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How Microsoft actually pulled this off, in practice, is impressive: the bulk of the Surface Book’s computing power is inside the display, as are the speakers and headphone jack. In the keyboard you’ve got a bunch of ports, a huge battery and a high-end graphics card, the nVidia GTX 1060 — if you pop off the screen, it’s a whole computer, without any compromises. Pop it back on and you’ve got a whole computer with a kick-ass graphics card.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Essentially, you’re getting the best of both worlds: you’ve got a great tablet computer like the iPad Pro, mixed with a laptop like the MacBook Pro. This &lt;em&gt;seems&lt;/em&gt; like a gimmick on the surface, but it's a life changing feature that's totally undersold: I use both laptop and tablet mode daily, and it's totally transformed my workflow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://owenwillia.ms/&quot;&gt;I'm a full-time freelance marketing and UX writer&lt;/a&gt;, so I'm often working in-person with clients in person. Being able to pop off my keyboard and write directly on the screen when we're brainstorming to draw all over a screenshot helps a lot, but giving &lt;em&gt;remote&lt;/em&gt; clients feedback with the tap of the pen eraser is &lt;em&gt;incredible&lt;/em&gt; for getting the message across in one go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I often catch myself quickly snapping a screenshot, drawing on it, and flicking it off with the native Mail app for feedback, or drawing up a wireframe to show how we could use copy and layout better, which saves writing out a few hundred words on a regular basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://char.gd/assets/_featured/DSCF7155.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;My worries about the transition from a desktop workflow to a tablet one are a relic from the days of Windows 8, where you were stuck in a weird tablet-interface land all the time. It felt forced at best.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft has done a great job of fixing that, and now seamlessly hands you off into a touch-friendly mode when you're using fingers or a pen, and a mouse-friendly interface when using the laptop format — and if you prefer, it can ask you which mode you want to be in when it’s ready to switch between them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve spent a ton of time with the iPad Pro and the Apple Pencil. They're incredible devices but constantly remind you of their own limitations as you're using them. The Surface Book is so much more powerful because it's already a part of your workflow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don't need some other device in there to get a specific task done, or to try and make the iPad Pro a serious computer: it's already in your backpack and it’s the same one you’re already using all day, just push the eject button to switch gears.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft spent so much time with the stylus to get it just right so they could compete. That's another thing I was initially skeptical of because since the Windows XP era support for ink support on Windows has been underwhelming, but it's come a long way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://char.gd/assets/DSCF7159.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;The response time on the pen is just as good as the iPad Pro, and the way it feels as it glides across the screen is really satisfying, as if you're writing on paper rather than jabbing a piece of plastic up on a slab of glass.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft has done a good job of making its pen more useful on a day-to-day basis as well:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The eraser on the pen &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;doubles as a button&lt;/strong&gt; for launching an app, taking a screenshot or writing down a note, and can be configured based on the amount of times it's clicked. This is huge if you've popped the screen off and need to quickly write something down, and tapping once to scribble on a screenshot is something I've come to use regularly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The pen can &lt;strong&gt;magnetically attach to the screen &lt;/strong&gt;on the left or the right, making it a lot harder to lose.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OneNote, Microsoft's main app for taking notes and drawing scribbles, is really great at being a jot-pad for later. You can write as messy as you like, then select it later and it'll use handwriting recognition to convert it into text.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Microsoft calls all of these stylus-related features 'Windows Ink' and I can safely say I'm a skeptic turned into a believer here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet tw-align-center&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been pleasantly surprised by how good the pen is on Surface Book and how into writing/drawing on it I am, even if I'm a messy writer. &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/PmPmHzJLdM&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/PmPmHzJLdM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;— ⚡️ Owen (@ow) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ow/status/999219010607681536?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;May 23, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A note about touch&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For years Apple has told us that MacBooks aren't for touching and there's no place for a stylus or finger in that form factor, but instead that an iPad is much better even though it basically ends up being exactly the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That transformability has other advantages too: if you're watching Netflix on a plane or in bed, you can pop off the screen, spin it around and you've got an instant tablet stand (instead of doing that shitty iPad 'smart' cover folding dance).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://char.gd/assets/_featured/DSCF7171.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For cooking I just pop off the tablet and put it in easel mode to keep it clean while on the bench, or just ditch the keyboard altogether and use a cookbook stand. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doing this in public is my favorite part of owning this computer because people can't believe what they're seeing — did that guy just pull the screen off his laptop? It’s a great conversation starter, because most people don't believe it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Surface Book 2 does everything the iPad Pro does in a single device, so you can write code as well as use it for notes, drawing and watching Netflix. Being able to transition like this feels like using this crazy machine from the distant future: just hit a button, pop off the screen, and keep working. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you eject the screen, it's magical that it even works at all. How is it that I can watch Netflix on this huge, beautiful 15-inch screen that was a whole laptop a few seconds ago? Oh, and I can transition back to PHPStorm to check some code with a finger, too. It's absurd, and doesn't feel like it should be possible yet, but it boggles my mind consistently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Touch in &lt;em&gt;laptop mode&lt;/em&gt; isn’t something you’re going to use full time, but it’s a feature you’ll notice when it’s missing. I don’t actively touch my screen when I’m using my computer, but I subconsciously touch it to quickly shortcut my way around clicking on things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple is full of nonsense when it says things at WWDC like it doesn’t believe laptops should have the ability to use touch because it results in a less than ideal experience — it couldn’t be further from the truth. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I've come to believe that Apple only says this because it wants to sell you iPads.&lt;/strong&gt; As a result, Mac users are missing out on one of the shifts in computing I think that matters: the blurring of boundaries between different interaction models, from mouse to touch, all of the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of moving the mouse to close a window, or quickly change the sound, I just tap it, and it’s so much easier to do that when you switch back to a MacBook, you’ll find yourself trying to tap the screen almost immediately. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m constantly getting confused when trying to use my partner’s MacBook and told off for touching the screen. It's a habit that sticks, and it’s only been a few months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few notes about how convertibility works in practice are worth raising here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;To remove the screen, the keyboard has a &lt;strong&gt;dedicated eject button &lt;/strong&gt;which takes about 1-2 seconds to check it's able to be removed, then it'll light up green.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You might be worried about whether or not the keyboard could fall off the screen if holding it wrong. It can't; the mount is incredibly strong, as is the neck of the hinge, so there's no way to disconnect accidentally.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apps actively using the GTX 1060 can&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;block the ejection of the keyboard until they're closed &lt;/strong&gt;because if you were able to eject while in use, I assume bad things would happen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The ejection mechanism makes a slight &lt;em&gt;click &lt;/em&gt;sound when releasing which scared me at first, but I got more comfortable with how well engineered the hinge was over time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Being able to do this without skipping a beat never gets old, and it's a game changer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://char.gd/assets/_featured/detatch.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Consider me a convert on the all-in-one, which was just as surprising to me as it might be to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love the touch screen, but I also unexpectedly &lt;em&gt;love&lt;/em&gt; the inking, and would struggle to move away from it at this point. I’m a writer, but I usually prefer to jot notes by typing them out… and the Surface Book 2 completely turned that around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Apple’s trying to sell you a new version of the Corolla, Microsoft went and built the Ferrari of the future that turns into a jet plane when you feel like it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Day to day&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://char.gd/assets/_featured/DSCF7153.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over the last few years there was a big shift in how we think about our machines, and the type of form factors we were willing to use. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently realized that one of the big issues with the search for great ultra-powerful laptops, like the constant moaning about the MacBook Pro, is we’re asking so much more from them than the thermal envelope is able to deliver:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet tw-align-center&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone moans about how their MacBook isn't powerful enough but the real story is how desktop computers fell out of fashion and we're all throwing desktop workloads on thermally constrained, CPU-throttled laptops instead of just getting a desktop.&lt;br/&gt;— ⚡️ Owen (@ow) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ow/status/1004043866373320706?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;June 5, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Essentially, we all want laptops that can handle desktop-class workloads along with great battery life &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; a lightweight package. Most of us shifted from being chained to a beefy desktop PC when working and a laptop on the go to a different world: a single, powerful laptop that can do it all, both on the desk and on the go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think that expectation, often, is why people are disappointed in modern laptops — we’re pushing up against thermal limitations, imposed by the form factors we desire, and many of them just don’t live up to those demands. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because of all of this, I was skeptical of how Microsoft packed a laptop &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; a tablet into the same device and could make this work. At a distance, I found myself wondering how any of this was possible given the form factor and limitations. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Surface Book 2 that I'm using has an Intel i7-8650U quad-core processor, at 4.2GHz, 16 GB of RAM, a GTX 1060 with 6GB of memory and a 512GB hard drive, but it seems like that shouldn’t be feasible given the profile it's able to fit in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet tw-align-center&quot; data-conversation=&quot;none&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First thing I did on it &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/z4z5b2IqFR&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/z4z5b2IqFR&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;— ⚡️ Owen (@ow) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ow/status/993533233357668352?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;May 7, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was wrong, and quickly discovered it’s a beast that’s capable of basically anything I can throw at it without skipping a beat. I play Fortnite and a bunch of other games on it in high graphics at 60Hz, then I can move back to PHPStorm and carry on with my day on the same damn machine. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even better, it doesn’t sound like a 747 getting ready for takeoff like &lt;a href=&quot;https://char.gd/blog/2017/the-razer-blade-a-killer-macbook-pro-replacement&quot;&gt;the Razer Blade does&lt;/a&gt;, a non-starter if you're regularly out and about. It also has a better form factor while not needing some external graphics card to pull off all of this. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fact that it's in a computer that’s &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; a tablet is just the icing on the cake, a standout in a market of garish gaming laptops because it truly can do it all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are, however, some things worth raising here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There's a hard limitation of 16 GB of RAM even if you customize it&lt;/strong&gt;, which feels low for such a high-end machine. When you’re doing serious work, with a bunch of Vagrant virtual machines and a few design files open, it’s easy to fill up that memory fast.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Having a software battery slider is awesome &lt;/strong&gt;because you can quickly throttle the CPU to get more battery life &lt;em&gt;and &lt;/em&gt;limit the fan noise, or ramp it up for full-on productivity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I wasn't ever really able to bring the Surface Book to its knees. Fortnite worked on high graphics, at full near-4K resolution, and could pull 60 frames per second.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you disconnect the base, you're not going to have that GTX 1060. Not really an issue day to day, but if you were hoping to connect a dock to the tablet, then play Fortnite, that's not going to work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The RAM issue is a real one, but Microsoft nailed the perfect machine for transitioning from serious work to play and back again, and that's special in a world where we'd otherwise need to carry an array of different devices to get things done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Battery life&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is, of course, subjective, but I noted before getting the laptop that it has a serious amount of battery. &lt;strong&gt;There are two giant batteries onboard this laptop &lt;/strong&gt;with one in the display, and another in the base, which means you should see north of 12 hours if you're not pushing it too hard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took a flight from San Francisco to Amsterdam and watched Netflix basically the whole time, about a 10 hour trip, and landed with about 39 percent in the tank. Your mileage may vary, but in my experience, that's bonkers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My new workflow&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://char.gd/assets/_featured/pen.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’ve found something of a perfect day-to-day setup through the use of Microsoft’s separate product, the Surface Dock, which is quite literally what I had hoped the MacBook’s USB-C situation would be in the first place: a single port that charges the laptop, does my displays and everything else.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While that’s possible on the USB-C side if you buy a $1,000+ display with USB-PD and a USB-C port, the Surface Dock is arguably a better solution because it uses the magnetic, simple Magsafe port to pull it off. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I sit down at the office I plug in the Magsafe charger from the dock and boom: I’ve got a 4K 60Hz display, a bunch of USB stuff connected, and a 1Gbps ethernet connection up and running too. If you’re looking for a perfect personal-work transition, that has to be it, and it’s better than anything I ever found for my Mac.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet tw-align-center&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Single cable life on the Surface Book makes co-working setup so much nicer 😍 &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/lTmGdj04Hc&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/lTmGdj04Hc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;— ⚡️ Owen (@ow) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ow/status/1001046628172816384?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;May 28, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A fun side effect of the Surface Book’s convertibility is it lends itself to the desk setup quite well if you reverse the screen — you can put the keyboard out of the way at the back and use it as a second display right next to your primary one, which is a nice touch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make all of that convertibility work and still allow you to turn the laptop into a fully-functioning tablet, Microsoft did basically the opposite of what every other laptop maker does: it crammed almost all of the guts into the screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Literally everything is somewhere inside the screen panel, &lt;em&gt;except&lt;/em&gt; the GTX 1060, which is a part of the keyboard base which is disconnected when in tablet-only mode for fairly obvious reasons. That change is the entire reason the hinge is so wildly different: it needs to be a high-speed data transfer interface, while still allowing the user to eject the tablet at a moment’s notice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet tw-align-center&quot; data-conversation=&quot;none&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also Surface Book is like the 🔑 flying computer &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/9dBhc2GEev&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/9dBhc2GEev&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;— ⚡️ Owen (@ow) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ow/status/995261507985428480?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;May 12, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To manage this, there’s a button on the keyboard to eject the tablet and throw you into touch-first mode. Tap the button, wait a second for the hinge to release, and grab it out of its slot — now you’ve got an &lt;em&gt;enormous&lt;/em&gt; tablet. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://char.gd/assets/detatch.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;This transition is magic — if a little disconcerting at first because you're pulling an expensive, enormous screen off of your laptop — but it works seamlessly and you can move from writing code to running a meeting or taking notes then back again, without skipping a beat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I love the most about this is if I’ve ejected the screen and am taking notes but want to quickly show off my development environment or some code I need help with, I can still do that! It’s the same machine, and all of my things are here! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cherry on top of all of this is Windows Hello, an advanced facial recognition feature that makes it seamless to unlock the computer and 1Password instantly with a camera array on-par with Face ID in the iPhone X. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This has been a surprise improvement to my workflow that &lt;a href=&quot;https://char.gd/blog/2018/windows-10s-face-unlocking-is-incredible-but-nobody-knows-about-it&quot;&gt;you can read more about here&lt;/a&gt;, because it removes the friction regardless of what way I'm using the hardware. Just wake up, and boom, you're in. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a few things that are side effects of hardware decisions that become apparent over time as you get used to the device worth highlighting:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The screen is now where the cooling fans now live since the whole computer is there — you won’t hear them often, but it does mean the screen also gets warmer while the keyboard stays cool, an unexpected nicety if you play games a lot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The tablet part of the computer only has a minimal amount of ports&lt;/strong&gt;: a 3.5mm headphone jack and a Magsafe charging port where the screen was formerly docked to the keyboard. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Despite the lack of ports, &lt;strong&gt;you can still use a whole external screen and dock with the tablet part only by plugging in a Surface Dock &lt;/strong&gt;which was a &lt;em&gt;holy shit &lt;/em&gt;moment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you reverse the display when at your desk, you get an extra screen without a keyboard in front of it; an unexpected nicety that I now do every day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The most confusing decision about this computer is that the USB-C port is… not quite a full USB-C port. It &lt;em&gt;looks &lt;/em&gt;like one, but is USB 3.1 which comes with a few annoying limitations, such as the ability to use USB-C displays, but the inability to do things like drive dual 4K displays at 60Hz over a single port on a machine that has more than enough guts to actually do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reasoning for this seems to be to do with the four Thunderbolt lanes underneath being split in half across the USB-C port and that fancy Magsafe port, which allows the dock to work — but why not just make a USB-C dock instead? This is not something that degraded my work day, but it just seemed &lt;em&gt;weird&lt;/em&gt; to have such a powerful machine limited by… a crappy port choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That USB-Cish port, in addition to the proprietary charging slot, is a welcome addition though. Instead of needing to carry the proprietary Magsafe charger you can actually choose how to charge it: use the official charger, or whatever's lying around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I actually use a 15-inch MacBook Pro charger cable most of the time, because it’s compatible with my phone and Nintendo Switch too, and works just fine. Having an actual option is awesome, particularly after having already mourned the loss of Magsafe on the Mac.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah, it basically means I can finally stop carrying a thousand stupid dongles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The great divide&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://char.gd/assets/hw.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most people that I showed the Surface to were impressed by what they saw, but almost always came back to the same thing: it doesn’t run macOS. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m increasingly frustrated by this because it’s almost always a misunderstanding of how far Windows 10 has come, and how compatible the workflow now is regardless of what you might do for a job. I suspect most people haven't touched Windows since &lt;em&gt;years &lt;/em&gt;ago and it's time for a serious second look if so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve written about web development on Windows 10 before, but even since a year ago it’s come such a long way. The Bash on Windows environment is now so performant and well supported that you won’t even know the difference if you move from a MacBook, and Microsoft continues to improve it at an impressive clip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unless you’re using Xcode, your workflow will almost certainly move from macOS to Windows as a non-event: it’s that good now, and I spend most of my time living in the Bash environment without any problems — even with complicated situations like Symlinks &lt;em&gt;inside&lt;/em&gt; Bash now actually working fully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next thing to come up, inevitably, is apps. macOS has had the upper-hand in attracting high quality developers for years, but over the past few years has diminished in popularity as the rise of Electron consumed almost everything out there. Microsoft, however, seems to have quietly built up a more compelling app store in the meantime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Windows Store now has the big ones you’d expect, like a native Netflix app with offline support (yes, really), Facebook Messenger, Spotify and so on, but the native apps, including Mail and Calendar are legitimately great too — to the point I use them on a daily basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://char.gd/assets/DSCF7140.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Generally, the sticking point for designers is Sketch, which to date refuses to build a Windows client — a ridiculous, anti-user move that I hope eventually will cause people to reconsider it in their workflows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As tools like &lt;a href=&quot;http://figma.com&quot;&gt;Figma&lt;/a&gt;, Framer and Atomic have gained popularity, it’s possible to live without it, and I encourage almost all of my clients to switch to Figma because it’s cross-platform and opens up the design process to everyone in the company, regardless of whether they’re on Mac, Windows or a Chromebook, which needs to be more common.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft's betting on that shift to the web and now allows Progressive Web Apps, which work offline but offer a native-like experience, in the Windows Store. Long term this will likely have a big impact as more rich tools like Figma come along, and I believe this is the way forward over the opposite approach Apple is now pursuing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft has pushed the Windows team to actually innovate in a space that seemed dead to find new ways of working, and it’s paying off. Features like Tab Sets which allow you to combine a web browser with, say, your calendar and the Sonos app, in a single, tabbed window are a game-changer for organizing by task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Microsoft’s efforts on the store, the new 'fluent' design language rolling out and new ideas for the desktop environment like Tab Sets, Windows has come a long way from the janky driver hell of yesteryear, and those that refuse to use it are missing out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Wrap up&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://char.gd/assets/DSCF7025.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;The crux of any search for the ‘perfect’ laptop is that in pursuit of perfection you’re almost certainly going to be disappointed as there will always be a compromise to be found. You can pick apart the Surface Book 2 and find one or two, but the sum of its parts is something special.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you had told me that Microsoft would make a machine like this even four years ago, there’s no way I’d have believed you — it’s that good, and feels like something Apple &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; have made, but failed to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Surface Book 2 is a laptop that’s beyond great, with a few tiny misses that make you scratch your head, but don’t ruin the experience. That’s an unfortunate distraction, because there’s so many great things about it that it’s worth owning, and is much better than anything else I’ve tried despite those problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By focusing on making a device that transitions incredibly well from being a serious, work-focused laptop to one that can play games and render videos, then to a tablet that’s perfect for taking notes, Microsoft built something truly beyond the rest of the industry and I think will define the category for years to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can’t sing the Surface Book 2’s praises enough; this is a laptop that’s superb in almost every way imaginable, and blurs the lines of what a laptop should actually be able to do. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This laptop is a developer's dream that can do so much more than just laptop stuff, which makes it exponentially more useful than I'd expected. The value of transitioning between modes can't be overstated, and you shouldn't settle for anything less at this point. Why carry two devices when you can use just one?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s no way I’ll go back to a MacBook again now that I know this exists, and if you’re looking for something else to try for your development workflow, or even if you're a designer, start here — you won’t be disappointed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For more like this, check out my switching to Windows series:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://char.gd/blog/2017/why-i-left-mac-for-windows-apple-has-given-up&quot;&gt;I'm giving up on the Mac&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://char.gd/blog/2017/the-razer-blade-a-killer-macbook-pro-replacement&quot;&gt;Testing the Razer Blade as a MacBook alternative&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://char.gd/blog/2017/how-to-set-up-the-perfect-modern-dev-environment-on-windows&quot;&gt;How to set up Bash on Windows for a Mac-like development environment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://char.gd/blog/2017/a-startup-made-a-better-laptop-than-anyone-else-could&quot;&gt;Testing the Eve V as a MacBook alternative&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://char.gd/blog/2017/essential-apps-for-switching-from-mac-to-windows&quot;&gt;Essential apps for switching from Mac to Windows&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://char.gd/blog/2018/ive-finally-found-a-macbook-replacement-that-doesnt-suck&quot;&gt;Testing the Dell XPS 15 as a MacBook alternative&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 14:37:29 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ChrisLTD</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://char.gd/blog/2018/the-surface-book-2-is-everything-the-macbook-pro-should-be-and-then-some</og:url>
<og:title>The Surface Book 2 is everything the MacBook Pro should be | Charged</og:title>
<og:description>How is it that Microsoft is the only one making interesting computers?</og:description>
<og:image>https://char.gd/assets/_featured/DSCF7128.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://char.gd/blog/2018/the-surface-book-2-is-everything-the-macbook-pro-should-be-and-then-some</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why ActivityPub is the future</title>
<link>https://blog.joinmastodon.org/2018/06/why-activitypub-is-the-future/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.joinmastodon.org/2018/06/why-activitypub-is-the-future/</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;container&quot; readability=&quot;53.252735615955&quot;&gt;
&lt;header class=&quot;article-header&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-large&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.joinmastodon.org/2018/06/why-activitypub-is-the-future/ezgif-2-60f1b00403.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/header&gt;&lt;p&gt;We often tout things like “Mastodon is based on open web protocols” as one of its advantages. I want to elaborate why exactly that’s a good thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a refresher, Mastodon implements the so-called ActivityPub protocol to enable Mastodon servers to talk to each other; that’s the basis of the “federation” we also like to bring up. Federation is what you already know from e-mail, even if you may not know it by name: It’s the concept of servers hosting users that can talk to users from other servers. That protocol pins down on paper how exactly such inter-server communication would look like, using a vocabulary that can be applied for a variety of purposes. And here’s the kicker:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The social network that is Mastodon isn’t really Mastodon&lt;/strong&gt;. It’s &lt;em&gt;bigger&lt;/em&gt;. It’s &lt;em&gt;any piece of software that implements ActivityPub&lt;/em&gt;. That software can be wildly different in how it looks and what it does! But the social graph–what we call the people and their connections–is the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Mastodon is the software built around 500-character text posts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You want a video platform? That’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://joinpeertube.org/en/home/&quot;&gt;PeerTube&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You want something centered on photos and pictures? &lt;a href=&quot;https://pixelfed.org/&quot;&gt;PixelFed&lt;/a&gt; is here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You want to write long, rich blog posts? &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Plume-org/Plume&quot;&gt;Plume&lt;/a&gt; is in development.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;That’s not to mention a multitude of variations on the same concepts. PeerTube and PixelFed won’t be the only ones in their categories. For example, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/syuilo/misskey&quot;&gt;Misskey&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://pleroma.social/&quot;&gt;Pleroma&lt;/a&gt; have a similar use case as Mastodon, but they make different choices in programming languages, design and functionality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of these platforms are different and they focus on different needs. And yet, the foundation is all the same: people subscribing to receive posts from other people. And so, they are all compatible. From within Mastodon, Pleroma, Misskey, PixelFed and PeerTube users can be followed and interacted with all the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And that’s the strength of using open web protocols&lt;/strong&gt;. When you decide to switch to Mastodon, you’re not just gambling on the success of one project. You can be certain that regardless what happens with Mastodon, the network will live on and flourish. Newer and better software will be born within this ecosystem, but you will never have to drag all your friends and followers someplace else again–they’ll already be where they need to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If Twitter shuts down, you’ll lose your followers. If Facebook shuts down, you’ll lose your friends. For some platforms, it’s not a question of “if”, but “when”. Such events are usually followed by a scrambling into a variety of different platforms, where you inevitably lose some people as you have to make a choice which one to stay on. This happened before. But it doesn’t have to happen again. Use the federated web. Join Mastodon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;footer class=&quot;article-footer&quot;&gt;&lt;nav class=&quot;entry-nav&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;prev-entry sep-before&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.joinmastodon.org/2018/06/why-we-must-oppose-the-new-copyright-directive/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Previous&lt;/strong&gt; Why we must oppose the new copyright directive&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/nav&gt;&lt;/footer&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 13:46:04 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>daveid</dc:creator>
<og:title>Why ActivityPub is the future</og:title>
<og:description>We often tout things like “Mastodon is based on open web protocols” as one of its advantages. I want to elaborate why exactly that’s a good thing.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>http://blog.joinmastodon.org/2018/06/why-activitypub-is-the-future/</og:url>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.joinmastodon.org/2018/06/why-activitypub-is-the-future/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Slack outage: Connectivity issues affecting all workspaces</title>
<link>https://status.slack.com/2018-06/142edcb9e52c7663</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://status.slack.com/2018-06/142edcb9e52c7663</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;note&quot; readability=&quot;12.044117647059&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;incident_done_icon&quot; src=&quot;https://status.slack.com/img/v2/DetailPageCheck.png&quot; srcset=&quot;/img/v2/DetailPageCheck.png 1x, /img/v2/DetailPageCheck@2x.png 2x&quot;/&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;black_licorice&quot;&gt;We're happy to report that workspaces should be able to connect again, as we've isolated the problem. Some folks may need to refresh (Ctrl + R or Cmd + R). If you're still experiencing issues, please drop us a line at feedback@slack.com.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;raven_gray margin_top_6px date&quot;&gt;9:49 AM PDT・&lt;a class=&quot;underline&quot; href=&quot;https://www.timeanddate.com/worldclock/fixedtime.html?iso=20180627T0949&amp;amp;p1=224&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;See in your timezone&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;note&quot; readability=&quot;8.7179487179487&quot;&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;black_licorice&quot;&gt;Our efforts to isolate the problem and resume connections are ongoing. Your patience through this is greatly appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;raven_gray margin_top_6px date&quot;&gt;9:33 AM PDT・&lt;a class=&quot;underline&quot; href=&quot;https://www.timeanddate.com/worldclock/fixedtime.html?iso=20180627T0933&amp;amp;p1=224&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;See in your timezone&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;note&quot; readability=&quot;8.1132075471698&quot;&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;black_licorice&quot;&gt;We're getting closer to a solution, but we aren't out of the woods yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;raven_gray margin_top_6px date&quot;&gt;9:03 AM PDT・&lt;a class=&quot;underline&quot; href=&quot;https://www.timeanddate.com/worldclock/fixedtime.html?iso=20180627T0903&amp;amp;p1=224&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;See in your timezone&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;note&quot; readability=&quot;9.8359788359788&quot;&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;black_licorice&quot;&gt;We really appreciate you sticking with us. We know this is a big disruption to your day, and we've got all eyes on this issue to get us back up to normal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;raven_gray margin_top_6px date&quot;&gt;8:33 AM PDT・&lt;a class=&quot;underline&quot; href=&quot;https://www.timeanddate.com/worldclock/fixedtime.html?iso=20180627T0833&amp;amp;p1=224&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;See in your timezone&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;note&quot; readability=&quot;9.5333333333333&quot;&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;black_licorice&quot;&gt;We have no new information to share just yet, but we're continuing our efforts. Your patience is truly appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;raven_gray margin_top_6px date&quot;&gt;8:03 AM PDT・&lt;a class=&quot;underline&quot; href=&quot;https://www.timeanddate.com/worldclock/fixedtime.html?iso=20180627T0803&amp;amp;p1=224&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;See in your timezone&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;note&quot; readability=&quot;8.936170212766&quot;&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;black_licorice&quot;&gt;We are continuing to work on fixing the connection problems that have been impacting folks. We hope to have the issue fully resolved as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;raven_gray margin_top_6px date&quot;&gt;7:33 AM PDT・&lt;a class=&quot;underline&quot; href=&quot;https://www.timeanddate.com/worldclock/fixedtime.html?iso=20180627T0733&amp;amp;p1=224&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;See in your timezone&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;note&quot; readability=&quot;9.562091503268&quot;&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;black_licorice&quot;&gt;Our team is still looking into the cause of the connectivity issues, and we'll continue to update you on our progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;raven_gray margin_top_6px date&quot;&gt;7:03 AM PDT・&lt;a class=&quot;underline&quot; href=&quot;https://www.timeanddate.com/worldclock/fixedtime.html?iso=20180627T0703&amp;amp;p1=224&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;See in your timezone&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;note&quot; readability=&quot;9.8235294117647&quot;&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;black_licorice&quot;&gt;We've received word that all workspaces are having troubles connecting to Slack. We're currently investigating the issue, and will have updates shortly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;raven_gray margin_top_6px date&quot;&gt;6:33 AM PDT・&lt;a class=&quot;underline&quot; href=&quot;https://www.timeanddate.com/worldclock/fixedtime.html?iso=20180627T0633&amp;amp;p1=224&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;See in your timezone&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 13:35:58 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>abdullahdiaa</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:title>Slack System Status</og:title>
<og:image>https://status.slack.com/img/slack_hash_twitter.png</og:image>
<og:description>Resources for real-time and historical information about the Slack service.</og:description>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://status.slack.com/2018-06/142edcb9e52c7663</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Flights to Rome</title>
<link>https://flightstorome.moovellab.com/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://flightstorome.moovellab.com/</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;p--large p--white p--margin-sm&quot;&gt;Also people on magical small islands sometimes want to leave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p--white&quot;&gt;When calculating the roadway from every place on earth to the nearest airport we eventually ended up with the most remote airports. Book a flight here, if you've had enough of Rome, New York or Tokyo.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 10:43:21 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>anc84</dc:creator>
<og:title>Flights to Rome - moovel lab</og:title>
<og:url>https://flightstorome.moovellab.com</og:url>
<og:image>https://flightstorome.moovellab.com/static/seo/seo.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>&quot;Flights to Rome&quot; is a data visualization project that explores the idiom, &quot;all roads lead to Rome&quot;. The outcome is both information visualization and data art and unveils mobility infrastructures on land and in the air.</og:description>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://flightstorome.moovellab.com/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Norwegian Consumer Council report on how tech companies use dark patterns [pdf]</title>
<link>https://fil.forbrukerradet.no/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/2018-06-27-deceived-by-design-final.pdf</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://fil.forbrukerradet.no/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/2018-06-27-deceived-by-design-final.pdf</guid>
<description>&lt;a href=&quot;https://fil.forbrukerradet.no/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/2018-06-27-deceived-by-design-final.pdf&quot;&gt;Download PDF&lt;/a&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 06:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>erlend_sh</dc:creator>
<og:title>Flights to Rome - moovel lab</og:title>
<og:url>https://flightstorome.moovellab.com</og:url>
<og:image>https://flightstorome.moovellab.com/static/seo/seo.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>&quot;Flights to Rome&quot; is a data visualization project that explores the idiom, &quot;all roads lead to Rome&quot;. The outcome is both information visualization and data art and unveils mobility infrastructures on land and in the air.</og:description>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://fil.forbrukerradet.no/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/2018-06-27-deceived-by-design-final.pdf</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Show HN: B2blaze – A Backblaze B2 library for Python</title>
<link>https://github.com/sibblegp/b2blaze</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/sibblegp/b2blaze</guid>
<description>&lt;h3&gt;README.md&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;markdown-body entry-content&quot; itemprop=&quot;text&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/768f34f36f2aed7bb6678dc5ac4025ace2b6bf98/68747470733a2f2f696d672e736869656c64732e696f2f636972636c6563692f70726f6a6563742f6769746875622f736962626c6567702f6232626c617a652e737667&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/768f34f36f2aed7bb6678dc5ac4025ace2b6bf98/68747470733a2f2f696d672e736869656c64732e696f2f636972636c6563692f70726f6a6563742f6769746875622f736962626c6567702f6232626c617a652e737667&quot; alt=&quot;CircleCI&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/circleci/project/github/sibblegp/b2blaze.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the b2blaze library for Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Backblaze B2 provides the cheapest cloud object storage and transfer available on the internet. Comparatively, AWS S3 is 320% more expensive to store and 400% more expensive to transfer to the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This library will allow you to easily interact with B2 buckets and files as first class objects in Python 2 and 3. It is licensed under the MIT license so feel free to use it anywhere! If you enjoy it, please feel free to contribute or request features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To install b2blaze, run the following command in the proper environment:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
pip install b2blaze
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Setup&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will need a key_id and an application_key to run b2blaze. You can obtain these in the B2 portal. Then, either pass them into B2() or set the environment variables B2_KEY_ID and B2_APPLICATION_KEY.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Example Usage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b2blaze is built around OOP principles and as such all buckets and files are objects which you can interact with. Let's see an example where we list all of our files in a bucket:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-python&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; b2blaze &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; B2
b2 &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; B2()
bucket &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; b2.buckets.get(&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;test_bucket&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;)
files &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; bucket.files.all()
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Files will be a list of B2File objects with all of their properties which can then be downloaded by running:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-python&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
content &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; files[&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;].download()
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a BytesIO object that you can manipulate in any way include saving locally or serving on a website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The B2 Object&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-python&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; b2blaze &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; B2
b2 &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; B2()
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The B2 object is how you access b2blaze's functionality. You can optionally pass in &quot;key_id&quot; and &quot;application_key&quot; as named arguments but you should probably set them as environment variable as described above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Buckets&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Buckets are essentially the highest level folders in B2, similar to how buckets are used in AWS S3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Bucket Properties&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-python&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
bucket_id
bucket_name
bucket_type
bucket_info
lifecycle_rules
revision
cors_rules
deleted
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;List All Buckets&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-python&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
buckets &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; b2.buckets.all()
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Create a Bucket&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-python&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
bucket &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; b2.buckets.create(&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;test_bucket&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;pl-v&quot;&gt;security&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;b2.buckets.public)
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Buckets can either be public or private. This does not change the functionality of the library other than that you will need to manually authorize when using file URLs (see below).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Retrieve a bucket&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-python&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
bucket_by_name &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; b2.buckets.get(&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;test_bucket&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;)
bucket_by_id &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; b2.buckets.get(&lt;span class=&quot;pl-v&quot;&gt;bucket_id&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;abcd&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;)
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Delete a bucket&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-python&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
bucket.delete()
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will delete both the bucket and all files within it. There is no confirmation. Use carefully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Files&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Files are the same files you store locally. They can be stored inside folders placed in buckets but this means they simply have a name like &quot;folder/test.txt&quot;. There is no distinction between folders and files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;File Properties&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-python&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
file_id
file_name
content_sha1
content_length
content_type
file_info
action
uploadTimestamp
deleted
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;List All Files in a Bucket&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-python&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
bucket.files.all()
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NOTE: There may be tens of thousands of files (or more) in a bucket. This operation will get information and create objects for all of them. It may take quite some time and be computationally expensive to run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Create (upload) a File&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-python&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
text_file &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;open&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;hello.txt&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;).read()
new_file &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; bucket.files.upload(&lt;span class=&quot;pl-v&quot;&gt;contents&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;text_file, &lt;span class=&quot;pl-v&quot;&gt;file_name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;folder/hello.txt&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;)
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NOTE: Reading the file is optional. You don't have to call .read() and instead can send the file directly to contents. This should save some memory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Retrieve a File's Information (Necessary before Downloading)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-python&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
file_by_name &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; bucket.files.get(&lt;span class=&quot;pl-v&quot;&gt;file_name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;folder/hello.txt&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;)
file_by_id &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; bucket.files.get(&lt;span class=&quot;pl-v&quot;&gt;file_id&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;abcd1234&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;)
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Download a file&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-python&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-v&quot;&gt;file&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; bucket.files.get(&lt;span class=&quot;pl-v&quot;&gt;file_name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;folder/hello.txt&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;)
downloaded_file &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-v&quot;&gt;file&lt;/span&gt;.download()
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This returns a BytesIO object which you can manipulate in Python using a tool like PIL, serve on a website, or easily save like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-python&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
save_file &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;open&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;save_pic.jpg&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;wb&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;)
save_file.write(downloaded_file.read())
save_file.close()
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Delete a file&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-python&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-v&quot;&gt;file&lt;/span&gt;.delete()
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NOTE: There is no confirmation and this will delete all of a file's versions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;LICENSE&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MIT License&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Copyright (c) 2018 George Sibble&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a copy of this software and associated documentation files (the &quot;Software&quot;), to deal in the Software without restriction, including without limitation the rights to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense, and/or sell copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the Software is furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The above copyright notice and this permission notice shall be included in all copies or substantial portions of the Software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;THE SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED &quot;AS IS&quot;, WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND NONINFRINGEMENT. IN NO EVENT SHALL THE AUTHORS OR COPYRIGHT HOLDERS BE LIABLE FOR ANY CLAIM, DAMAGES OR OTHER LIABILITY, WHETHER IN AN ACTION OF CONTRACT, TORT OR OTHERWISE, ARISING FROM, OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE SOFTWARE OR THE USE OR OTHER DEALINGS IN THE SOFTWARE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 04:20:29 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>gsibble</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars2.githubusercontent.com/u/1026474?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>sibblegp/b2blaze</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/sibblegp/b2blaze</og:url>
<og:description>b2blaze</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/sibblegp/b2blaze</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Facebook abandons Aquila, its internet drone</title>
<link>https://code.facebook.com/posts/190457848334738</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://code.facebook.com/posts/190457848334738</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Today nearly 4 billion people globally do not have access to the Internet. It’s why Facebook, along with many other companies and governments, is investing heavily to address the three key barriers to getting everyone, everywhere online: &lt;a href=&quot;https://l.facebook.com/l.php?u=https%3A%2F%2Fnewsroom.fb.com%2Fnews%2F2018%2F02%2Fstate-of-connectivity-2017%2F&amp;amp;h=AT0dUrzbGK20Ch-wYSOoNHRbrHc1omPpeAfjkjRlNDmNR8n5CJwcst_K7COrHdXiQQIXRy70zv0IoF2PfBdAr_sismGg81V_uATs7v01C-KViKQynKuWqUxOX-GvDabEhDuXXXOfgCYF4SIuvCObORb8&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot; data-lynx-mode=&quot;asynclazy&quot;&gt;availability, affordability, and awareness&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part of that investment has been in developing next-generation connectivity technologies like &lt;a href=&quot;https://code.facebook.com/posts/993520160679028/building-communications-networks-in-the-stratosphere/&quot;&gt;Aquila&lt;/a&gt;, a high altitude platform station (HAPS) system. This has involved a lot of trial and error. When we started the Aquila program back in 2014, very few companies were involved in this area — and they were all working independently of one other. In addition, the only spectrum available for these platforms wasn’t suitable for broadband due to technical and geographical limitations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So we decided to start from scratch and invest in the building blocks needed to make this technology work — most important of all, the aircraft. To increase our chances of success we took on every part of our aircraft’s design, development, and testing, work that was led by our team in Bridgwater, U.K. Thanks to their efforts, we were able to demonstrate that an aircraft of this design was viable — with two successful full-scale test flights, including &lt;a href=&quot;https://code.facebook.com/posts/200887800439084/aquila-s-successful-second-flight-another-step-forward-in-bringing-the-world-closer-together/&quot;&gt;a textbook landing&lt;/a&gt; on “Aquila beach.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, HAPS connectivity requires more than just an aircraft. We’ve made important progress on some of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://code.facebook.com/posts/348442828901047/aquila-what-s-next-for-high-altitude-connectivity-/&quot;&gt;other key parts of the system&lt;/a&gt; — including &lt;a href=&quot;https://code.facebook.com/posts/183097092210150&quot;&gt;setting new records&lt;/a&gt; using millimeter-wave (MMW) technology in air-to-ground and point-to-point communication. And then we more than doubled our MMW record with 40 Gbps connectivity simultaneously in both directions from a ground location to a circling Cessna aircraft over 7 kilometers away. We’ve also pushed for improvements to spectrum and aviation policy — including more consistency in the global regulatory environment to open up HAPS to new entrants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we’ve worked on these efforts, it’s been exciting to see leading companies in the aerospace industry start investing in this technology too — including the design and construction of new high-altitude aircraft. Given these developments, we’ve decided not to design or build our own aircraft any longer, and to close our facility in Bridgwater. Going forward, we’ll continue to work with &lt;a href=&quot;https://code.facebook.com/posts/2265698886989780/facebook-and-airbus-working-together-to-advance-high-altitude-connectivity/&quot;&gt;partners like Airbus&lt;/a&gt; on HAPS connectivity generally, and on the other technologies needed to make this system work, like flight control computers and high-density batteries. On the policy front, we’ll be working on a proposal for 2019 World Radio Conference to get more spectrum for HAPS, and we’ll be actively participating in a number of aviation advisory boards and rule-making committees in the US and internationally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Connectivity for everyone, everywhere is one of the great challenges of our generation. Facebook has already connected nearly 100 million people as a result of our efforts. And &lt;a href=&quot;https://code.facebook.com/posts/218840725330904/global-connectivity-working-together-to-bring-more-people-online/&quot;&gt;we are continuing to invest&lt;/a&gt; in developing next-generation technologies like &lt;a href=&quot;https://l.facebook.com/l.php?u=https%3A%2F%2Fterragraph.com%2F%23terragraph&amp;amp;h=AT3bcv67FU0oiS6VC5O85rXF7Hw7x32NEOpo53353eHmSazGZnK9TD_CZ9QiW4KH5r1HeejT9iWfyL0V3zoi-l-6mPmdgA3efjr2hAYqmc6hRpXvQ54MQ5sXM9aMkouLzRP2QZMAKIkVHUm3GmC7YQqM&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot; data-lynx-mode=&quot;asynclazy&quot;&gt;Terragraph&lt;/a&gt;, working with partners on new infrastructure builds like &lt;a href=&quot;https://code.facebook.com/posts/1642803246023947/airtel-and-bcs-with-support-from-facebook-to-build-shared-fiber-backhaul-connectivity-in-uganda/&quot;&gt;our fiber project in Uganda&lt;/a&gt;, and supporting entrepreneurs in programs like Express Wi-Fi — all to help connect the 4 billion people who still do not have access to the Internet. We’re excited about what’s next.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 01:13:25 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ajuhasz</dc:creator>
<og:title>High altitude connectivity: The next chapter</og:title>
<og:description>Facebook Open Source</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:image>https://code.fb.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/BLOG-IMAGE-CROP_CX-Map.jpg?w=640</og:image>
<og:url>https://code.fb.com/connectivity/high-altitude-connectivity-the-next-chapter/</og:url>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://code.fb.com/connectivity/high-altitude-connectivity-the-next-chapter/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Berkeley Deep Drive Dataset</title>
<link>http://bdd-data.berkeley.edu/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://bdd-data.berkeley.edu/</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;http://bdd-data.berkeley.edu/&quot;&gt;http://bdd-data.berkeley.edu/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17405018&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17405018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Points: 285&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 49&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;hnrss is a labor of love, but if the project has made your job
or hobby project easier and you want to show some gratitude, &lt;a
href=&quot;https://www.paypal.com/cgi-bin/webscr?cmd=_s-xclick&amp;amp;hosted_button_id=ZP9Q7QUNS3QYY&quot;&gt;donations are very much
appreciated&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks!&lt;/p&gt;
        </description>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 00:39:37 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>MuhammedAbiola</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://bdd-data.berkeley.edu/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>