<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Why did we wait so long for the bicycle?</title>
<link>https://rootsofprogress.org/why-did-we-wait-so-long-for-the-bicycle</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://rootsofprogress.org/why-did-we-wait-so-long-for-the-bicycle</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;date&quot;&gt;July 13, 2019 &lt;span class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;centerdot;&lt;/span&gt; 11 min read&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bicycle, as we know it today, was not invented until the late 1800s. Yet it was a simple mechanical invention. It would seem to require no brilliant inventive insight, and certainly no scientific background.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why, then, wasn’t it invented much earlier?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I asked this question &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jasoncrawford/status/1143622870477791233&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, and read some discussion &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.quora.com/How-come-bicycles-werent-invented-earlier-in-history-What-was-missing&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;on Quora&lt;/a&gt;. People proposed many hypotheses, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;23.984655172414&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;5.8830409356725&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technology factors.&lt;/strong&gt; Metalworking improved a lot in the 1800s: we got improved iron refining and eventually cheap steel, better processes for shaping metal, and ability to make parts like hollow tubes. Wheel technology improved: &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wire_wheel&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;wire-spoke&lt;/a&gt; (aka tension-spoked) wheels replaced heavier designs; vulcanized rubber (1839) was needed for tires; inflatable tires weren’t invented until 1887. Chains, gears, and ball bearings are all crucial parts that require advanced manufacturing techniques for precision and cost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Design iteration.&lt;/strong&gt; Early bicycles were inconvenient and dangerous. The first version didn’t even have pedals. Some versions didn’t have steering, and could only be turned by leaning. (!) The famous “penny-farthing” design, with its huge front wheel, made it impossible to balance with your feet, was prone to tipping forward on a hard stop, and generally left the rider high in the air, all of which increased risk of injury. It took decades of iteration to get to a successful bicycle model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;7.5691202872531&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quality of roads.&lt;/strong&gt; Roads in the 1800s and earlier were terrible by modern standards. Roads were often dirt, rutted from the passage of many carts, turning muddy in the rain. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Macadam&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Macadam paving&lt;/a&gt;, which gave smooth surfaces to roads, wasn’t invented until about 1820. City roads at the time were paved with cobblestones, which were good for horses but too bumpy for bicycles. (The unevenness was apparently a feature, assisting in the runoff of sewage—leading &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.quora.com/How-come-bicycles-werent-invented-earlier-in-history-What-was-missing/answer/Chris-Crawford-6&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;one Quora answer&lt;/a&gt; to claim that the construction of city sewers was what opened the door to bicycles.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;6.7958333333333&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Competition from horses.&lt;/strong&gt; Horses were a common and accepted mode of transportation at the time. They could deal with all kinds of roads. They could carry heavy loads. Who then needs a bicycle? In this connection, it has been claimed that the bicycle was invented in response to food shortages due to the “&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Year_Without_a_Summer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Year without a Summer&lt;/a&gt;”, an 1816 weather event caused by the volcanic explosion of Mt. Tambora the year earlier, which darkened skies and lowered temperatures in many parts of the world. The agricultural crisis caused horses as well as people to starve, which led to some horses being slaughtered for food, and made the remaining ones more expensive to feed. This could have motivated the search for alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;General economic growth.&lt;/strong&gt; Multiple commenters pointed out the need for a middle class to provide demand for such an invention. If all you have are a lot of poor peasants and a few aristocrats (who, by the way, have horses, carriages, and drivers), there isn’t much of a market for bicycles. This is more plausible when you realize that bicycles were more of a hobby for entertainment before they became a practical means of transportation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cultural factors.&lt;/strong&gt; Maybe there was just a general lack of interest in useful mechanical inventions until a certain point in history? But when did this change, and why?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;These are all good hypotheses. But some of them start to buckle under pressure:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The quality of roads is relevant, but not really the answer. Bicycles can be ridden on dirt roads or sidewalks (although the latter led to run-ins with pedestrians and made bicycles unpopular among the public at first). And historically, roads didn’t improve until &lt;em&gt;after&lt;/em&gt; bicycles became common—indeed it seems that it was in part the cyclists who called for the improvement of roads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t think horses explain it either. A bicycle, from what I’ve read, was cheaper to buy than a horse, and it was certainly cheaper to maintain (if nothing else, you don’t have to feed a bicycle). And it turns out that inventors were interested in the problem of human-powered vehicles, dispensing with the need for horses, for a long time before the modern bicycle. Even Karl von Drais, who invented the first two-wheeled human-powered vehicle after the Year without a Summer, had been working on the problem for years before that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Technology factors are more convincing to me. They may have been necessary for bicycles to become practical and cheap enough to take off. But they weren’t needed for early experimentation. Frames can be built of wood. Wheels can be rimmed with metal. Gears can be omitted. Chains can be replaced with belts; some early designs even used treadles instead of pedals, and at least one design drove the wheels with levers, as on a steam locomotive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what’s the real explanation?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;To understand this, I dug into the history of the bicycle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The concept of a human-powered vehicle goes back many centuries. The earliest reference I have found is to Venetian engineer Giovanni Fontana, who in the early 1400s described a four-wheeled carriage powered by a driver pulling on a loop of rope connected by gears to the wheels (it’s unclear if he ever even attempted to build such a machine; Fontana sketched &lt;a href=&quot;https://publicdomainreview.org/2018/01/24/the-dreams-of-an-inventor-in-1420/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;a lot of strange things&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://rootsofprogress.org/img/giovanni-fontana-carriage.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://rootsofprogress.org/img/giovanni-fontana-carriage.png&quot; alt=&quot;Giovanni Fontana's self-driving carriage&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Giovanni Fontana's self-driving carriage
&lt;p&gt;Another early concept was described in the book &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2005/01/30/books/chapters/bicycle.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bicycle&lt;/em&gt; by David V. Herlihy&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;14&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More than three centuries ago, the distinguished French mathematician Jacques Ozanam spelled out the theoretical advantages of a human-powered carriage “in which one can drive oneself wherever one pleases, without horses.” Its owner could freely roam along the roads without having to care for an animal and might even enjoy a healthy exercise in the process. Moreover, this particular type of “self-moving” vehicle, in contrast to those that called for wind or steam for propulsion, would run on that most abundant and accessible of all resources: willpower. But how to construct such a valuable vehicle? That was the twenty-third of some fifty “useful and entertaining” problems Ozanam identified and addressed in his famous &lt;em&gt;Récréations Mathématiques et Physiques&lt;/em&gt;, published in 1696.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ozanam’s book presented a proposed solution from another inventor: another four-wheeled carriage, driven by two people (one to steer, one to power the vehicle by stepping up and down on large treadles connected to the wheels by ropes, pulleys, and gears).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://rootsofprogress.org/img/ozanam-carriage.jpg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://rootsofprogress.org/img/ozanam-carriage.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Human-powered carriage in Récréations Mathématiques&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Human-powered carriage in Récréations Mathématiques &lt;span class=&quot;image-credit&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.cul.columbia.edu/rbml/2010/08/12/problem-how-to-construct-a-vehicle-with-which-one-can-transport-oneself-where-one-likes-without-out-a-horse/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Columbia University Libraries&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems that for centuries, the carriage was the model for human-powered vehicles. Various inventors tried their hand at designs, and some were even built. There is a record in a London journal of an attempt in 1774 that went up to six miles an hour. French inventor Jean-Pierre Blanchard (who would later go on to fame in ballooning) built a human-powered carriage that went a dozen miles from Paris to Versailles. An American mechanic named Bolton built a version in 1804 that used mechanical leverage from interlocking gears. Presumably, all these attempts went nowhere because the machines were too large and heavy to be practical.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key insight was to stop trying to build a mechanical carriage, and instead build something more like a mechanical horse. This step was taken by the aforementioned Karl von Drais in the early 1800s. Drais was an aristocrat; he held a position as forest master in Baden that is &lt;a href=&quot;https://regencyredingote.wordpress.com/2010/03/05/of-velocipedes-and-draisiennes-the-rise/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; to have given him free time to tinker. His first attempts, beginning in 1813, were four-wheeled carriages like their predecessors, and like them failed to gain the support of authorities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But in 1817 (possibly motivated by the aforementioned food crisis and resultant shortage of horses, although this is unclear), he tried again with a new design: a two-wheeled, one-person vehicle that is a recognizable ancestor of the modern bicycle. It was made of wood, with iron tires. He called it the &lt;em&gt;Laufmaschine&lt;/em&gt;, or “running machine”; it had no pedals, and instead was powered by directly pushing off the ground with one’s feet. It was also called the “velocipede” (from the Latin for “swift foot”) or the “draisine” (English) or “draisienne” (French) after its inventor; an improved version made by a London coachmaker was known in England as the “pedestrian curricle”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://rootsofprogress.org/img/draisine.jpg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://rootsofprogress.org/img/draisine.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Draisine c. 1820, Kurpfälzisches Museum, Heidelberg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Draisine c. 1820, Kurpfälzisches Museum, Heidelberg &lt;span class=&quot;image-credit&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Draisine_or_Laufmaschine,_around_1820._Archetype_of_the_Bicycle._Pic_01.jpg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Wikimedia Commons (CC BY-SA 3.0)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://rootsofprogress.org/img/pedestrian-curricle.jpg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://rootsofprogress.org/img/pedestrian-curricle.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;New-York Tribune, Sep 1894&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; New-York Tribune, Sep 1894 &lt;span class=&quot;image-credit&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/nirak/6364040147&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Flickr / Karin Dalziel (CC BY-NC 2.0)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without pedals or gears, this proto-bicycle couldn’t achieve the speed or efficiency of modern designs. But, like the scooters still used by children today, it allowed you to coast, especially downhill, and it held your weight as you moved forward. Drais got up to 12 miles per hour on his machine. It became a fad in Europe in 1818–19, then faded. It seems the reasons were a combination of the potential for injury and the general annoyance of the public that these things were being driven through pedestrian areas such as sidewalks and parks (some things never change; we’re repeating this today with the scooter wars in San Francisco and other cities).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next key advance didn’t come until decades later, when someone put pedals on the bike. There are conflicting claims to first inventor (going back to 1839), but it was definitely done by the 1860s in France. In any case, it was in the 1860s that bicycle development really took off. Pedals allowed the rider to propel the machine faster and more efficiently. This model was manufactured in France, at first with wooden frames, later with iron, and became commonly known as the “boneshaker” (which gives you an idea of how rough the ride still was).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://rootsofprogress.org/img/michaux-boneshaker.jpg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://rootsofprogress.org/img/michaux-boneshaker.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Michaux “boneshaker”, 1870&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Michaux “boneshaker”, 1870 &lt;span class=&quot;image-credit&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Michaux_boneshaker.jpg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Wikimedia / Classic Motorcycle Archive (CC BY-SA 3.0)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://rootsofprogress.org/img/the-american-velocipede.jpg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://rootsofprogress.org/img/the-american-velocipede.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;“The American Velocipede”, wood engraving by Theodore Davis, Harper's Weekly, Dec 1868&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; “The American Velocipede”, wood engraving by Theodore Davis, Harper's Weekly, Dec 1868
&lt;p&gt;At this point, though, there were still no gears or chains. The pedals were attached directly to the front wheel. This gave the rider little mechanical advantage: it’s the same as a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fixed-gear_bicycle&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;fixie&lt;/a&gt; with a 1:1 gear ratio (vs. the ratios most commonly used today which are closer to 3:1). Think of what it’s like to pedal a bike that’s in too low a gear: you pump your legs a lot without going very fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only solution was to make the wheel larger, leading around 1870 to the ridiculous-looking “penny-farthing” or “high-wheel” design with the huge front wheel, which you’ve probably seen and may associate with the late 1800s. By around this time, bicycles were being made with metal frames, wire-spoke wheels, and solid rubber (not yet inflatable) tires. This design did give a faster ride, and a smoother one, since the large wheel absorbed shocks better. But it required acrobatic balance to ride, and as noted above it was prone to nasty spills and injuries, including “taking a header” if you stopped suddenly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://rootsofprogress.org/img/penny-farthing.jpg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://rootsofprogress.org/img/penny-farthing.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Penny-farthing bicycle&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Penny-farthing bicycle &lt;span class=&quot;image-credit&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/calitexican/7082467327&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Flickr / calitexican (CC BY-NC-SA 2.0)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third and final key advance, then, was to separate the pedals from the wheel. Variations on this “safety bicycle”, including at least one driven by treadles and levers, were attempted from the 1870s if not before. The first commercially successful model, using the familiar crank and chain design, was produced in 1885 by John Starley. Finally, in 1888, inflatable (pneumatic) tires were introduced by John Dunlop, cushioning the ride and eliminating the last advantage of the penny-farthing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, by the end of the 1880s, bicycles had evolved into the form we know them today, with (approximately) equal-sized wheels, pedals, chains, metal frames, wire-spoke wheels, and inflatable rubber tires.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://rootsofprogress.org/img/starley-safety-bicycle.jpg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://rootsofprogress.org/img/starley-safety-bicycle.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;So what can we conclude?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First, the correct design was not obvious.&lt;/strong&gt; For centuries, progress was stalled because inventors were all trying to create multi-person four-wheeled carriages, rather than single-person two-wheeled vehicles. It’s unclear why this was; certainly inventors were copying an existing mode of transportation, but why would they draw inspiration only from the horse-and-carriage, and not from the horse-and-rider? (Some commenters have suggested that it was not obvious that a two-wheeled vehicle would balance, but I find this unconvincing given how many other things people have learned to balance on, from dugout canoes to horses themselves.) It’s possible (I’m purely speculating here) that early mechanical inventors had a harder time realizing the fundamental impractiability of the carriage design because they didn’t have much in the way of mathematical engineering principles to go on, but then again it’s unclear what led to Drais’s breakthrough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And even after Drais hit on the two-wheeled design, it took multiple iterations, which happened over decades, to get to a design that was efficient, comfortable, and safe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://rootsofprogress.org/img/early-bicycle-models.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://rootsofprogress.org/img/early-bicycle-models.png&quot; alt=&quot;Early “velocipede” models, from an 1887 German encyclopedia. Many designs were tried&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Early “velocipede” models, from an 1887 German encyclopedia. Many designs were tried &lt;span class=&quot;image-credit&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Velocipedes.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Wikimedia Commons&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Second, advances in materials and manufacturing were probably necessary for a commercially successful bicycle.&lt;/strong&gt; It’s a bit hard, from where I stand, to untangle which advances in design were made possible by new materials and techniques, and which were simply sparks of inventive imagination that hadn’t been conceived or developed before. But the fact that people were willing to put up with the precarious high-wheeled design indicates to me that pneumatic tires were crucial. And it’s plausible to me that advanced metalworking was needed to make small, lightweight chains and gears of high and consistent quality, at an acceptable price—and that no other design, such as a belt or lever, would have worked instead. It’s also plausible to me that wooden frames just weren’t light and strong enough to be practical (I certainly wouldn’t be eager to ride a wooden bicycle today).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But we can go deeper, and ask the questions that inspired my intense interest in this question in the first place. Why was no one even experimenting with two-wheeled vehicles until the 1800s? And why was no one, as far as we know, even considering the question of human-powered vehicles until the 1400s? Why weren’t there bicycle mechanics in the 1300s, when there were clockmakers, or at least by the 1500s, when we had watches? Or among the ancient Romans, who built water mills and harvesting machines? Or the Greeks, who built the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Antikythera_mechanism&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Antikythera mechanism&lt;/a&gt; ? Even if they didn’t have tires and chains, why weren’t these societies at least experimenting with draisines? Or even the failed carriage designs?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To even begin to answer this, we have to realize that it’s part of a much wider phenomenon. I asked the same question of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://rootsofprogress.org/why-did-we-wait-so-long-for-the-cotton-gin&quot;&gt;cotton gin&lt;/a&gt;, which unlike the bicycle did not require advanced materials: it’s a wooden box, a wire mesh, and a drum with wire teeth; in fact, it was so simple that once the concept was out, plantation owners made bootleg copies by hand (depriving Eli Whitney of most of his patent royalties). The same question can be asked of all of the key inventions of &lt;a href=&quot;https://rootsofprogress.org/out-of-whole-cloth&quot;&gt;textile mechanization&lt;/a&gt;; Anton Howes, an economic historian who chimed in on the Twitter thread linked above, has &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@antonhowes/is-innovation-in-human-nature-48c2578e27ba&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;noted of John Kay’s flying shuttle&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;19&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kay’s innovation was extraordinary in its simplicity. As the inventor Bennet Woodcroft put it, weaving with an ordinary shuttle had been “performed for upwards of five thousand years, by millions of skilled workmen, without any improvement being made to expedite the operation, until the year 1733”. All Kay added was some wood and some string. And he applied it to weaving wool, which had been England’s main industry since the middle ages. He had no special skill, he required no special understanding of science for it, and he faced no special incentive to do it. As for institutions, the flying shuttle was technically illegal because it saved labour, the patent was immediately pirated by competitors to little avail, and Kay was forced to move to France, hounded out of the country by angry weavers who threatened his property and even his life. Kay faced no special incentives — he even innovated despite some formidable social and legal barriers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are also other stories in which an early attempt at invention was demonstrated, the idea found no backers if it wasn’t already fully viable, and then development was dropped for decades. Richard Trevithick’s early, failed experiments with locomotives come to mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In light of this, I think the deepest explanation is in general economic and cultural factors.&lt;/strong&gt; Regarding economic factors, it seems that there needs to be a certain level of surplus to support the culture-wide research and development effort that creates inventions. Note that Karl von Drais was a baron who apparently had a cushy job and invented in his spare time. This is common of researchers of that era: they were often aristocrats or otherwise independently wealthy (and those who weren’t had to scramble for support from wealthy patrons). Today we have research labs in both universities and corporations, plus venture capitalists to fund development of new products and services. The moment it becomes clear that a certain type of innovation &lt;em&gt;might&lt;/em&gt; be possible, there are multiple teams funded and hustling to bring it to market. There are no multi-decade gaps in the innovation timeline anymore, or at least vastly fewer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at economic factors on the demand side, surplus also would seem to create markets for new products. Maybe GDP per capita just has to hit a certain point before people even have time, attention and energy to think about new inventions that aren’t literally putting food on the table, a roof over your head, or a shirt on your back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, there are cultural factors. Howes says that “innovation is not in human nature, but is instead received. … when people do not innovate, it is often simply because &lt;em&gt;it never occurs to them to do so.&lt;/em&gt;” Joel Mokyr says, similarly, that “&lt;a href=&quot;https://rootsofprogress.org/the-idea-of-progress&quot;&gt;progress isn’t natural&lt;/a&gt;” (and his book on this topic, &lt;a href=&quot;https://rootsofprogress.org/books/a-culture-of-growth&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Culture of Growth&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, helped inspire this blog). I agree with both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fully elucidating these economic and cultural factors is a major future project of this blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sources and further reading: Excerpt from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2005/01/30/books/chapters/bicycle.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bicycle&lt;/em&gt;, by David V. Herlihy&lt;/a&gt;, “&lt;a href=&quot;https://regencyredingote.wordpress.com/2010/03/05/of-velocipedes-and-draisiennes-the-rise/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Of Velocipedes and Draisiennes&lt;/a&gt;”, “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.livescience.com/44765-who-invented-the-bicycle.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Who Invented the Bicycle?&lt;/a&gt;”, and many Wikipedia articles including “&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/History_of_the_bicycle&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;History of the bicycle&lt;/a&gt;”.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2019 18:43:51 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>exolymph</dc:creator>
<og:description>The bicycle, as we know it today, was not invented until the late 1800s. Yet it was a simple mechanical invention. It would seem to require no brilliant inventive insight, and certainly no scientific background.</og:description>
<og:title>Why did we wait so long for the bicycle?</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://rootsofprogress.org/why-did-we-wait-so-long-for-the-bicycle</og:url>
<og:image>https://rootsofprogress.org/img/the-american-velocipede.jpg</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://rootsofprogress.org/why-did-we-wait-so-long-for-the-bicycle</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>How many kinds of USB-C to USB-C cables are there?</title>
<link>https://people.kernel.org/bleung/how-many-kinds-of-usb-c-to-usb-c-cables-are-there</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://people.kernel.org/bleung/how-many-kinds-of-usb-c-to-usb-c-cables-are-there</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;tl;dr&lt;/em&gt;: There are 6, it's unfortunately very confusing to the end user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Classic USB from the 1.1, 2.0, to 3.0 generations using USB-A and USB-B connectors have a really nice property in that cables were directional and plugs and receptacles were physically distinct to specify a different capability. A USB 3.0 capable USB-B plug was physically larger than a 2.0 plug and would not fit into a USB 2.0-only receptacle. For the end user, this meant that as long as they have a cable that would physically connect to both the host and the device, the system would function properly, as there is only ever one kind of cable that goes from one A plug to a particular flavor of B plug.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does the same hold for USB-C™?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sadly, the answer is no. Cables with a USB-C plug on both ends (C-to-C), hitherto referred to as “USB-C cables”, come in several varieties. Here they are, current as of the USB Type-C™ Specification 1.4 on June 2019:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;USB 2.0 rated at 3A&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;USB 2.0 rated at 5A&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;USB 3.2 Gen 1 (5gbps) rated at 3A&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;USB 3.2 Gen 1 (5gbps) rated at 5A&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;USB 3.2 Gen 2 (10gbps) rated at 3A&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;USB 3.2 Gen 2 (10gpbs) rated at 5A&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;We have a matrix of 2 x 3, with 2 current rating levels (3A max current, or 5A max current), and 3 data speeds (480mbps, 5gbps, 10gpbs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adding a bit more detail, cables 3-6, in fact, have 10 more wires that connect end-to-end compared to the USB 2.0 ones in order to handle SuperSpeed data rates. Cables 3-6 are called “Full-Featured Type-C Cables” in the spec, and the extra wires are actually required for more than just faster data speeds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Full-Featured Type-C Cables” are required for the most common USB-C &lt;em&gt;Alternate Mode&lt;/em&gt; used on PCs and many phones today, &lt;em&gt;VESA DisplayPort Alternate Mode&lt;/em&gt;. VESA DP Alt mode requires most of the 10 extra wires present in a Full-Featured USB-C cable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My new Pixelbook, for example, does not have a dedicated physical DP or HDMI port and relies on VESA DP Alt Mode in order to connect to any monitor. Brand new monitors and docking stations may have a USB-C receptacle in order to allow for a DisplayPort, power and USB connection to the laptop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suddenly, with a USB-C receptacle on both the host and the device (the monitor), and a range of 6 possible USB-C cables, the user may encounter a pitfall: They may try to use the USB 2.0 cable that came with their laptop with the display and the display doesn't work, despite the plugs fitting on both sides because 10 wires aren't there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why did it come to this? This problem was created because the USB-C connectors were designed to replace all of the previous USB connectors at the same time as vastly increasing what the cable could do in power, data, and display dimensions. The new connector may be and virtually impossible to plug in improperly (no USB superposition problem, no grabbing the wrong end of the cable), but sacrificed for that simplicity is the ability to intuitively know whether the system you've connected together has all of the functionality possible. The USB spec also cannot simply mandate that all USB-C cables have the maximum number of wires all the time because that would vastly increase BOM cost for cases where the cable is just used for charging primarily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we fix this? Unfortunately, it's a tough problem that has to involve user education. USB-C cables are mandated by USB-IF to bear a particular logo in order to be certified:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.applegazette.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/3644.USB-C-image-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Collectively, we have to teach users that if they need DisplayPort to work, they need to find cables with the two logos on the right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Technically, there is something that software can do to help the education problem. Cables 2-6 are required by the USB specification to include an electronic marker chip which contains vital information about the cable. The host should be able to read that eMarker, and identify what its data and power capabilities are. If the host sees that the user is attempting to use DisplayPort Alternate Mode with the wrong cable, rather than a silent failure (ie, the external display doesn't light up), the OS should tell the user via a notification they may be using the wrong cable, and educate the user about cables with the right logo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is something that my team is actively working on, and I hope to be able to show the kernel pieces necessary soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2019 18:38:35 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>zdw</dc:creator>
<og:title>How many kinds of USB-C™ to USB-C™ cables are there?</og:title>
<og:description>tl;dr: There are 6, it&amp;#39;s unfortunately very confusing to the end user. Classic USB from the 1.1, 2.0, to 3.0 generations using USB-A...</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://people.kernel.org/bleung/how-many-kinds-of-usb-c-to-usb-c-cables-are-there</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.applegazette.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/3644.USB-C-image-2.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://people.kernel.org/bleung/how-many-kinds-of-usb-c-to-usb-c-cables-are-there</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Amazon workers launch protests on Prime Day</title>
<link>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-48990482</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-48990482</guid>
<description>&lt;figure class=&quot;media-with-caption&quot; readability=&quot;-24&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;player-with-placeholder&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img class=&quot;media-placeholder player-with-placeholder__image lead-video-placeholder&quot; src=&quot;https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/images/ic/720x405/p07gyffv.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Media playback is unsupported on your device&lt;/p&gt;
      
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;figcaption class=&quot;media-with-caption__caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Media caption&lt;/span&gt;'I have to pick an item every eight seconds, or 332 per hour, for a 10-hour day'&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;story-body__introduction&quot;&gt;Thousands of workers in Amazon sites around the world are staging protests about pay and conditions as the online retailer begins its annual sale.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Monday, Amazon starts offering discounts to its Prime service members.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unions say that 2,000 workers are on strike in Germany, while in the US, workers in a Minnesota centre reportedly plan a six-hour stoppage. In the UK, week-long protests are planned.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Amazon says it offers great employment opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;William Stolz, a picker at a warehouse in the Shakopee warehouse in Minnesota, told the BBC that workers wanted  &quot;safe, reliable jobs&quot; from Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He says he has to pick an item about every eight seconds, or 332 per hour, for a 10 hour day.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;The speeds that we have to work are very physically and mentally exhausting, in some cases leading to injuries,&quot; he said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul class=&quot;story-body__unordered-list&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-wales-46626990&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link&quot;&gt;Staff at Amazon's Swansea warehouse 'treated like robots'&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-48884596&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link&quot;&gt;Amazon at 25: The story of a giant&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Basically we just want them to treat us with respect as human beings and not treat us like machines,&quot; he said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Prime Day begins on Monday, but actually lasts 48 hours. The Seattle-based retailer, founded by Jeff Bezos, says new deals will launch as often as every five minutes &quot;giving shoppers plenty of reasons to come back again and again&quot;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the most valuable public companies in the world - making Mr Bezos the world's richest man - Amazon rang up total sales of $235bn (£188bn) of online sales last year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape no-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
        &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;In Germany, where Amazon employs 20,000 people, labour union Verdi said more than 2,000 workers at seven sites had gone on strike under the logo &quot;no more discount on our incomes&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;While Amazon fuels bargain hunting on Prime Day with hefty discounts, employees are being deprived of a living wage,&quot; said Orhan Akman, retail specialist at Verdi.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the UK, GMB union officials handed leaflets to workers arriving at the site in Peterborough in the East Midlands, and in the coming days protests are expected at other sites such as Swansea and Rugeley, in the West Midlands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mick Rix, GMB national officer, said: &quot;Amazon workers want Jeff Bezos to know they are people not robots. It's prime time for Amazon to get round the table with GMB and discuss ways to make the workplaces safer and to give their workers and independence voice&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape has-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
                 &lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image copyright&lt;/span&gt;
                 &lt;span class=&quot;story-image-copyright&quot;&gt;EPA&lt;/span&gt;
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
            &lt;figcaption class=&quot;media-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image caption&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;media-caption__text&quot;&gt;
                    Unions say that 2,000 workers are on strike in Germany
                &lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;While the GMB was not calling on shoppers to boycott Amazon, he said customers could act.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;We're not calling for economic damage for Amazon,&quot; he said. &quot;What we're asking for is for people to be aware. Leave feed back on Amazon&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In response, Amazon said it &quot;provided great employment opportunities with excellent pay&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It encouraged people to compare its operations in Shakopee with other employees in the area.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the UK, where it employs 29,500 people, a spokesperson said the company offered industry-leading pay starting at £9.50 per hour and was the &quot;employer of choice for thousands of people across the UK&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It said its German operations offered wages &quot;at the upper end of what is paid in comparable jobs&quot; and it was &quot;seeing very limited participation [in strikes] across Germany with zero operational impact and therefore no impact on customer deliveries&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In total, Amazon has a global workforce of 630,000, with 300,000 in the US.&lt;/p&gt;
            </description>
<pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2019 17:41:35 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>pmoriarty</dc:creator>
<og:title>Amazon workers launch protests on Prime Day</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>Thousands of workers are calling for better conditions as the retail giant's annual sale starts.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.bbc.com/news/business-48990482</og:url>
<og:image>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/images/ic/1024x576/p07gyffv.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-GB</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-48990482</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Epic Games Supports Blender Foundation with $1.2M</title>
<link>https://www.blender.org/press/epic-games-supports-blender-foundation-with-1-2-million-epic-megagrant/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.blender.org/press/epic-games-supports-blender-foundation-with-1-2-million-epic-megagrant/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;July 15, 2019 (Cary, NC) – Epic Games, as part of the company’s $100 million Epic MegaGrants program, is awarding the Blender Foundation $1.2 million in cash to further the success of Blender, the free and open source 3D creation suite that supports the full range of tools empowering artists to create 3D graphics, animation, special effects or games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Epic MegaGrants initiative is designed to assist game developers, enterprise professionals, media and entertainment creators, students, educators, and tool developers doing outstanding work with Unreal Engine or enhancing open-source capabilities for the 3D graphics community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Epic MegaGrant will be delivered incrementally over the next three years and will contribute to Blender’s Professionalizing Blender Development Initiative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Having Epic Games on board is a major milestone for Blender,” said Blender Foundation founder and chairman Ton Roosendaal. “Thanks to the grant we will make a significant investment in our project organization to improve on-boarding, coordination and best practices for code quality. As a result, we expect more contributors from the industry to join our projects.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Open tools, libraries and platforms are critical to the future of the digital content ecosystem,” said Tim Sweeney, founder and CEO of Epic Games. “Blender is an enduring resource within the artistic community, and we aim to ensure its advancement to the benefit of all creators.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information about Epic MegaGrants, visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.unrealengine.com/en-US/megagrants&quot;&gt;unrealengine.com/en-US/megagrants&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About Blender Foundation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The Blender Foundation (2002) is an independent nonprofit public benefit corporation with the purpose to provide individual artists and small teams with a complete, free and open source 3D creation pipeline, managed by public projects on blender.org. Its spin-off Blender Institute hosts the foundation’s offices and currently employs 15 people who work on the Blender software and creative projects to validate and stress Blender in production environments.&lt;br/&gt;For more information, visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.blender.org/foundation/&quot;&gt;blender.org/foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About Unreal Engine&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Epic Games’ Unreal Engine technology brings high-quality games to PC, console, mobile, AR and VR platforms. Creators also use Unreal for photorealistic visualization, interactive product design, film, virtual production, mixed reality TV broadcast and animated entertainment. Follow @UnrealEngine and download Unreal for free at unrealengine.com.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About Epic Games&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Founded in 1991, Epic Games is the creator of Fortnite, Unreal, Gears of War, Shadow Complex, and the Infinity Blade series of games. Epic’s Unreal Engine technology, which brings high-fidelity, interactive experiences to PC, console, mobile, AR, VR and the Web, is freely available at unrealengine.com. The Epic Games store offers a handpicked library of games, available at epicgames.com. Follow @EpicGames for updates.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2019 16:07:44 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>brachi</dc:creator>
<og:title> Epic Games supports Blender Foundation with $1.2 million Epic MegaGrant — blender.org</og:title>
<og:description>Home of the Blender project - Free and Open 3D Creation Software</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.blender.org/press/epic-games-supports-blender-foundation-with-1-2-million-epic-megagrant/</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.blender.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/megagrant_16x9-480x270.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.blender.org/press/epic-games-supports-blender-foundation-with-1-2-million-epic-megagrant/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>New 2019 MacBook Air features a slower SSD than 2018 model</title>
<link>https://www.imore.com/new-2019-macbook-air-features-slower-ssd-2018-model</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.imore.com/new-2019-macbook-air-features-slower-ssd-2018-model</guid>
<description>&lt;div readability=&quot;40.364341085271&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;article-body__drop-character article-body__first-paragraph&quot;&gt;The new 2019 MacBook Air with a True Tone display, upgraded keyboard and a price cut has been out for a week already, but we're finding out more about. The latest bit of information from &lt;a href=&quot;https://consomac.fr/news-10886-des-ssd-moins-rapides-dans-les-macbook-air-de-2019.html&quot;&gt;Consomac&lt;/a&gt; confirms an unfortunate drawback: the SSD is slower than the previous 2018 model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The French site conducted some tests on the new 2019 MacBook Air using Blackmagic Disk Speed Test and it achieved speeds of 1.3 GB/s read and 1 GB/s write. Compare it to the 2018 MacBook Air, which achieved 2 GB/s read and 0.9 GB/s write.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;52.389741800419&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple's newer laptop improved slightly on the writing side, but its performance downgraded by 35% on the reading side. That can be attributed to a slower SSD Apple included in the new MacBook Air.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before you go and start casting aspersions at Apple, the move makes a lot of sense. It'd be one thing if it did this and raised the price, but it actually lowered the price by $100, and the education discount brings it down to $999, making it the most affordable modern MacBook laptop ever (the outdated MacBook Air does not count).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that as the background, Apple was bound to make a sacrifice or two to reached the aggressive price point and it did so with the SSD. Most people will take that over it removing something like Touch ID or another feature they'd use on a daily basis. It's also worth pointing out that given it is an entry-level point product, most users who pick up the new notebook likely won't notice the difference at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regardless, the new MacBook Air is still the most affordable Apple laptop you can &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imore.com/macbook-air-2018-review&quot;&gt;buy right now&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;article-token article-token--prime-day-deals&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;article-token__title separator&quot;&gt;Latest And Best Prime Day Deals&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;th-deal-embed__image lazy&quot; src=&quot;https://www.imore.com/sites/all/themes/mbn2_twig/assets/images/1x1.png&quot; alt=&quot;The Ring Alarm security system is reaching new low prices for Prime Day&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; data-src=&quot;https://firebasestorage.googleapis.com/v0/b/thrifter-production.appspot.com/o/images%2Fdeals%2F077fc260-1c1c-4409-b906-5b70b406979d%2Fcropped_ring-alarm.png?alt=media&quot;/&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;th-deal-embed__image&quot; src=&quot;https://firebasestorage.googleapis.com/v0/b/thrifter-production.appspot.com/o/images%2Fdeals%2F077fc260-1c1c-4409-b906-5b70b406979d%2Fcropped_ring-alarm.png?alt=media&quot; alt=&quot;The Ring Alarm security system is reaching new low prices for Prime Day&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;400&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;8.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ring Alarm home security systems&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;th-deal-embed__price&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;th-deal-embed__summary&quot;&gt;Various configurations of the Ring Alarm are discounted to their best prices yet exclusively for Prime members at Amazon through Tuesday night to help keep your home secure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;th-deal-embed__image lazy&quot; src=&quot;https://www.imore.com/sites/all/themes/mbn2_twig/assets/images/1x1.png&quot; alt=&quot;The Sonos Beam Prime Day deal includes a $40 discount and 2 $50 Amazon gift cards&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; data-src=&quot;https://blog.thrifter.com/sites/thrifter.com/files/styles/w400h400crop/public/sonos-beam.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;th-deal-embed__image&quot; src=&quot;https://blog.thrifter.com/sites/thrifter.com/files/styles/w400h400crop/public/sonos-beam.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Sonos Beam Prime Day deal includes a $40 discount and 2 $50 Amazon gift cards&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;400&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Sonos Beam Prime Day deal includes a $40 discount and $100 in Amazon gift cards&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;th-deal-embed__price&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;th-deal-embed__new-price&quot;&gt;$359.00&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;th-deal-embed__old-price&quot;&gt;$499.00&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;th-deal-embed__save-price&quot;&gt;Save $140&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;th-deal-embed__summary&quot;&gt;That's just so much savings in one deal. You'll have to wait for the physical gift cards, but that's basically $100 to spend however you want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;th-deal-embed__image lazy&quot; src=&quot;https://www.imore.com/sites/all/themes/mbn2_twig/assets/images/1x1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Prime Day dropped this PlayStation 4 console bundle to just $250&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; data-src=&quot;https://firebasestorage.googleapis.com/v0/b/thrifter-production.appspot.com/o/images%2Fdeals%2F58eee663-c42b-4f11-b1ba-b30eaaa521e2%2Fcropped_ps4-prime-day-bundle.png?alt=media&quot;/&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;th-deal-embed__image&quot; src=&quot;https://firebasestorage.googleapis.com/v0/b/thrifter-production.appspot.com/o/images%2Fdeals%2F58eee663-c42b-4f11-b1ba-b30eaaa521e2%2Fcropped_ps4-prime-day-bundle.png?alt=media&quot; alt=&quot;Prime Day dropped this PlayStation 4 console bundle to just $250&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;400&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PlayStation 4 Slim 1TB console with Marvel's Spider-Man and Horizon Zero Dawn&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;th-deal-embed__price&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;th-deal-embed__new-price&quot;&gt;$249.99&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;th-deal-embed__old-price&quot;&gt;$359.98&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;th-deal-embed__save-price&quot;&gt;Save $110&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;th-deal-embed__summary&quot;&gt;This deal on the PlayStation 4 Slim console saves you $50 off its regular price while also including Marvel's Spider-Man and Horizon Zero Dawn Complete Edition for free. You'll just need an Amazon Prime membership to snag it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;th-deal-embed__image lazy&quot; src=&quot;https://www.imore.com/sites/all/themes/mbn2_twig/assets/images/1x1.png&quot; alt=&quot;The newest device in the Echo family, the Show 5, is now down to just $50&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; data-src=&quot;https://firebasestorage.googleapis.com/v0/b/thrifter-production.appspot.com/o/images%2Fdeals%2F7b994055-7956-4714-b143-34f422ff5b7c%2Fcropped_echo-show-5.jpg?alt=media&quot;/&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;th-deal-embed__image&quot; src=&quot;https://firebasestorage.googleapis.com/v0/b/thrifter-production.appspot.com/o/images%2Fdeals%2F7b994055-7956-4714-b143-34f422ff5b7c%2Fcropped_echo-show-5.jpg?alt=media&quot; alt=&quot;The newest device in the Echo family, the Show 5, is now down to just $50&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;400&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;6.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Echo Show 5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;th-deal-embed__price&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;th-deal-embed__new-price&quot;&gt;$49.99&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;th-deal-embed__old-price&quot;&gt;$89.99&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;th-deal-embed__save-price&quot;&gt;Save $40&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;th-deal-embed__summary&quot;&gt;It's only been on the market since May, but it hasn't escaped the Prime Day price cuts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;th-deal-embed__image lazy&quot; src=&quot;https://www.imore.com/sites/all/themes/mbn2_twig/assets/images/1x1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Amp up your home security with these huge Prime Day discount on nearly all Ring products&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; data-src=&quot;https://blog.thrifter.com/sites/thrifter.com/files/styles/w400h400crop/public/ring-doorbell-2.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;th-deal-embed__image&quot; src=&quot;https://blog.thrifter.com/sites/thrifter.com/files/styles/w400h400crop/public/ring-doorbell-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Amp up your home security with these huge Prime Day discount on nearly all Ring products&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;400&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Save on Ring products today only&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;th-deal-embed__price&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;th-deal-embed__summary&quot;&gt;Whether you need a video doorbell, whole home alarm system, or some lights to brighten a dark area, Amazon has it all marked down today!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;th-deal-embed__image lazy&quot; src=&quot;https://www.imore.com/sites/all/themes/mbn2_twig/assets/images/1x1.png&quot; alt=&quot;These huge price drops on the entire Galaxy S10 lineup might be one of the best Prime Day phone deals we'll see&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; data-src=&quot;https://firebasestorage.googleapis.com/v0/b/thrifter-production.appspot.com/o/images%2Fdeals%2Faab544fd-ba5f-47da-bee4-7159b05ea418%2Fcropped_samsung-galaxy-s10.jpg?alt=media&quot;/&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;th-deal-embed__image&quot; src=&quot;https://firebasestorage.googleapis.com/v0/b/thrifter-production.appspot.com/o/images%2Fdeals%2Faab544fd-ba5f-47da-bee4-7159b05ea418%2Fcropped_samsung-galaxy-s10.jpg?alt=media&quot; alt=&quot;These huge price drops on the entire Galaxy S10 lineup might be one of the best Prime Day phone deals we'll see&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;400&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;8.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Samsung Galaxy S10 128GB unlocked Prism Black Android smartphone&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;th-deal-embed__price&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;th-deal-embed__new-price&quot;&gt;$599.99&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;th-deal-embed__old-price&quot;&gt;$900.00&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;th-deal-embed__save-price&quot;&gt;Save $300&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;th-deal-embed__summary&quot;&gt;We love the Galaxy S10, and we love deals. This combines two of our true loves in one!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;th-deal-embed__image lazy&quot; src=&quot;https://www.imore.com/sites/all/themes/mbn2_twig/assets/images/1x1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Scour Amazon Warehouse's deals to save an extra 20% on tech and more through Prime Day&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; data-src=&quot;https://firebasestorage.googleapis.com/v0/b/thrifter-production.appspot.com/o/images%2Fdeals%2Fb56c56ff-7db2-4f5f-8e83-13504a7df885%2Fcropped_amazon-warehouse-prime-day-sale.png?alt=media&quot;/&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;th-deal-embed__image&quot; src=&quot;https://firebasestorage.googleapis.com/v0/b/thrifter-production.appspot.com/o/images%2Fdeals%2Fb56c56ff-7db2-4f5f-8e83-13504a7df885%2Fcropped_amazon-warehouse-prime-day-sale.png?alt=media&quot; alt=&quot;Scour Amazon Warehouse's deals to save an extra 20% on tech and more through Prime Day&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;400&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;11.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extra 20% off Amazon Warehouse&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;th-deal-embed__price&quot; readability=&quot;14&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;th-deal-embed__summary&quot;&gt;Amazon Warehouse sells a myriad of items in varying conditions, from refurbished to open-box, used, warehouse-damaged, and more. It's a great place to snag a deal, and now Prime members can save an extra 20% off select items at checkout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;th-deal-embed__image lazy&quot; src=&quot;https://www.imore.com/sites/all/themes/mbn2_twig/assets/images/1x1.png&quot; alt=&quot;There's never been a better deal on the Ring Video Doorbell 2 than this pre-Prime Day offer&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; data-src=&quot;https://firebasestorage.googleapis.com/v0/b/thrifter-production.appspot.com/o/images%2Fdeals%2F04856c11-eaaa-43d8-bcf7-0403036ffdae%2Fcropped_ring-video-doorbell-2.png?alt=media&quot;/&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;th-deal-embed__image&quot; src=&quot;https://firebasestorage.googleapis.com/v0/b/thrifter-production.appspot.com/o/images%2Fdeals%2F04856c11-eaaa-43d8-bcf7-0403036ffdae%2Fcropped_ring-video-doorbell-2.png?alt=media&quot; alt=&quot;There's never been a better deal on the Ring Video Doorbell 2 than this pre-Prime Day offer&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;400&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ring Video Doorbell 2 (Certified Refurbished)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;th-deal-embed__price&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;th-deal-embed__new-price&quot;&gt;$89.99&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;th-deal-embed__old-price&quot;&gt;$169.99&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;th-deal-embed__save-price&quot;&gt;Save $80&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;th-deal-embed__summary&quot;&gt;Amazon is taking $80 off the certified refurbished Ring Video Doorbell 2, which lets you see and speak with visitors at your front door no matter where you are in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;article-token__link cta&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/l/13887280011?mnsid=mbnx3-20&amp;amp;tag=mbnx33-20&quot;&gt;More Prime Day Deals&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2019 15:49:31 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>gbaygon</dc:creator>
<og:title>Apple included slower SSD in the new MacBook Air</og:title>
<og:description>As were shuffling around with the new MacBook Air that Apple introduced last week, we are learning more and more about it. The latest bit of info confirms Apple included a slower SSD compare to the 2018 model.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.imore.com/new-2019-macbook-air-features-slower-ssd-2018-model</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.imore.com/sites/imore.com/files/styles/large/public/field/image/2019/03/macbook-air-2018-front-hero-9c7o.jpg?itok=s4h8Ud_g</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.imore.com/new-2019-macbook-air-features-slower-ssd-2018-model</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Boeing 737 Max ordered by Ryanair undergoes name change</title>
<link>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2019/jul/15/boeing-737-max-ordered-by-ryanair-undergoes-name-change</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.theguardian.com/business/2019/jul/15/boeing-737-max-ordered-by-ryanair-undergoes-name-change</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;A Boeing 737 Max due to be delivered to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/business/ryanair&quot; data-link-name=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; data-component=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Ryanair&lt;/a&gt; has had the name Max dropped from the livery, further fuelling speculation that the manufacturer and airlines will seek to rebrand the troubled plane once it is given the all clear to fly again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photos have emerged of a 737 Max in Ryanair colours outside Boeing’s manufacturing hub, with the designation 737-8200 – instead of 737 Max – on the nose. The 737-8200 is a type name for the aircraft that is used by aviation agencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Max aircraft remains grounded worldwide after two &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/lion-air-crash-flight-jt610&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;crashes in Indonesia&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/ethiopian-airlines-crash&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Ethiopia&lt;/a&gt; killed a total of 346 people. Boeing has &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/business/2019/jun/26/united-extends-ban-on-boeing-737-max-after-regulator-finds-new-problem&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;yet to convince regulators&lt;/a&gt; that software modifications are sufficient to ensure the plane’s safety.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ryanair has 135 of the 737 Max models on order, the first five of which are due for delivery in the autumn, once regulators have declared the plane safe. The airline’s fleet order is comprised entirely of a larger version of the Max 8, with 197 seats, which it has until now referred to in official Ryanair announcements as the 737 Max 200.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;js-tweet tweet&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;tweet__user-name&quot;&gt;Woodys Aeroimages&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;tweet__user-id&quot;&gt;(@AeroimagesChris)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot; class=&quot;tweet-body&quot;&gt;HI-Res Photos: The MAX name has been dropped from the high capacity version of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/737MAX8?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;#737MAX8&lt;/a&gt; that &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Ryanair?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;@Ryanair&lt;/a&gt; has on order. &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/3q5QBN0TTg&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/3q5QBN0TTg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/AeroimagesChris/status/1150602370104975360?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;tweet-date&quot;&gt;July 15, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neither Ryanair nor &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/business/boeing&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Boeing&lt;/a&gt; has commented on nor confirmed the substitution of the 737-8200 for the better known Max, as seen on the photographs taken at Renton in Washington, US, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/AeroimagesChris/status/1150602370104975360&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;posted on social media by&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/AeroimagesChris/status/1150602370104975360&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Woodys Aeroimages&lt;/a&gt;. In previous photos from the same source, new Ryanair 737 Max 200 planes from Boeing are shown with 737 Max on their noses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is understood that what is painted on the plane is a matter for the airline rather than the manufacturer. According to sources reported in the Wall Street Journal, the Max plane is unlikely to return to the skies before 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ryanair would not be the first airline to use a different formulation in referring to the plane. International Airlines Group, which owns carriers including British Airways and Aer Lingus, was equally coy when &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/business/2019/jun/18/british-airlines-parent-iag-reveals-plans-buy-200-boeing-737-max-jets&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;purchasing discounted Max planes&lt;/a&gt; from Boeing last month. Announcing the letter of intent signed at the Paris airshow, IAG referred to “200 B737 aircraft” that would join its fleet from 2023, which it described as “a mix of 737-8 and 737-10 aircraft”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details data-snippet-id=&quot;f750d2ba-beda-413e-9d75-4f34351248bb&quot; data-snippet-type=&quot;timeline&quot; class=&quot;atom atom--snippet atom--snippet--timeline&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;atom--snippet__label&quot;&gt;Timeline&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;atom--snippet__headline&quot;&gt;Boeing’s 737 Max crisis&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;button class=&quot;atom__button atom__button--large atom__button--rounded atom--snippet__handle&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;is-on&quot;&gt; Show&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;is-off&quot;&gt; Hide&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/button&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__body&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__item&quot;&gt;&lt;time class=&quot;atom--snippet__event-date&quot; datetime=&quot;2018-10-29T00:00:00&quot;&gt;29 October 2018&lt;/time&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__heading&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lion Air crash&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2018/oct/29/lion-air-plane-lost-contact-indonesia-flight-jt610-jakarta&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Lion Air flight JT610 crashes&lt;/a&gt; after making a sudden, sharp dive into the Java Sea 13 minutes after departing from Jakarta, Indonesia. All 189 people onboard are killed. That particular plane had been in use for less than three months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__item&quot;&gt;&lt;time class=&quot;atom--snippet__event-date&quot; datetime=&quot;2018-11-07T00:00:00&quot;&gt;7 November 2018&lt;/time&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__heading&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Boeing's new advice&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/business/2018/nov/07/lion-air-crash-boeing-and-faa-to-issue-advice-to-airlines-on-737-max-jets-report&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Boeing issues revised instructions&lt;/a&gt; on how pilots should react to erroneous readings from “angle of attack” sensors, believed to be a key factor in the Lion Air crash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__item&quot;&gt;&lt;time class=&quot;atom--snippet__event-date&quot; datetime=&quot;2018-11-28T00:00:00&quot;&gt;28 November 2018&lt;/time&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__heading&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lion Air crash report&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“In our view, the plane was not airworthy,” is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2018/nov/28/lion-air-jet-was-not-airworthy-on-flight-before-crash-indonesia-investigators-say&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;the interim finding of the official investigation into the crash&lt;/a&gt;. The Indonesian transport safety agency did not pinpoint a definitive cause of the accident, but said Lion Air kept putting the plane back into service despite repeatedly failing to fix a problem with the airspeed indicator.  &lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__item&quot;&gt;&lt;time class=&quot;atom--snippet__event-date&quot; datetime=&quot;2019-03-10T00:00:00&quot;&gt;10 March 2019&lt;/time&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__heading&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ethiopia Airlines crash&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2019/mar/10/ethiopian-flight-302-second-new-boeing-737-max-8-to-crash-in-four-months&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Flight ET302 crashes&lt;/a&gt; approximately six minutes after taking off from the Ethiopian capital, Addis Ababa, killing all 157 people onboard. The captain had reported difficulties, and flight radar data shows the aircraft was climbing erratically with an unstable vertical airspeed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__item&quot;&gt;&lt;time class=&quot;atom--snippet__event-date&quot; datetime=&quot;2019-03-13T18:59:00&quot;&gt;13 March 2019&lt;/time&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__heading&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Boeing grounds fleet&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The EU, Canada and the US all ground the Boeing 737 Max. &lt;a href=&quot;https://boeing.mediaroom.com/news-releases-statements?item=130404&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Boeing itself issues a statement&lt;/a&gt; saying it “continues to have full confidence in the safety of the 737 Max”, but that “out of an abundance of caution and in order to reassure the flying public” it is recommending the grounding of the entire global fleet of 371 aircraft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__item&quot;&gt;&lt;time class=&quot;atom--snippet__event-date&quot; datetime=&quot;2019-04-04T00:00:00&quot;&gt;4 April 2019&lt;/time&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__heading&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interim report findings&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2019/apr/04/ethiopian-airlines-crash-pilots-followed-procedure-report-finds&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;The interim report into the Ethiopian Airlines crash&lt;/a&gt; finds that the pilots correctly followed Boeing’s emergency instructions, but were still unable to stop the plane’s nose repeatedly pointing down. The jet hit an airspeed of 500 knots (575mph), well above its operational limits, before cockpit data recordings stopped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__item&quot;&gt;&lt;time class=&quot;atom--snippet__event-date&quot; datetime=&quot;2019-06-27T08:22:31&quot;&gt;27 June 2019&lt;/time&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__heading&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A new potential risk&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Airlines extend their ban on using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/business/boeing&quot; data-link-name=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; data-component=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Boeing&lt;/a&gt; 737 Max after the US aviation regulator said it had identified a new potential risk with the plane.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__item&quot;&gt;&lt;time class=&quot;atom--snippet__event-date&quot; datetime=&quot;2019-06-27T08:22:31&quot;&gt;27 June 2019&lt;/time&gt;
&lt;p&gt;United Airlines becomes the latest carrier to extend its ban on using the Boeing 737 Max after the US aviation regulator said it had identified a new potential risk with the plane.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__item&quot;&gt;&lt;time class=&quot;atom--snippet__event-date&quot; datetime=&quot;2019-07-10T08:21:06&quot;&gt;10 July 2019&lt;/time&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the wake of Boeing’s troubles, Airbus seems set to overtake it as the world's biggest planemaker. As Boeing reported 239 commercial plane deliveries in the first half of the year, a 37% fall, rival Airbus shipped 389 deliveries, up 28% on the same period last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;footer class=&quot;atom--snippet__footer&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__feedback&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Was this helpful?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__ack&quot; hidden=&quot;&quot; aria-role=&quot;alert&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot;&gt;Thank you for your feedback.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/footer&gt;&lt;/details&gt;&lt;p&gt;Plenty of observers – among them Donald Trump – have advised Boeing to rebrand the plane before its eventual return to service. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/realdonaldtrump/status/1117736685721223168?lang=en&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;The US president tweeted&lt;/a&gt; in April: “If I were Boeing, I would FIX the Boeing 737 MAX, add some additional great features, &amp;amp; REBRAND the plane with a new name.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boeing told reporters at the Paris show that it would consider changing the name to help the model return to the skies, although the company said it was not working on a name change in its most recent statement on the matter: “We remain open-minded to all input from customers and other stakeholders but have no plans at this time to change the name of the 737 Max.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Max is Boeing’s top-selling aircraft, with about 5,000 ordered, although deliveries have ceased since the grounding in April and IAG’s is the only significant – and provisional – order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Investigations into the two disasters involving the 737 Max have highlighted the role played by anti-stall software that countermanded pilots’ commands as both planes crashed soon after takeoff. Airlines fear some passengers will refuse to fly on the Max.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;United Airlines, one of the main operators to date, has drawn up schedules without the 737 Max until November.&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2019 13:20:35 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>maratumba</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://www.theguardian.com/business/2019/jul/15/boeing-737-max-ordered-by-ryanair-undergoes-name-change</og:url>
<og:description>Decision fuels speculation that troubled plane will be rebranded once it is given all clear to fly</og:description>
<og:image>https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/61379310f763ab808e81fb80052e239bddf652df/0_0_3276_1966/master/3276.jpg?width=1200&amp;height=630&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=crop&amp;overlay-align=bottom%2Cleft&amp;overlay-width=100p&amp;overlay-base64=L2ltZy9zdGF0aWMvb3ZlcmxheXMvdGctZGVmYXVsdC5wbmc&amp;enable=upscale&amp;s=e6b01138d581f87aa02d241491ee9431</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Boeing 737 Max ordered by Ryanair undergoes name change</og:title>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2019/jul/15/boeing-737-max-ordered-by-ryanair-undergoes-name-change</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>EU&amp;#039;s GPS satellites have been down for four days in mysterious outage</title>
<link>https://www.zdnet.com/article/european-gps-satellites-have-been-down-for-four-days-in-mysterious-outage/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.zdnet.com/article/european-gps-satellites-have-been-down-for-four-days-in-mysterious-outage/</guid>
<description>&lt;span class=&quot;img aspect-set&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://zdnet1.cbsistatic.com/hub/i/2019/02/26/7e7d80d6-4780-4a74-a190-d2e43bbbd313/2d0d28956bcbde947918cff1749665d4/istock-939134866.jpg&quot; class=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;a satellite orbiting the earth with illuminated cities at night&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;3D rendering of a satellite orbiting the earth with illuminated cities at night. Map From: http://planetpixelemporium.com/earth.html Software for rendering: https://www.blender.org&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;Getty Images/iStockphoto&lt;/span&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Galileo, the EU's global navigation satellite system, has been down for four days, since July 11, following a mysterious outage. All Galileo satellites are still non-operational, at the time of writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.is/jbW9y&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;a service status page&lt;/a&gt;, 24 of the 26 Galileo satellites are listed as &quot;not usable,&quot; while the other two are listing a status of &quot;testing,&quot; which also means they're not ready for real-world usage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The European GNSS Agency (GSA), the organization in charge of Galileo, has not published any information in regards to the root of the outage, which began four days ago, on Thursday, July 11.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On that day, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gsc-europa.eu/notification-notice-advisory-to-galileo-users-nagu-2019025&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;the GSA published an advisory&lt;/a&gt; on its website alerting companies and government agencies employing the Galileo system that satellite signals have degraded and they &quot;may not be available nor meet the minimum performance levels.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The agency warned that the Galileo system &quot;should be employed at users' own risk.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The GSA published &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gsc-europa.eu/notification-notice-advisory-to-galileo-users-nagu-2019026&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;a more dire warning&lt;/a&gt; on Saturday, July 13, when it said that Galileo was experiencing a full-service outage and that &quot;signals are not to be used.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the time of writing, the service is nearing 100 hours of downtime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;sharethrough-top&quot; data-component=&quot;medusaContentRecommendation&quot; data-medusa-content-recommendation-options=&quot;{&amp;quot;promo&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;promo_ZD_recommendation_sharethrough_top_in_article_desktop&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;spot&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;dfp-in-article&amp;quot;}&quot;&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;p&gt;The system going down forced the Galileo's userbase (government agencies and private companies) to switch to alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Galileo_(satellite_navigation)&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;The Galileo satellite system&lt;/a&gt; was launched in 2016 and was funded by the EU as an alternative to the US Air Force's Global Position System (GPS) and the Russian government's GLONASS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is provided under both free and commercial offerings and is widely used by governments agencies and private companies for navigation and search and rescue operations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because it's provided for free, it is also widely used by the private tech sector and by most of the world's academia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The downtime also comes after widespread GPS outages were reported across &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.almasdarnews.com/article/gps-disruption-hits-iran-iraq-syria-israeli-radio-blames-russian-at-hmeimim-airbase/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Israel, Iran, Iraq, and Syria&lt;/a&gt; at the end of June. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thejewishadvocate.com/articles/russians-may-be-behind-ben-gurion-gps-outage/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Israeli media blamed&lt;/a&gt; the downtime &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.zdnet.com/article/report-deems-russia-a-pioneer-in-gps-spoofing-attacks/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;on Russian interference&lt;/a&gt;, rather than a technical problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Updated on July 15, 5:30am ET:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gsa.europa.eu/newsroom/news/update-availability-some-galileo-initial-services&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;In a statement&lt;/a&gt; published after this article's publication, the GSA blamed the Galileo outage on &quot;a technical incident related to its ground infrastructure.&quot; The agency said that the search and rescue (SAR) feature -- used for locating and helping people in distress situations for example at sea or mountains -- remained operational during the outage, which impacted only navigational and satellite-based timing services.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;relatedContent alignNone&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;heading&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;int&quot;&gt;More Prime Day&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2019 12:43:58 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>new_guy</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.zdnet.com/article/european-gps-satellites-have-been-down-for-four-days-in-mysterious-outage/</og:url>
<og:title>EU's GPS satellites have been down for four days in mysterious outage | ZDNet</og:title>
<og:description>EU's Galileo global navigation satellite system nears 100 hours of downtime.</og:description>
<og:image>https://zdnet3.cbsistatic.com/hub/i/r/2019/02/26/7e7d80d6-4780-4a74-a190-d2e43bbbd313/thumbnail/770x578/3cbe86efa9b86648f788ab184cd2248d/istock-939134866.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.zdnet.com/article/european-gps-satellites-have-been-down-for-four-days-in-mysterious-outage/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>To Break Google’s Monopoly on Search, Make Its Index Public</title>
<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-07-15/to-break-google-s-monopoly-on-search-make-its-index-public</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-07-15/to-break-google-s-monopoly-on-search-make-its-index-public</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-07-15/to-break-google-s-monopoly-on-search-make-its-index-public&quot;&gt;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-07-15/to-break-google-s-monopoly-on-search-make-its-index-public&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=20440079&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=20440079&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 751&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 529&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2019 12:21:07 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>JumpCrisscross</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bloomberg.com/tosv2.html?vid=&amp;uuid=431f21c0-a765-11e9-a61f-6b231221bd9b&amp;url=L25ld3MvYXJ0aWNsZXMvMjAxOS0wNy0xNS90by1icmVhay1nb29nbGUtcy1tb25vcG9seS1vbi1zZWFyY2gtbWFrZS1pdHMtaW5kZXgtcHVibGlj</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Alan Turing to feature on new £50 note</title>
<link>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-48962557</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-48962557</guid>
<description>&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape no-caption full-width lead&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                &lt;img class=&quot;js-image-replace&quot; alt=&quot;Alan Turning banknote concept&quot; src=&quot;https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/320/cpsprodpb/2D80/production/_107884611_turingnote.jpg&quot; width=&quot;976&quot; height=&quot;549&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image copyright&lt;/span&gt;
                 &lt;span class=&quot;story-image-copyright&quot;&gt;Bank of England&lt;/span&gt;
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
        &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;story-body__introduction&quot;&gt;Computer pioneer and codebreaker Alan Turing will feature on the new design of the Bank of England's £50 note.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He is celebrated for his code-cracking work that proved vital to the Allies in World War Two.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The £50 note will be the last of the Bank of England collection to switch from paper to polymer when it enters circulation by the end of 2021.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The note was once described as the &quot;currency of corrupt elites&quot; and is the least used in daily transactions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, there are still 344 million £50 notes in circulation, with a combined value of £17.2bn, according to the Bank of England's &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bankofengland.co.uk/statistics/banknote&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link-external&quot;&gt;banknote circulation figures&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Alan Turing was an outstanding mathematician whose work has had an enormous impact on how we live today,&quot; said Bank of England governor Mark Carney.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-with-caption&quot; readability=&quot;-24&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;player-with-placeholder&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img class=&quot;media-placeholder player-with-placeholder__image narrative-video-placeholder&quot; src=&quot;https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/images/ic/720x405/p07gyzm5.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Media playback is unsupported on your device&lt;/p&gt;
      
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;figcaption class=&quot;media-with-caption__caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Media caption&lt;/span&gt;Mark Carney praises Alan Turing's achievements&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;As the father of computer science and artificial intelligence, as well as a war hero, Alan Turing's contributions were far-ranging and path breaking. Turing is a giant on whose shoulders so many now stand.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;story-body__crosshead&quot;&gt;Why was Turing chosen?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The work of Alan Turing, who was educated in Sherborne, Dorset, helped accelerate Allied efforts to read German Naval messages enciphered with the Enigma machine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Less celebrated is the pivotal role he played in the development of early computers, first at the National Physical Laboratory and later at the University of Manchester.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2013, he was given &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-25495315&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link&quot;&gt;a posthumous royal pardon&lt;/a&gt; for his 1952 conviction for gross indecency following which he was chemically castrated. He had been arrested after having an affair with a 19-year-old Manchester man.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Bank said his legacy continued to have an impact on science and society today.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape no-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
        &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;story-body__crosshead&quot;&gt;Analysis: Paul Rincon, BBC News website science editor&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Alan Turing played an absolutely crucial role in Allied victories through his codebreaking work. He is also considered a towering figure in the development of computing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;idt2&quot;&gt;&lt;div data-idt-uuid=&quot;ae7b94e0-3d8a-43f2-8f37-a43694bf7d52&quot;&gt;&lt;div data-graphicuuid=&quot;ae7b94e0-3d8a-43f2-8f37-a43694bf7d52&quot; class=&quot;PicContainer-iky41v-0 dkfFzK&quot;&gt;&lt;div data-graphicpic=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;Img__PicImage-s1jp862x-1 dtAYqF&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.files.bbci.co.uk/include/idt2/assets/92100036-88b4-43eb-8661-a94a7080e578&quot; alt=&quot;BBC copyright&quot; class=&quot;Img__Image-s1jp862x-0 lmLsXj&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;BBC copyright&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div data-graphictext=&quot;true&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot; class=&quot;TextContainer-s1h09wvt-0 bTxczK&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Title-s5nqr84-0 vrMTP&quot;&gt;Alan Turing&lt;/span&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;Subheading-s1hcgie-0 kWIEYU&quot;&gt;1912 – 1954&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul class=&quot;idt-cloud-normal-figures FigureList-yjhr8u-0 dUzJAX&quot; readability=&quot;1.5&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;FigureList__Figure-yjhr8u-1 kBgHrk&quot; readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;RegularFigureList__Impact-n4skma-0 jNAUnX&quot;&gt;1912 &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;BaseText-w2isnj-0 fEqugv&quot;&gt;Alan Mathison Turing was born in West London&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;FigureList__Figure-yjhr8u-1 kBgHrk&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;RegularFigureList__Impact-n4skma-0 jNAUnX&quot;&gt;1936  &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;BaseText-w2isnj-0 fEqugv&quot;&gt;Produced “On Computable Numbers”, aged 24&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;FigureList__Figure-yjhr8u-1 kBgHrk&quot; readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;RegularFigureList__Impact-n4skma-0 jNAUnX&quot;&gt;1952 &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;BaseText-w2isnj-0 fEqugv&quot;&gt;Convicted of gross indecency for his relationship with a man&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;FigureList__Figure-yjhr8u-1 kBgHrk&quot; readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;RegularFigureList__Impact-n4skma-0 jNAUnX&quot;&gt;2013 &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;BaseText-w2isnj-0 fEqugv&quot;&gt;Received royal pardon for the conviction&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Source__SourceText-s1mlfx3o-0 cjWJHv&quot;&gt;Source:  BBC&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yet for decades, the idea of Turing being featured on a banknote seemed impossible. This will be seen as an attempt to signal how much has changed in society following the long, ultimately successful campaign to pardon Turing of his 1952 conviction - under contemporary laws - for having a homosexual relationship. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;His work helped cement the concept of the algorithm - the set of instructions used to perform computations - that are at the heart of our relationship with computers today. He was also a pioneer in the field of artificial intelligence: one of his best known achievements in this field is the Turing Test, which aims to measure whether a machine is &quot;intelligent&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape no-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
        &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;Former Manchester MP and gay rights campaigner John Leech, who campaigned for Alan Turing's pardon, said: &quot;This is a fitting and welcome tribute to a true Manchester hero. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;But more importantly I hope it will serve as a stark and rightfully painful reminder of what we lost in Turing, and what we risk when we allow that kind of hateful ideology to win.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Bank asked the public to offer suggestions for the scientist whose portrait should appear on the £50 note. In six weeks, the Bank received 227,299 nominations covering 989 eligible scientists.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A shortlist was drawn up by a committee, including experts from the field of science, before the governor made the final decision.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape has-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
                 &lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image copyright&lt;/span&gt;
                 &lt;span class=&quot;story-image-copyright&quot;&gt;Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
            &lt;figcaption class=&quot;media-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image caption&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;media-caption__text&quot;&gt;
                    Rosalind Franklin, Stephen Hawking and Ada Lovelace all appeared on the shortlist
                &lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;The shortlisted characters, or pairs of characters, considered were: Mary Anning, Paul Dirac, Rosalind Franklin, William Herschel and Caroline Herschel, Dorothy Hodgkin, Ada Lovelace and Charles Babbage, Stephen Hawking, James Clerk Maxwell, Srinivasa Ramanujan, Ernest Rutherford, Frederick Sanger and Alan Turing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The debate over representation on the Bank's notes could resurface after this decision.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jane Austen will continue to be the only woman, apart from the Queen, whose image will be seen on the four notes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There was also a campaign calling for a historic figure from a black and ethnic minority background (BAME) to feature on the new £50 note.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In response to Maidstone MP Helen Grant, who raised the issue in Parliament, the governor said: &quot;The Bank will properly consider all protected characteristics, and seek to represent on its banknotes characters reflecting the diversity of British society, its culture and its values.&quot; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;story-body__crosshead&quot;&gt;How will the banknote change?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Steam engine pioneers James Watt and Matthew Boulton appear on the current £50 note, issued in 2011.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The new £50 Turing note will enter circulation by the end of 2021, Mr Carney announced at the Science and Industry Museum in Manchester. It will feature: &lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul class=&quot;story-body__unordered-list&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;A photo of Turing taken in 1951 by Elliott and Fry, and part of the National Portrait Gallery's collection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;A table and mathematical formulae from Turing's 1936 paper &quot;On Computable Numbers, with an application to the Entscheidungsproblem&quot; - foundational for computer science&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;The Automatic Computing Engine (ACE) Pilot Machine - the trial model of Turing's design and one of the first electronic stored-program digital computers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;Technical drawings for the British Bombe, the machine specified by Turing and one of the primary tools used to break Enigma-enciphered messages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;A quote from Alan Turing, given in an interview to The Times newspaper on 11 June 1949: &quot;This is only a foretaste of what is to come, and only the shadow of what is going to be&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;His signature from the visitor's book at Bletchley Park in 1947&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;Ticker tape depicting Alan Turing's birth date (23 June 1912) in binary code. The concept of a machine fed by binary tape featured in Turing's 1936 paper.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Current Bank of England £5 and £10 notes are plastic - which the Bank says are more durable, secure and harder to forge. The next version of the £20, to enter circulation next year, will also be made of the same polymer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, the £50 note will be the last of the Bank's collection to change.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;story-body__crosshead&quot;&gt;Why do we even have a £50 note?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In recent years, there have been doubts that the £50 note would continue to exist at all.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fears that the largest denomination note was widely used by criminals and rarely for ordinary purchases prompted a government-led discussion on whether to abolish it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The £50 note was described by Peter Sands, former chief executive of Standard Chartered bank, as the &quot;currency of corrupt elites, of crime of all sorts and of tax evasion&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape no-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
        &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;There has also been considerable discussion over the future of cash in the UK, as cards and digital payments accelerate and the use of notes and coins declines.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, in October, ministers announced plans for a new version of the note, to be printed in the UK.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;story-body__crosshead&quot;&gt;What about other banknotes?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Polymer £5 and £10 notes are already in circulation, while a £20 design will be issued in 2020.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jane Austen was chosen to appear on the plastic £10 note after &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-41255976&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link&quot;&gt;a campaign to represent women other than the Queen on English notes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape no-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
                 &lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image copyright&lt;/span&gt;
                 &lt;span class=&quot;story-image-copyright&quot;&gt;Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
        &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2015, a total of 30,000 people nominated 590 famous visual artists for the £20 note, before JMW Turner was selected with the help of focus groups. He will replace economist Adam Smith on the note in 2020.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape no-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
        &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sir Winston Churchill appears on the polymer £5 note.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape no-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
                 &lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image copyright&lt;/span&gt;
                 &lt;span class=&quot;story-image-copyright&quot;&gt;PA&lt;/span&gt;
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
        &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;A host of different people have appeared on banknotes issued in Scotland and Northern Ireland. Ulster Bank's vertical £5 and £10 notes entered circulation in Northern Ireland in February. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape no-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
        &lt;/figure&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2019 10:20:05 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>hanoz</dc:creator>
<og:title>New face of the £50 note is revealed</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>The note - once called the currency of corrupt elites - gets a makeover with the image of a computer pioneer.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.bbc.com/news/business-48962557</og:url>
<og:image>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/2D80/production/_107884611_turingnote.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-GB</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-48962557</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Florida DMV sells personal info to private companies, marketing firms</title>
<link>https://www.abcactionnews.com/news/local-news/i-team-investigates/i-team-florida-dmv-sells-your-personal-information-to-private-companies-marketing-firms</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.abcactionnews.com/news/local-news/i-team-investigates/i-team-florida-dmv-sells-your-personal-information-to-private-companies-marketing-firms</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;RichTextArticleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;RichTextArticleBody-body&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LAKELAND, Fla. — A local woman is blaming the state government for an onslaught of robocalls and direct mail offers – accusations that come as the I-Team uncovered the DMV makes millions by selling Florida drivers personal information to outside companies, including marketing firms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I-Team Investigator Adam Walser obtained records showing the state sold information on Florida drivers and ID cardholders to more than 30 private companies, including marketing firms, bill collectors, insurance companies and data brokers in the business of reselling information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Florida Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles raked in more than $77 million for driver and ID cardholder information sales in fiscal 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The I-Team wanted to know how much of that money came from marketing firms, but the agency in charge of driver information estimated it would take 154 hours of research and cost nearly $3,000 for the state to give taxpayers an answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Enhancement&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Enhancement-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;Link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.abcactionnews.com/news/local-news/i-team-investigates&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;I-TEAM INVESTIGATIONS | Our latest investigations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Lakeland woman and her sister told the I-Team they blame DMV sales for an onslaught of recent robocalls and direct mail offers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tonia Batson moved from Idaho to Florida last year to live with her twin sister Sonia Arvin, who is now her legal guardian because Batson has an intellectual disability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We take her to get an ID because she’s a Medicaid patient,” said Arvin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Days later, Arvin said Batson started receiving direct mail offers for lawn service, credit cards, cell phones and insurance. She also now receives constant robocalls and salespeople have even started showing up at her door.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;She had no digital footprint – until she got an ID&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I really don’t understand about credit cards or checkbooks or nothing,” said Batson.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Idaho, Batson lived in a group home where someone else handled her finances, daily living and healthcare arrangements. She had no digital footprint because she can’t read or write.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s why Arvin wanted to know how marketers got Batson’s personal information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The only one that had it was the DMV,” said Arvin. “Even if it’s a public record in Florida – if we tell them we want it private, it should be kept private.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The state opened an investigation into Batson’s case after the I-Team alerted FHSMV officials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s because Florida Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles said companies buying data on Floridians are not allowed to use that information for marketing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But not every company plays by the rules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Companies caught abusing the system&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The state told the I-Team it has banned data sales to three companies since 2017 for misusing driver and ID cardholder information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Florida Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles told the I-Team under the law, it must provide driver information but said federal privacy laws and its own rules limit how outside companies can access Floridian’s personal information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read the state’s privacy statement by &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Enhancement&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Enhancement-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;Link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flhsmv.gov/privacy-statement/driver-privacy-protection-act/&quot;&gt;clicking here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the data brokers accessing Florida DMV information is Arkansas-based marketing firm Acxiom, which has an agreement with the state to buy driver and ID cardholder data for a penny a record.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On its website, Acxiom claims it has collected information from almost every adult in the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Acxiom provides clients with access to 2.5 billion customers and two-thirds of the world’s population,” states a promotional video on Acxiom’s website, which claims the company has a client list that includes banks, automakers and department stores.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The I-Team contacted Acxiom to find out how they are using information on Florida drivers and ID card holders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A company spokesperson declined an on-camera interview but emailed a statement:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Acxiom acquires information from a variety of sources to inform its marketing and commercial products, including Acxiom’s identity verification and fraud prevention products. We maintain all information in strict compliance with state and federal laws. But because sound data governance, including ethical and responsible use of information, is foundational to our business, we go beyond legal compliance to ensure additional transparency and clarity for consumers. To learn more about Acxiom’s products, and the choices consumers have regarding use of their information, please visit &lt;span class=&quot;Enhancement&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Enhancement-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;Link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.acxiom.com/about-us/privacy/highlights-for-us-products-privacy-policy/&quot;&gt;Acxiom.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; .&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lawyer: Companies looking for cheap data on you&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Miami attorney Al Saikali, who advises his clients how to legally and ethically use public data for commercial purposes, said his clients are increasingly using public records laws to obtain information for a cheap price.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We’re only going to see this continue over time. Companies are going to continue to seek more data about you,” said Saikali. “Companies are essentially paying for information, for leads, for lead generation.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saikali said consumers can limit the number of marketers contacting them by setting up a secondary email account to give government agencies – which is only checked periodically for renewal notices and other important information – and only giving a telephone number to government agencies when it’s absolutely necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A state spokesperson said there’s no way for drivers to opt out if they don’t want their personal information sold, saying in an emailed statement:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The Florida Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles provides public records as legally required, in accordance with federal and state law, and as a necessary function in order for customers to efficiently conduct everyday business. The department has successfully instituted proactive security measures to ensure customer information is protected and any misuse of customer information will be pursued to the fullest extent of the law.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the I-Team uncovered Acxiom does provide a way for anyone to request personal information be excluded from the company’s marketing data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To opt out &lt;span class=&quot;Enhancement&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Enhancement-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;Link&quot; href=&quot;https://isapps.acxiom.com/optout/optout.aspx&quot;&gt;click here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have a story you’d like the I-Team to investigate, email &lt;span class=&quot;Enhancement&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Enhancement-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;Link&quot; href=&quot;mailto:adam@abcactionnews.com&quot;&gt;adam@abcactionnews.com.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2019 05:05:46 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>green-eclipse</dc:creator>
<og:title>I-Team: Florida DMV sells your personal information to private companies, marketing firms</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.abcactionnews.com/news/local-news/i-team-investigates/i-team-florida-dmv-sells-your-personal-information-to-private-companies-marketing-firms</og:url>
<og:image>https://ewscripps.brightspotcdn.com/dims4/default/aad11d3/2147483647/strip/true/crop/1000x525+0+5/resize/1200x630!/quality/90/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fewscripps.brightspotcdn.com%2Feb%2F53%2F4760f199422481c1cf42be84e25e%2Fi-team-dmv.png</og:image>
<og:description>The I-Team uncovered the DMV makes millions by selling Florida drivers personal information to outside companies.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.abcactionnews.com/news/local-news/i-team-investigates/i-team-florida-dmv-sells-your-personal-information-to-private-companies-marketing-firms</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>