<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Show HN: Hacker News Classics</title>
<link>http://jsomers.net/hn</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://jsomers.net/hn</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;meta http-equiv=&quot;Content-Type&quot; content=&quot;text/html; charset=utf-8&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;viewport&quot; content=&quot;width=device-width, initial-scale=1.0&quot; /&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;shortcut icon&quot; href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/favicon.ico&quot; /&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot; href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/news.css&quot; /&gt;&lt;title&gt;The Hacker Classics&lt;/title&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot; readability=&quot;31.014554794521&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;about&quot; readability=&quot;17.722602739726&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hacker News is no different from most of today's web in emphasizing what's new. When you're following a bunch of feeds, it's easy to forget that the web is the greatest library in the history of the world—and that a good library doesn't just have a rack of newspapers, it has a vast collection of books and archives: the stacks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, then, are the stories that occasionally surface on news.yc when someone goes diving into the stacks. It includes every HN post with a date like &quot;(1999)&quot; in its title that has earned more than 40 votes. You can see how this page is built &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jsomers/hacker-classics&quot;&gt;on Github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;placeholder&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://jsomers.net/hn/loader.gif&quot; id=&quot;loader&quot; name=&quot;loader&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2018 00:11:29 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jsomers</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://jsomers.net/hn/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Self-owning corporations are legally possible</title>
<link>https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2954173</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2954173</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;note note-list&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;76 Pages&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;Posted: 18 Apr 2017&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;authors&quot; readability=&quot;6.4210526315789&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;University of California, Los Angeles (UCLA) - School of Law&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date Written: April 17, 2017&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;abstract-text&quot; readability=&quot;57&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an article published in the Northwestern University Law Review in 2014, Professor Shawn Bayern demonstrated that anyone can confer legal personhood on an autonomous computer algorithm merely by putting it in control of a limited liability company. Bayern’s demonstration coincided with the development of “autonomous” online businesses that operate independently of their human owners — accepting payments in online currencies and performing the off-line aspects of their businesses by contracting with human agents. At about the same time, leading technologists Elon Musk, Bill Gates, and Stephen Hawking said that they regard human-level artificial intelligence as an existential threat to the human race.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This Article argues that algorithmic entities — legal entities that have no human controllers — greatly exacerbate the threat of artificial intelligence. Algorithmic entities are likely to prosper first and most in criminal, terrorist, and other anti-social activities because that is where they have their greatest comparative advantage over human-controlled entities. Control of legal entities will contribute to algorithms’ prosperity by providing them with identities that will enable them to accumulate wealth and participate in commerce.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Four aspects of corporate law make the human race vulnerable to the threat of algorithmic entities. First, algorithms can lawfully have exclusive control of not just American LLC’s but also a large majority of the entity forms in most countries. Second, entities can change regulatory regimes quickly and easily through migration. Third, governments — particularly in the United States — lack the ability to determine who controls entities they charter and so cannot determine which have non-human controllers. Lastly, corporate charter competition, combined with ease of entity migration, makes it virtually impossible for any government to regulate algorithmic control of entities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keywords:&lt;/strong&gt; corporations, charter competition, internal affairs doctrine, business associations, artificial intelligence, entity migration, reincorporation, beneficial owners, terrorism, corporate disclosure, autonomous entities, algorithms, regulatory competition, financial action task force&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;hidden-xs hidden-sm&quot;&gt;Suggested Citation:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2954173#&quot; class=&quot;suggested-citation-btn btn-link visible-xs visible-sm&quot;&gt;Suggested Citation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;selectable&quot; onclick=&quot;selectText('selectable')&quot; class=&quot;suggested-citation&quot; readability=&quot;10.166666666667&quot;&gt;LoPucki, Lynn M., Algorithmic Entities (April 17, 2017). 95 Washington University Law Review (Forthcoming).; UCLA School of Law, Law-Econ Research Paper No. 17-09. Available at SSRN: &lt;a href=&quot;https://ssrn.com/abstract=2954173&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://ssrn.com/abstract=2954173&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 21:23:20 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>gwern</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2954173</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>China&amp;#039;s Xinjiang surveillance is the dystopian future nobody wants</title>
<link>https://www.engadget.com/2018/02/22/china-xinjiang-surveillance-tech-spread/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.engadget.com/2018/02/22/china-xinjiang-surveillance-tech-spread/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Xinjiang is the home to the Uyghurs, a Turkic people who mostly follow Islam and have a distinct culture and language. Not surprisingly, the region has a tenuous relationship with Beijing, which is more than 1,400 miles away. Protests, riots and even terrorist attacks have been connected to the Uyghur struggle, which gives cover to Chinese authorities to implement the harshest strategies there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Abuses are most apparent in Xinjiang because of the lack of privacy protections but also because the power imbalance between the people there and the police is the greatest in China,&quot; said Maya Wang, China researcher at Human Rights Watch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;half-width right&quot; readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;The power imbalance between the people there and the police is the greatest in China.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is why security investment in Xinjiang skyrocketed after the riots. According to Adrian Zenz, a lecturer at the European School of Culture and Theology who has written extensively about the police presence in Xinjiang and Tibet, the region's security forces doubled between 2009 and 2011 to more than 11,000 people. And it kept growing: In 2017, he documented more than 65,000 public job advertisements for security-related positions in Xinjiang, and last year Amnesty International estimated that there were 90,000 security staff in the region, the highest ratio of people to security in any province in China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several new tools and tactics accompanied this rise in security personnel, most notably the implementation of &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/article/us-china-xinjiang-security-insight/terror-threats-transform-chinas-uighur-heartland-into-security-state-idUSKBN1713AS&quot;&gt;convenience police stations&lt;/a&gt;,&quot; a dense network of street corner, village or neighborhood police stations designed to keep an eye out everywhere and rapidly respond to any threat, perceived or real. But there were also corresponding investments in security technology on a globally unprecedented scale. It started with a drive to put up security cameras in the aftermath of the 2009 riots before evolving into something far more sophisticated, as Xinjiang turned into a place for state-connected companies to test all of their surveillance innovations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;The rule of law doesn't exist,&quot; said William Nee, China researcher at Amnesty International. &quot;They are able to pioneer new methods of control that, if successful, they could use elsewhere in China.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, Xinjiang has both a massive security presence and ubiquitous surveillance technology: facial-recognition cameras; iris and body scanners at checkpoints, gas stations and government facilities; the collection of DNA samples for a massive database; mandatory apps that monitor messages and data flow on Uyghurs' smartphones; drones to monitor the borders. While there's some debate over how advanced the system tying these technologies together is, it's clear that China's plan is for a fully integrated system that uses artificial intelligence to rapidly process massive amounts of information for use by the similarly massive numbers of police in convenience stations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;half-width left&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;[Xinjiang] represents a very new frontier and approach when it comes to online surveillance and oppression.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Uyghurs, it means that wherever they go, whomever they talk to and even whatever they read online are all being monitored by the Chinese government. According to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/02/03/opinion/sunday/china-surveillance-state-uighurs.html&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &quot;When Uighurs buy a kitchen knife, their ID data is etched on the blade as a QR code.&quot; &lt;em&gt;BuzzFeed&lt;/em&gt; documented stories of family members too scared to speak openly to relatives abroad. And the combination of all of these tools through increasingly powerful AI and data processing means absolute control and little freedom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;It's one thing to have GPS tracking. It's another thing to monitor social media usage of large populations,&quot; said Feldstein. &quot;But to do that in combination with a large DNA database of up to 40 million people and to integrate those methods with other modes of surveillance and intrusion -- that represents a very new frontier and approach when it comes to online surveillance and oppression.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The result, at least for China, is a massive success. Violence in the region has fallen as riots, protests and attacks are now rare in Xinjiang. Part of that is due to the presence of the state, but it's also related to a rise in fear, as no one is sure how pervasive the Chinese surveillance apparatus is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;People can never be sure if they are free from monitoring,&quot; said Nicole Morgret, project coordinator at the Uyghur Human Rights Project. &quot;The fear is such that even if the surveillance is not complete, people behave as if it is. The technology is being rolled out so quickly.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is because access to the actual platforms being used by the Chinese authorities is limited, and much of the knowledge about surveillance technology comes from observations by the few journalists who can report from Xinjiang or through looking at public tender and budget documents. Or, increasingly, the knowledge comes from observing how other regions in China are being monitored and how Chinese tech companies abroad are deploying or marketing similar tools.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 21:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Ajedi32</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.engadget.com/2018/02/22/china-xinjiang-surveillance-tech-spread/</og:url>
<og:title>China's Xinjiang surveillance is the dystopian future nobody wants</og:title>
<og:description>In July 2009, deadly riots broke out in Urumqi, the capital of Xinjiang, China. Nearly 200 people died, the majority ethnic Han Chinese, and thousands of Chines...</og:description>
<og:image>https://o.aolcdn.com/images/dims?thumbnail=1200%2C630&amp;quality=80&amp;image_uri=https%3A%2F%2Fs.aolcdn.com%2Fhss%2Fstorage%2Fmidas%2Fdc3d5910c0bb1ad8d59b109edb342ffa%2F206150575%2Fdims.jpg&amp;client=cbc79c14efcebee57402&amp;signature=5424d3f44bb68cb6853c45f2e03ab83b5d396e7e</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.engadget.com/2018/02/22/china-xinjiang-surveillance-tech-spread/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>YC&amp;#039;s Series A Diligence Checklist</title>
<link>https://blog.ycombinator.com/ycs-series-a-diligence-checklist/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.ycombinator.com/ycs-series-a-diligence-checklist/</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot; readability=&quot;58.879653238144&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we launched our &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.ycombinator.com/yc-series-a-program/&quot;&gt;Series A program&lt;/a&gt; a few months ago, we decided that what we learn along the way shouldn’t just be kept inside of YC. We’re going to publish tools and learnings from the program that should help every company create better outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the first tool. It’s simple, but effective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below, you’ll find a Series A diligence checklist. This runs through all the pieces of information you’ll need to have ready once you sign a term sheet. Having all of this together in one place – a Data Room – before you sign a term sheet will cut as much as a week off of your closing process. Founders don’t generally realize that closing an A can take more than a month, much of which is often spent tracking down documents for lawyers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jason Kwon, the GC of YC Continuity put this checklist together after being involved in hundreds of financings with nearly every law firm and VC fund in the valley.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Corporate Records and Charter Documents&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;All minutes of directors’ and stockholders’ meetings, and all written consents of directors and stockholders.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Certificate of Incorporation, Certificates of Designation, Rights, etc., and Bylaws.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Similar information for the Company and subsidiaries, if any.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A corporate entity organizational chart, if there are any parents or subsidiaries.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Business Plan and Financials&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Current business plan and any financial projections.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most recent financial statements.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Intellectual Property&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;A list of the Company’s trademarks, patents, copyrights and domain names (or any applications therefore) including documentation of filing or registration with the appropriate governmental entities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If any of the foregoing were assigned to the Company, please so state and provide documentation of the assignment and recordation with the appropriate governmental entities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Security Issuances and Agreements Concerning Securities&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;A list of the Company’s stockholders, including issuance dates and original issuance price.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A list of the Company’s option holders, including grant dates and exercise prices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copies of agreements relating to outstanding options, warrants, rights (including conversion or preemptive rights) or agreements for the purchase or acquisition of any of the Company’s securities, and agreements relating to the Company’s past stock issuances.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any documents evidencing registration rights for the Company’s securities, or evidencing any agreements among the Company’s shareholders or between the Company and its shareholders.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A summary of the vesting schedules of any stock or options subject to vesting, including any vesting acceleration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Agreements relating to voting of securities and restrictive share transfers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evidence of qualification or exemption under applicable federal (including Rule 701) and state blue sky laws for issuance or transfer of the Company’s securities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Material Agreements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;The Company’s standard terms of service / terms of use for its customers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any agreements, understanding, instruments, contracts or proposed transactions to which the Company is a party or by which it is bound which involve obligations of, or payments to, the Company in excess of $25,000.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any personal property leases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any agreements concerning the purchase, lease, or sublease of real property.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any documents evidencing indebtedness for money borrowed or any other liabilities incurred by the Company.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any documents evidencing any mortgages, liens, loans and encumbrances with respect to the Company’s property or assets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any documents evidencing any loans or advances made by the Company.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any licenses or agreements of any kind with respect to the Company’s or others’ patent, copyright, trade secret or other proprietary rights, proprietary information or technology, including employee confidentiality and proprietary information agreements.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any insurance policies held by the Company or of which the Company is a beneficiary and a summary of such policies, if available.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any judgment, order, writ or decree by which the Company is bound or to which it is a party.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any standard forms of agreements used by the Company.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any joint venture and partnership agreements.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any management, service and marketing agreements.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any confidentiality and nondisclosure agreements.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any agreements requiring consents or approvals in connection with the financing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any consulting contracts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any other agreements material to the business of the Company, or outside the ordinary course of business.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A list of officers and directors. If any officers are not currently devoting 100 percent of their business time to the Company, please note them on this list.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Information Regarding Disputes and Potential Litigation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Any correspondence or documents relating to any pending or threatened action, suit or proceeding or investigation, including, without limitation, (i) those involving the Company’s employees in connection with their prior or present employment or use of technology and (ii) those being conducted by or before any governmental entity or regulatory agency.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any correspondence or documents relating to allegations of the Company’s infringement of the proprietary rights of others.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any correspondence or documents relating to any labor agreements or actions, union representation, or strike or other labor dispute.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Information Regarding Employees and Employee Benefits&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;A list of the Company’s employees and consultants, including title, base salary, target bonus (if applicable), commission plan (if applicable), classification (including, if an employee, whether the employee is exempt or non-exempt) and state of residence.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Company’s standard form of offer letter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any agreements, understandings or proposed transactions between the Company and any of its officers, directors, affiliates, or any affiliate thereof, including without limitation, employment agreements and offer letters with severance benefits or vesting acceleration provisions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any plans, agreements or arrangements that provide benefits contingent upon a change in control.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any severance or deferred compensation plans (including any salary deferral agreements, whether written or oral, with employees or consultants).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any employee benefit plans, including, without limitation, stock option plans, 401(k) plans, pension plans and insurance plans.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any forms of agreements used in connection with any stock option plans (such as a form of option agreement, notice of exercise and restricted stock purchase agreement).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the Company sponsors a 401(k) plan, any determination or opinion letter and Form 5500 filings for the last 3 years.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All documents or other information relating to any loans made by the Company to its employees, directors or consultants.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Company’s employee handbook.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the Company has any foreign employees, separately list (by country) all benefits provided to foreign employees.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Equity Grants&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;If you have any pending or promised equity grants you haven’t already taken care of before you start your Series A process, do that ASAP. More people than not believe that once you have a term sheet, you can no longer use your current 409A valuation for option/stock grants because a material event has occurred that implies a newer (and hopefully higher) valuation for the company’s common stock. Team members that were hired earlier who haven’t been granted their equity yet will then have to receive their equity at a higher strike price, which reduces their upside. Some hires will realize this and you may then have to increase their compensation (in equity, cash or both) to make up the difference to avoid a morale issue. Since you cannot control the exact timing of when you receive a term sheet, the prudent thing to do is to make sure there isn’t a significant backlog of equity grants while you are in the middle of your fundraise process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;mc_embed_signup&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;mc_copy&quot;&gt;Sign up for weekly updates from Y Combinator.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 19:31:26 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>akharris</dc:creator>
<og:title>YC’s Series A Diligence Checklist</og:title>
<og:url>https://blog.ycombinator.com/ycs-series-a-diligence-checklist/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>When we launched our Series A program a few months ago, we decided that what we learn along the way shouldn’t just be kept inside of YC. We're going to publish tools and learnings from the program that should help every company create better outcomes. This is the first tool. It’s simple, but effecti</og:description>
<og:image>https://blog.ycombinator.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/YCs-Series-A-Diligence-Checklist-2.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.ycombinator.com/ycs-series-a-diligence-checklist/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>My Python Development Environment, 2018 Edition</title>
<link>https://jacobian.org/writing/python-environment-2018/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://jacobian.org/writing/python-environment-2018/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;For years I’ve noodled around with various setups for a Python development environment, and never really found something I loved – until now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My setup pieces together &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/pyenv/pyenv&quot;&gt;pyenv&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.pipenv.org/&quot;&gt;pipenv&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/mitsuhiko/pipsi&quot;&gt;pipsi&lt;/a&gt;. It’s probably a tad more complex that is ideal for most Python users, but for the things I need, it’s perfect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;my-requirements&quot; readability=&quot;6.7878787878788&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;My Requirements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do have somewhat specific (maybe unusual?) requirements:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;simple&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;I need to develop against multiple Python versions, including 2.7, various Python 3 versions (3.5 and 3.6, mostly), and PyPy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I work on many projects simultaneously, each with different sets of dependencies, so some sort of virtual environment or isolation is critical.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I use multiple OSes: macOS at work, and Linux (well, Linux-ish - actually it’s &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/wsl/about&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;WSL&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) at home.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I want to avoid using the System-provided Python. On macOS it’s too outdated. On Linux, the system Python is used by the &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;OS&lt;/span&gt; itself, so if you hose your Python you can hose your system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I use a bunch Python-based &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;CLI&lt;/span&gt; stuff, like &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://rg3.github.io/youtube-dl/&quot;&gt;youtube-dl&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/cli/&quot;&gt;awscli&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://doc2dash.readthedocs.io/en/stable/&quot;&gt;doc2dash&lt;/a&gt;, etc. I want to be able to install and use them without fussing around with activating environments, but I also don’t want their dependencies to clutter up a global installation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I deploy stuff mostly to Heroku (personal) and &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://cloud.gov/&quot;&gt;cloud.gov&lt;/a&gt; (work). I expect this not to change: I’m spoiled, and never want to manage my own infrastructure again.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Although Docker meets all these requirements, I don’t really like using it. I find it slow, frustrating, and overkill for my purposes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;the-setup&quot; readability=&quot;29.38148340249&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Setup&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;id1&quot; readability=&quot;24.148044692737&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;1. &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/pyenv/pyenv&quot;&gt;pyenv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why?&lt;/strong&gt; I need to run multiple Python versions, isolated from the system Python. &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/pyenv/pyenv&quot;&gt;pyenv&lt;/a&gt; makes it easy to install, manage, and switch between those multiple Pythons. As a bonus, &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.pipenv.org/&quot;&gt;pipenv&lt;/a&gt; integrates with &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/pyenv/pyenv&quot;&gt;pyenv&lt;/a&gt; and will automatically install missing Python versions if they’re required by a &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;Pipfile&lt;/tt&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On my Mac, I installed &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/pyenv/pyenv&quot;&gt;pyenv&lt;/a&gt; from Homebrew (&lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;brew install pyenv&lt;/tt&gt;). On Linux, I used the Github installation technique documented in the &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/pyenv/pyenv#installation&quot;&gt;installation instructions&lt;/a&gt;, which was easy and went smoothly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, I installed some Python versions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;literal-block&quot;&gt;
pyenv install 3.6.4
pyenv install 3.5.4
pyenv install 2.7.14
pyenv install pypy3.5-5.10.0
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And made sure my default Python was set to the latest and greatest:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;literal-block&quot;&gt;
pyenv global 3.6.4
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;id2&quot; readability=&quot;27.073426573427&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;2. &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/mitsuhiko/pipsi&quot;&gt;pipsi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/mitsuhiko/pipsi&quot;&gt;pipsi&lt;/a&gt; lets me install Python-based &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;CLI&lt;/span&gt; stuff (like &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://rg3.github.io/youtube-dl/&quot;&gt;youtube-dl&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/cli/&quot;&gt;awscli&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://doc2dash.readthedocs.io/en/stable/&quot;&gt;doc2dash&lt;/a&gt;, etc.) without those projects’ dependencies messing up my global Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Normally, installing &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/mitsuhiko/pipsi&quot;&gt;pipsi&lt;/a&gt; is easy:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;literal-block&quot;&gt;
curl https://raw.githubusercontent.com/mitsuhiko/pipsi/master/get-pipsi.py | python
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, at the time I’m writing this (late February 2018), this didn’t work for me; I needed to do some tweaking to get it to work. I followed the workarounds documented in issues &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/mitsuhiko/pipsi/issues/124&quot;&gt;#124&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/mitsuhiko/pipsi/issues/125&quot;&gt;#125&lt;/a&gt;. Hopefully this’ll be fixed shortly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn’t do this, but it might be a good idea to install &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/mitsuhiko/pipsi&quot;&gt;pipsi&lt;/a&gt; using the system Python (i.e. run &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;pyenv local system&lt;/tt&gt; before running the installer). The downside is that this will use a potentially old-ass Python, but the upside is that you won’t break your &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/mitsuhiko/pipsi&quot;&gt;pipsi&lt;/a&gt; install if you delete a pyenv version (like upon an upgrade).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;what-it-looks-like-in-use&quot; readability=&quot;39.66511627907&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What it looks like in use&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this all together, all my use-cases are handled simply:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To start new projects, I just make a directory and type &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;pipenv install ...&lt;/tt&gt; to start installing my dependencies. Pipenv creates a &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;Pipfile&lt;/tt&gt; for me, and manages it, and I’m up and running.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To work on existing projects, I clone a repository and either run &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;pipenv install&lt;/tt&gt; (for projects that already have a &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;Pipfile&lt;/tt&gt;), or &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;pipenv install &lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;-r&lt;/span&gt; requirements.txt&lt;/tt&gt; (which as a side-effect automatically converts a the requirements file to a &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;Pipfile&lt;/tt&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I need to switch Python versions, I run &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;pyenv local &amp;lt;version&amp;gt;&lt;/tt&gt; in my project directory. I can also add:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;literal-block&quot;&gt;
[requires]
python_version = &quot;&amp;lt;version&amp;gt;&quot;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;to my &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;Pipfile&lt;/tt&gt;, and &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;pipenv&lt;/tt&gt; will enforce that version requirement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I want to install &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;CLI&lt;/span&gt; stuff, I use pipsi:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;literal-block&quot;&gt;
pipsi install awscli
pipsi install doc2dash
# ... etc
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes time to deploy, both Heroku and &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://cloud.gov/&quot;&gt;cloud.gov&lt;/a&gt; will read and understand my &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;Pipfile&lt;/tt&gt;. If I need to deploy to something that doesn’t do &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;Pipfile&lt;/tt&gt;-based installs, I create a &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;requirements.txt&lt;/tt&gt; by running &lt;tt class=&quot;docutils literal&quot;&gt;pipenv lock &lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;--requirements&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/tt&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 17:23:52 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>craigkerstiens</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://jacobian.org/writing/python-environment-2018/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Robinhood Opens Cryptocurrency Trading</title>
<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-02-22/line-gets-longer-at-robinhood-as-cryptocurrency-trading-begins</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-02-22/line-gets-longer-at-robinhood-as-cryptocurrency-trading-begins</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;More than 4 million people have signed up to open accounts at Robinhood Markets Inc. as the brokerage app begins offering commission-free trading of Bitcoin and Ethereum today for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The Palo Alto, California-based firm, which first gained traction by offering a free stock-trading app, said last month that it was getting into digital assets. Trading in the two largest cryptocurrencies is available to users in California, Massachusetts, Missouri, Montana and New Hampshire. The startup aims offer the service in most U.S. states by midyear.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Robinhood had signed up 2 million users as of April, a figure it saw jump to 3 million in November and skyrocket since saying it would offer crypto trading.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;lazy-img-324251404&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/ifLhY96dL4vo/v2/60x-1.png&quot; data-native-src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/ifLhY96dL4vo/v2/-1x-1.png&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img__image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This gives another financial technology startup and popular digital currency exchange, Coinbase Inc., a new competitor. It’s unclear how many of these new accounts either moved from Coinbase or have accounts at both startups, but each firm is targeting a similar demographic. According to a recent survey, more than half of Bitcoin holders are between the ages of 18 and 34. Robinhood said its average customer is 30. When comparing the user bases, Coinbase had 13 million users as of late &lt;a itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-01-25/robinhood-is-adding-bitcoin-and-other-cryptocurrency-trading&quot; title=&quot;Robinhood Is Adding Bitcoin and Other Cryptocurrency Trading (1)&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;last year&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Anyone that uses the Robinhood platform to buy Bitcoin or Ethereum today comes into a market that has lost roughly half of its value over the past couple of months. After nearly touching $20,000 in December, Bitcoin recently dropped below $10,000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For more on cryptocurrencies, check out the &lt;em&gt;Decrypted&lt;/em&gt; podcast:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 16:48:13 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>rayuela</dc:creator>
<og:description>More than 4 million people have signed up to open accounts at Robinhood Markets Inc. as the brokerage app begins offering commission-free trading of Bitcoin and Ethereum today for the first time.</og:description>
<og:image>https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/i4_xPQCbyJuU/v0/1200x800.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>Robinhood Opens Cryptocurrency Trading</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-02-22/line-gets-longer-at-robinhood-as-cryptocurrency-trading-begins</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-02-22/line-gets-longer-at-robinhood-as-cryptocurrency-trading-begins</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>A Global Optimization Algorithm Worth Using</title>
<link>http://blog.dlib.net/2017/12/a-global-optimization-algorithm-worth.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://blog.dlib.net/2017/12/a-global-optimization-algorithm-worth.html</guid>
<description>Here is a common problem: you have some machine learning algorithm you want to use but it has these damn &lt;em&gt;hyperparameters&lt;/em&gt;. These are numbers like weight decay magnitude, Gaussian kernel width, and so forth. The algorithm doesn't set them, instead, it's up to you to determine their values. If you don't set these parameters to &quot;good&quot; values the algorithm doesn't work. So what do you do? Well, here is a list of everything I've seen people do, listed in order of most to least common:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Guess and Check&lt;/strong&gt;: Listen to your gut, pick numbers that feel good and see if they work. Keep doing this until you are tired of doing it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grid Search&lt;/strong&gt;: Ask your computer to try a bunch of values spread evenly over some range.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Random Search&lt;/strong&gt;: Ask your computer to try a bunch of values by picking them randomly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bayesian Optimization&lt;/strong&gt;: Use a tool like MATLAB's &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mathworks.com/help/stats/bayesopt.html&quot;&gt;bayesopt&lt;/a&gt; to automatically pick the best parameters, then find out Bayesian Optimization has more hyperparameters than your machine learning algorithm, get frustrated, and go back to using guess and check or grid search.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Local Optimization With a Good Initial Guess&lt;/strong&gt;: This is what &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mit-nlp/MITIE&quot;&gt;MITIE&lt;/a&gt; does, it uses the &lt;a href=&quot;http://dlib.net/optimization.html#find_min_bobyqa&quot;&gt;BOBYQA&lt;/a&gt; algorithm with a well chosen starting point. Since BOBYQA only finds the nearest &lt;em&gt;local&lt;/em&gt; optima the success of this method is heavily dependent on a good starting point. In MITIE's case we know a good starting point, but this isn't a general solution since usually you won't know a good starting point. On the plus side, this kind of method is extremely good at finding a local optima. I'll have more to say on this later.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div&gt;The vast majority of people just do guess and check. That sucks and there should be something better. We all want some black-box optimization strategy like Bayesian optimization to be useful, but in my experience, if you don't set its hyperparameters to the right values it doesn't work as well as an expert doing guess and check. Everyone I know who has used Bayesian optimization has had the same experience. Ultimately, if I think I can do better hyperparameter selection manually then that's what I'm going to do, and most of my colleagues feel the same way. The end result is that I don't use automated hyperparameter selection tools most of the time, and that bums me out. I badly want a parameter-free global optimizer that I can trust to do hyperparameter selection.&lt;p&gt;So I was very excited when I encountered the paper &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1703.02628&quot;&gt;Global optimization of Lipschitz functions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; by Cédric Malherbe and Nicolas Vayatis in this year's international conference on machine learning. In this paper, they propose a very simple &lt;em&gt;parameter-free and provably correct method&lt;/em&gt; for finding the $x \in \mathbb{R}^d$ that maximizes a function, $f(x)$, even if $f(x)$ has many local maxima. The key idea in their paper is to maintain a piecewise linear upper bound of $f(x)$ and use that to decide which $x$ to evaluate at each step of the optimization. So if you already evaluated the points $x_1, x_2, \cdots, x_t$ then you can define a simple upper bound on $f(x)$ like this:&lt;br/&gt;\[ \newcommand{\norm}[1]{\left\lVert#1\right\rVert} U(x) = \min_{i=1\dots t} (f(x_i) + k \cdot \norm{x-x_i}_2 ) \] Where $k$ is the Lipschitz constant for $f(x)$. Therefore, it is trivially true that $U(x) \geq f(x), \forall x$, by the definition of the Lipschitz constant. The authors go on to suggest a simple algorithm, called LIPO, that picks points at random, checks if the upper bound for the new point is better than the best point seen so far, and if so selects it as the next point to evaluate. For example, the figure below shows a plot of a simple $f(x)$ in red with a plot of its associated upper bound $U(x)$ in green. In this case $U(x)$ is defined by 4 points, indicated here with little black squares.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-J6B_BQWCR8o/WkFzO5qfFyI/AAAAAAAAA18/slBcjvnaupoNUlueG-I_V9BVxAwWfGDQwCEwYBhgL/s1600/g4175.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;It shouldn't take a lot of imagination to see how the upper bound helps you pick good points to evaluate. For instance, if you selected the max upper bound as the next iterate you would already get pretty close to the global maximizer. The authors go on to prove a bunch of nice properties of this method. In particular, they both prove mathematically and show empirically that the method is better than random search in a number of non-trivial situations. This is a fairly strong statement considering how competitive &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jmlr.org/papers/v13/bergstra12a.html&quot;&gt;random hyperparameter search&lt;/a&gt; turns out to be relative to competing hyperparameter optimization methods. They also compare the method to other algorithms like Bayesian optimization and show that it's competitive.&lt;p&gt;But you are probably thinking: &quot;Hold on a second, we don't know the value of the Lipschitz constant $k$!&quot;. This isn't a big deal since it's easily estimated, for instance, by setting $k$ to the largest observed slope of $f(x)$ before each iteration. That's equivalent to solving the following easy problem:&lt;br/&gt;\begin{align}&lt;br/&gt;\min_{k} &amp;amp; \quad k^2 \\&lt;br/&gt;\text{s.t.} &amp;amp; \quad U(x_i) \geq f(x_i), \quad \forall i \in [1\dots t] \\&lt;br/&gt;&amp;amp; \quad k \geq 0&lt;br/&gt;\end{align} Malherbe et al. test a variant of this $k$ estimation approach and show it works well.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is great. I love this paper. It's proposing a global optimization method called LIPO that is both parameter free and provably better than random search. It's also really simple. Reading this paper gives you one of those &quot;duah&quot; moments where you wonder why you didn't think of this a long time ago. That's the mark of a great paper. So obviously I was going to add some kind of LIPO algorithm to dlib, which I did in the recent &lt;a href=&quot;http://dlib.net/release_notes.html&quot;&gt;dlib v19.8 release&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, if you want to use LIPO in practice there are some issues that need to be addressed. The rest of this blog post discusses these issues and how the dlib implementation addresses them. First, if $f(x)$ is noisy or discontinuous even a little it's not going to work reliably since $k$ will be infinity. This happens in real world situations all the time. For instance, evaluating a binary classifier against the 0-1 loss gives you an objective function with little discontinuities anywhere samples switch their predicted class. You could cross your fingers and run LIPO anyway, but you run the very real risk of two $x$ samples closely straddling a discontinuity and causing the estimated $k$ to explode. Second, not all hyperparameters are equally important, some hardly matter while small changes in others drastically affect the output of $f(x)$. So it would be nice if each hyperparameter got its own $k$. You can address these problems by defining the upper bound $U(x)$ as follows:&lt;br/&gt;\[ U(x) = \min_{i=1\dots t} \left[ f(x_i) + \sqrt{\sigma_i +(x-x_i)^\intercal K (x-x_i)} \ \right] \] Now each sample from $f(x)$ has its own noise term, $\sigma_i$, which should be 0 most of the time unless $x_i$ is really close to a discontinuity or there is some stochasticity. Here, $K$ is a diagonal matrix that contains our &quot;per hyperparameter Lipschitz $k$ terms&quot;. With this formulation, setting each $\sigma$ to 0 and $K=k^2I$ gives the same $U(x)$ as suggested by Malherbe et al., but if we let them take more general values we can deal with the above mentioned problems.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Just like before, we can find the parameters of $U(x)$ by solving an optimization problem:&lt;br/&gt;\begin{align}&lt;br/&gt;\min_{K,\sigma} &amp;amp; \quad \norm{K}^2_F + 10^6 \sum_{i=1}^t {\sigma_i^2} &amp;amp;\\&lt;br/&gt;\text{s.t.} &amp;amp; \quad U(x_i) \geq f(x_i), &amp;amp; \quad \forall i \in [1\dots t] \\&lt;br/&gt;&amp;amp; \quad \sigma_i \geq 0 &amp;amp; \quad \forall i \in [1\dots t] \\&lt;br/&gt;&amp;amp; \quad K_{i,j} \geq 0 &amp;amp; \quad \forall i,j \in [1\dots d] \\&lt;br/&gt;&amp;amp; \quad \text{K is a diagonal matrix}&lt;br/&gt;\end{align} The $10^6$ penalty on $\sigma^2$ causes most $\sigma$ terms to be exactly 0. The behavior of the whole algorithm is insensitive to the particular penalty value used here, so long as it's reasonably large the $\sigma$ values will be 0 most of the time while still preventing $k$ from becoming infinite, which is the behavior we want. It's also possible to rewrite this as a big quadratic programming problem and solve it with a dual coordinate descent method. I'm not going into the details here. It's all in the dlib code for those really interested. The TL;DR is that it turns out to be easy to solve using well known methods and it fixes the infinite $k$ problem.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The final issue that needs to be addressed is LIPO's terrible convergence in the area of a local maximizer. So while it's true that LIPO is great at getting onto the tallest peak of $f(x)$, once you are there it does not make very rapid progress towards the optimal location (i.e. the very top of the peak). This is a problem shared by many &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Derivative-free_optimization&quot;&gt;derivative free optimization&lt;/a&gt; algorithms, including MATLAB's Bayesian optimization tool. Fortunately, not all methods have this limitation. In particular, the late and great &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Michael_J._D._Powell&quot;&gt;Michael J. D. Powell&lt;/a&gt; wrote a series of papers on how to apply classic trust region methods to derivative free optimization. These methods fit a quadratic surface around the best point seen so far and then take the next iterate to be the maximizer of that quadratic surface within some distance of the current best point. So we &quot;trust&quot; this local quadratic model to be accurate within some small region around the best point, hence the name &quot;trust region&quot;. The BOBYQA method I mentioned above is one of these methods and it has excellent convergence to the nearest local optima, easily finding local optima to full floating point precision in a very small number of steps.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We can fix LIPO's convergence problem by combining these two methods, LIPO will explore $f(x)$ and quickly find a point on the biggest peak. Then a Powell style trust region method can efficiently find the exact maximizer of that peak. The simplest way to combine these two things is to alternate between them, which is what dlib does. On even iterations we pick the next $x$ according to our upper bound while on odd iterations we pick the next $x$ according to the trust region model. I've also used a slightly different version of LIPO that I'm calling MaxLIPO. Recall that Malherbe et al. suggest selecting any point with an upper bound larger than the current best objective value. However, I've found that selecting the maximum upper bounding point on each iteration is slightly better. This alternative version, MaxLIPO, is therefore what dlib uses. You can see this hybrid of MaxLIPO and a trust region method in action in the following video:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;center&gt;Video of optimizer running&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;In the video, the red line is the function to be optimized and we are looking for the maximum point. Every time the algorithm samples a point from the function we note it with a little box. The state of the solver is determined by the global upper bound $U(x)$ and the local quadratic model used by the trust region method. Therefore, we draw the upper bounding model as well as the current local quadratic model so you can see how they evolve as the optimization proceeds. We also note the location of the best point seen so far by a little vertical line.&lt;p&gt;You can see that the optimizer is alternating between picking the maximum upper bounding point and the maximum point according to the quadratic model. As the optimization proceeds, the upper bound becomes progressively more accurate, helping to find the best peak to investigate, while the quadratic model quickly finds a high precision maximizer on whatever peak it currently rests. These two things together allow the optimizer to find the true global maximizer to high precision (within $\pm{10^{-9}}$ in this case) by the time the video concludes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;table align=&quot;center&quot; cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;tr-caption-container&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/--GyQIadmxhU/WkF01s5kHVI/AAAAAAAAA2I/AFGIKZJhqlMAdfh_Y1YoHAxFbDYWtwaWACLcBGAs/s1600/page1-800px-Holder_table_function.pdf.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;600&quot; data-original-width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/--GyQIadmxhU/WkF01s5kHVI/AAAAAAAAA2I/AFGIKZJhqlMAdfh_Y1YoHAxFbDYWtwaWACLcBGAs/s400/page1-800px-Holder_table_function.pdf.jpg&quot; width=&quot;400&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tr-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;The Holder Table Test Function&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;from https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Holder_table_function.pdf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Now let's do an experiment to see how this hybrid of MaxLIPO and Powell's trust region method (TR) compares to MATLAB's Bayesian optimization tool with its default settings. I ran both algorithms on the Holder table test function 100 times and plotted the average error with one standard deviation error bars. So the plot below shows $f(x^\star)-f(x_i)$, the difference between the true global optimum and the best solution found so far, as a function of the number of calls to $f(x)$. You can see that MATLAB's BayesOpt stalls out at an accuracy of about $\pm{10^{-3}}$ while our hybrid method (MaxLIPO+TR, the new method in dlib) quickly approaches full floating point precision of around $\pm{10^{-17}}$.&lt;br/&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;



&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-Yo31249Ta0s/WkEPvou7SWI/AAAAAAAAA0o/O0rkQR5ar8cOpKmzTEq_KSq4af_xZTUCQCLcBGAs/s1600/bayesopt_vs_lipo.svg.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;I also reran some of the tests from Figure 5 of the LIPO paper. The results are shown in the table below. In these experiments I compared the performance of LIPO with and without the trust region solver (LIPO+TR and LIPO). Additionally, to verify that LIPO is better than pure random search I tested a version of the algorithm that alternates between pure random search and the trust region solver (PRS+TR) rather than alternating between a LIPO method and a trust region solver (LIPO+TR and MaxLIPO+TR). Pure random search (PRS) is also included for reference. Finally, the new algorithm implemented in dlib, MaxLIPO+TR, is included as well. In each test I ran the algorithm 1000 times and recorded the mean and standard deviation of the number of calls to $f(x)$ required to reach a particular solution accuracy. For instance, $\epsilon=0.01$ means that $f(x^\star)-f(x_i) \leq 0.01$, while &quot;target 99%&quot; uses the &quot;target&quot; metric from Malherbe's paper, which for most tests corresponds to an $\epsilon &amp;gt; 0.1$. Tests that took too long to execute are noted with a - symbol.&lt;p&gt;The key points to notice about these results are that the addition of a trust region method allows LIPO to reach much higher solution accuracy. It also makes the algorithm run faster. Recall that LIPO works internally by using random search of $U(x)$. Therefore, the number of calls LIPO makes to $U(x)$ is at least as many as PRS would require when searching $f(x)$. So for smaller $\epsilon$ it becomes very expensive to execute LIPO. For instance, I wasn't able to get results for LIPO, by itself, at accuracies better than $0.1$ on any of the test problems since it took too long to execute. However, with a trust region method the combined algorithm can easily achieve high precision solutions. The other significant detail is that, for tests with many local optima, all methods combining LIPO with TR are much better than PRS+TR. This is most striking on ComplexHolder, which is a version of the HolderTable test function with additional high frequency sinusoidal noise that significantly increases the number of local optima. On ComplexHolder, LIPO based methods require about an order of magnitude fewer calls to $f(x)$ than PRS+TR, further justifying the claims by Malherbe et al. of the superiority of LIPO relative to pure random search.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://dlib.net/find_max_global_results_table.svg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;The new method in dlib, MaxLIPO+TR, fares the best in all my tests. What is remarkable about this method is its simplicity. In particular, &lt;strong&gt;MaxLIPO+TR doesn't have any hyperparameters, making it very easy to use.&lt;/strong&gt; I've been using it for a while now for hyperparameter optimization and have been very pleased. It's the first black-box hyperparameter optimization algorithm I've had enough confidence in to use on real problems.&lt;p&gt;Finally, here is an example of how you can use this new optimizer from Python:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;holder_table&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;):&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;abs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;sin&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;cos&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;exp&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;abs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;sqrt&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;pi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)))&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;y&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;dlib&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;find_min_global&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;holder_table&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
                           &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;],&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;# Lower bound constraints on x0 and x1 respectively&lt;/span&gt;
                           &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;],&lt;/span&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;# Upper bound constraints on x0 and x1 respectively&lt;/span&gt;
                           &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;80&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;# The number of times find_min_global() will call holder_table()&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
Or in C++11:
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span&gt;auto&lt;/span&gt; holder_table &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; []&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;u&gt;double&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/span&gt; x0, &lt;span&gt;&lt;u&gt;double&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/span&gt; x1&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;strong&gt;{&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;abs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;sin&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;x0&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;cos&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;x1&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;exp&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;abs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;sqrt&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;x0&lt;span&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;x0&lt;span&gt;+&lt;/span&gt;x1&lt;span&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;x1&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;pi&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;;&lt;strong&gt;}&lt;/strong&gt;;

&lt;span&gt;// obtain result.x and result.y
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;auto&lt;/span&gt; result &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;find_min_global&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;holder_table, 
                             &lt;strong&gt;{&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;,&lt;span&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;}&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;span&gt;// lower bounds
&lt;/span&gt;                             &lt;strong&gt;{&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;,&lt;span&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;}&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;span&gt;// upper bounds
&lt;/span&gt;                             &lt;span&gt;max_function_calls&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;80&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;Both of these methods find holder_table's global optima to about 12 digits of precision in about 0.1 seconds. The C++ API exposes a wide range of ways to call the solver, including optimizing multiple functions at a time and adding integer constraints. &lt;a href=&quot;http://dlib.net/optimization.html#find_max_global&quot;&gt;See the documentation for full details&lt;/a&gt;.
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 16:17:02 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>blt</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://blog.dlib.net/2017/12/a-global-optimization-algorithm-worth.html</og:url>
<og:title>A Global Optimization Algorithm Worth Using</og:title>
<og:description>Here is a common problem: you have some machine learning algorithm you want to use but it has these damn  hyperparameters . These are number...</og:description>
<og:image>https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-J6B_BQWCR8o/WkFzO5qfFyI/AAAAAAAAA18/slBcjvnaupoNUlueG-I_V9BVxAwWfGDQwCEwYBhgL/w1200-h630-p-k-no-nu/g4175.png</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://blog.dlib.net/2017/12/a-global-optimization-algorithm-worth.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Hacker News&amp;#039;s Undocumented Features and Behaviors</title>
<link>https://github.com/minimaxir/hacker-news-undocumented</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/minimaxir/hacker-news-undocumented</guid>
<description>&lt;h3&gt;README.md&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;markdown-body entry-content&quot; itemprop=&quot;text&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Hacker News&lt;/a&gt;, a simple link aggregator owned and operated by Silicon Valley startup incubator &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ycombinator.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Y Combinator&lt;/a&gt;, has had many &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16409768&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;positive effects&lt;/a&gt; on SV startups and engineers as a whole. On Hacker News, users receive Karma whenever another user upvotes a submission or comment they made, which incentives positive contributions to the community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, in maintaining its simplicity, many new features and behaviors added over the years on Hacker News are not fully documented other than the &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=12073675&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;occasional&lt;/a&gt; comments from staff. This list details some of the hidden norms about Hacker News not otherwise covered in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/newsguidelines.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/newsfaq.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;FAQ&lt;/a&gt;, along with a few bonus features outside of typical HN usage. If there is anything missing/incorrect from this list, feel free to file a GitHub issue/PR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This list has no affiliation with Hacker News, Y Combinator, or any YC-backed company.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Undocumented Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Moderators&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hacker News currently has two full time moderators: Dan Gackle (&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/user?id=dang&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;dang&lt;/a&gt;) and Scott Bell (&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/user?id=sctb&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;sctb&lt;/a&gt;). Their &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/threads?id=dang&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;comment&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/threads?id=sctb&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;replies&lt;/a&gt; provide a pseudo-log of Hacker News moderation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both are very responsive when contacted at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:hn@ycombinator.com&quot;&gt;hn@ycombinator.com&lt;/a&gt;, and is the best option for resolving any issues on Hacker News.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Downvoting Comments&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All comments start with a score of 1 point (but in order to prevent bandwagoning, the comment score is not visible to users other than the author). After users reach &lt;strong&gt;501 Karma&lt;/strong&gt;, they gain the ability to downvote another comment. Downvoted comments (i.e. with a score &amp;lt; 1) reduce their placement on the comment thread and will appear desaturated to other users deemphasize them. There is no upper limit on the score of a comment, but the minimum score is -4 points.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/minimaxir/hacker-news-undocumented/blob/master/images/hn_downvotes.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/minimaxir/hacker-news-undocumented/raw/master/images/hn_downvotes.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Complaining about being downvoted is discouraged and usually results in even more downvotes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the comment desaturation makes Hacker News difficult to read, you can install the CSS extension &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16426569&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;discussed here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Flagging/Vouching&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a user has &lt;strong&gt;30 Karma&lt;/strong&gt;, they can flag submissions. Although submissions cannot be downvoted, flags act as a &quot;super&quot; downvote and enough flags will strongly reduce the rank of the submission, or kill it entirely (flagging is &lt;em&gt;supposed&lt;/em&gt; to be used for submissions which are spam/off-topic, but that isn't always the case in practice). A submission that's flagged to death will have a &lt;code&gt;[flagged]&lt;/code&gt; tag. Comments behave similarly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In contrast, a &lt;code&gt;[dead]&lt;/code&gt; submission is either killed by a moderator or by the software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a user has &lt;strong&gt;30 Karma&lt;/strong&gt;, they can also &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.ycombinator.com/two-hn-announcements/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;vouch&lt;/a&gt; for a &lt;code&gt;[flagged]&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;[dead]&lt;/code&gt; submission/comment. A vouched submission/comment has its rank restored, but it can be &lt;code&gt;[flagged]&lt;/code&gt; again at which point it can't be re-vouched.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Setting top color&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a user has &lt;strong&gt;250 Karma&lt;/strong&gt;, they can set the color of the top bar in their profile settings. The default is #ff6600. Here's the &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/topcolors&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;complete set&lt;/a&gt; of colors users have set.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Duplicate Submissions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hacker News encourages a single discussion on a given story. All others are marked as a &lt;code&gt;[dupe]&lt;/code&gt; and will be killed without the ability to vouch. This includes articles which are insubstantial variations of an earlier widely-discussed submission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Anti-Voting Manipulation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The FAQ states &quot;users should vote for a story because they personally find it intellectually interesting, not because someone has content to promote.&quot; Indeed, Hacker News &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=7972941&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;utilizes&lt;/a&gt; a voting ring detector which will prevent caught submissions from hitting the front page. Due to sites like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.producthunt.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Product Hunt&lt;/a&gt; normalizing the asking for upvotes or other engagement via social media, the implicit asking of upvotes is also done for Hacker News, usually due to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/minimaxir/status/958397508996055040&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;ignorance&lt;/a&gt; of the Hacker News rule against it. There are very few good reasons to draw attention to a Hacker News submission immediately after it has been submitted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One popular &quot;trick&quot; for obfuscating voting manipulation on Hacker News is to link to the Hacker News's &lt;code&gt;/newest&lt;/code&gt; page of new submissions (instead of a direct link which would otherwise make voting manipulation obvious), and asking friends to upvote the submission from that page. This trick doesn't actually work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Flame-War Detector&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The FAQ notes that submission rank is impacted by &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16020089&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;software which downweights overheated discussions&lt;/a&gt;.&quot; A good rule of thumb for this effect is when the number of comments on a submission exceeds its score. Moderators can overrule the downranking for appropriate, not-actually-a-flame-war discussions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Second-Chance Pool&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moderators will sometimes &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=11662380&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;rescue a post&lt;/a&gt; which didn't receive a lot of upvotes and reset the submission time on the post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Relatedly, moderators can also &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=10308900&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;invite users&lt;/a&gt; via email to resubmit a post which didn't get much traction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Edit/Delete Time Limits&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a post or comment is made, it can be edited by the author &lt;strong&gt;within 2 hours&lt;/strong&gt;. A post/comment can be deleted by the author within those two hours, &lt;strong&gt;but only if it has no replies&lt;/strong&gt;, in order to prevent discussion from being lost. In that case, the post/comment &lt;strong&gt;cannot be deleted&lt;/strong&gt; (This can result in a fake &lt;code&gt;[deleted]&lt;/code&gt; edit if a person wants to remove their comment in the limit but can't).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you need something deleted but you can't, you'll have to message &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:hn@ycombinator.com&quot;&gt;hn@ycombinator.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Comment Collapsing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments can be collapsed by clicking the &lt;code&gt;[+]&lt;/code&gt; icon to improve readability.&lt;code&gt;[flagged]&lt;/code&gt; comments are collapsed by default, and moderators can set a comment to automatically be collapsed if necessary (e.g. meta-discussion).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Shadowbanning&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both users and domains can be shadowbanned, where all posts/comments by that user / submissions to that domain will be instantly &lt;code&gt;[dead]&lt;/code&gt; and cannot receive votes/comments (but can still be vouched). A good way to tell if a user/domain is banned is to either have another user with &lt;code&gt;showdead&lt;/code&gt; enabled check for a series of &lt;code&gt;[dead]&lt;/code&gt; content from that source, or view those submissions in Private Browsing/Incognito mode to see if they appear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/minimaxir/hacker-news-undocumented/blob/master/images/shadowban.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/minimaxir/hacker-news-undocumented/raw/master/images/shadowban.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users/domains are usually shadowbanned for breaking HN rules/spam. If you feel you are unfairly shadowbanned, contact &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:hn@ycombinator.com&quot;&gt;hn@ycombinator.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Green Usernames&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Accounts which are less than &lt;strong&gt;2 weeks&lt;/strong&gt; old will appear with a green username.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Behaviors&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Implicit Downranking of Politics&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Guidelines state that political discussion is off-topic. However, as of recently, the line between technology and politics has become &lt;em&gt;extremely&lt;/em&gt; blurred. Most tech related submissions with a hint of political partisanship will quickly be flagged to death by users (or die a slow death due to the inevitable flame war).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Implicit Downranking of topics around Diversity and Inclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Likewise, topics around diversity and inclusion in tech have gained lots of visibility over the past few years. However, despite these discussions not being off-topic, they tend to be flagged to death by users regardless. Unfortunately. (Moderators occasionally unkill such threads if they see it in time, although it rarely sticks).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Paywalls&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many news websites have started implementing a paywall for their content, which has caused conflict with Hacker News's &quot;original source&quot; rule. The &lt;code&gt;web&lt;/code&gt; button next to submissions (that does a Google search for the given title) was partially intended to serve as a paywall workaround; however, recent changes to the paywall implementations have closed that loophole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result, submissions which link to paywalled sites tend to get many comments complaining about paywalls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Perceived Favoritism Toward YC Companies&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;YC Companies get two notable benefits on Hacker News; they can post jobs ads to the front page (which start of at Rank #6, cannot be voted/commented on, and have a fixed decay rate), and the ability to do a &lt;a href=&quot;https://hn.algolia.com/?query=Launch%20HN&amp;amp;sort=byPopularity&amp;amp;prefix=false&amp;amp;page=0&amp;amp;dateRange=all&amp;amp;type=story&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Launch HN&lt;/a&gt; when their startup launches out of a YC batch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, there is no evidence that non-job submissions about a YC startup receive preferential treatment on the front page, or kill submissions critical of a YC startup. In fact, the moderators have stated that they explicitly &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=8258752&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;avoid killing controversial YC posts&lt;/a&gt; when possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, founders of YC companies see each other's usernames &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2013/05/18/the-evolution-of-hacker-news/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;show up in orange,&lt;/a&gt; which--although not an explicit benefit--does allow fellow YC founders to immediately identify one another in discussions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Bonus Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Hacker News Classic&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hacker News allows people to use the &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/classic&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;old front page ranking algorithm&lt;/a&gt;. This results in different (and occasionally better) content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Hacker News Wayback&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hacker News allows users to see what the front page looks like &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/front?day=2012-03-24&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;at any point in time&lt;/a&gt;. You can also do a wayback view for any user at their registration date by clicking their registration date in their profile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Hacker News on BigQuery&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to gather large amount of Hacker News data for data analysis/machine learning, you should use the &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/bigquery/public-data/hacker-news&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Hacker News dataset on BigQuery&lt;/a&gt;, which is updated daily and is much more pragmatic to use than manually scraping data from the Hacker News API.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Hacker News Lists&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hacker News maintains a &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/lists&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;list of useful links&lt;/a&gt; that allow for primitive filtering by certain types of content. These currently include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/leaders&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;/leaders&lt;/a&gt; -- View a list of users with the most karma&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/front&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;/front&lt;/a&gt; -- Filter front page submissions for a given day (e.g. 2016-06-20), ordered by time spent there&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/best&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;/best&lt;/a&gt; -- View the highest-voted recent links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/active&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;/active&lt;/a&gt; -- View the links with the most active current discussions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;/bestcomments&lt;/a&gt; -- List the highest-voted recent comments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/noobstories&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;/noobstories&lt;/a&gt; -- Show submissions from new accounts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/noobcomments&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;/noobcomments&lt;/a&gt; -- List comments from new accounts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;This list is currently missing these additional links:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Filter out posts below a set number of votes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Want to catch-up on the best submissions over the last few days? Filter out all posts below a certain threshold with &lt;code&gt;over?points=100&lt;/code&gt;. Examples:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;To-Do&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Add more images/citations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Maintainer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Max Woolf (&lt;a href=&quot;http://minimaxir.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@minimaxir&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/user?id=minimaxir&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;minimaxir&lt;/a&gt; on Hacker News since 2012)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Max has no affiliation with Hacker News, Y Combinator, or any YC-backed company.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 15:04:14 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>minimaxir</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars0.githubusercontent.com/u/2179708?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>minimaxir/hacker-news-undocumented</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/minimaxir/hacker-news-undocumented</og:url>
<og:description>hacker-news-undocumented - This list details some of the hidden norms about Hacker News not otherwise covered in the Guidelines and the FAQ.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/minimaxir/hacker-news-undocumented</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The reason Facebook won’t ever change</title>
<link>https://om.co/2018/02/20/the-1-reason-facebook-wont-ever-change/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://om.co/2018/02/20/the-1-reason-facebook-wont-ever-change/</guid>
<description>&lt;img width=&quot;680&quot; height=&quot;454&quot; src=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/om.co/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/engineering-bootcamp-e1519152457391.jpg?fit=680%2C454&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; class=&quot;attachment-large size-large wp-post-image&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/om.co/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/engineering-bootcamp-e1519152457391.jpg?w=1500&amp;amp;ssl=1 1500w, https://i0.wp.com/om.co/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/engineering-bootcamp-e1519152457391.jpg?w=1360&amp;amp;ssl=1 1360w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Facebook’s (much deserved) media nightmare continued this week when it came under criticism for spamming members who signed up for two-factor authentication. This was followed by charges that its Protect VPN software (based on its Onava CDN) was essentially corporate spyware. The collective outrage over Facebook and its actions might result in a lot of talk, but it won’t really change Facebook, its ethos, and its ethics. Let me explain!&lt;span id=&quot;more-889203&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;**&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few years ago, I wrote that &lt;a href=&quot;https://om.co/2011/02/11/change-is-good-but-its-also-really-hard/&quot;&gt;companies have a core genetic profile&lt;/a&gt; and it is tough for them to deviate from it. That DNA defines every action, reaction, and a strategic move made by a company. The DNA represents a company’s ethos — and to a large extent, its ethics. Microsoft was and will always be a desktop software company, albeit one that is doing its best to adapt to the cloud and data-centric world. It has turned its desktop offerings into smart revenue streams on the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google’s core DNA is search and engineering, though some would say engineering that is driven by the economics of search, which makes it hard for the company to see the world through any other lens. Apple’s lens is that of product, design, and experience. This allows it to make great phones and to put emphasis on privacy, but makes it hard for them to build data-informed services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook’s DNA is that of a social platform addicted to growth and engagement. At its very core, every policy, every decision, every strategy is based on growth (at any cost) and engagement (at any cost). More growth and more engagement means more data — which means the company can make more advertising dollars, which gives it a nosebleed valuation on the stock market, which in turn allows it to remain competitive and stay ahead of its rivals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-889214&quot; src=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/om.co/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/Screen-Shot-2018-02-16-at-11.53.34-AM.png?resize=680%2C352&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;680&quot; height=&quot;352&quot; srcset=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/om.co/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/Screen-Shot-2018-02-16-at-11.53.34-AM.png?w=2420&amp;amp;ssl=1 2420w, https://i2.wp.com/om.co/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/Screen-Shot-2018-02-16-at-11.53.34-AM.png?resize=300%2C155&amp;amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i2.wp.com/om.co/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/Screen-Shot-2018-02-16-at-11.53.34-AM.png?resize=768%2C397&amp;amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i2.wp.com/om.co/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/Screen-Shot-2018-02-16-at-11.53.34-AM.png?resize=1024%2C530&amp;amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i2.wp.com/om.co/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/Screen-Shot-2018-02-16-at-11.53.34-AM.png?resize=560%2C290&amp;amp;ssl=1 560w, https://i2.wp.com/om.co/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/Screen-Shot-2018-02-16-at-11.53.34-AM.png?resize=1250%2C647&amp;amp;ssl=1 1250w, https://i2.wp.com/om.co/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/Screen-Shot-2018-02-16-at-11.53.34-AM.png?resize=400%2C207&amp;amp;ssl=1 400w, https://i2.wp.com/om.co/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/Screen-Shot-2018-02-16-at-11.53.34-AM.png?w=1360&amp;amp;ssl=1 1360w, https://i2.wp.com/om.co/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/Screen-Shot-2018-02-16-at-11.53.34-AM.png?w=2040&amp;amp;ssl=1 2040w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px&quot; data-recalc-dims=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Just look at these charts and you start to see why Facebook is addicted to growth and engagement. Engagement gets attention, and attention is a zero-sum game. Time spent on Facebook (or Messenger, Instagram, or WhatsApp) means that’s attention &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; spent on Twitter, Snapchat, or anyone else who dares to compete with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-889215&quot; src=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/om.co/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/Screen-Shot-2018-02-16-at-11.53.49-AM.png?resize=680%2C352&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;680&quot; height=&quot;352&quot; srcset=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/om.co/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/Screen-Shot-2018-02-16-at-11.53.49-AM.png?w=2418&amp;amp;ssl=1 2418w, https://i0.wp.com/om.co/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/Screen-Shot-2018-02-16-at-11.53.49-AM.png?resize=300%2C155&amp;amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/om.co/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/Screen-Shot-2018-02-16-at-11.53.49-AM.png?resize=768%2C398&amp;amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/om.co/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/Screen-Shot-2018-02-16-at-11.53.49-AM.png?resize=1024%2C530&amp;amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/om.co/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/Screen-Shot-2018-02-16-at-11.53.49-AM.png?resize=560%2C290&amp;amp;ssl=1 560w, https://i0.wp.com/om.co/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/Screen-Shot-2018-02-16-at-11.53.49-AM.png?resize=1250%2C647&amp;amp;ssl=1 1250w, https://i0.wp.com/om.co/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/Screen-Shot-2018-02-16-at-11.53.49-AM.png?resize=400%2C207&amp;amp;ssl=1 400w, https://i0.wp.com/om.co/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/Screen-Shot-2018-02-16-at-11.53.49-AM.png?w=1360&amp;amp;ssl=1 1360w, https://i0.wp.com/om.co/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/Screen-Shot-2018-02-16-at-11.53.49-AM.png?w=2040&amp;amp;ssl=1 2040w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px&quot; data-recalc-dims=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Facebook’s challenge is that their most lucrative market — the US and Canada — are saturated. And to keep making money in these markets — already a ridiculous $27 in ARPU for the last three months of 2017 — they need us to give more time and attention to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2017 compared to 2016, the average price per ad increased by 29%, as compared with approximately 5% in 2016, and the number of ads delivered increased by 15%, as compared with approximately 50% in 2016. &lt;em&gt;(From Facebook’s 2017 10k filing)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a crisis situation for Facebook because it doesn’t make as much money from markets outside of the US and Canada. For the same three months, it made $2.54 in ARPU in Asia-Pacific, $1.86 in rest of the world, and $8.86 in Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-889213&quot; src=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/om.co/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/Screen-Shot-2018-02-16-at-1.26.11-PM.png?resize=680%2C351&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;680&quot; height=&quot;351&quot; srcset=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/om.co/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/Screen-Shot-2018-02-16-at-1.26.11-PM.png?w=2430&amp;amp;ssl=1 2430w, https://i2.wp.com/om.co/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/Screen-Shot-2018-02-16-at-1.26.11-PM.png?resize=300%2C155&amp;amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i2.wp.com/om.co/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/Screen-Shot-2018-02-16-at-1.26.11-PM.png?resize=768%2C396&amp;amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i2.wp.com/om.co/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/Screen-Shot-2018-02-16-at-1.26.11-PM.png?resize=1024%2C528&amp;amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i2.wp.com/om.co/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/Screen-Shot-2018-02-16-at-1.26.11-PM.png?resize=560%2C289&amp;amp;ssl=1 560w, https://i2.wp.com/om.co/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/Screen-Shot-2018-02-16-at-1.26.11-PM.png?resize=1250%2C645&amp;amp;ssl=1 1250w, https://i2.wp.com/om.co/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/Screen-Shot-2018-02-16-at-1.26.11-PM.png?resize=400%2C206&amp;amp;ssl=1 400w, https://i2.wp.com/om.co/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/Screen-Shot-2018-02-16-at-1.26.11-PM.png?w=1360&amp;amp;ssl=1 1360w, https://i2.wp.com/om.co/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/Screen-Shot-2018-02-16-at-1.26.11-PM.png?w=2040&amp;amp;ssl=1 2040w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px&quot; data-recalc-dims=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-889212&quot; src=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/om.co/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/Screen-Shot-2018-02-16-at-1.26.51-PM.png?resize=680%2C353&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;680&quot; height=&quot;353&quot; srcset=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/om.co/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/Screen-Shot-2018-02-16-at-1.26.51-PM.png?w=2420&amp;amp;ssl=1 2420w, https://i0.wp.com/om.co/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/Screen-Shot-2018-02-16-at-1.26.51-PM.png?resize=300%2C156&amp;amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/om.co/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/Screen-Shot-2018-02-16-at-1.26.51-PM.png?resize=768%2C399&amp;amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/om.co/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/Screen-Shot-2018-02-16-at-1.26.51-PM.png?resize=1024%2C531&amp;amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/om.co/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/Screen-Shot-2018-02-16-at-1.26.51-PM.png?resize=560%2C291&amp;amp;ssl=1 560w, https://i0.wp.com/om.co/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/Screen-Shot-2018-02-16-at-1.26.51-PM.png?resize=1250%2C649&amp;amp;ssl=1 1250w, https://i0.wp.com/om.co/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/Screen-Shot-2018-02-16-at-1.26.51-PM.png?resize=400%2C208&amp;amp;ssl=1 400w, https://i0.wp.com/om.co/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/Screen-Shot-2018-02-16-at-1.26.51-PM.png?w=1360&amp;amp;ssl=1 1360w, https://i0.wp.com/om.co/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/Screen-Shot-2018-02-16-at-1.26.51-PM.png?w=2040&amp;amp;ssl=1 2040w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px&quot; data-recalc-dims=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;The ARPU numbers, especially in the US and Canada, explain why the company is publicly talking about the challenges of fake news and how it is trying to remove such news from users’ feeds — and instead refocusing on friends and their stuff. It has to make polite noises around fake news (aka spam) in order to get people back into the fold and staying on the site longer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t think this change of heart on the part of Facebook and Mark Zuckerberg is not altruistic. However, it &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; pretty evident that they are trying hard to get us back onto Facebook, and more often. At the same time, the company is running a campaign to burnish its image and come across as a company under siege, as outlined in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/story/inside-facebook-mark-zuckerberg-2-years-of-hell/&quot;&gt;recent Wired cover story&lt;/a&gt;. But Facebook isn’t the victim — it never is, and it never will be!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;**&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So now you know why Facebook does what it has been doing recently — sending various messages constantly to get you back on the service. I know first hand. I left Facebook on September 23, 2017, and not a single day has gone by when I don’t get at least a couple of emails or some SMS messages trying to get me back with notes about what friends have posted recently, or birthdays or other milestones. I keep unsubscribing and they still keep coming. Now I’ve set up a spam rule: all emails from Facebook.com go straight into the spam folder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook’s DNA also explains why it is pushing Protect (the VPN) and what it brings to the table. First of all, it allows the company to keep tabs on what apps people are using in different parts of the world, which in turn gives it a leg up on who or what to copy or, potentially, acquire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The VPN data also allows Facebook to better target its ads — much like how Google Mail and Google Chrome allows Google to better target what ads you see. By the way, Facebook isn’t the only one who is taking data from VPN mobile streams. Other data brokers buy data from other VPN apps. To be clear, just because others are doing it doesn’t make it right for Facebook to follow suit. I would love to see a US version of GDPR — a citizen data rights manifesto — to be put on the table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How does Protect help Facebook?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Protect can tell that you browsed H&amp;amp;M’s North American site, visited NYTimes.com, and bought groceries on Farmstead. It can figure out how much time you spend on various sites and services and start to build a better profile of your online usage for smarter ad targeting and to place you in more and more buckets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other words, Protect brings more granular and refined data into Facebook’s system, which in turn allows Facebook to refine its algorithms and become more efficient at targeting of ads. It is especially more useful in the Asia Pacific region and other emerging markets where it is pretty tricky to create buckets and hyper-targeting. Overseas users of Facebook are using the social platform on phones that are usually pre-paid phones and don’t have as much personalized information available from third party sources to create profiles. Facebook needs to find more high-value customers in the hordes of users in Asia, Africa, and LatAm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For 2017 , worldwide ARPU was $20.21 , an increase of 26% from 2016 . Over this period, ARPU increased by 41% in Europe, 36% in United States &amp;amp; Canada, 33% in Rest of World, and 22% in Asia-Pacific. &lt;em&gt;(From Facebook’s 2017 10k filing)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;**&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook’s ultimate goal is to make it expensive to buy hyper-personalized advertising — which is the Mount Olympus of advertising — and I am not surprised that Facebook is thinking about releasing touch screen smart speakers. It will be a great way to spy — sorry, I mean &lt;em&gt;acquire&lt;/em&gt; more continuous data about you and further bucket you for future ad targeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This helps keep the ARPU growing, which in turn means Facebook will keep making more money. More money, in turn, allows it to keep Wall Street happy, crush rivals, and suck up all the talent in the market. And yes, it will also &lt;a href=&quot;https://om.co/2018/02/16/facebooks-fake-account-problem-is-getting-bigger/&quot;&gt;accept fake accounts and spam on its platform&lt;/a&gt; even if it compromises elections, as long as it makes money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That may be a very simplified version of a sequence of events, but the fact of the matter is money and obsession with growth and engagement are what makes Facebook go around. That is embedded in its psyche, its DNA, and it will never change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook’s stated mission is to connect the world. They have already done that in the US, but their subsequent actions show that their real agenda is to extract user data — not strengthen connections. Just read their 10k filing and you’ll see it in black and white.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The increase in the ads delivered was driven by an increase in users and their engagement and an increase in the number and frequency of ads displayed on News Feed, partially offset by increasing user engagement with video content and other product changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook is about making money by keeping us addicted to Facebook. It always has been — and that’s why all of our angst and headlines are not going to change a damn thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-block sd-like jetpack-likes-widget-wrapper jetpack-likes-widget-unloaded&quot; id=&quot;like-post-wrapper-9440213-889203-5a8fc9f74c385&quot; data-src=&quot;https://widgets.wp.com/likes/#blog_id=9440213&amp;amp;post_id=889203&amp;amp;origin=om.co&amp;amp;obj_id=9440213-889203-5a8fc9f74c385&quot; data-name=&quot;like-post-frame-9440213-889203-5a8fc9f74c385&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Like this:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;likes-widget-placeholder post-likes-widget-placeholder&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;button&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Like&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;loading&quot;&gt;Loading...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 14:54:08 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>kawera</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>The #1 reason Facebook won’t ever change</og:title>
<og:url>https://om.co/2018/02/20/the-1-reason-facebook-wont-ever-change/</og:url>
<og:description>Facebook’s (much deserved) media nightmare continued this week when it came under criticism for spamming members who signed up for two-factor authentication. This was followed by charges that its P…</og:description>
<og:image>https://i0.wp.com/om.co/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/engineering-bootcamp-e1519152457391.jpg?fit=1200%2C800&amp;ssl=1</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://om.co/2018/02/20/the-1-reason-facebook-wont-ever-change/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Taiwan ban single-use plastic straws, plastic bags, disposable utensils by 2030</title>
<link>https://www.hongkongfp.com/2018/02/22/taiwan-ban-single-use-plastic-drinking-straws-plastic-bags-disposable-utensils-entirely-2030/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.hongkongfp.com/2018/02/22/taiwan-ban-single-use-plastic-drinking-straws-plastic-bags-disposable-utensils-entirely-2030/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Taiwan is set to ban single-use plastic drinking straws in several phases, starting with the food and beverage industry next year. The Environmental Protection Administration announced the plan last Tuesday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of next year, food and beverage stores such as fast food chains must stop providing plastic straws for in-store use. From 2020, free plastic straws will be banned from all food and beverage outlets. From 2025, the public will have to pay for takeaway plastic straws, and a blanket ban is to be imposed in 2030.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gcyberh gcyberh-3&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gcyberh-single acyberh-30&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;center/&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_150673&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-150673&quot; src=&quot;https://www.hongkongfp.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/1094104.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;plastic litter rubbish waste trash&quot; width=&quot;1050&quot; height=&quot;666&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.hongkongfp.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/1094104.jpg 1050w, https://www.hongkongfp.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/1094104-768x487.jpg 768w, https://www.hongkongfp.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/1094104-810x514.jpg 810w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1050px) 100vw, 1050px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;File photo: GovHK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Free plastic shopping bags, disposable food containers and disposable utensils will also be banned in 2020 from all retail stores that issue uniform invoices – widely used in Taiwan. Additional fees will also be imposed in 2025.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Minister Lee Ying-yuan said a blanket ban is set to be introduced in 2030 on all plastic bags, disposable utensils, and disposable beverage cups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_152848&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot; wp-image-152848&quot; src=&quot;https://www.hongkongfp.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/821316432371.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Lee Ying-yuan &quot; width=&quot;931&quot; height=&quot;422&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Lee Ying-yuan . Photo: Environmental Protection Administration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You can use steel products, or edible straws – or maybe you just don’t need to use straws at all,” he said. “There is no inconvenience caused at all.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lee said that the future prices for such disposable plastic items in stores will not necessarily be based on the price of such items in Europe, but will be based on prices in Taiwan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_152849&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-152849&quot; src=&quot;https://www.hongkongfp.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/sE_1870323031.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;steel straw&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;675&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.hongkongfp.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/sE_1870323031.jpg 900w, https://www.hongkongfp.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/sE_1870323031-768x576.jpg 768w, https://www.hongkongfp.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/sE_1870323031-810x608.jpg 810w, https://www.hongkongfp.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/sE_1870323031-632x474.jpg 632w, https://www.hongkongfp.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/sE_1870323031-536x402.jpg 536w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 900px) 100vw, 900px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Steel straws and cleaning tool. Photo: qc-tw.com.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He added that the reduction in the use of plastic is the responsibility of all members of the public rather than just his agency. The drive will create a better environment for future generations, he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yen Ning, Ocean Campaigner at Greenpeace East Asia, said she hoped bans on paper utensils and single-use chopsticks could be implemented in stages in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scotland is set to ban plastic straws by end of 2019, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.independent.co.uk/environment/scotland-plastic-straw-ban-pollution-2019-cotton-buds-a8206636.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;according&lt;/a&gt; to The Independent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Not-for-profit, run by journalists and completely independent. Contribute to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/HKFP2018&quot;&gt;our critical month-long HK$1m Funding Drive&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, help safeguard our independence and secure our operations for another year. Read how carefully we spend every cent &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/HKFP2017&quot;&gt;in our Annual/Transparency Report.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/HKFP2018&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-150987&quot; src=&quot;https://www.hongkongfp.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/2018-hkfp-promo-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2018 hkfp promo (2)&quot; width=&quot;1050&quot; height=&quot;276&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;gcyberh gcyberh-7&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gcyberh-single acyberh-50&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/2Ffv7AN&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.hongkongfp.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/sonar-festival-2018-hong-kong.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 13:43:53 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jacksmith21006</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Taiwan to ban single-use plastic drinking straws, plastic bags, disposable utensils entirely by 2030 | Hong Kong Free Press HKFP</og:title>
<og:description>Taiwan is set to ban single-use plastic drinking straws in several phases, starting with the food and beverage industry next year. The Environmental Protection Administration announced the plan last Tuesday. As of next year, food and beverage stores such as fast food chains must stop providing plastic straws for in-store use. …</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.hongkongfp.com/2018/02/22/taiwan-ban-single-use-plastic-drinking-straws-plastic-bags-disposable-utensils-entirely-2030/</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.hongkongfp.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/POWERPNT_2018-02-21_18-43-00.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-GB</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.hongkongfp.com/2018/02/22/taiwan-ban-single-use-plastic-drinking-straws-plastic-bags-disposable-utensils-entirely-2030/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>