<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>MF DOOM Has Died</title>
<link>https://consequenceofsound.net/2020/12/mf-doom-dead-obituary/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://consequenceofsound.net/2020/12/mf-doom-dead-obituary/</guid>
<description>&lt;div id=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://consequenceofsound.net/artist/mf-doom/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;MF DOOM&lt;/a&gt;, the British-born rapper and producer known for his masked “super villain” persona, expert rhyming abilities, and fondness for obscure pop culture samples, has died at the age of 49.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DOOM passed away on October 31st, but news of his death was only revealed today in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/mfdoom/posts/10160572598345884&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;statement&lt;/a&gt; issued by his wife, Jasmine. His cause of death was not disclosed.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The greatest husband, father, teacher, student, business partner, lover and friend I could ever ask for,” Jasmine wrote in a statement posted to Facebook. “Thank you for all the things you have shown, taught and given to me, our children and our family. Thank you for teaching me how to forgive beings and give another chance, not to be so quick to judge and write off. Thank you for showing how not to be afraid to love and be the best person I could ever be. My world will never be the same without you. Words will never express what you and Malachi mean to me, I love both and adore you always. May THE ALL continue to bless you, our family and the planet.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MF DOOM, whose real name was Daniel Dumile, was born in London, England on January 9th, 1971, the son of a Trinidadian mother and a Zimbabwean father. At the age of 17, after relocating to Long Island, New York, Daniel (performing under the name Zev Love X) teamed with his younger brother Dingilizwe Dumile (DJ Subroc) to form KMD. The hip-hop group — whose lineup was rounded out by Onyx the Birthstone Kid — experienced moderate success in the early 1990s. They made their debut in a guest capacity on 3rd Bass’ “The Gas Face”, and released their first album, &lt;em&gt;Mr. Hood&lt;/em&gt;, in 1991. Tragically, just before releasing their sophomore record, &lt;em&gt;Black Bastards&lt;/em&gt;, Subroc was struck by a car and killed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the death of his brother, Dumile relocated to Atlanta and took a three-year respite from music. In 1997, he returned to New York City, this time with a new persona — MF DOOM. Inspired by the Marvel Comics supervillain Doctor Doom, MF DOOM obscured his face by wearing a metal mask and began recording music built around obscure movie and TV samples. His solo debut as MF DOOM, &lt;em&gt;Operation: Doomsday&lt;/em&gt;, was released in 1999. Almost entirely self-produced, &lt;em&gt;Doomsday&lt;/em&gt; featured verbose bars and intricate rhymes over top elite crate-digger beats, crumbly guitars, and truncated disco samples. Two decade laters, it remains one of the most lauded and influential underground rap albums of all-time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the early 2000s, DOOM released a trio of albums under different monikers: &lt;em&gt;Take Me to Your Leader&lt;/em&gt;, released in June 2003, was attributed to the alias King Geedorah. Three months later, he returned with the first of two albums as Viktor Vaughn — &lt;em&gt;Vaudeville Villain&lt;/em&gt;. Its follow-up, &lt;em&gt;Venomous Villain&lt;/em&gt;, arrived a year later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;editors-picks&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Editors' Picks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2004 found DOOM at the height of his powers. He released the second MF DOOM album — &lt;em&gt;Mm..Food&lt;/em&gt; — an ambitious concept record which tied together the rapper’s obsessions with food and comic books alongside samples of Frank Zappa, Sade, and 1977’s &lt;em&gt;Fat Albert Halloween Special&lt;/em&gt;. Additionally, DOOM teamed up with Madlib for the debut release as &lt;em&gt;Madvillain, the widely-acclaimed &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Madvillainy&lt;/em&gt;. The album heavily sampled comic book and cartoon-centric sounds — including MF DOOM’s own namesake — in portraying DOOM and Madlib as master hip-hop villains, Lyrically, it was among DOOM’s finest performances, as he employed literary devices like multi-syllable and internal rhymes, alliteration, and double entendres.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2005, DOOM joined forces with Danger Mouse to form Danger Doom and released an album called &lt;em&gt;The Mouse and the Mask&lt;/em&gt;. He also appeared on the Gorillaz &lt;em&gt;Demon Days&lt;/em&gt; track, “November Has Come”, and produced several tracks for Ghostface Killah’s &lt;em&gt;Fishscale&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;More Fish&lt;/em&gt; albums.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DOOM’s last proper solo studio album came in 2009 with &lt;em&gt;Born Like This&lt;/em&gt;.  In the ensuing decade, his output ranged from collaborative projects with Jneiro Jarel, Bishop Nehru, and Westside Gunn to featured guest appearances on singles from Flying Lotus and The Avalanches. Earlier this year, he reunited with Bishop Nehru on &lt;a href=&quot;https://consequenceofsound.net/2020/04/bishop-nehru-mf-doom-new-song-meathead-stream/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;“Meathead”&lt;/a&gt; and partnered with BADBADNOTGOOD on &lt;a href=&quot;https://consequenceofsound.net/2020/12/mf-doom-badbadnotgood-the-chocolate-conquistadors-stream/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;“The Chocolate Conquistadors”&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adding to DOOM’s mystique was his disinterest in performing live. He only played a handful of shows over the course of his career, and even went as far to employe stand-ins to appear in place of him — which often got him into hot water with fans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He nonetheless remains a beloved and influential figure; upon hearing news of his passing, Q-Tip &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/QtipTheAbstract/status/1344760854324109320&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;referred&lt;/a&gt; to DOOM as “your favorite MC’s MC”. El-P of Run the Jewels &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/CJenegmj0X8/?utm_source=ig_embed&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;called&lt;/a&gt; DOOM a “writer’s writer” who “inspired us all and always will.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;embed-youtube&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe class=&quot;youtube-player&quot; width=&quot;806&quot; height=&quot;454&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/CRHyBwNtkLA?version=3&amp;amp;rel=1&amp;amp;showsearch=0&amp;amp;showinfo=1&amp;amp;iv_load_policy=1&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;hl=en-US&amp;amp;autohide=2&amp;amp;wmode=transparent&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; sandbox=&quot;allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;embed-youtube&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe class=&quot;youtube-player&quot; width=&quot;806&quot; height=&quot;454&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/-05kmeSkaB0?version=3&amp;amp;rel=1&amp;amp;showsearch=0&amp;amp;showinfo=1&amp;amp;iv_load_policy=1&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;hl=en-US&amp;amp;autohide=2&amp;amp;wmode=transparent&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; sandbox=&quot;allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;embed-youtube&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe class=&quot;youtube-player&quot; width=&quot;806&quot; height=&quot;454&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/GZAXE3-srfM?version=3&amp;amp;rel=1&amp;amp;showsearch=0&amp;amp;showinfo=1&amp;amp;iv_load_policy=1&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;hl=en-US&amp;amp;autohide=2&amp;amp;wmode=transparent&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; sandbox=&quot;allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;embed-youtube&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe class=&quot;youtube-player&quot; width=&quot;806&quot; height=&quot;454&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/h69FSgua80A?version=3&amp;amp;rel=1&amp;amp;showsearch=0&amp;amp;showinfo=1&amp;amp;iv_load_policy=1&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;hl=en-US&amp;amp;autohide=2&amp;amp;wmode=transparent&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; sandbox=&quot;allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;embed-youtube&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe class=&quot;youtube-player&quot; width=&quot;806&quot; height=&quot;454&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ewc1hixzYPY?version=3&amp;amp;rel=1&amp;amp;showsearch=0&amp;amp;showinfo=1&amp;amp;iv_load_policy=1&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;hl=en-US&amp;amp;autohide=2&amp;amp;wmode=transparent&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; sandbox=&quot;allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;jp-relatedposts-headline&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Related&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;31&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;contain-prev&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previous Story&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BABYMETAL to Play 10 Shows at Tokyo’s Famed Budokan Arena Beginning in January&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 22:43:23 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>laurex</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>R.I.P. MF DOOM, enigmatic masked rapper dead at 49</og:title>
<og:description>MF DOOM, the British-born rapper known for his masked &quot;super villain&quot; stage persona, expert rhyming abilities, and fondness for obscure pop culture samples, has died at the age of 49.</og:description>
<og:url>https://consequenceofsound.net/2020/12/mf-doom-dead-obituary/</og:url>
<og:image>https://consequenceofsound.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/MF-DOOM.jpg?quality=80</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://consequenceofsound.net/2020/12/mf-doom-dead-obituary/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Bitcoin is a disaster</title>
<link>https://www.metzdowd.com/pipermail/cryptography/2020-December/036510.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.metzdowd.com/pipermail/cryptography/2020-December/036510.html</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;title&gt;[Cryptography] Bitcoin is a disaster.&lt;/title&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;Index&quot; href=&quot;index.html&quot; /&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;made&quot; href=&quot;mailto:cryptography%40metzdowd.com?Subject=Re%3A%20%5BCryptography%5D%20Bitcoin%20is%20a%20disaster.&amp;amp;In-Reply-To=%3Cf8ac9ac83ced0ef207f144289fb50c25b65b6880.camel%40sonic.net%3E&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;robots&quot; content=&quot;index,nofollow&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta http-equiv=&quot;Content-Type&quot; content=&quot;text/html; charset=utf-8&quot; /&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;Previous&quot; href=&quot;036505.html&quot; /&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;Next&quot; href=&quot;036512.html&quot; /&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body bgcolor=&quot;#FFFFFF&quot; id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot; readability=&quot;66.278733800722&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ray Dillinger&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:cryptography%40metzdowd.com?Subject=Re%3A%20%5BCryptography%5D%20Bitcoin%20is%20a%20disaster.&amp;amp;In-Reply-To=%3Cf8ac9ac83ced0ef207f144289fb50c25b65b6880.camel%40sonic.net%3E&quot; title=&quot;[Cryptography] Bitcoin is a disaster.&quot;&gt;bear at sonic.net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mon Dec 28 20:07:03 EST 2020&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;pre&gt;
Okay, this may be just my depressive side talking, or it may be the
stress of the last year just boiling over.  But I'm inclined to think
it's not and it isn't. 

It is my opinion that Bitcoin is a failure.  Worse than that, it's a
disaster.  

The pseudonymity of coins being owned by the bearer of some
cryptographic key is a failure;  People have been eavesdropping and
aggressively analyzing the block chain from day 1.  And the block chain
will always be there, it will always be public, and it will always be
subject to further analysis.  And we are learning that analysis of that
record is sufficient to destroy any pretense of anonymity or
pseudonymity.  

The scarcity of block chain space has led people to re-invent every
last feature of the banks they thought they were going to be escaping.
Including debt brokering (lightning network) and fractional-reserve
banking, starting with the case of Mt.Gox and continuing to ventures
today by &quot;responsible&quot; businesspeople who just don't get, or don't
care, or both, that the entire reason the system existed, as far as the
early adopters were concerned, was to get away from exactly that.  They
have made Bitcoin into a debt-based system like any other; as long as
the &quot;exchange&quot; holds your keys for you, there is no obligation for them
to maintain assets equal to the deposits.  You can't prove that they
are, or aren't, maintaining sufficient assets until after those assets
are spent and the evidence appears in the block chain.

And it's useless for small transactions.  Had it been deployed to a
market the size of, say, a college campus it could bear the load and
the bidding for block space wouldn't exceed the value of most
transactions.  But had it been deployed to a market the size of a
college campus, the small pool of miners available would make mining 
bursty and unstable, and the block chain therefore not well protected
from tampering.  Same could have happened to Bitcoin early on, which is
why Satoshi was mining like crazy and jumping on when needed to prop up
the block rate and back off again when the blocks were coming too fast.

And that brings us to mining.  Bitcoin mining has encouraged corruption
(Because it's often done using electricity which is effectively stolen
from taxpayers with the help of government officials), wasted enormous
resources of energy, fostered botnets, centralized mining activity in a
country where centralization means it's effectively owned by exactly
the kind of government most people thought they *DIDN'T* want looking
up their butts and where the people who that government allows to &quot;own&quot;
this whole business work together as a cartel.  

There's a pretense of monitoring the network to guard against a 51%
attack, but to me it seems pretty clear that what they're guarding
against is merely the mistake of the cartel failing to give the latest
warehouse full of miners a distinct network identity.  The whole idea
of proof-of-work mining is broken the instant hardware comes out which
is specialized for mining and useless for general computation because
at that point the need to have compute power for other purposes is
absolutely irrelevant in having any effect on mining, and there ceases
to be any force that causes mining to be distributed around the world.
It becomes a &quot;race to the bottom&quot; to find where people can get the
cheapest electricity, and then mining anywhere else - anywhere the
government tries to make sure ordinary people actually get the benefit
from electricity bought for tax money, for example - becomes first
pointless, then a net loss. 


Mining is f***ng broken, and ASICs make it actively work against a
significant number of its design goals.

So, Bitcoin was a good effort, it deployed some new ideas and
technology, and showed that at some scale the &quot;block chain&quot; idea
worked, but ultimately, although a successful proof of concept, failed
to deliver.  It doesn't scale, except by becoming the very thing it was
supposed to replace.

The more scalable the network becomes, the more centralized it becomes,
until ultimately a &quot;scalable&quot; cryptocurrency would be doing things
exactly the same way as a credit card processor.

Bear


&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.metzdowd.com/mailman/listinfo/cryptography&quot;&gt;More information about the cryptography mailing list&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 22:25:56 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>wyldfire</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.metzdowd.com/pipermail/cryptography/2020-December/036510.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Happy New Year HN</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25595865</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25595865</guid>
<description>&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.58823529411765&quot;&gt;&lt;td bgcolor=&quot;#FF6600&quot;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr id=&quot;pagespace&quot; title=&quot;Happy New Year HN&quot;&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;11.446397188049&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table class=&quot;fatitem&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;6.603690685413&quot;&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing&quot; id=&quot;25595865&quot;&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;right&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;title&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25595865&quot; class=&quot;storylink&quot;&gt;Happy New Year HN&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.69230769230769&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;subtext&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;score&quot; id=&quot;score_25595865&quot;&gt;456 points&lt;/span&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/user?id=thunderbong&quot; class=&quot;hnuser&quot;&gt;thunderbong&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;age&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25595865&quot;&gt;5 hours ago&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span id=&quot;unv_25595865&quot;/&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/hide?id=25595865&amp;amp;goto=item%3Fid%3D25595865&quot;&gt;hide&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://hn.algolia.com/?query=Happy%20New%20Year%20HN&amp;amp;sort=byDate&amp;amp;dateRange=all&amp;amp;type=story&amp;amp;storyText=false&amp;amp;prefix&amp;amp;page=0&quot; class=&quot;hnpast&quot;&gt;past&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/fave?id=25595865&amp;amp;auth=d279b2796eabde5ed767c1b579e75be7e5f49df1&quot;&gt;favorite&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25595865&quot;&gt;127 comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;21.5&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;20&quot;&gt;Thanks to the mods and to all the members of HN for one of the bright spots of 2020.
&lt;p&gt;So many submissions, so many comments. Most of all, so many intelligent discussions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, so much guidance in how to live life - with curiosity, empathy and optimism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Times, both bad and good, will come and go. Lives will be lived and time will move on. But seeing the humanism of people, in my humble opinion, is reason for hope for a better future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have a wonderful new year everyone!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td&gt;

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.71604938271605&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;yclinks&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/newsguidelines.html&quot;&gt;Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/newsfaq.html&quot;&gt;FAQ&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/lists&quot;&gt;Lists&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/HackerNews/API&quot;&gt;API&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/security.html&quot;&gt;Security&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ycombinator.com/legal/&quot;&gt;Legal&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ycombinator.com/apply/&quot;&gt;Apply to YC&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:hn@ycombinator.com&quot;&gt;Contact&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 19:01:27 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>thunderbong</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25595865</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>SolarWinds hackers were able to access Microsoft source code</title>
<link>https://msrc-blog.microsoft.com/2020/12/31/microsoft-internal-solorigate-investigation-update/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://msrc-blog.microsoft.com/2020/12/31/microsoft-internal-solorigate-investigation-update/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;As we said in our recent &lt;a href=&quot;https://nam06.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fblogs.microsoft.com%2Fon-the-issues%2F2020%2F12%2F17%2Fcyberattacks-cybersecurity-solarwinds-fireeye%2F&amp;amp;data=04%7C01%7Crmcree%40microsoft.com%7C3c2b93314b6a4c82230608d8ada9c8dd%7C72f988bf86f141af91ab2d7cd011db47%7C1%7C0%7C637450292021293272%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C1000&amp;amp;sdata=lBCUFhcF45m9SfBqnm5V8sh9a7KKn3WN%2FguTUtzIfQo%3D&amp;amp;reserved=0&quot;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt;, we believe the Solorigate incident is an opportunity to work together in important ways, to share information, strengthen defenses and respond to attacks. Like other SolarWinds customers, we have been actively looking for indicators of the Solorigate actor and want to share an update from our ongoing internal investigation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our investigation into our own environment has &lt;strong&gt;found no evidence of access to production services or customer data. The investigation, which is ongoing, has also found no indications that our systems were used to attack others&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we previously reported, we detected malicious SolarWinds applications in our environment, which we isolated and removed. Having investigated further, we can now report that we have not found evidence of the common TTPs (tools, techniques and procedures) related to the abuse of forged SAML tokens against our corporate domains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our investigation has, however, revealed attempted activities beyond just the presence of malicious SolarWinds code in our environment. This activity has not put at risk the security of our services or any customer data, but we want to be transparent and share what we’re learning as we combat what we believe is a very sophisticated nation-state actor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We detected unusual activity with a small number of internal accounts and upon review, we discovered one account had been used to view source code in a number of source code repositories. The account did not have permissions to modify any code or engineering systems and our investigation further confirmed no changes were made. These accounts were investigated and remediated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Microsoft, we have an &lt;a href=&quot;https://nam06.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fen.wikipedia.org%2Fwiki%2FInner_source&amp;amp;data=04%7C01%7Crmcree%40microsoft.com%7C3c2b93314b6a4c82230608d8ada9c8dd%7C72f988bf86f141af91ab2d7cd011db47%7C1%7C0%7C637450292021293272%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C1000&amp;amp;sdata=XfTuzoczzfzFR6DNm73DwrWSDpHPeMvWqTmBMFZVXzI%3D&amp;amp;reserved=0&quot;&gt;inner source&lt;/a&gt; approach – the use of open source software development best practices and an open source-like culture – to making source code viewable within Microsoft. This means we do not rely on the secrecy of source code for the security of products, and our threat models assume that attackers have knowledge of source code. So viewing source code isn’t tied to elevation of risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with many companies, we plan our security with an “assume breach” philosophy and layer in defense-in-depth protections and controls to stop attackers sooner when they do gain access. We have found evidence of attempted activities which were thwarted by our protections, so we want to re-iterate the value of industry best practices such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://nam06.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fdocs.microsoft.com%2Fen-us%2Fsecurity%2Fcompass%2Fcompass&amp;amp;data=04%7C01%7Crmcree%40microsoft.com%7C3c2b93314b6a4c82230608d8ada9c8dd%7C72f988bf86f141af91ab2d7cd011db47%7C1%7C0%7C637450292021303231%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C1000&amp;amp;sdata=FtTGuwydiz6ciOghkMS94C%2FoM4%2BShzVCPvCV83iWojI%3D&amp;amp;reserved=0&quot;&gt;outlined here&lt;/a&gt;, and implementing &lt;a href=&quot;https://nam06.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fdocs.microsoft.com%2Fen-us%2Fwindows-server%2Fidentity%2Fsecuring-privileged-access%2Fprivileged-access-workstations&amp;amp;data=04%7C01%7Crmcree%40microsoft.com%7C3c2b93314b6a4c82230608d8ada9c8dd%7C72f988bf86f141af91ab2d7cd011db47%7C1%7C0%7C637450292021303231%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C1000&amp;amp;sdata=DOsOv9yqcEE92PsUjs8kn9EkVwUqG%2FdI7y5crtc4GoM%3D&amp;amp;reserved=0&quot;&gt;Privileged Access Workstations (PAW)&lt;/a&gt; as part of a strategy to protect privileged accounts. We will provide additional updates if and when we discover new information to help inform and enable the community. As we learn more from our own internal investigation, and from helping customers, we will continue to improve our security products and share these learnings with the community. For the up-to-date information and guidance, please visit our resource center at &lt;a href=&quot;https://nam06.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Faka.ms%2Fsolorigate&amp;amp;data=04%7C01%7Crmcree%40microsoft.com%7C3c2b93314b6a4c82230608d8ada9c8dd%7C72f988bf86f141af91ab2d7cd011db47%7C1%7C0%7C637450292021313185%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C1000&amp;amp;sdata=PR25evQwqqL6svp8uSIW3o8tbYWiHLp45dqBov%2F7FRQ%3D&amp;amp;reserved=0&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;https://aka.ms/solorigate&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 18:24:19 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>accountinhn</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://msrc-blog.microsoft.com/2020/12/31/microsoft-internal-solorigate-investigation-update/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Erdoğan’s censorship now targeting media outlets in Europe</title>
<link>https://www.turkishminute.com/2020/12/31/erdogans-censorship-now-targeting-media-outlets-in-europe/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.turkishminute.com/2020/12/31/erdogans-censorship-now-targeting-media-outlets-in-europe/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/cevheriguven&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cevheri Güven&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bold Medya, a YouTube channel run by the German-based International Journalists Association eV (IJA), was shut down due to efforts exerted by the government of Turkish President Recep Tayyip Erdoğan. Social media expert Yasin Kesen says Erdoğan is now resorting to fraudulent methods in an attempt to extend his crackdown on freedom of expression beyond Turkey’s borders and into the European Union, a dangerous trend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The IJA was set up by exiled Turkish journalists who had to flee Turkey to avoid persecution and incarceration. Nearly all its members are political refugees in Germany. Bold Medya, one of the most significant initiatives of the association, was a platform allowing independent journalists to pursue their professional activities. Within two years, the channel had attracted 250,000 subscribers. All its employees and voluntary supporters are based in Germany.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The channel, already under an access ban in Turkey since 2019, was shut down in mid-December and is now inaccessible on YouTube. The Erdoğan government had it shut down using YouTube’s copyright policy. Fatih Akalan, one of the channel’s chief editors, says they were performing a public service and that the Erdoğan regime is abusing YouTube’s regulations in a devious attempt at censorship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kesen points to the executives of YouTube’s Turkey office for the abuse of the platform’s rules and policies, claiming that they are either working together with the Turkish government or at the very least turning a blind eye to what is being done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erdoğan cracking down on free speech in Germany&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IJA Secretary-General Mustafa Kılıç says while censorship is almost taken for granted in Turkey, the situation is now getting more serious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“For the first time ever, Erdoğan has shut down a YouTube channel broadcasting from Europe. It is already well-known that under his long arm, various operations were ongoing in Europe, especially in Germany,” Kılıç said, in apparent reference to a series of espionage scandals in which the Turkish government was found to be spying on its critics living in Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“But now, we have seen that Erdoğan has succeeded in silencing a YouTube news channel operating from Germany. This is no different than shutting down Deutsche Welle’s Turkish channel. Our members are journalists who had already suffered a crackdown on their freedom of expression in Turkey. It is very scary to see that now it is being targeted here in Germany.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kesen: YouTube Turkey office cooperating with Erdoğan&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kesen claims that the spillover of Turkey’s online censorship to Europe has to do with the stance of YouTube’s Turkey office.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“YouTube grants what is called the Content Management System [CMS] to large production companies, TV channels and content providers. Nearly 20 organizations in Turkey enjoy this system, and one of them is the state-run broadcaster TRT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“YouTube allows those with CMS to directly take down a video in the event of copyright infringement and have the channel closed entirely after three violations. This is a privilege that YouTube grants to large companies based on trust. TRT, under Erdoğan’s direct control, is abusing this right and removing videos that he does not like by claiming copyright. And then it has the channel shut down after three consecutive copyright removals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“In reality, the deleted videos do not belong to TRT, and there is no copyright infringement. TRT has been engaged in this abuse for the past four-and-a-half years. When the right to CMS is misused three times, it should be revoked. YouTube’s Turkey office, however, has not barred TRT from the CMS panel despite the fact that the state-run channel has done it hundreds of times. YouTube allowing its system to be employed in favor of Erdoğan’s censorship and now this have gone beyond Turkey’s borders as Erdoğan has become able to use TRT to intervene against the exercise of free speech in other parts of the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This situation has repeatedly been communicated to YouTube’s Turkey office, which does not respond, either by e-mail or by phone,” Kesen said. “Due to this obedience to TRT, the work and channels of exiled journalists, artists and actors are being taken down.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;‘YouTube Turkey representatives might have unethical relations with Erdoğan’&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kesen says the practice undercuts YouTube’s global stance in favor of free speech and its brand value and that it might be caused by unethical engagement of local employees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“There might be interest-based relations between YouTube’s Turkey representatives and the Erdoğan regime. The censorship in Turkey is at an unbelievable level and completely against YouTube’s own policies,” Kesen says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Deleted videos do not match those of TRT&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kesen says the videos taken down over TRT’s copyright claims do not match the state-run broadcaster’s content and that it is impossible for YouTube’s local representatives to not have noticed this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“When we examine the cases, we see videos that in no way match up,” Kesen says. “It is inconceivable that YouTube’s Turkey office hasn’t noticed this. But there is a certain cooperation with the regime that leads to the silencing of individual YouTubers, journalists, artists, critics and relatively smaller channels.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Turkish-based company encroaching on copyright revenue&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kesen says there are other substantial examples of malpractice by YouTube’s Turkey office.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Normally, CMS is only granted to production companies and TV channels. But YouTube’s representation in Turkey extended this right to a company named Network Software [Network Yazılım], which has nothing to do with the field. The company monitors the videos trending in Turkey, and if these are from individual content providers and not from verified institutional accounts, it claims copyright and funnels all the ad revenue attached to the videos to itself. This is causing trouble for independent YouTubers in particular,” Kesen says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The office has not taken into account any complaints with regard to Network Software’s copyright fraud, which leads to suspicions that local YouTube employees are in a secret arrangement with the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;cb_p6_patreon_button&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liked it? Take a second to support Turkish Minute on Patreon!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.patreon.com/TurkishMinute?utm_content=post_button&amp;amp;utm_medium=patron_button_and_widgets_plugin&amp;amp;utm_campaign=&amp;amp;utm_term=&amp;amp;utm_source=https://www.turkishminute.com/2020/12/31/erdogan-censorship-targeting-media-outlets-in-europe/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.turkishminute.com/wp-content/plugins/patron-button-and-widgets-by-codebard/images/become_a_patron_button.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 17:08:48 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>doener</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.turkishminute.com/2020/12/31/erdogan-censorship-targeting-media-outlets-in-europe/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Rust 1.49.0</title>
<link>https://blog.rust-lang.org/2020/12/31/Rust-1.49.0.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.rust-lang.org/2020/12/31/Rust-1.49.0.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Dec. 31, 2020 · The Rust Release Team&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;118.925795053&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Rust team is happy to announce a new version of Rust, 1.49.0. Rust is a programming language that is empowering everyone to build reliable and efficient software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have a previous version of Rust installed via rustup, getting Rust 1.49.0 is as easy as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-console&quot;&gt;rustup update stable
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you don't have it already, you can &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rust-lang.org/install.html&quot;&gt;get &lt;code&gt;rustup&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; from the appropriate page on our website, and check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/blob/master/RELEASES.md#version-1490-2020-12-31&quot;&gt;detailed release notes for 1.49.0&lt;/a&gt; on GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What's in 1.49.0 stable&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this release, we have some new targets and an improvement to the test framework. See the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/blob/master/RELEASES.md#version-1490-2020-12-31&quot;&gt;detailed release notes&lt;/a&gt; to learn about other changes not covered by this post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;64-bit ARM Linux reaches Tier 1&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Rust compiler supports &lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.rust-lang.org/stable/rustc/platform-support.html&quot;&gt;a wide variety of targets&lt;/a&gt;, but the Rust Team can't provide the same level of support for all of them. To clearly mark how supported each target is, we use a tiering system:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Tier 3 targets are technically supported by the compiler, but we don't check whether their code build or passes the tests, and we don't provide any prebuilt binaries as part of our releases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tier 2 targets are guaranteed to build and we provide prebuilt binaries, but we don't execute the test suite on those platforms: the produced binaries might not work or might have bugs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tier 1 targets provide the highest support guarantee, and we run the full suite on those platforms for every change merged in the compiler. Prebuilt binaries are also available.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rust 1.49.0 promotes the &lt;code&gt;aarch64-unknown-linux-gnu&lt;/code&gt; target to Tier 1 support, bringing our highest guarantees to users of 64-bit ARM systems running Linux! We expect this change to benefit workloads spanning from embedded to desktops and servers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an important milestone for the project, since it's the first time a non-x86 target has reached Tier 1 support: we hope this will pave the way for more targets to reach our highest tier in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that Android is not affected by this change as it uses a different Tier 2 target.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;64-bit ARM macOS and Windows reach Tier 2&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rust 1.49.0 also features two targets reaching Tier 2 support:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The &lt;code&gt;aarch64-apple-darwin&lt;/code&gt; target brings support for Rust on Apple M1 systems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;code&gt;aarch64-pc-windows-msvc&lt;/code&gt; target brings support for Rust on 64-bit ARM devices running Windows on ARM.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Developers can expect both of those targets to have prebuilt binaries installable with &lt;code&gt;rustup&lt;/code&gt; from now on! The Rust Team is not running the test suite on those platforms though, so there might be bugs or instabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Test framework captures output in threads&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rust's built-in testing framework doesn't have a ton of features, but that doesn't mean it can't be improved! Consider a test that looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-rust&quot;&gt;#[test]
fn thready_pass() {
    println!(&quot;fee&quot;);
    std::thread::spawn(|| {
        println!(&quot;fie&quot;);
        println!(&quot;foe&quot;);
    })
    .join()
    .unwrap();
    println!(&quot;fum&quot;);
}
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's what running this test looks like before Rust 1.49.0:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;❯ cargo +1.48.0 test
   Compiling threadtest v0.1.0 (C:\threadtest)
    Finished test [unoptimized + debuginfo] target(s) in 0.38s
     Running target\debug\deps\threadtest-02f42ffd9836cae5.exe

running 1 test
fie
foe
test thready_pass ... ok

test result: ok. 1 passed; 0 failed; 0 ignored; 0 measured; 0 filtered out

   Doc-tests threadtest

running 0 tests

test result: ok. 0 passed; 0 failed; 0 ignored; 0 measured; 0 filtered out
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can see that the output from the thread is printed, which intermixes from the output of the test framework itself. Wouldn't it be nice if every &lt;code&gt;println!&lt;/code&gt; worked like that one that prints &quot;&lt;code&gt;fum&lt;/code&gt;?&quot; Well, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/pull/78227&quot;&gt;that's the behavior in Rust 1.49.0&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;❯ cargo test
   Compiling threadtest v0.1.0 (C:\threadtest)
    Finished test [unoptimized + debuginfo] target(s) in 0.52s
     Running target\debug\deps\threadtest-40aabfaa345584be.exe

running 1 test
test thready_pass ... ok

test result: ok. 1 passed; 0 failed; 0 ignored; 0 measured; 0 filtered out; finished in 0.00s

   Doc-tests threadtest

running 0 tests

test result: ok. 0 passed; 0 failed; 0 ignored; 0 measured; 0 filtered out; finished in 0.00s
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But don't worry; if the test were to fail, you'll still see all of the output. By adding a &lt;code&gt;panic!&lt;/code&gt; to the end of the test, we can see what failure looks like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;❯ cargo test
   Compiling threadtest v0.1.0 (C:\threadtest)
    Finished test [unoptimized + debuginfo] target(s) in 0.52s
     Running target\debug\deps\threadtest-40aabfaa345584be.exe

running 1 test
test thready_pass ... FAILED

failures:

---- thready_pass stdout ----
fee
fie
foe
fum
thread 'thready_pass' panicked at 'explicit panic', src\lib.rs:11:5
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Specifically, the test runner makes sure to capture the output, and saves it in case the test fails.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Library changes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Rust 1.49.0, there are three new stable functions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And two functions were made &lt;code&gt;const&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/blob/master/RELEASES.md#version-1490-2020-12-31&quot;&gt;detailed release notes&lt;/a&gt; to learn about other changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Other changes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are other changes in the Rust 1.49.0 release: check out what changed in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/blob/master/RELEASES.md#version-1490-2020-12-31&quot;&gt;Rust&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/cargo/blob/master/CHANGELOG.md#cargo-149-2020-12-31&quot;&gt;Cargo&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rust-clippy/blob/master/CHANGELOG.md#rust-149&quot;&gt;Clippy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Contributors to 1.49.0&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many people came together to create Rust 1.49.0. We couldn't have done it without all of you. &lt;a href=&quot;https://thanks.rust-lang.org/rust/1.49.0/&quot;&gt;Thanks!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 14:41:13 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>pietroalbini</dc:creator>
<og:title>Announcing Rust 1.49.0 | Rust Blog</og:title>
<og:description>Empowering everyone to build reliable and efficient software.</og:description>
<og:image>https://www.rust-lang.org/static/images/rust-social-wide.jpg</og:image>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.rust-lang.org/2020/12/31/Rust-1.49.0.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>WebAssembly Studio</title>
<link>https://webassembly.studio</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://webassembly.studio</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://webassembly.studio&quot;&gt;https://webassembly.studio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25592481&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25592481&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 310&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 173&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 13:31:06 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>joubert</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://webassembly.studio/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Elements of Statistical Learning [pdf]</title>
<link>https://web.stanford.edu/~hastie/Papers/ESLII.pdf</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://web.stanford.edu/~hastie/Papers/ESLII.pdf</guid>
<description>&lt;a href=&quot;https://web.stanford.edu/~hastie/Papers/ESLII.pdf&quot;&gt;Download PDF&lt;/a&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 12:48:09 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>happy-go-lucky</dc:creator>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://web.stanford.edu/~hastie/Papers/ESLII.pdf</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Mitsubishi Heavy to build biggest zero-carbon steel plant</title>
<link>https://asia.nikkei.com/Spotlight/Environment/Climate-Change/Mitsubishi-Heavy-to-build-biggest-zero-carbon-steel-plant</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://asia.nikkei.com/Spotlight/Environment/Climate-Change/Mitsubishi-Heavy-to-build-biggest-zero-carbon-steel-plant</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;TOKYO -- Japan's Mitsubishi Heavy Industries will soon complete in Austria the world's largest steel plant capable of attaining net-zero carbon dioxide emissions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mitsubishi Heavy, through a British unit, is constructing the pilot plant at a complex of Austrian steelmaker Voestalpine. Trial operation is slated to begin in 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plant will use hydrogen instead of coal in the reduction process for iron ore. The next-generation equipment will produce 250,000 tons of steel product a year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The global steel industry generated about 2 billion tons of CO2 in 2018, according to the International Energy Agency -- double the volume in 2000. The steel sector's share among all industries grew 5 percentage points to 25%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Iron ore reduction accounts for much of the CO2 emissions in steelmaking. Japanese steelmakers including Nippon Steel are developing hydrogen-consuming reduction processes based on the conventional blast furnace design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mitsubishi Heavy's plant adopts a process called direct reduced iron, or DRI. New blast furnaces require trillions of yen (1 trillion yen equals $9.6 billion) in investment. Although DRI equipment produces less steel, the investment is estimated at less than half of blast furnaces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For DRI to attain the same level of cost-competitiveness as blast furnaces, low-cost hydrogen will be key. Market costs for hydrogen now stand at around 100 yen per normal cu. meter, estimates the Ministry of Economy, Trade and Industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The government aims to get the hydrogen costs down to 30 yen per normal cu. meter by 2030, mainly via mass production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But for DRI to be feasible in the steel industry, &quot;the level needs to go below 10 yen,&quot; said an executive at a large steelmaker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Germany's SMS, the world's leading supplier of steelmaking equipment, is pursuing the hydrogen-fueled steelmaking process, along with runner-up Danieli of Italy. Among steelmakers, Luxembourg-based ArcelorMittal plans to build a German pilot hydrogen steel plant in 2021. Competitors such as Germany's Thyssenkrupp and Salzgitter are investing in DRI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mitsubishi Heavy, the world's third-largest steelmaking equipment supplier, is also securing a hydrogen supply chain. In October, the company bought a stake in a Norwegian outfit that makes hydrogen-producing equipment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elsewhere, Mitsubishi Heavy has decided to acquire stakes in hydrogen producers in such places as Australia. The group will oversee supply of hydrogen, together with equipment construction and engineering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The European Union announced in July an initiative to invest 470 billion euros ($572 billion) in hydrogen by 2050. Hydrogen steel plants are anticipated to receive support. Europe is home to a growing number of businesses that deal in hydrogen. Mitsubishi Heavy will capture the steel industry's demand for hydrogen to offset the softer growth prospects for thermal power plant equipment.&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 11:29:36 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>doener</dc:creator>
<og:title>Mitsubishi Heavy to build biggest zero-carbon steel plant</og:title>
<og:description>Austrian test facility to run on hydrogen when it goes online next year</og:description>
<og:image>https://www.ft.com/__origami/service/image/v2/images/raw/https%253A%252F%252Fs3-ap-northeast-1.amazonaws.com%252Fpsh-ex-ftnikkei-3937bb4%252Fimages%252F9%252F6%252F6%252F0%252F31470669-3-eng-GB%252FCropped-1609100872RTX72UDL.JPG?width=1024&amp;height=512&amp;fit=cover&amp;gravity=faces&amp;source=nar-cms</og:image>
<og:url>https://asia.nikkei.com/Spotlight/Environment/Climate-Change/Mitsubishi-Heavy-to-build-biggest-zero-carbon-steel-plant</og:url>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<dc:language>en-GB</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://asia.nikkei.com/Spotlight/Environment/Climate-Change/Mitsubishi-Heavy-to-build-biggest-zero-carbon-steel-plant</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>PyPy Project looking for sponsorship to add support for Apple Silicon</title>
<link>https://morepypy.blogspot.com/2020/12/mac-meets-arm64.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://morepypy.blogspot.com/2020/12/mac-meets-arm64.html</guid>
<description>&lt;strong&gt;Looking for sponsorship&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;p&gt;Apple now ships Macs which are running on an arm64 variant machine with the latest version of MacOS, Big Sur M1. We are getting requests for PyPy to support this new architecture. Here is our position on this topic (or at least mine, Armin Rigo's), and how you can help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Porting PyPy is harder than just re-running the compiler, because PyPy contains a few big architecture-dependent &quot;details&quot;, like the JIT compiler and the foreign function interfaces (CFFI and ctypes).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fixing the JIT compiler should not be too much work: we already support arm64, just the Linux one. But Apple made various details different (like the calling conventions). A few other parts need to be fixed too, notably CFFI and ctypes, again because of the calling conventions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fixing that would be a reasonable amount of work. I would do it myself for a small amount of money. However, the story doesn't finish here. Obviously, the &lt;strong&gt;start&lt;/strong&gt; of the story would be to get ssh access to a Big Sur M1 machine. (If at this point you're thinking &quot;sure, I can give you ssh access for three months&quot;, then please read on.) The &lt;strong&gt;next&lt;/strong&gt; part of the story is that we need a machine available long term. It can be either a machine provided and maintained by a third party, or alternatively a pot of money big enough to support the acquision of a machine and ongoing work of one of us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we go with the provided-machine solution: What we need isn't a lot of resources. Our CI requires maybe 10 GB of disk space, and a few hours of CPU per run. It should fit into 8 GB of RAM. We normally do a run every night but we can certainly lower the frequency a bit if that would help. However, we'd ideally like some kind of assurance that you are invested into maintaining the machine for the next 3-5 years (I guess, see below). We had far too many machines that disappeared after a few months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we go with the money-supported solution: it's likely that after 3-5 years the whole Mac base will have switched to arm64, we'll drop x86-64 support for Mac, and we'll be back to the situation of the past where there was only one kind of Mac machine to care about. In the meantime, we are looking at 3-5 years of lightweight extra maintenance. We have someone that has said he would do it, but not for free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If either of these two solutions occurs, we'll still have, I quote, &quot;probably some changes in distutils-type stuff to make python happy&quot;, and then some packaging/deployment changes to support the &quot;universal2&quot; architecture, i.e. including both versions inside a single executable (which will &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; be just an extra switch to clang, because the two versions need a different JIT backend and so must be translated separately).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, now all the factors are on the table. We won't do the minimal &quot;just the JIT compiler fixes&quot; if we don't have a plan that goes farther. Either we get sufficient money, and maybe support, and then we can do it quickly; or PyPy will just remain not natively available on M1 hardware for the next 3-5 years. We are looking forward to supporting M1, and view resources contributed by the community as a vote of confidence in assuring the future of PyPy on this hardware. Contact us: &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:pypy-dev@python.org&quot;&gt;pypy-dev@python.org&lt;/a&gt;, or our private mailing list &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:pypy-z@python.org&quot;&gt;pypy-z@python.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Armin Rigo&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 11:24:52 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>fniephaus</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://morepypy.blogspot.com/2020/12/mac-meets-arm64.html</og:url>
<og:title>Mac meets Arm64</og:title>
<og:description>Looking for sponsorship Apple now ships Macs which are running on an arm64 variant machine with the latest version of MacOS, Big Sur M1. ...</og:description>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://morepypy.blogspot.com/2020/12/mac-meets-arm64.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>