<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Going Critical</title>
<link>https://www.meltingasphalt.com/interactive/going-critical/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.meltingasphalt.com/interactive/going-critical/</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.meltingasphalt.com/interactive/going-critical/&quot;&gt;https://www.meltingasphalt.com/interactive/going-critical/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19905677&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19905677&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 313&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 12&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 00:48:43 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>bkudria</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.meltingasphalt.com/interactive/going-critical/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Third-Biggest U.S. Coal Company Files for Bankruptcy</title>
<link>https://flatheadbeacon.com/2019/05/10/third-biggest-u-s-coal-company-files-bankruptcy/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://flatheadbeacon.com/2019/05/10/third-biggest-u-s-coal-company-files-bankruptcy/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;GILLETTE, Wyo. – The nation’s third-largest coal company by production volume filed for bankruptcy Friday as utility companies increasingly turn to gas-fired generation and renewable energy for electricity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Gillette-based Cloud Peak Energy filed for Chapter 11 reorganization in U.S. Bankruptcy Court in Delaware. The move was widely expected since at least March, when the company received the first of several extensions to make a $1.8 million loan payment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The latest extension expired Friday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;dfp-ad-wrap dfp-inline-ad-wrap&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;div-gpt-ad-1464884580983-4&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cloud Peak owns and operates three mines in the Powder River Basin: the Antelope and Cordero Rojo mines in Wyoming and the Spring Creek Mine in Montana.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mines shipped 50 million tons of coal in 2018. Cloud Peak officials say the mines will remain in operation during the bankruptcy process.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 23:34:55 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>toomuchtodo</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Third-Biggest U.S. Coal Company Files for Bankruptcy - Flathead Beacon</og:title>
<og:description>GILLETTE, Wyo. – The nation’s third-largest coal company by production volume filed for bankruptcy Friday as utility companies increasingly turn to gas-fired generation and renewable energy for electricity. Gillette-based Cloud... more</og:description>
<og:url>https://flatheadbeacon.com/2019/05/10/third-biggest-u-s-coal-company-files-bankruptcy/</og:url>
<og:image>https://flatheadbeacon.com/wp-content/themes/flathead-beacon/library/images/fb-social-logo.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://flatheadbeacon.com/2019/05/10/third-biggest-u-s-coal-company-files-bankruptcy/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>WhatsApp voice calls were used to inject spyware on phones</title>
<link>https://www.ft.com/content/4da1117e-756c-11e9-be7d-6d846537acab</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.ft.com/content/4da1117e-756c-11e9-be7d-6d846537acab</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;A vulnerability in the messaging app WhatsApp has allowed attackers to inject commercial Israeli spyware on to phones, the company and a spyware technology dealer said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ft.com/stream/7b5b19ff-e034-4c9a-96f7-c3aab7c47f05&quot; data-trackable=&quot;link&quot;&gt;WhatsApp&lt;/a&gt;, which is used by 1.5bn people worldwide, discovered in early May that attackers were able to install surveillance software on to both iPhones and Android phones by ringing up targets using the app’s phone call function. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The malicious code, developed by the secretive Israeli company NSO Group, could be transmitted even if users did not answer their phones, and the calls often disappeared from call logs, said the spyware dealer, who was recently briefed on the WhatsApp hack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WhatsApp is too early into its own investigations of the vulnerability to estimate how many phones were targeted using this method, a person familiar with the issue said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As late as Sunday, as WhatsApp engineers raced to close the loophole, a UK-based human rights lawyer’s phone was targeted using the same method. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Researchers at the University of Toronto’s Citizen Lab said they believed that the spyware attack on Sunday was linked to the same vulnerability that WhatsApp was trying to patch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NSO’s flagship product is Pegasus, a program that can turn on a phone’s microphone and camera, trawl through emails and messages and collect location data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NSO advertises its products to Middle Eastern and Western intelligence agencies, and says Pegasus is intended for governments to fight terrorism and crime. NSO was recently valued at $1bn in a leveraged buyout that involved the UK private equity fund Novalpina Capital&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the past, human rights campaigners in the Middle East have received text messages over WhatsApp that contained links that would download Pegasus to their phones. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WhatsApp said that teams of engineers had worked around the clock in San Francisco and London to close the vulnerability. It began rolling out a fix to its servers on Friday last week, WhatsApp said, and issued a patch for customers on Monday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This attack has all the hallmarks of a private company known to work with governments to deliver spyware that reportedly takes over the functions of mobile phone operating systems,” the company said. “We have briefed a number of human rights organisations to share the information we can, and to work with them to notify civil society.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WhatsApp disclosed the issue to the US Department of Justice last week, according to a person familiar with the matter. A justice department spokesman declined to comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NSO said it had carefully vetted customers and investigated any abuse. Asked about the WhatsApp attacks, NSO said it was investigating the issue. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Under no circumstances would NSO be involved in the operating or identifying of targets of its technology, which is solely operated by intelligence and law enforcement agencies,” the company said. “NSO would not, or could not, use its technology in its own right to target any person or organisation, including this individual [the UK lawyer].”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The UK lawyer, who declined to be identified, has helped a group of Mexican journalists and government critics and a Saudi dissident living in Canada, sue NSO in Israel, alleging that the company shares liability for any abuse of its software by clients. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John Scott-Railton, a senior researcher at the University of Toronto’s Citizen Lab, said the attack had failed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We had a strong suspicion that the person’s phone was being targeted, so we observed the suspected attack, and confirmed that it did not result in infection,” said Mr Scott-Railton. “We believe that the measures that WhatsApp put in place in the last several days prevented the attacks from being successful.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;n-content-recommended--single-story&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;n-content-recommended__title&quot;&gt;Recommended&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;o-teaser o-teaser--small o-teaser--stacked o-teaser--has-image o-teaser--article o-teaser--syndicatable&quot; data-o-component=&quot;o-teaser&quot; data-trackable=&quot;teaser&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;o-teaser__image-container js-teaser-image-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;n-image-wrapper o-teaser__image-placeholder n-image-wrapper--lazy-loading n-image-wrapper--placeholder&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-srcset=&quot;https://www.ft.com/__origami/service/image/v2/images/raw/http%3A%2F%2Fprod-upp-image-read.ft.com%2F216d2392-6c1e-11e9-a9a5-351eeaef6d84?source=next&amp;amp;fit=scale-down&amp;amp;compression=best&amp;amp;width=2048 2048w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 1220px) 1168px, (min-width: 980px) 928px, (min-width: 740px) 688px, calc(100vw - 40px)&quot; role=&quot;presentation&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;n-image o-teaser__image n-image--lazy-loading n-image--fade-on-load&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;o-teaser__content&quot;&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;time data-o-component=&quot;o-date&quot; class=&quot;o-date&quot; data-o-date-format=&quot;time-ago-limit-4-hours&quot; datetime=&quot;2019-05-05T04:00:25.000Z&quot;&gt;Sunday, 5 May, 2019&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;Other lawyers working on the cases have been approached by people pretending to be potential clients or donors, who then try and obtain information about the ongoing lawsuits, the Associated Press reported in February.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s upsetting but not surprising that my team has been targeted with the very technology that we are raising concerns about in our lawsuits,” said Alaa Mahajne, a Jerusalem-based lawyer who is handling lawsuits from the Mexican and Saudi citizens. “This desperate reaction to hamper our work and silence us, itself shows how urgent the lawsuits are, as we can see that the abuses are continuing.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday, NSO will also face a legal challenge to its ability to export its software, which is regulated by the Israeli ministry of defence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amnesty International, which identified an attempt to hack into the phone of one its researchers, is backing a group of Israeli citizens and civil rights group in a filing in Tel Aviv asking the ministry of defence to cancel NSO’s export licence. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“NSO Group sells its products to governments who are known for outrageous human rights abuses, giving them the tools to track activists and critics. The attack on Amnesty International was the final straw,” said Danna Ingleton, deputy director of Amnesty Tech. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The Israeli ministry of defence has ignored mounting evidence linking NSO Group to attacks on human rights defenders. As long as products like Pegasus are marketed without proper control and oversight, the rights and safety of Amnesty International’s staff and that of other activists, journalists and dissidents around the world is at risk.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Additional reporting by Kadhim Shubber in Washington&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 22:21:09 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>EwanToo</dc:creator>
<og:title>WhatsApp voice calls used to inject Israeli spyware on phones</og:title>
<og:description>Messaging app discovers vulnerability that has been open for weeks</og:description>
<og:image>https://www.ft.com/__origami/service/image/v2/images/raw/http%3A%2F%2Fprod-upp-image-read.ft.com%2Fa5e1805e-75a7-11e9-be7d-6d846537acab?source=next-opengraph&amp;fit=scale-down&amp;width=900</og:image>
<og:url>https://www.ft.com/content/4da1117e-756c-11e9-be7d-6d846537acab</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-GB</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.ft.com/content/4da1117e-756c-11e9-be7d-6d846537acab</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>California jury says Bayer must pay $2B to couple in Roundup cancer trial</title>
<link>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-bayer-glyphosate-lawsuit/california-jury-says-bayer-must-pay-2-billion-to-couple-in-roundup-cancer-trial-idUSKCN1SJ29F</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.reuters.com/article/us-bayer-glyphosate-lawsuit/california-jury-says-bayer-must-pay-2-billion-to-couple-in-roundup-cancer-trial-idUSKCN1SJ29F</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;(Reuters) - A California jury on Monday awarded more than $2 billion to a couple who claimed Bayer AG’s glyphosate-based Roundup weed killer caused their cancer, in the largest U.S. jury verdict to date against the company in litigation over the chemical.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The large punitive damages award is likely to be reduced due to U.S. Supreme Court rulings that limit the ratio of punitive to compensatory damages to 9:1. The jury awarded a total of $2 billion in punitive damages and $55 million in compensatory damages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was the third consecutive U.S. jury verdict against the company in litigation over the chemical, which Bayer acquired as part of its $63 billion purchase of Monsanto last year. Both other jury verdicts also came in California, one in state court and one in federal court.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The jury in Alameda County Superior Court in Oakland on Monday said the company was liable for plaintiffs Alva and Alberta Pilliod’s contracting non-Hodgkin’s lymphoma, a spokeswoman for the couple said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It awarded $18 million in compensatory and $1 billion in punitive damages to Alva Pilliod, and $37 million in compensatory and $1 billion in punitive damages to his wife, Alberta Pilliod. The jury found Roundup had been defectively designed, that the company failed to warn of the herbicide’s cancer risk and that the company acted negligently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The German chemicals giant faces more than 13,400 U.S. lawsuits over the herbicide’s alleged cancer risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next jury trial in the glyphosate litigation is scheduled for August in Missouri state court, the first time a jury outside of California will hear a Roundup case. The trial will take place in St. Louis County, where Monsanto’s former headquarters are located.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bayer in a statement on Monday said it was disappointed with the verdict and will appeal. A spokesman called the jury’s decision “excessive and unjustifiable.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company said both Alva and Alberta Pilliod had long histories of illnesses known to be substantial risk factors for non-Hodgkin’s lymphoma.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The contrast between today’s verdict and (U.S. Environmental Protection Agency’s) conclusion that there are ‘no risks to public health from the current registered uses of glyphosate’ could not be more stark,” Bayer said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bayer says that decades of studies by the company and independent scientists have shown glyphosate and Roundup to be safe for human use. Bayer also points to several regulators around the world that found that glyphosate was not carcinogenic to humans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brent Wisner, a lawyer for the Pilliods, at a news conference following the verdict said Bayer had to take responsibility for its product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Monsanto keeps denying that it causes cancer and these two fine people here are casualties of that deception,” Wisner said, standing next to the California couple, who are in their 70s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alberta Pilliod called on Bayer to add a warning label to Roundup, saying she and her husband would not have used the product had it alerted them to a cancer risk. “We’ve been fighting cancer for more than nine years now and we can’t do any of the things we wanted to do. We really resent Monsanto for that,” Pilliod said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Image_container&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;LazyImage_container LazyImage_dark&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s2.reutersmedia.net/resources/r/?m=02&amp;amp;d=20190514&amp;amp;t=2&amp;amp;i=1386829308&amp;amp;r=LYNXNPEF4C1BF&amp;amp;w=20&quot; aria-label=&quot;Monsanto Co's Roundup is shown for sale in Encinitas, California, U.S., June 26, 2017. REUTERS/Mike Blake&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;Image_caption&quot;&gt;

&lt;span&gt;Monsanto Co's Roundup is shown for sale in Encinitas, California, U.S., June 26, 2017. REUTERS/Mike Blake&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The prior two jury verdicts against Bayer in U.S. Roundup trials triggered steep declines in Bayer shares.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A San Francisco state court jury in August 2018 awarded $289 million to a California groundskeeper, finding Monsanto’s glyphosate-based weed killers caused his cancer. That award was later reduced to $78 million and is on appeal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In March, a federal jury in San Francisco awarded $80 million to another California man after finding Roundup caused his cancer. The company also said it would appeal that decision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adam Zimmerman, a law professor at Loyola Law School in Los Angeles, on Monday said it was too early to speculate about a potential settlement of the litigation by Bayer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The legal questions on appeal in the previous two cases will ultimately inform how this litigation proceeds,” Zimmerman said. It also remains to be seen how juries in other part of the country react to the evidence in upcoming trials, he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shareholders have rebuked the company’s top management over its handling of the Monsanto acquisition and the litigation it inherited, which has wiped around 30 billion euros ($33.68 billion) from Bayer’s market value since the first jury verdict.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Pilliods allege the regular use of Roundup on their property between 1975 and 2011 caused them to develop cancers of the lymph system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They filed their lawsuit in 2017 after being diagnosed with cancer in 2011 and 2015, respectively. Both of them are currently in remission, but their trial had been expedited due to the risk of a relapse and potentially short life expectancy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;SmallImage_small-image SmallImage_standard SmallImage_caption-truncate&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Image_container&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;Image_caption Image_full-width&quot;&gt;

&lt;span&gt;FILE PHOTO: The Bayer AG logo sits on display at the headquarters in La Garenne-Colombes, near Paris, France, May 13, 2019. REUTERS/Benoit Tessier&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plaintiffs in the litigation allege that Monsanto had known about the herbicide’s cancer risk for decades, but failed to warn consumers and instead attempted to influence scientists and regulators to receive favorable assessments of its products. Bayer denies those allegations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lawsuits are largely based on a 2015 conclusion by the World Health Organization’s cancer arm, which classified glyphosate as “probably carcinogenic to humans.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A 2017 Reuters investigati&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/article/us-who-iarc-glyphosate-specialreport/in-glyphosate-review-who-cancer-agency-edited-out-non-carcinogenic-findings-idUSKBN1CO251&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; found that the World Health Organization's International Agency for Research on Cancer had dismissed and edited out &quot;non-carcinogenic&quot; findings that were at odds with its final conclusion that the chemical probably causes cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The U.S. EPA, the European Chemicals Agency and other regulators have found that glyphosate is not likely carcinogenic to humans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Attribution_container&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Attribution_attribution&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Attribution_content&quot;&gt;Reporting by Tina Bellon in New York; Editing by Leslie Adler&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;StandardArticleBody_trustBadgeContainer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;StandardArticleBody_trustBadgeTitle&quot;&gt;Our Standards:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;trustBadgeUrl&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thomsonreuters.com/en/about-us/trust-principles.html&quot;&gt;The Thomson Reuters Trust Principles.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 21:38:51 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mi100hael</dc:creator>
<og:title>California jury hits Bayer with $2 billion award in Roundup cancer...</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-bayer-glyphosate-lawsuit-idUSKCN1SJ29F</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>A California jury on Monday awarded more than $2 billion to a couple who claimed...</og:description>
<og:image>https://s2.reutersmedia.net/resources/r/?m=02&amp;d=20190514&amp;t=2&amp;i=1386829308&amp;w=1200&amp;r=LYNXNPEF4C1BF</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-bayer-glyphosate-lawsuit/california-jury-says-bayer-must-pay-2-billion-to-couple-in-roundup-cancer-trial-idUSKCN1SJ29F</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>To Message Bus or Not: Distributed Systems Design (2017)</title>
<link>https://www.netlify.com/blog/2017/03/02/to-message-bus-or-not-distributed-systems-design/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.netlify.com/blog/2017/03/02/to-message-bus-or-not-distributed-systems-design/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Distributed system design is hard. There are many decisions that you need to make in the architecture early that have long reaching impacts. One of these decisions is how systems will communicate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will components expose RESTful APIs?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will they interact with a messaging system (e.g. RabbitMQ, NATS, Kafka)? GRPC?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How will they share responses?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;I think that communication roughly falls into two schools: point to point and message bus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an architecture driven by a message bus it allows more ubiquitous access to data. The consumers are allowed to determine how they will consume the data. It is not something decided by the sender. The power created by decoupling the producer and consumer, far outweighs any operational overhead introduced. Point to point is easier in some ways, but it silos the data off from the rest of the system. This can be a perk, security and isolation for instance, but building these walled gardens of data will hurt innovation, development pace, and monitoring in the long run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.netlify.com/a94cdc19bc024781dee08ade593e8a4f89b9077d/4e2a1/img/blog/msg-styles.png&quot; alt=&quot;null&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Often systems will use a hybrid of the two communication styles. For instance, we have a service that will take commands from a message bus, but are provided a callback URL where they can funnel the responses. It could have easily been that we just send messages back on the bus. We chose the hybrid approach because it fit the existing architecture better. We could have also stood up a proxy/load balancer that would have distributed the messages but looked like a single instance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;point-to-point&quot;&gt;Point-to-Point&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In point to point, you’ll communicate between services directly. For instance, you’ll POST metrics directly to an endpoint, or funnel logs, or request an action. For scalability, you’ll often need to consider having multiple instances supporting that endpoint. To do this you’ll have some kind of load balancer or proxy. Setting up an maintaining proxies can be cumbersome, but they also provide a huge amount of power. Usually, you also have to address service discovery earlier in the system design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using load balancers to distribute load across multiple instances, is very helpful, arguably &lt;em&gt;essential&lt;/em&gt; when designing the system. Once in place it allows you to easily load multiple services into a box and provide a consistent port signature. However, the most powerful feature is the ability to fail an instance out of the load balancer. This allows the running production instance to stay running for troubleshooting while not compromising the integrity of the whole system. This flexibility is invaluable when you have a lot of services collaborating on a single logical request.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biggest drawback of a point-to-point communication structure is that the data is silo’d in the ecosystem from which it originates. The creator of the information determines how the data is used, by sending that data to a single point. This means that new crosscutting capabilities have to go fundamentally highjack that communication channel. They have to man-in-the-middle the receiver to get access to that data. Simple things like ‘how many requests is that service getting’ have to be built in and can’t be added afterwards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;message-bus&quot;&gt;Message bus&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using a message bus will allow for the same communications, but it’s a little more simple. Single request/reply, worker pool, and broadcast models are supported out of the box. Service discovery is a matter of just sending messages to the right topics. There is an operational cost of maintaining the message bus, and possibly having a piece of infrastructure that impacts all services. But, all the production grade buses support clustering, but still things can go wrong and it can lock the whole system up (looking at you RabbitMQ).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.netlify.com/2a4d35406fe181d43068d0aa699bfec90e7eb3a1/dad8f/img/blog/msg-patterns.png&quot; alt=&quot;undefined&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The primary benefit of a message bus architecture is that data is freely available. Services just provide data and don’t mandate how it is used. You still have the necessary coordination in developing a system; part a generates messages like this and part b will do that. But now you can have any new service start non-destructively consuming those messages. This free flow of data allows for rapid prototyping, simple services crosscutting, intuitive monitoring and easier development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an example you can look at how Netlify collect metrics from across the system. Each of our services has a message bus connection logging, command &amp;amp; control, and metrics. We knew that each of the services would need to be pushing out metrics (read: counting things), but we weren’t sure where we would be storing them. Because the data was just on the bus I could easily create a few different services that took the data and pushed it to different storage engines. I was able to quickly side-by-side influxDB, redshift, dynamo and a 3rd party system with no modifications to the actual services. I built some quick command line utilities to tap into streams and run little experiments (e.g. validating counts, debugging, monitoring throughput).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of these experiments are developed independently as I needed them. This flexibility let me ask a question and quickly answer it without potentially impacting the actual service. I could quickly look at real production data to answer any questions that came up. All of those perks is because the data wasn’t walled off, anyone with access to the message bus (which is secured) could look at the data without impacting other services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without a load balancer it is more difficult to leave an instance running but not communicating with the system directly. It requires specific code and for the end user to build this, not just configure the load balancer. There are also security concerns, once on the bus a consumer can start listening to data very easily. Enterprise messaging systems sometimes provide out of the box ACLs, but it is not in everyone. I would contend that this ease of access is far more valuable and worth the security considerations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;communicating-between-components&quot;&gt;Communicating between components&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a handful of ways to design communication systems in a distributed system. An architecture with a message bus as a core feature is very powerful. The decoupling between data creation and data consumption is invaluable in a growing system. New services can easily collaborate using the bus, and service agnostic tools (e.g. a message tailer) can interoperate easily. Point-to-point systems have some clear perks, but I think they’re outweighed by the capabilities created by a message bus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coordinating disparate systems is complex to say the least, designing how they communicate is vital to there success. But, which school is best for your system? As is always the case with engineering, the answer is “it depends”. Hopefully this helps you qualify which is the best for you. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 19:25:25 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>gk1</dc:creator>
<og:title> To Message Bus or Not: Distributed Systems Design | Netlify</og:title>
<og:description> Learn about a few ways that distributed systems can communicate.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.netlify.com/blog/2017/03/02/to-message-bus-or-not-distributed-systems-design/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Stack Overflow lets Facebook track users across their sites</title>
<link>https://meta.stackoverflow.com/questions/384864/stack-overflow-lets-facebook-track-us-across-their-sites?cb=1</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://meta.stackoverflow.com/questions/384864/stack-overflow-lets-facebook-track-us-across-their-sites?cb=1</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Seeing as there's no official answer by the Network, I thought I'd pipe up and write a general answer on how users can protect themselves from this type of tracking and basically what I regard as privacy invasion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've done some study/research on this and there's nothing private about the internet. Google and other sites also do this. Many companies have been forced to clean up their ways to an &quot;extent&quot;. Most end users are ignorant of what is being done with their data and the risk associated with what these sites view as non-PII (personal identifiable information) and how, in fact, the data can be matched (too long to get into) to reveal specific user details (including PII) without the user being aware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I manually select which cookies I'll accept on each site I visit. I have third-party cookies blocked and my browser set to remove cookies (with my selected exceptions) when I quit. I go through my cookies whenever I quit my browser and have been on new sites, or sites where I know the cookies are not removed when I quit, and I manually remove them. I can do this many times a day. I also closed all my social media accounts. Beyond this site having my real name, I'm entitled to my privacy and take it seriously. I prefer to have console errors or a page not to render properly than be tracked and harvested for money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also use an ad blocker and have for a long time. Some sites won't allow you to view pages with this active. If I'm desperate to see something I'll allow ads on that page. Websites are entitled to raise revenue, but I don't have to visit there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fun fact: Google was trying to patent the collection of user data few years back. Seriously! I use Google products, but with full awareness of what they do and regularly clear my usage histories. And as for Twitter et al, they're not better. All these sites are data mined for non-PII and put together and this data is utilised and sold. Sometimes information ends up on the Dark Web for sale. It's one of those things. Live your life so there's nothing you do that you will not be concerned about becoming public. Or do not use the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fun Fact Two: I live in Australia and not only is our internet appalling, but our government shows a flagrant disrespect for basic human rights, including the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.abc.net.au/news/science/2018-10-02/proposed-surveillance-laws-draw-international-criticism/10300170&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;right to privacy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 17:18:27 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Thorondor</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>https://meta.stackoverflow.com/questions/384864/stack-overflow-lets-facebook-track-us-across-their-sites?cb=1</og:url>
<og:image>https://meta.stackoverflow.com/content/Sites/stackoverflowmeta/img/apple-touch-icon@2.png?v=6de7587d1583</og:image>
<og:title>Stack Overflow lets Facebook track us across their sites</og:title>
<og:description>By now, everyone who follows technology should be aware of the scandals around Facebook's ethics and data privacy. Many users distrust them and are uncomfortable with their data collection practices.</og:description>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://meta.stackoverflow.com/questions/384864/stack-overflow-lets-facebook-track-us-across-their-sites?cb=1</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ask HN: What overlooked class of tools should a self-taught programmer look into</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19900955</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19900955</guid>
<description>15 years ago I learned Python by studying some O'Reilly books and I have been a hobbyist programmer ever since.
&lt;p&gt;The books went into detail and since reading them I've felt confident writing scripts I needed to scratch an itch. Over time, I grew comfortable believing I had a strong grasp of the practical details and anything I hadn't seen was likely either minor quibble, domain specific, or impractically theoretic.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This was until last year when I started working on a trading bot. I felt there should be two distinct parts to the bot, one script getting data then passing that data along to the other script for action. This seemed correct as later I might want multiple scripts serving both roles and passing data all around. Realizing the scripts would need to communicate over a network with minimal latency, I considered named pipes, Unix domain sockets, even writing files to /dev/shm but none of these solutions really fit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Googling, I encountered something I hadn't heard of called a message queue. More specifically, the ZMQ messaging library. Seeing some examples I realized this was important. The step of then plowing through the docs was nothing short of revelatory. Every next chapter introduced another brilliant pattern. While grokking Pub/Sub, Req/Res, Push/Pull and the rest I couldn't help breaking away, staring in space, struck by how this new thing I had just read could have deftly solved some fiendish memorable problem I'd previously struggled against.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later, I pondered the meaning of only now stumbling on something so powerful, so fundamental, so hidden in plain sight, as messaging middleware? What other great tools remain invisible to me for lack of even knowing what to look for?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My question: In the spirit of generally yet ridiculously useful things like messaging middleware, what non-obvious tools and classes of tools would you suggest a hobbyist investigate that they otherwise may never encounter?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 16:34:11 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>nathanasmith</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19900955</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>U.S. Farmers Are Being Bled by the Tractor Monopoly</title>
<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/opinion/articles/2019-04-23/u-s-farmers-need-a-better-way-to-fix-their-tractors</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bloomberg.com/opinion/articles/2019-04-23/u-s-farmers-need-a-better-way-to-fix-their-tractors</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/opinion/articles/2019-04-23/u-s-farmers-need-a-better-way-to-fix-their-tractors&quot;&gt;https://www.bloomberg.com/opinion/articles/2019-04-23/u-s-farmers-need-a-better-way-to-fix-their-tractors&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19900022&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19900022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 419&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 302&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 15:09:42 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jelliclesfarm</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bloomberg.com/tosv2.html?vid=&amp;uuid=7e3a57c0-761e-11e9-a4f2-972c1eba8200&amp;url=L29waW5pb24vYXJ0aWNsZXMvMjAxOS0wNC0yMy91LXMtZmFybWVycy1uZWVkLWEtYmV0dGVyLXdheS10by1maXgtdGhlaXItdHJhY3RvcnM=</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Audit suggests Google favors a small number of major news outlets</title>
<link>https://www.cjr.org/tow_center/google-news-algorithm.php</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.cjr.org/tow_center/google-news-algorithm.php</guid>
<description>&lt;span class=&quot;caption-top hidden-print&quot;&gt;Photo | Adobe Stock&lt;/span&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In the last week of April,&lt;/strong&gt; nearly 23 percent of all &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.parse.ly/resources/data-studies/referrer-dashboard/&quot;&gt;traffic to news sites tracked by web analytics firm Parse.ly&lt;/a&gt; came from search engines. Google alone accounts for nearly half of external referral traffic—traffic, that is, that comes from platforms, apps, and other outside sources— to news sites. Together with the fact that Facebook referral traffic is &lt;a href=&quot;https://slate.com/technology/2018/06/facebooks-retreat-from-the-news-has-painful-for-publishers-including-slate.html&quot;&gt;on the wane&lt;/a&gt;, this means that Google’s search algorithm is now perhaps the most powerful mediator of online attention to news.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But for all the influence Google has in directing attention, we know painfully little about how its algorithm selects and curates news. Which sites does it direct traffic toward? And how does Google’s news curation impact the diversity of information found?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ICYMI: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cjr.org/watchdog/lottery-winners-foia-reporting.php&quot;&gt;A reporter asked for 20 years of lottery winner data. After analyzing the records, he noticed something unusual.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To find out, the Computational Journalism Lab at Northwestern, including Daniel Trielli and I, &lt;a href=&quot;https://dl.acm.org/citation.cfm?id=3300683&quot;&gt;undertook an audit study&lt;/a&gt; of the “Top Stories” box on Google search. Top Stories often shows up in the prime real-estate at the top of search results, presenting a carousel of news articles relevant to the query.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-79459&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn.cjr.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/image3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;830&quot; height=&quot;465&quot; srcset=&quot;https://cdn.cjr.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/image3.jpg 830w, https://cdn.cjr.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/image3-800x448.jpg 800w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 830px) 100vw, 830px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To audit Top Stories, we scraped Google results for more than &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1LfYqz2xcWOno8Ve991amZj2uFLhNqg31UaSt_Drasgk/edit#gid=0&quot;&gt;200 queries&lt;/a&gt; related to news events in November, 2017. We selected the queries to test by looking at Google Trends every day and manually choosing terms related to hard news events. These included names of people in the news such as “colin kaepernick,” breaking news events such as “earthquake,” and issue-specific queries such as “tax reform” or “healthcare gov.” We set up our scraper to minimize the potential for result personalization (the process by which Google tailors its search results to an account or IP address based on past use), and ran each query once per minute for a full 24 hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;mc_embed_signup&quot; class=&quot;hidden-print&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;form-title-embed&quot;&gt;Sign up for &lt;span class=&quot;cjr-bold&quot;&gt;CJR&lt;/span&gt;'s &lt;nobr&gt;daily email&lt;/nobr&gt;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In total, we collected 6,302 unique links to news articles shown in the Top Stories box. For each of those links we count an article &lt;em&gt;impression&lt;/em&gt; each time one of those links appears.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data shows that just 20 news sources account for more than half of article impressions. The top 20 percent of sources (136 of 678) accounted for 86 percent of article impressions. And the top three accounted for 23 percent: CNN, &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/em&gt;. These statistics underscore the degree of concentration of attention to a relatively narrow slice of news sources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-79458&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn.cjr.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/image2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;614&quot; height=&quot;673&quot; srcset=&quot;https://cdn.cjr.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/image2.jpg 614w, https://cdn.cjr.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/image2-547x600.jpg 547w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 614px) 100vw, 614px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, the concentration of sources also varies depending on the query. On average there were 19 sources per query, but 30 percent of queries had 10 or fewer sources. And sometimes, even if there were more sources, most of the impressions could go to just a handful. For instance, the query “rex tillerson” had 38 sources, but just two of those sources—the &lt;em&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt; and CNN—were responsible for 75 percent of the article impressions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prior research has shown that search engines can affect users’ attitudes, shape opinions, alter perceptions and reinforce stereotypes, as well as affect &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nickdiakopoulos.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/i-vote-for-open-access.pdf&quot;&gt;how voters come to be informed during elections&lt;/a&gt;. As such, media diversity is an important aspect to the way that Google—or any news aggregator—curates sources and perspectives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get at this issue in our audit, we looked at the diversity of sources surfaced in Google Top Stories in terms of their ideological lean. More specifically, we used ratings data &lt;a href=&quot;https://science.sciencemag.org/content/348/6239/1130&quot;&gt;published in an earlier study&lt;/a&gt; which identifies the ideological alignment of the top 500 most-shared news sites on Facebook. The ratings don’t measure the slant of the media outlet per se, but rather reflect the self-reported political affiliation of Facebook users sharing content from those sources. The criteria were published in the peer-reviewed journal &lt;em&gt;Science&lt;/em&gt; in June, 2015 by Eytan Bakshy, Solomon Messing, and Lada Adamic from Facebook’s Core Data Science team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;pullquote-2015&quot;&gt;Organizations that can generate fresh copy may be more apt to have that material selected by the curation algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our data shows that 62.4 percent of article impressions were from sources rated by that research as left-leaning, whereas 11.3 percent were from sources rated as right-leaning. 26.3 percent of impressions were from news sources that didn’t have ratings. But even if that last set of unknown impressions happened to be right-leaning, the trend would still be clear: A higher proportion of left-leaning sources appear in Top Stories. (Again, this means news sources shared on Facebook more often by people with a left-leaning political affiliation.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is there simply more news produced on the left? It appears so. We confirmed this by searching the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gdeltproject.org/&quot;&gt;GDELT&lt;/a&gt; database of news articles for the same queries we used to audit Google. In GDELT there were 2.2 times as many articles from left-leaning sources as right-leaning sources. But in Google Top Stories that ratio was 3.2, indicating that the curation algorithm was slightly magnifying the left-leaning skew in comparison to the GDELT baseline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another aspect of Google’s news curation is the timeliness of articles selected. Just how quickly does Google churn through news content? Since the Top Stories box provides the approximate age of each article (e.g. “2 hours ago”), we were able to tabulate the recency of articles. What we found is that 83.5 percent of articles were less than 24 hours old and 13.1 percent were less than an hour old. What this means is that organizations that can generate fresh copy may be more apt to have that material selected by the curation algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-79457&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn.cjr.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/image1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;986&quot; height=&quot;476&quot; srcset=&quot;https://cdn.cjr.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/image1.jpg 986w, https://cdn.cjr.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/image1-800x386.jpg 800w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 986px) 100vw, 986px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the last part of our analysis, we looked at how much traffic an appearance in Top Stories actually generates. To do this, we combined our scraped data with referral data provided by Chartbeat. Across queries, there is a lot of variation in the number of people searching who could therefore be referred. As an example, in our data, “Matt Lauer” generated 3,961 referrals for each article impression we observed, far more than the average. But a majority of search terms (58 percent) averaged less than 100 referrals per impression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ICYMI: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cjr.org/first_person/tinazzi-motorcycle-mont-blanc-tunnel-fire-rescue.php&quot;&gt;I wrote a story that became a legend. Then I discovered it wasn’t true.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to account for the variability between terms, we built a statistical model that predicts an article’s referrals from Google based on how many impressions it has in the Top Stories Box or in organic search results. The model predicts that an article receiving 60 impressions in the middle position of Top Stories over the course of an hour (we measure one impression each minute) would lead to a 15.5 percent lift in referrals. That’s a boost of almost 1/6 more referrals for an article. And that’s if it’s visible for just an hour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Impressions generated organically by Google’s search algorithm, rather than in the Top Stories box, accounted for slightly fewer referrals. Sixty organic impressions in an hour would boost referrals by 9.4 percent. Keep in mind, though, that an article could be visible in Top Stories or in organic results for many different queries. Our model offers a lower bound on what the actual boost may be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on the proportion of impressions in our data, and using our predictive model, a very rough estimate would be that CNN received a 24 percent increase in referral traffic from Google from its article’s placements in Top Stories. NPR, on the other hand, perhaps got an increase of about 3.7 percent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As much as our results help better describe Google’s curation of news, what our study decidedly cannot say is &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; some sources dominate on Google. Perhaps some outlets have cracked the SEO code for Top Stories. Or there may be a number of other factors taken into account by Google’s algorithm that end up prioritizing certain outlets over others. We just don’t know unless Google is more transparent with the editorial design and goals of news curation in the Top Stories box.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What we do know is that Google’s algorithmic curation of news in search converts to real and substantial amounts of user attention and traffic. News source concentration on Google implies an unequal capture of attention and its benefits, including any advertising or potential subscription revenue that might result. If they are serious about supporting digital-first newsrooms, algorithmic news curators, including Google and others, might be more explicit in articulating the inherent design tradeoffs between the relevance desirable for individuals, the diversity desirable for society or democracy, and the fair competition desirable for news organizations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ICYMI: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cjr.org/united_states_project/sandra-bland-video.php&quot;&gt;Reporter says TV boss passed on Sandra Bland video, “didn’t think it was newsworthy”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;post-survey-box&quot; class=&quot;hidden-print&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Has America ever needed a media watchdog more than now? Help us by &lt;a href=&quot;https://ssl.palmcoastd.com/18801/apps/MEMBER1?ikey=5**M02&quot; onclick=&quot;ga('send', 'event', 'MemberSignUp', 'ArticleBoxLink', '');&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;joining CJR today&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;small class=&quot;bio-overline&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nicholas Diakopoulos is an assistant professor at Northwestern University School of Communication, author of the forthcoming book &quot;Automating the News: How Algorithms are Rewriting the Media&quot; on automation and algorithms in news media, and regular contributor to CJR on these topics.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/small&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 14:49:20 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>hhs</dc:creator>
<og:title>Audit suggests Google favors a small number of major outlets</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.cjr.org/tow_center/google-news-algorithm.php</og:url>
<og:image>https://cdn.cjr.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/AdobeStock_139324113-800x419.jpeg</og:image>
<og:description>&lt;p&gt;In the last week of April, nearly 23 percent of all traffic to news sites tracked by web analytics firm Parse.ly came from search engines. Google alone accounts for nearly half of external referral traffic—traffic, that is, that comes from platforms, apps, and other outside sources— to news sites. Together with the fact that Facebook […]&lt;/p&gt;</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.cjr.org/tow_center/google-news-algorithm.php</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Supreme Court rules antitrust lawsuit against Apple can proceed</title>
<link>https://www.wired.com/story/supreme-court-apple-decision-antitrust/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.wired.com/story/supreme-court-apple-decision-antitrust/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lede&quot;&gt;On Monday, the&lt;/span&gt; Supreme Court of the United States voted to allow a years-long antitrust case against &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/tag/apple/&quot;&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt; to move forward, despite Apple's objections. The case, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/story/pepper-v-apple-supreme-court-app-store-antitrust/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apple Inc. v. Pepper&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, concerns a group of iPhone users who accuse Apple of driving up the price of apps by charging third-party app developers a 30 percent commission. Apple argued that App Store customers technically buy apps from third-party developers and have no direct purchasing relationship with Apple, and therefore no standing to seek damages from the company. But in a 5–4 decision, written by conservative Justice Brett Kavanaugh, the court voted against Apple, allowing the case to proceed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;The sole question presented at this early stage of the case is whether these consumers are proper plaintiffs for this kind of antitrust suit—in particular, our precedents ask whether the consumers were 'direct purchasers' from Apple,&quot; the decision reads. &quot;It is undisputed that the iPhone owners bought the apps directly from Apple.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paywall&quot;&gt;The lawsuit, which was first filed in 2011 by lead plaintiff Robert Pepper and three other iPhone users, had been struck down in a district court, only to be revived in the Ninth Circuit, which found that the plaintiffs did, in fact, have standing to sue. Now the case will head back to the district court, where the question of whether Apple violated antitrust law will be resolved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paywall&quot;&gt;The decision was hailed by consumer advocates like the Center for Democracy &amp;amp; Technology. &quot;Today, more and more of consumers’ purchases go through platforms, where sellers and buyers meet virtually via technology, instead of in brick-and-mortar stores,&quot; Avery Gardiner, CDT’s senior fellow for competition, data and power, said in a statement. &quot;These technologies are evolving fast, and today’s decision shows that antitrust law is—as it should be—flexible enough to address allegations that companies may misuse their market strength in novel ways.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paywall&quot;&gt;The Supreme Court's decision to allow the case to proceed at all could also have an impact on other companies, like Amazon, that prefer to frame themselves as neutral marketplaces, not direct sellers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paywall&quot;&gt;&quot;I would anticipate that plaintiffs lawyers will be looking at this closely and looking at tech companies and internet platforms and thinking about who they might be able to sue now that this uncertainty is gone,&quot; says Valarie Williams, a partner at the Atlanta-based law firm Alston &amp;amp; Bird, who specializes in antitrust law.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;inset-left-component paywall&quot;&gt;
&lt;h5 name=&quot;inset-left&quot; class=&quot;inset-left-component__el&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/author/issie-lapowsky/?itm_campaign=AuthorCarveLeft&quot;&gt;Issie Lapowsky&lt;/a&gt; covers the intersection of tech, politics, and national affairs for WIRED.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paywall&quot;&gt;The Supreme Court's decision hinges on another 1977 case, &lt;em&gt;Illinois Brick Co. v. Illinois&lt;/em&gt;, in which the state of Illinois sued a number of brick manufacturers, accusing them of price fixing. The manufacturers argued that because their direct customers were contractors, not the government, the government couldn't sue them, and the case should be dismissed. The Supreme Court sided with the brick manufacturers, finding that indirect purchasers cannot seek antitrust damages, a principle now known as the Illinois Brick doctrine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paywall&quot;&gt;Apple used this same doctrine to argue that the plaintiffs in this case also lacked standing. In oral arguments last fall, a lawyer for Apple argued that because app developers set their own prices, App Store customers are really buying from the developers, not Apple itself. In other words, Apple positioned itself as merely the retail space where app developers pay to set up shop and sell their products. But in their decision the Supreme Court justices rejected this framing, writing that Apple was arguing &quot;strenuously&quot; against a &quot;simple conclusion.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paywall&quot;&gt;&quot;There is no intermediary in the distribution chain between Apple and the consumer,&quot; the decision reads. &quot;The iPhone owners purchase apps directly from the retailer Apple, who is the alleged antitrust violator.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paywall&quot;&gt;Tech companies and consumer advocates have been watching this case closely, bracing themselves for a ripple effect across the industry. But Williams says the court's decision in this case largely avoids drastic reinterpretation of the law. It does not, for instance, overturn the Illinois Brick doctrine by finding that indirect purchasers of a product have standing to sue for antitrust violations.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p class=&quot;paywall&quot;&gt;&quot;If they had overturned &lt;em&gt;Illinois Brick&lt;/em&gt; and allowed indirect purchasers to sue for federal antitrust claims, that would be a huge change,&quot; Williams says. Instead, the court merely found that under the law as written, App Store customers do have a direct purchasing relationship with Apple. That's largely because Apple prohibits people from buying iPhone apps anywhere other than its own App Store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paywall&quot;&gt;Just because the plaintiffs have proven they have the standing to sue, doesn't mean they'll be able to prove that Apple did, in fact, violate antitrust law. This is its own complex question, and one that Williams says is likely to end in a settlement. It's also a question that European regulators are grappling with, after &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/story/spotify-apple-complaint-warren-antitrust-issue/&quot;&gt;Spotify made a complaint&lt;/a&gt; against Apple to the European Commission earlier this year. Spotify similarly argued that by charging a 30 percent commission on in-app purchases, Apple is abusing its market dominance and requiring app developers to pass those costs on to consumers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paywall&quot;&gt;Apple didn't respond to WIRED's request for comment regarding the Supreme Court decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr class=&quot;paywall&quot;/&gt;&lt;h3 class=&quot;paywall&quot;&gt;More Great WIRED Stories&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 14:09:18 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>CWSZ</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Supreme Court Deals Blow to Apple in Antitrust Case</og:title>
<og:description>In Apple v. Pepper, the Supreme Court ruled in a 5–4 decision that Apple's App Store customers have standing to sue the company for antitrust violations.</og:description>
<og:image>https://media.wired.com/photos/5cd9b00d8e3893122fe4234b/191:100/pass/TimCook-social-1055500764.jpg</og:image>
<og:url>https://www.wired.com/story/supreme-court-apple-decision-antitrust/</og:url>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.wired.com/story/supreme-court-apple-decision-antitrust/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>