<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Chinese may take over Mombasa port: Ouko</title>
<link>https://www.nation.co.ke/news/Chinese-may-take-Mombasa-Port--Ouko/1056-4902162-xfphu7z/index.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nation.co.ke/news/Chinese-may-take-Mombasa-Port--Ouko/1056-4902162-xfphu7z/index.html</guid>
<description>&lt;section class=&quot;author noprint&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.nation.co.ke/image/view/-/1951494/medRes/593420/-/12ubx6dz/-/General+Image.jpg&quot; width=&quot;50&quot;/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;By DAVID MWERE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nation.co.ke/authors/1959272-4003520-view-asAuthor-jn4ko4z/index.html&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;author-profile&quot;&gt;More by this Author&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;Kenya could lose the port of Mombasa to the Chinese government if Kenya Railways Corporation (KRC) defaults in the payment of Sh227 billion owed to Exim Bank of China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;The government borrowed the billions to construct the Mombasa-Nairobi standard gauge railway (SGR), against opposition that the project by China Roads and Bridges Corporation (CRBC), a Chinese State-owned company, could become a white elephant. The country's sovereignty is now at stake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;A report by Auditor-General Edward Ouko states that the payment agreement substantively means the revenue of the Kenya Ports Authority would be used to clear the debt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;This is if the minimum volumes required for consignments are not met.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;The audit shows that KPA’s revenue was Sh42.7 billion as at June 30, 2018, a 7.9 percent increase from the Sh39.6 billion recorded the previous year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;“Exim Bank would become a principal over KPA if KRC defaults in its obligations and the Chinese bank exercises power over the escrow account security,” states a management letter sent to the KPA, that Mr FT Kimani signed on behalf of Mr Ouko.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;The letter says, “KPA assets are exposed since the authority signed the agreement in which it has been referred to as a borrower under clause 17.5.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;It adds, “Any proceedings against its assets by the lender would not be protected by sovereign immunity since the government waived the immunity on the KPA assets by signing the agreement.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;The auditor notes that the agreement is biased since any non-performance or dispute with the bank would be referred to arbitration in China, “whose fairness is resolving the disagreement may not be guaranteed”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;Mr Ouko accuses the KPA management of not disclosing the guarantee documents in its financial statements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;Despite the danger of losing the lucrative port, he recommends that the authority discloses pertinent issues and risks related to the guarantee in the statements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;The KPA is also required to confirm in the management representation letter that its assets are not a floating charge to the government of Kenya loan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;On its Twitter handle, the Office of the Auditor-General appeared to distance itself from the report though it neither confirmed nor denied the contents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;“Our attention has been drawn to reports that @OAG Kenya has released an audit report on @Kenya Ports for FY 2017/18. This is to clarify that the office has not released any such report,” the tweet read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;A source at the auditor-general’s office, who did not want to go on record, said the issues raised were being investigated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;“The issues raised are not conclusive. They are a work in progress and will be dropped if they don’t respond satisfactorily,” the source said.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;The transfer, according to the &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt;, gave China control of the territory just a few hundred miles off the shores of rival India.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;It is a strategic foothold along a critical commercial and military waterway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;“The case is one of the examples of China’s ambitious use of loans and aid to gain influence around the world and of its willingness to play hardball to collect,” says the &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt; of December 12, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;In September 2018, Zambia lost its international airport to China over debt repayment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;section class=&quot;related-articles sidebar-item noprint&quot;&gt;&lt;section class=&quot;related-articles sidebar-item&quot;&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Related Stories&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/section&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 26 Dec 2018 13:59:44 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>tartoran</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Chinese may take over Mombasa port: Ouko</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.nation.co.ke/news/Chinese-may-take-Mombasa-Port--Ouko/1056-4902162-xfphu7z/index.html</og:url>
<og:description>A Kenya Railways debt of Sh227 billion has put Kenya's sovereignty at risk.</og:description>
<og:image>https://www.nation.co.ke/image/view/-/4902232/medRes/2202558/-/t0w76wz/-/Uhuru-Jinping.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nation.co.ke/news/Chinese-may-take-Mombasa-Port--Ouko/1056-4902162-xfphu7z/index.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Artificial Intelligence Creates Realistic Pictures of People</title>
<link>http://www.openculture.com/2018/12/artificial-intelligence-creates-realistic-photos-of-people-none-of-whom-actually-exist.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.openculture.com/2018/12/artificial-intelligence-creates-realistic-photos-of-people-none-of-whom-actually-exist.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-1059356&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn8.openculture.com/2018/12/23205526/AI-Face-1-e15456263742702.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;451&quot; srcset=&quot;http://cdn8.openculture.com/2018/12/23205526/AI-Face-1-e15456263742702.png 900w, http://cdn8.openculture.com/2018/12/23205526/AI-Face-1-e15456263742702-240x120.png 240w, http://cdn8.openculture.com/2018/12/23205526/AI-Face-1-e15456263742702-360x180.png 360w, http://cdn8.openculture.com/2018/12/23205526/AI-Face-1-e15456263742702-768x385.png 768w, http://cdn8.openculture.com/2018/12/23205526/AI-Face-1-e15456263742702-300x150.png 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 900px) 100vw, 900px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each day in the 2010s, it seems, brings another startling development in the field of artificial intelligence — a field widely written off not all that long ago as a dead end. But now AI looks just as alive as the people you see in these photographs, despite the fact that none of them have ever lived, and it's questionable whether we can even call the images that depict them &quot;photographs&quot; at all. All of them come, in fact, as products of a state-of-the-art &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Generative_adversarial_network&quot;&gt;generative adversarial network&lt;/a&gt;, a type of artificial intelligence algorithm that pits multiple neural networks against each other in a kind of machine-learning match.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone wp-image-1059345 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn8.openculture.com/2018/12/23190541/AI-Face-3-e1545626386288.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;576&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These neural networks have, it seems, competed their way to generating images of fabricated human faces that genuine humans have trouble distinguishing from images of the real deal. Their architecture, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/pdf/1812.04948.pdf&quot;&gt;described in a paper by the Nvidia researchers who developed it&lt;/a&gt;, &quot;leads to an automatically learned, unsupervised separation of high-level attributes (e.g., pose and identity when trained on human faces) and stochastic variation in the generated images (e.g., freckles, hair), and it enables intuitive, scale-specific control of the synthesis.&quot; What they've come up with, in other words, has made it not just more possible than ever to create fake faces, but made those faces more customizable than ever as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Of course, the ability to create realistic AI faces raises troubling questions. (Not least of all, how long until stock photo models go out of work?)&quot; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2018/12/17/18144356/ai-image-generation-fake-faces-people-nvidia-generative-adversarial-networks-gans&quot;&gt;writes James Vincent at The Verge&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;Experts have been raising the alarm for the past couple of years about how AI fakery might impact society. These tools could be used for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2018/4/17/17247334/ai-fake-news-video-barack-obama-jordan-peele-buzzfeed&quot;&gt;misinformation and propaganda&lt;/a&gt; and might erode public trust in pictorial evidence, a trend that could damage the justice system as well as politics.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;oc-video-wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;youtube&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; class=&quot;youtube-player&quot; type=&quot;text/html&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;505&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/kSLJriaOumA?wmode=transparent&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;showsearch=0&amp;amp;rel=0&amp;amp;theme=dark&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;But still, &quot;you can’t doctor any image in any way you like with the same fidelity. There are also serious constraints when it comes to expertise and time. It took Nvidia’s researchers a week training their model on eight Tesla GPUs to create these faces.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-1059377&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn8.openculture.com/2018/12/23222604/aifaces5-e1545632775881.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;392&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though &quot;a running battle between AI fakery and image authentication for decades to come&quot; seems inevitable, the current ability of computers to create plausible faces certainly fascinates, especially when compared to their ability just four years ago, the hazy black-and-white fruits of which appear just above. Put that against the grid of faces at the top of the post, which shows how Nvidia's system can combine the features of the faces on one axis with the features on the other, and you'll get a sense of the technological acceleration involved. Such a process could well be used, for example, to give you a sense of what your future children might look like. But how long until it puts convincing visions of moving, speaking, even thinking human beings before our eyes?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;via &lt;a href=&quot;https://petapixel.com/2018/12/17/these-portraits-were-made-by-ai-none-of-these-people-exist/&quot;&gt;Petapixel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Related Content:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.openculture.com/2016/04/the-next-rembrandt.html&quot;&gt;Scientists Create a New Rembrandt Painting, Using a 3D Printer &amp;amp; Data Analysis of Rembrandt’s Body of Work&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.openculture.com/2018/01/artificial-intelligence-writes-a-piece-in-the-style-of-bach.html&quot;&gt;Artificial Intelligence Writes a Piece in the Style of Bach: Can You Tell the Difference Between JS Bach and AI Bach?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.openculture.com/2016/09/artificial-intelligence-program-tries-to-write-a-beatles-song-listen-to-daddys-car.html&quot;&gt;Artificial Intelligence Program Tries to Write a Beatles Song: Listen to “Daddy’s Car”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.openculture.com/2018/03/google-presents-a-free-course-on-artificial-intelligence-sign-up-for-its-new-machine-learning-crash-course.html&quot;&gt;Google Launches a Free Course on Artificial Intelligence: Sign Up for Its New “Machine Learning Crash Course”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.openculture.com/2018/03/google-launches-three-new-artificial-intelligence-experiments-that-could-be-godsends-for-artists.html&quot;&gt;Google Launches Three New Artificial Intelligence Experiments That Could Be Godsends for Artists, Museums &amp;amp; Designers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Based in Seoul, &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.colinmarshall.org/&quot;&gt;Colin Marshall&lt;/a&gt; writes and broadcasts on cities, language, and culture. His projects include the book &lt;/em&gt;The Stateless City: a Walk through 21st-Century Los Angeles &lt;em&gt;and the video series &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/channels/thecityincinema&quot;&gt;The City in Cinema&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Follow him on Twitter at &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/#%21/colinmarshall&quot;&gt;@colinmarshall&lt;/a&gt; or on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/colinmarshallessayist&quot;&gt;Faceboo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/colinmarshallessayist&quot;&gt;k&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 26 Dec 2018 12:54:13 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Liriel</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>http://www.openculture.com/2018/12/artificial-intelligence-creates-realistic-photos-of-people-none-of-whom-actually-exist.html</og:url>
<og:title>Artificial Intelligence Creates Realistic Photos of People, None of Whom Actually Exist</og:title>
<og:image>https://cdn8.openculture.com/2018/12/23205526/AI-Face-1-e15456263742702.png</og:image>
<og:description> Each day in the 2010s, it seems, brings another startling development in the field of artificial intelligence — a field widely written off not all that long ago as a dead end.</og:description>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.openculture.com/2018/12/artificial-intelligence-creates-realistic-photos-of-people-none-of-whom-actually-exist.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Recovering Nintendo’s Lost SimCity for the NES</title>
<link>https://gamehistory.org/simcity/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://gamehistory.org/simcity/</guid>
<description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;dib w-100 w-50-ns&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/box_front.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1751&quot; src=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/box_front.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;dib w-100 w-50-ns&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/box_back.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1751&quot; src=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/box_back.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
The unreleased packaging illustration from SimCity, as seen on a rare retail display sign from VidPro.
&lt;p&gt;A lot of you are probably aware of Nintendo’s remarkable rendition of SimCity for the Super Nintendo Entertainment System. The cartridge launched alongside the system here in the United States, and brought the popular PC game to a brand new console audience. But did you know that Nintendo’s version of SimCity actually started life on the original 8-bit Nintendo Entertainment System?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This version of the game was announced at the same time as its 16-bit cousin, and was said to contain all of its same features. It made a brief appearance at the Winter Consumer Electronics Show in 1991, but was canceled soon after, and was never seen again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;bg-purple pa3 white br2 fr-l db dib-l tc w-33-l mv3 ml3-l&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;We’re preserving the history of video games, one byte at a time.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;link db mt3 white oswald ttu pv2 ph3 f4 primary-color-bg grow&quot; href=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/donate/&quot; title=&quot;Donate&quot;&gt;Donate Now&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This version of the game was thought to be completely lost or, at best, confined to some deep dark archive inside of Nintendo’s offices. Either way, the game was seen as something of a Holy Grail among collectors and archivists alike, and the odds of ever seeing it outside of a handful of published screenshots seemed slim, until a cartridge containing an unfinished version of the game materialized at 2017’s Portland Retro Gaming Expo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had the once-in-a-lifetime opportunity to digitize the game for its owner at the show, and thanks to two very generous collectors, we were able to spend the last few months tearing the game apart for the following deep-dive analysis. Seen here for the first time in nearly twenty-seven years, this is SimCity for the Nintendo Entertainment System.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/N0q93b_allY&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
Here it is – SimCity on the NES! This video condenses about three hours of standard gameplay, and takes advantage of a glitch that gives the player nearly unlimited money.
&lt;p&gt;At a glance, the game doesn’t look like much more than an inferior version of the SimCity we saw on the Super Nintendo. However, once put into context, this artifact becomes extraordinary, and gives us new insight into one of the most unlikely creative collaborations in video game history. And to understand just why that is, we’re going to have to give you a brief history lesson first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;f2 black-90 pb2 ph3 bb b--purple bw2 nl3 nr3 mb0&quot;&gt;The Birth of SimCity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The original version of SimCity was written by Will Wright for the Commodore 64 as a follow-up to his first game, 1984’s Raid on Bungeling Bay, a helicopter flight simulator that was published by Brøderbund.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Wright often tells it, the germ of an idea for SimCity actually evolved out of Bungeling Bay’s map editing tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I found out that I had a lot more fun building the islands than I did flying around in the helicopter,” Wright told GameSpot in &lt;a class=&quot;link primary-color&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/19990508174116/http://www.gamespot.com/features/maxis/page2.html&quot;&gt;a 1999 interview&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;db&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/image11.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1723&quot; src=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/image11.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;When building his first published game, Raid on Bungeling Bay, Will Wright found that laying out the buildings and roads of his islands was more fun than the actual game he’d made.
&lt;p&gt;Wright combined this city-building tool with his love of system dynamics, and began tinkering with what was essentially a toy to simulate the effects of economics and population growth on a virtual city: not necessarily as a game mechanic — at least, not yet — but more as a virtual sandbox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ironically, it was the success of Nintendo’s 8-bit console that allowed Wright the financial freedom to spend time tinkering with this experiment. In 1984 in Japan, software creator Hudson Soft was among the first third-party publishers to get in on the ground floor of selling games for Nintendo’s new hit console, the Family Computer – or as we know it, the NES. Among its first products was a conversion of Wright’s Raid on Bungeling Bay, the rights for which the company licensed from Brøderbund.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;db&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/bungeling_bay_box.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1715&quot; src=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/bungeling_bay_box.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The NES version of Raid on Bungeling Bay was a huge hit in Japan, which afforded Wright the luxury to work on SimCity for several years.
&lt;p&gt;Here in the U.S., the game had sold about 30,000 units for home computers, a number no doubt hampered by the Commodore 64’s rampant piracy. In Japan, where the Famicom’s early adopters were hungry for new games – and where piracy of its cartridge-based games was in its infancy – the game sold about 750,000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Back then the terms you got from the publishers was pretty generous, because they didn’t spend much on marketing or anything like that,” Wright said in &lt;a class=&quot;link primary-color&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://www.gamasutra.com/view/feature/134754/the_replay_interviews_will_wright.php&quot;&gt;an interview with Tristan Donovan&lt;/a&gt; for his history book Replay. “I earned enough off of that game to live for several years, and that’s when I was working on SimCity.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;db&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/image6.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1719&quot; src=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/image6.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The original SimCity was built for the Commodore 64, but wasn’t sold until years after its completion – publisher Brøderbund had a hard time seeing its potential.
&lt;p&gt;“After about six months or so I started attaching some graphics to it. It was fairly abstract to begin with,” &lt;a class=&quot;link primary-color&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://books.google.com/books?id=tGePP1Nu_P8C&amp;amp;pg=PA411&amp;amp;lpg=PA411&amp;amp;dq=%22After+about+six+months+or+so+I+started+attaching+some+graphics+to+it.%22&amp;amp;source=bl&amp;amp;ots=T_iP4AziAn&amp;amp;sig=LDhHQB3LB2HEHsAtSbGXJoA-kwk&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ved=2ahUKEwi6lpi4_rnfAhUBTd8KHSjwB9YQ6AEwBXoECAAQAQ#v=onepage&amp;amp;q=%22After%20about%20six%20months%20or%20so%20I%20started%20attaching%20some%20graphics%20to%20it.%22&amp;amp;f=false&quot;&gt;Wright told author Richard Rouse III&lt;/a&gt;. “And then I started thinking, you know, this might be an interesting game.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wright showed a prototype to friends at Brøderbund, who agreed to license the title from him as a commercial game. Wright continued to work on it for about a year, polishing it until he felt it was done, but Brøderbund was reluctant to publish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;db&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wright_and_braun.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1717&quot; src=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wright_and_braun.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Jeff Braun (left) and Will Wright (right) co-founded Maxis Software in 1987 in order to self-publish SimCity. The success of the game – and a licensing deal from Nintendo – helped to expand the studio exponentially.&lt;span class=&quot;db mt3 i&quot;&gt;Photo: Andy Freeberg, via Fortune magazine&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“They kept saying, ‘When is it going to be a game? When is it going to have a win/lose situation?'” Wright told Rouse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately Brøderbund decided not to market the game, and it remained dormant for years, until Wright showed it to Jeff Braun, who saw its commercial potential. Instead of finding another partner, the two co-founded their own software company, Maxis, and converted the game to the newer Amiga and Macintosh platforms, while also adding some new features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This simulation-based concept was practically a new genre for home computers, so the game was a slow burn after its February, 1989 release. But sales quickly ignited as word-of-mouth and press accolades spread. By 1992, the game would sell a million copies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;f2 black-90 pb2 ph3 bb b--purple bw2 nl3 nr3 mb0&quot;&gt;The Nintendo Connection&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;db&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/simcity/&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1723&quot; src=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/image10.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Nintendo designer Shigeru Miyamoto helps to promote the then-new Super Famicom console.
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile in Japan, Nintendo was planning software for its upcoming console successor, the Super Famicom. The company’s star designer, Mario and Zelda creator Shigeru Miyamoto, was tinkering with the idea of a city-building game, unaware that a game similar to what he had in mind already existed in SimCity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“When we were first developing game ideas for the Super Famicom, I proposed a game that allowed you to create your own world,” Miyamoto told Nintendo Power magazine for a feature published in its February, 1991 issue. “I was pleasantly surprised to find that a great game like the one I envisioned already existed in SimCity.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Negotiations began between Maxis and Nintendo to obtain the console rights to SimCity. A group of Nintendo employees, including Miyamoto, flew out to Maxis in Emeryville, California, and spent some time seeing the sights and getting to know the team. Eventually a deal was struck, with Nintendo paying an undisclosed amount of money. We still don’t know exactly how much, but one rumor from the time put the price tag north of $1 million.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s where things get really interesting. After the deal was signed, Will Wright was flown to Nintendo’s headquarters in Kyoto, where he and Miyamoto spent a week redesigning the game, moving it further away from its hardcore simulation roots and toward a Nintendo-friendly console game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think about this. In 1990, two famous game designers from opposite ends of the globe sat down and collaborated. The guy who just shipped SimCity, probably the most famous computer game at the time, and the guy who just shipped Super Mario Bros. 3, probably the most famous console game of the time, came together briefly to combine forces on a project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;db&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/miyamoto_wright.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1748&quot; src=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/miyamoto_wright.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Nintendo’s new, improved SimCity was the result of an international collaboration between superstar game designers Shigeru Miyamoto and Will Wright, who spent a week together in Kyoto and became fast friends.
&lt;p&gt;The unlikely combination of Miyamoto’s mastery of joyous movement and Wright’s fascination with computational systems merged beautifully into an experience that neither Maxis nor Nintendo could have accomplished on their own. SimCity, a mouse-driven game that seemed like it could only ever work on a computer, somehow evolved into a game that felt like it had always belonged on consoles, without losing anything in the process. It was a design miracle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What makes the NES SimCity find really remarkable from an historical perspective is that it was developed before the Super Nintendo version, which means that not only do we have the final product to come from this collaboration, we now also have a rough draft. The NES prototype gives us insight into some of those collaborative ideas that didn’t make the final cut! We’ll get into those later, but first we need a primer on the new ideas that came from the Wright-Miyamoto collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;f2 black-90 pb2 ph3 bb b--purple bw2 nl3 nr3 mb0&quot;&gt;Turning SimCity Into a Nintendo Game&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fr w-100 w-50-ns mb2 mt4 ml2-ns mr0&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/qwOk88bvDx4&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
Nintendo created a brand new character, Dr. Wright, to help add personality – as well as a friendly tutorial – to the game.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most memorable addition to Nintendo’s new version of SimCity was a cartoon virtual adviser, Dr. Wright (named, obviously, after Will Wright). While the original SimCity tossed players right into the simulation, expecting that they’d read the included documentation, Dr. Wright eased players into the experience by slowly explaining what might otherwise be complex mechanics. He also brought a fresh personality to the game, showing excitement when the player did well, comically tripping over himself, and even getting annoyed should the player bother him too much for advice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;db&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wright_animated_gif.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1714&quot; src=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wright_animated_gif.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Dr. Wright’s appearance in promotional artwork differed between the United States and Japan, where the character wore a bow tie and was depicted in brighter, bolder colors.
&lt;p&gt;A quick sidenote: did you know that the Japanese and American designs for Dr. Wright are different? In the U.S., his colors were toned down, and his bow tie changed to a more formal necktie. Perhaps this was just more relateable to Americans…or maybe Nintendo of America figured it only had room for one bow tie-wearing mascot – Game Counselor head and “Fun Club President” Howard Phillips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;db&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wright_origins.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1720&quot; src=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wright_origins.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Dr. Wright’s name and appearance was a tribute to SimCity creator Will Wright. Was the character’s bow tie removed from American marketing so as not to confuse the character with company spokesman Howard Phillips?
&lt;p&gt;Another much-needed addition was the bank loan. The original SimCity demanded the player spend their available funds very, very conservatively, because you can’t do anything in SimCity without money. You can’t grow your city, you can’t fix roads, and you certainly can’t respond to natural disasters. When a player ran out of money, it became a waiting game, with additional taxpayer money coming in only at the end of every virtual year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;dib w-100 w-50-ns&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/bankcomparison_01.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1751&quot; src=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/bankcomparison_01.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;dib w-100 w-50-ns&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/bankcomparison_02.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1751&quot; src=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/bankcomparison_02.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
The addition of a bank loan in Nintendo’s version of SimCity provided much-needed financial relief for players of the game, and ultimately made it more fun to play.
&lt;p&gt;While this is still true in Nintendo’s version, the bank alleviates this quite a bit, allowing players to take out a massive lump sum to be paid back in slow, small increments. The bank is also time-based, and appears right around when most players are running out of money. While additional funding was available in other versions of the game via what amounted to a cheat code, making this a part of the official game design was a much-welcomed acknowledgment that it actually made the game more fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most importantly of all, Nintendo’s version of SimCity finally managed to turn the simulation into a proper game. Wright’s original version for the Commodore 64 wasn’t meant to be a game, it was more of a simulation toybox. While its optional Scenario mode attempted to add traditional game mechanics, it comes across as a reluctant add-on, probably in response to Broderbund’s reluctance to sell the title. In fact, in the original Commodore 64 version, the scenarios had no win or lose parameters at all – at least, not in the software itself. Want to see if you can help San Francisco recover from an earthquake? If you’re the player, it’s all on you. The instructions tell you to load the pre-made San Francisco city layout, manually trigger an earthquake, and get to work. Whether you win or lose is entirely based on the honor system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;db&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/c64instructions.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1720&quot; src=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/c64instructions.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The original SimCity was built much more as a simulation toybox than a game. Any “game mechanics” were up to the player’s imaginations – even the win/lose parameters were up to the player to enforce on themselves.
&lt;p&gt;Maxis’ updated versions for the Amiga, Macintosh and later IBM PCs improved this feature somewhat. Now, a scenario’s disasters happen automatically, and players are given a time limit to solve the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is what passed for a game when it came to the computer version of SimCity. And while similar scenarios are available in the Nintendo version, it is a handful of simple but ingenious additions to the main simulation itself that finally brought the video game mechanics to SimCity that Brøderbund felt was missing. Any goals for virtual mayors on computers were entirely for them to decide and enforce. There was no end state, no congratulatory messaging…there wasn’t even a game over. A player could rack up an infinite amount of cash or an infinite amount of debt, the software just didn’t care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fr w-100 w-50-ns mv2 ml2-ns mr0&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/gqiSFhj3U6Y&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
Nintendo’s take on SimCity gives the player a sense of progression absent from the original. As their cities expand, they “level up,” from town to city to capital and all the way up to the rarely seen “Megalopolis.”&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This new design added just what SimCity always needed: a sense of progression. Players of Nintendo’s version would see their humble plots of land graduate as their populations grew, from a town to a city and beyond. Each time a population milestone was met, Dr. Wright would appear to congratulate the player. Afterward, the music itself that plays during the game would change, reflecting a city’s growing complexity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And in what is the most Miyamoto-esque touch of all, players would occasionally get presents as they progressed. The original SimCity never strayed from its default tile set: players could zone areas on the map to be residential, commercial or industrial, but it was up to them to imagine any fun buildings that might be in those zones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fr w-100 w-50-ns mv2 ml2-ns mr0&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/IDEYlzgXYMs&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
This version also awards the player with occasional “presents” in the form of fun new buildings to place on the map, a mechanic that feels like it may have been contributed by Miyamoto.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The present system allowed players to add some fun new pieces to the map, such as theme parks, zoos, and train stations. And they weren’t just fun to look at: they also increased the land value of surrounding tiles, adding a new layer of strategy for building a perfect city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of these new ideas were so good that Maxis would go on to use them in its own sequels. This new version of SimCity was undeniably an improvement on the original.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;f2 black-90 pb2 ph3 bb b--purple bw2 nl3 nr3 mb0&quot;&gt;The Announcement&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;db&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/SimCityJPNRelease-1-2.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1729&quot; src=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/SimCityJPNRelease-1-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Nintendo’s SimCity was announced to the world in the June 7, 1990 edition of The Nikkei, and shows that both the 8-bit NES and 16-bit SNES versions were announced at the same time – with the former being exclusive to the United States.
&lt;p&gt;We don’t know exactly when Wright’s week in Kyoto took place, but we do have a paper trail of when Nintendo and Maxis announced their partnership. The earliest report we could find was in the June 7, 1990 edition of The Nikkei (nick-kay). The story says that two versions of the game – a Super Famicom version in Japan and a Nintendo Entertainment System version in the United States – would be out in summer of 1991.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was true for the Super Famicom, which saw SimCity debut on April 26, 1991. An American release for the Super NES would follow when the system itself finally launched that August.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the NES version, it made one brief appearance at January 1991’s Winter Consumer Electronics Show. Outside of a small handful of players doing focus tests around this time, this was the only time anyone outside of Nintendo had seen this version of the game. Until now, this brief segment from an American television series called Video Power was the only footage anyone had ever seen of the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/2GSqc4mjh2o&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
The only time the NES version of SimCity was seen outside of Nintendo was at the Winter Consumer Electronics Show in January of 1991. This footage from the American television show Video Power was, for twenty-six years, the only known footage of the game.
&lt;p&gt;Sometime after this, we don’t know exactly when, the NES version of the game – still left incomplete – was quietly cancelled, and wouldn’t be seen again by the public for twenty-six years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;f2 black-90 pb2 ph3 bb b--purple bw2 nl3 nr3 mb0&quot;&gt;NES Prototype Find&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;db&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/prototype_find.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1730&quot; src=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/prototype_find.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;In 2017, two prototype cartridges for SimCity NES surfaced at a used video game store in Washington state. This still image comes from &lt;a class=&quot;link primary-color&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=V7-M_LcqJsc&quot;&gt;a video&lt;/a&gt; recorded by the store’s owner.
&lt;p&gt;In 2017, two playable prototype cartridges of the NES version of SimCity surfaced, when their owner brought them into a used game shop in the Seattle area. This was the first time the game had been seen by the public since its showing at CES.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unreleased games like these can be high-ticket items in the collector community. This is only compounded by it being a game made internally by Nintendo. Because of this, the original owner brought them both to the largest vintage video game collector show, Portland Retro Gaming Expo, to entertain offers. Ultimately, one of the cartridges was sold to a private collector, while the other remained with its original owner. And thanks to a financial contribution from one of our own board members, Steve Lin, we were able to take home a digital copy of the game to examine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fl w-100 w-50-ns mv2 mh0&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;db&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/proto_cart.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1744&quot; src=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/proto_cart.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;A close-up of one of the two prototype cartridges. This shell was used internally for testing at Nintendo, and provided easy access for removing and replacing the circuit board’s ROM chips in order to swap games.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fr w-100 w-50-ns mt2 mb3 pl2-ns mr0&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;db&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/christian_with_cart.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1746&quot; src=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/christian_with_cart.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;A deal was struck at the 2017 Portland Retro Gaming Expo by collector (and VGHF board member) Steve Lin to preserve the game’s data for educational use. Additionally, collector Christian Deitering (pictured) purchased one of the two cartridges to take home.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the show, we were able to confirm that the data on both cartridges is 100% identical, byte-for-byte. Further, we noted that one of the cartridges had a build date on its front label: December 20, 1990. A person familiar with the game’s development later explained to us that this particular cartridge was used to demonstrate the game to focus test groups. And given the date, it’s not unreasonable to assume that this is the same exact version of the game that was used at CES just a couple weeks later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;f2 black-90 pb2 ph3 bb b--purple bw2 nl3 nr3 mb0&quot;&gt;Examining the Game&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;db&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/nintendo_power_preview.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1731&quot; src=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/nintendo_power_preview.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The official American announcement for SimCity NES came via this page in the November/December 1991 issue of Nintendo Power, the company’s in-house magazine. Coincidentally, another game on this page, Earth Bound, was also unreleased.
&lt;p&gt;In its February, 1991 preview, Nintendo’s official in-house magazine, Nintendo Power, said that the differences between the Super Famicom and NES versions of the game “will be a matter of graphic detail only,” and having examined the game thoroughly, that’s mostly true. The core gameplay remains largely the same as the Maxis version, and the majority of the features added for the Super Famicom version of the game are present here – albeit some of them in skeletal or rough draft form.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To cut to the chase: This prototype is obviously not a finished game, as there are critical bugs, typos, and missing content, but the majority of the game’s features are intact in one form or another and the game is completely playable. Given the cartridge’s intended purpose, this shouldn’t come as a surprise. The game was never meant to be played outside of a controlled environment, whether it be a focus test with Nintendo employees present, or, as we suspect, a trade show, so there was no reason for it to be completely polished. The developers never anticipated historians somehow accessing this game nearly 30 years later and tearing it apart. They probably didn’t even expect anyone to play it for more than a few minutes! While theoretically players of this cartridge at the time could get far enough into the game to start noticing its flaws, this was extremely unlikely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;dib w-100 w-50-ns&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/donutcomparison_01.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1751&quot; src=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/donutcomparison_01.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;dib w-100 w-50-ns&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/donutcomparison_02.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1751&quot; src=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/donutcomparison_02.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
A popular strategy on the Super Nintendo version is to build “donuts,” increasing the property value of residential and commercial tiles by tiling them around a Present building. Because the tile sizes of presents and zones differ on the NES, this strategy is impossible.
&lt;p&gt;From a gameplay perspective, the most unique aspect of the NES version of SimCity is the size of its tiles. Rather than a typical tile (say, a residential zone) being a 3×3 grid, as they are in the original PC versions and the Super Nintendo version, NES zone tiles are 2×2. However, the Present tiles – the unique reward buildings added to the Nintendo versions of SimCity – are 3×3, meaning traditional strategies like building “donuts” will not work in the NES game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fr w-100 w-50-ns mv2 ml2-ns mr0&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/HmJP5EFUEpw&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
The NES version of SimCity featured a never-before-heard score by composer Soyo Oka. The entire sountrack is analyzed here by YouTube channel Retro Game Audio.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biggest surprise in the prototype was its completely unique soundtrack by Soyo Oka, the composer of Super Mario Kart and Pilotwings, among others. While Oka also wrote the music for the Super Nintendo version of SimCity, she composed her tracks uniquely for each platform. In fact, only one track, the “Metropolis Theme,” is common between the two versions. She was obviously attached to it, as she was once quoted in an interview as saying that this specific track was one of her best compositions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;pt3&quot;&gt;What’s Here&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s start our examination of the NES prototype by showing what it has in common with the Super Nintendo version. As we go through these, it’s worth keeping in mind that the majority of the NES version is believed to have been developed prior to starting over on the Super Nintendo. This is not a 100% confirmed fact, but it’s how Soyo Oka remembered things in an interview. A source familiar with the game’s development also independently told us this was their recollection, and even provided some vintage documentation that seems to back this memory up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;dib w-100 w-50-ns&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/titlecomparison_01.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1751&quot; src=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/titlecomparison_01.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;dib w-100 w-50-ns&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/titlecomparison_02.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1751&quot; src=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/titlecomparison_02.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
The title screens for the NES and SNES versions of the game feature similar layouts, though the cityscape scrolls in the more advanced 16-bit version.
&lt;div&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;db&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/ui_comparison_gif.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1751&quot; src=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/ui_comparison_gif.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
The screen flow and much of the UI design of the Super Nintendo version had its origin in the original NES game.
&lt;p&gt;First, the title screen itself. Both feature a similar design, with Maxis’ original SimCity logo floating over a thriving city at night. The Super Nintendo refresh flexed its muscles by having the city scroll.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The in-game UI shares what more or less amounts to the same layout, with some minor rearrangement in the Super Nintendo version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fr w-100 w-50-ns mv2 ml2-ns mr0&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/kB0iigd6Nys&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
Dr. Wright’s original NES appearance saw him wearing the neck tie seen in the character’s American marketing art. This character design was never seen in a commercially-released game.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr. Wright is here, and has a lot of the same animations as he would later have in the Super Nintendo version, along with many similar messages. Remember the regional design differences noted above, with Wright’s bowtie changing into a necktie? Look closely: the NES version uses the American design of the character, while the SNES game – even in the U.S. – uses his Japanese design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fr w-100 w-50-ns mv2 ml2-ns mr0&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ltW949eWoUc&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
The NES version of the game’s bank loan screen featured a completely unique bank manager character that didn’t make the transition to the Super Nintendo game.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new bank loan mechanic is in both versions, and behaves exactly the same way. Although in the NES version, we’re treated to a unique sprite of what must be the bank’s manager, giving us a tiny glimpse into what other people must look like in Dr. Wright’s world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And finally, the majority of the quality-of-life improvements that are unique to the Super Nintendo version made their debut here. The color palettes change with the seasons, presents are awarded when reaching certain milestones, and as the player’s city grows, so does the complexity of the game’s soundtrack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;pt3&quot;&gt;What’s Different&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see, most of the new core features added to the Super Nintendo game were present in the NES prototype, but there were also some features that are exclusively in this version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s a very EarthBound-like feature completely unique to the NES version. When creating a new city, the game asks you to type your favorite word, not explaining why. As the game progresses, the word players typed in makes a surprise appearance as the name of their “sister city.” It’s a very Nintendo touch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;dib w-100 w-50-ns&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/favoriteword_01.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1751&quot; src=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/favoriteword_01.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;dib w-100 w-50-ns&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/favoriteword_02.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1751&quot; src=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/favoriteword_02.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
In a screen reminiscent of EarthBound, the NES version of SimCity asks the player for their favorite word at the start of the game, without explaining why. It finally pays off late in the game as the name of the player’s “sister city.”
&lt;div class=&quot;fr w-100 w-50-ns mv2 ml2-ns mr0&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/NzcZd7nlpzc&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
The NES version of SimCity shares a lot of its design DNA with the original Macintosh version, which Nintendo’s developers were referencing for the port. This includes voice samples playing from the in-game traffic helicopter, despite the extreme cost of ROM space.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are still a few elements in the NES version specifically that harken back to the original Maxis release for the Macintosh, which Nintendo’s developers were clearly referencing when making this port. Check out the UI for the budget screen, which is practically identical, down to the hourglass and the giant Mac-like button to click on the bottom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the SNES saw a similar screen, what’s unique in the NES game is its speech samples. Just like in the Mac version, the NES game plays a sample when a helicopter floats over heavy traffic, or when a monster is on screen. These samples actually eat up a surprisingly large amount of ROM space.&lt;/p&gt;

The evolution of SimCity’s monster, from the Maxis version’s obvious Godzilla homage, to the NES prototype’s more generic beast and, finally, to the Super Nintendo version replacing the monster with Bowser from the Super Mario Bros. series.
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of the monster, it’s still a generic beast in the NES game. On the Super Nintendo, this was changed to Bowser, from the Super Mario Bros. series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;pt3&quot;&gt;What’s Missing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the flipside, some features that made it to the Super Nintendo are not present here. For one, anything that used the Super Nintendo’s sprite scaling and rotation features, such as the magnifying glass, just aren’t present on the NES.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;dib w-100 w-50-ns&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/sneseffects_01.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1751&quot; src=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/sneseffects_01.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;dib w-100 w-50-ns&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/sneseffects_02.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1751&quot; src=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/sneseffects_02.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Features such as these were added specifically for the Super Nintendo version to show off the hardware’s scaling and sprite layer capabilities. These features would not have been possible on the Macintosh or NES games. &lt;a class=&quot;db tc&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/ufo_animation.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1723&quot; src=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/ufo_animation.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Tiles for the UFO are present inside of the NES game’s data, but are never used in the game itself. The color palette and animation seen here were made up – there is no palette or animation data present yet in the ROM.
&lt;p&gt;There was also a unique level on the Super Nintendo: once players completed all six scenarios, two new ones opened up, including a UFO attack on Las Vegas. That scenario was not present in the original Maxis release, though UFOs would make appearances in subsequent sequels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While this feature is technically in the NES game, the city scenario is a placeholder, with no UFO ever appearing…though if you dig into the ROM, the tiles are there for it, they just never get called. A disassembly of the code reveals that there isn’t even a function in the game to call for them yet, they’re just art tiles waiting to be programmed into the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;pt3&quot;&gt;What’s Broken&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only is the game is unfinished, we were able to confirm with an inside source that the game was NEVER finished, so what we see here is probably the best we could ever hope to see. Just in case, we closely examined every published promotional screenshot of the game, including those found on what would have been the game’s box art, and all of them appear to be from even earlier versions than this. If the game got any further along than the data on this prototype suggests, it was never shown to anyone. This appears to be the last build of the game that Nintendo’s developers in Japan ever sent to the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;db pa2&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/comparison_image.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/comparison_image.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Despite being unfinished, a close examination of every published screenshot of SimCity for the NES reveals that the data on the prototype cartridge is further along in development than anything previously seen.
&lt;p&gt;One big core problem with the prototype is in its math. Land value just doesn’t seem to function properly, especially with the presents. In the Super Nintendo version, presents would increase the land value of the tiles in its vicinity. Here, they don’t seem to do anything, which means that from a strategic standpoint presents work against you, as you’re wasting valuable tile space for no benefit. The game is still completely playable, but fans of the Super Nintendo version may notice their cities growing much slower, and sometimes declining for no observable reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fr w-100 w-50-ns mv2 ml2-ns mr0&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ve4AyCz03Z4&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
An easy way to get infinite money on NES SimCity – simply owe the bank more money at the end of the year than you have. The dollar amount rolls around into a negative value and overflows.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One bug that may actually be intentional for the sake of the demo is that it’s possible to receive infinite money. In other versions of the game, if your spending for the year exceeded your collected taxes, you’d have a negative amount of money in the bank. In the NES prototype, if you owe the bank more money at the end of the year than you have, your funds roll over into a huge positive sum, completely eliminating any challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;db&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/boat_tiles.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/boat_tiles.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Most of the boat tiles and some partial floating behavior exist in the NES ROM, but are never used during normal gameplay.
&lt;p&gt;Something completely absent in the NES version of the game is boats. Normally, when players build a seaport, boats start floating around in the city’s water – and even evolve in appearance depending on the in-game year. In the NES prototype, the boat tiles are mostly present and accounted for, and there’s even some partial movement behavior in the game’s code, but the boats never appear through normal gameplay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The prototype’s Practice scenario, despite having a clear goal, has no win or lose state. Like the boats, code exists in the ROM itself to trigger these win or lose messages, it’s just never called by the game. This might have been intentional – perhaps the developers commented this functionality out for this build of the game, so that the game could run indefinitely without being interrupted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;f2 black-90 pb2 ph3 bb b--purple bw2 nl3 nr3 mb0&quot;&gt;Digital Archaeology&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And on that note, there’s actually a lot of unused information in the ROM itself that is never accessed through normal gameplay. There may be more unused art in this ROM file than in any known commercial NES game. This is really exciting. Not only do we have a rough draft of the Wright-Miyamoto collaborative take on SimCity, we also have glimpses into even earlier ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;db tc pb3&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/botanical_garden.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1723&quot; src=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/botanical_garden.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The Botanical Garden was an early present that didn’t make the final cut – either in the NES or Super NES versions of the game.
&lt;p&gt;For example, here’s a unique present: the Botanical Garden. Unfortunately there doesn’t appear to be any code left in the game to tell us how this might have been earned, so we’ll probably never know, but the tiles themselves are completely intact. This might have been one of the earliest presents conceived, as its name appears among a handful of other present names in a completely unused section of tile data, suggesting an earlier implementation of the Presents mechanic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of unused tiles, there are quite a few sports structures present, including a couple baseball stadiums and what appears to be a horse track. There actually isn’t animation or color palette data for these tiles, so what you’re seeing here are my best guesses for what they’d look like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;dib tc pv3 ph2 w-33&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/unused_sports_1.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1723&quot; src=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/unused_sports_1.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;dib tc pv3 ph2 w-33&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/unused_sports_2.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1723&quot; src=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/unused_sports_2.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;dib tc pv3 ph2 w-33&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/unused_sports_3.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1723&quot; src=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/unused_sports_3.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The only sports structure ever used in the game is a football stadium, but tiles exist for two baseball fields and what appears to be a horse track. The color palette applied here is a best guess based on palettes in the ROM, while the animation frame order and speed are pure guesswork.
&lt;p&gt;There are also two unused airport tiles…perhaps they were meant to evolve with time, as the airplanes themselves do? We’re not sure, as no version of the original SimCity to my knowledge has varying airports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;dib tc pv3 ph2 w-33&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/unused_airport_1.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1723&quot; src=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/unused_airport_1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;dib tc pv3 ph2 w-33&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/unused_airport_2.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1723&quot; src=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/unused_airport_2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Two unused airport designs can be found in the ROM’s tile data. Their usage in the game is unknown.
&lt;p&gt;The Mayor’s House present has three unused versions too. In the Super Nintendo game, your house grew along with the city’s population, so it’s likely that was the intended use here too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;dib tc pv3 ph2 w-33&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/unused_house_1.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1723&quot; src=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/unused_house_1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;dib tc pv3 ph2 w-33&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/unused_house_2.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1723&quot; src=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/unused_house_2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;dib tc pv3 ph2 w-33&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/unused_house_3.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1723&quot; src=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/unused_house_3.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;In the Super Nintendo version of the game, the mayor’s house tile would evolve as their city grew larger. Tiles to support this feature are in the NES ROM, but are never used in the game.
&lt;p&gt;Four unused Dr. Wright animations are present in the ROM, and can be accessed by hacking the game. All four would go on to appear in the Super Nintendo version. Two of these flicker badly on a real NES due to its limitation of showing only eight sprites per scanline – this restriction was removed via emulation for the sake of this video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/EbXMQWJg_Ek&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
Four unused Dr. Wright animations are present in the ROM, and can be accessed by hacking the game. All four would go on to appear in the Super Nintendo version. Two of these flicker badly on a real NES due to its limitation of showing only eight sprites per scanline – this restriction was removed via emulation for the sake of this video.
&lt;h2 class=&quot;f2 black-90 pb2 ph3 bb b--purple bw2 nl3 nr3 mb0&quot;&gt;The SimCity Digital Archive&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fr w-100 w-50-ns mv2 ml2-ns mr0&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/X0pAbaw5X-Q&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
Thanks to an extensive disassembly by CaH4e3, the game’s boat functionality has been partially restored.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s actually a whole lot more to dig into in the game’s code. Friend of the foundation and NES expert &lt;a class=&quot;link primary-color&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;http://cah4e3.shedevr.org.ru/&quot;&gt;CaH4e3&lt;/a&gt; (pronounced “Sanchez”) has spent several months doing a complete, commented disassembly of the game, along with extensive documentation of cut features, oddities, and other findings from his extensive archaeological dig. He even fixed bugs and started implementing cut features, including the lost boats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And hey, remember how I said that one of the prototype cartridges was sold to a collector? That’s our friend Christian Deitering, who has created an incredibly extensive guide for the NES prototype at GameFAQs, among other places.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And finally, the digital ROM file itself was uploaded to the internet by Steve Lin, and should be playable on just about any modern NES emulator that supports games running on MMC5 hardware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;db bg-black-10 pa3 mv3 br2 tc&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;db&quot;/&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;db mt3&quot;&gt;Check out the &lt;a class=&quot;link primary-color&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://archive.org/details/simcity-nes&quot;&gt;SimCity NES Prototype Archive&lt;/a&gt; at the Internet Archive!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;f2 black-90 pb2 ph3 bb b--purple bw2 nl3 nr3 mb0&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see, the recovery and study of artifacts such as these is only made possible through a group effort. From the archiving of the game to the interpretation of its worth and everything in-between, the story of SimCity for the NES – a game that could easily have been lost forever – could only be told thanks to the combined work of archivists, historians, collectors, and financial benefactors working together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Special thanks to Steve Lin, Christian Deitering, CaH4e3, LuigiBlood, Chris Covell, Kelsey Lewin, Patrick Todd, Adam Patrick Murray, and especially to our ongoing patrons for making this all of this possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to help save video game history along with us, head on over to &lt;a class=&quot;link primary-color&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;http://gamehistory.org/donate&quot;&gt;our donation page&lt;/a&gt; to learn how you can get involved. Everything we do here is publicly funded by people just like you, and every single dollar we receive helps make it all possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;bg-purple pa3 white br2 db tc w-100 mv3&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;db&quot;&gt;We’re preserving the history of video games, one byte at a time.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;link dib mt3 white oswald ttu pv2 ph3 f4 primary-color-bg grow&quot; href=&quot;https://gamehistory.org/donate/&quot; title=&quot;Donate&quot;&gt;Donate Now&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 26 Dec 2018 01:05:22 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>em3rgent0rdr</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://gamehistory.org/simcity/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>New Office Hours Aim for Well Rested, More Productive Workers</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/12/24/well/mind/work-schedule-hours-sleep-productivity-chronotype-night-owls.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2018/12/24/well/mind/work-schedule-hours-sleep-productivity-chronotype-night-owls.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;css-u5vfum StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;A few years ago, scientists conducted a &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/25772446&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;real-world experiment at a ThyssenKrupp steel factory&lt;/a&gt; in Germany. They assigned the day shift to early risers and the late shift to night owls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Soon the steel workers, many of whom had been skeptical at the outset, were getting an extra hour of sleep on work nights. By simply aligning work schedules with people’s internal clocks, the researchers had helped people get more and better rest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“They got 16 percent more sleep, almost a full night’s length over the course of the week,” said Till Roenneberg, a chronobiologist at Ludwig-Maximilian University in Munich, who headed the study. “That is enormous.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;In recent years, American educators have been paying increased attention to their students’ sleep needs, with &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/09/07/us/california-school-start-times.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;growing debate about delaying school start times&lt;/a&gt;. Now a number of businesses are following suit, encouraging their employees to work when their bodies are most awake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-1m2ozyi&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;css-u5vfum StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“It’s a huge financial burden not to sleep properly,” Dr. Roenneberg said. “The estimates go toward 1 percent of gross national product,” both in the United States and Germany.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Emerging science reveals that each of us has an optimal time to fall asleep and wake up, a personalized biological rhythm known as a “chronotype.” When you don’t sleep at the time your body wants to sleep — your so-called biological night — you don’t sleep as well or as long, setting the stage not only for fatigue, poor work performance and errors but also health problems ranging from heart disease and obesity to anxiety and depression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;A full 80 percent of people have work schedules that clash with their internal clocks, said Céline Vetter, an assistant professor at the University of Colorado at Boulder and director of the university’s circadian and sleep epidemiology lab. “The problem is huge,” Dr. Vetter said. “If we consider your individual chronotype and your work hours, the chances are very high that there’s quite a bit of misalignment.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Put it this way: If you rely on an alarm clock to wake up, you’re out of sync with your own biology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Studies on workers in the call center of a &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;http://www.producao.ufrgs.br/arquivos/publicacoes/59_art01.pdf&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;mobile phone company&lt;/a&gt;, a &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://content.iospress.com/articles/work/wor0371&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;packaging manufacturer&lt;/a&gt; and an &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;http://www.producao.ufrgs.br/arquivos/publicacoes/68_art10.pdf&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;oil transportation company&lt;/a&gt; show that these employees are more stressed and may experience more work-related discomfort and pain. It’s the mismatch — not the hours themselves — that matters. &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;http://care.diabetesjournals.org/content/38/9/1707&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;A 2015 Harvard Medical School study&lt;/a&gt; found that for night owls, working during the day increases diabetes risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-1m2ozyi&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-u5vfum StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Among the companies seeking to remedy the problem is Southwest Airlines, which allows pilots to choose between morning and evening flight schedules. The United States Navy recently traded an 18-hour submarine shift schedule for a 24-hour one that more closely matches sailors’ biological rhythms. And at some pharmaceutical, software and financial companies, managers expect employees to come to the office for only a few hours in the middle of the day — or to work off site entirely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“I think circadian rhythms will be a huge issue for human resources in the future,” said Camilla Kring, a Danish consultant who has helped employees at AbbVie, Roche, Medtronic and other companies learn to respect their natural sleep cycles. “It really makes sense to think about when people have the most energy and when they’re peaking mentally.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Worker fatigue has played a role in many workplace accidents, most famously the &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2517096/&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Challenger space shuttle explosion&lt;/a&gt; and the Exxon Valdez oil spill, but no doubt countless more on the commute to and from work. The National Highway Traffic Safety Administration estimates that drowsy drivers cause 16.5 percent of fatal crashes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;A &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nsc.org/work-safety/safety-topics/fatigue/survey-report&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;survey released last year by the National Safety Council&lt;/a&gt; found that 97 percent of workers have at least one risk factor for fatigue, with 27 percent reporting having unintentionally fallen asleep on the job in the previous month and 16 percent that they had experienced at least one safety incident because of fatigue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“We have a 24/7 society, so we knew fatigue was definitely affecting part of our work force,” said Emily Whitcomb, senior program manager of the council’s fatigue initiative. “But we did not anticipate that fatigue was going to be affecting almost 100 percent of our work force.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Sleep deprivation may even lead to ethical breaches at work. In a &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0956797614541989&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;2014 experiment&lt;/a&gt;, Christopher Barnes of the University of Washington and colleagues asked 142 people with extreme chronotypes to show up at their laboratory either at 7 a.m. or at midnight for a dice-rolling game that offered a $500 prize. Reporting was on the honor system. Morning people lied 18 percent more when they did the task at midnight than when they did it in the morning, whereas night owls lied 16 percent more when doing the task at 7 a.m.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Dr. Roenneberg has collected data from 300,000 people and found that chronotypes plot as a bell-shaped curve, with a few individuals at each extreme and most falling somewhere in the middle. According to Dr. Roenneberg’s research, the most frequent chronotype — held by about 13 percent of the population — sleeps from around midnight to 8 a.m. Thirty-one percent of people have an earlier natural bedtime, and 56 percent have a later one. That means for at least 69 percent of the population, getting to the office by 8 or 9 a.m. requires waking up before their body is ready.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-1m2ozyi&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-u5vfum StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Not all experts acknowledge such fine-grained distinctions, instead grouping people into morning, evening and “intermediate” types. Regardless, while true “larks” and “owls” &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/08/25/style/sleep-problem-late-night.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;tend to dominate the conversation&lt;/a&gt;, they make up a small percentage of the population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;To determine your chronotype, imagine that you have two weeks of vacation to spend as you like, with no evening or morning commitments and no pets or children to wake you. Chronotypes reflect habits as well as biology, so you would also need to eliminate caffeine and avoid artificial light at night, which pushes a person’s chronotype later. At what time would you tend to fall asleep and wake up? Don’t be surprised if you’re unsure. After years spent accommodating work, family and social commitments at the expense of sleep, “a lot of people don’t know what rhythm they have,” Ms. Kring said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;css-11q3cgf ewiwup50&quot;/&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Chronotypes shift in a predictable way over the course of a lifetime. Between the ages of 12 and 21, everyone’s natural sleep schedule gets about 2 1/2 hours later — which is why adolescents have so much trouble waking up for school. After that, chronotype creeps in the other direction, which is why older people typically find themselves waking earlier than they used to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;But chronotype determines more than when you sleep and wake. It orchestrates predictable peaks and troughs of energy over the course of the 24-hour day. The so-called “window of circadian low” — the hours when the body is least adapted for wakefulness — typically occurs between 2 a.m. and 6 a.m. There’s another, smaller dip 12 hours later, in the midafternoon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;There are also two high points, when thinking is sharp and reaction times quick. One occurs within an hour or two after waking, and the other after the daytime dip. This cycle is shifted earlier in a morning person and later in an evening or night person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;At the Denmark offices of the pharmaceutical company AbbVie, employees design work schedules that take advantage of their biological strengths. A nine-hour training program helps them identify when they are ripe for creative or challenging projects, typically mornings for early risers and afternoons for late risers. Lower-energy periods are meant for more mundane tasks, like handling emails or doing administrative chores. Workers save commuting time by avoiding rush hour traffic, and can better mesh their personal and professional lives — for example, by getting their children from school in the afternoon, then working from home in the evening after the kids are in bed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Employee satisfaction with work-life balance has risen from 39 percent 10 years ago, when the program launched, to nearly 100 percent today, according to company surveys. Last year the Denmark division of Great Place to Work, a global organization that ranks companies based on employee satisfaction, named AbbVie the top middle-size company in the country. “The flexibility actually empowers people to deliver the best possible results,” said Christina Jeppesen, the company’s general manager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-1m2ozyi&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-u5vfum StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;A 2018 survey by the Society for Human Resource Management, which represents 300,000 H.R. professionals in more than 165 countries, found that 57 percent of its members offer flexible hours, 5 percent more than in 2014. “Managers who give it a try often find that employees’ morale, engagement and productivity all go up, because they are working at a time that works best for them, and able to get the most work done,” said Lisa Horn, the group’s vice president of congressional affairs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Some companies restrict meetings to “core hours,” between, say, 10 a.m. and 3 p.m., to accommodate various schedules. Others build flextime into the workweek. At Phase 2, a software development firm in Oklahoma City, each week ends with “productivity Friday,” when employees are expected to work remotely in a place of their choice — whether that be from home, a coffee shop or at a weekend house at the lake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Stefan Volk, a senior lecturer at the University of Sydney Business School, has suggested that businesses can leverage chronotypes to maximize team success. For example, members of a surgery team should have similar chronotypes because they need to be in top form simultaneously. But at a nuclear power plant, workers should have different energy peaks, so that someone is always on the alert.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;But while lots of corporations promise flexibility, veering from the traditional 9 to 5 work hours requires a cultural shift. A &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/record/2014-23623-001&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;2014 study led by Dr. Barnes&lt;/a&gt; found that many managers have an ingrained prejudice in favor of early birds, whom they perceived as more conscientious simply because they arrived at work early, a view that could dissuade some workers from using flextime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;But sticking to traditional hours can be counterproductive, leading to “presenteeism” — employees showing up and being only minimally functional. “Companies are wasting the potential of their people,” Dr. Volk said. “You have someone sitting there from 7 til 9 a.m. sipping coffee, being completely unproductive, and then you send them home at 4 when they actually start getting productive.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;For many office workers, the answer may be as simple as delaying work start times an hour or two — say until 9:30 or 10 a.m. Since many people are in the middle of the chronotype continuum and wake naturally around 8 or 9 a.m., such a modest shift could provide widespread relief. “We’re talking about one hour,” Ms. Kring said, “not a revolution.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-1m2ozyi&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 26 Dec 2018 00:19:54 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>acjohnson55</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/12/24/well/mind/work-schedule-hours-sleep-productivity-chronotype-night-owls.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>New Office Hours Aim for Well Rested, More Productive Workers</og:title>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/12/25/science/25CHRONOGRAPH-GIF/25CHRONOGRAPH-GIF-facebookJumbo.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>A growing number of businesses are encouraging their employees to work when their bodies are most awake.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/12/24/well/mind/work-schedule-hours-sleep-productivity-chronotype-night-owls.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Machine learning has become alchemy (2017) [video]</title>
<link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=x7psGHgatGM</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=x7psGHgatGM</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=x7psGHgatGM&quot;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=x7psGHgatGM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=18759241&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=18759241&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 232&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 111&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 25 Dec 2018 21:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>henning</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=x7psGHgatGM</og:url>
<og:title>NIPS 2017 Test of Time Award &quot;Machine learning has become alchemy.” | Ali Rahimi, Google</og:title>
<og:image>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/x7psGHgatGM/maxresdefault.jpg</og:image>
<og:description> </og:description>
<og:type>video.other</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=x7psGHgatGM</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Deciphering the postcard-sized raytracer</title>
<link>https://fabiensanglard.net/postcard_pathtracer/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://fabiensanglard.net/postcard_pathtracer/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;F S(V p,I&amp;amp;m){F d=1\ e9;V f=p;f.z=0;char l[]=&quot;5O5_5W9W5_9_COC_AOEOA_E_IOQ_I_QOUOY_Y_]OWW[WaOa_aW\ eWa_e_cWiO&quot;;for(I i=0;i0?f\ absf(sqrtf(o%o)-2):(o.y+=o.y&amp;gt;0?-2:2,sqrtf(o%o)));}d=powf(powf(d,8)+powf(p.z, 8),.125)-.5;m=1;F r=L(-L(B(p,V(-30,-.5,-30),V(30,18,30)),B(p,V(-25,17,-25),V (25,20,25))),B(V(fmodf(fabsf(p.x),8),p.y,p.z),V(1.5,18.5,-25),V(6.5,20,25))) ;if(r&lt;d s=&quot;19.9-p.y;if(s&amp;lt;d)d=s,m=3;R&quot; d=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;241.67849381791&quot;&gt;I M(V o,V d,V&amp;amp;h,V&amp;amp;n){I m,s= 0;F t=0,c;for(;t99)R n=!V(S(h+V(.01,0 ),s)-c,S(h+V(0,.01),s)-c,S(h+V(0,0,.01),s)-c),m;R 0;}
&lt;div readability=&quot;104&quot;&gt;V T(V o,V d){V h,n,r,t= 1,l(!V(.6,.6,1));for(I b=3;b--;){I m=M(o,d,h,n);if(!m)break;if(m==1){d=d+n*( n%d*-2);o=h+d*.1;t=t*.2;}if(m==2){F i=n%l,p=6.283185*U(),c=U(),s=sqrtf(1-c), g=n.z0&amp;amp;&amp;amp;M(h +n*.1,l,h,n)==3)r=r+t*V(500,400,100)*i;}if(m==3){r=r+t*V(50,80,100);break;}} R r;}
&lt;div readability=&quot;154&quot;&gt;I main(){I w=960,h=540,s=16;V e(-22,5,25),g=!(V(-3,4,0)+e*-1),l=!V(g.z, 0,-g.x)*(1./w),u(g.y*l.z-g.z*l.y,g.z*l.x-g.x*l.z,g.x*l.y-g.y*l.x);printf(&quot;P\ 6 %d %d 255 &quot;,w,h);for(I y=h;y--;)for(I x=w;x--;){V c;for(I p=s;p--;)c=c+T(e ,!(g+l*(x-w/2+U())+u*(y-h/2+U())));c=c*(1./s)+14./241;V o=c+1;c=V(c.x/o.x,c. y/o.y,c.z/o.z)*255;printf(&quot;%c%c%c&quot;,(I)c.x,(I)c.y,(I)c.z);}}
&lt;p&gt;// Andrew Kensler&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each section is described in detail in the rest of the article:&lt;/p&gt;

usual tricks,

Vector class,

Utils,

Database,

Ray marching,

Sampling,

main.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Usual #define and typedef tricks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;The usual tricks are the usage of #define and typedef to drastically shorten the notation. Here, we have F=float, I=int, R=return, and O=operator. These are trivial to reverse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;V class&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Next is the V class which I renamed Vec (even though it is also used to store RGB float channels as we will see later).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span&gt;struct&lt;/span&gt; Vec &lt;span&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span&gt;float&lt;/span&gt; x&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; y&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; z&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;

    Vec&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;float&lt;/span&gt; v &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; x &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; y &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; z &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; v&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
    Vec&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;float&lt;/span&gt; a&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;float&lt;/span&gt; b&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;float&lt;/span&gt; c &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; x &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; a&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; y &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; b&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; z &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; c&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

    Vec &lt;span&gt;operator&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;+&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;Vec r&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; Vec&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;x &lt;span&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; r&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;x&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; y &lt;span&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; r&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;y&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; z &lt;span&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; r&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;z&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
    Vec &lt;span&gt;operator&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;Vec r&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; Vec&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;x &lt;span&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; r&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;x&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; y &lt;span&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; r&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;y&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; z &lt;span&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; r&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;z&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span&gt;// dot product&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span&gt;float&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;operator&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;%&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;Vec r&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; x &lt;span&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; r&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;x &lt;span&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; y &lt;span&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; r&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;y &lt;span&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; z &lt;span&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; r&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;z&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span&gt;// inverse square root&lt;/span&gt;
    Vec &lt;span&gt;operator&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;this&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;1&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; sqrtf&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;this&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;%&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;this&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice the absence of subtraction (-) operator so instead of writing &quot;X = A - B&quot;, we will see &quot;X = A + B * -1&quot;. The inverse square root is useful to normalize vectors later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Main function&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;main() is the one symbol that cannot be obfuscated since it is called by libc's _start function. It is usually a good place to start working and a low hanging fruit. It took a bit of guessing from the first letter of the symbols, and a bit of fuzzing but I was able to get something readable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span&gt;int&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;main&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;int&lt;/span&gt; w &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;960&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; h &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;540&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; samplesCount &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;16&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
  Vec position&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;22&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;25&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
  Vec goal &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;Vec&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; position &lt;span&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
  Vec left &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;!&lt;/span&gt;Vec&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;goal&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;z&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;goal&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;x&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; w&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;

  &lt;span&gt;// Cross-product to get the up vector&lt;/span&gt;
  Vec up&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;goal&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;y &lt;span&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; left&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;z &lt;span&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; goal&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;z &lt;span&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; left&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;y&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
         goal&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;z &lt;span&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; left&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;x &lt;span&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; goal&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;x &lt;span&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; left&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;z&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
         goal&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;x &lt;span&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; left&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;y &lt;span&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; goal&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;y &lt;span&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; left&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;x&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;

  &lt;span&gt;printf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;P6 &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;%d&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;%d&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; 255 &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; w&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; h&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;int&lt;/span&gt; y &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; h&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; y&lt;span&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;int&lt;/span&gt; x &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; w&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; x&lt;span&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
      Vec color&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;int&lt;/span&gt; p &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; samplesCount&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; p&lt;span&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
        color &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; color &lt;span&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; Trace&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;position&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;goal &lt;span&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; left &lt;span&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;x &lt;span&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; w &lt;span&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;2&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; randomVal&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; 
        up &lt;span&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;y &lt;span&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; h &lt;span&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;2&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; randomVal&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;

      &lt;span&gt;// Reinhard tone mapping&lt;/span&gt;
      color &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; color &lt;span&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; samplesCount&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;14&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;241&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
      Vec o &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; color &lt;span&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
      color &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; Vec&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;color&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;x &lt;span&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; o&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;x&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; color&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;y &lt;span&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; o&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;y&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; color&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;z &lt;span&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; o&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;z&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;255&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span&gt;printf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;%c&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;%c&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;%c&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;int&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; color&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;x&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;int&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; color&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;y&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;int&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; color&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;z&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice how the float type literals have no &quot;f&quot; and how the fractional part is omitted in order to save space. The same trick is used later where the integer part is omitted (float x = .5). The &quot;for&quot; statement is also unusual with the iteration expression blended inside the stop condition.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a pretty standard main function for a raytracer/pathtracer. Camera vectors are defined and for each pixel, rays are cast. The difference between a raytracer and a path tracer is that in a path tracer, several rays are cast per pixel and they are slightly nudged at random. Then the color retrieved for each ray in a pixel is accumulated in three float R,B,G channels. At the end, the result is tone-mapped with Reinhard's method.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The most important part is the sampleCount which can be set to 1 to speedup rendition and iterate faster on hypothesis. Here are renditions with sample values ranging from 1 to 2048.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://fabiensanglard.net/postcard_pathtracer/vanilla2048.png&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; id=&quot;sampleCountTestImage.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Utils&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another set of low hanging fruits are the utility functions. In this occurrence we have a trivial min() function, a random value [0,1] generator, and a much more interesting boxTest() which is part of the Constructive Solid Geometry (CSG) system used to carve the world. CSG is explained in the next section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span&gt;float&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;min&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;float&lt;/span&gt; l&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;float&lt;/span&gt; r&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; l &lt;span&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; r &lt;span&gt;?&lt;/span&gt; l &lt;span&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; r&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span&gt;float&lt;/span&gt; randomVal&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;float&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;rand&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; RAND_MAX&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span&gt;// Rectangle CSG equation. Returns minimum signed distance from &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span&gt;// space carved by lowerLeft vertex and opposite rectangle&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span&gt;// vertex upperRight.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span&gt;float&lt;/span&gt; BoxTest&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;Vec position&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; Vec lowerLeft&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; Vec upperRight&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
  lowerLeft &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; position &lt;span&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; lowerLeft &lt;span&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
  upperRight &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; upperRight &lt;span&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; position &lt;span&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;min&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span&gt;min&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span&gt;min&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;lowerLeft&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;x&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; upperRight&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;x&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
      &lt;span&gt;min&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;lowerLeft&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;y&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; upperRight&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;y&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
    &lt;span&gt;min&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;lowerLeft&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;z&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; upperRight&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;z&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Constructive Solid Geometry functions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are no vertices in the code. Everything is done with CSG functions. If you are unfamiliar with them, let's just say that they are functions describing if a coordinate is inside or outside an object. If a function returns a positive distance, the point is inside the object. A negative distance indicates that the point is outside the object. There are many functions to describe many objects but for the sake of simplicity, let's take the example of a sphere and two points A and B.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://fabiensanglard.net/postcard_pathtracer/sphereTest.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;pre&gt;
 &lt;span&gt;
  // Signed distance point(p) to sphere(c,r)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;float&lt;/span&gt; testSphere&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;Vec p&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; Vec c&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;float&lt;/span&gt; r&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    Vec delta &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; c &lt;span&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; p&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span&gt;float&lt;/span&gt; distance &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; sqrtf&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;delta&lt;span&gt;%&lt;/span&gt;delta&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; radius &lt;span&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; distance&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;  

  Vec A &lt;span&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;6&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; 
  Vec B &lt;span&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; 
  Vec C &lt;span&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; 
  &lt;span&gt;float&lt;/span&gt; r &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;

  testSphere&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;A&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; C&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; r&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;// == -1 (outside)&lt;/span&gt;
  testSphere&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;B&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; C&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; r&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;// ==  1 (inside)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The function testSphere() returns -1 for A (so it is outside) and 1 for B (so it is inside). Signing the distance is just a trick to provide two information instead of one with one value. The same type of function can be written to describe a box (this is what is done in function BoxTest).&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://fabiensanglard.net/postcard_pathtracer/boxTest.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;pre&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;// Signed distance point(p) to Box(c1,c2)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;float&lt;/span&gt; testRectangle&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;Vec p&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; Vec c1&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; Vec c2&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    c1 &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; p &lt;span&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; c1 &lt;span&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
    c2 &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; c2 &lt;span&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; position &lt;span&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;min&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span&gt;min&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span&gt;min&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;c1&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;x&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; c2&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;x&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
        &lt;span&gt;min&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;c1&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;y&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; c2&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;y&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
      &lt;span&gt;min&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;c1&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;z&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; c2&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;z&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;  

  Vec A  &lt;span&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; Vec B  &lt;span&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;6&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
  Vec C1 &lt;span&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; Vec C2 &lt;span&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
  testRectangle&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;A&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; C1&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; C2&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;//  1.41 (inside)&lt;/span&gt;
  testRectangle&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;B&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; C1&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; C2&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;// -2.23 (outside)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now look what happens if we reverse the sign of the return value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://fabiensanglard.net/postcard_pathtracer/carveTest.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;pre&gt;
 &lt;span&gt; // Signed distance point(p) to carved box(c1,c2)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;float&lt;/span&gt; testCarveBox&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;Vec p&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; Vec c1&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; Vec c2&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    c1 &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; p &lt;span&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; c1 &lt;span&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
    c2 &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; c2 &lt;span&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; position &lt;span&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;min&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span&gt;min&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span&gt;min&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;c1&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;x&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; c2&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;x&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
        &lt;span&gt;min&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;c1&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;y&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; c2&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;y&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
      &lt;span&gt;min&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;c1&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;z&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; c2&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;z&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;  

  Vec A  &lt;span&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; Vec B  &lt;span&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;6&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
  Vec C1 &lt;span&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; Vec C2 &lt;span&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
  testCarveBox&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;A&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; C1&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; C2&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;// == -1.41 (outside)&lt;/span&gt;
  testCarveBox&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;B&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; C1&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; C2&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;// ==  2.23 (inside)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of describing a solid object, we have declared the whole world solid and instead carved a space inside it. Functions can be used as building blocks which once combined together describe more complex forms. With union operation (min function) we can carve two rectangles on top of each others and the result looks as follows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://fabiensanglard.net/postcard_pathtracer/roomTest.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;pre&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;// Signed distance point to room    &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;float&lt;/span&gt; testRoom&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;Vec p&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    Vec C1 &lt;span&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; Vec C2 &lt;span&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;// Lower room&lt;/span&gt;
    Vec C3 &lt;span&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; Vec C4 &lt;span&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;// Upper room&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span&gt;// min() is the union of the two carved volumes.&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;min&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;testCarvedBox&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;p&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; C1&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; C2&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
               testCarvedBox&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;p&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; C3&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; C4&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

  Vec A  &lt;span&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; 
  Vec B  &lt;span&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;6&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
  testRoom&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;A&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; C1&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; C2&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;// == -1.41 (outside)&lt;/span&gt;
  testRoom&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;B&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; C1&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; C2&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;// ==  1.00 (inside)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;If you start to think this looks like the room we are studying, it is because this is the way the lower room is expressed: with two simple carving boxes. Now armed with expert knowledge of CSG, we can go back to the code and take a look at the database function which is the heaviest part to digest.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;define&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; HIT_NONE 0&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;define&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; HIT_LETTER 1&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;define&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; HIT_WALL 2&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;define&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; HIT_SUN 3&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span&gt;// Sample the world using Signed Distance Fields.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span&gt;float&lt;/span&gt; QueryDatabase&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;Vec position&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;int&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt;hitType&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;float&lt;/span&gt; distance &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;1e9&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
  Vec f &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; position&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;// Flattened position (z=0)&lt;/span&gt;
  f&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;z &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;char&lt;/span&gt; letters&lt;span&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;15&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;+&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;               &lt;span&gt;// 15 two points lines&lt;/span&gt;
          &lt;span&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;5O5_&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;5W9W&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;5_9_&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span&gt;// P (without curve)&lt;/span&gt;
          &lt;span&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;AOEO&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;COC_&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;A_E_&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span&gt;// I&lt;/span&gt;
          &lt;span&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;IOQ_&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;I_QO&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;                &lt;span&gt;// X&lt;/span&gt;
          &lt;span&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;UOY_&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Y_]O&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;WW[W&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span&gt;// A&lt;/span&gt;
          &lt;span&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;aOa_&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;aWeW&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;a_e_&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;cWiO&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;// R (without curve)&lt;/span&gt;

  &lt;span&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;int&lt;/span&gt; i &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; i &lt;span&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;sizeof&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;letters&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; i &lt;span&gt;+&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    Vec begin &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; Vec&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;letters&lt;span&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;i&lt;span&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;79&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; letters&lt;span&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;i &lt;span&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;79&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;.5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
    Vec e &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; Vec&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;letters&lt;span&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;i &lt;span&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;79&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; letters&lt;span&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;i &lt;span&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;79&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;.5&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; begin &lt;span&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
    Vec o &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; f &lt;span&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;begin &lt;span&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; e &lt;span&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;min&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;min&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;begin &lt;span&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; f &lt;span&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;%&lt;/span&gt; e &lt;span&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;e &lt;span&gt;%&lt;/span&gt; e&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
                                      &lt;span&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
                                 &lt;span&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
    distance &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;min&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;distance&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; o &lt;span&gt;%&lt;/span&gt; o&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;// compare squared distance.&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
  distance &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; sqrtf&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;distance&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;// Get real distance, not square distance.&lt;/span&gt;

  &lt;span&gt;// Two curves (for P and R in PixaR) with hard-coded locations.&lt;/span&gt;
  Vec curves&lt;span&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;Vec&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;11&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;6&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; Vec&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;11&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;6&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;int&lt;/span&gt; i &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; i&lt;span&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    Vec o &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; f &lt;span&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; curves&lt;span&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;i&lt;span&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
    distance &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;min&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;distance&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
                   o&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;x &lt;span&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;0&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;?&lt;/span&gt; fabsf&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;sqrtf&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;o &lt;span&gt;%&lt;/span&gt; o&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
                           &lt;span&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;o&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;y &lt;span&gt;+&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; o&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;y &lt;span&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;0&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;?&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;2&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; sqrtf&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;o &lt;span&gt;%&lt;/span&gt; o&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
               &lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
  distance &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; powf&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;powf&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;distance&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; powf&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;position&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;z&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;.125&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;.5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
  hitType &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; HIT_LETTER&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;

  &lt;span&gt;float&lt;/span&gt; roomDist &lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
  roomDist &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;min&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;// min(A,B) = Union with Constructive solid geometry&lt;/span&gt;
               &lt;span&gt;//-min carves an empty space&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;min&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;// Lower room&lt;/span&gt;
                     BoxTest&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;position&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; Vec&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;30&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;.5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;30&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; Vec&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;30&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;18&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;30&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
                     &lt;span&gt;// Upper room&lt;/span&gt;
                     BoxTest&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;position&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; Vec&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;25&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;17&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;25&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; Vec&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;25&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;20&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;25&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
                BoxTest&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;// Ceiling &quot;planks&quot; spaced 8 units apart.&lt;/span&gt;
                  Vec&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;fmodf&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;fabsf&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;position&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;x&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
                      position&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;y&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
                      position&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;z&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
                  Vec&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;1.5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;18.5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;25&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
                  Vec&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;6.5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;20&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;25&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;roomDist &lt;span&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; distance&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; distance &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; roomDist&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; hitType &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; HIT_WALL&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;

  &lt;span&gt;float&lt;/span&gt; sun &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;19.9&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; position&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;y &lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;// Everything above 19.9 is light source.&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;sun &lt;span&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; distance&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;distance &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; sun&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; hitType &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; HIT_SUN&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;

  &lt;span&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; distance&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We recognize the &quot;carving&quot; box function which uses only two rectangles to build the whole room (our brain does the rest and imagines these are walls). The horizontal ladder is a slightly more complex CSG function involving a modulo. Finally the PIXAR letters are made of 15 lines with an origin/delta pair and two special cases for the curves in the P and R of PixaR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ray Matching&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;With a database of CSG functions describing the world, all that has to be done is to march all the rays cast in main(). The ray marching is distance function assigned. This mean the sample position moves forward by the distance of the closest obstacle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span&gt;// Perform signed sphere marching&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span&gt;// Returns hitType 0, 1, 2, or 3 and update hit position/normal&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span&gt;int&lt;/span&gt; RayMarching&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;Vec origin&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; Vec direction&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; Vec &lt;span&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt;hitPos&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; Vec &lt;span&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt;hitNorm&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;int&lt;/span&gt; hitType &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; HIT_NONE&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;int&lt;/span&gt; noHitCount &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;float&lt;/span&gt; d&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;// distance from closest object in world.&lt;/span&gt;

  &lt;span&gt;// Signed distance marching&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;float&lt;/span&gt; total_d&lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; total_d &lt;span&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;100&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; total_d &lt;span&gt;+&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; d&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;d &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; QueryDatabase&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;hitPos &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; origin &lt;span&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; direction &lt;span&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; total_d&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; hitType&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;.01&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;+&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;+&lt;/span&gt;noHitCount &lt;span&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;99&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; hitNorm &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;
         &lt;span&gt;!&lt;/span&gt;Vec&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;QueryDatabase&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;hitPos &lt;span&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; Vec&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;.01&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; noHitCount&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; d&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
              QueryDatabase&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;hitPos &lt;span&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; Vec&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;.01&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; noHitCount&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; d&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
              QueryDatabase&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;hitPos &lt;span&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; Vec&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;.01&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; noHitCount&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; d&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
         &lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; hitType&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;// Weird return statement where a variable is also updated.&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea behind distance assisted ray marching is to move forward by the distance of the closest object. Ultimately the ray gets close enough to a surface that a hit point is declared.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://fabiensanglard.net/postcard_pathtracer/distance_assisted_marching.svg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; id=&quot;sampleCountTestImage&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice how ray marching does not returns an exact intersection with the surface but rather an approximation. This is why in the code we see marching stop when d &amp;lt; 0.01f.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Putting it all together: Sampling&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;We are almost done exploring the path tracer. We are missing the bridge which connects the main() function to the ray marcher. This last section which I remaned &quot;Trace&quot; is the &quot;brain&quot; where rays bounce or stop based on what they hit.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
Vec Trace&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;Vec origin&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; Vec direction&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
  Vec sampledPosition&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; normal&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; color&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; attenuation &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
  Vec lightDirection&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;!&lt;/span&gt;Vec&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;.6&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;.6&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;// Directional light&lt;/span&gt;

  &lt;span&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;int&lt;/span&gt; bounceCount &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; bounceCount&lt;span&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span&gt;int&lt;/span&gt; hitType &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; RayMarching&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;origin&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; direction&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; sampledPosition&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; normal&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;hitType &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; HIT_NONE&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;break&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;// No hit. This is over, return color.&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;hitType &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; HIT_LETTER&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;// Specular bounce on a letter. No color acc.&lt;/span&gt;
      direction &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; direction &lt;span&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; normal &lt;span&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt; normal &lt;span&gt;%&lt;/span&gt; direction &lt;span&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
      origin &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; sampledPosition &lt;span&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; direction &lt;span&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;0.1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
      attenuation &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; attenuation &lt;span&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;0.2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;// Attenuation via distance traveled.&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;hitType &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; HIT_WALL&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;// Wall hit uses color yellow?&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span&gt;float&lt;/span&gt; incidence &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; normal &lt;span&gt;%&lt;/span&gt; lightDirection&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span&gt;float&lt;/span&gt; p &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;6.283185&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; randomVal&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span&gt;float&lt;/span&gt; c &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; randomVal&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span&gt;float&lt;/span&gt; s &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; sqrtf&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;1&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; c&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span&gt;float&lt;/span&gt; g &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; normal&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;z &lt;span&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;0&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;?&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;1&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span&gt;float&lt;/span&gt; u &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;1&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;g &lt;span&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; normal&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;z&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span&gt;float&lt;/span&gt; v &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; normal&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;x &lt;span&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; normal&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;y &lt;span&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; u&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
      direction &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; Vec&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;v&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
                      g &lt;span&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; normal&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;y &lt;span&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; normal&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;y &lt;span&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; u&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
                      &lt;span&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;normal&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;y&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;cosf&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;p&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; s&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
                  &lt;span&gt;+&lt;/span&gt;
                  Vec&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;1&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; g &lt;span&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; normal&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;x &lt;span&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; normal&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;x &lt;span&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; u&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
                      g &lt;span&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; v&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
                      &lt;span&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;g &lt;span&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; normal&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;x&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;sinf&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;p&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; s&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; normal &lt;span&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; sqrtf&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;c&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
      origin &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; sampledPosition &lt;span&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; direction &lt;span&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;.1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
      attenuation &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; attenuation &lt;span&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;0.2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;incidence &lt;span&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;0&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt;
          RayMarching&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;sampledPosition &lt;span&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; normal &lt;span&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;.1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
                      lightDirection&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
                      sampledPosition&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
                      normal&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; HIT_SUN&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
        color &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; color &lt;span&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; attenuation &lt;span&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; Vec&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;500&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;400&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;100&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; incidence&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;hitType &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; HIT_SUN&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;//&lt;/span&gt;
      color &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; color &lt;span&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; attenuation &lt;span&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; Vec&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;50&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;80&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;100&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;break&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;// Sun Color&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; color&lt;span&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I played a little with this function to change the maximum number of allowed ray bounce. A value of &quot;2&quot; gives an oddly good looking varnished Vantablack&lt;a name=&quot;back_4&quot; href=&quot;https://fabiensanglard.net/postcard_pathtracer/#footnote_4&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[4]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; look to the letters.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://fabiensanglard.net/postcard_pathtracer/vanilla512_bouce2.png&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; id=&quot;bouncingImage.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full cleaned up source code&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;To put it all together, here is the fully cleaned up source code &lt;a href=&quot;https://fabiensanglard.net/postcard_pathtracer/formatted_full.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p id=&quot;paperbox&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://fabiensanglard.net/postcard_pathtracer/#back_1&quot;&gt;^&lt;/a&gt; [1] Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/lexfrench/status/1049196936161415169&quot;&gt;Twitter post by lexfrench on Oct 8, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://fabiensanglard.net/postcard_pathtracer/#back_2&quot;&gt;^&lt;/a&gt; [2] Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Netpbm_format.&quot;&gt;Wikipedia: NetPBM image format&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://fabiensanglard.net/postcard_pathtracer/#back_3&quot;&gt;^&lt;/a&gt; [3] Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://fabiensanglard.net/postcard_pathtracer/&quot;&gt;Rendition performed on a maxed out MacBook Pro, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://fabiensanglard.net/postcard_pathtracer/#back_4&quot;&gt;^&lt;/a&gt; [4] Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vantablack&quot;&gt;Wikipedia: Vantablack&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;center&gt;*&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 25 Dec 2018 20:11:48 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Impossible</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://fabiensanglard.net/postcard_pathtracer/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>My video with 47M views was stolen on YouTube [video]</title>
<link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=z4AeoAWGJBw</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=z4AeoAWGJBw</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=z4AeoAWGJBw&quot;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=z4AeoAWGJBw&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=18758758&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=18758758&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 233&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 86&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 25 Dec 2018 19:08:16 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Michie</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=z4AeoAWGJBw</og:url>
<og:title>How my video with 47 million views was stolen on YouTube</og:title>
<og:image>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/z4AeoAWGJBw/maxresdefault.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>PLEASE SIGN THE PETITION: https://goo.gl/Jo85kU #FixYouTubeCopyright Twitter: http://twitter.com/ThisIsTheFatRat Facebook: http://www.facebook.com/thisisthef...</og:description>
<og:type>video.other</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=z4AeoAWGJBw</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Human blood cells can be directly reprogrammed into neural stem cells</title>
<link>https://www.dkfz.de/en/presse/pressemitteilungen/2018/dkfz-pm-18-71-Human-blood-cells-can-be-directly-reprogrammed-into-neural-stem-cells.php</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.dkfz.de/en/presse/pressemitteilungen/2018/dkfz-pm-18-71-Human-blood-cells-can-be-directly-reprogrammed-into-neural-stem-cells.php</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Stem cells are considered to be the all-rounders of our tissues: they can multiply indefinitely and then - if they are pluripotent embryonic stem cells - generate all conceivable cell types. In 2006, the Japanese scientist Shinya Yamanaka recognized that such cells could also be produced in the laboratory - from mature body cells. Four genetic factors alone are sufficient to reverse the course of development and produce so-called induced pluripotent stem cells (iPS) that have identical properties to embryonic stem cells. Yamanaka was awarded the Nobel Prize for Medicine in 2012 for this discovery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;This was a major breakthrough for stem cell research,&quot; said Andreas Trumpp, German Cancer Research Center (DKFZ) and Director of HI-STEM in Heidelberg. &quot;This applies in particular to for research in Germany, where the generation of human embryonic stem cells is not permitted. Stem cells have enormous potential both for basic research and for the development of regenerative therapies that aim to restore diseased tissue in patients. However, reprogramming is also associated with problems: For example, pluripotent cells can form germ line tumors, so-called teratomas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another possibility is not to completely turn back the course of development. For the first time, Trumpp's team has succeeded in reprogramming mature human cells in such a way that a defined type of induced neural stem cells is produced that can multiply almost indefinitely. &quot;We used four genetic factors like Yamanaka, but different ones for our reprogramming,&quot; explains Marc Christian Thier, first author of the study. &quot;We assumed that our factors would allow reprogramming to an early stage of development of the nervous system.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the past, other research groups also reprogrammed connective tissue cells into mature nerve cells or neural precursor cells. However, these artificially produced nerve cells often could not be expanded and could therefore hardly be used for therapeutic purposes. &quot;Often, it was a heterogeneous mixture of different cell types that might not exist in the body under physiological conditions,&quot; said Andreas Trumpp explaining the problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Together with stem cell researcher Frank Edenhofer from the University of Innsbruck and neuroscientist Hannah Monyer from DKFZ and the Heidelberg University Hospital, Trumpp and his team have succeeded in reprogramming different human cells: connective tissue cells of the skin or pancreas as well as peripheral blood cells. &quot;The origin of the cells had no influence on the properties of the stem cells,&quot; said Thier. In particular, the possibility of extracting neural stem cells from the blood of patients without invasive intervention is a decisive advantage for future therapeutic approaches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is special about the reprogrammed cells of the Heidelberg researchers is that they are a homogeneous cell type that resembles a stage of neural stem cells that occurs during the embryonic development of the nervous system. &quot;Corresponding cells exist in mice and probably also in humans during early embryonic brain development,&quot; said Thier. &quot;We have described here a new neural stem cell type in the mammalian embryo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These so called &quot;induced Neural Plate Border Stem Cells&quot; (iNBSCs) have a broad development potential. The iNBSCs of the Heidelberg scientists are expandable and multipotent and can develop in two different directions. On the one hand, they can take the path of development to mature nerve cells and their supplier cells, the glial cells, i.e. become cells of the central nervous system. On the other hand, they can also develop into cells of the neural crest, from which different cell types emerge, for example peripheral sensitive nerve cells or cartilage and bones of the skull.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The iNBSCs thus form an ideal basis for generating a broad range of different cell types for an individual patient. &quot;These cells have the same genetic material as the donor and are therefore presumably recognized as &quot;self&quot; by the immune system and are not rejected,&quot; explains Thier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CRISPR/Cas9 gene scissors can be used to modify the iNBSC or repair genetic defects, as the scientists have shown in their experiments. &quot;They are therefore of interesting both for basic research and the search for new active substances and for the development of regenerative therapies, for example in patients with diseases of the nervous system. However until we can use them in patients, a lot of research work will still be necessary,&quot; emphasizes Trumpp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*The Heidelberg Institute for Stem Cell Research and Experimental Medicine (HI-STEM) gGmbH was founded in 2008 as a public-private partnership between the DKFZ and the Dietmar Hopp Foundation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marc Christian Thier, Oliver Hommerding, Jasper Panten, Roberta Pinna, Diego García-González, Thomas Berger, Philipp Wörsdörfer, Yassen Assenov, Roberta Scognamiglio, Adriana Przybylla, Paul Kaschutnig, Lisa Becker, Michael D. Milsom, Anna Jauch, Jochen Utikal, Carl Herrmann, Hannah Monyer, Frank Edenhofer and Andreas Trumpp. Cell Stem Cell (2018), DOI: 10.1016/j.stem.2018.11.015&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 25 Dec 2018 19:03:11 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>myinnerbanjo</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.dkfz.de/en/presse/pressemitteilungen/2018/dkfz-pm-18-71-Human-blood-cells-can-be-directly-reprogrammed-into-neural-stem-cells.php</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Emacs Fireplace</title>
<link>https://github.com/johanvts/emacs-fireplace</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/johanvts/emacs-fireplace</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;Box-header px-2 clearfix&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;Box-title pr-3&quot;&gt;README.rst&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Box-body p-6&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;markdown-body entry-content&quot; itemprop=&quot;text&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://travis-ci.org/johanvts/emacs-fireplace&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/af12fd9c0ac0d8e026c02441341c3145f4c840ee/68747470733a2f2f6170692e7472617669732d63692e6f72672f6a6f68616e7674732f656d6163732d66697265706c6163652e737667&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://api.travis-ci.org/johanvts/emacs-fireplace.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://coveralls.io/r/johanvts/emacs-fireplace&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/82111326ce80db3d38693b0591209f69d1057d0e/68747470733a2f2f636f766572616c6c732e696f2f7265706f732f6a6f68616e7674732f656d6163732d66697265706c6163652f62616467652e737667&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://coveralls.io/repos/johanvts/emacs-fireplace/badge.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://melpa.org/#/fireplace&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/20cae8fdbe1c7058e3c70ef8007741febaa9fd8b/687474703a2f2f6d656c70612e6f72672f7061636b616765732f66697265706c6163652d62616467652e737667&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;http://melpa.org/packages/fireplace-badge.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://stable.melpa.org/#/fireplace&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/fb40631fcb8d8afe9ece6934adced95a851012b0/687474703a2f2f737461626c652e6d656c70612e6f72672f7061636b616765732f66697265706c6163652d62616467652e737667&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;http://stable.melpa.org/packages/fireplace-badge.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/johanvts/emacs-fireplace/tags&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/97a524b5c2c3e660a538b87de9223b3f677a79f6/68747470733a2f2f696d672e736869656c64732e696f2f6769746875622f7461672f6a6f68616e7674732f656d6163732d66697265706c6163652e737667&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/tag/johanvts/emacs-fireplace.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gnu.org/licenses/gpl-3.0.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/3ff3f8b43676ebcaa5049d1e12537434b9359e35/687474703a2f2f696d672e736869656c64732e696f2f3a6c6963656e73652d67706c332d626c75652e737667&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;http://img.shields.io/:license-gpl3-blue.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/fb294d4545fdc5558777cffe6d21777748fec615/68747470733a2f2f7261772e6769746875622e636f6d2f6a6f68616e7674732f656d6163732d66697265706c6163652f6d61737465722f696d672f66697265706c6163652e676966&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;https://raw.github.com/johanvts/emacs-fireplace/master/img/fireplace.gif&quot; src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/fb294d4545fdc5558777cffe6d21777748fec615/68747470733a2f2f7261772e6769746875622e636f6d2f6a6f68616e7674732f656d6163732d66697265706c6163652f6d61737465722f696d672f66697265706c6163652e676966&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://raw.github.com/johanvts/emacs-fireplace/master/img/fireplace.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A cozy fireplace for emacs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Usage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After you installed the fireplace package from &lt;a href=&quot;http://melpa.org/#/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;melpa&lt;/a&gt; you can start the fire using &lt;code&gt;M-x fireplace&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fireplace will try to fill the current window with a new buffer. To put the fire out use &lt;code&gt;M-x fireplace-off&lt;/code&gt; or hotkey &lt;code&gt;q&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead valign=&quot;bottom&quot;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;Key bind&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Function&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;C-+&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Move fire up&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;C--&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Move fire down&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;C-*&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Toggle smoke&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;q&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Turn off fire&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;Use &lt;code&gt;M-x customize-group RET fireplace RET&lt;/code&gt; to view and change the user defined variables and read their documentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Configuration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can tweak the setting of &lt;code&gt;fireplace&lt;/code&gt; the way you please with the &lt;code&gt;customize-group&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;fireplace&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;fireplace-faces&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among the options, the name of the buffer, the frequency of refresh, the smoke char, or the faces used in the fireplace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Manual Installation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you don't want to use melpa to install this package, follow these steps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Download &lt;code&gt;fireplace.el&lt;/code&gt; and place it somewhere in your &lt;code&gt;.emacs.d&lt;/code&gt; directory, say in &lt;code&gt;.emacs.d/fireplace/&lt;/code&gt;. Compile the file using &lt;code&gt;M-x byte-compile-file&lt;/code&gt;. Put &lt;code&gt;(load &quot;~/.emacs.d/fireplace/fireplace&quot;)&lt;/code&gt; in your init file (&lt;code&gt;.emacs&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that there is a significant performance difference between the compiled and non-compiled fireplace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Acknowledgment&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A big thanks to Dan Torop for his &lt;a href=&quot;http://dantorop.info/project/emacs-animation/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;emacs animation guide&lt;/a&gt; and Vasilij Schneidermann for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/wasamasa/xbm-life&quot;&gt;xbm-life&lt;/a&gt; package. The code relies heavily on these two sources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Contribution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please feel free to do whatever you want with this code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ideas and pull requests are very welcome. I can be reached through &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:johanvts@gmail.com&quot;&gt;johanvts@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt; or on twitter @johanvts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;To-Do&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Better status bar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 25 Dec 2018 18:23:23 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>clircle</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars2.githubusercontent.com/u/1846239?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>johanvts/emacs-fireplace</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/johanvts/emacs-fireplace</og:url>
<og:description>A cozy fireplace for emacs. Contribute to johanvts/emacs-fireplace development by creating an account on GitHub.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/johanvts/emacs-fireplace</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>T * sin (t) ≈ Christmas tree</title>
<link>https://github.com/anvaka/atree</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/anvaka/atree</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;Box-body p-6&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;markdown-body entry-content&quot; itemprop=&quot;text&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found animated Christmas tree on reddit:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/1ef821cdc5a42e5a04bfb71b0c830f7f4a6572d3/687474703a2f2f692e696d6775722e636f6d2f46793453316a522e676966&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/1ef821cdc5a42e5a04bfb71b0c830f7f4a6572d3/687474703a2f2f692e696d6775722e636f6d2f46793453316a522e676966&quot; alt=&quot;reddit tree&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/Fy4S1jR.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Was curious to make it in js. Current results are here: &lt;a href=&quot;http://anvaka.github.io/atree/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Happy new 2018!&lt;/a&gt;. Wish you all great successes and joy, doing what you love!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How it's built?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tree is built of two spirals. These &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/anvaka/atree/blob/2937249242a0204929aca45cdb8b937cfb5af3e5/index.js#L86-L97&quot;&gt;11 lines of code&lt;/a&gt; render one line on spiral. It includes 3d projection and background shadow. &lt;em&gt;Almost&lt;/em&gt; the same as this &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:ComplexSinInATimeAxe.gif&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;wiki image&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/99bc360506276759bf0e0e8ecf2d429990974189/687474703a2f2f75706c6f61642e77696b696d656469612e6f72672f77696b6970656469612f636f6d6d6f6e732f612f61352f436f6d706c657853696e496e4154696d654178652e676966&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/99bc360506276759bf0e0e8ecf2d429990974189/687474703a2f2f75706c6f61642e77696b696d656469612e6f72672f77696b6970656469612f636f6d6d6f6e732f612f61352f436f6d706c657853696e496e4154696d654178652e676966&quot; alt=&quot;spiral&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/a/a5/ComplexSinInATimeAxe.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;It's almost perfect now&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EDIT:&lt;/strong&gt; Thank you reddit. With your help we made it almost perfect. You are awesome!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Huge appreciation goes to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/CensoredUsername&quot;&gt;@CensoredUsername&lt;/a&gt; who made &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/programming/comments/1tswai/t_sin_t_christmas_tree/cebhvu9&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;significant improvement&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Yazuak&quot;&gt;@Yazuak&lt;/a&gt; first gave and implemented &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/programming/comments/1tswai/t_sin_t_christmas_tree/cebajpt&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;idea&lt;/a&gt; of how to manage even distribution of points along the curves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vitaliy Kaurov implemented the same tree in Wolfram language... in just &lt;a href=&quot;http://community.wolfram.com/groups/-/m/t/175891&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;15 lines of code&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/davidlibrera&quot;&gt;David Librera&lt;/a&gt; rewrote this in CoffeScript. Checkout &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/davidlibrera/atree/tree/master/js/coffee&quot;&gt;his repository&lt;/a&gt; for nice OO design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what's left? Just small changes which could make this tree perfect:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Shadows are not accurate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I think code is more complex than it should be (subjectively).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MIT&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 25 Dec 2018 17:44:51 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>adamnemecek</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars2.githubusercontent.com/u/225407?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>anvaka/atree</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/anvaka/atree</og:url>
<og:description>Just a simple christmas tree, based on redit story - anvaka/atree</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/anvaka/atree</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>