<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Ending our Medium integration</title>
<link>https://write.as/blog/ending-our-medium-integration</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://write.as/blog/ending-our-medium-integration</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Sometime in the past few weeks, Medium abruptly &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/macguru17/status/1088387105519255553&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;deleted third-party access&lt;/a&gt; to their publishing API. There was no warning before, or notice after, this happened — apps just stopped working (including ours).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When anyone on &lt;a href=&quot;https://write.as&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Write.as&lt;/a&gt; tries to interact with Medium now, the response we get from their API is plain:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Application not found (6005)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So unfortunately, we've removed our Medium integration. You'll no longer see the option to connect a Medium account or cross-post to one in the editor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We contacted Medium's team to see how we could regain API access. But then, after a little more thought, we decided to make this change permanent, and not continue support for their platform, regardless of what their response is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our original goal in supporting the Medium API was to create more bridges between different web silos. That was part of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@ev/welcome-to-medium-9e53ca408c48&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;promise of Medium&lt;/a&gt; back when it started, after all — a &lt;em&gt;network&lt;/em&gt; of blogs, instead of individual islands. When they opened their API, we knew that would be the perfect chance to help writers connect with more readers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We trusted that Medium might not do what many VC-funded platforms have done before: open an API, attract developers and users, grow, then shut it all down. Unfortunately, that's exactly what they did. And unlike their &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.niemanlab.org/2018/05/medium-abruptly-cancels-the-membership-programs-of-its-21-remaining-publisher-partners/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;previous pivots&lt;/a&gt;, they didn't even give the courtesy of a small heads-up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's this pattern of disregard for everyone else, as they clamor for a business model, that is mostly driving our decision to part ways. They've done a lot of good for the web (and indeed helped inspire Write.as). But we believe there's a better way forward, and based on their decisions, they probably won't be a part of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this change, we'll be honing the focus of our product even more, evolving the &lt;a href=&quot;https://writefreely.org&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;open source software behind it all&lt;/a&gt;, and continuing to build a sustainable, human-centric platform for publishing on the web.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2019 13:05:07 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>thebaer</dc:creator>
<og:title>Ending our Medium integration</og:title>
<og:description>Sometime in the past few weeks, Medium abruptly deleted third-party access to their publishing API. There was no warning before, or notic...</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://write.as/blog/ending-our-medium-integration</og:url>
<og:image>https://write.as/img/w-sq-light.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://write.as/blog/ending-our-medium-integration</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Remembering Roger Boisjoly: He Tried to Stop Shuttle Challenger Launch</title>
<link>https://www.npr.org/sections/thetwo-way/2012/02/06/146490064/remembering-roger-boisjoly-he-tried-to-stop-shuttle-challenger-launch</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.npr.org/sections/thetwo-way/2012/02/06/146490064/remembering-roger-boisjoly-he-tried-to-stop-shuttle-challenger-launch</guid>
<description>&lt;div id=&quot;res146490853&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap image large&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;imagewrap&quot; data-crop-type=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2012/02/06/ap910901091_custom-86160ed8319f56f9e6b028740254b283b7dfd523-s1100-c15.jpg&quot; data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2012/02/06/ap910901091_custom-86160ed8319f56f9e6b028740254b283b7dfd523-s1100.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img lazyOnLoad&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;credit-caption&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-wrap&quot; readability=&quot;8.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image caption&quot; readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Engineer Roger Boisjoly examines a model of the O-Rings, used to bring the Space Shuttle into orbit, at a meeting of senior executives and academic representatives in Rye, New York in Sept. 1991. &lt;strong class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;AP&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong class=&quot;hide-caption&quot;&gt;hide caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;strong class=&quot;toggle-caption&quot;&gt;toggle caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;AP&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;enlarge_measure&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img_wrap&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2012/02/06/ap910901091_custom-86160ed8319f56f9e6b028740254b283b7dfd523-s1200.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;enlarge_html&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image_data&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Engineer Roger Boisjoly examines a model of the O-Rings, used to bring the Space Shuttle into orbit, at a meeting of senior executives and academic representatives in Rye, New York in Sept. 1991.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;AP&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roger Boisjoly was a booster rocket engineer at NASA contractor Morton Thiokol in Utah in January, 1986, when he and four colleagues became embroiled in the fatal decision to launch the Space Shuttle Challenger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boisjoly was also one of two confidential sources quoted by NPR three weeks later in the first detailed report about the Challenger launch decision, and the stiff resistance by Boisjoly and other Thiokol engineers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The experience both haunted and inspired Boisjoly in the decades that followed. We learned this weekend from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2012/02/04/us/roger-boisjoly-73-dies-warned-of-shuttle-danger.html&quot;&gt;this story in &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that Boisjoly died last month in Utah at age 73.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bulky, bald and tall, Boisjoly was an imposing figure, especially when armed with data. He found disturbing the data he reviewed about the booster rockets that would lift Challenger into space. Six months before the Challenger explosion, he predicted &quot;a catastrophe of the highest order&quot; involving &quot;loss of human life&quot; in a memo to managers at Thiokol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem, Boisjoly wrote, was the elastic seals at the joints of the multi-stage booster rockets. They tended to stiffen and unseal in cold weather and NASA's ambitious shuttle launch schedule included winter lift-offs with risky temperatures, even in Florida.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id=&quot;ad-backstage-wrap&quot; aria-label=&quot;advertisement&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;On January 27, 1986, the forecast for the next morning at the Kennedy Space Center included a launch-time temperature as low as 30 degrees Fahrenheit. NASA had never launched in temperatures that cold and Boisjoly and his four colleagues at Thiokol headquarters in Utah concluded it would be too dangerous too launch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three weeks later, he told NPR's Daniel Zwerdling in an unrecorded and confidential interview, &quot;I fought like Hell to stop that launch. I'm so torn up inside I can hardly talk about it, even now.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;article id=&quot;res146485468&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap resaudio secondary insecure&quot; aria-label=&quot;audio-module&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;audio-module&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;audio-module-title&quot;&gt;NPR's Daniel Zwerdling Reports In 1986&lt;/h4&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;&lt;p&gt;But Boisjoly did talk about it in a hotel room in Alabama, revealing for the first time the details of that effort to keep Challenger on the launch pad. He asked that he not be named but he agreed to be quoted anonymously. As he spoke with Zwerdling, a second engineer revealed the same details to me under the same conditions at his home in Brigham City, Utah.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boisjoly's family agreed to release him from our pledge of confidentiality so that his efforts to get the truth out can be widely known.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;We all knew what the implication was without actually coming out and saying it,&quot; a tearful Boisjoly told Zwerdling in 1986. &quot;We all knew if the seals failed the shuttle would blow up.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Armed with the data that described that possibility, Boisjoly and his colleagues argued persistently and vigorously for hours. At first, Thiokol managers agreed with them and formally recommended a launch delay. But NASA officials on a conference call challenged that recommendation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;I am appalled,&quot; said NASA's George Hardy, according to Boisjoly and our other source in the room. &quot;I am appalled by your recommendation.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another shuttle program manager, Lawrence Mulloy, didn't hide his disdain. &quot;My God, Thiokol,&quot; he said. &quot;When do you want me to launch — next April?&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These words and this debate were not known publicly until our interviews with Boisjoly and his colleague. They told us that the NASA pressure caused Thiokol managers to &quot;put their management hats on,&quot; as one source told us. They overruled Boisjoly and the other engineers and told NASA to go ahead and launch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;We thought that if the seals failed the shuttle would never get off the launch pad,&quot; Boisjoly told Zwerdling. So, when Challenger lifted off without incident, he and the others watching television screens at Thiokol's Utah plant were relieved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;And when we were one minute into the launch a friend turned to me and said, 'Oh God. We made it. We made it!'&quot; Boisjoly continued. &quot;Then, a few seconds later, the shuttle blew up. And we all knew exactly what happened.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until NPR's story, the special commission investigating the Challenger tragedy hadn't even interviewed all the engineers involved in the pre-launch debate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The explosion of Challenger and the deaths of its crew, including Teacher-in Space Christa McAuliffe, traumatized the nation and left Boisjoly disabled by severe headaches, steeped in depression and unable to sleep. When I visited him at his Utah home in April of 1987, he was thin, tearful and tense. He huddled in the corner of a couch, his arms tightly folded on his chest. But he was ready to speak publicly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;article id=&quot;res146485548&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap resaudio secondary insecure&quot; aria-label=&quot;audio-module&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;audio-module&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;audio-module-title&quot;&gt;NPR's Howard Berkes Talks With Roger Boisjoly In 1987&lt;/h4&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;I'm very angry that nobody listened,&quot; Boisjoly told me. And he asked himself, he said, if he could have done anything different. But then a flash of certainty returned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;We were talking to the right people,&quot; he said. &quot;We were talking to the people who had the power to stop that launch.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boisjoly testified before the Challenger Commission and filed unsuccessful lawsuits against Thiokol and NASA. He continued to suffer and was ostracized by some of his colleagues. One said he'd drop his kids on Boisjoly's doorstep if they all lost their jobs, according to his wife Roberta.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;He took it very hard,&quot; she recalls. &quot;He had always been held in such high esteem and it hurt so bad when they wouldn't listen to him.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A therapist recommended speaking out even more and for close to three decades, Boisjoly traveled to engineering schools around the world, speaking about ethical decision-making and sticking with data. &quot;This is what I was meant to do,&quot; he told Roberta, &quot;to have impact on young people's lives.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boisjoly continued to respond to emails and letters from engineering students right up until his sudden death in his sleep last month in St. George, Utah. He was diagnosed with cancer two weeks before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;He always stood by his work,&quot; Roberta recalls, her voice breaking. &quot;He lived an honorable and ethical life. And he was at peace when he died.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2019 02:11:36 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>drewvolpe</dc:creator>
<og:title>Remembering Roger Boisjoly: He Tried To Stop Shuttle Challenger Launch</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.npr.org/sections/thetwo-way/2012/02/06/146490064/remembering-roger-boisjoly-he-tried-to-stop-shuttle-challenger-launch</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>Boisjoly was the engineer who boisterously warned about problems with the Challenger's elastic seals. That he couldn't do anything about the launch haunted him and turned him into a crusader for ethics in engineering. Boisjoly died at age 73.</og:description>
<og:image>https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2012/02/06/ap910901091_wide-4b9d81f04c302c13e2c4eb67c743b479310f37ad.jpg?s=1400</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.npr.org/sections/thetwo-way/2012/02/06/146490064/remembering-roger-boisjoly-he-tried-to-stop-shuttle-challenger-launch</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ask HN: Why can’t I block all incoming calls that aren’t in my contact list?</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19031711</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19031711</guid>
<description>&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19033901&quot; readability=&quot;10.037037037037&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;5.0185185185185&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;10.037037037037&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;8.6683501683502&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19036033&quot; readability=&quot;15.622895622896&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;7.8114478114478&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;15.622895622896&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;14.158249158249&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19036040&quot; readability=&quot;4.7314578005115&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.3657289002558&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.7314578005115&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;5.2046035805627&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19034106&quot; readability=&quot;3.4947368421053&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.7473684210526&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.4947368421053&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19035516&quot; readability=&quot;3.5229357798165&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.7614678899083&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.5229357798165&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19035986&quot; readability=&quot;3.4666666666667&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.7333333333333&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.4666666666667&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;120&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19035571&quot; readability=&quot;0.57894736842105&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19035972&quot; readability=&quot;3.4285714285714&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.7142857142857&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.4285714285714&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19034439&quot; readability=&quot;9.5793499043977&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.7896749521989&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;9.5793499043977&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19035595&quot; readability=&quot;5.4&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.7&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.4&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19035944&quot; readability=&quot;4.5819397993311&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.2909698996656&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.5819397993311&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;120&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;4.123745819398&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19035711&quot; readability=&quot;4.3181818181818&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.1590909090909&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.3181818181818&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;120&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;4.75&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19035807&quot; readability=&quot;2.4&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.2&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.4&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;120&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19036036&quot; readability=&quot;6.4678362573099&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.233918128655&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.4678362573099&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;160&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;4.6198830409357&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19035950&quot; readability=&quot;2.5548387096774&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.2774193548387&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.5548387096774&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;160&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19036101&quot; readability=&quot;1.3953488372093&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19035706&quot; readability=&quot;3.43961352657&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.719806763285&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.43961352657&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;120&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19034527&quot; readability=&quot;2.4135338345865&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.2067669172932&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.4135338345865&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19035598&quot; readability=&quot;1.8139534883721&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19035249&quot; readability=&quot;1.4352941176471&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19035278&quot; readability=&quot;1.4102564102564&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19035434&quot; readability=&quot;5.2941176470588&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.6470588235294&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.2941176470588&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;160&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19035497&quot; readability=&quot;4.222972972973&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.1114864864865&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.222972972973&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;200&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19035010&quot; readability=&quot;8.6108108108108&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.3054054054054&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;8.6108108108108&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;6.2189189189189&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19035948&quot; readability=&quot;1.5137614678899&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19034905&quot; readability=&quot;3.8666666666667&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19034074&quot; readability=&quot;7.3725490196078&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.6862745098039&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7.3725490196078&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;5.5294117647059&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19034100&quot; readability=&quot;3.0943396226415&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19035314&quot; readability=&quot;1.3611111111111&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19035166&quot; readability=&quot;4.3478260869565&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.1739130434783&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.3478260869565&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19035603&quot; readability=&quot;1.2923076923077&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19034371&quot; readability=&quot;1.2941176470588&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19034680&quot; readability=&quot;3.5611814345992&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.7805907172996&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.5611814345992&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19035616&quot; readability=&quot;5.6210526315789&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.8105263157895&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.6210526315789&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;3.7473684210526&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19031765&quot; readability=&quot;9.9459459459459&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.972972972973&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;9.9459459459459&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;3.3153153153153&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19034036&quot; readability=&quot;7.5700575815739&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.7850287907869&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7.5700575815739&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;7.5700575815739&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19035833&quot; readability=&quot;8.5090909090909&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.2545454545455&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;8.5090909090909&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;8.5090909090909&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19034546&quot; readability=&quot;2.3714285714286&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19036077&quot; readability=&quot;5.3956834532374&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.6978417266187&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.3956834532374&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;120&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19035322&quot; readability=&quot;2.5174825174825&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.2587412587413&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.5174825174825&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;120&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19035386&quot; readability=&quot;6.5420560747664&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.2710280373832&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.5420560747664&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;160&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19035645&quot; readability=&quot;6.3846153846154&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.1923076923077&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.3846153846154&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;160&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;4.5604395604396&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19035448&quot; readability=&quot;2.448&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.224&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.448&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;160&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19035932&quot; readability=&quot;2.4563758389262&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.2281879194631&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.4563758389262&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19036056&quot; readability=&quot;2.3225806451613&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19033597&quot; readability=&quot;5.5075987841945&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.7537993920973&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.5075987841945&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19035162&quot; readability=&quot;2.4634146341463&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.2317073170732&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.4634146341463&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19035326&quot; readability=&quot;0.93023255813953&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19033953&quot; readability=&quot;1.4375&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19031897&quot; readability=&quot;4.3989071038251&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.1994535519126&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.3989071038251&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19031973&quot; readability=&quot;2.2758620689655&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19032540&quot; readability=&quot;3.244094488189&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.6220472440945&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.244094488189&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;120&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19034437&quot; readability=&quot;4.5&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.25&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.5&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;160&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19032964&quot; readability=&quot;2.9906542056075&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19032203&quot; readability=&quot;0.8780487804878&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19033619&quot; readability=&quot;1.1923076923077&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19032681&quot; readability=&quot;4.5994065281899&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.299703264095&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.5994065281899&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;120&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;4.1394658753709&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19032970&quot; readability=&quot;1.4193548387097&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19035216&quot; readability=&quot;2.5961538461538&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.2980769230769&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.5961538461538&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;200&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19033880&quot; readability=&quot;0.85714285714286&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19034059&quot; readability=&quot;2.0629370629371&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19033163&quot; readability=&quot;1.2830188679245&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19032709&quot; readability=&quot;3.5951417004049&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.7975708502024&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.5951417004049&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;3.5951417004049&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19033164&quot; readability=&quot;6.6387096774194&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.3193548387097&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.6387096774194&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;6.1645161290323&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19035407&quot; readability=&quot;4.3351063829787&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.1675531914894&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.3351063829787&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19032021&quot; readability=&quot;5.607476635514&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.803738317757&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.607476635514&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;5.607476635514&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19033055&quot; readability=&quot;4.3962264150943&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19035492&quot; readability=&quot;2.54&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.27&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.54&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;120&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19032032&quot; readability=&quot;7.1202749140893&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.5601374570447&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7.1202749140893&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19033119&quot; readability=&quot;3.6967509025271&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.8483754512635&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.6967509025271&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;3.6967509025271&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19032564&quot; readability=&quot;8.2151162790698&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.1075581395349&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;8.2151162790698&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;5.4767441860465&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19032701&quot; readability=&quot;15.689655172414&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;7.8448275862069&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;15.689655172414&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;17.160560344828&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19032745&quot; readability=&quot;10.693023255814&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;5.346511627907&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;10.693023255814&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;11.179069767442&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19034786&quot; readability=&quot;15.722481654436&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;7.8612408272181&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;15.722481654436&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;120&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;18.670446964643&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19035689&quot; readability=&quot;6.5581854043393&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.2790927021696&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.5581854043393&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;160&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;5.1528599605523&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19033332&quot; readability=&quot;11.578558225508&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;5.7892791127542&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;11.578558225508&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;10.13123844732&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19035694&quot; readability=&quot;0.95744680851064&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19035342&quot; readability=&quot;18.670347003155&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;9.3351735015773&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;18.670347003155&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;20.144321766562&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19035621&quot; readability=&quot;9.1489361702128&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.5744680851064&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;9.1489361702128&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;5.4893617021277&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19033513&quot; readability=&quot;5.4274809160305&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.7137404580153&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.4274809160305&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;4.5229007633588&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19033629&quot; readability=&quot;4.6814404432133&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.3407202216066&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.6814404432133&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19032761&quot; readability=&quot;6.4354838709677&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.2177419354839&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.4354838709677&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;5.9758064516129&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19035114&quot; readability=&quot;6.4789644012945&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.2394822006472&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.4789644012945&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;4.6278317152104&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19032973&quot; readability=&quot;9.7445972495088&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.8722986247544&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;9.7445972495088&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;9.7445972495088&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19034628&quot; readability=&quot;5.4457831325301&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.7228915662651&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.4457831325301&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19035769&quot; readability=&quot;2.0769230769231&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19032627&quot; readability=&quot;15.524547803618&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;7.7622739018088&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;15.524547803618&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19032702&quot; readability=&quot;9.6763754045307&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.8381877022654&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;9.6763754045307&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;6.289644012945&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19032760&quot; readability=&quot;6.7116968698517&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.3558484349259&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.7116968698517&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;120&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;9.5881383855025&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19035535&quot; readability=&quot;19.605181986428&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;9.8025909932141&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;19.605181986428&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;160&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;7.8420727945713&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19032793&quot; readability=&quot;25.651108518086&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;12.825554259043&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;25.651108518086&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;120&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19032790&quot; readability=&quot;1.7076923076923&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19035459&quot; readability=&quot;6.4096385542169&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.2048192771084&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.4096385542169&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;160&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19032818&quot; readability=&quot;5.8402366863905&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.9201183431953&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.8402366863905&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19035437&quot; readability=&quot;3.3913043478261&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.695652173913&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.3913043478261&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19033368&quot; readability=&quot;1.4878048780488&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19035775&quot; readability=&quot;3.0921985815603&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19035364&quot; readability=&quot;0.95454545454545&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19033085&quot; readability=&quot;7.3166885676741&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.6583442838371&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7.3166885676741&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;6.4021024967148&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19033115&quot; readability=&quot;5.212213740458&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.606106870229&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.212213740458&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;7.818320610687&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19035349&quot; readability=&quot;2.4961832061069&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.2480916030534&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.4961832061069&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19034716&quot; readability=&quot;7.4973821989529&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.7486910994764&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7.4973821989529&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19034940&quot; readability=&quot;4.1564417177914&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.0782208588957&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.1564417177914&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;3.3251533742331&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19033097&quot; readability=&quot;1.4910179640719&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19033365&quot; readability=&quot;0.66666666666667&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19033173&quot; readability=&quot;6.4956772334294&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.2478386167147&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.4956772334294&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;5.5677233429395&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19033944&quot; readability=&quot;3.681660899654&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.840830449827&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.681660899654&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19035378&quot; readability=&quot;2.4926470588235&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.2463235294118&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.4926470588235&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;120&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19032016&quot; readability=&quot;2.8527607361963&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19035953&quot; readability=&quot;2.043956043956&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19035659&quot; readability=&quot;5.1940298507463&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.5970149253731&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.1940298507463&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19033028&quot; readability=&quot;4.7222222222222&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.3611111111111&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.7222222222222&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19036013&quot; readability=&quot;7.4838709677419&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.741935483871&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7.4838709677419&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;4.6774193548387&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19032677&quot; readability=&quot;2.3961038961039&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19032596&quot; readability=&quot;1.3125&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19031971&quot; readability=&quot;7.4324324324324&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.7162162162162&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7.4324324324324&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19035396&quot; readability=&quot;1.425&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19032831&quot; readability=&quot;5.9407894736842&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.9703947368421&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.9407894736842&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19032141&quot; readability=&quot;3.4619883040936&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.7309941520468&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.4619883040936&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19032651&quot; readability=&quot;2.381679389313&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19033423&quot; readability=&quot;6.4063604240283&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.2031802120141&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.4063604240283&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;3.660777385159&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19035720&quot; readability=&quot;7.6901004304161&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.845050215208&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7.6901004304161&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;5.7675753228121&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19032451&quot; readability=&quot;9.5365418894831&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.7682709447415&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;9.5365418894831&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;9.0597147950089&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19033631&quot; readability=&quot;3.6181818181818&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.8090909090909&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.6181818181818&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;3.6181818181818&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19034228&quot; readability=&quot;1.44&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19035629&quot; readability=&quot;7.9385382059801&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.96926910299&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7.9385382059801&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;6.6154485049834&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19035404&quot; readability=&quot;9.7390272835113&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.8695136417556&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;9.7390272835113&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;6.8173190984579&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19034094&quot; readability=&quot;9.7384806973848&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.8692403486924&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;9.7384806973848&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;8.7646326276463&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19032827&quot; readability=&quot;2.5792682926829&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.2896341463415&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.5792682926829&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;3.4390243902439&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19031983&quot; readability=&quot;9.3981481481481&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.6990740740741&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;9.3981481481481&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;7.9884259259259&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19032168&quot; readability=&quot;4.2885245901639&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19032698&quot; readability=&quot;5.1659192825112&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.5829596412556&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.1659192825112&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19035011&quot; readability=&quot;0.78260869565217&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19032756&quot; readability=&quot;17.446494464945&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;8.7232472324723&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;17.446494464945&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;8.2386223862239&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19033033&quot; readability=&quot;6.7195994277539&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.359799713877&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.7195994277539&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;8.6394849785408&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19033069&quot; readability=&quot;4.377990430622&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.188995215311&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.377990430622&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;4.377990430622&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19034226&quot; readability=&quot;1.2885906040268&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19034292&quot; readability=&quot;3.6140350877193&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.8070175438596&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.6140350877193&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19033594&quot; readability=&quot;15.815513626834&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;7.9077568134172&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;15.815513626834&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;12.850104821803&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19033759&quot; readability=&quot;2.5945945945946&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.2972972972973&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.5945945945946&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19033986&quot; readability=&quot;11.645756457565&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;5.8228782287823&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;11.645756457565&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;10.190036900369&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19034928&quot; readability=&quot;8.4694736842105&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.2347368421053&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;8.4694736842105&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;120&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;5.1757894736842&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19033646&quot; readability=&quot;17.781287970838&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;8.8906439854192&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;17.781287970838&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;26.671931956258&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;comment&quot; readability=&quot;27.94266994267&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;commtext c00&quot;&gt;I don't mean this maliciously but unless I've misread your comment this is a lot of text that boils down to &quot;sometimes you'll be unreachable&quot;. Some of the reasons you list:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;commtext c00&quot;&gt;- family members getting new phones&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;commtext c00&quot;&gt;- missed connections + job offers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;commtext c00&quot;&gt;- teenage child being angry with you&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;commtext c00&quot;&gt;- emergencies&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;commtext c00&quot;&gt;Two responses:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;commtext c00&quot;&gt;1. The cellular phone has existed only for so long, and people found a way to exist before it. I'm not going to belabor the point since it's not very deep but this concept that you need to be reachable 99% of the time in 99% of the cases is wrong -- the cases where you actually &lt;em&gt;absoutely need&lt;/em&gt; to be reached is often &amp;lt;1% of the time.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;commtext c00&quot;&gt;2. The problem is &lt;em&gt;identity&lt;/em&gt; here -- it's not that you don't want certain numbers calling you, it's that you don't want &lt;em&gt;certain numbers&lt;/em&gt; calling you. This could be solved by creating a system that links identities to numbers, though it's exceedingly optimistic notion that we'd get everyone to agree on the &lt;em&gt;same&lt;/em&gt; system.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;commtext c00&quot;&gt;In all the situations when you give someone your phone number or they give you theirs, you're agreeing to talk to &lt;em&gt;each other&lt;/em&gt;. If you instead exchanged some sort of identity (let's say GPG key), the problem no longer is &quot;how can I call a number they &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; be at&quot;, it's &quot;how do I find how to contact this person with this identity&quot;. The latter question can be solved much more robustly.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;commtext c00&quot;&gt;I've thought about something like this -- creating just a online store of &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; identities that you can freely create and discard, boiling down to GPG key. Having such a shared resource would mean that chat apps, telco providers, and various other usecases could just use GPG (in this example) to &lt;em&gt;look up&lt;/em&gt; the right contact method... Attempting to create a widely used standard is basically suicide though so maybe this idea has no legs.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;commtext c00&quot;&gt;In this imaginary scenario you have a whitelist that works the way you want -- &lt;em&gt;people&lt;/em&gt; you want to contact you can, and you can have very limited overrides like a shared identity/utility key for hospitals/government/etc.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;commtext c00&quot;&gt;[EDIT] - I also wanted to add -- again, I &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; think that this would have bad effects on &quot;free and open communication&quot;, but I'm not sure it might actually be bad for society -- maybe free-and-open-communication by default for some mediums isn't good. I don't think closing down this loophole for phone numbers is going to squelch productive protests (one of the phenomenons I personally think we'd want to protect), but maybe I'm wrong.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19033787&quot; readability=&quot;4.6476510067114&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.3238255033557&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.6476510067114&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19035183&quot; readability=&quot;2.462962962963&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.2314814814815&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.462962962963&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;120&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19035439&quot; readability=&quot;1.0612244897959&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19033043&quot; readability=&quot;6.2626262626263&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19034926&quot; readability=&quot;11.443037974684&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;5.7215189873418&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;11.443037974684&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;6.6751054852321&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19033079&quot; readability=&quot;2.4388489208633&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.2194244604317&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.4388489208633&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19031774&quot; readability=&quot;3.3239436619718&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.6619718309859&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.3239436619718&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19031903&quot; readability=&quot;3.3743016759777&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.6871508379888&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.3743016759777&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19031955&quot; readability=&quot;7.4385964912281&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.719298245614&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7.4385964912281&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;4.6491228070175&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19033707&quot; readability=&quot;3.4248366013072&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.7124183006536&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.4248366013072&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19032604&quot; readability=&quot;4.2105263157895&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.1052631578947&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.2105263157895&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19035510&quot; readability=&quot;2.3555555555556&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19032995&quot; readability=&quot;4.4331983805668&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.2165991902834&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.4331983805668&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;3.9898785425101&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19033951&quot; readability=&quot;9.3873085339168&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.6936542669584&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;9.3873085339168&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;7.0404814004376&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19035559&quot; readability=&quot;2.8627450980392&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19032755&quot; readability=&quot;8.7450980392157&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.3725490196078&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;8.7450980392157&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;10.202614379085&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19032077&quot; readability=&quot;2.5828877005348&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.2914438502674&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.5828877005348&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19032094&quot; readability=&quot;0.54545454545455&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19035215&quot; readability=&quot;3.4011976047904&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.7005988023952&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.4011976047904&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;3.4011976047904&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19035414&quot; readability=&quot;2.3893805309735&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19032368&quot; readability=&quot;3.6157205240175&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.8078602620087&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.6157205240175&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;4.0676855895197&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19032656&quot; readability=&quot;9.6960486322188&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.8480243161094&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;9.6960486322188&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;5.8176291793313&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19035460&quot; readability=&quot;1.4831460674157&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19032779&quot; readability=&quot;0.098360655737705&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19032500&quot; readability=&quot;7.4959349593496&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.7479674796748&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7.4959349593496&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;6.5589430894309&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19032578&quot; readability=&quot;4.5736434108527&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.2868217054264&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.5736434108527&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19032880&quot; readability=&quot;2.25&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19032534&quot; readability=&quot;6.5090909090909&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.2545454545455&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.5090909090909&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19032840&quot; readability=&quot;3.4491017964072&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.7245508982036&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.4491017964072&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19032461&quot; readability=&quot;6.6457489878543&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.3228744939271&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.6457489878543&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;5.6963562753036&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19033716&quot; readability=&quot;2.6292134831461&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.314606741573&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.6292134831461&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19033837&quot; readability=&quot;4.5973154362416&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.2986577181208&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.5973154362416&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;5.0570469798658&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19032922&quot; readability=&quot;1.4782608695652&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19032475&quot; readability=&quot;1.4408602150538&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19032736&quot; readability=&quot;3.1496062992126&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19031874&quot; readability=&quot;3.5175879396985&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.7587939698492&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.5175879396985&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19035476&quot; readability=&quot;2.6443298969072&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.3221649484536&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.6443298969072&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19031894&quot; readability=&quot;2.328&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19031929&quot; readability=&quot;0.79166666666667&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19031947&quot; readability=&quot;7.4236311239193&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.7118155619597&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7.4236311239193&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;120&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19031958&quot; readability=&quot;3.3777777777778&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.6888888888889&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.3777777777778&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;120&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19031991&quot; readability=&quot;4.140625&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.0703125&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.140625&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;160&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19032695&quot; readability=&quot;4.5584045584046&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.2792022792023&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.5584045584046&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19032754&quot; readability=&quot;2.5243902439024&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.2621951219512&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.5243902439024&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19033058&quot; readability=&quot;4.5&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.25&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.5&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;4.5&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19033288&quot; readability=&quot;1.4318181818182&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19033495&quot; readability=&quot;10.529182879377&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;5.2645914396887&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;10.529182879377&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;3.8287937743191&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19032993&quot; readability=&quot;6.2425828970332&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.1212914485166&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.2425828970332&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;8.0261780104712&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19032300&quot; readability=&quot;9.7399527186761&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.8699763593381&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;9.7399527186761&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;9.2529550827423&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19035422&quot; readability=&quot;3.4690265486726&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.7345132743363&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.4690265486726&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;4.7699115044248&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19033678&quot; readability=&quot;3.4093959731544&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.7046979865772&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.4093959731544&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19032936&quot; readability=&quot;4.5020746887967&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.2510373443983&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.5020746887967&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19031994&quot; readability=&quot;5.4700315457413&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.7350157728707&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.4700315457413&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19035491&quot; readability=&quot;2.6497461928934&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.3248730964467&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.6497461928934&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19032373&quot; readability=&quot;3.4475138121547&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.7237569060773&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.4475138121547&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19032670&quot; readability=&quot;2.4230769230769&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.2115384615385&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.4230769230769&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19032549&quot; readability=&quot;3.5276752767528&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.7638376383764&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.5276752767528&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19032151&quot; readability=&quot;2.5241379310345&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.2620689655172&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.5241379310345&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19033756&quot; readability=&quot;2.5510204081633&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.2755102040816&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.5510204081633&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;5.1020408163265&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19032775&quot; readability=&quot;2.8235294117647&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19032363&quot; readability=&quot;8.5581818181818&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.2790909090909&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;8.5581818181818&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;8.0827272727273&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19032530&quot; readability=&quot;2.4634146341463&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.2317073170732&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.4634146341463&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19032259&quot; readability=&quot;10.5875&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;5.29375&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;10.5875&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;11.06875&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19035013&quot; readability=&quot;1.4712643678161&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19032644&quot; readability=&quot;4.6048632218845&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.3024316109422&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.6048632218845&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19032659&quot; readability=&quot;6.4634146341463&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.2317073170732&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.4634146341463&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;5.0783972125436&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19032990&quot; readability=&quot;5.3977695167286&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.6988847583643&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.3977695167286&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19033063&quot; readability=&quot;3.361963190184&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.680981595092&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.361963190184&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19034191&quot; readability=&quot;5.4056603773585&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.7028301886792&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.4056603773585&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19034197&quot; readability=&quot;3.3178294573643&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.6589147286822&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.3178294573643&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19033044&quot; readability=&quot;3.4563106796117&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.7281553398058&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.4563106796117&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19033087&quot; readability=&quot;3.4954954954955&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.7477477477477&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.4954954954955&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19033723&quot; readability=&quot;2.6181818181818&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.3090909090909&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.6181818181818&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;3.4909090909091&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19034424&quot; readability=&quot;1.3734939759036&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19032449&quot; readability=&quot;8.2677966101695&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.1338983050847&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;8.2677966101695&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19032111&quot; readability=&quot;3.1351351351351&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19032652&quot; readability=&quot;2.4715909090909&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.2357954545455&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.4715909090909&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19032820&quot; readability=&quot;1.1428571428571&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19032258&quot; readability=&quot;1.5555555555556&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19032595&quot; readability=&quot;0.8&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19032809&quot; readability=&quot;0.93181818181818&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19035506&quot; readability=&quot;0.36363636363636&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19032768&quot; readability=&quot;1.0344827586207&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19031730&quot; readability=&quot;1.4285714285714&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19031959&quot; readability=&quot;4.4229607250755&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19031866&quot; readability=&quot;5.6240963855422&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.8120481927711&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.6240963855422&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;5.155421686747&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19031951&quot; readability=&quot;5.8597285067873&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.9298642533937&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.8597285067873&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;3.3484162895928&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19033167&quot; readability=&quot;7.2977099236641&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.6488549618321&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7.2977099236641&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;120&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19031952&quot; readability=&quot;5.5333333333333&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.7666666666667&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.5333333333333&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19032811&quot; readability=&quot;2.3777777777778&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19032023&quot; readability=&quot;4.1082802547771&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.0541401273885&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.1082802547771&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19033219&quot; readability=&quot;6.5267605633803&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.2633802816901&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.5267605633803&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19033194&quot; readability=&quot;2.2871287128713&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19033246&quot; readability=&quot;3.6818181818182&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.8409090909091&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.6818181818182&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19034390&quot; readability=&quot;7.5391791044776&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.7695895522388&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7.5391791044776&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;6.2826492537313&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19034083&quot; readability=&quot;1.4878048780488&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19033074&quot; readability=&quot;2.2659574468085&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19031723&quot; readability=&quot;3.1711711711712&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19031869&quot; readability=&quot;2.4566929133858&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.2283464566929&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.4566929133858&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19031891&quot; readability=&quot;4.3348623853211&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.1674311926606&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.3348623853211&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19033035&quot; readability=&quot;1.3134328358209&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19031899&quot; readability=&quot;5.421686746988&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.710843373494&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.421686746988&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19031943&quot; readability=&quot;2.22&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19032457&quot; readability=&quot;3.3557046979866&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.6778523489933&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.3557046979866&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19032676&quot; readability=&quot;2.4152542372881&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.2076271186441&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.4152542372881&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;120&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19031857&quot; readability=&quot;4.4605809128631&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.2302904564315&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.4605809128631&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;4.0145228215768&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;19033527&quot; readability=&quot;1.4526315789474&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;morespace&quot;&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2019 01:23:04 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>tones411</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19031711</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Google Takes Its First Steps Toward Killing the URL</title>
<link>https://www.wired.com/story/google-chrome-kill-url-first-steps/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.wired.com/story/google-chrome-kill-url-first-steps/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lede&quot;&gt;In September, members&lt;/span&gt; of Google's Chrome security team put forth a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/story/google-wants-to-kill-the-url/&quot;&gt;radical proposal&lt;/a&gt;: Kill off URLs as we know them. The researchers aren't actually advocating a change to the web's underlying infrastructure. They do, though, want to rework how browsers convey what website you're looking at, so that you don't have to contend with increasingly long and unintelligible URLs—and the fraud that has &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/story/phishing-schemes-use-encrypted-sites-to-seem-legit/&quot;&gt;sprung up&lt;/a&gt; around them. In a talk at the Bay Area Enigma security conference on Tuesday, Chrome usable security lead Emily Stark is wading into the controversy, detailing Google's first steps toward more robust website identity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stark emphasizes that Google isn't trying to induce chaos by eliminating URLs. Rather, it wants to make it harder for hackers to capitalize on user confusion about the identity of a website. Currently, the endless haze of complicated URLs gives attackers cover for effective scams. They can create a malicious link that seems to lead to a legitimate site, but actually automatically redirects victims to a phishing page. Or they can design malicious pages with URLs that look similar to real ones, hoping victims won't notice that they're on G00gle rather than Google. With so many URL shenanigans to combat, the Chrome team is already at work on two projects aimed at bringing users some clarity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paywall&quot;&gt;&quot;What we’re really talking about is changing the way site identity is presented,&quot; Stark told WIRED. &quot;People should know easily what site they’re on, and they shouldn’t be confused into thinking they’re on another site. It shouldn’t take advanced knowledge of how the internet works to figure that out.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;inset-left-component paywall inset-left-component--pullquote&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;inset-left&quot; class=&quot;inset-left-component__el&quot; readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;A key challenge is avoiding flagging legitimate domains as suspicious.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;inset-left&quot; class=&quot;inset-left-component__el&quot;&gt;Emily Stark, Google Chrome&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paywall&quot;&gt;The Chrome team's efforts so far focus on figuring out how to detect URLs that seem to deviate in some way from standard practice. The foundation for this is an open source tool called TrickURI, launching in step with Stark's conference talk, that helps developers check that their software is displaying URLs accurately and consistently. The goal is to give developers something to test against so they know how URLs are going to look to users in different situations. Separate from TrickURI, Stark and her colleagues are also working to create warnings for Chrome users when a URL seems potentially phishy. The alerts are still in internal testing, because the complicated part is developing heuristics that correctly flag malicious sites without dinging legitimate ones.*&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paywall&quot;&gt;For Google users, the first line of defense against phishing and other online scams is still the company's &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/story/google-safe-browsing-oral-history/&quot;&gt;Safe Browsing platform&lt;/a&gt;. But the Chrome team is exploring complements to Safe Browsing that specifically focus on flagging sketchy URLs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;cite class=&quot;caption-component__credit&quot;&gt;Google&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paywall&quot;&gt;&quot;Our heuristics for detecting misleading URLs involve comparing characters that look similar to each other and domains that vary from each other just by a small number of characters,&quot; Stark says. &quot;Our goal is to develop a set of heuristics that pushes attackers away from extremely misleading URLs, and a key challenge is avoiding flagging legitimate domains as suspicious. This is why we're launching this warning slowly, as an experiment.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;paywall&quot;&gt;Google says it hasn't started rolling out the warnings to the general user population while the Chrome team refines those detection capabilities. And while URLs may not be going anywhere anytime soon, Stark emphasizes that there is more in the works on how to get users to focus on important parts of URLs and to refine how Chrome presents them. The big challenge is showing people the parts of URLs that are relevant to their security and online decision-making, while somehow filtering out all the extra components that make URLs hard to read. Browsers also sometimes need to help users with the opposite problem, by expanding shortened or truncated URLs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paywall&quot;&gt;&quot;The whole space is really challenging because URLs work really well for certain people and use cases right now, and lots of people love them,&quot; Stark says. &quot;We’re excited about the progress that we’ve made with our new open source URL display 'TrickURI' tool and our exploratory new warnings on confusable URLs.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paywall&quot;&gt;The Chrome security team has taken on internet-wide security issues before, developing fixes for them in Chrome and then throwing Google's weight around to motivate everyone to adopt the practice. The strategy was particularly successful over the last five years in stimulating a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/2016/11/googles-chrome-hackers-flip-webs-security-model/&quot;&gt;movement toward universal adoption&lt;/a&gt; of HTTPS web encryption. But &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/story/google-chrome-https-not-secure-label/&quot;&gt;critics of the approach&lt;/a&gt; fear the drawbacks of Chrome's power and ubiquity. The same influence that has been used for positive change could be misdirected or abused. And with something as foundational as URLs, critics fear that the Chrome team could land on website identity display tactics that are good for Chrome, but don't actually benefit the rest of the web. Even seemingly minor changes to Chrome's privacy and security posture can have &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/story/google-chrome-login-privacy/&quot;&gt;major impacts&lt;/a&gt; on the web community.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p class=&quot;paywall&quot;&gt;Additionally, a tradeoff of that ubiquity is being beholden to risk-averse corporate customers. &quot;URLs as they work now are often unable to convey a risk level users can quickly identify,&quot; says Katie Moussouris, founder of the responsible vulnerability disclosure firm Luta Security. &quot;But as Chrome grows in enterprise adoption, rather than the consumer space, their ability to radically change visible interfaces and underlying security architecture will be reduced by the pressure of their customers. Great popularity comes not only with great responsibility to keep people safe, but to minimize churn in features, usability, and backwards compatibility.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paywall&quot;&gt;If it all sounds like a lot of confusing and frustrating work, that's exactly the point. The next question will be how the Chrome team's new ideas perform in practice, and whether they really wind up making you safer on the web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paywall&quot;&gt;*&lt;em&gt;Correction January 29, 10:30pm: This story originally stated that TrickURI uses machine learning to parse URL samples and test warnings for suspicious URLs. It has been updated to reflect that the tool instead assess whether software displays URLs accurately and consistently.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;paywall&quot;/&gt;&lt;h3 class=&quot;paywall&quot;&gt;More Great WIRED Stories&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2019 00:06:53 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>glassworm</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Google Takes Its First Steps Toward Killing the URL</og:title>
<og:description>Google wants to get rid of URLs. But first, it needs to show you why.</og:description>
<og:image>https://media.wired.com/photos/5c50d9d8bb78982ce8efe7a8/191:100/pass/Google%20Takes%20Its%20First%20Steps%20Toward%20Killing%20the%20URL.jpg</og:image>
<og:url>https://www.wired.com/story/google-chrome-kill-url-first-steps/</og:url>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.wired.com/story/google-chrome-kill-url-first-steps/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Facebook has been paying people to install a “Research” VPN</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2019/01/29/facebook-project-atlas/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2019/01/29/facebook-project-atlas/</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;speakable-summary&quot;&gt;Desperate for data on its competitors, &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://crunchbase.com/organization/facebook&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;facebook&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; has been secretly paying people to install a “Facebook Research” VPN that lets the company suck in all of a user’s phone and web activity, similar to Facebook’s Onavo Protect app that Apple banned in June and that was removed in August. Facebook sidesteps the App Store and rewards teenagers and adults to download the Research app and give it root access to network traffic in what may be a violation of Apple policy so the social network can decrypt and analyze their phone activity, a TechCrunch investigation confirms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook admitted to TechCrunch it was running the Research program to gather data on usage habits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since 2016, Facebook has been paying users ages 13 to 35 up to $20 per month plus referral fees to sell their privacy by installing the iOS or Android “Facebook Research” app. Facebook even asked users to screenshot their Amazon order history page. The program is administered through beta testing services Applause, BetaBound and uTest to cloak Facebook’s involvement, and is referred to in some documentation as “Project Atlas” — a fitting name for Facebook’s effort to map new trends and rivals around the globe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seven hours after this story was published, Facebook told TechCrunch it would shut down the iOS version of its Research app in the wake of our report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But on Wednesday morning, an &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2019/01/30/apple-bans-facebook-vpn/&quot;&gt;Apple spokesperson confirmed that Facebook violated its policies, and it had blocked Facebook’s Research app&lt;/a&gt; before the social network seemingly pulled it voluntarily without mentioning it was forced to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We designed our Enterprise Developer Program solely for the internal distribution of apps within an organization,” said a spokesperson. “Facebook has been using their membership to distribute a data-collecting app to consumers, which is a clear breach of their agreement with Apple. Any developer using their enterprise certificates to distribute apps to consumers will have their certificates revoked, which is what we did in this case to protect our users and their data.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Facebook’s Research program will continue to run on Android.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook’s Research app requires users to ‘Trust’ it with extensive access to their dataWe asked Guardian Mobile Firewall’s security expert Will Strafach to dig into the Facebook Research app, and he told us that “If Facebook makes full use of the level of access they are given by asking users to install the Certificate, they will have the ability to continuously collect the following types of data: private messages in social media apps, chats from in instant messaging apps – including photos/videos sent to others, emails, web searches, web browsing activity, and even ongoing location information by tapping into the feeds of any location tracking apps you may have installed.” It’s unclear exactly what data Facebook is concerned with, but it gets nearly limitless access to a user’s device once they install the app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;breakout wp-image-1775664 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Facebook-Research-App-Install1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1667&quot; height=&quot;934&quot; srcset=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Facebook-Research-App-Install1.png 1667w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Facebook-Research-App-Install1.png?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Facebook-Research-App-Install1.png?resize=300,168 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Facebook-Research-App-Install1.png?resize=768,430 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Facebook-Research-App-Install1.png?resize=680,381 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Facebook-Research-App-Install1.png?resize=50,28 50w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1667px) 100vw, 1667px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The strategy shows how far Facebook is willing to go and how much it’s willing to pay to protect its dominance — even at the risk of breaking the rules of Apple’s iOS platform on which it depends. Apple may have asked Facebook to discontinue distributing its Research app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A more stringent punishment would be to revoke Facebook’s permission to offer employee-only apps. The situation could further chill relations between the tech giants. Apple’s Tim Cook has repeatedly criticized Facebook’s data collection practices. Facebook disobeying iOS policies to slurp up more information could become a new talking point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_1775572&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; readability=&quot;33&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;breakout wp-image-1775572&quot; src=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Facebook-Project-Atlas.jpg?w=680&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;414&quot; srcset=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Facebook-Project-Atlas.jpg 6000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Facebook-Project-Atlas.jpg?resize=150,78 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Facebook-Project-Atlas.jpg?resize=300,155 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Facebook-Project-Atlas.jpg?resize=768,398 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Facebook-Project-Atlas.jpg?resize=680,352 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Facebook-Project-Atlas.jpg?resize=50,26 50w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Facebook’s Research program is referred to as Project Atlas on sign-up sites that don’t mention Facebook’s involvement&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The fairly technical sounding ‘install our Root Certificate’ step is appalling,” Strafach tells us. “This hands Facebook continuous access to the most sensitive data about you, and most users are going to be unable to reasonably consent to this regardless of any agreement they sign, because there is no good way to articulate just how much power is handed to Facebook when you do this.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Facebook’s surveillance app&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook first got into the data-sniffing business when it &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2013/10/13/facebook-buys-mobile-analytics-company-onavo-and-finally-gets-its-office-in-israel/&quot;&gt;acquired Onavo&lt;/a&gt; for around $120 million in 2014. The VPN app helped users track and minimize their mobile data plan usage, but also gave Facebook deep analytics about what other apps they were using. Internal documents acquired by Charlie Warzel and Ryan Mac of &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/02/12/facebook-starts-pushing-its-data-tracking-onavo-vpn-within-its-main-mobile-app/&quot;&gt;BuzzFeed News&lt;/a&gt; reveal that Facebook was able to leverage Onavo to learn that WhatsApp was sending more than twice as many messages per day as Facebook Messenger. &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://crunchbase.com/organization/onavo&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;onavo&quot;&gt;Onavo&lt;/a&gt; allowed Facebook to spot WhatsApp’s meteoric rise and justify paying $19 billion to buy the chat startup in 2014. WhatsApp has since tripled its user base, demonstrating the power of Onavo’s foresight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-1775658 size-large&quot; src=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Onavo-Protect.png?w=680&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;680&quot; height=&quot;354&quot; srcset=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Onavo-Protect.png 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Onavo-Protect.png?resize=150,78 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Onavo-Protect.png?resize=300,156 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Onavo-Protect.png?resize=680,354 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Onavo-Protect.png?resize=50,26 50w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the years since, Onavo clued Facebook in to what apps to copy, features to build and flops to avoid. By 2018, Facebook was promoting the &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/02/12/facebook-starts-pushing-its-data-tracking-onavo-vpn-within-its-main-mobile-app/&quot;&gt;Onavo app in a Protect&lt;/a&gt; bookmark of the main Facebook app in hopes of scoring more users to snoop on. Facebook also launched the &lt;a href=&quot;https://gizmodo.com/facebook-launches-another-deceptive-security-app-design-1823650981&quot;&gt;Onavo Bolt app&lt;/a&gt; that let you lock apps behind a passcode or fingerprint while it surveils you, but Facebook shut down the app the day it was discovered following privacy criticism. Onavo’s main app remains available on Google Play and has been installed more than 10 million times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The backlash heated up after security expert &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@chronic_9612/notes-on-analytics-and-tracking-in-onavo-protect-for-ios-904bdff346c0&quot;&gt;Strafach detailed&lt;/a&gt; in March how Onavo Protect was reporting to Facebook when a user’s screen was on or off, and its Wi-Fi and cellular data usage in bytes even when the VPN was turned off. In June, Apple updated its developer policies to ban collecting data about usage of other apps or data that’s not necessary for an app to function. Apple proceeded to inform Facebook in August that Onavo Protect violated those data collection policies and that the social network needed to remove it from the App Store, which it did, Deepa Seetharaman of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/facebook-to-remove-data-security-app-from-apple-store-1534975340&quot;&gt;WSJ&lt;/a&gt; reported.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But that didn’t stop Facebook’s data collection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Project Atlas&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TechCrunch recently received a tip that despite Onavo Protect being banished by Apple, Facebook was paying users to sideload a similar VPN app under the Facebook Research moniker from outside of the App Store. We investigated, and learned Facebook was working with three app beta testing services to distribute the Facebook Research app: BetaBound, uTest and Applause. Facebook began distributing the Research VPN app in 2016. It has been referred to as Project Atlas since at least mid-2018, around when backlash to Onavo Protect magnified and Apple instituted its new rules that prohibited Onavo. Previously, a similar program was called Project Kodiak. Facebook didn’t want to stop collecting data on people’s phone usage and so the Research program continued, in disregard for Apple banning Onavo Protect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_1775666&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption alignright&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-1775666 size-large&quot; src=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Facebook-Research-App-Icon.png?w=339&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;339&quot; height=&quot;359&quot; srcset=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Facebook-Research-App-Icon.png 339w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Facebook-Research-App-Icon.png?resize=142,150 142w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Facebook-Research-App-Icon.png?resize=283,300 283w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Facebook-Research-App-Icon.png?resize=47,50 47w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 339px) 100vw, 339px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Facebook’s Research App on iOS&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ads (shown below) for the program run by uTest on Instagram and Snapchat sought teens 13-17 years old for a “paid social media research study.” The &lt;a href=&quot;http://smrsignup.applause.com/refer&quot;&gt;sign-up page&lt;/a&gt; for the Facebook Research program administered by Applause doesn’t mention Facebook, but seeks users “Age: 13-35 (parental consent required for ages 13-17).” If minors try to sign-up, they’re asked to get their parents’ permission with a form that reveal’s Facebook’s involvement and says “There are no known risks associated with the project, however you acknowledge that the inherent nature of the project involves the tracking of personal information via your child’s use of apps. You will be compensated by Applause for your child’s participation.” For kids short on cash, the payments could coerce them to sell their privacy to Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Applause site explains what data could be collected by the Facebook Research app (emphasis mine):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“By installing the software, you’re giving our client permission to collect data from your phone that will help them understand how you browse the internet, and how you use the features in the apps you’ve installed . . . This means you’re &lt;strong&gt;letting our client collect information such as which apps are on your phone, how and when you use them&lt;/strong&gt;, data about your activities and content within those apps, as well as how other people interact with you or your content within those apps. You are also &lt;strong&gt;letting our client collect information about your internet browsing activity&lt;/strong&gt; (including the websites you visit and data that is exchanged between your device and those websites) and your use of other online services. There are some instances when &lt;strong&gt;our client will collect this information even where the app uses encryption&lt;/strong&gt;, or from within secure browser sessions.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://my.betabound.com/key/atlas&quot;&gt;BetaBound sign-up page&lt;/a&gt; with a URL ending in “Atlas” explains that “For $20 per month (via e-gift cards), you will install an app on your phone and let it run in the background.” It also offers $20 per friend you refer. That site also doesn’t initially mention Facebook, but the instruction manual for installing Facebook Research reveals the company’s involvement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_1775846&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; readability=&quot;34&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;breakout wp-image-1775846 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Facebook-advertises-Project-Atlas-Research1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;915&quot; height=&quot;898&quot; srcset=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Facebook-advertises-Project-Atlas-Research1.png 915w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Facebook-advertises-Project-Atlas-Research1.png?resize=150,147 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Facebook-advertises-Project-Atlas-Research1.png?resize=300,294 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Facebook-advertises-Project-Atlas-Research1.png?resize=768,754 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Facebook-advertises-Project-Atlas-Research1.png?resize=680,667 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Facebook-advertises-Project-Atlas-Research1.png?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Facebook-advertises-Project-Atlas-Research1.png?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Facebook-advertises-Project-Atlas-Research1.png?resize=64,64 64w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 915px) 100vw, 915px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Facebook’s intermediary uTest ran ads on Snapchat and Instagram, luring teens to the Research program with the promise of money&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Facebook seems to have purposefully avoided TestFlight, Apple’s official beta testing system, which requires apps to be reviewed by Apple and is limited to 10,000 participants. Instead, the instruction manual reveals that users download the app from r.facebook-program.com and are told to install an Enterprise Developer Certificate and VPN and “Trust” Facebook with root access to the data their phone transmits. Apple requires that developers agree to only use this certificate system for distributing internal corporate apps to their own employees. Randomly recruiting testers and paying them a monthly fee appears to violate the spirit of that rule.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_1775895&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption alignright&quot; readability=&quot;34&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;vertical wp-image-1775895 size-large&quot; src=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Facebook-Research-App-Code-The-Same-As-Onavo.jpg?w=298&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;298&quot; height=&quot;584&quot; srcset=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Facebook-Research-App-Code-The-Same-As-Onavo.jpg 298w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Facebook-Research-App-Code-The-Same-As-Onavo.jpg?resize=77,150 77w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Facebook-Research-App-Code-The-Same-As-Onavo.jpg?resize=153,300 153w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Facebook-Research-App-Code-The-Same-As-Onavo.jpg?resize=26,50 26w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 298px) 100vw, 298px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Security expert Will Strafach found Facebook’s Research app contains lots of code from Onavo Protect, the Facebook-owned app Apple banned last year&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once installed, users just had to keep the VPN running and sending data to Facebook to get paid. The Applause-administered program requested that users screenshot their Amazon orders page. This data could potentially help Facebook tie browsing habits and usage of other apps with purchase preferences and behavior. That information could be harnessed to pinpoint ad targeting and understand which types of users buy what.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TechCrunch commissioned Strafach to analyze the Facebook Research app and find out where it was sending data. He confirmed that data is routed to “&lt;a href=&quot;http://vpn-sjc1.v.facebook-program.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; data-saferedirecturl=&quot;https://www.google.com/url?q=http://vpn-sjc1.v.facebook-program.com&amp;amp;source=gmail&amp;amp;ust=1548865211198000&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNEzl7D5RC3O41RcVhVzAo59Er0fTw&quot;&gt;vpn-sjc1.v.facebook-program.&lt;wbr/&gt;com&lt;/a&gt;” that is associated with Onavo’s IP address, and that the facebook-program.com domain is registered to Facebook, according to MarkMonitor. The app can update itself without interacting with the App Store, and is linked to the email address PeopleJourney@fb.com. He also discovered that the Enterprise Certificate first acquired in 2016 indicates Facebook renewed it on June 27th, 2018 — weeks after Apple announced its new rules that prohibited the similar Onavo Protect app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It is tricky to know what data Facebook is actually saving (without access to their servers). The only information that is knowable here is what access Facebook is capable of based on the code in the app. And it paints a very worrisome picture,” Strafach explains. “They might respond and claim to only actually retain/save very specific limited data, and that could be true, it really boils down to how much you trust Facebook’s word on it. The most charitable narrative of this situation would be that Facebook did not think too hard about the level of access they were granting to themselves . . . which is a startling level of carelessness in itself if that is the case.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;“Flagrant defiance of Apple’s rules”&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In response to TechCrunch’s inquiry, a Facebook spokesperson confirmed it’s running the program to learn how people use their phones and other services. The spokesperson told us “Like many companies, we invite people to participate in research that helps us identify things we can be doing better. Since this research is aimed at helping Facebook understand how people use their mobile devices, we’ve provided extensive information about the type of data we collect and how they can participate. We don’t share this information with others and people can stop participating at any time.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_1775696&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; readability=&quot;34&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;breakout wp-image-1775696&quot; src=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Facebook-Research-Install-Root-Certificate.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;558&quot; srcset=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Facebook-Research-Install-Root-Certificate.png 1319w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Facebook-Research-Install-Root-Certificate.png?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Facebook-Research-Install-Root-Certificate.png?resize=300,167 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Facebook-Research-Install-Root-Certificate.png?resize=768,429 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Facebook-Research-Install-Root-Certificate.png?resize=680,379 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Facebook-Research-Install-Root-Certificate.png?resize=50,28 50w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Facebook’s Research app requires Root Certificate access, which Facebook gather almost any piece of data transmitted by your phone&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook’s spokesperson claimed that the Facebook Research app was in line with Apple’s Enterprise Certificate program, but didn’t explain how in the face of evidence to the contrary. They said Facebook first launched its Research app program in 2016. They tried to liken the program to a focus group and said Nielsen and comScore run similar programs, yet neither of those ask people to install a VPN or provide root access to the network. The spokesperson confirmed the Facebook Research program does recruit teens but also other age groups from around the world. They claimed that Onavo and Facebook Research are separate programs, but admitted the same team supports both as an explanation for why their code was so similar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_1775661&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption alignright&quot; readability=&quot;33&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;vertical wp-image-1775661 size-large&quot; src=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Facebook-Research-Screenshot-Amazon.png?w=371&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;371&quot; height=&quot;680&quot; srcset=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Facebook-Research-Screenshot-Amazon.png 491w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Facebook-Research-Screenshot-Amazon.png?resize=82,150 82w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Facebook-Research-Screenshot-Amazon.png?resize=164,300 164w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Facebook-Research-Screenshot-Amazon.png?resize=371,680 371w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Facebook-Research-Screenshot-Amazon.png?resize=27,50 27w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 371px) 100vw, 371px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Facebook’s Research program requested users screenshot their Amazon order history to provide it with purchase data&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, Facebook’s claim that it doesn’t violate &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.slideshare.net/joshsc/apple-policy-prohibits-distributing-enterprise-certificate-apps-to-nonemployees&quot;&gt;Apple’s Enterprise Certificate policy&lt;/a&gt; is directly contradicted by the terms of that policy. Those include that developers “Distribute Provisioning Profiles only to Your Employees and only in conjunction with Your Internal Use Applications for the purpose of developing and testing”. The policy also states that “You may not use, distribute or otherwise make Your Internal Use Applications available to Your Customers” unless under direct supervision of employees or on company premises. Given Facebook’s customers are using the Enterprise Certificate-powered app without supervision, it appears Facebook is in violation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seven hours after this report was first published, Facebook updated its position and told TechCrunch that it would shut down the iOS Research app. Facebook noted that the Research app was started in 2016 and was therefore not a replacement for Onavo Protect. However, they do share similar code and could be seen as twins running in parallel. A Facebook spokesperson also provided this additional statement:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Key facts about this market research program are being ignored. Despite early reports, there was nothing ‘secret’ about this; it was literally called the Facebook Research App. It wasn’t ‘spying’ as all of the people who signed up to participate went through a clear on-boarding process asking for their permission and were paid to participate. Finally, less than 5 percent of the people who chose to participate in this market research program were teens. All of them with signed parental consent forms.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook did not publicly promote the Research VPN itself and used intermediaries that often didn’t disclose Facebook’s involvement until users had begun the signup process. While users were given clear instructions and warnings, the program never stresses nor mentions the full extent of the data Facebook can collect through the VPN. A small fraction of the users paid may have been teens, but we stand by the newsworthiness of its choice not to exclude minors from this data collection initiative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook disobeying Apple so directly and then pulling the app could hurt their relationship. “The code in this iOS app strongly indicates that it is simply a poorly re-branded build of the banned Onavo app, now using an Enterprise Certificate owned by Facebook in direct violation of Apple’s rules, allowing Facebook to distribute this app without Apple review to as many users as they want,” Strafach tells us. ONV prefixes and mentions of graph.onavo.com, “onavoApp://” and “onavoProtect://” custom URL schemes litter the app. “This is an egregious violation on many fronts, and I hope that Apple will act expeditiously in revoking the signing certificate to render the app inoperable.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook is particularly interested in what teens do on their phones as the demographic has increasingly abandoned the social network in favor of Snapchat, YouTube and Facebook’s acquisition Instagram. Insights into how popular with teens is Chinese video music app TikTok and meme sharing led Facebook to launch a clone called Lasso and begin developing a meme-browsing feature called LOL, TechCrunch first reported. But Facebook’s desire for data about teens riles critics at a time when the company has been battered in the press. Analysts on tomorrow’s Facebook earnings call should inquire about what other ways the company has to collect competitive intelligence now that it’s ceased to run the Research program on iOS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year when Tim Cook was asked what he’d do in Mark Zuckerberg’s position in the wake of the Cambridge Analytica scandal, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nbcnews.com/tech/tech-news/mark-zuckerberg-fires-back-apple-ceo-s-extremely-glib-comment-n862056&quot;&gt;he said&lt;/a&gt; “I wouldn’t be in this situation . . . The truth is we could make a ton of money if we monetized our customer, if our customer was our product. We’ve elected not to do that.” Zuckerberg told Ezra Klein that he felt Cook’s comment was “extremely glib.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now it’s clear that even after Apple’s warnings and the removal of Onavo Protect, Facebook was still aggressively collecting data on its competitors via Apple’s iOS platform. “I have never seen such open and flagrant defiance of Apple’s rules by an App Store developer,” Strafach concluded. Now that Facebook has ceased the program on iOS and its Android future is uncertain, it may either have to invent new ways to surveil our behavior amidst a climate of privacy scrutiny, or be left in the dark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Additional reporting by Zack Whittaker. Updated with comment from Facebook, and on Wednesday with a statement from Apple. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 23:39:36 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>randomacct3847</dc:creator>
<og:title>Facebook pays teens to install VPN that spies on them</og:title>
<og:description>Desperate for data on its competitors, Facebook has been secretly paying people to install a “Facebook Research” VPN that lets the company suck in all of a user’s phone and web activity, similar to Facebook’s Onavo Protect app that Apple banned in June and that was removed i…</og:description>
<og:image>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/facebook-research-vpn-project-atlas.jpg?w=711</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2019/01/29/facebook-project-atlas/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2019/01/29/facebook-project-atlas/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Office 365 global authentication outage</title>
<link>https://status.office365.com/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://status.office365.com/</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://status.office365.com/&quot;&gt;https://status.office365.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19030099&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19030099&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 325&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 144&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 21:48:01 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Jedd</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://status.office365.com/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Instacart paying 80 cents an hour because worker received a large tip</title>
<link>https://www.workingwa.org/instacart-eighty-cents</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.workingwa.org/instacart-eighty-cents</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;In case that email is as confusing to you as it looks to us, let us help you parse it: what Brie is saying is that &lt;strong&gt;because the customer left a high tip on this particular job, the “batch payment” — the amount Instacart actually pays to the worker — was just 80 cents,&lt;/strong&gt; including a mileage reimbursement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other words, Instacart is now confirming &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.workingwa.org/22cents&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;what workers have been saying since the change in pay structure&lt;/a&gt;: that &lt;strong&gt;the company is actually using customers’ tips to pay workers’ wages&lt;/strong&gt;. When a customer tips up-front, it doesn't mean extra money for the worker. Instacart just pays the worker less to make up for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's right: the customer's tip doesn't get added to the worker's check — it just gets deducted from what Instacart pays. In other words, &lt;strong&gt;up-front tips go to Instacart, not to the worker.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even Instacart seems to know how messed up it is to pay workers less when they get tipped more — which is why &lt;strong&gt;they’ve denied the practice when speaking to reporters at&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/instacart-shoppers-threaten-boycott-claim-lower-pay-2018-12&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Business Insider&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&amp;amp; the&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.miamiherald.com/site-services/new-newsletters/business-news/article224072360.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Miami Herald&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, it seems like Instacart has been hearing us speaking out about the issue…and decided to double down by finally &lt;strong&gt;admitting that they’re taking workers’ tips&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instacart knows it’s wrong. Workers know it’s wrong. We know it’s wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s not let them get away with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Think a company paying workers 80 cents for more than an hour of work needs to be held accountable?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Want to tell Instacart you don’t think taking workers’ tips is more “accurate” or treats them as “valuable”?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://actionnetwork.org/petitions/instacart-heres-our-22-cents-no-more-tip-theft-low-pay-and-black-box-pay-algorithms&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Click here to sign on to our demands for Instacart&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; — we’ll be in touch to tell you how you can fight back.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if you’re a customer on Instacart, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.workingwa.org/22cents&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;click here to learn how you can work around Instacart taking your tips&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by tipping just 22 cents up-front and changing it later.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 21:10:18 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>timebomb0</dc:creator>
<og:title>earn eighty cents an hour by delivering groceries with instacart! — Working Washington</og:title>
<og:url>http://www.workingwa.org/instacart-eighty-cents/</og:url>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:description>Yep, that’s right. Eighty cents. That’s what Instacart actually paid Tom, an Instacart worker, for 69 minutes of his time .</og:description>
<og:image>http://static1.squarespace.com/static/5237604ce4b0e51f969029ae/t/5c4e498c575d1f05fb47f0b9/1548634512546/tom+fb+link+version.png?format=1500w</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.workingwa.org/instacart-eighty-cents</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Apple was warned about the FaceTime eavesdropping bug last week</title>
<link>https://www.theverge.com/2019/1/29/18202398/apple-facetime-bug-warned-eavesdropping</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.theverge.com/2019/1/29/18202398/apple-facetime-bug-warned-eavesdropping</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;zgkLqj&quot;&gt;Yesterday, a worrying and invasive bug that allowed callers to secretly listen in on unknowing recipients &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2019/1/28/18201383/apple-facetime-bug-iphone-eavesdrop-listen-in-remote-call-security-issue&quot;&gt;through Apple’s FaceTime app&lt;/a&gt; quickly made news headlines. It was discovered that people could initiate a FaceTime call and, with a couple short steps, tap into the microphone on the other end as the call rang — without the other person accepting the FaceTime request. Apple said last night that an iOS update to eliminate the privacy bug is coming this week; in the meantime, the company took the step of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2019/1/29/18201667/apple-group-facetime-disabled-server-side-major-security-flaw-fix&quot;&gt;disabling group FaceTime at the server level&lt;/a&gt; as an immediate emergency fix. However, new information suggests that Apple has already had several days to respond; the company was tipped off about it last week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;94Uw32&quot;&gt;Back on January 20th, a Twitter user tweeted at Apple’s support account clearly outlining the gist of the FaceTime bug: “My teen found a major security flaw in Apple’s new iOS. He can listen in to your iPhone/iPad without your approval.” The parent’s teenager had discovered the problem one day prior on January 19th, according to tech entrepreneur John Meyer, who has been in contact with them. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnet.com/news/apples-facetime-bug-was-discovered-by-a-teen-playing-fortnite/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;CNET&lt;/em&gt; has identified the tipster as Michele Thompson&lt;/a&gt;, whose 14-year-old son first encountered the flaw while setting up a group FaceTime call with friends to coordinate strategy during a game of &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;kcdnCK&quot; readability=&quot;8.7647058823529&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; readability=&quot;11.394117647059&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Quick facts from my call with the 14 year old’s mom:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;- Yes, a 14 year old discovered this bug. He did so &quot;around&quot; Saturday, 1/19&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;- Mother is a local lawyer in AZ and sent a formal notice to Apple on 1/25&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;- That formal notice the mom sent to Apple on 1/25 is attached &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/RMbXp3huab&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/RMbXp3huab&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
— John H. Meyer (@BEASTMODE) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/BEASTMODE/status/1090303269090529280?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;January 29, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;4up3pg&quot;&gt;FaceTime wasn’t mentioned in the tweet, but it’s still something that would seem worth looking into. Thompson’s warning has now received a lot of attention, but it could’ve flown under the radar for Apple’s customer service / social media team at the time. There was no direct reply from Apple, but the tweet said a bug report had been filed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;e-image__inner&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;e-image__image&quot; data-original=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13722471/Screen_Shot_2019_01_29_at_1.44.12_PM.png&quot;&gt; &lt;img srcset=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/sqiTZ93x23ZB7TjBCgbWvaCr8yA=/0x0:1184x868/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:1184x868):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13722471/Screen_Shot_2019_01_29_at_1.44.12_PM.png 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1ZXd3ermCeNoM3-WR_WFptLRBIU=/0x0:1184x868/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:1184x868):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13722471/Screen_Shot_2019_01_29_at_1.44.12_PM.png 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0qSwo1HYTQx2IeZdLt7GrEYlgj8=/0x0:1184x868/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:1184x868):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13722471/Screen_Shot_2019_01_29_at_1.44.12_PM.png 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3pkq0lh9nkeGBRG1WM94qHWj2x8=/0x0:1184x868/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:1184x868):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13722471/Screen_Shot_2019_01_29_at_1.44.12_PM.png 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zeUTGd1eAxf57nmjcuJJe1qXcOk=/0x0:1184x868/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:1184x868):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13722471/Screen_Shot_2019_01_29_at_1.44.12_PM.png 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_CXeUjwvRa3hedk7S8nkV6UvSZ4=/0x0:1184x868/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:1184x868):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13722471/Screen_Shot_2019_01_29_at_1.44.12_PM.png 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/T31A4G7nVefMZOoaCOx4GeKZHX4=/0x0:1184x868/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:1184x868):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13722471/Screen_Shot_2019_01_29_at_1.44.12_PM.png 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9gGAD3G86F2v1ftp07aF2n72Ga8=/0x0:1184x868/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:1184x868):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13722471/Screen_Shot_2019_01_29_at_1.44.12_PM.png 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/FZZ4Kmn2fD6XfjE_ZCQhKzkwjyY=/0x0:1184x868/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:1184x868):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13722471/Screen_Shot_2019_01_29_at_1.44.12_PM.png 1920w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 1221px) 846px, (min-width: 880px) calc(100vw - 334px), 100vw&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-upload-width=&quot;1184&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/DuRWWLqQLpxMPtbWKLjv1c9RNOo=/0x0:1184x868/1200x0/filters:focal(0x0:1184x868):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13722471/Screen_Shot_2019_01_29_at_1.44.12_PM.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;uMY4IN&quot;&gt;In fact, through subsequent tweets, Thompson claimed that she made multiple attempts to reach Apple and inform the company of the issue. An email dated January 22nd warned of “a major privacy and security flaw.” Another image seemingly confirms that Thompson eventually emailed product-security@apple.com, which is &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT201220&quot;&gt;exactly what the company says should be done&lt;/a&gt; in this kind of urgent situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;e-image__inner&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;e-image__image&quot; data-original=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13723266/Screen_Shot_2019_01_29_at_2.07.07_PM.png&quot;&gt; &lt;img srcset=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/HAEN5pyfbhayCoAH3TXhgeTz-2k=/0x0:1672x806/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:1672x806):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13723266/Screen_Shot_2019_01_29_at_2.07.07_PM.png 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/jJ1R0yfR8ZVdOwum7LTReyraOPE=/0x0:1672x806/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:1672x806):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13723266/Screen_Shot_2019_01_29_at_2.07.07_PM.png 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/HRH9FL37fZ0iANSzYO1A7s4GLb0=/0x0:1672x806/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:1672x806):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13723266/Screen_Shot_2019_01_29_at_2.07.07_PM.png 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zrezAXK0-NdK3ugN3G2Uwd_vzuo=/0x0:1672x806/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:1672x806):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13723266/Screen_Shot_2019_01_29_at_2.07.07_PM.png 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1UBwYN277Y9i-YtJI61jHdiGWG4=/0x0:1672x806/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:1672x806):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13723266/Screen_Shot_2019_01_29_at_2.07.07_PM.png 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/b1GlDN0DWNIS2yKguuQnGP5P7lY=/0x0:1672x806/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:1672x806):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13723266/Screen_Shot_2019_01_29_at_2.07.07_PM.png 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/DMX4uvqBo8ESGxukCh1rleN0LGY=/0x0:1672x806/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:1672x806):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13723266/Screen_Shot_2019_01_29_at_2.07.07_PM.png 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/KZLLmsL4x0Op8mTrv5MbwhkUZNo=/0x0:1672x806/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:1672x806):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13723266/Screen_Shot_2019_01_29_at_2.07.07_PM.png 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pGxZeGRajz2tdkjJijkzRt6q3PI=/0x0:1672x806/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:1672x806):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13723266/Screen_Shot_2019_01_29_at_2.07.07_PM.png 1920w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 1221px) 846px, (min-width: 880px) calc(100vw - 334px), 100vw&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-upload-width=&quot;1672&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZWOTQVSsNMK7GZCK090H5_k54nw=/0x0:1672x806/1200x0/filters:focal(0x0:1672x806):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13723266/Screen_Shot_2019_01_29_at_2.07.07_PM.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;zOWRm9&quot; readability=&quot;5.6197183098592&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; readability=&quot;5.6197183098592&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Here is another example of the mother reaching out to Apple again over email on Jan 22, after being ignored repeatedly leading up to 1/22. &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/aN52VqWewv&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/aN52VqWewv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
— John H. Meyer (@BEASTMODE) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/BEASTMODE/status/1090307675152363520?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;January 29, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;9gDrKh&quot;&gt;The emails emphasized the bug’s significance, calling it “a huge issue” that Thompson had personally verified. Without revealing the necessary steps to exploit the bug in that email — she had questions regarding Apple’s bug bounty program and wondered if her son might receive a monetary reward for discovering it — Thompson asked Apple to get in touch immediately so that a fix could be quickly developed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;yRQ6x8&quot;&gt;But no response came, leading her to both email and fax a formal document to Apple on January 25th. Here, the full bug is laid out in detail, and the message — titled &lt;strong&gt;Urgent Security Issue Regarding iOS 12.1.3&lt;/strong&gt; — contained an unlisted YouTube link to a video that demonstrated the FaceTime issue. “My fear is that this flaw could be used for nefarious purposes,” Thompson wrote. “At this point, I will not release this information to anyone until I hear back from you.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;QXIQL6&quot; readability=&quot;8.5511363636364&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; readability=&quot;11.116477272727&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;VIDEO: Here is a video, recorded &amp;amp; sent to Apple by a 14 yr old &amp;amp; his mom, on JAN 23rd, alerting them to the dangerous &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/FaceTime?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#FaceTime&lt;/a&gt; bug, that has threatened the privacy of millions. I've removed sensitive / private info on behalf of the mother (an attorney), whom I just spoke to. &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/YIBKXEP3mI&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/YIBKXEP3mI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
— John H. Meyer (@BEASTMODE) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/BEASTMODE/status/1090298850764644352?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;January 29, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;dNz53L&quot;&gt;At some point, Apple did indeed apparently respond, but instructed her to go through the process of filing a bug report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;0qvs1p&quot; readability=&quot;7.9529085872576&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; readability=&quot;9.7202216066482&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Here is the mom’s official bug report to Apple. Note that the mom self-describes as “not at all techy” and was baffled that Apple Support asked her, an average citizen, to sign up for an Apple developer account to then submit an official bug report, in order to be taken seriously &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/PWdrsych5t&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/PWdrsych5t&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
— John H. Meyer (@BEASTMODE) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/BEASTMODE/status/1090314332225843201?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;January 29, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;SnrcwN&quot;&gt;If Apple became aware of the FaceTime exploit before it was widely publicized yesterday, the company did not take any immediate actions to block consumers from being vulnerable to it. &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; was able to verify the eavesdropping capability firsthand before Apple shut down group FaceTime as a quick fix. It might have already been investigating the situation when the news broke, however. The company has not commented on the bug beyond yesterday’s statement about an iOS update coming in the next few days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;VdWtJZ&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update January 29th 2:45PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;The article has been updated with more details about the person who reported the FaceTime bug to Apple.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 20:34:53 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>josu</dc:creator>
<og:description>The bug allowed people to secretly listen in on others.</og:description>
<og:image>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/E3Z7nv0iFjl6ztUEK-xF1QWI2rc=/0x146:2040x1214/fit-in/1200x630/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13721811/DSCF2931.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>Apple was warned about alarming FaceTime eavesdropping bug last week</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.theverge.com/2019/1/29/18202398/apple-facetime-bug-warned-eavesdropping</og:url>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.theverge.com/2019/1/29/18202398/apple-facetime-bug-warned-eavesdropping</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Advice to new programmers</title>
<link>http://olafurw.com/2019-01-27-programmer-advice/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://olafurw.com/2019-01-27-programmer-advice/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;It’s not every day where students new to programming get to ask 709 software developers for advice.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;overview&quot;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a school here in Malmö, Sweden called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thegameassembly.com/&quot;&gt;The Game Assembly&lt;/a&gt;. This school focuses on teaching students game production. Everything from programming to art and design. This is a three year program where the last year is spent at a games studio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I work for a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.massive.se/&quot;&gt;games company&lt;/a&gt;, we get asked to hold lectures for the students. I’ve done this a few times over the years and feel very honored when I get the opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year I got to speak to the first year students. The idea was to go over &lt;a href=&quot;https://speakerdeck.com/olafurw/the-basics-of-object-oriented-programming&quot;&gt;the basics of object oriented programming&lt;/a&gt; but I had another idea as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why not reach out to Twitter and ask if they had any advice for some “impressionable youth” ?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot; readability=&quot;13.291139240506&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Hey, Programming Twitter!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'm going to be speaking to impressionable youth in a couple of days&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;They are in their early years of learning. In the 20ish age range.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What is your one solid advice? Language Agnostic.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;RT's are loved&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;(I'm gonna quote you in the slides so be nice :)&lt;/p&gt;
— Ólafur Waage (@olafurw) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/olafurw/status/1087438169585434624?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;January 21, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting well over 700 replies was not something I imagined would happen. Because I only had two days from the tweet until the talk, I was not able to summarize all of the wisdom. But I tried to find the most liked ones and replies from individuals that work in the gaming industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there was just too much data to gloss over. I needed to analyze the replies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;getting-the-data&quot;&gt;Getting the data&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First I tried to just browse the timeline on Twitter and copy the text from there. But apparently when a thread reaches a certain size, Twitter limits how many tweets you can see. So from that data set I was only able to get 285 replies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next up was to use the Twitter Developer API, which is heavily throttled but allows for more granularity in searching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using Python and Tweepy and a 5 minute sleep between requests, I was able to fetch 763 tweets that were a direct reply to my request. This took &lt;strong&gt;362 minutes&lt;/strong&gt;, or &lt;strong&gt;6 hours&lt;/strong&gt;. It might have been ok to have a shorter sleep but I left it overnight, so it didn’t matter much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-python highlighter-rouge&quot; readability=&quot;9.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;14&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;page&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tweepy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Cursor&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;api&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;search&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;q&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;to:olafurw&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;since_id&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;'1087438169585434624'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tweet_mode&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;'extended'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;pages&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;():&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;repliesFile&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;open&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;replies.txt&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;a&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  
  &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tweet&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;page&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;repliesFile&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;write&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tweet&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;in_reply_to_status_id_str&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;se&quot;&gt;\n&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;repliesFile&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;write&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tweet&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;user&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;screen_name&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;se&quot;&gt;\n&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;repliesFile&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;write&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tweet&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;id_str&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;se&quot;&gt;\n&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;repliesFile&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;write&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tweet&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;full_text&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;encode&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;utf-8&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;se&quot;&gt;\n&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;repliesFile&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;write&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;se&quot;&gt;\n&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;--==--&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;se&quot;&gt;\n&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  
  &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;repliesFile&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;flush&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;repliesFile&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;close&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
  
  &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;time&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;sleep&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;300&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;basic-analysis&quot;&gt;Basic Analysis&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Analyzing a text corpus is an educational field on it’s own and I don’t have the knowledge or the time to go in depth. But I do want to highlight a few things that stood out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;programming-is-a-human-field&quot;&gt;Programming is a human field&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;131 out of 763 tweets talk about other people. &lt;strong&gt;17.1%&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They talk about humans, teams, peers, friends, colleagues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some examples:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;3.5714285714286&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/tomjadams/status/1088336413827915776&quot;&gt;@tomjadams&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Software is a team sport&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;5.5221238938053&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mrdowden/status/1087882550964641792&quot;&gt;@mrdowden&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The most important thing in life – and something you always control – is how you treat other people&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;7.4458874458874&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/originalJonLowe/status/1087594133357760513&quot;&gt;@originalJonLowe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Be supportive and kind in your journey for knowledge&lt;br/&gt;Build other developers up because at the end of the day, you’re a part of a team&lt;br/&gt;Be a team player over a “Rockstar” because knowledge is meant to be shared&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;4.3076923076923&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ccmccomb/status/1087845662937546756&quot;&gt;@ccmccomb&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Never forget to find room for compassion in computation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;programming-is-about-continuous-learning&quot;&gt;Programming is about continuous learning&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;13 replies were literally “Never stop learning”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;82 out of 763 tweets talked about learning or practice in some way. &lt;strong&gt;10.7%&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some examples:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;6.1884057971014&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/iam_js_/status/1088153200371355650&quot;&gt;@iam_js_&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;There are no shortcuts, practice, practice and more practice&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;4.4&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/curtisko/status/1087725805982093312&quot;&gt;@curtisko&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;You are responsible for continued learning and career progression&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;6.637037037037&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hedgeb/status/1087525264140234752&quot;&gt;@hedgeb&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Even if you are just one page ahead in the manual, you can mentor someone and help them along in their journey learning to code&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;6.5302013422819&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/howbazaar/status/1087773774374522881&quot;&gt;@howbazaar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;You are going to keep learning&lt;br/&gt;You’re not done&lt;br/&gt;Being good takes practice&lt;br/&gt;Read books, read blogs&lt;br/&gt;Don’t expect to be great in six months&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;programming-can-be-intimidating&quot;&gt;Programming can be intimidating&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many replies reflected this well. There is a lot to learn and a lot you do not know. Looking at experts in the field can be daunting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;27 replies talked about mistakes or failing, 29 about fear, being afraid or scared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;5.3617021276596&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jitterted/status/1087575050318835712&quot;&gt;@jitterted&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Don’t compare yourself to others, compare yourself to where &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; were in the past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;5.5555555555556&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/greberger/status/1087842355481325574&quot;&gt;@greberger&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Never be afraid to say that you don’t know something&lt;br/&gt;Don’t be afraid to ask for help&lt;br/&gt;We all suffer(ed) impostor syndrome&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;6.578313253012&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ben_deane/status/1087805790423904256&quot;&gt;@ben_deane&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;We all make mistakes&lt;br/&gt;Try to honestly accept responsibility for your mistakes without being ashamed, and don’t put shame on others when they make mistakes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;6.5767441860465&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/FiddlersCode/status/1087619274032721926&quot;&gt;@FiddlersCode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Tech is ephemeral but relationships last&lt;br/&gt;Get to know your colleagues and yourself emotionally&lt;br/&gt;Have the courage to be vulnerable about your struggles&lt;br/&gt;Ask for help even if you’re afraid of looking dumb&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;programming-is-not-just-the-latest-tech&quot;&gt;Programming is not just the latest tech&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes the shiny new library/language/framework is cool. But as many replies showed, the fundamentals mattered much more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;34 replies talked directly about tech, algorithms and focusing on the bigger picture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;9.4573643410853&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/bjorn_fahller/status/1087439484709490689&quot;&gt;@bjorn_fahller&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Languages and tools come and go.&lt;br/&gt;Learn to see patterns that repeat, or rather rhyme, in different languages and libraries and even paradigms.&lt;br/&gt;Learn the pros and cons of different techniques, so you can choose wisely for your specific problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;10.738095238095&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/aras_p/status/1087443639750529025&quot;&gt;@aras_p&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Find area of programming that interests you and do work there.&lt;br/&gt;Small incremental tasks - “hey I made screen red! now I made a gradient!”, “hey I made button on the page move!” etc.&lt;br/&gt;Language, framework, library, “tech stack” does not matter (ignore everyone who say it does).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;5.0434782608696&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/rickschott/status/1087492136331812867&quot;&gt;@rickschott&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The world needs problem solvers, not memorized algorithms&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;programming-can-ask-too-much-of-you&quot;&gt;Programming can ask too much of you&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personal health was also a common discussion point. Sleep and eating right were top of the list regarding healthy behaviors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;33 replies talk about sleep, eating, personal health and working hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;9.6296296296296&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/sehurlburt/status/1087448744113684481&quot;&gt;@sehurlburt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Get sleep, eat healthy, take care of your body— even if you feel fine&lt;br/&gt;More hours working doesn’t mean better work, it doesn’t even mean more work gets done&lt;br/&gt;You don’t have to have your career figured out&lt;br/&gt;You don’t need to hit external life milestones to be just fine and happy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;11.512195121951&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/caffodian/status/1087449579589591044&quot;&gt;@caffodian&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Take care of yourself physically&lt;br/&gt;Yea, actual programming skills are useful, but so is being able to use a mouse without hurting yourself, or being able to sit without back pain, looking at screens without giving yourself headaches, etc&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;6.0869565217391&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ArvidGerstmann/status/1087462222551490560&quot;&gt;@ArvidGerstmann&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Don’t overdo it. Enjoy your god damn life while you can. Signed, a 24 year old who feels like 44.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;7.5984555984556&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ma_lindstedt/status/1087683256835809281&quot;&gt;@ma_lindstedt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Working 100 hour weeks does not mean you are dedicated&lt;br/&gt;Take care of your body, speak with managers and be frank&lt;br/&gt;Enjoy your spare time so you can deliver your best work every time&lt;br/&gt;Hobbies + friends are not mutually exclusive with good work ethics&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;programming-other-interesting-replies&quot;&gt;Programming, other interesting replies&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The categories above were common themes, but there are some that don’t fit into a generalized category but are worth mentioning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;30 replies mention testing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;4.6783625730994&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/brianokken/status/1088177245431115776&quot;&gt;@brianokken&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Learn to ask early these questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;How do I know it’s working?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do I automate that?&lt;br/&gt;Learning to rely on automated tests ASAP will save them loads of time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;18 replies talk about some kind of version control&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;5.1176470588235&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/UndefinedBehav/status/1087441412747128832&quot;&gt;@UndefinedBehav&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Use a version control system&lt;br/&gt;I would have love it if someone would have told me before&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;14 replies mention debugging&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;5.6666666666667&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/AliBeeGfx/status/1087826867363741696&quot;&gt;@AliBeeGfx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Coding is often like the opposite of the uncertainty principle&lt;br/&gt;the only way to have any certainty something is &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; happening is to observe very closely via debugging!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;grateful&quot;&gt;Grateful&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A thread like this comes once in a blue moon. That so many individuals took their time to reply is beyond comprehension.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thank you to all who replied, re-tweeted and liked.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope the thread inspired you and I hope this blog post helped as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;4.1538461538462&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ericniebler/status/1087447876286869504&quot;&gt;@ericniebler&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Stay humble, stay curious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 19:40:05 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ingve</dc:creator>
<og:title>Advice to new Programmers</og:title>
<og:description>It’s not every day where students new to programming get to ask 709 software developers for advice. Overview There is a school here in Malmö, Sweden called The Game Assembly. This school focuses on teaching students game production. Everything from programming to art and design. This is a three year...</og:description>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>https://olafurw.github.io/2019-01-27-programmer-advice/</og:url>
<og:image>https://olafurw.github.io/img/avatar-icon.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://olafurw.com/2019-01-27-programmer-advice/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>AresDB: Uber’s GPU-Powered Open-Source, Real-Time Analytics Engine</title>
<link>https://eng.uber.com/aresdb/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://eng.uber.com/aresdb/</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;td-post-featured-image&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Featured-1.png&quot; data-caption=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;696&quot; height=&quot;298&quot; class=&quot;entry-thumb td-modal-image&quot; src=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Featured-1-696x298.png&quot; srcset=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Featured-1-696x298.png 696w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Featured-1-300x128.png 300w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Featured-1-768x329.png 768w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Featured-1-1024x438.png 1024w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Featured-1-1068x457.png 1068w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Featured-1-981x420.png 981w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Featured-1.png 1500w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 696px) 100vw, 696px&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Featured&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;At Uber, real-time analytics allow us to attain business insights and operational efficiency, enabling us to make data-driven decisions to improve experiences on the Uber platform. For example, our operations team relies on data to monitor the market health and spot potential issues on our platform; software powered by machine learning models leverages data to predict rider supply and driver demand; and data scientists use data to improve machine learning models for better forecasting.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;In the past, we have utilized many third-party database solutions for real-time analytics, but none were able to simultaneously address all of our functional, scalability, performance, cost, and operational requirements.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Released in November 2018, AresDB is an open source, real-time analytics engine that leverages an unconventional power source, graphics processing units (GPUs), to enable our analytics to grow at scale. An emerging tool for real-time analytics, GPU technology has advanced significantly over the years, making it a perfect fit for real-time computation and data processing in parallel.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;In the following sections, we describe the design of AresDB and how this powerful solution for real-time analytics has allowed us to more performatively and efficiently unify, simplify, and improve Uber’s real-time analytics database solutions. After reading this article, we hope you try out AresDB for your own projects and find the tool useful your own analytics needs, too!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Real-time analytics applications at Uber&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Data analytics are crucial to the success of Uber’s business. Among other functions, these analytics are used to:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Build&lt;/span&gt; &lt;strong&gt;dashboards&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;span&gt;to monitor our business metrics&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Make&lt;/span&gt; &lt;strong&gt;automated decisions&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;span&gt;(such as&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.uber.com/drive/partner-app/how-surge-works/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;trip pricing&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/advanced-technologies-detecting-preventing-fraud-uber/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;fraud detection&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;) based on aggregated metrics that we collect&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Make&lt;/span&gt; &lt;strong&gt;ad hoc queries&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;span&gt;to diagnose and troubleshoot business operations issues&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;We can summarize these functions into categories with different requirements as follows:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dashboards&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Decision Systems&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ad hoc Queries&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;Query Pattern&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;Well known&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;Well known&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;Arbitrary&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;Query QPS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;High&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;High&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;Low&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;Query Latency&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;Low&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;Low&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;High&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;Dataset&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;Subset&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;Subset&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;All data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Dashboards and decision systems leverage real-time analytical systems to make similar queries over relatively small, yet highly valuable, subsets of data (with maximum data freshness) at high QPS and low latency.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The need for another analytical engine&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The most common problem that real-time analytics solves at Uber is how to compute time series aggregates, calculations that give us insight into the user experience so we can improve our services accordingly. With these computations, we can request metrics by specific dimensions (such as day, hour, city ID, and trip status) over a time range on arbitrarily filtered (or sometimes joined) data. Over the years, Uber has deployed multiple solutions to solve this problem in different ways.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Some of the third-party solutions we’ve used for solving this type of problem include:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/apache/incubator-pinot&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apache Pinot&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, an open source distributed analytical database written in Java, can be leveraged for large-scale data analytics. Pinot employs a lambda architecture internally to query batch and real-time data in columnar storage, uses inverted bitmap index for filtering, and relies on star-tree for aggregate result caching. However, it does not support key-based deduplication, upsert, joins, and advanced query features such as geo-spatial-filtering. In addition, being a JVM-based database, query execution on Pinot runs at a higher cost in terms of memory usage.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.elastic.co/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Elasticsearch&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;is used at Uber for a variety of streaming analytics needs. It was built on Apache&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://lucene.apache.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Lucene&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;for full-text keyword search that stores documents and inverted index. It has been widely adopted and extended to also support aggregates. The inverted index enables filtering, yet it is not optimized for time range-based storage and filtering. It stores records as JSON documents, imposing additional storage and query access overhead. Like Pinot, Elasticsearch is a JVM-based database, and as such, does not support joins and its query execution runs at a higher memory cost.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;While these technologies have strengths of their own, they lacked crucial functionalities for our use case. We needed a unified, simplified, and optimized solution, and thought outside-of-the-box (or rather, inside the GPU) to reach a solution.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Leveraging GPUs for real-time analytics&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;To render realistic views of images at a high frame rate, GPUs process a massive amount of geometries and pixels in parallel at high speed. While the clock-rate increase for processing units has plateaued over the past few years, the number of transistors on a chip has only increased per&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Moore%27s_law&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Moore’s law&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;. As a result, GPU computation speeds, measured in Gigaflops per second (GFLOP/s), are rapidly increasing. Figure 1, below, depicts the theoretical GFLOP/s trend comparing NVIDIA GPUs and Intel CPUs over the years:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image11-2.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-5345&quot; src=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image11-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;314&quot; srcset=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image11-2.png 1999w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image11-2-300x157.png 300w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image11-2-768x402.png 768w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image11-2-1024x536.png 1024w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image11-2-696x365.png 696w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image11-2-1068x559.png 1068w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image11-2-802x420.png 802w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Figure 1: Comparison of CPU and GPU single precision floating point performance through the years. Image taken from Nvidia’s CUDA C programming guide.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;When designing our real-time analytics querying engine, integrating GPU processing was a natural fit. At Uber, the typical real-time analytical query processes a few days of data with millions to billions of records and then filters and aggregates them in a short amount of time. This computation task fits perfectly into the parallel processing model of general purpose GPUs because they:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Process data in parallel very quickly.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Deliver greater computation throughput (GFLOPS/s), making them a good fit for heavy computation tasks (per unit data) that can be parallelized.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Offer greater compute-to-storage (ALU to GPU global memory) data access throughput (not latency) compared to central processing units (CPUs), making them ideal for processing I/O (memory)-bound parallel tasks that require a massive amount of data.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Once we settled on using a GPU-based analytical database, we assessed a few existing analytics solutions that leveraged GPUs for our needs:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kinetica.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kinetica&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, a GPU-based analytics engine, was initially marketed towards U.S. military and intelligence applications in 2009. While it demonstrates the great potential of GPU technology in analytics, we found many key features missing&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;for our use case, including&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;schema alteration, partial insertion or updates, data compression, column-level memory/disk retention configuration, and join by geospatial relationships.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.omnisci.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OmniSci&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, an open source, SQL-based query engine, seemed like a promising option, but as we evaluated the product, we realized that it did not have critical&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;features for Uber’s use case, such as deduplication. While&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;OminiSci&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;open sourced their project in 2017, after some analysis of their C++-based solution, we concluded that neither contributing back nor forking their codebase was viable.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;GPU-based real-time analytics engines, including&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cse.ust.hk/gpuqp/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;GPUQP&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://cogadb.dfki.de/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;CoGaDB&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vldb.org/pvldb/vol6/p817-yuan.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;GPUDB&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vldb.org/pvldb/vol6/p709-heimel.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Ocelot&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vldb.org/pvldb/vol6/p1374-he.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;OmniDB&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, and&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bakks/virginian&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Virginian&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, are frequently used by academic institutions. However, given their academic purpose, these solutions focus on developing algorithms and designing proof of concepts as opposed to handling real-world production scenarios. For this reason, we discounted them for our scope and scale.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Overall,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;these engines&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;demonstrate the great advantage and potential of data processing using GPU technology, and they inspired us to build our own GPU-based, real-time analytics solution tailored to Uber’s needs. With these concepts in mind, we built and open sourced AresDB.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;AresDB architecture overview&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;At a high level, AresDB stores most of its data in host memory (RAM that is connected to CPUs), handling data ingestion using CPUs and data recovery via disks. At query time, AresDB transfers data from host memory to GPU memory for parallel processing on GPU. As shown in Figure 2, below, AresDB consists of a memory store, a meta datastore, and a disk store:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image20.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-5346&quot; src=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image20.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;340&quot; srcset=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image20.png 1999w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image20-300x170.png 300w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image20-768x435.png 768w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image20-1024x580.png 1024w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image20-696x394.png 696w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image20-1068x605.png 1068w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image20-741x420.png 741w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Figure 2: The AresDB single instance architecture features memory and disk stores, and meta stores.
&lt;h4&gt;Tables&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Unlike most&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;relational database management systems (&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;RDBMSs), there is no database or schema scope in AresDB. All tables belong to the same scope in the same AresDB cluster/instance, enabling users to refer to them directly. Users store their data as fact tables and dimension tables.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Fact table&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;A fact table stores an infinite stream of time series events. Users use a fact table to store events/facts that are happening in real time, and each event is associated with an event time, with the table often queried by the event time. An example of the type of information stored by fact tables are trips, where each trip is an event and the trip request time is often designated as the event time. In case an event has multiple timestamps associated with it, only one timestamp is designated as the time of the event displayed in the fact table.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Dimension table&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;A dimension table stores current properties for entities (including cities, clients, and drivers). For example, users can store city information, such as city name, time zone, and country, in a dimension table. Compared to fact tables, which grow infinitely over time, dimension tables are always bounded by size (e.g., for Uber, the cities table is bounded by the actual number of cities in the world). Dimension tables do not need a special time column.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Data types&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Table below details the current data types supported in AresDB:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;tbody readability=&quot;7.4910277324633&quot;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/uber/aresdb/wiki/Data-Types&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data Types&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Storage (in Bytes)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Details&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;Bool&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;1/8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;Boolean type data, stored as single bit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;Int8, Uint8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Integer number types. User can choose based on cardinality of field and memory cost.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;Int16, Uint16&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;Int32, Uint32&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;SmallEnum&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;Strings are auto translated into enums. SmallEnum can holds string type with cardinality up to 256&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;BigEnum&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;Similar to BigEnum, but holds higher cardinality up to 65532&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;Float32&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;Floating point number. We support Float32 and intend to add Float64 support as needed&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.43243243243243&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;UUID&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;16&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Universally_unique_identifier&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Universally unique identifier&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;GeoPoint&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;Geographic points&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;GeoShape&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;Variable Length&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;Polygon or multi-polygons&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;With AresDB, strings are converted to&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Enumerated_type&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;enumerated types&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;(enums) automatically before they enter the database for better storage and query efficiency. This allows case-sensitive equality checking, but does not support advanced operations such as concatenation, substrings, globs, and regex matching. We intend to add full string support in the future.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;span&gt;Key features&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;AresDB’s architecture supports the following features:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Column-based storage with compression&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;span&gt;for storage efficiency (less memory usage in terms of bytes to store data) and query efficiency (less data transfer from CPU memory to GPU memory during querying)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Real-time upsert with primary key deduplication&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;span&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;high data accuracy and near real-time data freshness within seconds&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GPU powered query processing&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;span&gt;for highly parallelized data processing powered by GPU, rendering low query latency (sub-seconds to seconds)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Columnar storage&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Vector&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;AresDB stores all data in a columnar format. The values of each column are stored as a columnar value vector. Validity/nullness of the values in each column&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;is stored in a separate null vector, with the validity of each value represented by one bit.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;&lt;span&gt;Live store&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;AresDB&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;stores uncompressed and unsorted columnar data (live vectors) in a live store&lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;span&gt;Data records in a live store are partitioned into (live) batches of configured capacity. New batches are created at ingestion, while old batches are purged after records are archived. A primary key index is used to locate the records for deduplication and updates. Figure 3, below, demonstrates how we organize live records and use a primary key value to locate them:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image23.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-5347 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image23.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;577&quot; height=&quot;232&quot; srcset=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image23.png 577w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image23-300x121.png 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 577px) 100vw, 577px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Figure 3: We use a primary key value to locate the batch and position within the batch for each record.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The values of each column within a batch are stored as a columnar vector. Validity/nullness of the values in each value vector is stored as a separate null vector, with the validity of each value represented by one bit. In Figure 4, below, we offer an an example with five values for a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;city_id&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;column:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image3-4-e1548709370771.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-5348&quot; src=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image3-4-e1548709370771.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;440&quot; srcset=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image3-4-e1548709370771.png 1635w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image3-4-e1548709370771-300x220.png 300w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image3-4-e1548709370771-768x563.png 768w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image3-4-e1548709370771-1024x751.png 1024w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image3-4-e1548709370771-80x60.png 80w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image3-4-e1548709370771-696x510.png 696w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image3-4-e1548709370771-1068x783.png 1068w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image3-4-e1548709370771-573x420.png 573w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Figure 4: We store values (actual value) and null vectors (validity) for uncompressed columns in the data table.
&lt;h5&gt;Archive store&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;AresDB also stores mature, sorted, and compressed columnar data (archive vectors) in an archive store via fact tables. Records in archive store are also partitioned into batches. Unlike live batches,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;an&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;archive batch contains records of a particular Universal Time Coordinated (UTC) day. Archive batch uses the number of days since Unix Epoch as its batch ID.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Records are kept sorted according to a user configured column sort order. As depicted in Figure 5, below, we sort by&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;city_id&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;column first, followed by a status column:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image16-1-e1548709469337.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-5349&quot; src=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image16-1-e1548709469337.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;239&quot; srcset=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image16-1-e1548709469337.png 1994w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image16-1-e1548709469337-300x119.png 300w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image16-1-e1548709469337-768x306.png 768w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image16-1-e1548709469337-1024x408.png 1024w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image16-1-e1548709469337-696x277.png 696w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image16-1-e1548709469337-1068x425.png 1068w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image16-1-e1548709469337-1055x420.png 1055w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Figure 5: We sort all rows by&lt;span&gt;&lt;em&gt;city_id&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, followed by status, then compress each column using run-length encoding. Each column will have a count vector after being sorted and compressed.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The goal of configuring the user-configured column sort order is to:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Maximize compression effects by sorting low cardinality columns earlier. Maximized compression increases storage efficiency (less bytes needed for storing data) and query efficiency (less bytes transferred from CPU to GPU memory).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Allow cheap range-based prefiltering for common equi-filters such as&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;city_id=12&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;. Prefiltering enables us to minimize the bytes needed to be transferred from CPU memory to GPU memory, thereby maximizing query efficiency.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;A column is compressed only if it appears in the user-configured sort order. We do not attempt to compress high cardinality columns because the amount of storage saved by compressing high cardinality columns is negligible.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;After sorting, the data for each qualified column is compressed using a variation of run-length encoding. In addition to the value vector and null vector, we introduce the count vector to represent a repetition of the same value.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Real-time ingestion with upsert support&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Clients ingest data through the ingestion HTTP API by posting an upsert batch. The upsert batch is a custom, serialized binary format that minimizes space overhead while still keeping the data randomly accessible.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;When AresDB receives an upsert batch for ingestion, it first writes the upsert batch to redo logs for recovery. After an upsert batch is appended to the end of the redo log, AresDB then identifies and skips late records on fact tables for ingestion into the live store. A record is considered “late” if its event time is older than the archived cut-off event time. For records not considered “late,” AresDB uses the primary key index to locate the batch within live store where they should be applied to. As depicted in Figure 6, below, brand new records (not seen before based on the primary key value) will be applied to the empty space while existing records will be updated directly:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image10-2.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-5350&quot; src=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image10-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;586&quot; height=&quot;308&quot; srcset=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image10-2.png 586w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image10-2-300x158.png 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 586px) 100vw, 586px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Figure 6: During ingestion, after the upsert batch is appended to the redo log, “late” records will be appended to a backfill queue while other records will be applied to the live store.
&lt;h5&gt;Archiving&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;At ingestion time, records are either appended/updated in the live store or appended to a backfill queue waiting to be placed in the archive store.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;We periodically run a scheduled process, referred to as archiving, on live store records to merge the new records (records that have never been archived before) into the archive store. Archiving will only process records in the live store with their event time falling into the range of the old cut-off time (the cut-off time from last archiving process) and new cut-off time (the new cut-off time based on the archive delay setting in the table schema).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The records’ times of event will be used to determine which archive batch the records should be merged into as we batch archived data into daily batches. Archiving does not require primary key value index deduplication during merging since only records between the old cut-off and new cut-off ranges will be archived.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Figure 7, below, depicts the timeline based on the given record’s event time:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image14.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-5351&quot; src=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image14.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;433&quot; srcset=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image14.png 622w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image14-300x217.png 300w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image14-324x235.png 324w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image14-582x420.png 582w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Figure 7: We use event time and cut-off times to determine which records are new (live) and old (with an event time older than the archiving cut-off).
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;In this scenario, the archiving interval is the time between two archiving runs, while the archiving delay is the duration after the event time but before an event can be archived. Both are defined in AresDB’s table schema configurations.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Backfill&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;As shown in Figure 7, above, old records (with event time older than the archiving cut-off) for fact tables are appended to the backfill queue and eventually handled by the backfill process. This process is also triggered by the time or size of the backfill queue onces it reaches its threshold. Compared to ingestion by the live store, backfilling is asynchronous and relatively more expensive in terms of CPU and memory resources. Backfill is used in the following scenarios:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Handling occasional very late arrivals&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Manual fixing of historical data from upstream&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Populating historical data for recently added columns&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Unlike archiving, backfilling is idempotent and requires primary key value-based deduplication.  The data being backfilled will eventually be visible to queries.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The backfill queue is maintained in memory with a pre-configured size, and, during massive backfill loads, the client will be blocked from proceeding before the queue is cleared by a backfill run.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Query processing&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;With the current implementation, the user will need to use&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/uber/aresdb/wiki/Ares-Query-Language&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Ares Query Language&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;(AQL), created by Uber to run queries against AresDB. AQL is an effective time series analytical query language and does not follow the standard SQL syntax of SELECT FROM WHERE GROUP BY like other SQL-like languages. Instead, AQL is specified in structured fields and can be carried with JSON, YAML, and Go objects. For instance, instead of&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;SELECT count(*) FROM trips GROUP BY city_id WHERE status =&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;‘completed’&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;AND &lt;span&gt;request_at &amp;gt;= 1512000000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;the equivalent AQL in JSON is written as:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt; “table”: “trips”,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt; “dimensions”: [&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;   {“sqlExpression”: “city_id”}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt; ],&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt; “measures”: [&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;   {“sqlExpression”: “count(*)”}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt; ],&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;;”&amp;gt; &lt;span&gt; “rowFilters”: [&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;   “status = ‘completed'”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt; ],&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt; “timeFilter”: {&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;   “column”: “request_at”,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;   “from”: “2 days ago”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt; }&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;In JSON-format, AQL provides better programmatic query experience than SQL for dashboard and decision system developers, because it allows them to easily compose and manipulate queries using code without worrying about issues like SQL injection. It serves as the universal query format on typical architectures from web browsers, front-end servers, and back-end servers, all the way back into the database (AresDB). In addition, AQL provides handy&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Syntactic_sugar&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;syntactic sugar&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;for time filtering and bucketization, with native time zone support. The language also supports features like&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;implicit sub-queries&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;to avoid common query mistakes and makes query analysis and rewriting easy for back-end developers.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Despite the various benefits AQL provides, we are fully aware that most engineers are more familiar with SQL. Exposing a SQL interface for querying is one of the next steps that we will look into to enhance the AresDB user experience.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;We depict the AQL query execution flow in Figure 8, below:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image19.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-5352&quot; src=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image19.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;267&quot; srcset=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image19.png 624w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image19-300x134.png 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Figure 8: AresDB’s query execution flow leverages our homegrown AQL query language for fast, efficient data processing and retrieval.
&lt;h5&gt;Query compilation&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;An AQL query is compiled into&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;internal query context&lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;span&gt;Expressions in filters, dimensions, and measurements are parsed into abstract syntax trees (AST) for later processing via GPU.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Data feeding&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;AresDB&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;utilizes pre-filters&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;to cheaply filter archived data before sending them to a GPU for parallel processing. Since archived data is sorted according to a configured column order, some filters may be able to utilize this sorted order by applying binary search to locate the corresponding matching range. In particular, equi-filters on all of the first X-sorted columns and optionally range filter on sorted X+1 columns can be processed as pre-filters, as depicted in Figure 9, below:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image13-2.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-5353&quot; src=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image13-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;566&quot; height=&quot;413&quot; srcset=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image13-2.png 566w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image13-2-300x219.png 300w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image13-2-324x235.png 324w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 566px) 100vw, 566px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Figure 9: AresDB pre-filters columnar data before sending it to the GPU for processing.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;After prefiltering, only the green values (satisfying filter condition) need to be pushed to the GPU for parallel processing.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;Input data is fed to the GPU and executed there one batch at a time. This includes both live batches and archive batches.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;AresDB utilizes&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://devblogs.nvidia.com/gpu-pro-tip-cuda-7-streams-simplify-concurrency/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;CUDA streams&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;for pipelined data feeding and execution. Two streams are used alternately on each query for processing in two overlapping stages. In Figure 10, below, we offer a timeline illustration of this process:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image8-2.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-5354&quot; src=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image8-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;128&quot; srcset=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image8-2.png 622w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image8-2-300x64.png 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Figure 10: With AresDB, two CUDA streams alternate on data transfer and processing.
&lt;h5&gt;Query execution&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;For simplicity, AresDB utilizes the&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.nvidia.com/thrust&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Thrust library&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;to implement query execution procedures, which offers fine-tuned parallel algorithm building blocks for quick implementation in the current query engine.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;In Thrust, input and output vector data is accessed using random access iterators. Each GPU thread seeks the input iterators to its workload position, reads the values and performs the computation, and then writes the result to the corresponding position on the output iterator.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;AresDB follows the one-operator-per-kernel (OOPK) model for evaluating expressions.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Figure 11, below, demonstrates this procedure on an example AST, generated from a dimension expression&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;request_at – request_at % 8640&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;in the query compilation stage:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image7-1.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-5355 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image7-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;368&quot; height=&quot;333&quot; srcset=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image7-1.png 368w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image7-1-300x271.png 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 368px) 100vw, 368px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Figure 11: AresDB leverages the OOPK model model for expression evaluation.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;In the OOPK model, the AresDB query engine traverses each leaf node of the AST tree and returns an iterator for its parent node. In cases where the root node is also a leaf, the root action is taken directly on the input iterator.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;At each non-root non-leaf node (&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Modulo_operation&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;modulo operation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;in this example), a temporary scratch space vector is allocated to store the intermediate result produced from&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;request_at % 86400&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;expression. Leveraging Thrust, a kernel function is launched to compute the output for this operator on GPU. The results are stored in the scratch space iterator.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;At the root node, a kernel function is launched in the same manner as a non-root, non-leaf node. Different output actions are taken based on the expression type, detailed below:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Filter action to reduce the cardinality of input vectors&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Write dimension output to the dimension vector for later aggregation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Write measure output to the measure vector for later aggregation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;After expression evaluation,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://thrust.github.io/doc/group__sorting.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;sorting&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://thrust.github.io/doc/group__reductions.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;reduction&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;are executed to conduct final aggregation. In both sorting and reduction operations, we use the values of the dimension vector as the key values of sorting and reduction, and the values of the measure vector as the values to aggregate on. In this way, rows with same dimension values will be grouped together and aggregated. Figure 12, below, depicts this sorting and reduction process:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image22.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-5356&quot; src=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image22.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;233&quot; srcset=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image22.png 624w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image22-300x116.png 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Figure 12: After expression evaluation, AresDB sorts and reduces data by key value on the dimension (key value) and measure (value) vectors.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;AresDB also supports the following advanced query features:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Resource management&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;As an in-memory-based database, AresDB needs to manage the following types of memory usage:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;tbody readability=&quot;8.5&quot;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Allocation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Management Mode&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;Live Store Vectors (live store columnar data)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;C&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;Tracked&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;Archive Store Vectors (archive store columnar data)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;C&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;Managed (Load and eviction)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;Primary Key Index (hash table for record deduplication)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;C&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;Tracked&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;Backfill Queue (store “late” arrival data waiting for backfill)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;Golang&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;Tracked&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;Archive / Backfill Process Temporary Storage (Temporary memory allocated during the Archive and Backfill process)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;C&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;Tracked&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;&lt;td readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Ingestion / Query Temporary Storage;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Process Overheads;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Allocation fragmentations&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;Golang and C&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;Statically Configured Estimate&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;When AresDB goes into production, it leverages a configured total memory budget. This budget is shared by all six memory types and should also leave enough room for the operating system and other processes. This budget also covers a statically configured overhead estimation, live data storage monitored by the server, and archived data that the server can decide to load and evict depending on the remaining memory budget.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Figure 13, below, depicts the AresDB host memory model:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image12-2.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-5357&quot; src=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image12-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;273&quot; srcset=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image12-2.png 617w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image12-2-300x137.png 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Figure 13: AresDB manages its own memory usage so that it does not exceed the configured total process budget.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;AresDB allows users to configure pre-loading days and priority at the column level for fact tables, and only pre-loads archive data within pre-loading days. Non-preloaded data is loaded into memory from disk on demand. Once full, AresDB also evicts archived data from the host memory. AresDB’s eviction policies are based on the number of preloading days, column priorities, the day of the batch, and the column size.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;AresDB also manages multiple GPU devices and models device resources as GPU threads and device memory, tracking GPU memory usage as processing queries. AresDB manages GPU devices through device manager, which models GPU device resources in two dimensions–GPU threads and device memory–and tracks the usage while processing queries. After query compilation, AresDB enables users to estimate the amount of resources needed to execute the query. Device memory requirements must be satisfied before a query is allowed to start; the query must wait to run if there is not enough memory at that moment on any device. Currently, AresDB can run either one or several queries on the same GPU device simultaneously, so long as the device satisfies all resource requirements.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;In the current implementation, AresDB does not cache input data in device memory for reuse across multiple queries. AresDB targets supporting queries on datasets that are constantly updated in real time and hard to cache correctly. We intend to implement a data caching functionality GPU memory in future iterations of AresDB, a step that will help optimize query performance.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Use Case: Uber’s Summary Dashboard&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;At Uber, we use AresDB to build dashboards for extracting real-time business insights. AresDB plays the role of storing fresh raw events with constant updates and computing crucial metrics  against them in sub seconds using GPU power with low cost so that users can utilize the dashboards interactively. For example, anonymized trip data, which has a long lifespan in the datastore, is updated by multiple services, including our dispatch, payments, and ratings systems. To utilize trips data effectively, users will slice and dice the data into different dimensions to get insights for real-time decisions.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Leveraging AresDB, Uber’s Summary Dashboard is a widely used analytics dashboard leveraged by teams across the company to retrieve relevant product metrics and respond in real time to improve user experience.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image18.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-5358&quot; src=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image18.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;293&quot; srcset=&quot;https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image18.png 624w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image18-300x147.png 300w, https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/image18-533x261.png 533w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Figure 14: The Uber Summary Dashboard’s hourly view uses AresDB to view real-time data analytics during specific time periods.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;To build the mock-up dashboard, above, we modeled the following tables:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trips (fact table)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;trip_id&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;request_at&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;city_id&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;status&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;driver_id&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;fare&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;1542058870&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;completed&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;8.5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;1541977200&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;rejected&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;10.75&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;…&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cities (dimension table)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;city_id&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;city_name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;timezone&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;San Francisco&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;America/Los_Angeles&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;New York&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;America/New_York&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;…&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Table schemas in AresDB&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;To create the two modeled tables described above, we will first need to create the tables in AresDB in the following schemas:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;tbody readability=&quot;22.5&quot;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trips&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cities&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;45&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt; “name”: “trips”,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt; “columns”: [&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;   {&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;     “name”: “request_at”,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;     “type”: “Uint32”,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;   },&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;   {&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;     “name”: “trip_id”,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;     “type”: “UUID”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;   },&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;   {&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;     “name”: “city_id”,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;     “type”: “Uint16”,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;   },&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;   {&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;     “name”: “status”,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;     “type”: “SmallEnum”,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;   },&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;   {&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;     “name”: “driver_id”,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;     “type”: “UUID”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;   },&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;   {&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;     “name”: “fare”,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;     “type”: “Float32”,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;   }&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt; ],&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt; “primaryKeyColumns”: [&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;   1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt; ],&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt; “isFactTable”: true,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt; “config”: {&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;   “batchSize”: 2097152,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;   “archivingDelayMinutes”: 1440,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;   “archivingIntervalMinutes”: 180,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;  “recordRetentionInDays”: 30&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt; },&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt; “archivingSortColumns”: [2,3]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt; “name”: “cities”,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt; “columns”: [&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt; {&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;     “name”: “city_id”,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;    “type”: “Uint16”,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;   },&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;   {&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;     “name”: “city_name”,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;     “type”: “SmallEnum”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;   },&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;   {&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;     “name”: “timezone”,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;     “type”: “SmallEnum”,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;   }&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt; ],&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt; “primaryKeyColumns”: [&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;   0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt; ],&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt; “isFactTable”: false,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt; “config”: {&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;   “batchSize”: 2097152&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt; }&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;As described in schema, trips tables are created as fact tables, representing trips events that are happening in real time, while cities tables are created as dimension tables, storing information about actual cities.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;After tables are created, users may leverage the&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/uber/aresdb/blob/master/client/connector.go#L48&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;AresDB client library&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;to ingest data from an event bus such as Apache&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://kafka.apache.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Kafka&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, or streaming or batch processing platforms such as Apache&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://flink.apache.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Flink&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;or Apache&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://spark.apache.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Spark&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sample queries against AresDB&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;In the mock-up dashboards, we choose two metrics as examples, total trip fare and active drivers. In the dashboard, users can filter the city for the metrics, eg. San Francisco. To draw the time series for these two metrics for the last 24 hours shown in the dashboards, we can run the following queries in AQL:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;tbody readability=&quot;18&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total trips fare in San Francisco in the last 24 hours group by hours&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Active drivers in San Francisco in the last 24 hours group by hours&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt; “table”: “trips”,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt; “joins”: [&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;   {&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;     “alias”: “cities”,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;     “name”: “cities”,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;     “conditions”: [&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;       “cities.id = trips.city_id”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;     ]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;   }&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt; ],&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt; “dimensions”: [&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;   {&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;     “sqlExpression”: “request_at”,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;     “timeBucketizer”: “hour”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;   }&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt; ],&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt; “measures”: [&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;   {&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;     “sqlExpression”: “sum(fare)”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;   }&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt; ],&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt; “rowFilters”: [&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;   “status = ‘completed'”,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;   “cities.city_name = ‘San Francisco'”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt; ],&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt; “timeFilter”: {&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;   “column”: “request_at”,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;   “from”: “24 hours ago”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt; },&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt; “timezone”: “America/Los_Angeles”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt; “table”: “trips”,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt; “joins”: [&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;   {&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;     “alias”: “cities”,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;     “name”: “cities”,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;     “conditions”: [&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;       “cities.id = trips.city_id”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;     ]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;   }&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt; ],&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt; “dimensions”: [&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;   {&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;     “sqlExpression”: “request_at”,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;     “timeBucketizer”: “hour”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;   }&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt; ],&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt; “measures”: [&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;   {&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;     “sqlExpression”: “countDistinctHLL(driver_id)”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;   }&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt; ],&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt; “rowFilters”: [&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;   “status = ‘completed'”,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;   “cities.city_name = ‘San Francisco'”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt; ],&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt; “timeFilter”: {&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;   “column”: “request_at”,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;   “from”: “24 hours ago”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt; },&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt; “timezone”: “America/Los_Angeles”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sample results from the query:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The above mock-up queries will produce results in the following time series result, which can be easily drawn into time-series graphs, as shown below:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;tbody readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total trips fare in San Francisco in the last 24 hours group by hours&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Active drivers in San Francisco in the last 24 hours group by hours&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;18&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt; “results”: [&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;   {&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;     “1547060400”: 1000.0,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;     “1547064000”: 1000.0,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;     “1547067600”: 1000.0,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;     “1547071200”: 1000.0,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;     “1547074800”: 1000.0,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;     …&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;   }&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt; ]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt; “results”: [&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;   {&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;     “1547060400”: 100,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;     “1547064000”: 100,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;     “1547067600”: 100,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;     “1547071200”: 100,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;     “1547074800”: 100,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;    …  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;   }&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt; ]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;In the above example, we demonstrated how to leverage AresDB to ingest raw events happening in real-time within seconds and issue arbitrary user queries against the data right away to compute metrics in sub seconds. AresDB helps engineers to easily build data products that extract metrics crucial to businesses that requires real-time insights for human or machine decisions.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Next steps&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;AresDB is widely used at Uber to power our real-time data analytics dashboards, enabling us to make data-driven decisions at scale about myriad aspects of our business. By open sourcing this tool, we hope others in the community can leverage AresDB for their own analytics.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;In the future, we intend to enhance the project with the following features:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Distributed design: &lt;span&gt;We are working on building out the distributed design of AresDB, including replication, sharding management, and schema management to improve its scalability and reduce operational costs.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Developer support and tooling:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;span&gt;Since open sourcing AresDB in November 2018, we have been working on building more intuitive tooling, refactoring code structures, and enriching documentation to improve the onboarding experience, enabling developers to quickly integrate AresDB to their analytics stack.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Expanding feature set:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;span&gt;We also plan to expand our query feature set to include functionality such as window functions and nested loop joins, thereby allowing the tool to support more use cases.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Query engine optimization&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;: We will also be looking into developing more advanced ways to optimize query performance, such as&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://llvm.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Low Level Virtual Machine (LLVM)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;and GPU memory caching.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;AresDB is&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/uber/aresdb&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;open sourced&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;under the Apache License. We encourage you to try out AresDB and join our community.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;If building large-scale, real-time data analytics technologies interests you, consider applying for a role on our team.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Acknowledgements&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Special thanks to Kate Zhang, Jennifer Anderson, Nikhil Joshi, Abhi Khune, Shengyue Ji, Chinmay Soman, Xiang Fu, David Chen, and Li Ning for making this project a fabulous success!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 18:49:07 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>manojlds</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://eng.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Featured-1.png</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Introducing AresDB: Uber’s GPU-Powered Open Source, Real-time Analytics Engine</og:title>
<og:description>AresDB, Uber's open source real-time analytics engine, leverages GPUs to enable real-time computation and data processing in parallel.</og:description>
<og:url>https://eng.uber.com/aresdb/</og:url>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://eng.uber.com/aresdb/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>