<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Magnus Carlsen Beats Fabiano Caruana to Win World Chess Championship</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/11/28/sports/magnus-carlsen-fabiano-caruana-world-chess-championship.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2018/11/28/sports/magnus-carlsen-fabiano-caruana-world-chess-championship.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;css-u5vfum StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;After three weeks, 12 straight draws and a day of tiebreakers, Norway’s Magnus Carlsen finally retained the world chess championship in London on Wednesday with a victory against Fabiano Caruana, his American challenger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Carlsen’s victory came in what amounted to sudden-death chess: a scheduled series of four so-called rapid games in which the players started with 25 minutes to make their moves. The speedier pace of the games, after the far more deliberate matchups of the previous three weeks, meant players were more likely to make blunders. And that increased the chance of a victory by one player.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Carlsen won the first two games, then closed out Caruana in Game 3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“Everything kind of went perfectly,” Carlsen said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;In Game 1, Carlsen, playing white, quickly seized control of the center and, after a flurry of exchanges, wound up with a pawn advantage. For the first time in the match, he was able to turn the edge into a win; Caruana resigned after 55 moves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-1m2ozyi&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;css-u5vfum StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Caruana got the white pieces for Game 2 and seized an early advantage of his own. But he seemed to press his advantage a little too hard, commentators said, and Carlsen turned the tables on him for win No. 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;That left Caruana needing two straight wins to extend the championship to the next round of even speedier matches. But Carlsen needed only a single draw, and when he got his third win — in the face of an increasingly aggressive series of moves by Caruana — the title was his.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Caruana, 26, was bidding to become the first American champion since Bobby Fischer beat Boris Spassky to win the world title in 1972. The famously cantankerous Fischer forfeited his title in 1975 amid a dispute with the world chess federation, and the sport has been dominated by Russians and Eastern Europeans in the decades since then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The tiebreaker result was not a shock. While Carlsen, 27, and Caruana, 26, are closely matched in longer conventional chess games, known as classical chess, Carlsen had been considered the favorite in the tiebreaker because he has had better rapid chess results than Caruana.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The tiebreaker was a decisive end to a match that promised excitement when it began Nov. 9 but instead fizzled amid an interminable run of draws. Carlsen and Caruana are the two best players in the world, and an eager crowd watched them play from behind one-way glass in London. Millions of others, including &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/11/21/sports/world-chess-magnus-carlsen.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;a surprisingly large portion of Carlsen’s native Norway&lt;/a&gt;, followed the moves and the commentary about them on television and over the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-1m2ozyi&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-u5vfum StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The first 12 games of the championship, played at conventional length, all ended in draws. Some of the games lasted as long as seven hours, while others were relatively quick. In a few of the games, one player or the other seemed to gain a small advantage, only to fail to capitalize on it and close out a win.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-1m2ozyi&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-wrapper&quot; class=&quot;css-79elbk ehw59r11&quot;&gt;

&lt;div data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-children&quot; class=&quot;css-1a48zt4 ehw59r111&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1xdhyk6 e1vv25i80&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1afaoz0&quot;&gt;Image&lt;/span&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;css-1m50asq&quot; src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/11/28/sports/28chessWEB2/merlin_147428592_d73be552-146a-4088-be89-b040198acc6b-articleLarge.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;auto=webp&amp;amp;disable=upscale&quot; srcset=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/11/28/sports/28chessWEB2/merlin_147428592_d73be552-146a-4088-be89-b040198acc6b-articleLarge.jpg?quality=90&amp;amp;auto=webp 600w,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/11/28/sports/28chessWEB2/merlin_147428592_d73be552-146a-4088-be89-b040198acc6b-jumbo.jpg?quality=90&amp;amp;auto=webp 1024w,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/11/28/sports/28chessWEB2/merlin_147428592_d73be552-146a-4088-be89-b040198acc6b-superJumbo.jpg?quality=90&amp;amp;auto=webp 2048w&quot; sizes=&quot;((min-width: 600px) and (max-width: 1004px)) 84vw, (min-width: 1005px) 60vw, 100vw&quot; itemprop=&quot;url&quot; itemid=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/11/28/sports/28chessWEB2/merlin_147428592_d73be552-146a-4088-be89-b040198acc6b-articleLarge.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;auto=webp&amp;amp;disable=upscale&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;css-8i9d0s e1olku6u0&quot;&gt;Magnus Carlsen, left, beat Fabiano Caruana in tiebreaking games on Wednesday.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot; class=&quot;css-vuqh7u e18m0s9i0&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1afaoz0&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Dan Kitwood/Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-u5vfum StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;It was the first time in the history of the world championship, which dates to the 1800s, that regulation play ended with every game a draw. A player needs 6½ points from those games to win the title, but the series of draws left the match tied, 6-6, after Monday’s 12th game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Chess fans seemed especially disappointed by Game 12. Carlsen seemed to be ahead on the board and had more time on his clock to ponder his remaining actions, but nonetheless he offered a draw after only 31 moves, a tepid ending to the main part of the match.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The legendary former champion Garry Kasparov suggested the draw offer was a sign that Carlsen was losing his nerve, and on Twitter he proclaimed Caruana the favorite in the tiebreakers. “They’re entitled to their stupid opinions,” Carlsen said with a smile of his critics after his victory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Kasparov did praise Carlsen’s play on Wednesday: “We all play worse as we play faster and faster, but his ratio may be the smallest ever.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-1m2ozyi&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-u5vfum StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Questioned about the parade of draws, Caruana &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2018/nov/27/carlsen-caruana-world-chess-championship-armageddon&quot; title=&quot;Guardian&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;seemed unperturbed&lt;/a&gt;. “We work with the match that we have,” he said. “If the powers that be want to change it, then we’ll work with something else.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-1m2ozyi&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-u5vfum StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Had the four rapid games ended with the players still tied, they would have moved on to a series of blitz chess games, in which players start with only five minutes each.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Carlsen won the world chess title in 2013 at age 22, then successfully defended it in 2014 and 2016. Carlsen’s 2016 match against Sergey Karjakin of Russia also went to tiebreakers, although each player had posted a victory in the 12 conventional games. Carlsen won with two wins and two draws in the four rapid games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Caruana, like Fischer, &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/11/03/sports/bobby-fischer-chess-caruana.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;NYT&quot;&gt;is a Brooklyn-bred grandmaster&lt;/a&gt; and is at the vanguard of an improved group of American players who are challenging the dominance of Russia and others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Caruana moved to Europe at age 12 to find better chess opportunities and returned to the United States three years ago, when he &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2015/03/11/sports/chasing-world-chess-title-us-recruits-from-abroad.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;switched his chess nationality&lt;/a&gt; to the United States from Italy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“I am very disappointed,” Caruana said. “I maybe missed like two big chances,” in the opening 12 games, “and Magnus also had two. I can’t really say I missed more chances than Magnus over all.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Carlsen’s recent success has led to a chess boom in Norway. Carlsen has become one of the country’s most famous people, and viewers attracted to the game by his victories now play it in clubs, bars and even on trams in Oslo. For the past month, many of those players — new and old — have been glued to televisions to watch his matches. Even the draws.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Those fans were rewarded on Wednesday; Caruana stymied him for weeks, but in the end, Carlsen is still the world champion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-1m2ozyi&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 19:13:42 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>tosh</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/11/28/sports/magnus-carlsen-fabiano-caruana-world-chess-championship.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Magnus Carlsen Beats Fabiano Caruana to Win World Chess Championship</og:title>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/11/29/sports/29chess2/29chess2-facebookJumbo.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>After three weeks of draws failed to produce a winner, the players settled the title in rapid chess, with Carlsen retaining his title.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/11/28/sports/magnus-carlsen-fabiano-caruana-world-chess-championship.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Amazon Quantum Ledger Database</title>
<link>https://aws.amazon.com/qldb/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://aws.amazon.com/qldb/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon QLDB is a fully managed ledger database that provides a transparent, immutable, and cryptographically verifiable transaction log ‎owned by a central trusted authority. Amazon QLDB tracks each and every application data change and maintains a complete and verifiable history of changes over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ledgers are typically used to record a history of economic and financial activity in an organization. Many organizations build applications with ledger-like functionality because they want to maintain an accurate history of their applications' data, for example, tracking the history of credits and debits in banking transactions, verifying the data lineage of an insurance claim, or tracing movement of an item in a supply chain network. Ledger applications are often implemented using custom audit tables or audit trails created in relational databases. However, building audit functionality with relational databases is time-consuming and prone to human error. It requires custom development, and since relational databases are not inherently immutable, any unintended changes to the data are hard to track and verify. Alternatively, blockchain frameworks, such as Hyperledger Fabric and Ethereum, can also be used as a ledger. However, this adds complexity as you need to set-up an entire blockchain network with multiple nodes, manage its infrastructure, and require the nodes to validate each transaction before it can be added to the ledger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazon QLDB is a new class of database that eliminates the need to engage in the complex development effort of building your own ledger-like applications. With QLDB, your data’s change history is immutable – it cannot be altered or deleted – and using cryptography, you can easily verify that there have been no unintended modifications to your application’s data. QLDB uses an immutable transactional log, known as a journal, that tracks each application data change and maintains a complete and verifiable history of changes over time. QLDB is easy to use because it provides developers with a familiar SQL-like API, a flexible document data model, and full support for transactions. QLDB is also serverless, so it automatically scales to support the demands of your application. There are no servers to manage and no read or write limits to configure. With QLDB, you only pay for what you use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sign Up for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.awscloud.com/QuantumLedgerDatabase-preview.html&quot;&gt;Amazon QLDB preview&lt;/a&gt; today!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking to build a blockchain application? Learn more about Amazon Managed Blockchain &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/managed-blockchain/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 17:23:17 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mcrute</dc:creator>
<og:title>Amazon QLDB</og:title>
<og:type>company</og:type>
<og:url>https://aws.amazon.com/qldb/</og:url>
<og:image>https://a0.awsstatic.com/libra-css/images/logos/aws_logo_smile_1200x630.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://aws.amazon.com/qldb/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Amazon Timestream – Fast, scalable, fully managed time series database</title>
<link>https://aws.amazon.com/timestream/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://aws.amazon.com/timestream/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon Timestream is a fast, scalable, fully managed time series database service for IoT and operational applications that makes it easy to store and analyze trillions of events per day at 1/10th the cost of relational databases. Driven by the rise of IoT devices, IT systems, and smart industrial machines, time-series data — data that measures how things change over time — is one of the fastest growing data types. Time-series data has specific characteristics such as typically arriving in time order form, data is append-only, and queries are always over a time interval. While relational databases can store this data, they are inefficient at processing this data as they lack optimizations such as storing and retrieving data by time intervals. Timestream is a purpose-built time series database that efficiently stores and processes this data by time intervals. With Timestream, you can easily store and analyze log data for DevOps, sensor data for IoT applications, and industrial telemetry data for equipment maintenance. As your data grows over time, Timestream’s adaptive query processing engine understands its location and format, making your data simpler and faster to analyze. Timestream also automates rollups, retention, tiering, and compression of data, so you can manage your data at the lowest possible cost. Timestream is serverless, so there are no servers to manage. It manages time-consuming tasks such as server provisioning, software patching, setup, configuration, or data retention and tiering, freeing you to focus on building your applications.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 17:16:20 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>irs</dc:creator>
<og:title>Amazon Timestream</og:title>
<og:type>company</og:type>
<og:url>https://aws.amazon.com/timestream/</og:url>
<og:image>https://a0.awsstatic.com/libra-css/images/logos/aws_logo_smile_1200x630.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://aws.amazon.com/timestream/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Building a company is fucking hard</title>
<link>https://nvdk.co/2018/11/28/entrepreneurship/building-a-company-is-fucking-hard/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://nvdk.co/2018/11/28/entrepreneurship/building-a-company-is-fucking-hard/</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;has-content-area&quot; data-url=&quot;https://nvdk.co/2018/11/28/entrepreneurship/building-a-company-is-fucking-hard/&quot; data-title=&quot;Building a company is fucking hard.&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I set out to tell you the story of my life, there isn’t much – and yet, a whole lot! I’ve only been up and around for about 4 years, a happy ignorant high school teenager before that. I have yet experienced more professional hardship in these four years than most people do in all of their lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About 36 months ago, I decided to drop out of college, and pursue a career in business. Looking back at the spontaneity of the entire thing, I am surprised I managed to make it so far, quite literally. The entire thing happened in less than 3 days, after I realised I couldn’t care less about education system we have in India. I did not have a business plan, a company name, domain, partner, funding, idea or a network. I was just a college student, excited about getting on with exploring the world, and making my mark there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because I was already freelancing as a web developer, an IT services business was naturally the easiest direction to head in. I remember this time as around September of the year. By March next year, we were about 15 people, serving about 20 different clients. During that time, and after, when people asked how I managed to make it all work, the only answer I had was quoting Steve Jobs –&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;em&gt;You cannot connect the dots looking forward.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I truly believed in it. I could see no other way of making it happen. No number of courses or money, or any other such factor would have made it the right time to start. And ever since, I have held on to this as the core emotion that drives me. I find goals that excite me, and I dedicate every molecule in my body towards achieving this goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cut a long story short, and skip a year and some, and I leave my company ( after an acquisition ), and move on to building my second. It has been a year and half since I’ve started on this venture, and the new quote that I think aptly describes this phase of my life is from Elon Musk –&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;em&gt;Running a start-up is like chewing glass and staring into the abyss. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you’re building a company, you shall always have the usual list of problems the internet accurately lists out for you – but here are some things I did not anticipate, and took significant strength.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;You will need significant emotional strength.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you move through months building your company, you shall come across big and small successes, and a lot of failures. You will come across demotivating meetings, and often instances that make you reconsider your choices and decisions. It is easy to want to give up during this time, or lose faith – in yourself and your business. While most people would tell you to fight it, and remember to stay focused, and &lt;em&gt;hustle, hustle, hustle,&lt;/em&gt; I think it is important to let experience these phases as well. For some time now, if I have a demotivating day, or week – I let these emotions wash over myself, and allow myself a slow relaxed week. I’ve learnt that it is okay to not be at the top of your game 100% of the time, and to be demotivated / sad some of the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like these instances and people you come across who give you the low phases, you’re very likely to come across events that make you feel better too – and I use them as my motivation tickets, driving energy from them to keep going, keep building. You have to remember you’re going to be here for a long time, and you best allow yourself some down time when your mind needs some.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;You will need friends.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Entrepreneurship calls for your time with the business every waking hour you spend out of bed, all of your weekends, and vacations. For the first few years, you can expect to give up on all leisures of life – it might have been different for a lot of people, but the experience has been similar with most colleagues I have. ( Don’t worry – it isn’t very difficult when you love your work. ) With this schedule, it is easy to fall out of touch with your social life, and forget to spend time with your friends and family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are going to want to make serious commitments to paying just as much as attention to your personal life as you do to your work life, because the later shall quickly start to feel like a weight without enough energy from the first. There are going to be some pretty dark times, and you’ll want to have a strong FnF network that you can rely on during these times for help and love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will also want to make friends within the business, and it is always a lot easier to be building a business if you have a partner. Make good, strong relationships with everyone you come across, and not just for the sake of business – but with genuine intentions to start friendship. Your clients, employees, business leads, clients and fellow entrepreneurs can all be friends – life is easier when you have a team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;You will need mentors.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most start ups will die because of mistakes made from the one bucket of common errors – about 90% of them. These include bad financial management, hiring errors, product errors, marketing errors, etc. I believe they can be easily avoided, but can also be easily forgotten about when you’re busy hustling. You will want to find and work with a mentor that you can connect with, someone you can rely on for advice and support for the next few years. Most accelerators will give you a mentor, but it is almost always better to have someone you have a personal relationship with, and someone you look up to and respect. You might come across such a person as you fly through meetings and introductions, keep an eye open and don’t be afraid to ask!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your network of mentors will come in really handy when you’re going through a difficult phase, and you will!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;You will make mistakes.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My post comes at a time where I am in a dark spot myself, and miss these things – these are lessons that I have learnt from my mistakes, and am going to work to fix in the coming weeks. It is important to remember that you will err, and while it is important to forgive yourself, it is equally import to learn, stay focussed, and work towards eliminating the same errors from haltering your stride to success again. Every mistake you make is a lesson, one you couldn’t have learnt otherwise – not in school, and a strength added to your personality. Every time you err and correct yourself, you’re better poised to take your venture to success, and a little more capable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make mistakes – keep them inexpensive, learn from them, and move on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And hey, if you run an e commerce business, check &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.startwithsquare1.com/?_s=yc_naved&amp;amp;_m=yc&amp;amp;_c=yc&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; out. We built this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.10digi.com/&quot;&gt;thing&lt;/a&gt; too. You can write to me &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:naved+leadfromwordpress@sqre1.com&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;! Follow me on &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/navidkhn1&quot;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;robots-nocontent sd-block sd-social sd-social-text sd-sharing&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Share this:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 14:25:52 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>navidkhn1</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Building a company is fucking hard. - Naved's Blog</og:title>
<og:description>If I set out to tell you the story of my life, there isn’t much – and yet, a whole lot! I’ve only been up and around for about 4 years, a happy ignorant high...</og:description>
<og:url>https://nvdk.co/2018/11/28/entrepreneurship/building-a-company-is-fucking-hard/</og:url>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://nvdk.co/2018/11/28/entrepreneurship/building-a-company-is-fucking-hard/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>SubEthaEdit 5 is now free and open source</title>
<link>https://rant.monkeydom.de/posts/2018/11/28/see-is-back</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://rant.monkeydom.de/posts/2018/11/28/see-is-back</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The new version 5 of &lt;a href=&quot;https://subethaedit.net&quot;&gt;SubEthaEdit&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Apple_Design_Awards#2003&quot;&gt;Apple Design Award winning&lt;/a&gt; text editor for macOS, is now available free of charge in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://subethaedit.net/appstore&quot;&gt;App Store&lt;/a&gt; and as &lt;a href=&quot;https://subethaedit.net/SubEthaEdit.zip&quot;&gt;direct download&lt;/a&gt;. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/subethaedit/SubEthaEdit&quot;&gt;complete source code&lt;/a&gt; with history going back 15 years is also available under the MIT License.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This release fills me with great pride and joy. SubEthaEdit always has a special place in my heart. It is where my journey as a developer in the Apple ecosystem started. I owe it the position I am in today. This connection is why I'm taking the time to maintain it again and try to lead it towards a long lasting future. Therefore I think it is worthwhile looking at how everything came together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;History&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It all started with the initial set of peers at our university at the end of 2002: Ulrich Bauer, Martin Ott, &lt;a href=&quot;https://martin.pittenauer.com&quot;&gt;Martin Pittenauer&lt;/a&gt; and me. As university students we wanted to build something real. So we searched for a project to grow into a fully grown app. Motivated by the Apple Design Awards competition, we challenged ourselves with a fitting deadline to do submit an entry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At that point in time there weren't many good native text editors on the platform, so doing a general purpose text editor was always an aspiration of mine. I had recently switched from my old &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/RiscPC&quot;&gt;Acorn RiscPC&lt;/a&gt; over to the Mac, and was really missing my then beloved &lt;a href=&quot;http://stronged.iconbar.com&quot;&gt;StrongEd&lt;/a&gt; (fair warning that website is quite a sight, as sadly most of the RiscOS ecosystem is and almost always was in terms of style).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was playing around with the existing text editors, but &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.barebones.com/products/bbedit/&quot;&gt;BBEdit&lt;/a&gt; really wasn't for me (and at this time very Carbon, and as such looked dated and did not integrate too smoothly into the new OS X). Personally I went with MacroMedia's Dreamweaver as the least bad option for my web development work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily one of us dug up an old &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.researchgate.net/publication/220876978_High-Latency_Low-Bandwidth_Windowing_in_the_Jupiter_Collaboration_System&quot;&gt;Xerox Parc Paper&lt;/a&gt; that showed how latency free live collaboration can be done. At that time it fit perfectly with the newly released &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wikidata.org/wiki/Q892647&quot;&gt;Bonjour&lt;/a&gt; technology to allow for networking without configuration between Macs. That was super exciting and we quickly got to a point where we could see this technology as viable and so we went on to build our application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was with great joy that we submitted our freely available work, then named &lt;strong&gt;Hydra&lt;/strong&gt;, to the awards, and with even more joy that &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Apple_Design_Awards#2003&quot;&gt;we won&lt;/a&gt; in the student category we applied in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Apple_Design_Awards#2003&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://rant.monkeydom.de/assets/posts/ADA2003.svg&quot; width=&quot;300&quot;/&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://rant.monkeydom.de/assets/posts/ADA2003.png&quot; width=&quot;100&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At that time we didn't charge any money for it. Only at the end of our university careers, the three remaining of us started out our luck as &lt;a href=&quot;https://codingmonkeys.de&quot;&gt;TheCodingMonkeys&lt;/a&gt; to live the dream of a Mac indie studio. We all started out doing this part time, the transition from free software to paid shareware did not support more than one person at that time. And while it was fantastic to see SubEthaEdit being used in conferences all over the world, the financial aspects weren't looking great for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marketing wise we shoehorned ourselves into the collaborative aspects, and failed to communicate the fact that SubEthaEdit was a great general purpose text editor of its own right. Worse, the commercial start of SubEthaEdit was overshadowed by the then not yet released &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wikidata.org/wiki/Q2297533&quot;&gt;TextMate&lt;/a&gt;. This was mainly based on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wikidata.org/wiki/Q719413&quot;&gt;David Heinemeier Hansson&lt;/a&gt;'s well deserved hype of the initial &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Gzj723LkRJY&quot;&gt;ruby on rails videos&lt;/a&gt; featuring it. So we lost the race for the second most popular text editor on the platform (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.barebones.com/products/bbedit/&quot;&gt;BBEdit&lt;/a&gt; still got the first place because of Mac users loyalty and steady development), and therefore the commercial success too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was at this point that we began struggling a little. While we had enough success to sustain one person, we were not on track to support more than that. Developing and maintaining SubEthaEdit easily consumed most of our time though. It is by that fact, that we all had still day jobs. And while we dabbled in other product ideas (one of the bigger ones a more creative writing based collaboration tool codenamed 'Fenchurch') we didn't get to produce any.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://rant.monkeydom.de/assets/posts/SEE5-Fenchurch.png&quot; width=&quot;243&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fenchurch prototype mockup.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead we got another lucky break. The great folks at &lt;a href=&quot;https://panic.com&quot;&gt;Panic&lt;/a&gt; were planning their then secret &lt;a href=&quot;https://panic.com/coda&quot;&gt;Coda&lt;/a&gt;, and were looking for something they could base their editing engine on. And that influx of financial support was what enabled us to become a real working company. We are forever grateful to &lt;a href=&quot;https://panic.com&quot;&gt;Panic&lt;/a&gt; for this, as they essentially gave us this opportunity. This was the point in time when Martin Ott, our third co-founder left us, and we started venturing to build &lt;a href=&quot;https://carcassonneapp.com&quot;&gt;Carcassonne&lt;/a&gt; for iOS. Another project of mine that was very close to my heart. I have been a board game geek from my early teens on, and joining this with my professional world was just a fantastic opportunity. It also gave me the opportunity to do real production work with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.erlang.org&quot;&gt;Erlang&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The success of Carcassonne also had a somewhat unfortunate side effect for us: With still no real viable long term business story for SubEthaEdit it moved more and more on the back burner. We still maintained it and brought it up to the App Store eventually, but sadly it couldn't prove its financial viability. A big shout out goes to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ellduin&quot;&gt;Lisa Brodner&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/merrysuperstar&quot;&gt;Michael Ehrmann&lt;/a&gt;, who took the bulk of the work to create the 4.x releases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And while it served us well, even for our own development – SubEthaEdit was our main editor to develop it, in the times of Project Builder with external editor support – it did not plant roots in any specific community. And with Xcode slowly getting better, moving to the single window layout only and providing all the Project aware metadata we couldn't, even our own top use case went away. However, we are still very fond of it and use it for all things scripting and of course text creation and collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fast forwarding to 4 years ago, I left TheCodingMonkeys to try my luck in the US working for UIKit at Apple while Martin Pittenauer took over the company. It was with both surprise and delight that I experienced how SubEthaEdit still resonated with many of my colleagues there. Even with the success of Carcassonne, SubEthaEdit seemed to have been the product that was part of many of their pasts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So now that I'm back to a more independent life I feel that SubEthaEdit deserves a future. Although I'm not rejoining TheCodingMonkeys, we are on good terms and we were able to make an arrangement that hopefully proves beneficial to everyone. From today on SubEthaEdit will be free and open source.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;What was the focus for this release?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Bring the code base into a state that builds fine and fully supports macOS Mojave&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generate a nice repository with as much history as possible, both for reference and educational purposes &lt;em&gt;(Fun fact: SubEthaEdit started out in Subversion, had a long time in Mercurial and very much later moved on to git)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update and or remove dependent libraries, support current Mojave features&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get into shape for dual App Store and Website download releases, so contributions can have a quick turnaround time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove the dependency on the Website for system integration, e.g. the see tool and authorization scripts are now part of the distribution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h4&gt;What are my hopes for the future?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Attract contributors to ensure a long term thriving ecosystem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The free availability both in and out of the App Store should reduce the barrier to entry to the collaborative use cases in education, pair programming, etc, leading to good bug reports and use cases that are worth investing some future development in&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support for more languages, modes and contributions thereof&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Longevity of SubEthaEdit as a product&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;So I hope you all share and enjoy this release, file bug reports, enhancement requests and contribute the scripts, modes and styles you make.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 11:04:18 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>schwuk</dc:creator>
<og:title>rant-dom: SubEthaEdit 5 – Now free and open source!</og:title>
<og:image>https://rant.monkeydom.de/assets/square1024.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://rant.monkeydom.de/posts/2018/11/28/see-is-back</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>I Bootstrapped My Side Project to $6k/Month (2017)</title>
<link>https://blog.usejournal.com/how-i-bootstrapped-a-side-project-to-6k-month-while-secretly-hating-everything-it-stands-for-f7405823de4</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.usejournal.com/how-i-bootstrapped-a-side-project-to-6k-month-while-secretly-hating-everything-it-stands-for-f7405823de4</guid>
<description>&lt;p name=&quot;c27d&quot; id=&quot;c27d&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;Every story that starts with “How I bootstrapped…”, is a happy story. Nobody ever bootstrapped a product to profitability and felt bad about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;da89&quot; id=&quot;da89&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;This is different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;8cc0&quot; id=&quot;8cc0&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;This is the long story of how I built and grew AppyGEN’s revenue to 6k+/month. And why I started hating it while still working full time on it, and how you can avoid going through the same thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;432b&quot; id=&quot;432b&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://appygen.net?utm_source=medium_post&quot; data-href=&quot;https://appygen.net?utm_source=medium_post&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;AppyGEN&lt;/a&gt; is a native Android app builder, designed for internet marketers, or more specifically: non-developers looking to make money online. &lt;br/&gt;It was launched in 2014, and since that time, I’ve done my best to keep it under the radar and basically never talk about it to anyone who was not a potential customer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*IOsOygPowKytANG89SIllQ.png&quot; data-width=&quot;1514&quot; data-height=&quot;471&quot; data-is-featured=&quot;true&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*IOsOygPowKytANG89SIllQ.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*IOsOygPowKytANG89SIllQ.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
October’s Earnings
&lt;h3 name=&quot;76fc&quot; id=&quot;76fc&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--h3-strong&quot;&gt;How it all started&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;2fc7&quot; id=&quot;2fc7&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;I’ve always loved building stuff. I made my first $1000 at 14, selling remote administration tools to wannabe hackers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;45c4&quot; id=&quot;45c4&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;So while pursuing my college degree (in France) and struggling to pay my rent, I started taking remote freelance dev jobs whenever I could. I was making a substantial amount of money for a broke 22 year old, doing what I loved. I even started investing some of it in online poker, heck, I even built a bot to play for me (didn’t work out though).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;cc0c&quot; id=&quot;cc0c&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;After saving enough to pay my debts and some more to sustain my lifestyle, I decided that I could do this for a long time. So I went back to my home country (Morocco) where the cost of living was about 5 times cheaper than France.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;8403&quot; id=&quot;8403&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Fast forward to a few months later, I had amassed enough money to live comfortably for the next two years. But with all my friends working on their 9 to 5 jobs all day, I got bored pretty fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;0a52&quot; id=&quot;0a52&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;So, I decided to start a company (with a friend) and bring the startup mindset to traditional small businesses. I remember thinking : I’ll be the first to do this so I’ll definitely have an edge in the long run. (Spoiler alert : Didn’t work).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;fa2a&quot; id=&quot;fa2a&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;We had the bright idea to sell a CRM to doctors who were still using pen and paper at the time (Nope, not even excel). We sold a few copies, but it quickly became obvious that most of them didn’t need our tool, there was no market for our product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;dc36&quot; id=&quot;dc36&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;After that, we tried making a cool b2c app startup. We had no experience in mobile dev but it was fun learning everything from scratch. A few months later, we had 10.000+ users on our app, but not enough revenue. Ad revenue was too low to keep us afloat and eventually, we ran out of money to pay the office rent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;41c2&quot; id=&quot;41c2&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;With no money and no vision for the future, we were back to square one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*wfCEGUoqaeGjruGR_Cp1OA.jpeg&quot; data-width=&quot;800&quot; data-height=&quot;800&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*wfCEGUoqaeGjruGR_Cp1OA.jpeg&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*wfCEGUoqaeGjruGR_Cp1OA.jpeg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 name=&quot;637f&quot; id=&quot;637f&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;The inception of AppyGEN&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;65ba&quot; id=&quot;65ba&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;One night, in an effort to sharpen his Android dev skills, my partner built a simple app with a list of videos, targeting a specific trending niche.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;afbc&quot; id=&quot;afbc&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;In a matter of days, we were up to thousands of downloads from all around the world. The RPM (Revenue per 1000 impressions) was high, and almost overnight we started making a good amount of money just from the ads in that single app. So we thought, let’s make more of those apps!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;6405&quot; id=&quot;6405&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;There was no need for us to spend months building an original startupy app, we could just make similarly simple apps and make a ton of money!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;b07c&quot; id=&quot;b07c&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;And it worked, a month later we had enough money to pay our rent for the rest of the year. I loved automating stuff, especially if it could make me money and save me time at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;9170&quot; id=&quot;9170&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;So we turned our apps into templates and I made a tool where we could just input the app name, icon and content, click a button, and get a native &amp;amp; profitable app, ready to be published. We used the tool to make dozens of those apps until we ran out of niches to target. Since we had enough money coming in, there was no real motivation to keep doing this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;04f9&quot; id=&quot;04f9&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;As an experiment, we’ve decided to turn our tool into a product and sell it to people looking to make money online, and I knew just the place : The Warrior Forum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;2333&quot; id=&quot;2333&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;We wrote a PDF to teach the process of finding niches to target, monetizing and publishing the apps on the play store. And started selling v1 for a whopping $49 lifetime payment, including updates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;71b5&quot; id=&quot;71b5&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Here’s an old video of one of the early versions :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p name=&quot;e75f&quot; id=&quot;e75f&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;Embarrassing right? Not to the members of the warrior forum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;0516&quot; id=&quot;0516&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;They were so used to overpriced bullshit courses that they couldn’t believe this simple, cheap software was helping them make a consistent and recurring revenue in a matter of days!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;da32&quot; id=&quot;da32&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;They loved it and sales skyrocketed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;743f&quot; id=&quot;743f&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;We’ve updated the tool a few more times and raised the price to $97 per license. I loved reading the reviews and getting emails from our customers saying we’ve changed their lives. I wanted to do this forever, and quickly stopped pursuing the original vision of the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;fdad&quot; id=&quot;fdad&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;On the other hand, my partner who didn’t get to work on AppyGEN or enjoy it as much as I did started losing interest. So I bought his shares, and he went off to do his own thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 name=&quot;8d3b&quot; id=&quot;8d3b&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Where’s my recurring revenue ?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;450f&quot; id=&quot;450f&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;A few months later after me and my partner parted ways, sales started dwindling and I had to take another freelance gig to make some extra money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;b448&quot; id=&quot;b448&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;One day, I was having a conversation with one of AppyGEN’s customers and he shared with me his ad revenue on Skype. This guy had made hundreds of apps in less than two months, and was making 10 times what I was making from the software sales!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;f774&quot; id=&quot;f774&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;I was blown away, and to be honest, I also felt entitled to some of it. And that’s when it dawned on me. Why was I giving away lifetime licenses to a tool that helps you make money every month ?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;deac&quot; id=&quot;deac&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;The answer was simple : I had no real experience in entrepreneurship, pricing, marketing or growth. All I knew how to do was build stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;b2c8&quot; id=&quot;b2c8&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;So I dropped my freelance gig, and embarked on a 6 month journey to learn everything about startups &amp;amp; entrepreneurship. As well as sharpen my web development and sysadmin skills. By the end of the learning phase I had a solid plan :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;postList&quot;&gt;&lt;li name=&quot;4ac9&quot; id=&quot;4ac9&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--p&quot;&gt;To turn the software into a SaaS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;46f2&quot; id=&quot;46f2&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;To have a free plan where users could make and monetize apps in exchange for a cut from their ad revenue.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;ee81&quot; id=&quot;ee81&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;To have a paid plan for users who want to keep 100% of their ad inventory.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*VpYQanwqPDGp4BlTGNcujA.jpeg&quot; data-width=&quot;3264&quot; data-height=&quot;2448&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*VpYQanwqPDGp4BlTGNcujA.jpeg&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*VpYQanwqPDGp4BlTGNcujA.jpeg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Learning time
&lt;p name=&quot;1dde&quot; id=&quot;1dde&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;It wasn’t simple. I had to figure out a way to compile native Android apps on the cloud ( emphasis on native ), and handle the ton of traffic pouring in from the apps, in real time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;2123&quot; id=&quot;2123&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;I also had to keep my promise to the hundreds of early adopters who purchased the lifetime plan when the software didn’t have any server costs, and basically just give them premium features and 100% of their revenue for life ( including the thousands apps guy ).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;e9d7&quot; id=&quot;e9d7&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;I stopped selling the desktop software and spent another six months building the web platform. It was an extremely fulfilling experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 name=&quot;e366&quot; id=&quot;e366&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf-after--p&quot;&gt;SaaS is hard, making money from free users is even harder&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;024b&quot; id=&quot;024b&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;I silently launched a beta to the existing ( lifetime ) customers and they helped me eliminate the bugs I had missed. At that point, I thought it was a done deal. All I had to do was drive some traffic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;afa7&quot; id=&quot;afa7&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Since users could sign up for free, I wouldn’t even have to invest time in converting them to paid users or optimizing the funnel. I’d be sharing their ad revenue and making money wether they upgrade to a paid account or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;a430&quot; id=&quot;a430&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;But still, I wasn’t very confident about my ability to manage tons of API calls from every app made through the software. So I decided to soft launch to a small audience of 200 people who had signed up to the waiting list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;d4b0&quot; id=&quot;d4b0&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;This part was only supposed to take a few weeks. Just enough time for the new users to build and publish some apps and make sure that the platform does not break down under heavy load. It ended up taking months before I could get those users to publish any apps at all. There were so many things I didn’t account for, more specifically :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;postList&quot;&gt;&lt;li name=&quot;38fd&quot; id=&quot;38fd&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Cumbersome Onboarding : Getting someone who had no development or app experience from “I want to make money online” to “I just published my first app on the play store” to “I just made my first dollar” was extremely hard to do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p name=&quot;4cb7&quot; id=&quot;4cb7&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--li&quot;&gt;I had to figure out a way to teach users how to :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;postList&quot;&gt;&lt;li name=&quot;dc6d&quot; id=&quot;dc6d&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Research for profitable niches find or create copyright-free content for their apps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;7ca7&quot; id=&quot;7ca7&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;Create a developer account on the play store ( And convincing them to pay the $25 fee before they made a cent )&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;1cf7&quot; id=&quot;1cf7&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;Publish apps and do ASO.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p name=&quot;6d54&quot; id=&quot;6d54&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--li&quot;&gt;Also, free users lack motivation. I never had that issue with the early adopters, most likely because they paid a price to use the tool. No matter how small that price was, they weren’t going to just drop everything whenever they stumble along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;f9d8&quot; id=&quot;f9d8&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;The new users, not so much. At the slightest whim, like “Create an icon for your app”, or “Pay the $25 google play developer fee”, they’d just close everything and disappear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*GthXGY1DVXRhV0yWeB9nZw.png&quot; data-width=&quot;1024&quot; data-height=&quot;427&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*GthXGY1DVXRhV0yWeB9nZw.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*GthXGY1DVXRhV0yWeB9nZw.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;e13c&quot; id=&quot;e13c&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;So I was back at square one again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;497a&quot; id=&quot;497a&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;After spending almost a year working my ass off, I still had no recurring revenue, new server costs, and a shitload of subtle obstacles I didn’t account for and had no idea how to deal with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 name=&quot;acb2&quot; id=&quot;acb2&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Self-doubt and not changing the world like everyone else&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;e796&quot; id=&quot;e796&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;AppyGEN was taking a toll on my personal life. I had previously disabled all my social networks to focus on it, and more than a year had gone by with nothing to show for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;d329&quot; id=&quot;d329&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Reading the successes of other simpler products made me angry at myself, why did I have to go after such a complicated project ? Couldn’t I have just made a to-do list app ?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;3a31&quot; id=&quot;3a31&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;I also came to the conclusion that AppyGEN didn’t really help make the world a better place like every other startup I read about. It seemed to me like it was just making the play store a worse place, helping non-developers publish hundreds of unoriginal apps that only took away from the visibility and chances of more ambitious apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;e711&quot; id=&quot;e711&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;I was myself an app developer once and I could clearly see how my product ultimately harmed other developers. I started hating everything AppyGEN stands for, no matter how much money it continued to make for my existing customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*7furBdEezxSqdfO8Oid-SQ.jpeg&quot; data-width=&quot;750&quot; data-height=&quot;422&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*7furBdEezxSqdfO8Oid-SQ.jpeg&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*7furBdEezxSqdfO8Oid-SQ.jpeg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;ad43&quot; id=&quot;ad43&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;But what else could I do ? I had already invested so much of my time into it, and I knew for a fact that it could eventually become a profitable business, plus I needed the money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;a399&quot; id=&quot;a399&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;I had learned so much in the process of building the platform, and for that I was grateful. There was still a lot to learn too, and I was confident it would serve me well in my future ventures. So I decided to secretly keep working on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;5909&quot; id=&quot;5909&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Whenever someone would ask me what I’m working on, I’d say I’m freelancing. Whenever I’d get a freelancing offer, I’d turn it down saying I had too much on my plate right now. Gone were the days where I would proudly say that I’m building an awesome SaaS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 name=&quot;b86e&quot; id=&quot;b86e&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Onboarding and motivating free users&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;efa2&quot; id=&quot;efa2&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;I did my best to optimize the onboarding process as much as I could. Which was not enough considering the fact that users still had to do some work in order to be able to generate unique apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;ac1a&quot; id=&quot;ac1a&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;I didn’t want every app made through the software to look the same, and I knew there was no way they would be able to make an income just copying existing or demo apps. They had to invest some time in reading the tutorials, doing research, creating icons and assets, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;532f&quot; id=&quot;532f&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;So I tried a bunch of things like drip campaigns, a concierge service for paid users, a forum, and a bunch of other hacks I had read about in case studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;a0bc&quot; id=&quot;a0bc&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Although these things did help decrease churn a little bit, it wasn’t enough. Only about 5% of new users would get to the point where they got value from the software to invest more of their time in building apps and growing their revenue ( and mine ).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;a73e&quot; id=&quot;a73e&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;You’d think that if you promised someone they’d make a consistent, growing and recurring income, without requiring any upfront investment, they’d be all over it day and night. It wasn’t an onboarding or engagement problem, it was a motivation problem. And it took me some time to figure this out since none of the churned users would answer my emails when I reached out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;b204&quot; id=&quot;b204&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Completely burned out and disenchanted, I decided I’d try one last thing before giving up : &lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;Gamification&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;1e0b&quot; id=&quot;1e0b&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;The idea was to turn the whole thing into a game, where you learn a bunch of stuff about making profitable apps, build your app portfolio, and grow your ad revenue. All at the same time, while having fun and competing with other members.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;8816&quot; id=&quot;8816&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;It felt like the perfect ( and only ) answer to all my problems, so I scrapped about 50% of the existing code and re-wrote it in a way that made gamification an essential and required part of the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;53d8&quot; id=&quot;53d8&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;New users would automatically be assigned a “rank” and two or three “missions” they needed to complete in order to move to the next level, every mission had a step by step tutorial on how to complete it and every time a user gets to a higher level, they’d get rewarded with a new rank and a shiny badge icon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;167b&quot; id=&quot;167b&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Users could see their progress in real time and compete for the top 10 spots on the leaderboard, automatically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;3c67&quot; id=&quot;3c67&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;It worked great and everyone loved it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*3bNsuxShs6WUKqfzf2nPXg.png&quot; data-width=&quot;2818&quot; data-height=&quot;1358&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*3bNsuxShs6WUKqfzf2nPXg.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*3bNsuxShs6WUKqfzf2nPXg.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
The new gamified dashboard
&lt;p name=&quot;c389&quot; id=&quot;c389&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;Dividing the onboarding process in terms of “levels” also helped me figure out ( thanks to mixpanel’s analytics ) that anyone who got to level 3 in the first week, would most likely keep coming back, making more apps, and eventually making his first dollar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;68b3&quot; id=&quot;68b3&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;It was one of those amazing Aha moments that got me into entrepreneurship in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;adf7&quot; id=&quot;adf7&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Before I knew it, the conversion rate from new user to active user ( level 3+ ) skyrocketed from 5% to 45%. I could finally start driving traffic to the site and working on other things like acquisition and retention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 name=&quot;1dcb&quot; id=&quot;1dcb&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Growing slowly, quietly and automatically&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;fd94&quot; id=&quot;fd94&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;Eventually, we reached a 1000+ active users and monthly revenue had reached a consistent $3k+/Month for the past 6 months. 70% of it from sharing the ad revenue of free users, and 30% from paid subscriptions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;febb&quot; id=&quot;febb&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;I couldn’t understand why users who were making a thousand dollars in ad revenue each month, didn’t upgrade their accounts, after all it only costs $25. Turns out, a lot of these users were living in countries where they couldn’t have a Visa card or PayPal account, and just couldn’t pay me even if they wanted to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;29ae&quot; id=&quot;29ae&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;In terms of revenue, this worked out fine for me, I’d probably be making a lot less money without the rev-share plan and I wouldn’t have been able to offer the service for free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;a570&quot; id=&quot;a570&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Remember earlier when I said I hated what AppyGEN stands for ? &lt;br/&gt;The recurring revenue didn’t fix that, I still felt too self conscious about the whole thing, and I would constantly think about it whenever I was working on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;54a0&quot; id=&quot;54a0&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;It’s hard growing a business you hate, no matter how much money it made or could make. But I couldn’t just ignore it and be contented with the current revenue, hoping it will never drop. It happened once, one of my biggest earners had lost his play store account due to policy violations and overnight the revenue dropped to 2K until the same guy decided to get back at it. So I had to keep a continuous flow of new users at all times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;f6d7&quot; id=&quot;f6d7&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;I sucked at seo and paid advertising, press, social and content marketing were out of the question since it would put me and the software in front of all kinds of readers, and I wasn’t ready for that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;5705&quot; id=&quot;5705&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;In retrospect, a bunch of my worries were exclusively in my head, but that’s what you get when you spend so much time keeping your work to yourself, convinced that what you’re doing is bad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;4bdc&quot; id=&quot;4bdc&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Although I still enjoyed adding new features, I still felt bad about sharing it with the world, and acquisition is all about sharing nowadays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;9425&quot; id=&quot;9425&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;So I came up with the idea to get my users to share it, so that I didn’t have to. To do so, I set up a very enticing referral program :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;a58b&quot; id=&quot;a58b&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--p&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users could share their referral link and get a 10% cut of the ad revenue from every app the referred user makes, forever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;b4f6&quot; id=&quot;b4f6&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--blockquote&quot;&gt;For example, if user A brings in user B, and user B makes an app that brings in $10/day, user A would get $1 every day without lifting a finger. &lt;br/&gt;If user B decides to upgrade to a premium account, user A would get a commission every time user B pays his subscription.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;c89c&quot; id=&quot;c89c&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;And it worked! some users even stopped making apps and focused solely on referring new users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;149b&quot; id=&quot;149b&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;A few months later, AppyGEN’s revenue doubled to reach $6k+/Month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 name=&quot;6d0f&quot; id=&quot;6d0f&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Lessons learned&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;28b1&quot; id=&quot;28b1&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;Today, I am actually grateful that AppyGEN is bringing in enough money for me to work on whatever I want. But more importantly, I am so grateful about the hard lessons I learned along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;169c&quot; id=&quot;169c&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Hopefully, you were able to extract some of those lessons through this post. If not, here are the most important rules you should keep in mind for your next project :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;postList&quot;&gt;&lt;li name=&quot;ea4d&quot; id=&quot;ea4d&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Making money should never be your main motivation when working on something new.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;ef90&quot; id=&quot;ef90&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;Never, ever, keep your work to yourself. Share as much as you can, as soon as you can.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;68a5&quot; id=&quot;68a5&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;Build something you’d be proud of 5 years from now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p name=&quot;cfd0&quot; id=&quot;cfd0&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--li&quot;&gt;If you have questions or want to get in touch or want to work with me on something, I’d love to chat. Email me (eothmane.io[at]gmail.com), follow me on Twitter (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/get_eo&quot; data-href=&quot;https://twitter.com/get_eo&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;@get_eo&lt;/a&gt;) &amp;amp; Medium (&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@e_othmane&quot; data-href=&quot;https://medium.com/@e_othmane&quot; data-anchor-type=&quot;2&quot; data-user-id=&quot;2ba9d4a65efd&quot; data-action-value=&quot;2ba9d4a65efd&quot; data-action=&quot;show-user-card&quot; data-action-type=&quot;hover&quot; class=&quot;markup--user markup--p-user&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Othmane E.&lt;/a&gt;), or leave a comment below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;0d49&quot; id=&quot;0d49&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p graf--trailing&quot;&gt;Thank you for reading!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 06:28:33 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>WD-42</dc:creator>
<og:title>How I Bootstrapped My Side Project to $6k/Month While Hating Everything It Stands For</og:title>
<og:url>https://blog.usejournal.com/how-i-bootstrapped-a-side-project-to-6k-month-while-secretly-hating-everything-it-stands-for-f7405823de4</og:url>
<og:image>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*IOsOygPowKytANG89SIllQ.png</og:image>
<og:description>Every story that starts with “How I bootstrapped…”, is a happy story. Nobody ever bootstrapped a product to profitability and felt bad…</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.usejournal.com/how-i-bootstrapped-a-side-project-to-6k-month-while-secretly-hating-everything-it-stands-for-f7405823de4?gi=edaf42aeda84</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>You Only Need 50% of Job “Requirements”</title>
<link>https://talent.works/blog/2018/11/27/the-science-of-the-job-search-part-vii-you-only-need-50-of-job-requirements/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://talent.works/blog/2018/11/27/the-science-of-the-job-search-part-vii-you-only-need-50-of-job-requirements/</guid>
<description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Project Manager needed. Must have 5+ years of experience, be Six Sigma certified, have advanced deep learning knowledge, and be able to perform surgery on occasion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who really has all that? Turns out, basically no one. &lt;strong&gt;You’re as likely to get a job interview m&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;eeting 50% of job requirements as meeting 90% of them.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;6268&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://talent.works/blog/2018/11/27/the-science-of-the-job-search-part-vii-you-only-need-50-of-job-requirements/requirements_required-2/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/talentworks.blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/requirements_required-1.png?fit=1168%2C778&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1168,778&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;requirements_required&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/talentworks.blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/requirements_required-1.png?fit=450%2C300&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/talentworks.blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/requirements_required-1.png?fit=750%2C500&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; class=&quot; size-full wp-image-6268 aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/talentworks.blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/requirements_required-1.png?resize=750%2C500&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; alt=&quot;requirements_required&quot; width=&quot;750&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; srcset=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/talentworks.blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/requirements_required-1.png?w=1168&amp;amp;ssl=1 1168w, https://i0.wp.com/talentworks.blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/requirements_required-1.png?resize=450%2C300&amp;amp;ssl=1 450w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px&quot; data-recalc-dims=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;So requirement is a bit of a flexible word in this context, then…
&lt;p&gt;We were curious about how many job requirements are actually required, so we analyzed job postings and resumes for 6,000+ applications across 118 industries from our database of users. We found that while matching requirements is important, you don’t necessarily need to match all of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Your chances of getting an interview start to go up once you meet about 40% of job requirements.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You’re not any more likely to get an interview matching 90% of job requirements compared to matching just 50%.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For women, these numbers are about 10% &lt;em&gt;lower&lt;/em&gt; i.e. women’s interview chances go up once they meet 30% of job requirements, and matching 40% of job requirements is as good as matching 90% for women.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;You only need 50% of job requirements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You’re just as likely to get an interview matching 50% of requirements as matching 90%.&lt;/strong&gt; We saw a clear upward trend in interview rates based on matching requirements, but with an upper bound. When users applied to jobs where they matched 40 – 50% of job requirements, they were &lt;strong&gt;85&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;% more likely&lt;/strong&gt; to get an interview than when they matched less, and applying to jobs where they matched 50 – 60% of requirements made them an extra &lt;strong&gt;192% more likely&lt;/strong&gt; to get an interview over the 40 – 50% matches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But after that point, you’re in diminishing returns. Applying to jobs where they matched 60% or more of job requirements didn’t provide any additional boost in interview rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Job Search Tip #1: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apply for jobs once you match 50% of job requirements.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;For women, the % of requirements required is lower&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may have seen stories before about how women in particular &lt;a href=&quot;https://hbr.org/2014/08/why-women-dont-apply-for-jobs-unless-theyre-100-qualified&quot;&gt;don’t apply for jobs unless they’re 100% qualified&lt;/a&gt;. We wondered if they were on to something – maybe there’s gender discrimination at play and hiring managers look for women to meet more of the requirements. Turns out, &lt;strong&gt;our findings apply just as much to women as to men&lt;/strong&gt;, and actually, &lt;strong&gt;for women, the chances of getting an interview start increasing as soon as you meet 30% of requirements&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;6264&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://talent.works/blog/2018/11/27/the-science-of-the-job-search-part-vii-you-only-need-50-of-job-requirements/requirements_required_by_gender-2/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/talentworks.blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/requirements_required_by_gender-1.png?fit=1169%2C779&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1169,779&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;requirements_required_by_gender&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/talentworks.blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/requirements_required_by_gender-1.png?fit=450%2C300&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/talentworks.blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/requirements_required_by_gender-1.png?fit=750%2C500&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; class=&quot; size-full wp-image-6264 aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/talentworks.blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/requirements_required_by_gender-1.png?resize=750%2C500&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; alt=&quot;requirements_required_by_gender&quot; width=&quot;750&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; srcset=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/talentworks.blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/requirements_required_by_gender-1.png?w=1169&amp;amp;ssl=1 1169w, https://i0.wp.com/talentworks.blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/requirements_required_by_gender-1.png?resize=450%2C300&amp;amp;ssl=1 450w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px&quot; data-recalc-dims=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;Women get interviews at higher rates with fewer matched requirements – if only they applied to those jobs in the first place.
&lt;p&gt;As you can see in the graph above, we see the same general trend for women as for men, but for women, &lt;strong&gt;you’re as likely to get an interview matching 40% of the job requirements as matching 90%&lt;/strong&gt;. Note also that, &lt;a href=&quot;https://talent.works/blog/2018/01/08/the-science-of-the-job-search-part-i-13-data-backed-ways-to-win/&quot;&gt;as we’ve seen in previous analysis&lt;/a&gt;, women in general have higher interview rates than men.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet, despite this, among our users, we’ve observed the same trend that has been studied elsewhere. Women are more likely to turn down jobs where they match some but not all of the qualifications – over the last 8 weeks, &lt;strong&gt;64&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;% of our female users rejected at least one job where they matched 50 – 60% of the requirements, while only 37% of male users did&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;6267&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://talent.works/blog/2018/11/27/the-science-of-the-job-search-part-vii-you-only-need-50-of-job-requirements/requirements_required_feedback_rates-3/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://i1.wp.com/talentworks.blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/requirements_required_feedback_rates-2.png?fit=1169%2C779&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1169,779&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;requirements_required_feedback_rates&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://i1.wp.com/talentworks.blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/requirements_required_feedback_rates-2.png?fit=450%2C300&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://i1.wp.com/talentworks.blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/requirements_required_feedback_rates-2.png?fit=750%2C500&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; class=&quot; size-full wp-image-6267 aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;https://i1.wp.com/talentworks.blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/requirements_required_feedback_rates-2.png?resize=750%2C500&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; alt=&quot;requirements_required_feedback_rates&quot; width=&quot;750&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; srcset=&quot;https://i1.wp.com/talentworks.blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/requirements_required_feedback_rates-2.png?w=1169&amp;amp;ssl=1 1169w, https://i1.wp.com/talentworks.blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/requirements_required_feedback_rates-2.png?resize=450%2C300&amp;amp;ssl=1 450w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px&quot; data-recalc-dims=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, yes, women, you too should be applying to jobs where you don’t meet all the requirements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Job Search Tip #2: Stop second guessing yourself – you DO deserve that job.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;You’re not guaranteed to get an interview, even when you match 90% of job requirements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Base case scenario, you’re looking at about a 15% chance of getting an interview. &lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pplying for jobs is still fundamentally a numbers game&lt;/strong&gt; – the more applications you put in, the more likely you are to get an interview, and the more interviews you have, the more likely you are to get a job offer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Put another way, if you want to get a job offer, the number of jobs you need to apply to is a function of your interview rate (what % of applications do you get interviews for) and your job offer rate (what % of interviews do you get job offers for), specifically: &lt;code&gt;# of applications needed to get n job offers = n / interview rate / job offer rate&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;Interview Rate&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Job Offer Rate&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;# of Applications Needed to Get 1 Job Offer&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;5%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;400&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;10%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;100&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;15%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;15%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;45&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;Clearly, improving your interview rate and job offer rate pay off, but what if you can’t find 45 jobs that are perfect matches for you? &lt;strong&gt;It never hurts to broaden your search to jobs that feel like more of a stretch&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;Sure, your interview rate will be lower, but that’s balanced by applying to more jobs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Job Search Tip #3: Apply to as many jobs as possible to increase your chances of an interview.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No time to fill in all those applications? &lt;a href=&quot;https://talent.works/automate-your-job-search?utm_source=blog&quot;&gt;We can help with that&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;6250&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://talent.works/blog/2018/11/27/the-science-of-the-job-search-part-vii-you-only-need-50-of-job-requirements/appbot/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/talentworks.blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/appbot.gif?fit=1400%2C934&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1400,934&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;appbot&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/talentworks.blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/appbot.gif?fit=450%2C300&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/talentworks.blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/appbot.gif?fit=750%2C501&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-6250&quot; src=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/talentworks.blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/appbot.gif?resize=750%2C500&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; alt=&quot;appbot&quot; width=&quot;750&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; data-recalc-dims=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;ApplicationAssistant will fill out all those applications for you (and submit them at the best days and times too).
&lt;h2&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you’re out looking for the perfect job, don’t be intimidated by a long list of requirements!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Even if you only match 50% of the requirements, you should feel confident hitting “apply.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This applies just as much to women as it does to men (actually, even more so!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cast an even broader net to improve your chances of getting an interview.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Remember, getting an interview is your big break – &lt;strong&gt;it’s your opportunity to prove that you can do the job even if you don’t meet all the “requirements.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Methodology&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, we randomly sampled 6,348 applications for 668 different users from TalentWorks. Then we extracted the qualifications from the original job postings and the users’ submitted resumes using proprietary algorithms. Finally, we grouped the results based on qualification match and regressed the interview rate using a Bagging ensemble of Random Forest regressors. All analysis and graphing was done using python with pandas, sklearn, scipy, and bokeh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why Are We Doing This?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With ApplicationAssistant right now, we &lt;a href=&quot;https://talent.works/automate-your-job-search/?utm_source=blog&quot;&gt;can boost the average job-seeker’s hireability by ~5.8x.&lt;/a&gt; But, what makes ApplicationAssistant work has been an internal company secret until now. We’re fundamentally a mission-driven company and we believe we can help &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; people by sharing our learnings. So, that’s exactly what we’re doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Creative Commons&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re not only sharing this but also &lt;strong&gt;sharing all of it under the &lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&quot;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike license&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. In other words, as long as you follow a few license terms, this means you can:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Share:&lt;/strong&gt; Copy, redistribute the material in any medium or format.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adapt:&lt;/strong&gt; Remix, transform, and build upon the material.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 04:51:15 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>pixelcort</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>The Science of the Job Search, Part VII: You Only Need 50% of Job “Requirements”</og:title>
<og:url>https://talent.works/blog/2018/11/27/the-science-of-the-job-search-part-vii-you-only-need-50-of-job-requirements/</og:url>
<og:description>You're as likely to get a job interview meeting 50% of job requirements as meeting 90% of them.</og:description>
<og:image>https://i0.wp.com/talentworks.blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/requirements_required-1.png?fit=1168%2C778&amp;ssl=1</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://talent.works/blog/2018/11/27/the-science-of-the-job-search-part-vii-you-only-need-50-of-job-requirements/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Japan Is Giving Away 8M Abandoned Houses</title>
<link>https://www.travelandleisure.com/travel-news/japan-free-abandoned-house</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.travelandleisure.com/travel-news/japan-free-abandoned-house</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;title&gt;Japan Is Giving Away 8 Million Abandoned Houses — Here's How to Get One | Travel + Leisure&lt;/title&gt;&lt;meta charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;shortcut icon&quot; href=&quot;/favicon.ico&quot; type=&quot;image/vnd.microsoft.icon&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;icon&quot; href=&quot;/img/favicons/favicon-32.png&quot; sizes=&quot;32x32&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta http-equiv=&quot;X-UA-Compatible&quot; content=&quot;IE=edge&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;apple-touch-icon&quot; href=&quot;/img/favicons/favicon-57.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;apple-touch-icon&quot; href=&quot;/img/favicons/favicon-57.png&quot; sizes=&quot;57x57&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;apple-touch-icon&quot; href=&quot;/img/favicons/favicon-72.png&quot; sizes=&quot;72x72&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;apple-touch-icon&quot; href=&quot;/img/favicons/favicon-76.png&quot; sizes=&quot;76x76&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;apple-touch-icon&quot; href=&quot;/img/favicons/favicon-114.png&quot; sizes=&quot;114x114&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;apple-touch-icon&quot; href=&quot;/img/favicons/favicon-120.png&quot; sizes=&quot;120x120&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;apple-touch-icon&quot; href=&quot;/img/favicons/favicon-144.png&quot; sizes=&quot;144x144&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;apple-touch-icon&quot; href=&quot;/img/favicons/favicon-152.png&quot; sizes=&quot;152x152&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;apple-touch-icon&quot; href=&quot;/img/favicons/favicon-180.png&quot; sizes=&quot;180x180&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;icon&quot; sizes=&quot;192x192&quot; href=&quot;/img/favicons/favicon-192.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;manifest&quot; href=&quot;/manifest.json&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;viewport&quot; content=&quot;width=device-width, initial-scale=1, maximum-scale=1, minimum-scale=1, user-scalable=no&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;keywords&quot; content=&quot;Japan,Asia&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;news_keywords&quot; content=&quot;Japan,Asia&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;description&quot; content=&quot;The Japanese government is launching a program to reduce the number of abandoned homes across the country by offering them for sale for nearly nothing&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;canonical&quot; href=&quot;https://www.travelandleisure.com/travel-news/japan-free-abandoned-house&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;author&quot; content=&quot;https://plus.google.com/+travelandleisure/posts&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;amphtml&quot; href=&quot;https://amp.travelandleisure.com/travel-news/japan-free-abandoned-house?source=dam&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:title&quot; content=&quot;Japan Is Giving Away 8 Million Abandoned Houses — Here's How to Get One (Video)&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:type&quot; content=&quot;article&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:site_name&quot; content=&quot;Travel + Leisure&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:url&quot; content=&quot;https://www.travelandleisure.com/travel-news/japan-free-abandoned-house&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:description&quot; content=&quot;The Japanese government is launching a program to reduce the number of abandoned homes across the country by offering them for sale for nearly nothing, or actually nothing.&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;pinterest:url&quot; content=&quot;https://www.travelandleisure.com/travel-news/japan-free-abandoned-house&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:card&quot; content=&quot;summary&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:url&quot; content=&quot;https://www.travelandleisure.com/travel-news/japan-free-abandoned-house&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:title&quot; content=&quot;Japan is giving away 8 million abandoned houses — here's how to get one&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:description&quot; content=&quot;The Japanese government is launching a program to reduce the number of abandoned homes across the country by offering them for sale for nearly nothing&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;pinterest:description&quot; content=&quot;The Japanese government is launching a program to reduce the number of abandoned homes across the country by offering them for sale for nearly nothing, or actually nothing.&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:site&quot; content=&quot;@TravelLeisure&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;pinterest:media&quot; content=&quot;https://cdn-image.travelandleisure.com/sites/default/files/styles/1600x1000/public/1542742762/Shirakawa-go-Gifu-Japan-FREEHOUSE1118.jpg?itok=qIm3dP5e&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:image&quot; content=&quot;https://cdn-image.travelandleisure.com/sites/default/files/styles/1600x1000/public/1542742762/Shirakawa-go-Gifu-Japan-FREEHOUSE1118.jpg?itok=qIm3dP5e&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:image&quot; content=&quot;https://cdn-image.travelandleisure.com/sites/default/files/styles/1600x1000/public/1542742762/Shirakawa-go-Gifu-Japan-FREEHOUSE1118.jpg?itok=qIm3dP5e&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;fb:app_id&quot; content=&quot;1186687021348564&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;fb:pages&quot; content=&quot;25440929072&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;dns-prefetch&quot; href=&quot;//tia.timeinc.net&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;dns-prefetch&quot; href=&quot;//imagesvc.timeincapp.com&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;dns-prefetch&quot; href=&quot;//ape-asset-tag.timeinc.com&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;dns-prefetch&quot; href=&quot;//cdn.segment.com&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;dns-prefetch&quot; href=&quot;//subscription-assets.timeinc.com&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot; href=&quot;/dist/style.css&quot; lazyload=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;title&gt;Travel + Leisure&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Travel + Leisure&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Close&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Down&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Down&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Down&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Down&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Down&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Down&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Down&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Down&lt;/title&gt;&lt;title&gt;Down&lt;/title&gt;&lt;link href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/travelandleisure&quot;/&gt;&lt;link href=&quot;https://twitter.com/TravelLeisure&quot;/&gt;&lt;link href=&quot;https://plus.google.com/+travelandleisure&quot;/&gt;&lt;link href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/travelandleisure&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta content=&quot;https://www.travelandleisure.com/travel-news/japan-free-abandoned-house&quot;/&gt;&lt;title&gt;Travel + Leisure&lt;/title&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body class=&quot;template-article undefined mobile karma-site-container&quot; id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;header class=&quot;navigation&quot;&gt;&lt;nav class=&quot;main no-secondary-ribbon no-utility-ribbon contextual-social-enabled has-headline&quot;&gt;&lt;section class=&quot;container primary&quot;&gt;&lt;section class=&quot;subcontainer&quot;&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;title-display desktop-only&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;title-text padding-16-right&quot;&gt;Japan Is Giving Away 8 Million Abandoned Houses — Here's How to Get One (Video)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;




&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/nav&gt;&lt;nav class=&quot;main has-promo-tout notification-banner-wrapper&quot; data-embed-type=&quot;notification-banner&quot;/&gt;





&lt;/header&gt;


&lt;footer class=&quot;main padding-24-top&quot;&gt;


&lt;/footer&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 02:20:04 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>rmason</dc:creator>
<og:title>Japan Is Giving Away 8 Million Abandoned Houses — Here's How to Get One (Video)</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.travelandleisure.com/travel-news/japan-free-abandoned-house</og:url>
<og:description>The Japanese government is launching a program to reduce the number of abandoned homes across the country by offering them for sale for nearly nothing, or actually nothing.</og:description>
<og:image>https://cdn-image.travelandleisure.com/sites/default/files/styles/1600x1000/public/1542742762/Shirakawa-go-Gifu-Japan-FREEHOUSE1118.jpg?itok=qIm3dP5e</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.travelandleisure.com/travel-news/japan-free-abandoned-house</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>FOSS is free as in toilet</title>
<link>http://unhandledexpression.com/general/2018/11/27/foss-is-free-as-in-toilet.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://unhandledexpression.com/general/2018/11/27/foss-is-free-as-in-toilet.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I am a bit dissatisfied with the use of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tragedy_of_the_commons&quot;&gt;Tragedy of the commons&lt;/a&gt; to represent issues with free and open source software development. It is not an abstract resource that can be depleted when overused. It is not magically maintained if left alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is based on the work of people, and we should not erase those people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately (and it is by design), most of the licences and the vocabulary around it are focused on the software’s user. After all, they work by reducing the creator’s right to empower the user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As examples of this vocabulary, we have the distinction between “free as in beer” and “free as in speech” to show that the “free” word in “free software” has more to do with freedom and people’s rights to use, study, modify and share a program, than its actual price. Although, in practice, the overwhelming majority of FOSS will not cost you anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This model has won, FOSS is everywhere, companies not only use it, but even heavily rely on it, millions of devices run with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But at which cost? Open source developers are burning out. Some core libraries, on which basically everything relies, are maintained by very small teams of people working on their free time. We still have the right to study the software, but the most interesting parts are now in the user’s data, which is jealously guarded by a few huge companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not a tragedy, this is a fucking farce.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s own up to the absurdity of talking about a personal freedom that depends mainly on hidden people working for free. Let’s add more ridicule to it. Let’s start using a new expression to describe it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FOSS IS FREE AS IN TOILET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nobody believes that a free toilet will be magically cleaned up and maintained, somebody has to do it, and that person would better get paid for it. Sharing a toilet means that you flush, clean up after yourself, and always leave some paper, it’s basic manners. And yet, like toilets, as FOSS gets used by more and more people, it gets more likely that you will see obnoxious people that shit all over your commons and then complain about it. And nobody will want to take care of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Treating correctly the people who work on the software you use is just basic FOSS hygiene.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2018 22:38:11 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>bellinom</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://unhandledexpression.com/general/2018/11/27/foss-is-free-as-in-toilet.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>South Koreans lock themselves up to escape prison of daily life</title>
<link>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-southkorea-prisonstay-idUSKCN1NS0JB</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.reuters.com/article/us-southkorea-prisonstay-idUSKCN1NS0JB</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;HONGCHEON, South Korea (Reuters) - For most people, prison is a place to escape from. For South Koreans in need of a break from the demands of everyday life, a day in a faux jail is the escape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This prison gives me a sense of freedom,” said Park Hye-ri, a 28-year-old office worker who paid $90 to spend 24 hours locked up in a mock prison.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since 2013, the “Prison Inside Me” facility in northeast Hongcheon has hosted more than 2,000 inmates, many of them stressed office workers and students seeking relief from South Korea’s demanding work and academic culture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I was too busy,” said Park as she sat in a 5-sq-m (54-sq-foot) cell. “I shouldn’t be here right now, given the work I need to do. But I decided to pause and look back at myself for a better life.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(To see accompanying package, click on &lt;a href=&quot;https://reut.rs/2qZ4D1a&quot;&gt;reut.rs/2qZ4D1a&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prison rules are strict. No talking with other inmates. No mobile phones or clocks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clients get a blue prison uniform, a yoga mat, tea set, a pen and notebook. They sleep on the floor. There is a small toilet inside the room, but no mirror.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The menu includes steamed sweet potato and a banana shake for dinner, and rice porridge for breakfast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Co-founder Noh Ji-Hyang said the mock prison was inspired by her husband, a prosecutor who often put in 100-hour work weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“He said he would rather go into solitary confinement for a week to take a rest and feel better,” she said. “That was the beginning.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A downturn in South Korea’s high-tech, export-driven economy has intensified a hyper-competitive school and work environment that experts say adds to a high incidence of stress and suicide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;South Koreans worked 2,024 hours on average in 2017, the third longest after Mexico and Costa Rica, in a survey of 36 member countries in the Organisation for Economic Cooperation and Development (OECD).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Slideshow_container Slideshow_small Slideshow_standard&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Slideshow_preview-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;LazyImage_container LazyImage_dark&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s2.reutersmedia.net/resources/r/?m=02&amp;amp;d=20181123&amp;amp;t=2&amp;amp;i=1327839504&amp;amp;r=LYNXNPEEAM0EI&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

Slideshow &lt;span class=&quot;Slideshow_count&quot;&gt;(27 Images)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To help people work less and earn more, the government has raised the minimum wage and cut the legal cap on working hours to 52 per week from 68. But the policies could backfire and put at risk more jobs than they create, economists say.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Noh said some customers are wary of spending 24 or 48 hours in a prison cell, until they try it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“After a stay in the prison, people say, ‘This is not a prison, the real prison is where we return to,’” she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Attribution_container&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Attribution_attribution&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Attribution_content&quot;&gt;Reporting by Minwoo Park and Yijin Kim; Editing by Josh Smith and Darren Schuettler&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;StandardArticleBody_trustBadgeContainer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;StandardArticleBody_trustBadgeTitle&quot;&gt;Our Standards:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;trustBadgeUrl&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thomsonreuters.com/en/about-us/trust-principles.html&quot;&gt;The Thomson Reuters Trust Principles.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2018 21:27:27 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jacobbudin</dc:creator>
<og:title>South Koreans lock themselves up to escape prison of daily life</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-southkorea-prisonstay-idUSKCN1NS0JB</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>For most people, prison is a place to escape from. For South Koreans in need of ...</og:description>
<og:image>https://s2.reutersmedia.net/resources/r/?m=02&amp;d=20181123&amp;t=2&amp;i=1327839504&amp;w=1200&amp;r=LYNXNPEEAM0EI</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-southkorea-prisonstay-idUSKCN1NS0JB</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>