<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Jony Ive to form independent design company with Apple as client</title>
<link>https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2019/06/jony-ive-to-form-independent-design-company-with-apple-as-client/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2019/06/jony-ive-to-form-independent-design-company-with-apple-as-client/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Cupertino, California — Apple today announced that Sir Jony Ive, Apple’s chief design officer, will depart the company as an employee later this year to form an independent design company which will count Apple among its primary clients. While he pursues personal projects, Ive in his new company will continue to work closely and on a range of projects with Apple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Jony is a singular figure in the design world and his role in Apple’s revival cannot be overstated, from 1998’s groundbreaking iMac to the iPhone and the unprecedented ambition of Apple Park, where recently he has been putting so much of his energy and care,” said Tim Cook, Apple’s CEO. “Apple will continue to benefit from Jony’s talents by working directly with him on exclusive projects, and through the ongoing work of the brilliant and passionate design team he has built. After so many years working closely together, I’m happy that our relationship continues to evolve and I look forward to working with Jony long into the future.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Design team leaders Evans Hankey, vice president of Industrial Design, and Alan Dye, vice president of Human Interface Design, will report to Jeff Williams, Apple’s chief operating officer. Both Dye and Hankey have played key leadership roles on Apple’s design team for many years. Williams has led the development of Apple Watch since its inception and will spend more of his time working with the design team in their studio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“After nearly 30 years and countless projects, I am most proud of the lasting work we have done to create a design team, process and culture at Apple that is without peer. Today it is stronger, more vibrant and more talented than at any point in Apple’s history,” said Ive. “The team will certainly thrive under the excellent leadership of Evans, Alan and Jeff, who have been among my closest collaborators. I have the utmost confidence in my designer colleagues at Apple, who remain my closest friends, and I look forward to working with them for many years to come.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple’s design team, recognized with countless design awards, brings together creatives from around the world representing multiple disciplines, including user interface, industrial design, graphic and font design, haptics and sound design.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 20:56:30 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>briandear</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Jony Ive to form independent design company with Apple as client</og:title>
<og:description>Sir Jony Ive, Apple’s chief design officer, will depart the company later this year to form an independent design company.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2019/06/jony-ive-to-form-independent-design-company-with-apple-as-client/</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.apple.com/newsroom/images/people/executives/Apple-update-tim-cook-jonathan-ive-062619_LP_hero.jpg.og.jpg?201906272132</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2019/06/jony-ive-to-form-independent-design-company-with-apple-as-client/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>“The books will stop working.”</title>
<link>https://twitter.com/rdonoghue/status/1144011630197522432</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://twitter.com/rdonoghue/status/1144011630197522432</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;And, look, I love ebooks.

I do.

Epubs. Gaming PDFs. The whole shebang.

I see no contradiction between that and loving physical books, and I don't get those who do. They each have wonderful advantages.

This is not about ebooks. It's about bullshit.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 18:48:23 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>_Microft</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://mobile.twitter.com/rdonoghue/status/1144011630197522432</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Reinventing Firefox for Android</title>
<link>https://blog.mozilla.org/futurereleases/2019/06/27/reinventing-firefox-for-android-a-preview/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.mozilla.org/futurereleases/2019/06/27/reinventing-firefox-for-android-a-preview/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;At Firefox, we’re passionate about providing solutions for people who care about safety, privacy and independence. For several months, we’ve been working on a new strategy for our Android products to serve you even better. Today we’re very happy to announce a pilot of our new browser for Android devices that is &lt;a href=&quot;https://app.adjust.com/9rp33dq&quot;&gt;available to early adopters for testing as of now&lt;/a&gt;. We’ll have a feature-rich, polished version of this flagship application available for this fall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_2641&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ffp4g1ylyit3jdyti1hqcvtb-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/futurereleases/files/2019/06/logo-and-wordmark-horizontal-stacked@3x.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img aria-describedby=&quot;caption-attachment-2641&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-2641 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://ffp4g1ylyit3jdyti1hqcvtb-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/futurereleases/files/2019/06/logo-and-wordmark-horizontal-stacked@3x.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;675&quot; height=&quot;240&quot; srcset=&quot;https://blog.mozilla.org/futurereleases/files/2019/06/logo-and-wordmark-horizontal-stacked@3x.png 675w, https://blog.mozilla.org/futurereleases/files/2019/06/logo-and-wordmark-horizontal-stacked@3x-300x107.png 300w, https://blog.mozilla.org/futurereleases/files/2019/06/logo-and-wordmark-horizontal-stacked@3x-600x213.png 600w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 675px) 100vw, 675px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;caption-attachment-2641&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Firefox Preview — our new mobile pilot app for Android&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Always-on, always private: a new and improved mobile Firefox&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.mozilla.org/blog/2019/06/04/firefox-now-available-with-enhanced-tracking-protection-by-default/&quot;&gt;Big Tech, which only recently started to put more emphasis on privacy&lt;/a&gt;, we &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.mozilla.org/blog/2016/11/17/introducing-firefox-focus-a-free-fast-and-easy-to-use-private-browser-for-ios/&quot;&gt;launched Firefox Focus&lt;/a&gt; about two and a half years ago, a mobile browser for iOS and Android that allows you to discover the web without being followed around by trackers. While continuously improving Firefox Focus over time, we realized that users demanded a full-fledged mobile browsing experience, but more private and secure than any existing app. So we decided to make Firefox more like Focus, but with all the ease and amenities of a full-featured mobile browser. The result is an early version of what we currently call &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/mozilla-mobile/fenix&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Firefox Preview&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bringing Firefox Quantum performance to mobile, with GeckoView&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Firefox Preview, we’re combining the best of what our lightweight Focus application and our current mobile browsers have to offer to create a best in class mobile experience. The new application is powered by Firefox’s own mobile browser engine — GeckoView — the same high-performance, feature enabling motor that &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.mozilla.org/blog/2018/10/02/new-firefox-focus-comes-with-search-suggestions-revamped-visual-design-and-an-under-the-hood-surprise-for-android-users/&quot;&gt;fuels our Focus app&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might remember how we revamped the engine behind the Firefox desktop browser in 2017 enabling us to significantly improve the desktop user experience. As a result, today’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.mozilla.org/blog/2017/11/14/introducing-firefox-quantum/&quot;&gt;Firefox Quantum&lt;/a&gt; is much faster, more efficient, equipped with a modern user interface and clearly the next-gen Firefox. Quite similarly, implementing GeckoView paves the way for a complete makeover of the mobile Firefox experience. While all other major Android browsers today are based on Blink and therefore reflective of Google’s decisions about mobile, Firefox’s GeckoView engine ensures us and our users independence. Building Firefox for Android on GeckoView also results in greater flexibility in terms of the types of privacy and security features we can offer our mobile users. With GeckoView we have the ability to develop faster, more secure and more user friendly browsers that deliver unprecedented performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To speak more specifically about features, here are some new functions Firefox Preview will offer, partially enabled by GeckoView:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Faster than ever:&lt;/em&gt; Firefox Preview &lt;em&gt;is up to 2x faster than previous versions of Firefox for Android.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fast by design:&lt;/em&gt; with a minimalist start screen and bottom navigation bar, Preview helps you get more done on the go.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Stay organized:&lt;/em&gt; Make sense of the web with Collections, a new feature that helps you save, organize, and share collections of sites. Quickly save and return to tasks like your morning routine, shopping lists, travel planning and more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tracking Protection on by default:&lt;/em&gt; Everyone deserves freedom from invasive advertising trackers and other bad actors so Firefox Preview blocks trackers by default. The result is faster browsing and fewer annoyances.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ffp4g1ylyit3jdyti1hqcvtb-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/futurereleases/files/2019/06/Collections.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-2644 size-medium&quot; src=&quot;https://ffp4g1ylyit3jdyti1hqcvtb-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/futurereleases/files/2019/06/Collections-300x533.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;533&quot; srcset=&quot;https://blog.mozilla.org/futurereleases/files/2019/06/Collections-300x533.png 300w, https://blog.mozilla.org/futurereleases/files/2019/06/Collections-768x1365.png 768w, https://blog.mozilla.org/futurereleases/files/2019/06/Collections-600x1067.png 600w, https://blog.mozilla.org/futurereleases/files/2019/06/Collections-1000x1778.png 1000w, https://blog.mozilla.org/futurereleases/files/2019/06/Collections.png 1080w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ffp4g1ylyit3jdyti1hqcvtb-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/futurereleases/files/2019/06/Collections-Expanded.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-2643&quot; src=&quot;https://ffp4g1ylyit3jdyti1hqcvtb-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/futurereleases/files/2019/06/Collections-Expanded-300x533.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;533&quot; srcset=&quot;https://blog.mozilla.org/futurereleases/files/2019/06/Collections-Expanded-300x533.png 300w, https://blog.mozilla.org/futurereleases/files/2019/06/Collections-Expanded-768x1365.png 768w, https://blog.mozilla.org/futurereleases/files/2019/06/Collections-Expanded-600x1067.png 600w, https://blog.mozilla.org/futurereleases/files/2019/06/Collections-Expanded-1000x1778.png 1000w, https://blog.mozilla.org/futurereleases/files/2019/06/Collections-Expanded.png 1080w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_2642&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ffp4g1ylyit3jdyti1hqcvtb-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/futurereleases/files/2019/06/Bottom-URL-bar.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img aria-describedby=&quot;caption-attachment-2642&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-2642 size-medium&quot; src=&quot;https://ffp4g1ylyit3jdyti1hqcvtb-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/futurereleases/files/2019/06/Bottom-URL-bar-300x533.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;533&quot; srcset=&quot;https://blog.mozilla.org/futurereleases/files/2019/06/Bottom-URL-bar-300x533.png 300w, https://blog.mozilla.org/futurereleases/files/2019/06/Bottom-URL-bar-768x1365.png 768w, https://blog.mozilla.org/futurereleases/files/2019/06/Bottom-URL-bar-600x1067.png 600w, https://blog.mozilla.org/futurereleases/files/2019/06/Bottom-URL-bar-1000x1778.png 1000w, https://blog.mozilla.org/futurereleases/files/2019/06/Bottom-URL-bar.png 1080w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;caption-attachment-2642&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;With Firefox Preview you’re browsing the mobile web faster, more efficiently and more privately&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information about how we’re planning to use GeckoView in our product portfolio, check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://hacks.mozilla.org/2019/06/geckoview-in-2019&quot;&gt;this blog post on Mozilla Hacks&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be among the first to test&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we release products to the world, we run many different experiments and tests which we learn from and help us make our products better for real consumption. For example, our Firefox Quantum desktop browser has a beta release, a separate channel aimed at developers or early tech adopters to test upcoming features before they’re released to all consumers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Likewise, what we’re releasing today is an &lt;a href=&quot;https://app.adjust.com/9rp33dq&quot;&gt;early version&lt;/a&gt; for our experimental browser for Android users based on GeckoView. Firefox Preview is a separate mobile application primarily aimed at developers and early adopters who want to help us improve Firefox on Android. The user experience of this early version will differ significantly from the final product, planned for release later this year. We’re counting on our passionate users to try it now and provide the kind of feedback (via &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:firefox-preview-feedback@mozilla.com&quot;&gt;email&lt;/a&gt; or on &lt;a href=&quot;https://bit.ly/2GCr8Ai&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;) that will enable us to release the best mobile Firefox possible and continuously improve GeckoView.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How our new mobile strategy affects existing products&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the rest of 2019, we’re going to direct our efforts into optimizing the entire Firefox experience on all Android devices. In order to have a strong foundation for the next generation of mobile Firefox browsers and put all our efforts and resources in GeckoView, work on Firefox Focus will currently be on hold. Don’t worry though, you can still keep using our privacy browser, Focus, as well as our current Firefox for Android.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stay tuned for more!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hope this update from the Firefox Mobile Team sparks excitement for the new mobile strategy we’re rolling out in 2019. We plan to take mobile browsing to a whole new level. No matter where, when or on which device, we at Firefox believe that you always deserve the best possible user experience. And we’ll do our best to bring it to your screens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://app.adjust.com/9rp33dq&quot;&gt;Try the preview of our new Firefox for Android&lt;/a&gt;, let us know what you think about this GeckoView-based mobile app and stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 16:06:31 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mncolinlee</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://blog.mozilla.org/futurereleases/2019/06/27/reinventing-firefox-for-android-a-preview</og:url>
<og:title>Reinventing Firefox for Android: a Preview – Future Releases</og:title>
<og:description>With Firefox Preview, we’re combining the best of what our lightweight Focus application and our current mobile browsers have to offer to create a best in class mobile experience. The new application is powered by Firefox's own mobile browser engine -- GeckoView -- the same high-performance, feature enabling motor that fuels our Focus app.</og:description>
<og:image>https://blog.mozilla.org/futurereleases/files/2019/06/Fx_Blog_Future_Releases_Mobile_Copy.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.mozilla.org/futurereleases/2019/06/27/reinventing-firefox-for-android-a-preview/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Everything everywhere is securities fraud</title>
<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/opinion/articles/2019-06-26/everything-everywhere-is-securities-fraud</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bloomberg.com/opinion/articles/2019-06-26/everything-everywhere-is-securities-fraud</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/opinion/articles/2019-06-26/everything-everywhere-is-securities-fraud&quot;&gt;https://www.bloomberg.com/opinion/articles/2019-06-26/everything-everywhere-is-securities-fraud&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=20295229&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=20295229&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 219&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 71&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 15:24:42 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>dwohnitmok</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bloomberg.com/tosv2.html?vid=&amp;uuid=461f64d0-9940-11e9-af3c-33cfa74aa66a&amp;url=L29waW5pb24vYXJ0aWNsZXMvMjAxOS0wNi0yNi9ldmVyeXRoaW5nLWV2ZXJ5d2hlcmUtaXMtc2VjdXJpdGllcy1mcmF1ZA==</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Google’s new reCAPTCHA has a dark side</title>
<link>https://www.fastcompany.com/90369697/googles-new-recaptcha-has-a-dark-side</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.fastcompany.com/90369697/googles-new-recaptcha-has-a-dark-side</guid>
<description>&lt;div readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve all tried to log into a website or submit a form only to be stuck clicking boxes of traffic lights or storefronts or bridges in a desperate attempt to finally convince the computer that we’re not actually a bot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;ad-wrapper ad-wrapper--mobileparallax_1&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ad-wrapper--ad-unit-wrap&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;advertisement&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ad-wrapper ad-wrapper--native_mid_article_inject&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ad-wrapper--ad-unit-wrap&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;advertisement&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;61.327926865231&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For many years, this has been one of the predominant ways that reCaptcha—the Google-run internet bot detector—has determined whether a user is a bot or not. But last fall, Google launched a new version of the tool, with the goal of eliminating that annoying user experience entirely. Now, when you enter a form on a website that’s using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/recaptcha/intro/v3.html&quot;&gt;reCaptcha V3&lt;/a&gt;, you won’t see the “I’m not a robot” checkbox, nor will you have to prove you know what a cat looks like. Instead, you won’t see anything at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-90369990 lazyload&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;786&quot; height=&quot;293&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px&quot; data-src=&quot;https://images.fastcompany.net/image/upload/w_596,c_limit,q_auto:best,f_auto/wp-cms/uploads/2019/06/i-2-90369697-the-secret-way-google-tracks-you-around-the-web.jpg&quot;/&gt;[Image: courtesy Google]
&lt;p&gt;“It’s a better experience for users. Everyone has failed a Captcha,” says Cy Khormaee, the reCaptcha product lead at Google. Instead, Google analyzes the way users navigate through a website and assigns them a risk score based on how malicious their behavior is. Khormaee won’t share what signals Google uses to determine these scores because he says that would make it easier for scammers to imitate benign users, but he believes that this new version of reCaptcha makes it incredibly difficult for bots or Captcha farmers—humans who are paid tiny amounts to break Captchas online—to fool Google’s system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-90369991 lazyload&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1009&quot; height=&quot;496&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px&quot; data-src=&quot;https://images.fastcompany.net/image/upload/w_596,c_limit,q_auto:best,f_auto/wp-cms/uploads/2019/06/i-3-90369697-the-secret-way-google-tracks-you-around-the-web.jpg&quot;/&gt;An old version of reCaptcha. [Image: courtesy Google]
&lt;p&gt;“You have to understand what behavior on the site should be and mimic that well enough to fool us,” he says. “That’s a really hard problem versus the general problem of, ‘Pretend like I’m a human.'” Website administrators then get access to their visitors’ risk scores and can decide how to handle them: For instance, if a user with a high risk score attempts to log in, the website can set rules to ask them to enter additional verification information through two-factor authentication. As Khormaee put it, the “worst case is we have a little inconvenience for legitimate users, but if there is an adversary, we prevent your account from being stolen.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to tech statistics website Built With, more than &lt;a href=&quot;https://trends.builtwith.com/websitelist/reCAPTCHA-v3&quot;&gt;650,000 websites&lt;/a&gt; are already using reCaptcha v3; overall, there are at least &lt;a href=&quot;https://trends.builtwith.com/widgets/reCAPTCHA&quot;&gt;4.5 million websites use reCaptcha&lt;/a&gt;, including 25% of the top 10,000 sites. Google is also now testing an enterprise version of reCaptcha v3, where Google creates a customized reCaptcha for enterprises that are looking for more granular data about users’ risk levels to protect their site algorithms from malicious users and bots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But this new, risk-score based system comes with a serious trade-off: users’ privacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to two security researchers who’ve studied reCaptcha, one of the ways that Google determines whether you’re a malicious user or not is whether you already have a Google cookie installed on your browser. It’s the same cookie that allows you to open new tabs in your browser and not have to re-log in to your Google account every time. But according to &lt;a href=&quot;https://makrout.github.io/&quot;&gt;Mohamed Akrout&lt;/a&gt;, a computer science PhD student at the University of Toronto who has studied reCaptcha, it appears that Google is also using its cookies to determine whether someone is a human in reCaptcha v3 tests. Akrout wrote in &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/pdf/1903.01003.pdf&quot;&gt;an April paper&lt;/a&gt; about how reCaptcha v3 simulations that ran on a browser with a connected Google account received lower risk scores than browsers without a connected Google account. “If you have a Google account it’s more likely you are human,” he says. Google did not respond to questions about the role that Google cookies play in reCaptcha.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ad-wrapper ad-wrapper--mobilerectangle_1&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ad-wrapper--ad-unit-wrap&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;advertisement&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;60.393389325386&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With reCaptcha v3, technology consultant Marcos Perona and Akrout’s tests both found that their reCaptcha scores were always low risk when they visited a test website on a browser where they were already logged into a Google account. Alternatively, if they went to the test website from a private browser like Tor or a VPN, their scores were high risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Image: courtesy Google]To make this risk-score system work accurately, website administrators are supposed to embed reCaptcha v3 code on &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; of the pages of their website, not just on forms or log-in pages. Then, reCaptcha learns over time how their website’s users typically act, helping the machine learning algorithm underlying it to generate more accurate risk scores. Because reCaptcha v3 is likely to be on every page of a website,  if you’re signed into your Google account there’s a chance Google is getting data about every single webpage you go to that is embedded with reCaptcha v3—and there many be no visual indication on the site that it’s happening, beyond a small reCaptcha logo hidden in the corner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Khormaee would not address the way that Google uses data for reCaptcha in any way and instead referred &lt;em&gt;Fast Company&lt;/em&gt; to Google’s terms of service, which is linked beneath the reCaptcha logo on most sites. However, there was no reference to reCaptcha anywhere in the terms of service. After this story was published, Google reached out to say that reCaptcha’s API sends hardware and software information, including device and application data, back to Google for analysis, and that the service is only used to fight spam and abuse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google encouraging site admins to put reCaptcha all over their sites, and then sharing the resulting risk scores with those admins is great for security, Perona thinks, because he says it “gives site owners more control and visibility over what’s going on” with potential scammer and bot attacks, and the system will give admins more accurate scores than if reCaptcha is only using data from a single webpage to analyze user behavior. But there’s the trade-off. “It makes sense and makes it more user-friendly, but it also gives Google more data,” he says. Google would not clarify what it does with the data it captures about user behavior via reCaptcha, only that it is used for improving reCaptcha and general security purposes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This kind of cookie-based data collection happens elsewhere on the internet. Giant companies use it as a way to assess where their users go as they surf the web, which can then be tied into providing better targeted advertising. For instance, Google’s reCaptcha cookie follows the same logic of the Facebook “like” button when it’s embedded in other websites—it gives that site some social media functionality, but it also &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/alexkantrowitz/heres-how-facebook-tracks-you-when-youre-not-on-facebook&quot;&gt;lets Facebook know that you’re there&lt;/a&gt;. Previously, Google &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/google-no-captcha-adtruth-privacy-research-2015-2/&quot;&gt;has said&lt;/a&gt; that the data captured from reCaptcha is not used for ad targeting or analyzing user interests and preferences. After this story was published, Google said that the information collected through reCaptcha will not be used for personalized advertising by Google.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perona views Google’s use of reCaptcha as an “online land grab” that strengthens Google’s hold over the internet. He thinks reCaptcha is similar in this way to other Google products like &lt;a href=&quot;https://amp.dev/&quot;&gt;Accelerated Mobile Pages&lt;/a&gt; (AMP), a program to make news sites’ pages load faster on mobile devices but has caused some &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/01/01/technology/google-amp-mobile-publishing.html&quot;&gt;consternation from publishers&lt;/a&gt; over whether Google is taking web traffic away from news sites. Same goes for Google Chrome, which the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2019/06/21/google-chrome-has-become-surveillance-software-its-time-switch/?utm_term=.2954d44a386c&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Washington Post&lt;/em&gt; recently called “surveillance software&lt;/a&gt;” (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fastcompany.com/90174010/bye-chrome-why-im-switching-to-firefox-and-you-should-too&quot;&gt;I’m among those who have ditched Chrome for Firefox&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ad-wrapper ad-wrapper--mobilerectangle_2&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ad-wrapper--ad-unit-wrap&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;advertisement&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;19&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s always a double-edged sword,” Perona says. “You gain something, but you’re also giving Google a little more control over everything online.” The gain is security and a better user experience, but privacy may suffer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google did not address any potential privacy problems and insisted that reCaptcha v3 is a matter of corporate responsibility. It sees reCaptcha v3 as a way of ensuring a safe, frictionless online experience. “Google is so deeply integrated with the internet,” Khormaee says. “We want to do anything we can to protect it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ad-wrapper ad-wrapper--native_recommendationlink&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ad-wrapper--ad-unit-wrap&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;advertisement&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 14:41:11 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ProAm</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Google’s new reCAPTCHA has a dark side</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.fastcompany.com/90369697/googles-new-recaptcha-has-a-dark-side</og:url>
<og:description>The latest version of the bot detector reCaptcha is invisible to users and has spread to more than 650,000 websites. It’s great for security—but not so great for your privacy.</og:description>
<og:image>https://images.fastcompany.net/image/upload/w_1280,f_auto,q_auto,fl_lossy/wp-cms/uploads/2019/06/p-1-90369697-the-secret-way-google-tracks-you-around-the-web.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.fastcompany.com/90369697/googles-new-recaptcha-has-a-dark-side</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>What I Learned Co-Founding Dribbble</title>
<link>http://simplebits.com/2019/06/25/dribbble.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://simplebits.com/2019/06/25/dribbble.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Last month, I gave a 30-minute talk at the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://conference.awwwards.com/san-francisco&quot;&gt;Awwwards&lt;/a&gt;  conference in San Francisco. I used to give talks fairly often, mostly covering CSS and web design in general, but this one was a bit different. I decided to share 20 things I’ve learned by co-founding Dribbble over the last 10 years. The timing was cosmic, as I’d just made the decision to retire fully from Dribbble, stepping aside to figure out what’s next. More on that in a bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reflecting on what I’ve learned from building a community for designers, learning how to run a business, and navigating some tough life years proved both fun and difficult. I thought I’d share those thoughts in hypertext should they be useful. And so here we are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I need to preface what follows with a large disclaimer: &lt;strong&gt;None of this is prescriptive.&lt;/strong&gt; These are simply my own experiences, so take with a grain of (pink Himalayan) salt. Oh, and none of this reflects Dribbble as a company or the views of the current team (which is fantastic and kicking ass). These are my own personal thoughts using a historical lens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;choose-your-partner-wisely&quot;&gt;1. Choose your partner wisely&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was fortunate that &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://thornett.com/&quot;&gt;Rich Thornett&lt;/a&gt;  (Dribbble’s Co-Founder) and I found each other. We were neighbors in Salem, Massachusetts. I could see his back door from my front door, our kids were friends, etc. Our skillsets meshed perfectly. Dribbble started as a side project. There was no business plan, or mission to disrupt the design industry, or belief that we were changing the world. We had an idea and started building it. The rest followed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;photo-medium&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://simplebits.com/img/post/dan-rich.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said, if you’re in the position to &lt;em&gt;choose&lt;/em&gt; partners and/or co-founders, know that it’s very much like a marriage. Should you be blessed with any amount of success, you’ll be going through some stuff with these people. You’ll be spending a lot of time together. You’ll be making big life decisions together. You won’t always get along. You won’t always see eye-to-eye. You’ll have to put up with terrible puns—no wait, I actually enjoy Rich’s talent for wordplay. But you get the idea: Co-founding a company requires you to be married, and sometimes that isn’t easy. But it’s important for you to be close on a level that can test your will. Communication is paramount.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m relieved that after all we’ve gone through, Rich and I have remained great friends. It means an immense amount to me. Choose your partner(s) wisely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;start-with-a-t-shirt&quot;&gt;2. Start with a t-shirt&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;photo&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://simplebits.com/img/post/dribbble-tee.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No really. Every good thing starts with a t-shirt. I had the logo and t-shirt made for Dribbble before anything else. It’s called priorities, people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We sent 50 shirts along with a card to friends and colleagues announcing Dribbble’s beta back in 2008. This first batch of members played a pivotal role in the foundation of the community and how it would develop. The shirt helped guilt them into actually checking out the site. That’s the key takeaway here: Instead of a generic email, send something to folks you’d like to join your community. Like a free t-shirt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;your-first-100-members-are-critical&quot;&gt;3. Your first 100 members are critical&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Selfishly, we chose designers that we wanted to see what they were working on. Later, when we issued invitations, it was this initial bunch who invited the next wave and so on and so forth. There was a sense of responsibility in the “family tree” in those early days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are also the folks that you’ll get an enormous amount of feedback from. You chose them, they’re special, and they’ll feel that. You’ll do a lot of listening to them. Primarily because the signal to noise ratio is high.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We launched an invitation system mostly to combat support and throttle the amount of scaling we needed while we worked day jobs. It was never meant to be a barrier for legitimate designers. But a positive byproduct of an invitations system was that the quality of work shared remained so high.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;pave-the-cowpaths&quot;&gt;4. Pave the cowpaths&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Listening and &lt;em&gt;watching&lt;/em&gt; those early members was crucial in shepherding the community and the site’s functionality that followed. Many of Dribbble’s early features (Rebounds, Playoffs, etc.) were a direct reaction to how the community &lt;em&gt;wanted&lt;/em&gt; things to work—regardless of whether we’d built a feature set around it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By taking a slow, observatory position as a company, carefully adding features that our members clearly wanted, it enabled us to avoid some of the pitfalls that other similar communities ran into where there were often very strict rules and rigid UI that tried to &lt;em&gt;predict&lt;/em&gt; what members wanted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This happens elsewhere too, of course. Twitter’s @mentions and hashtags, Instagram Stories, etc.—you can never predict how a community will end up using the tools you build. And that’s okay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;dont-be-afraid-to-throw-thingsaway&quot;&gt;5. Don’t be afraid to throw things away&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We built a lot of really dumb features. Some really out-there stuff. Luckily a lot of it was never seen publicly. We would iterate internally, throw stuff at the wall and see what sticks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;photo-medium&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://simplebits.com/img/post/pixel-meter.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Occasionally, however, something you believe to be a great idea has a ton of resources dumped into it, is released, and then fails. It’s not easy, but you’ll need to learn to let go of that, trash it and move on. Chalk it up to a learning experience. Even if it’s a mountain of code and time you’re tossing out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sure, we had to walk back on some feature releases, but thankfully avoided most insane ideas from seeing the light of day by &lt;strong&gt;iterating internally and deploying slowly&lt;/strong&gt;. This is the opposite of, “ship quickly and often”, and I’m thankful for our more methodical approach. Here’s a perfect example of an insanely terrible idea that we spent way too much time on:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;persistent-iteration-over-flashylaunches&quot;&gt;6. Persistent iteration over flashy launches&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We tried our best to make subtle, consistent tweaks so as not to disrupt the familiarity the site had. It’s tempting to make a big splash with a giant redesign complete with keg party and a 20-foot long Beef Wellington… but those moments are fleeting. And potentially jarring to the community that uses your site every day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When designing for a community, building trust and a place that’s comfortable for folks to come back to every day is essential, especially when just starting out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;not-knowing-what-youre-doing-isokay&quot;&gt;7. Not knowing what you’re doing is okay&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It took me a long time to realize this. In business and life in general, no one really knows what the hell they’re doing. And everyone is winging it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;photo-medium&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://simplebits.com/img/post/saw.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was 12 I wanted to build a quarter-pipe skateboard ramp. Thankfully my dad offered to help. Like me, he’s not particularly handy, but he’s willing to try anything. So, we’re in the basement cutting a board with his Sears circular saw when all of a sudden I heard this &lt;em&gt;Whirrrrrrrrsssssssshhhhhhhup!&lt;/em&gt; And the saw was dead. My dad had cut right through the cord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now we were lucky there wasn’t an electrical shock during all of this, but suffice to say, that ended any potential future sawing projects. But here’s what I remember most about that day: My dad just laughing. He laughed it off. It became somewhat of an embarrassing family legend over the years—but my dad &lt;em&gt;owned it&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having the ability to laugh at your mistakes while at the same time being unafraid of jumping into things you don’t know how to do is an incredibly powerful quality. And I think it’s crucial for people to have that when creating and running businesses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;grow-thick-skinquickly&quot;&gt;8. Grow thick skin. Quickly.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Designing for designers is… &lt;em&gt;difficult&lt;/em&gt;. We’re an opinionated bunch, aren’t we?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like most of everything on the web, Dribbble has endured a ton of negativity over the years. It comes with the territory. With any increased exposure and traction, the critics come out en masse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dribbble has been accused of ruining the design industry. Which is pretty awesome, really. I mean, if a website for designers is capable of ruining an entire discipline, well that’s rather impressive, no? But more seriously, it’s not always easy to stomach when you’re on the other side. It gets personal. And the quicker you learn to grow thick skin and understand what matters, the better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A couple of things to consider:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Learn who to ignore Over time, you’ll recognize patterns, especially from those on social media. You’ll begin to sort out who is being genuinely critical from those that just love to pick a fight. Ignore the latter. You’ll never please them anyway, and they certainly aren’t fun at parties.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Celebrate the positive Focus on praise and positivity and make sure your team reads it all. Early on we started a #highlights Slack channel where we’d collect and republish positive mentions of Dribbble. I’m also reminded of Jeff Veen telling me that in the early days of &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://fonts.adobe.com/&quot;&gt;Typekit,&lt;/a&gt;  the team would print out positive tweets from customers and hang them up around the conference room walls.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s not always easy, but try and stay focused on the positive voices surrounding what you’re doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;trends-come-and-go-and-come-backagain&quot;&gt;9. Trends come and go and come back again&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the things Dribbble would often get dinged on was its Popular page and the seemingly homogenous trends it would perpetuate. I loved it and still do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite eras in UI design was the skeuomorphic period of the late 2000s. It was a fun, creative puzzle-finding way to take the standard iOS icon shape and fitting insanely detailed renderings within. I discovered so many talented pixel artists at this time through Dribbble. Many of them from Eastern Europe and Asia. There’s something in the water there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;photo&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://simplebits.com/img/post/skeu.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If looking at the Popular page around this time, we would hear, &lt;em&gt;“Dribbble is nothing but icon designers”.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later, it was long shadows…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;photo&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://simplebits.com/img/post/long-shadows.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Draw something neat, then add a 45º shadow to it. Remember this trend? It was fun and oddly short-lived. Then it became everything flat and monlined…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;photo&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://simplebits.com/img/post/monoline.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then it was all cats…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;photo&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://simplebits.com/img/post/cats.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wait, no it’s always been cats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyhow, I always loved being able to see these trends ebb and flow. They would be very apparent for a period of time, but would always morph and change, sometimes resurfacing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My advice was to not worry about trends, but rather use the style best applied for the task at hand and stick to it. Go with what feels right for the problem you’re solving. And then have fun watching what people gravitate towards. Be patient and what was old and played out will become new again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;everything-is-temporary-and-thatsok&quot;&gt;10. Everything is temporary and that’s ok&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another reason not to get hung up on whether something’s trendy or not: It’s all temporary anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was going through some old work in my portfolio, some good some bad of course. I’ve made some pretty silly and questionable stuff over the years…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;photo&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://simplebits.com/img/post/work.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing all of this has in common is that it’s all gone. It doesn’t exist anymore. Kaput. Deleted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now you can either get really depressed about how digital work is so disposable, or you can view that as a positive. That you can continue to reinvent yourself and your work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember how important some of this stuff seemed at the time? Emergency meetings? Calls while on vacation? There are no lives at stake here. It’s here and then it’s replaced. Something I try to keep in mind when things start getting a little urgent and stressy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not to get all spiritual on you, but isn’t &lt;em&gt;everything&lt;/em&gt; temporary really? Like it’s all just stardust swirling around for a while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knowing your work is temporary can be a bit freeing and add some protection from worrying about trends and/or being the best ever in the world at &lt;em&gt;xyz&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;people-and-relationships-are-whats-most-important&quot;&gt;11. People and relationships are what’s most important&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, while pixels can disappear and your work is temporary, people and relationships stick around. Soon, you’ll realize they are the most important part of all of this. Long after the work is gone, if you do things right, you’ll have good people, friends, co-workers, future co-workers around you that will be much more valuable than the things you created.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;photo&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://simplebits.com/img/post/team.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, be kind to who you work with. You never know if your paths may cross again. A client or co-worker today could be a future job lead or new company founder. You just never know. I can attribute my entire career path to breaks I got from friends and past co-workers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in the early 2000s, I was working with the team at Odeo as a freelance designer. Toward the end of the project Ev Williams kindly asked:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Hey, do you want to do some design for this new project we started called Twttr?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“No thanks, I’m too busy.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know. What a moron I was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But here’s the thing: You never know where your next project or big opportunity is going to come from-and more specifically &lt;em&gt;who&lt;/em&gt; it’s going to come from. Be nice. It’s all about people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;stay-sharp-with-sideprojects&quot;&gt;12. Stay sharp with side projects&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I learned while focused on a single product vs. freelancing multiple short-term projects: It’s easy for your chops to get rusty. It’s easy to feel like you’re falling behind. When you’re jumping from client to client you’re continually reinventing your process and toolset. It’s like starting fresh every time. When you’re running a business, you’re moving much slower, wearing different hats, getting out of the loop on certain tech, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep things fresh with side projects. Experiment and learn new things on the side to keep those learning gears moving. My limited attention span has always generated multiple side projects whether I planned them or not, but I’m always thankful to keep learning new things while I’m maintaining others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heck, Dribbble itself started out as a side project for Rich and me!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://advencher.co/&quot;&gt;Advencher Supply Co.&lt;/a&gt;  is a side project I started a while back that combines a whole host of interests for me: Designing physical products, outdoors, adventure, etc. I’m learning a slew of new skills on the manufacturing and retail end of things and it’s fascinating. Not to mention puppeteering and video production ;) More on this in a bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe title=&quot;vimeo-player&quot; src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/317122027&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no number 13 as it’s an unlucky number.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;dont-be-superstitious&quot;&gt;14. Don’t be superstitious&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;find-a-good-lawyer-and-accountant&quot;&gt;15. Find a good lawyer and accountant&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is absolutely key and best to have these in your pocket before you actually need them. A large fruit company sent us a cease and desist letter in the early days and having the proper counsel that knew how to handle it saved us a lot of grief.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, remember #1, where I likened co-founding to marriage? Should your venture be successful you’ll have to navigate some big financial and legal life stuff together. Lawyers and accountants that understand your business will be invaluable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;identify-when-youre-beingstubborn&quot;&gt;16. Identify when you’re being stubborn&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Work on something long enough and things can start to get comfortable. It’s easy to get set in your ways and/or complacent. I was certainly guilty of this and here’s one prime example of me being dumb.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was incredibly reluctant to use &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://sass-lang.com/&quot;&gt;Sass&lt;/a&gt;  in our front-end toolkit. Sass is an extension that makes writing CSS easier. Rich lobbied hard for us to use Sass in the codebase, and I stubbornly refused based on my absurd need to control even the most inconsequential formatting preferences in my stylesheets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My argument at the time was that, damnit I learned web design by using View Source and the way code was &lt;em&gt;rendered&lt;/em&gt; was important to me. Over time a few things happened: Browser inspection tools got better. View source gave way to more powerful dissection of front-end code built right into browsers. And I began to realize the massive benefits Sass would give us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It took a year (maybe longer) for me to come around. Not long after that, I wrote the book, &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://abookapart.com/products/sass-for-web-designers&quot;&gt;Sass For Web Designers&lt;/a&gt; . Which probably kills Rich. 😂&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The moral here: &lt;strong&gt;Try to identify when you’re blocking something that might ultimately help the business&lt;/strong&gt;—especially when it’s for reasons of just being stubborn or closed off from change. Another one that’s not easy! But once you unblock yourself and learn something new, then it’s time to…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;write-teach-and-share-what-yourelearning&quot;&gt;17. Write, teach, and share what you’re learning&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I owe my entire career to writing and sharing. It started with blogs. Blogs were the way we communicated ideas back in those early web days. I loved blogs because they were so empowering. I dropped out of college, had no formal training in much of anything, yet I could share my thoughts on a blog and reach most of the world. Magical.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so I starting writing. I wrote about what I was learning as I was learning it. It forced me to think about what I was learning in a different way, how to explain it to someone as green as I was. It turns out this is not only helpful for retaining knowledge about a subject, but it’s also a nice way for other folks to learn. It’s the way I learned from other people figuring it out as they went as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something to keep in mind is that &lt;strong&gt;you don’t need to be an expert to start teaching&lt;/strong&gt;. Everyone is figuring things out as they go. This became a recurring theme in the fifty-odd interviews I did on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://dribbble.com/overtime&quot;&gt;Overtime podcast&lt;/a&gt;. So many talented folks attribute teaching &lt;em&gt;while they were learning&lt;/em&gt; to helping their career. Start writing and sharing no matter what stage your career is at.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;dont-takefunding&quot;&gt;18. Don’t take funding&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have nothing against funding in general, but I’m happy Dribbble was (and is) a fully-bootstrapped company. There was a lot of interest over the years from venture capital firms, but we ultimately realized that taking on outside investors would’ve changed the trajectory of the business. We’d be on someone else’s timeline, with vastly different priorities. A return on that investment would be the singular target (naturally) and our product roadmap would likely need to change drastically to accommodate that. Whereas our priorities would always aim to align with the designers and the community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VC funding is great for some, just be aware of how that can adversely affect what you’re building and who you’re building it for before taking it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;take-care-of-yourselffirst&quot;&gt;19. Take care of yourself first&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a crucial one, and something I learned the hard way. I started having panic attacks in my early thirties. I’ve had anxiety disorder my whole life, though I wasn’t diagnosed until the panic attacks started getting worse. Over several years, I finally got the right treatments of medication and therapy and it was literally life-changing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anxiety is a medical condition—it’s biological. A chemical imbalance where our primitive “fight or flight” response kicks in at times it shouldn’t. It’s also a condition that’s often misunderstood by those that don’t experience it. But it needs to lose its stigma. It should be talked about more. Millions suffer from it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of my doctors described anxiety as a spectrum, where the older you get, the anxiety finds different ways to manifest itself and make daily life difficult. That changes over time. But understanding it is the first step toward living normally with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dealing with anxiety (or any health issue) when you’re juggling a business is an obvious challenge. Throw a difficult divorce and children into the mix and things can swirl well out of anyone’s control. Which brings me back to #1, where your choice in partner(s) becomes all the more important. Support and understanding from that partner can mean all the difference—and again I was very fortunate there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I bring all of this up because I wish it was discussed more out in the open. Take care of yourself first so that you can be a good leader for your team. Like when you’re on a plane and they tell you to secure your air mask before helping others. I hate flying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;knowing-when-to-letgo&quot;&gt;20. Knowing when to let go&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That goes for this lengthy article as well ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few years ago, Rich and I sold a majority stake of Dribbble to &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://www.tinycapital.com/&quot;&gt;Tiny&lt;/a&gt; . It was time to enlist help in areas we needed and enter a new phase for the company. A year later I went down to half time and focused primarily on growing the Overtime podcast. And now I’m finally letting go completely and retiring from the day-to-day. Dribbble is in excellent hands, with &lt;a href=&quot;http://zack415.com/&quot;&gt;Zack Onisko&lt;/a&gt; at the helm and an outstanding team that has now grown to 50 folks working remotely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not easy walking away from something you’ve spent 10 years worrying about. There are mixed emotions, but overall I’m ready for…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;whats-next&quot;&gt;What’s next?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I still have you (and yes it’s presumptuous of me to assume you’ve read this far) here’s what I’m going to do next:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://advencher.co/&quot;&gt;Advencher Supply Co.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The aforementioned passion side project. A place to experiment making physical goods. I’ll be putting a lot more energy into this and coupling that with the outside stuff I enjoy doing (boating, fly fishing, overlanding, photography). It’s a labor of love and I’m excited to devote more time to growing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Podcasting&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;I loved learning how to edit and produce a podcast. I really had no idea what I was doing (as usual) and learned an immense amount from the conversations I had with the community. I felt fortunate to be able to host Overtime and would love to create a new show on my own if I can find a new partner/sponsor to help me put it together. I’d love to continue having conversations with creative folks and digging into their stories, process, and life in general. Perhaps with a little adventure sprinkled in. Interested? &lt;a href=&quot;http://simplebits.com/&quot;&gt;Please get in touch&lt;/a&gt; :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Making logos&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;I love making logos and branding and might dip my toes back into this for other folks again after a little break. I’d especially love to work with smaller businesses and help elevate companies and orgs that need a boost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for listening! Keep sharing, keep learning, keep creating, keep encouraging and remember that everything is stardust, and stardust is everything. ✌️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;end&quot;&gt;•&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 14:06:39 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>doppp</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://simplebits.com/2019/06/25/dribbble.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>How Bad Are Things? (2015)</title>
<link>https://slatestarcodex.com/2015/12/24/how-bad-are-things/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://slatestarcodex.com/2015/12/24/how-bad-are-things/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;One “advantage” of working in psychiatry is getting a window into an otherwise invisible world of really miserable people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I work in a wealthy, mostly-white college town consistently ranked one of the best places to live in the country. If there’s anywhere that you might dare hope wasn’t filled to the brim with people living hopeless lives, it would be here. But that hope is not realized. Every day I get to listen to people describe problems that would seem overwrought if they were in a novel, and made-up if they were in a thinkpiece on The Fragmentation Of American Society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A perfectly average patient will be a 70 year old woman who used to live somewhere else but who moved her a few years ago after her husband died in order to be closer to family. She has some medical condition or other that prevents her from driving or walking around much, and the family she wanted to be closer to have their own issues, so she has no friends within five hundred miles and never leaves her house except to go to doctors’ appointments. She has one son, who is in jail, and one daughter, who married a drug addict. She also has one grandchild, her only remaining joy in the world – but her drug-addict son-in-law uses access to him as a bargaining chip to make her give him money from her rapidly-dwindling retirement account so he can buy drugs. When she can’t cough up enough quickly enough, he bans her from visiting or talking to the grandchild, plus he tells the grandchild it’s her fault. Her retirement savings are rapidly running out and she has no idea what she will do when they’re gone. Probably end up on the street. Also, her dog just died.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If my patients were to read the above paragraph, there are a handful who would sue me for breach of confidentiality, assuming I had just written down their medical history and gotten a couple of details like the number of children wrong. I didn’t. This is a &lt;em&gt;type&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s another. 60 year old guy who was abused as a child, still has visible scars. Ran off at age 15, got a job in a factory, married let’s say a waitress. There was some kind of explosion in his factory, he got PTSD, now he freaks out every time he steps within a hundred meters of a place where manufacturing is going on. Gradually stopped going outside because there were too many scary loud noises, his wife started yelling at him and telling him he was useless, he started beating his wife, put in jail for a year or two for domestic violence, came out, by this point his wife has run off with another man and took everything he owned with her. Moved in with an abusive uncle who is 80 years old and hates his guts, but the uncle needed a caretaker and the guy needed a place to live and they were each other’s only affordable option. Currently lives off disability payments, but the government keeps trying to cut them off, and he keeps having to spend what little he has on a lawyer to prevent them from taking even that away, but half the time he doesn’t make it to his lawyer appointments because he’s too nervous about going outside. Also he has chronic pain. Also he only sleeps two hours a night because of the nightmares, and he’s tired all the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(“You have the pill that fixes all of this, right, Doctor? The one they advertised on TV?”)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A while ago &lt;a href=&quot;https://slatestarcodex.com/2014/09/30/i-can-tolerate-anything-except-the-outgroup/&quot;&gt;I wrote about&lt;/a&gt; how strongly we filter for people who are like us intellectually and politically:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;25&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Gallup polls, about 46% of Americans are creationists. Not just in the sense of believing God helped guide evolution. I mean they think evolution is a vile atheist lie and God created humans exactly as they exist right now. That’s half the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I don’t have a single one of those people in my social circle. It’s not because I’m deliberately avoiding them; I’m pretty live-and-let-live politically, I wouldn’t ostracize someone just for some weird beliefs. And yet, even though I probably know about a hundred fifty people, I am pretty confident that not one of them is creationist. Odds of this happening by chance? 1/2^150 = 1/10^45 = approximately the chance of picking a particular atom if you are randomly selecting among all the atoms on Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About forty percent of Americans want to ban gay marriage. I think if I really stretch it, maybe ten of my top hundred fifty friends might fall into this group. This is less astronomically unlikely; the odds are a mere one to one hundred quintillion against.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People like to talk about social bubbles, but that doesn’t even begin to cover one hundred quintillion. The only metaphor that seems really appropriate is a bizarre dark matter parallel universe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since starting working in psychiatry, I have realized that we also filter for misery. I think a big part of this is sorting by social class. But it’s in a more subtle way than you might think. That first patient, the 70 year old, might on paper have more than the median income if her dead husband’s pension is high enough. I could even imagine the second patient getting a decent payout from his factory and being financially in the clear for a while. It’s more complicated than that – something to do with being the sort of person who ends up in these sorts of situations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have three non-mutually exclusive theories for this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1. The people who come to a psychiatrist are disproportionately the unhappiest and most disturbed. This is obviously true to some degree. But I got the same sort of people when I worked in general medicine and primary care. Even the people who come to a primary care doctor are going to be a little biased towards the sorts of conditions that produce or result from sickness, but people were still much worse off than I thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2. My ordinary life shields me from these people. I don’t live in an especially bad neighborhood, so I won’t meet the unhappiest people there. Unhappy people are really depressing, so their lives won’t be covered as much by newspapers and TV. And insofar as they stay in their homes all the time and never come out or talk to anyone else, that in itself is going to prevent me from meeting them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3. Or maybe many of the people I know are in fact this unhappy, but they never tell anyone except their psychiatrist all of the pieces necessary to put their life story together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If it were mostly (1), that would be pretty encouraging and mean I’m just biased toward seeing very unlucky people. If it were mostly (2) or (3), that would be pretty bad, and mean everyone else is biased toward not realizing how unlucky everybody else is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I made a short script based on the following information:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;– About 1% of people are &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_States_incarceration_rate&quot;&gt;in prison&lt;/a&gt; at any given time&lt;br/&gt;– About 2% of people are &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pewtrusts.org/en/about/news-room/press-releases/0001/01/01/one-in-31-us-adults-are-behind-bars-on-parole-or-probation&quot;&gt;on probation&lt;/a&gt;, which can actually be really limiting and unpleasant&lt;br/&gt;– About 1% of people are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.caregiver.org/selected-long-term-care-statistics&quot;&gt;in nursing homes or hospices&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;– About 2% of people have &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alz.org/facts/&quot;&gt;dementia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;– About 20% of people have &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.medicaldaily.com/stress-severe-pain-11-americans-suffer-chronic-pain-nih-states-347292&quot;&gt;chronic pain&lt;/a&gt;, though this &lt;a href=&quot;http://nationalpainreport.com/the-numbers-game-ii-how-many-americans-have-chronic-pain-8825066.html&quot;&gt;varies widely&lt;/a&gt; with the exact survey question, but we are not talking minor aches here. About two-thirds of people with chronic pain describe it as “constant”, and half of people describe it as “unbearable and excruciating”.&lt;br/&gt;– About 7% of people have &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nimh.nih.gov/health/statistics/prevalence/major-depression-among-adults.shtml&quot;&gt;depression&lt;/a&gt; in any given year&lt;br/&gt;– About 2% of people are &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.aafp.org/afp/2000/0215/p1059.html&quot;&gt;cognitively disabled&lt;/a&gt; aka mentally retarded&lt;br/&gt;– About 1% of people are &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.schizophrenia.com/szfacts.htm&quot;&gt;schizophrenic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;– About 20% of people are on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cnsnews.com/news/article/ali-meyer/food-stamp-beneficiaries-exceed-46000000-38-straight-months&quot;&gt;food stamps&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;– About 1% of people are &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.newdisability.com/wheelchairstatistics.htm&quot;&gt;wheelchair-bound&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;– About 7% of people are &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.niaaa.nih.gov/alcohol-health/overview-alcohol-consumption/alcohol-use-disorders&quot;&gt;alcoholic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;– About 0.5% of people are &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.forbes.com/sites/jacobsullum/2014/03/10/how-many-daily-heroin-users-are-there-in-the-u-s-somewhere-between-60000-and-1-million-maybe/&quot;&gt;chronic heroin users&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;– About 5% of people are &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.deptofnumbers.com/unemployment/us/&quot;&gt;unemployed&lt;/a&gt; as per the official definition which includes only those looking for jobs&lt;br/&gt;– About 3% of people are former workers now receiving &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ssa.gov/oact/STATS/dibStat.html&quot;&gt;disability payments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;– About 1% of people experience &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.clicktoempower.org/domestic-violence-facts&quot;&gt;domestic violence&lt;/a&gt; each year&lt;br/&gt;– About 10% of people were &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.victimsofcrime.org/media/reporting-on-child-sexual-abuse/child-sexual-abuse-statistics&quot;&gt;sexually abused as children&lt;/a&gt;, many of whom are still working through the trauma.&lt;br/&gt;– Difficult to get statistics, but possibly about 20% of people were physically abused as children, likewise.&lt;br/&gt;– About 9% of people (male and female) have been &lt;a href=&quot;https://rainn.org/get-information/statistics/sexual-assault-victims&quot;&gt;raped&lt;/a&gt; during their lifetime, likewise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These numbers might be inflated, since I took them from groups working on these problems and those groups have every incentive to make them sound as bad as possible. There’s also a really big problem where a lot of these are conditional upon one another – that is, a person in prison is not also in a nursing home, but a person who is unemployed is far more likely to be on food stamps. This will likely underestimate both the percent of people who have no problems at all, and the percent of people who have multiple problems at once.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, I ran &lt;a href=&quot;http://codepad.org/C8hvzTuf&quot;&gt;the script&lt;/a&gt; twenty times to simulate twenty different people, and here’s what I got (NP stands for “no problems”):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;01. Chronic pain&lt;br/&gt;02. Alcoholic&lt;br/&gt;03. Chronic pain&lt;br/&gt;04. NP&lt;br/&gt;05. NP&lt;br/&gt;06. Sexually molested as a child + suffering from domestic violence&lt;br/&gt;07. Unemployed&lt;br/&gt;08. Alcoholic&lt;br/&gt;09. NP&lt;br/&gt;10. NP&lt;br/&gt;11. NP&lt;br/&gt;12. Abused as a child&lt;br/&gt;13. NP&lt;br/&gt;14. Chronic pain&lt;br/&gt;15. NP&lt;br/&gt;16. Abused as a child + unemployed&lt;br/&gt;17. NP&lt;br/&gt;18. Alcoholic + on food stamps&lt;br/&gt;19. NP&lt;br/&gt;20. Clinically depressed&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the two problems mentioned above haven’t totally thrown off the calculations, this makes me think Psychiatrist-Me is getting a much better window into reality than Normal-Person-Me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And remember, this doesn’t count all of the problems that don’t fall into easily quantified categories, like “everyone hates them because they’re really ugly and annoying”. It doesn’t count things that I couldn’t find good statistics on, like “had a child die recently”. It doesn’t count things that I would have gotten in trouble for including, like “autistic” or “single mother”. It doesn’t count &lt;em&gt;a lot of things&lt;/em&gt;. Consider that the first patient I mentioned – the homebound seventy year old with no friends who’s being extorted by her drug addict son-in-law – would appear on this list as “NP”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The world is almost certainly a much worse place than any of us want to admit. And that’s &lt;em&gt;before you’ve even left America&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is part of why I get enraged whenever somebody on Tumblr says “People in Group X need to realize they have it really good”, or “You’re a Group X member, so stop pretending like you have real problems.” The town where I practice psychiatry is mostly white and mostly wealthy. That doesn’t save it. And whenever some online thinkpiece writer laughs about how good people in Group X have it and how hilarious it is that they sometimes complain about their lives, it &lt;em&gt;never fails&lt;/em&gt; that I have just gotten home from treating a member of Group X who attempted suicide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is also why I am wary whenever people start boasting about how much better we’re doing than back in the bad old days. That precise statement seems to in fact be true. But people have a bad tendency to follow it up with “And so now most people have it pretty good”. I don’t think we have any idea how many people do or don’t have it pretty good. Nobody who hasn’t read polls would intuitively guess that 40-something percent of Americans are young-Earth creationists. How should they know how many people have it pretty good or not?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think about all of the miserable people in my psychiatric clinic. Then I multiply by ten psychiatrists in my clinic. Then I multiply by ten similarly-sized clinics in my city. Then I multiply by a thousand such cities in the United States. Then I multiply by hundreds of countries in the world, and by that time my brain has mercifully stopped being able to visualize what that signifies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This wasn’t supposed to be a Christmas post, but it took me longer than I expected to write, so here we are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this wasn’t supposed to be advocating any particular response, but I was recently asked to plug &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.givingwhatwecan.org/get-involved/join/&quot;&gt;Giving What We Can’s pledge drive&lt;/a&gt;, and maybe one of the good responses to realizing how awful things are is committing to donate a little bit of what you’ve got to making them better.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 12:50:02 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>barry-cotter</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>How Bad Are Things?</og:title>
<og:url>https://slatestarcodex.com/2015/12/24/how-bad-are-things/</og:url>
<og:description>One “advantage” of working in psychiatry is getting a window into an otherwise invisible world of really miserable people. I work in a wealthy, mostly-white college town consistently ra…</og:description>
<og:image>https://slatestarcodex.com/wp-content/themes/two_column_pujugama/images/codex_spotlight.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://slatestarcodex.com/2015/12/24/how-bad-are-things/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>A 30th anniversary note to Prince of Persia fans</title>
<link>https://www.jordanmechner.com/prince-of-persia-30th-anniversary/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.jordanmechner.com/prince-of-persia-30th-anniversary/</guid>
<description>&lt;div readability=&quot;70.98997995992&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;A 30th anniversary note to Prince of Persia fans&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;time class=&quot;postdate&quot; datetime=&quot;2019-06-27&quot;&gt;⌚ June 27, 2019&lt;/time&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thirty years ago today, I was at my Apple II, crunching on a six-week deadline to finish Prince of Persia by mid-July to ship in September.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know this because I wrote it in my journal. If I hadn't, those details would have long since faded from my memory, along with the 6502 hex op codes I once knew by heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1989, I could never have imagined that Prince of Persia would last this long — much less have foreseen it being ported to a future generation of game consoles from the makers of the Walkman. (Or to the big screen by the producer of Beverly Hills Cop.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To all of you who've played, watched, and supported PoP over the years — thank you! I've been especially moved by the things you've shared about the ways PoP has touched your lives. Your kind and encouraging words have been an inspiration to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of you have asked when there will be a new PoP game (or movie, or TV series). If you feel that it's been a long time since the last one, you're not alone. I wish I had a magic dagger to accelerate the process — it would have been poetic to time a major game announcement with this 30th-anniversary year. But I'm only a small part of a bigger picture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is one PoP announcement I &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; make, and am happy to share with you. &lt;a href=&quot;https://press.stripe.com/&quot;&gt;Stripe Press&lt;/a&gt;, an imprint specializing in books about innovation and technological advancement, will publish a hardcover collector's edition of &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jordanmechner.com/backstage/journals/&quot; class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;The Making of Prince of Persia&lt;/a&gt;&quot; — my 1980s original game development journals, newly illustrated with notes, sketches, work-in-progress screen shots, and as many visual features as we have the bandwidth to add by our target &quot;gold master&quot; date of September 2019 (30 years after Apple II PoP signed out of Broderbund QA). Oh, and there'll be an audiobook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;What I cherish about books&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me as a kid who dreamed of creating mass entertainment, in the pre-internet days, when you still needed a printing press to make a book and a film lab to make a movie, the Apple II was a game-changer: a technological innovation that empowered every user to innovate. Suddenly, I didn't need adult permission (or funding) to tell a story of adventure that might reach thousands — and ultimately millions — of people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That direct connection between author and public is still possible today for small indie games — and for books. By contrast, making a major movie or AAA game requires millions of dollars and hundreds of people. It's a thrilling ride, and the rewards can be great, but by nature it's beyond the scope of what one person or even a tight-knit creative team can accomplish alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So it felt very much in the magical 8-bit spirit when Stripe's co-founder Patrick Collison emailed me to propose this book, and less than two months later, we're doing it. For me personally, in the midst of longer-term projects whose announcement is still a ways off, it's refreshing to add one whose timeline is reckoned in months rather than years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;42.114572333685&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2012, when the PoP source code disks I thought I'd lost turned up in my dad's closet, I discovered that an incredible retro-gaming fan and archivist community has been keeping the flame of early game development knowledge alive. The Internet Archive and Strong Museum of Play (which houses work materials and artifacts from my past projects) are already on board to help us make the collector's edition of &quot;The Making of Prince of Persia&quot; as feature-rich as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we move toward beta, we'll document and share our progress online via Facebook, Instagram and Twitter. With luck, we'll be able to bring boxes of printed hardcover books to PAX East in spring 2020 — 30 years after the PC release of Prince of Persia (which is the one most people remember). I hope to see many of you there in person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until then, here's a fateful time-capsule post (and photo) from the week PoP went alpha, thirty years ago. Reading it now, the drollest part is that I still thought (as usual) I was about two weeks from the finish line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then there's the mullet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;27&quot;&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;July 26, 1989&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Left a stack of disks three inches high on my desk for Brian. Eleven for sales, three for QA, plus seven more. Hope they work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I played the whole game straight through for the first time ever, start to finish, cheat keys turned off. Made it with seconds to spare (my hour ran out while I was fighting the Grand Vizier).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You know what? It was &lt;em&gt;fun!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's a level of tension generated when you know you can't cheat, which is completely absent from the normal playtesting I do. By the time that final battle rolled around, I had a solid hour invested, and damned if I was going to lose!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still a few bugs — two weeks of work, like I said — but it's a game, and a damn good one. I'm content. I'm ready to go river rafting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jordanmechner.com/images/articles/jordan-pop-july1989-large.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.jordanmechner.com/images/articles/jordan-pop-july1989.jpg&quot; class=&quot;illustration&quot; width=&quot;450&quot; height=&quot;642&quot; alt=&quot;July 1989 photograph of Jordan finishing work on the original Prince of Persia&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;metamain&quot;&gt;Join the anniversary celebration and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/jmechner/posts/10156025344966326&quot;&gt;tell us about your personal experiences&lt;/a&gt; with Prince of Persia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 12:26:02 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>michalbe</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.jordanmechner.com/prince-of-persia-30th-anniversary/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Using AWK and R to parse 25TB</title>
<link>https://livefreeordichotomize.com/2019/06/04/using_awk_and_r_to_parse_25tb/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://livefreeordichotomize.com/2019/06/04/using_awk_and_r_to_parse_25tb/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to read this post:&lt;/strong&gt; I sincerely apologize for how long and rambling the following text is. To speed up skimming of it for those who have better things to do with their time, I have started most sections with a &lt;span class=&quot;lesson_learned&quot;&gt;“Lesson learned”&lt;/span&gt; blurb that boils down the takeaway from the following text into a sentence or two.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Just show me the solution!&lt;/strong&gt; If you just want to see how I ended up solving the task jump to the section &lt;a href=&quot;https://livefreeordichotomize.com/2019/06/04/using_awk_and_r_to_parse_25tb/#getting-more-creative&quot;&gt;Getting More Creative&lt;/a&gt;, but I honestly think the failures are more interesting/valuable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;how-not-to-do-this&quot; readability=&quot;62.956622998544&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To appropriate a cliched quote:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn’t fail a thousand times, I just discovered a thousand ways &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; to parse lots of data into an easily query-able format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;the-first-attempt&quot; class=&quot;section level2&quot; readability=&quot;30.860569715142&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The first attempt&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lesson_learned&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lesson Learned:&lt;/strong&gt; There’s no cheap way to parse 25tb of data at once.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having taken a class at Vanderbilt titled ‘Advanced methods in Big Data’ I was sure I had this in the bag. &lt;label for=&quot;tufte-mn-&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot;&gt;⊕&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;tufte-mn-&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;marginnote&quot;&gt;Capital B capital D Big Data, so you know it’s serious.&lt;/span&gt;It would be maybe an hour or two of me setting up a Hive server to run over all our data and then calling it good. Since our data is stored on AWS S3 I used a service called &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/athena/&quot;&gt;Athena&lt;/a&gt; which allows you to run Hive SQL queries on your S3 data. Not only do you get to avoid setting/ spinning up a Hive cluster, you only pay for the data searched.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After pointing Athena to my data and its format I ran a few tests with queries like&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;sql&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;select * from intensityData limit 10;&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and got back results fast and well formed. I was set.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until we tried to use the data in real life….&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was asked to grab all the data for a SNP so we could test a model on it. I ran the query:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;sql&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;select * from intensityData 
where snp = 'rs123456';&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;… and I waited. Eight minutes and 4+ terabytes of data queried later I had my results. Athena charges you by data searched at the reasonable rate of $5 per TB. So this single query cost $20 and eight minutes. &lt;label for=&quot;tufte-mn-&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot;&gt;⊕&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;tufte-mn-&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;marginnote&quot;&gt;If we ever wanted to run a model over all the data we better be ready to wait roughly 38 years and pay $50 million.&lt;/span&gt; Clearly this wasn’t going to work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;this-should-be-a-walk-in-the-parquet&quot; class=&quot;section level2&quot; readability=&quot;24.576844955992&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;This should be a walk in the Parquet…&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lesson_learned&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lesson Learned:&lt;/strong&gt; Be careful with your Parquet file sizes and organization.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first attempt to remedy the situation was to convert all of the TSV’s to &lt;a href=&quot;https://Parquet.apache.org&quot;&gt;Parquet files&lt;/a&gt;. Parquet files are good for working with larger datasets because they store data in a ‘columnar’ fashion. Meaning each column is stored in its own section of memory/disk, unlike a text file with lines containing every column. This means to look for something you only have to read the necessary column. Also, they keep a record of the range of values by column for each file so if the value you’re looking for isn’t in the column range Spark doesn’t waste it’s time scanning through the file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ran a simple &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/glue/&quot;&gt;AWS Glue job&lt;/a&gt; to convert our TSVs to Parquet and hooked up the new Parquet files to Athena. This took only around five hours. However, when I ran a query it took just about the same amount of time and a tiny bit less money. This is because Spark in its attempt to optimize the job just unzipped a single TSV chunk and placed it in its own Parquet chunk. Because each chunk was big enough to contain multiple people’s full records, this meant that every file had every SNP in them and thus Spark had to open all of them to extract what we wanted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;label for=&quot;tufte-mn-&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot;&gt;⊕&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;tufte-mn-&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;marginnote&quot;&gt;Interestingly the default (and recomended) Parquet compression type: ‘snappy’ is not splitable. So each executor was still stuck with the task of uncompressing and loading an entire 3.5gig dataset.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://livefreeordichotomize.com/using_awk_and_r_to_parse_25tb/large_parquet_chunks.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;sorting-out-the-issue&quot; class=&quot;section level2&quot; readability=&quot;21.738095238095&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sorting out the issue&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lesson_learned&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lesson Learned:&lt;/strong&gt; Sorting is hard, especially when data is distributed.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought that I had the problem figured out now. All I needed to do was to sort the data on the SNP column instead of the individual. This would allow a given chunk of data to only have a few SNPs in it and Parquet’s smart only-open-if-values-in-range feature could shine. Unfortunately, sorting billions of rows of data distributed across a cluster is not a trivial task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot; readability=&quot;8.8850174216028&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Me taking algorithms class in college: “Ugh, no one cares about computational complexity of all these sorting algorithms”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Me trying to sort on a column in a 20TB &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/Spark?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#Spark&lt;/a&gt; table: “Why is this taking so long?” &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/DataScience?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#DataScience&lt;/a&gt; struggles.&lt;/p&gt;
— Nick Strayer (&lt;span class=&quot;citation&quot;&gt;@NicholasStrayer&lt;/span&gt;) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/NicholasStrayer/status/1105127759318319105?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;March 11, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;label for=&quot;tufte-mn-&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot;&gt;⊕&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;tufte-mn-&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;marginnote&quot;&gt;AWS doesn’t exactly want to give refunds for the cause ‘I am an absent minded graduate student.’&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After attempting to run this on Amazon’s glue it ran for 2 days and then crashed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;what-about-partitioning&quot; class=&quot;section level2&quot; readability=&quot;20.78531598513&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What about partitioning?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lesson_learned&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lesson Learned:&lt;/strong&gt; Partitions in Spark need to be balanced.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another idea I had was to partition the data into chromosomes. There are 23 of these (plus a few extra to account for mitochondrial DNA or unmapped regions). This would provide a way of cutting down the data into much more manageable chunks. By adding just a single line to the Spark export function in the glue script: &lt;code&gt;partition_by = &quot;chr&quot;&lt;/code&gt;, the data should be put into those buckets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;label for=&quot;tufte-mn-&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot;&gt;⊕&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;tufte-mn-&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;marginnote&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.prod-carehubs.net/n2/71b34990bba71dfd/uploads/2018/07/boldchromosomecellturquoise.png&quot; alt=&quot;Chromosome graphic&quot;/&gt; DNA is made up of multiple chunks called Chromosomes. Img via &lt;a href=&quot;https://kintalk.org/genetics-101/&quot;&gt;kintalk.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately things didn’t work out well. This is because the chromosomes are different sizes and thus have different amounts of data within them. This meant that the tasks Spark sent out to its workers were unbalanced and ran slowly due to some of the nodes finishing early and sitting idle. The jobs &lt;em&gt;did&lt;/em&gt; finish, however. But when querying for a single SNP the unbalance caused problems again. With SNPS in larger chromosomes (aka where we will actually want to get data) the cost was only improved ~10x. A lot but not enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;what-about-even-finer-partitioning&quot; class=&quot;section level2&quot; readability=&quot;16&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What about even finer partitioning?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lesson_learned&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lesson Learned:&lt;/strong&gt; Never, ever, try and make 2.5 million partitions.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to get crazy with my partitioning and partitioned on each SNP. This guaranteed that each partition would be equal in size. &lt;strong&gt;THIS WAS A BAD IDEA.&lt;/strong&gt; I used Glue and added the innocent line of &lt;code&gt;partition_by = 'snp'&lt;/code&gt;. The job started and ran. A day later I checked and noticed nothing had been written to S3 yet so I killed the job. Turns out Glue &lt;em&gt;was&lt;/em&gt; writing intermediate files to hidden S3 locations, and a lot of them, like 2 billion. This mistake ended up costing more than a thousand dollars and didn’t make my advisor happy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;partitioning-sorting&quot; class=&quot;section level2&quot; readability=&quot;28.095980311731&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Partitioning + Sorting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lesson_learned&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lesson Learned:&lt;/strong&gt; Sorting is still hard and so is tuning Spark.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last attempt in the partitioning era was to partition on chromosome and then sort each partition. In theory this would have made each query quicker because the desired SNP data would only reside in the ranges of a few of the Parquet chunks within a given region. Alas, it turns out sorting even the partitioned data was a lot of work. I ended up switching to EMR for a custom cluster, using 8 powerful instances (C5.4xl) and using Sparklyr to build a more flexible workflow…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;r&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;# Sparklyr snippet to partition by chr and sort w/in partition
# Join the raw data with the snp bins
raw_data
  group_by(chr) %&amp;gt;%
  arrange(Position) %&amp;gt;% 
  Spark_write_Parquet(
    path = DUMP_LOC,
    mode = 'overwrite',
    partition_by = c('chr')
  )&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;…but no mater what the job never finished. I tried all the tuning tricks: bumped up the memory allocated to each executor of the queries, used high ram node types, broadcasting variables, but it would always get around half way done then executors would slowly start failing till everything eventually ground to a halt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot; readability=&quot;3.0412371134021&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Update: so it begins. &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/agY4GU2ru5&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/agY4GU2ru5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
— Nick Strayer (&lt;span class=&quot;citation&quot;&gt;@NicholasStrayer&lt;/span&gt;) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/NicholasStrayer/status/1128703858610450434?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;May 15, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;getting-more-creative&quot; readability=&quot;170.77486910995&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lesson_learned&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lesson Learned:&lt;/strong&gt; Sometimes bespoke data needs bespoke solutions.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every SNP has a position value. This is an integer corresponding to how many bases along its chromosome it lies. This is a nice and natural method of organizing our data. The first thought I had was building partitions by regions of each chromosome. Aka (positions 1 - 2000, 2001 - 4000, etc). The problem is SNPs are not evenly distributed along their chromosomes, so the bins would be wildly different in size.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://livefreeordichotomize.com/using_awk_and_r_to_parse_25tb/uneven_snps.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The solution I came up with was to bin by position &lt;em&gt;rank&lt;/em&gt;. I ran a query on our already loaded data to get the list of the unique SNPs, their positions, and their chromosomes. I then sorted within each chromosome and bundled the SNPs into bins of a given size. E.g. 1000 SNPS. This gave me a mapping from SNP -&amp;gt; bin-in-chromosome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;label for=&quot;tufte-mn-&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot;&gt;⊕&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;tufte-mn-&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;marginnote&quot;&gt;I ended up using 75 SNPs per bin, I explain why later.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;r&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;snp_to_bin &amp;lt;- unique_snps %&amp;gt;% 
  group_by(chr) %&amp;gt;% 
  arrange(position) %&amp;gt;% 
  mutate(
    rank = 1:n()
    bin = floor(rank/snps_per_bin)
  ) %&amp;gt;% 
  ungroup()&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;first-attempt-with-spark&quot; class=&quot;section level2&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;First attempt with Spark&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lesson_learned&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lesson Learned:&lt;/strong&gt; Spark joining is fast, but partitioning is still expensive&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal was to read this small (2.5 million row) dataframe into Spark, join it with the raw data, and then partition on the newly added &lt;code&gt;bin&lt;/code&gt; column.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;r&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;# Join the raw data with the snp bins
data_w_bin &amp;lt;- raw_data %&amp;gt;%
  left_join(sdf_broadcast(snp_to_bin), by ='snp_name') %&amp;gt;%
  group_by(chr_bin) %&amp;gt;%
  arrange(Position) %&amp;gt;% 
  Spark_write_Parquet(
    path = DUMP_LOC,
    mode = 'overwrite',
    partition_by = c('chr_bin')
  )&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;label for=&quot;tufte-mn-&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot;&gt;⊕&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;tufte-mn-&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;marginnote&quot;&gt;Notice the use of &lt;code&gt;sdf_broadcast()&lt;/code&gt;, this lets Spark know it should send this dataframe to all nodes. It’s helpful when the data is small and needed for all tasks. Otherwise Spark tries to be clever and waits to distribute it till it needs it which can cause bottlenecks.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, things didn’t work out. Like the sorting attempt, the jobs would run for a while, finish the joining task, and then as the partitioning started executors would start crashing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;bringing-in-awk&quot; class=&quot;section level2&quot; readability=&quot;24.397590361446&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Bringing in AWK&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lesson_learned&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lesson Learned:&lt;/strong&gt; Don’t sleep on the basics. Someone probably solved your problem in the 80s.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Up to this point all my Spark failures were due to the data being shuffled around the cluster because it was starting all mixed up. Perhaps I could help it out with some preprocessing. I decided to try and split the raw text data on the chromosome column, that way I would be able to provide Spark with somewhat ‘pre-partitioned’ data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I stack overflow searched how to split by column value and found &lt;a href=&quot;https://unix.stackexchange.com/questions/114061/extract-data-from-a-file-and-place-in-different-files-based-on1-column-value&quot;&gt;this wonderful answer.&lt;/a&gt; Using AWK you can split a text file up by a column’s values by performing the writing in the script rather than sending results to &lt;code&gt;stdout&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wrote up a bash script to test this. I downloaded one of the gzipped tsv, then unzipped it using &lt;code&gt;gzip&lt;/code&gt;, piped that to &lt;code&gt;awk&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;gzip -dc path/to/chunk/file.gz |
awk -F '\t' \
'{print $1&quot;,...&quot;$30&quot;&amp;gt;&quot;chunked/&quot;$chr&quot;_chr&quot;$15&quot;.csv&quot;}'&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It worked!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;using-newly-parsed-data&quot; class=&quot;section level2&quot; readability=&quot;18&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Using newly parsed data&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lesson_learned&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lesson Learned:&lt;/strong&gt; Spark likes uncompressed data and does not like combining partitions.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that I had the data sitting in an unzipped (see splittable) and semi-organized format on S3 I could go back to Spark. Surprise – things didn’t workout again! It was very hard to accurately tell Spark how the data was partitioned and even when I did it seemed to like to split things into way too many partitions (like 95k), which then when I used &lt;code&gt;coalesce&lt;/code&gt; to reduce down to a reasonable number of partitions, ended up ruining the partitioning I had used. &lt;label for=&quot;tufte-mn-&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot;&gt;⊕&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;tufte-mn-&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;marginnote&quot;&gt;I am sure there is a way to fix this but I couldn’t find it over a couple days of looking.&lt;/span&gt; I did end up getting things to finish on Spark, it took a while however and my split Parquet files were not super tiny (~200KB) But the data was where it needed to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://livefreeordichotomize.com/using_awk_and_r_to_parse_25tb/uneven_small_partitions.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;photo_caption&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Too small and uneven, wonderful!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;testing-out-local-spark-queries&quot; class=&quot;section level2&quot; readability=&quot;27&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Testing out local Spark queries&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lesson_learned&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lesson Learned:&lt;/strong&gt; Spark is a lot of overhead for simple jobs.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the data loaded up into a reasonable format I could test out the speed. I setup an R script to spin up a local Spark server and then load a Spark dataframe from a given Parquet bins location. &lt;label for=&quot;tufte-mn-&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot;&gt;⊕&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;tufte-mn-&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;marginnote&quot;&gt;I tried loading all the data but couldn’t get Sparklyr to recognize the partitioning for some reason.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;r&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;sc &amp;lt;- Spark_connect(master = &quot;local&quot;)

desired_snp &amp;lt;- 'rs34771739'

# Start a timer
start_time &amp;lt;- Sys.time()

# Load the desired bin into Spark
intensity_data &amp;lt;- sc %&amp;gt;% 
  Spark_read_Parquet(
    name = 'intensity_data', 
    path = get_snp_location(desired_snp),
    memory = FALSE )

# Subset bin to snp and then collect to local
test_subset &amp;lt;- intensity_data %&amp;gt;% 
  filter(SNP_Name == desired_snp) %&amp;gt;% 
  collect()

print(Sys.time() - start_time)&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This took 29.415 seconds. Much better than before, but still not a great sign for mass testing of anything. In addition, I couldn’t try and speed it up by enabling caching because when I tried to cache the bin’s Spark dataframe in memory Spark always crashed, even when I gave it 50+ gigs of memory for a dataset that was at this point smaller than 15.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;back-to-awk&quot; class=&quot;section level2&quot; readability=&quot;58.123850398529&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Back to AWK&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lesson_learned&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lesson Learned:&lt;/strong&gt; Associative arrays in AWK are super powerful.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I knew I could do better. I remembered that I had read in this charming &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.grymoire.com/Unix/Awk.html&quot;&gt;AWK guide by Bruce Barnett&lt;/a&gt; about a cool feature in AWK called &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.grymoire.com/Unix/Awk.html#uh-22&quot;&gt;&quot;associative arrays’&lt;/a&gt;. These are essentially a key-value stores in AWK that for some reason had been given a different name and thus I never thought too much about. &lt;label for=&quot;tufte-mn-&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot;&gt;⊕&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;tufte-mn-&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;marginnote&quot;&gt;It was brought to my attention by &lt;a href=&quot;https://ro-che.info&quot;&gt;Roman Cheplyaka&lt;/a&gt; that the term ‘Associative Array’ is much older than ‘key-value store’. In fact, key-value store &lt;a href=&quot;https://books.google.com/ngrams/graph?content=key-value+store%2Cassociative+array&amp;amp;year_start=1800&amp;amp;year_end=2000&amp;amp;corpus=15&amp;amp;smoothing=3&amp;amp;share=&amp;amp;direct_url=t1%3B%2Cassociative%20array%3B%2Cc0#t1%3B%2Cassociative%20array%3B%2Cc0&quot;&gt;doesn’t even show up on google ngrams&lt;/a&gt; when you look for it, but associative array does! In addition, key-value stores are more often associated with database systems and thus a hashmap is really a more appropriate comparison here.&lt;/span&gt; I realized that I could use these associative arrays to perform the union between my SNP -&amp;gt; bin table and my raw data without using Spark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To do this I used the &lt;code&gt;BEGIN&lt;/code&gt; block in my AWK script. This is a block of code that gets run before any lines of data are fed into the main body of the script.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;join_data.awk&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;BEGIN {
  FS=&quot;,&quot;;
  batch_num=substr(chunk,7,1);
  chunk_id=substr(chunk,15,2);
  while(getline &amp;lt; &quot;snp_to_bin.csv&quot;) {bin[$1] = $2}
}
{
  print $0 &amp;gt; &quot;chunked/chr_&quot;chr&quot;_bin_&quot;bin[$1]&quot;_&quot;batch_num&quot;_&quot;chunk_id&quot;.csv&quot;
}&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;while(getline...)&lt;/code&gt; command loaded all the rows in from my bin csv and set the first column (the SNP name) as the key to the &lt;code&gt;bin&lt;/code&gt; associative array and the second value (the bin) to the value. Then, in the &lt;code&gt;{&lt;/code&gt; block &lt;code&gt;}&lt;/code&gt; that gets run on every line of the main file, each line is sent to an output file that was had a unique name based upon its bin: &lt;code&gt;..._bin_&quot;bin[$1]&quot;_...&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;label for=&quot;tufte-mn-&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot;&gt;⊕&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;tufte-mn-&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;marginnote&quot;&gt;The variables of &lt;code&gt;batch_num&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;chunk_id&lt;/code&gt; corresponded to data given by the pipeline that allowed me to avoid race conditions in my writing by making sure that every thread run by &lt;code&gt;parallel&lt;/code&gt; wrote to its own unique file.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because I had all the raw data split into chromosome folders from my previous AWK experiment I could now write another bash script to work through a chromosome at a time and send back the further partitioned data to S3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;DESIRED_CHR='13'

# Download chromosome data from s3 and split into bins
aws s3 ls $DATA_LOC |
awk '{print $4}' |
grep 'chr'$DESIRED_CHR'.csv' |
parallel &quot;echo 'reading {}'; aws s3 cp &quot;$DATA_LOC&quot;{} - | awk -v chr=\&quot;&quot;$DESIRED_CHR&quot;\&quot; -v chunk=\&quot;{}\&quot; -f split_on_chr_bin.awk&quot;

# Combine all the parallel process chunks to single files and upload to rds using R
ls chunked/ |
cut -d '_' -f 4 |
sort -u |
parallel &quot;echo 'zipping bin {}'; cat chunked/*_bin_{}_*.csv | ./upload_as_rds.R '$S3_DEST'/chr_'$DESIRED_CHR'_bin_{}.rds&quot;
rm chunked/*&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This script has two &lt;code&gt;parallel&lt;/code&gt; sections:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first one reads in every file containing data for the desired chromosome and divvies them up to multiple threads that spit their files into its representative bins. In order to prevent race conditions from the multiple threads writing to the same bin file, AWK is passed the name of the file which it uses to write to unique locations, e.g. &lt;code&gt;chr_10_bin_52_batch_2_aa.csv&lt;/code&gt; This results in a &lt;em&gt;ton&lt;/em&gt; of tiny files located on the disk (I used 1TB EBS volumes for this).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second &lt;code&gt;parallel&lt;/code&gt; pipeline goes through and merges every bin’s separate files into single csv’s with &lt;code&gt;cat&lt;/code&gt;, and sends them for export…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;div id=&quot;divvying-out-the-work&quot; class=&quot;section level2&quot; readability=&quot;70&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Divvying out the work&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lesson_learned&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lesson Learned:&lt;/strong&gt; Don’t try to hand optimize jobs, let the computer do it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that I had the workflow for a single chromosome working, I needed to process every chromosome’s data. I wanted to spin up multiple ec2 instances to convert all my data but I also didn’t want to have super unbalanced job loads (just like how Spark suffered from the unbalanced partitions). &lt;label for=&quot;tufte-mn-&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot;&gt;⊕&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;tufte-mn-&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;marginnote&quot;&gt;I also didn’t want to spin up a single instance for each chromosome, since there is a limit by default of 10 instances at a time for AWS accounts.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My solution was to write a brute force job optimization script using R….&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First I queried S3 to figure out how large each chromosome was in terms of storage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;r&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;library(aws.s3)
library(tidyverse)

chr_sizes &amp;lt;- get_bucket_df(
  bucket = '...', prefix = '...', max = Inf
) %&amp;gt;% 
  mutate(Size = as.numeric(Size)) %&amp;gt;% 
  filter(Size != 0) %&amp;gt;% 
  mutate(
    # Extract chromosome from the file name 
    chr = str_extract(Key, 'chr.{1,4}\\.csv') %&amp;gt;%
             str_remove_all('chr|\\.csv')
  ) %&amp;gt;% 
  group_by(chr) %&amp;gt;% 
  summarise(total_size = sum(Size)/1e+9) # Divide to get value in GB&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;# A tibble: 27 x 2
   chr   total_size
   &amp;lt;chr&amp;gt;      &amp;lt;dbl&amp;gt;
 1 0           163.
 2 1           967.
 3 10          541.
 4 11          611.
 5 12          542.
 6 13          364.
 7 14          375.
 8 15          372.
 9 16          434.
10 17          443.
# … with 17 more rows&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I wrote a function that would take this total size info, shuffle the order, and split into &lt;code&gt;num_jobs&lt;/code&gt; groups and report how variable the sizes of each job’s data was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;r&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;num_jobs &amp;lt;- 7
# How big would each job be if perfectly split?
job_size &amp;lt;- sum(chr_sizes$total_size)/7

shuffle_job &amp;lt;- function(i){
  chr_sizes %&amp;gt;%
    sample_frac() %&amp;gt;% 
    mutate(
      cum_size = cumsum(total_size),
      job_num = ceiling(cum_size/job_size)
    ) %&amp;gt;% 
    group_by(job_num) %&amp;gt;% 
    summarise(
      job_chrs = paste(chr, collapse = ','),
      total_job_size = sum(total_size)
    ) %&amp;gt;% 
    mutate(sd = sd(total_job_size)) %&amp;gt;% 
    nest(-sd)
}

shuffle_job(1)&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;# A tibble: 1 x 2
     sd data            
  &amp;lt;dbl&amp;gt; &amp;lt;list&amp;gt;          
1  153. &amp;lt;tibble [7 × 3]&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once this was setup I ran a thousand shuffles using purrr and picked the best one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;r&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;1:1000 %&amp;gt;% 
  map_df(shuffle_job) %&amp;gt;% 
  filter(sd == min(sd)) %&amp;gt;% 
  pull(data) %&amp;gt;% 
  pluck(1)&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This gave me a set of jobs that were all very close in size. All I had do do then was wrap my previous bash script in a big for loop… &lt;label for=&quot;tufte-mn-&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot;&gt;⊕&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;tufte-mn-&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;marginnote&quot;&gt;It took me ~10 mins to write this job optimization which was way less time than the inballance caused by my manual job creation would have added to the processing so I think I didn’t fall for premature optimization here.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;for DESIRED_CHR in &quot;16&quot; &quot;9&quot; &quot;7&quot; &quot;21&quot; &quot;MT&quot;
do
# Code for processing a single chromosome
fi&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;add a shutdown command at the end….&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;sudo shutdown -h now&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;… and I was off the the races. I used the AWS CLI to spin up a bunch of instances, passing them their job’s bash script via the &lt;code&gt;user_data&lt;/code&gt; option. They ran and then shutdown automatically so I didn’t pay for extra compute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;aws ec2 run-instances ...\
--tag-specifications &quot;ResourceType=instance,Tags=[{Key=Name,Value=&amp;lt;&amp;lt;job_name&amp;gt;&amp;gt;}]&quot; \
--user-data file://&amp;lt;&amp;lt;job_script_loc&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;packing-it-up&quot; readability=&quot;34.332116788321&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lesson_learned&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lesson Learned:&lt;/strong&gt; Keep API simple for your end users and flexible for you.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, the data was where and how I needed it. The last step was to simplify the process for using the data as much as possible for my lab members. I wanted to provide a simple API for querying. If in the future I did decide to switch from using &lt;code&gt;.rds&lt;/code&gt; to Parquet files I wanted to be able to make that my issue and not my lab mate’s. The way I decided to to this was an internal R package.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I built and documented a very simple package that contains just a few functions for accessing the data, centered around the function &lt;code&gt;get_snp&lt;/code&gt;. Additionally, I built a &lt;a href=&quot;https://pkgdown.r-lib.org&quot;&gt;pkgdown site&lt;/a&gt; so lab members could easily see examples/docs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://livefreeordichotomize.com/using_awk_and_r_to_parse_25tb/pkg_down.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;intelligent-caching.&quot; class=&quot;section level2&quot; readability=&quot;36&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Intelligent caching.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lesson_learned&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lesson Learned:&lt;/strong&gt; If your data is setup well, caching will be easy!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since one of the main workflows for these data was running the same model/ analysis across a bunch of SNPs at a time, I decided that I should use the binning to my advantage. When pulling the data down for a SNP, the entire bin’s data is kept and attached to the returned object. This means if a new query is run the old queries result’s can (potentially) be used to speed it up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;r&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;# Part of get_snp()
...
  # Test if our current snp data has the desired snp.
  already_have_snp &amp;lt;- desired_snp %in% prev_snp_results$snps_in_bin

  if(!already_have_snp){
    # Grab info on the bin of the desired snp
    snp_results &amp;lt;- get_snp_bin(desired_snp)

    # Download the snp's bin data
    snp_results$bin_data &amp;lt;- aws.s3::s3readRDS(object = snp_results$data_loc)
  } else {
    # The previous snp data contained the right bin so just use it
    snp_results &amp;lt;- prev_snp_results
  }
...&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;label for=&quot;tufte-mn-&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot;&gt;⊕&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;tufte-mn-&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;marginnote&quot;&gt;While building the package I ran a lot of benchmarks to compare the speed between different methods. I recomend it because sometimes the results went against my intuition. For instance, &lt;code&gt;dplyr::filter&lt;/code&gt; was much faster than using indexing based filtering for grabbing rows, but getting a single column from a filtered dataframe was much faster using indexing syntax.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice that the &lt;code&gt;prev_snp_results&lt;/code&gt; object contains the key &lt;code&gt;snps_in_bin&lt;/code&gt;. This is an array of all unique SNPs in the bin, allowing fast checking for if we already have the data from a previous query. It also makes it easy for the user to loop through all the SNPs in a bin using code like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;r&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;# Get bin-mates
snps_in_bin &amp;lt;- my_snp_results$snps_in_bin

for(current_snp in snps_in_bin){
  my_snp_results &amp;lt;- get_snp(current_snp, my_snp_results)
  # Do something with results 
}&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 11:51:48 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>markus_zhang</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://livefreeordichotomize.com/2019/06/04/using_awk_and_r_to_parse_25tb/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Simple Genius of Checklists</title>
<link>https://blog.nuclino.com/the-simple-genius-of-checklists-from-b-17-to-the-apollo-missions</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.nuclino.com/the-simple-genius-of-checklists-from-b-17-to-the-apollo-missions</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-medium&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.nuclino.com/files/cb7980a9-e85a-4b6a-a166-5354871054d4/steven-lindsey-flight-deck-checklists.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;steven-lindsey-flight-deck-checklists&quot; data-displaymode=&quot;medium&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“&lt;em&gt;Why do I love checklists? Because rather than letting my imagination run amok to my detriment, effective use of checklists allows me to direct my imagination to more productive purposes.&lt;/em&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— David Oberhettinger, the Chief Knowledge Officer of the Jet Propulsion Lab, NASA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The year is 1935, and the U.S. Army Air Corps is holding a competition for airplane manufacturers vying to secure a contract to build the military’s next long-range bomber.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boeing unveils their state-of-the-art airplane B-299, later known as the B-17 Flying Fortress. A stunning design, in perfect working order. The test pilots are experienced and well-trained. They add power for takeoff, become airborne...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then abruptly &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Accidents_and_incidents_involving_the_Boeing_B-17_Flying_Fortress&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;crash after climbing only a few hundred feet&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The crash wasn’t caused by a design flaw, but rather a pilot error. While the new bomber could fly faster and further than any other, it was also very complex to operate. The pilot had to keep track of four different engines, the wing flaps, the landing gear, and much more. Preoccupied, &lt;strong&gt;he simply&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boeing_B-17_Flying_Fortress&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;forgot to disengage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong&gt;a new locking mechanism&lt;/strong&gt; on the elevator and rudder controls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of making the pilots undergo further training, however, Boeing came up with a simple yet ingenious solution – &lt;strong&gt;a pilot checklist&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-medium&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.nuclino.com/files/0b7e5b0f-e91f-4ce6-a000-710c05257b57/b-17-bomber-pilot-checklist.png&quot; alt=&quot;b-17-bomber-pilot-checklist&quot; data-displaymode=&quot;medium&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It spelled out all the basic – even obvious – tasks that were needed to fly the plane successfully. It was almost stupidly simple. Armed with the checklist, the pilots went on to fly the B-17 1.8 million miles without a single accident. The Army ended up ordering over 13,000 units, which became one of the most recognizable heavy bombers of World War II.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lessons learned during the test flight of the B-17 bomber prototype put a start to a best practice that became an integral part of safety culture at NASA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Checklists proliferated to every corner of habitable environment of Apollo 11 and became what astronaut Michael Collins called the spacecraft’s “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.airspacemag.com/space/the-fourth-crewmember-37046329/&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;fourth crew member&lt;/a&gt;” – and, for all intents and purposes, its real commander.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-medium&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.nuclino.com/files/064eb918-528e-41b9-8c88-9f7a1d36ddf0/nasa-apollo-11-cuff-checklist.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;nasa-apollo-11-cuff-checklist&quot; data-displaymode=&quot;medium&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Checklists even covered their spacesuits, for example, the left gloves of Armstrong and Aldrin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Armed with the legendary pressurized-ink Fisher Space Pen, produced through a $1 million private R&amp;amp;D program, astronauts made regular updates to the procedures and kept their checklists up-to-date throughout their missions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ground personnel also had access to the crew's checklists, often annotating them with messages, jokes, their signatures – and whimsical 'Easter eggs'.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-medium&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.nuclino.com/files/5b8a6105-3da5-4b1e-a903-c74c72c9627d/apollo-12-cuff-checklist-snoopy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;apollo-12-cuff-checklist-snoopy&quot; data-displaymode=&quot;medium&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, the cuff checklists used by the Apollo 12 astronauts were adorned with Snoopy cartoons alongside &lt;a href=&quot;https://aphelis.net/seen-any-interesting-hills-valley-playmates-on-the-moon-1969/&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;black-and-white prints of Playboy models&lt;/a&gt;. Conrad and Bean later said that they hadn’t noticed the Playmates until well into their moonwalk – and thoroughly enjoyed them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-medium&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.nuclino.com/files/27571ae7-9d87-46a6-8ee2-0b65297a2887/apollo-11-checklist-playmate.png&quot; alt=&quot;apollo-11-checklist-playmate&quot; data-displaymode=&quot;medium&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Checklists continue to be widely used at NASA. “We use checklists in everything from procedures in system test plans to reminders on how to restore backups to our computer, says David Oberhettinger, the Chief Knowledge Officer of the Jet Propulsion Lab. “With so many risks that are 'unknown unknowns' in NASA programs and projects, checklists assure adherence to routine practice and help limit risk to the more novel elements of a mission.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But most of us don't fly spacecrafts, our work doesn't involve life-and-death decisions, and our dashboards don't have hundreds of buttons and switches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We do love our to-do lists, crossing off items with almost neurotic satisfaction. But process checklists and manuals? They seem dehumanizing and interfere with our creative work. Being forced to follow a checklist, especially for seemingly obvious and straightforward tasks that we've done a thousand times, feels redundant and even insulting. We should be trusted to do our job without having to waste our time repeatedly checking off boxes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The cognitive overload of the knowledge economy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So why do we fail so often? In his book &lt;a href=&quot;http://a-fwd.com/es=farstrblo068-21&amp;amp;it=farstrblo0a-21&amp;amp;fr=farstrblo08-21&amp;amp;de=farstrblo07-21&amp;amp;uk=farstrblo-21&amp;amp;ca=farst-20&amp;amp;com=farnamstreet-20&amp;amp;asin-es=0312430000&amp;amp;asin-it=0312430000&amp;amp;asin-fr=0312430000&amp;amp;asin-de=0312430000&amp;amp;asin-uk=0312430000&amp;amp;asin-ca=0312430000&amp;amp;asin-com=0312430000&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;The Checklist Manifesto: How to Get Things Right&lt;/a&gt;, Atul Gawande explains that there are two main factors that we have control over – ignorance and ineptitude. We fail because we either don't have the information to perform a task or, if we do have the information, we fail to apply that information consistently and correctly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-medium&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.nuclino.com/files/0e6569cc-3a4c-4cbd-acec-69e716c191a9/atul-gawande-checklist-manifesto.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;atul-gawande-checklist-manifesto&quot; data-displaymode=&quot;medium&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For most of history, we’ve failed because of ignorance. We had only a partial understanding of how things worked. In the modern age, however, we know more than ever before, and the information has never been so readily available. But the complexity of the problems we are solving on a daily basis has also increased exponentially.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's not that we are stupid or lack the aptitude – &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/science/science-news/12114150/Human-brain-can-store-4.7-billion-books-ten-times-more-than-originally-thought.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;human brains can hold up to 4.7 million books in their memory&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;The real problem is retrieving that information accurately and when we need it.&lt;/strong&gt; It's a problem of effort and attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where checklists come into play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The holy grail of checklists&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The checklist of all checklists may be &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2007/12/10/the-checklist&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;the one created by Dr. Peter Pronovost&lt;/a&gt; of the Johns Hopkins University School of Medicine. Having observed that intravenous lines used to deliver medication often became infected, resulting in thousands of deaths per year, Pronovost compiled a simple five-step checklist:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wash their hands with soap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clean the patient’s skin with chlorhexidine antiseptic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Put sterile drapes over the entire patient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wear a sterile mask, hat, gown and gloves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Put a sterile dressing over the catheter site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;The results were dramatic: &lt;strong&gt;the infection rate went from 11% to almost zero.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Michigan ICUs put the checklist into practice over a period of 18 months, line infections were virtually eliminated, saving about 1,500 lives and an estimated $175 million in hospital expenses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to The New Yorker, Pronovost's “work has already saved more lives than that of any laboratory scientist in the past decade”. In 2008, Time named Pronovost one of the 100 most influential people in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&quot;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/full/10.1002/bjs.11151&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;new study&lt;/a&gt;, published in April of 2019 in the British Journal of Surgery, offers further evidence of the transformative power of checklists. According to the study of 6.8 million surgical patients, since Scotland implemented the checklist in 2008, &lt;strong&gt;surgery mortality rates have dropped by 37%&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No amount of wisdom in a given field makes us immune to forgetfulness. Implementing a checklist lightens our cognitive load, frees up our attention and allows us to focus that hard-earned knowledge on higher level problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are just some of the reasons why we use checklists at Nuclino:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol readability=&quot;16.428171641791&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Checklists act as a check against our ego.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stupid simple stuff is often so obvious, that we feel that it’s not as important as the challenging and “sexy” work. But in reality, it’s often our most basic tasks that can spell the difference between success and disaster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Checklists free up our mental RAM.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though many scoff at checklists and see them as constraining, they can be liberating. We don’t have to bother remembering to do the basics because there’s a checklist for that. Offloading that need frees up the brain to concentrate on the important stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Checklists get stuff done.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s something about having a checklist that spurs people to get things done. Nothing like the dopamine rush that comes with checking something off! Here's one of the release checklists our own team created for the Nuclino desktop app update:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-medium&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.nuclino.com/files/1c01a2ee-059f-45d5-be06-e7bd13032aa6/nuclino-desktop-app-release-checklist.png&quot; alt=&quot;nuclino-desktop-app-release-checklist&quot; data-displaymode=&quot;medium&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Checklists help contain knowledge within our team.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Experts are known to hoard knowledge and know-how, whether intentionally or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what if they retire or get a new job? Sure, they could spend their last week meticulously documenting all of their workflows and processes for the next person to take over. But what if they get sick and have to leave abruptly? Or are the bridge-burning type and wouldn't want to bother?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;4.8967551622419&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Checklists save us time.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Often you can get things done quicker by doing things in a specific order. We try to work out the fastest route for every task and process, put it into a checklist, and stick to it. New team members get going faster as well. For example, here's the checklist we have created in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nuclino.com/&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Nuclino&lt;/a&gt; to onboard new team members:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-medium&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.nuclino.com/files/e3c6f35a-6bb5-4f91-be53-dd523e842d45/nuclino-employee-onboarding-checklist.png&quot; alt=&quot;nuclino-employee-onboarding-checklist&quot; data-displaymode=&quot;medium&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Our checklist for creating checklists&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Daniel Boorman, a veteran pilot working for Boeing and the technical lead for the development of the 787’s pilot system of checklists, has worked with the FBI, the World Health Organization, the American Society of Radiation Oncologists, and many more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rules that our own team follows when creating checklists were to a large extent inspired by his recommendations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol readability=&quot;13&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Investigate your failures.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We start every new checklist by looking for friction points in our routine. They become the basis for the checklist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Focus on the “stupid” stuff.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A checklist is not meant to be a comprehensive manual. We already know how to do our jobs, so we focus on the basic but essential stuff without trying to include and explain every detail. The shorter the checklist is, the better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keep it simple.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The look of the checklist matters as well. It should ideally fit on one page, be free of clutter and unnecessary color (an occasional emoji is a guilty pleasure we allow ourselves to indulge in 😉). It's best to settle on one simple and easily readable font – sans serif is best, according to Boorman, so we use Source Sans Pro at Nuclino.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Decide between a “DO-CONFIRM” or a “READ-DO” checklist.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the task requires extra precision, we go with a READ-DO checklist, meaning that we read and perform a task on the checklist before we move to the next task. Otherwise, we use a DO-CONFIRM checklist, performing the tasks from memory and then stopping to go through the checklist to verify everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;Checklists are unlikely to go out of fashion any time soon. As Erich Mahr, assistant chief pilot at Boeing says, “I don’t think the future will hold significant change to the concept of checklists. Technology may change the methodology, but the principle remains the same. It is by far the best tool to contain errors.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 10:44:15 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>zzaner</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.nuclino.com/the-simple-genius-of-checklists-from-b-17-to-the-apollo-missions</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>