<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Julian Assange arrested in London</title>
<link>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-47891737</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-47891737</guid>
<description>&lt;figure class=&quot;media-with-caption&quot; readability=&quot;-24&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;player-with-placeholder&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Media playback is unsupported on your device&lt;/p&gt;
      
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;figcaption class=&quot;media-with-caption__caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Media caption&lt;/span&gt;Video footage shows Julian Assange being dragged from the Ecuadorian embassy in London&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;story-body__introduction&quot;&gt;Wikileaks co-founder Julian Assange has been arrested at the Ecuadorian embassy in London.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Assange took refuge in the embassy in 2012 to avoid extradition to Sweden over a sexual assault case that has since been dropped.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At Westminster Magistrates' Court on Thursday he was found guilty of failing to surrender to the court.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He now faces US federal conspiracy charges related to one of the largest ever leaks of government secrets.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The UK will decide whether to extradite Assange, in response to allegations by the Department for Justice that he conspired with former US intelligence analyst Chelsea Manning to download four classified databases. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He faces up to five years in US prison if convicted on the charges of conspiracy to commit computer intrusion.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Assange's lawyer Jennifer Robinson said they would be fighting the extradition request. She said it set a &quot;dangerous precedent&quot; where any journalist could face US charges for &quot;publishing truthful information about the United States&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She said she had visited Assange in the police cells where he thanked supporters and said: &quot;I told you so.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Assange had predicted that he would face extradition to the US if he left the embassy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul class=&quot;story-body__unordered-list&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-11047811&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link&quot;&gt;Profile: Julian Assange&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-11949341&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link&quot;&gt;Timeline: Julian Assange saga&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;After his arrest, the 47-year-old was initially taken to a central London police station before appearing at Westminster Magistrates' Court. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dressed in a black suit and black polo shirt, he waved to the public gallery and gave a thumbs up. He pleaded not guilty to the 2012 charge of failing to surrender to the court.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The court heard that during his arrest at the embassy he had to be restrained and shouted: &quot;This is unlawful, I am not leaving.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finding him guilty, District Judge Michael Snow said Assange's behaviour was &quot;the behaviour of a narcissist who cannot get beyond his own selfish interest&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He sent him to Southwark Crown Court for sentencing, where he faces up to 12 months in prison.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape has-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
                 &lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image copyright&lt;/span&gt;
                 &lt;span class=&quot;story-image-copyright&quot;&gt;Reuters&lt;/span&gt;
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
            &lt;figcaption class=&quot;media-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image caption&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;media-caption__text&quot;&gt;
                    Assange gave a thumbs up as he was taken to Westminster Magistrates' Court in a police van
                &lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;Australian national Assange set up Wikileaks in 2006 with the aim of obtaining and publishing confidential documents and images. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The organisation hit the headlines four years later when it released footage of US soldiers killing civilians from a helicopter in Iraq. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Former US intelligence analyst Chelsea Manning was arrested in 2010 for disclosing more than 700,000 confidential documents, videos and diplomatic cables to the anti-secrecy website. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She said she only did so to spark debates about foreign policy, but US officials said the leak put lives at risk.   &lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape no-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
        &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;story-body__crosshead&quot;&gt;What are the US charges against Julian Assange?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The indictment, issued last year in the state of Virginia, alleges that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.justice.gov/opa/pr/wikileaks-founder-charged-computer-hacking-conspiracy&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link-external&quot;&gt;Mr Assange conspired in 2010 with former US Army intelligence analyst Chelsea Manning to access classified information on Department of Defense computers&lt;/a&gt;. He faces up to five years in jail.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Manning downloaded four databases from US departments and agencies between January and May 2010, the indictment says. This information, much of which was classified, was provided to Wikileaks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The US Justice Department described it as &quot;one of the largest compromises of classified information in the history of the United States&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cracking a password stored on the computers, the indictment alleges, would have allowed Manning to log on to them in such a way as to make it harder for investigators to determine the source of the disclosures. It is unclear whether the password was actually broken.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Correspondents say the narrowness of the charge seems intended to avoid falling foul of the US Constitution's First Amendment guarantee of freedom of the press.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape no-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
        &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;Assange had been in the Ecuadorian embassy in London since 2012, after seeking asylum there to avoid extradition to Sweden on a rape allegation. The investigation into the alleged rape, which he denied, was later dropped.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Scotland Yard said it was invited into the embassy by the ambassador, following the Ecuadorian government's withdrawal of asylum.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After his arrest for failing to surrender to the court, police said he had been further arrested on behalf of US authorities under an extradition warrant. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape has-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
                 &lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image copyright&lt;/span&gt;
                 &lt;span class=&quot;story-image-copyright&quot;&gt;Reuters&lt;/span&gt;
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
            &lt;figcaption class=&quot;media-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image caption&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;media-caption__text&quot;&gt;
                    Julian Assange outside the embassy in 2017
                &lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ecuadorian president Lenin Moreno said the country had &quot;reached its limit on the behaviour of Mr Assange&quot; after he intervened in the internal affairs of other states.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mr Moreno said: &quot;The most recent incident occurred in January 2019, when Wikileaks leaked Vatican documents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;This and other publications have confirmed the world's suspicion that Mr Assange is still linked to WikiLeaks and therefore involved in interfering in internal affairs of other states.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;His accusations against Assange also included blocking security cameras at the embassy, accessing security files and confronting guards.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mr Moreno said the British government had confirmed in writing that Assange &quot;would not be extradited to a country where he could face torture or the death penalty&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape no-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
        &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;It comes a day after Wikileaks said it had uncovered an extensive spying operation against its co-founder at the Ecuadorian embassy.   &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There has been a long-running dispute between the Ecuadorian authorities and Assange about what he was and was not allowed to do in the embassy. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul class=&quot;story-body__unordered-list&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-latin-america-46027963&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link&quot;&gt;Ecuador court throws out Assange lawsuit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;BBC diplomatic correspondent James Landale said that over the years they have removed his access to the internet and accused him of engaging in political activities - which is not allowed when claiming asylum.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He said: &quot;Precisely what has happened in the embassy is not clear - there has been claim and counter claim.&quot; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;story-body__crosshead&quot;&gt;'Dangerous precedent'&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Prime Minister Theresa May told the House of Commons: &quot;This goes to show that in the UK, no one is above the law.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Foreign Secretary Jeremy Hunt said the arrest was the result of &quot;years of careful diplomacy&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He said: &quot;We're not making any judgement about Julian Assange's innocence or guilt, that is for the courts to decide. But what is not acceptable is for someone to escape facing justice and he has tried to do that for a very long time.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Press freedom organisation Reporters Without Borders said that the UK should resist extradition, because it would &quot;set a dangerous precedent for journalists, whistleblowers, and other journalistic sources that the US may wish to pursue in the future&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The actress Pamela Anderson, who has visited the embassy to support Assange, said &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/pamfoundation/status/1116296488068571136&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link-external&quot;&gt;the arrest was a &quot;vile injustice&quot; that proved he was &quot;right all along&quot;&lt;/a&gt; about the threat of extradition.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Australia's Foreign Minister Marise Payne said he would continue to receive &quot;the usual consular support&quot; and that consular officers will try to visit him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr class=&quot;story-body__line&quot;/&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;story-body__crosshead&quot;&gt;Timeline: Julian Assange saga&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul class=&quot;story-body__unordered-list&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;August 2010&lt;/strong&gt; - The Swedish Prosecutor's Office first issues an arrest warrant for Assange. It says there are two separate allegations - one of rape and one of molestation. Assange says the claims are &quot;without basis&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;December 2010&lt;/strong&gt; - Assange is arrested in London and bailed at the second attempt  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;May 2012&lt;/strong&gt; - The UK's Supreme Court rules he should be extradited to Sweden to face questioning over the allegations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;June 2012&lt;/strong&gt; - Assange enters the Ecuadorean embassy in London&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;August 2012&lt;/strong&gt; - Ecuador grants asylum to Assange, saying there are fears his human rights might be violated if he is extradited&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;August 2015&lt;/strong&gt; - Swedish prosecutors drop their investigation into two allegations - one of sexual molestation and one of unlawful coercion because they have run out of time to question him. But he still faces the more serious accusation of rape.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;October 2015&lt;/strong&gt; - Metropolitan Police announces that officers will no longer be stationed outside the Ecuadorean embassy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;February 2016&lt;/strong&gt; - A UN panel rules that Assange has been &quot;arbitrarily detained&quot; by UK and Swedish authorities since 2010&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;May 2017 &lt;/strong&gt;- Sweden's director of public prosecutions announces that the rape investigation into Assange is being dropped&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;July 2018 &lt;/strong&gt;- The UK and Ecuador confirm they are holding ongoing talks over the fate of Assange&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;October 2018&lt;/strong&gt; - Assange is given a set of house rules at the Ecuadorean embassy in London. He then launches legal action against the government of Ecuador&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;December 2018&lt;/strong&gt; - Assange's lawyer rejects an agreement announced by Ecuador's president to see him leave the Ecuadorean embassy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;February 2019&lt;/strong&gt; - Australia grants Assange a new passport amid fears Ecuador may bring his asylum to an end&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;April 2019&lt;/strong&gt; - The Metropolitan Police arrests him for &quot;failing to surrender to the court&quot; over a warrant issued in 2012&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2019 09:37:56 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>kragniz</dc:creator>
<og:title>Wikileaks co-founder Julian Assange arrested</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>He faces extradition to the US for his alleged role in one of the largest leaks of government secrets.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.bbc.com/news/uk-47891737</og:url>
<og:image>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/images/ic/1024x576/p0766t2y.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-GB</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-47891737</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Katie Bouman, the computer scientist behind the first black hole image</title>
<link>https://www.bbc.com/news/science-environment-47891902</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bbc.com/news/science-environment-47891902</guid>
<description>&lt;figure class=&quot;media-with-caption&quot; readability=&quot;-24&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;player-with-placeholder&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img class=&quot;media-placeholder player-with-placeholder__image lead-video-placeholder&quot; src=&quot;https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/images/ic/720x405/p07654l1.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Media playback is unsupported on your device&lt;/p&gt;
      
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;figcaption class=&quot;media-with-caption__caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Media caption&lt;/span&gt;Katie Bouman designed an algorithm that made the image possible&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;story-body__introduction&quot;&gt;A 29-year-old computer scientist has earned plaudits worldwide for helping develop the algorithm that created the first-ever image of a black hole. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Katie Bouman led development of a computer program that made the breakthrough image possible.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The remarkable photo, showing a halo of dust and gas 500 million trillion km from Earth, was released on Wednesday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For Dr Bouman, its creation was the realisation of an endeavour previously thought impossible.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Excitedly bracing herself for the groundbreaking moment, Dr Bouman was pictured loading the image on her laptop.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Watching in disbelief as the first image I ever made of a black hole was in the process of being reconstructed,&quot; she wrote in the caption to the Facebook post.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She started making the algorithm three years ago while she was a graduate student at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There, she led the project, assisted by a team from MIT's Computer Science and Artificial Intelligence Laboratory, the Harvard-Smithsonian Center for Astrophysics and the MIT Haystack Observatory.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape no-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
        &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;The black hole image, captured by the Event Horizon Telescope (EHT) - a network of eight linked telescopes - was rendered by Dr Bouman's algorithm. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/p0765z1x&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link&quot;&gt;&quot;When we saw it for the first time, we were all in disbelief. It was quite spectacular,&quot;&lt;/a&gt; she told BBC Radio 5 live.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;We got really lucky with the weather... We got lucky in so many ways.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the hours after the photo's momentous release, Dr Bouman became an international sensation, with her name trending on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul class=&quot;story-body__unordered-list&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/science-environment-47873592&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link&quot;&gt;First ever black hole image released&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/av/science-environment-47884028/the-first-ever-picture-of-a-black-hole&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link&quot;&gt;WATCH: Picture 'a dream come true'&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dr Bouman was also hailed by MIT and the Smithsonian on social media.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;3 years ago MIT grad student Katie Bouman led the creation of a new algorithm to produce the first-ever image of a black hole,&quot; MIT's Computer Science &amp;amp; Artificial Intelligence Lab wrote. &quot;Today, that image was released.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape no-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
        &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;But Dr Bouman, now an assistant professor of computing and mathematical sciences at the California Institute of Technology, insisted the team that helped her deserves equal credit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The effort to capture the image, using telescopes in locations ranging from Antarctica to Chile, involved a team of more than 200 scientists. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;No one of us could've done it alone,&quot; she told CNN. &quot;It came together because of lots of different people from many different backgrounds.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;story-body__crosshead&quot;&gt;What do we know about the black hole?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul class=&quot;story-body__unordered-list&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;The black hole, which is &quot;unseeable&quot; to the naked eye, measures 40 billion km across, or three million times the size of the Earth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;It was scanned over a period of 10 days in the Messier 87 galaxy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;It is &quot;larger than the size of our entire Solar System&quot;, Prof Heino Falcke, of Radboud University in the Netherlands, who proposed the experiment, told the BBC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;story-body__crosshead&quot;&gt;How did her algorithm create the image?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Put simply, Dr Bouman and others developed a series of algorithms that converted telescopic data into the historic photo shared by the world's media. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In mathematics and computer science, an algorithm is a process or set of rules used to solve problems.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape has-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
                 &lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image copyright&lt;/span&gt;
                 &lt;span class=&quot;story-image-copyright&quot;&gt;Reuters&lt;/span&gt;
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
            &lt;figcaption class=&quot;media-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image caption&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;media-caption__text&quot;&gt;
                    The first ever photo of a black hole, taken using a global network of telescopes
                &lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;No single telescope is powerful enough to capture the black hole, so a network of eight was set up to so do using a technique called interferometry.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The data they captured was stored on hundreds of hard drives that were flown to central processing centres in Boston, US, and Bonn, Germany. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dr Bouman's method of processing this raw data was said to be instrumental in the creation of the striking image.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She spearheaded a testing process whereby multiple algorithms with &quot;different assumptions built into them&quot; attempted to recover a photo from the data.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape has-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
            &lt;figcaption class=&quot;media-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image caption&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;media-caption__text&quot;&gt;
                    The eventual EHT array will have 12 widely spaced participating radio facilities
                &lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape no-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
        &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;The results of the algorithms were then analysed by four separate teams to build confidence in the veracity of their findings.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;We're a melting pot of astronomers, physicists, mathematicians and engineers, and that's what it took to achieve something once thought impossible,&quot; Dr Bouman says. &lt;/p&gt;
            </description>
<pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2019 08:25:22 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>tigerlily</dc:creator>
<og:title>The woman behind first black hole image</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>Katie Bouman, 29, has earned plaudits for helping develop the algorithm that made the photo possible.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.bbc.com/news/science-environment-47891902</og:url>
<og:image>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/images/ic/1024x576/p07654l1.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bbc.com/news/science-environment-47891902</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Random Forests for Complete Beginners</title>
<link>https://victorzhou.com/blog/intro-to-random-forests/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://victorzhou.com/blog/intro-to-random-forests/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, most Machine Learning tutorials aren’t beginner-friendly enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last month, I wrote an &lt;a href=&quot;https://victorzhou.com/blog/intro-to-neural-networks/&quot;&gt;introduction to Neural Networks &lt;strong&gt;for complete beginners&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. This post will adopt the same strategy, meaning it again &lt;strong&gt;assumes ZERO prior knowledge of machine learning&lt;/strong&gt;. We’ll learn what Random Forests are and how they work from the ground up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ready? Let’s dive in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-decision-trees-&quot;&gt;1. Decision Trees 🌲&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Random Forest 🌲🌲🌲 is actually just a bunch of Decision Trees 🌲 bundled together (ohhhhh that’s why it’s called a &lt;em&gt;forest&lt;/em&gt;). We need to talk about trees before we can get into forests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look at the following dataset:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://victorzhou.com/media/random-forest-post/dataset.svg&quot;/&gt;The Dataset&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I told you that there was a new point with an &lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;xx&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; coordinate of &lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;11&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, what color do you think it’d be?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blue, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You just evaluated a decision tree in your head:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://victorzhou.com/media/random-forest-post/decision-tree.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s a simple decision tree with one &lt;strong&gt;decision node&lt;/strong&gt; that &lt;strong&gt;tests&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;x&amp;lt;2x &amp;lt; 2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mrel&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. If the test passes (&lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;x&amp;lt;2x &amp;lt; 2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mrel&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;), we take the left &lt;strong&gt;branch&lt;/strong&gt; and pick Blue. If the test fails (&lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;x≥2x \geq 2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mrel&quot;&gt;≥&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;), we take the right &lt;strong&gt;branch&lt;/strong&gt; and pick Green.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://victorzhou.com/media/random-forest-post/dataset-split.svg&quot;/&gt;The Dataset, split at x=2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Decision Trees are often used to answer that kind of question: given a &lt;strong&gt;labelled&lt;/strong&gt; dataset, how should we &lt;strong&gt;classify&lt;/strong&gt; new samples?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Labelled&lt;/strong&gt;: Our dataset is &lt;em&gt;labelled&lt;/em&gt; because each point has a &lt;strong&gt;class&lt;/strong&gt; (color): blue or green.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Classify&lt;/strong&gt;: To &lt;em&gt;classify&lt;/em&gt; a new datapoint is to assign a class (color) to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s a dataset that has 3 classes now instead of 2:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://victorzhou.com/media/random-forest-post/dataset2.svg&quot;/&gt;The Dataset v2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our old decision tree doesn’t work so well anymore. Given a new point &lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;(x,y)(x, y)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mopen&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mpunct&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;y&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mclose&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;If &lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;x≥2x \geq 2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mrel&quot;&gt;≥&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, we can still confidently classify it as green.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If &lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;x&amp;lt;2x &amp;lt; 2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mrel&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, we can’t immediately classify it as blue - it could be red, too.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;We need to add another &lt;strong&gt;decision node&lt;/strong&gt; to our decision tree:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://victorzhou.com/media/random-forest-post/decision-tree2.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://victorzhou.com/media/random-forest-post/dataset2-split.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pretty simple, right? That’s the basic idea behind decision trees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-training-a-decision-tree&quot;&gt;2. Training a Decision Tree&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s start training a decision tree! We’ll use the 3 class dataset again:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://victorzhou.com/media/random-forest-post/dataset2.svg&quot;/&gt;The Dataset v2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;21-training-a-decision-tree-the-root-node&quot;&gt;2.1 Training a Decision Tree: The Root Node&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our first task is to determine the root decision node in our tree. Which feature (&lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;xx&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; or &lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;yy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;y&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;) will it test on, and what will the test threshold be? For example, the root node in our tree from earlier used the &lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;xx&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; feature with a test threshold of &lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;22&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://victorzhou.com/media/random-forest-post/decision-tree2-root.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intuitively, we want a decision node that makes a “good” split, where “good” can be loosely defined as &lt;strong&gt;separating different classes as much as possible&lt;/strong&gt;. The root node above makes a “good” split: &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; the greens are on the right, and &lt;em&gt;no&lt;/em&gt; greens are on the left.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, our goal is now to pick a root node that gives us the “best” split possible. &lt;strong&gt;But how do we quantify how good a split is?&lt;/strong&gt; It’s complicated. I wrote &lt;a href=&quot;https://victorzhou.com/blog/gini-impurity/&quot;&gt;an entire blog post about one way to do this using a metric called Gini Impurity&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;← I recommend reading it right now&lt;/strong&gt; before you continue - we’ll be using those concepts later in this post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Welcome back!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;8.0913461538462&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully, you just read &lt;a href=&quot;https://victorzhou.com/blog/gini-impurity/&quot;&gt;my Gini Impurity post&lt;/a&gt;. If you didn’t, here’s a very short TL;DR: We can use Gini Impurity to calculate a value called &lt;strong&gt;Gini Gain&lt;/strong&gt; for any split. &lt;strong&gt;A better split has higher Gini Gain&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back to the problem of determining our root decision node. Now that we have a way to evaluate splits, all we have to do to is find the best split possible! For the sake of simplicity, we’re just going to &lt;strong&gt;try every possible split&lt;/strong&gt; and use the best one (the one with the highest Gini Gain). &lt;strong&gt;This is not the fastest way to find the best split&lt;/strong&gt;, but it is the easiest to understand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trying every split means trying&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Every feature (&lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;xx&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; or &lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;yy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;y&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All “unique” thresholds. &lt;strong&gt;We only need to try thresholds that produce different splits.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;For example, here are the thresholds we might select if we wanted to use the &lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;xx&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; coordinate:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://victorzhou.com/media/random-forest-post/dataset2-thresholds-x.svg&quot;/&gt;x Thresholds&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s do an example Gini Gain calculation for the &lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;x=0.4x = 0.4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mrel&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; split.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;Split&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Left Branch&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Right Branch&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;x=0.4x = 0.4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mrel&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;First, we calculate the Gini Impurity of the whole dataset:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;katex-display&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;Ginitial=∑i=13p(i)∗(1−p(i))=3∗(13∗23)=23\begin{aligned} G_{initial} &amp;amp;= \sum_{i=1}^3 p(i) * (1 - p(i)) \\ &amp;amp;= 3 * (\frac{1}{3} * \frac{2}{3}) \\ &amp;amp;= \boxed{\frac{2}{3}} \\ \end{aligned}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mtable&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;col-align-r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-t vlist-t2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;G&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;msupsub&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-t vlist-t2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sizing reset-size6 size3 mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault mtight&quot;&gt;i&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault mtight&quot;&gt;n&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault mtight&quot;&gt;i&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault mtight&quot;&gt;t&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault mtight&quot;&gt;i&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault mtight&quot;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault mtight&quot;&gt;l&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-s&quot;&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-s&quot;&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;col-align-l&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-t vlist-t2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mrel&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mop op-limits&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-t vlist-t2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sizing reset-size6 size3 mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault mtight&quot;&gt;i&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mrel mtight&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mtight&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mop op-symbol large-op&quot;&gt;∑&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sizing reset-size6 size3 mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mtight&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-s&quot;&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;p&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mopen&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;i&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mclose&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mbin&quot;&gt;∗&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mopen&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mbin&quot;&gt;−&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;p&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mopen&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;i&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mclose&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mclose&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mrel&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mbin&quot;&gt;∗&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mopen&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mfrac&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-t vlist-t2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-s&quot;&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mbin&quot;&gt;∗&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mfrac&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-t vlist-t2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-s&quot;&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mclose&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mrel&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-t vlist-t2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord boxpad&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mfrac&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-t vlist-t2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-s&quot;&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-s&quot;&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-s&quot;&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, we calculate the Gini Impurities of the two branches:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;katex-display&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;Gleft=0∗1+1∗0+0∗1=0G_{left} = 0 * 1 + 1 * 0 + 0 * 1 = \boxed{0}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;G&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;msupsub&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-t vlist-t2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sizing reset-size6 size3 mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault mtight&quot;&gt;l&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault mtight&quot;&gt;e&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault mtight&quot;&gt;f&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault mtight&quot;&gt;t&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-s&quot;&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mrel&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mbin&quot;&gt;∗&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mbin&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mbin&quot;&gt;∗&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mbin&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mbin&quot;&gt;∗&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mrel&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-t vlist-t2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord boxpad&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-s&quot;&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;katex-display&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;Gright=38∗58+28∗68+38∗58=2132\begin{aligned} G_{right} &amp;amp;= \frac{3}{8} * \frac{5}{8} + \frac{2}{8} * \frac{6}{8} + \frac{3}{8} * \frac{5}{8} \\ &amp;amp;= \boxed{\frac{21}{32}} \\ \end{aligned}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mtable&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;col-align-r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-t vlist-t2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;G&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;msupsub&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-t vlist-t2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sizing reset-size6 size3 mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault mtight&quot;&gt;r&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault mtight&quot;&gt;i&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault mtight&quot;&gt;g&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault mtight&quot;&gt;h&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault mtight&quot;&gt;t&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-s&quot;&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-s&quot;&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;col-align-l&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-t vlist-t2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mrel&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mfrac&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-t vlist-t2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-s&quot;&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mbin&quot;&gt;∗&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mfrac&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-t vlist-t2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-s&quot;&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mbin&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mfrac&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-t vlist-t2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-s&quot;&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mbin&quot;&gt;∗&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mfrac&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-t vlist-t2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;6&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-s&quot;&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mbin&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mfrac&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-t vlist-t2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-s&quot;&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mbin&quot;&gt;∗&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mfrac&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-t vlist-t2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-s&quot;&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mrel&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-t vlist-t2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord boxpad&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mfrac&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-t vlist-t2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-s&quot;&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-s&quot;&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-s&quot;&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, we calculate Gini Gain by subtracting the weighted branch impurities from the original impurity:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;katex-display&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;Gain=Ginitial−19Gleft−89Gright=23−19∗0−89∗2132=0.083\begin{aligned} \text{Gain} &amp;amp;= G_{initial} - \frac{1}{9} G_{left} - \frac{8}{9} G_{right} \\ &amp;amp;= \frac{2}{3} - \frac{1}{9} * 0 - \frac{8}{9} * \frac{21}{32} \\ &amp;amp;= \boxed{0.083} \\ \end{aligned}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mtable&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;col-align-r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-t vlist-t2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord text&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;Gain&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-s&quot;&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;col-align-l&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-t vlist-t2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mrel&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;G&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;msupsub&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-t vlist-t2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sizing reset-size6 size3 mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault mtight&quot;&gt;i&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault mtight&quot;&gt;n&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault mtight&quot;&gt;i&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault mtight&quot;&gt;t&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault mtight&quot;&gt;i&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault mtight&quot;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault mtight&quot;&gt;l&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-s&quot;&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mbin&quot;&gt;−&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mfrac&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-t vlist-t2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;9&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-s&quot;&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;G&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;msupsub&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-t vlist-t2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sizing reset-size6 size3 mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault mtight&quot;&gt;l&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault mtight&quot;&gt;e&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault mtight&quot;&gt;f&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault mtight&quot;&gt;t&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-s&quot;&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mbin&quot;&gt;−&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mfrac&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-t vlist-t2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;9&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-s&quot;&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;G&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;msupsub&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-t vlist-t2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sizing reset-size6 size3 mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault mtight&quot;&gt;r&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault mtight&quot;&gt;i&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault mtight&quot;&gt;g&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault mtight&quot;&gt;h&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault mtight&quot;&gt;t&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-s&quot;&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mrel&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mfrac&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-t vlist-t2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-s&quot;&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mbin&quot;&gt;−&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mfrac&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-t vlist-t2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;9&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-s&quot;&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mbin&quot;&gt;∗&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mbin&quot;&gt;−&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mfrac&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-t vlist-t2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;9&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-s&quot;&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mbin&quot;&gt;∗&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mfrac&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-t vlist-t2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-s&quot;&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mrel&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-t vlist-t2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord boxpad&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-s&quot;&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-s&quot;&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;5.0232558139535&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Confused about what just happened? I told you you should’ve read &lt;a href=&quot;https://victorzhou.com/blog/gini-impurity/&quot;&gt;my Gini Impurity post&lt;/a&gt;. It’ll explain all of this Gini stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can calculate Gini Gain for every possible split in the same way:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;Split&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Left Branch&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Right Branch&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Gini Gain&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;x=0.4x = 0.4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mrel&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;0.0830.083&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;x=0.8x = 0.8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mrel&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;0.0480.048&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;x=1.1x = 1.1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mrel&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;0.1330.133&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;x=1.3x = 1.3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mrel&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;0.2330.233&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;x=2x = 2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mrel&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;0.3330.333&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;x=2.4x = 2.4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mrel&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;0.1910.191&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;9&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;x=2.8x = 2.8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mrel&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;0.0830.083&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;y=0.8y = 0.8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;y&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mrel&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;0.0830.083&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;y=1.2y = 1.2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;y&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mrel&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;0.1110.111&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;y=1.8y = 1.8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;y&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mrel&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;0.2330.233&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;y=2.1y = 2.1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;y&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mrel&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;0.2330.233&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;y=2.4y = 2.4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;y&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mrel&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;0.1110.111&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;y=2.7y = 2.7&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;y&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mrel&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;7&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;0.0480.048&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;y=2.9y = 2.9&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;y&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mrel&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;9&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;0.0830.083&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://victorzhou.com/media/random-forest-post/dataset2-thresholds.svg&quot;/&gt;All Thresholds&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After trying all thresholds for both &lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;xx&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;yy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;y&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, we’ve found that the &lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;x=2x = 2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mrel&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; split has the highest Gini Gain, so we’ll make our root decision node use the &lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;xx&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; feature with a threshold of &lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;22&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. Here’s what we’ve got so far:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://victorzhou.com/media/random-forest-post/decision-tree2-build1.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making progress!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;22-training-a-decision-tree-the-second-node&quot;&gt;2.2: Training a Decision Tree: The Second Node&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time to make our second decision node. Let’s (arbitrarily) go to the left branch. &lt;strong&gt;We’re now only using the datapoints that would take the left branch&lt;/strong&gt; (i.e. the datapoints satisfying &lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;x&amp;lt;2x &amp;lt; 2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mrel&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;), specifically the 3 blues and 3 reds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To build our second decision node, &lt;strong&gt;we just do the same thing!&lt;/strong&gt; We try every possible split for the 6 datapoints we have and realize that &lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;y=2y = 2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;y&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mrel&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; is the best split. We make that into a decision node and now have this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://victorzhou.com/media/random-forest-post/decision-tree2-build2.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our decision tree is almost done…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;23-training-a-decision-tree-when-to-stop&quot;&gt;2.3 Training a Decision Tree: When to Stop?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s keep it going and try to make a third decision node. We’ll use the right branch from the root node this time. The only datapoints in that branch are the 3 greens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, we try all the possible splits, but they all&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Are equally good.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have a Gini Gain of 0 (the Gini Impurity was already 0 and can’t go any lower).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;It doesn’t makes sense to add a decision node here because doing so wouldn’t improve our decision tree. Thus, we’ll make this node a &lt;strong&gt;leaf node&lt;/strong&gt; and slap the Green label on it. This means that &lt;strong&gt;we’ll classify any datapoint that reaches this node as Green&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we continue to the 2 remaining nodes, the same thing will happen: we’ll make the bottom left node our Blue leaf node, and we’ll make the bottom right node our Red leaf node. That brings us to the final result:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://victorzhou.com/media/random-forest-post/decision-tree2.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Once all possible branches in our decision tree end in leaf nodes, we’re done.&lt;/strong&gt; We’ve trained a decision tree!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;3-random-forests-&quot;&gt;3. Random Forests 🌲🌳🌲🌳🌲&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re finally ready to talk about Random Forests. Remember what I said earlier?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Random Forest is actually just a bunch of Decision Trees bundled together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s true, but is a bit of a simplification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;31-bagging&quot;&gt;3.1 Bagging&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider the following algorithm to train a bundle of decision trees given a dataset of &lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;nn&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;n&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; points:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Sample, &lt;strong&gt;with replacement&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;nn&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;n&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; training examples from the dataset.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Train a decision tree on the &lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;nn&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;n&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; samples.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Repeat &lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;tt&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;t&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; times, for some &lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;tt&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;t&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;To make a prediction using this model with &lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;tt&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;t&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; trees, we aggregate the predictions from the individual decision trees and either&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Take the &lt;strong&gt;majority vote&lt;/strong&gt; if our trees produce class labels (like colors).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take the &lt;strong&gt;average&lt;/strong&gt; if our trees produce numerical values (e.g. when predicting temperature, price, etc).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;This technique is called &lt;strong&gt;bagging&lt;/strong&gt;, or &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bootstrap_aggregating&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;b&lt;/strong&gt;ootstrap &lt;strong&gt;agg&lt;/strong&gt;regating&lt;/a&gt;. The sampling with replacement we did is known as a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bootstrapping_(statistics)&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;bootstrap&lt;/a&gt; sample.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://victorzhou.com/media/random-forest-post/random-forest.svg&quot;/&gt;Bagged Decision Trees predicting color&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bagged decision trees are very close to Random Forests - they’re just missing one thing…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;32-bagging-→-random-forest&quot;&gt;3.2 Bagging → Random Forest&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bagged decision trees have only one parameter: &lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;tt&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;t&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, the number of trees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Random Forests have a second parameter that controls &lt;strong&gt;how many features to try when finding the best split&lt;/strong&gt;. Our simple dataset for this tutorial only had &lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;22&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; features (&lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;xx&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;yy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;y&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;), but most datasets will have far more (hundreds or thousands).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suppose we had a dataset with &lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;pp&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;p&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; features. Instead of trying all features every time we make a new decision node, we &lt;strong&gt;only try a subset of the features&lt;/strong&gt;, usually of size &lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;p\sqrt{p}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord sqrt&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-t vlist-t2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;svg-align&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;p&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-s&quot;&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; or &lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;p3\frac{p}{3}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mfrac&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-t vlist-t2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-r&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sizing reset-size6 size3 mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mtight&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sizing reset-size6 size3 mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mtight&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault mtight&quot;&gt;p&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vlist-s&quot;&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. We do this primarily to inject randomness that makes individual trees more unique and &lt;strong&gt;reduces correlation between trees&lt;/strong&gt;, which improves the forest’s performance overall. This technique is sometimes referred to as &lt;strong&gt;feature bagging&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;4-now-what&quot;&gt;4. Now What?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s a beginner’s introduction to Random Forests! A quick recap of what we did:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Introduced &lt;strong&gt;decision trees&lt;/strong&gt;, the building blocks of Random Forests.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learned how to train decision trees by iteratively making the best split possible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Defined &lt;a href=&quot;https://victorzhou.com/blog/gini-impurity/&quot;&gt;Gini Impurity&lt;/a&gt;, a metric used to quantify how “good” a split is.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Saw that &lt;strong&gt;a random forest = a bunch of decision trees.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understood how &lt;strong&gt;bagging&lt;/strong&gt; combines predictions from multiple trees.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learned that &lt;strong&gt;feature bagging&lt;/strong&gt; is the difference between bagged decision trees and a random forest.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;A few things you could do from here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That concludes this tutorial. I like &lt;a href=&quot;https://victorzhou.com/tag/machine-learning&quot;&gt;writing about Machine Learning&lt;/a&gt; (but also other topics), so &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://eepurl.com/gf8JCX&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;subscribe&lt;/a&gt; if you want to get notified about new posts.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2019 08:16:40 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>signa11</dc:creator>
<og:title>Random Forests for Complete Beginners - victorzhou.com</og:title>
<og:description>The definitive guide to Random Forests and Decision Trees.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:image>https://victorzhou.com/media/random-forest-post/random-forest.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://victorzhou.com/blog/intro-to-random-forests/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Japanese study uncovers protein that keeps skin youthful</title>
<link>https://www.japantimes.co.jp/news/2019/04/04/national/science-health/japanese-study-uncovers-protein-keeps-skin-youthful-helping-strong-cells-squeeze-weak/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.japantimes.co.jp/news/2019/04/04/national/science-health/japanese-study-uncovers-protein-keeps-skin-youthful-helping-strong-cells-squeeze-weak/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Beauty might only be skin deep, but for those wondering how to keep that skin young, Japanese scientists may have found an answer in the form of a protein that encourages cell competition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The prosaically named COL17A1 might not sound like a fountain of youth, but the new study suggests it does the heavy lifting when it comes to keeping skin intact and unimpaired.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The protein works by encouraging cell competition, a key process to maintain tissue fitness. That effectively “drives out” weaker cells while encouraging replication of stronger ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Damaged or stressed stem cells can be selectively eliminated by intact stem cells every day in our skin,” said research leader Emi Nishimura, a professor at Tokyo Medical and Dental University’s Stem Cell Biology department.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But aging results in a depletion of COL17A1, as do familiar enemies of youthful skin, like UV radiation and other stress factors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And when that happens, weaker cells replicate, leaving the skin thinner, more prone to damage and slower to heal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The research, published Thursday in the journal Nature, is based on investigations using mice tails, which share many of the same characteristics as human skin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After confirming the importance of COL17A1, the team decided to investigate whether they could stimulate the protein once it was depleted — effectively looking for compounds that could kick-start the anti-aging process in skin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They isolated two chemical compounds — Y27632 and apocynin — and tested both on skin cells, with positive results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Application of these drugs to full-thickness skin wounds significantly promoted wound repair,” the study said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two compounds point to ways of “facilitating skin regeneration and reducing skin aging,” the study added.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a review of the study commissioned by Nature, two professors from the University of Colorado said cell competition had previously only been studied extensively in fruit flies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The research “provides evidence that healthy cells in mammals can also efficiently repopulate adult tissues, replacing unfit or damaged cells,” wrote professors Ganna Bilousova and James DeGregori.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And they said the research offered “proof-of-principle” that the two chemical compounds could combat aging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Future studies are needed to determine the mechanisms of cell competition in other tissues, and to identify compounds capable of reversing aging in other organs,” they said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nishimura said that the work could eventually lead to products like creams or tablets that could stop skin deterioration and promote repair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We are going to collaborate with pharmaceutical or cosmetic companies for the clinical use of the chemicals,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She said additional research would investigate whether the same process might also be at work in other parts of the body that have so-called epithelial cells like skin does.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We are working on other epithelial organs as well to find out (whether) similar competition may underlie long-term tissue maintenance as well as organ aging,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;jtarticle_related&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;jtarticle_related_ttl&quot;&gt;LATEST NATIONAL STORIES&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2019 05:49:04 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>clouddrover</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Japanese study uncovers protein that keeps skin youthful, helping strong cells squeeze out the weak | The Japan Times</og:title>
<og:description>Beauty might only be skin deep, but for those wondering how to keep that skin young, Japanese scientists may have found an answer in the form of a protein</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.japantimes.co.jp/news/2019/04/04/national/science-health/japanese-study-uncovers-protein-keeps-skin-youthful-helping-strong-cells-squeeze-weak/</og:url>
<og:image>https://cdn.japantimes.2xx.jp/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/n-skin-a-20190405-870x580.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.japantimes.co.jp/news/2019/04/04/national/science-health/japanese-study-uncovers-protein-keeps-skin-youthful-helping-strong-cells-squeeze-weak/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Google AMP lowered our page speed, and there&amp;#039;s no choice but to use it</title>
<link>https://unlikekinds.com/article/google-amp-page-speed</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://unlikekinds.com/article/google-amp-page-speed</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;For those that don’t know, a very quick primer. AMP is a set of rules that publishers (typically news and analysis content providers) &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/search/docs/guides/mark-up-content&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;must abide by&lt;/a&gt; in order to appear in the “Top Stories” section of Google’s search results, a lucrative position at the top of the page. It’s also required for your content to appear as a “rich” result, meaning emphasized links with images, which can receive a lot more attention from users. AMP must be implemented by the publisher on their site, and it’s not trivial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google puts the onus on publishers to, effectively, rejig large tracts of their websites layout, content, and functionality, in return for preferential treatment. Google promotes AMP as a way to make websites faster. That’s supposed to be the primary benefit, and the reason Google is pushing AMP so forcefully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;amp-can-make-your-site-slower&quot;&gt;AMP can make your site slower&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We here at unlike kinds decided that we had to implement Google AMP. We have to be in the Top Stories section because otherwise we’re punted down the page and away from potential readers. We didn’t really want to; our site is already fast because we made it fast, largely with a combination of clever caching and minimal code. But hey, maybe AMP would speed things up. Maybe Google’s new future is bright.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It isn’t. According to Google’s own Page Speed Insights audit (which Google recommends to check your performance), the AMP version of articles got a performance score of 80. The non-AMP versions? 86. Mind you, the AMP versions are hobbled - unauthorised javascript interaction is forbidden by Google, so you can’t vote or comment in place - it’ll kick you to the full version of the page. This is the fruit of weeks of labour converting the site: a slower, less interactive, more clunky site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;google-doesnt-need-amp-to-rank-pages-by-speed&quot;&gt;Google doesn’t need AMP to rank pages by speed&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But maybe this humble publication is so darn well made, our coders’ abilities so incredible, that when you consider all the slow sites out there, the greater good is served by bringing all sites up to scratch, performance-wise, even if fast sites are forced to slow down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But &lt;a href=&quot;https://webmasters.googleblog.com/2018/01/using-page-speed-in-mobile-search.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Google already ranks websites by speed&lt;/a&gt;. This tells us that every crawled site’s performance is measured in some way that Google finds accurate enough to use for a site’s ranking - you know, the position on Google’s results that can literally mean the difference between a failed business and one that makes millions of dollars, that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/tjmccue/2018/07/30/seo-industry-approaching-80-billion-but-all-you-want-is-more-web-traffic/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;an $80 billion industry&lt;/a&gt; is built upon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So you’d imagine that Google’s existing page speed ranking could easily be used to limit which sites appear in the carousel. Anything with a performance score below an 80 could appear as a performance issue in Google Search Console, and the site demoted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But no, Google insists you build your website with their technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;amp-isnt-about-speed-its-about-control&quot;&gt;AMP isn’t about speed. It’s about control.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AMP is an open source project. That evokes images of open, honest, collaboration amongst equals. But that’s not what’s happening. For a start, anyone contributing to AMP is required to sign a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ampproject/meta/issues/3&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;contributor license agreement&lt;/a&gt; (CLA) for their code to be accepted into the project. The CLA requires that you “grant to Google and to recipients of software distributed by Google a perpetual, worldwide, non-exclusive, no-charge, royalty-free, irrevocable copyright license”. There’s also a clause for much the same regarding any patents. Note, you don’t grant these rights to the AMP Project, you grant them to Google. Google owns the code and patents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The issues on AMP’s GitHub page is littered with revolts. Most notorious was Google’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/02/13/amp-for-email-is-a-terrible-idea/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;attempt&lt;/a&gt; to co-opt email itself. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ampproject/amphtml/issues/13457&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;issue is full&lt;/a&gt; of non-Google developers in open revolt against Google’s power-grab, with users describing it as misguided and user-hostile, complete with frequent use of the thumbs-down emoji. Google’s response? They’ve labeled the issue Priority 2: “Soon” and “INTENT TO IMPLEMENT”, and are powering ahead regardless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then there’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ampproject/amphtml/issues/4555&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;users begging Google&lt;/a&gt; to allow them to use more than 50kb of CSS. Yes, most site’s CSS is bloated. But 50kb is an absurdly small, arbitrary limit. Stylesheets these days handle resets for normalising behaviour between browsers, grid systems so you can lay things out without resorting to murder-suicide, and responsive queries so that your site looks great on mobile and desktop (and tablet and landscape and Android and iPhone.) These essential components will take you a decent way to to the 50kb already. If you’re looking to create an advanced layout or something unique and attractive, you’re shit out of luck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google’s own websites and apps are infamously bloated with CSS and JavaScript creating advanced layouts and interactivity, so you can imagine they think interactive or uniquely designed websites are worth the kilobytes. But customizability is for them, not for you. Publishers are limited to a meagre set of bundled components. If you believe in a web that’s beautiful with distinctive websites full of personality, it’s like trying to make an intricate sculpture out out of Legos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an example, you’re limited to using Google’s lightbox implementation. This component won’t let you allow users to close it by tapping on the image itself, instead they have to tap a black area around the image. It goes against the conventions established by other sites on the web, so users will inevitably struggle with it, as it behaves in a way that they won’t expect. And if you want something really nice for users, like scrolling up to dismiss the lightbox? Google says no. No javascript. Only components. Want to add a dark mode button? Google says no.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the core of the problem. If you’re trying to build a brand with something unique or distinctive, Google forbids you. And let’s not forget, it’ll be served from a Google domain, further diminishing your brand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sure you can build 2 sites, one AMP, one non-AMP. But it won’t help. Instead you’ll confuse your users (and certainly not entice them) with links like “visit the full version of the site to comment”. Google even &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ampproject.org/docs/fundamentals/converting/discoverable&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;encourages publishers&lt;/a&gt; to make one version of their site. An AMP version. An internet where every publisher is using the same 30 components controlled by one company? No thanks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google’s in an incredible position of power. According to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/google-amp-gets-mixed-reviews-from-publishers-1477648838&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Wall Street Journal&lt;/a&gt;: Publishers who are critical of AMP were reluctant to speak publicly about their frustrations, or to remove their AMP content. One executive said he would not comment on the record for fear that Google might “turn some knob that hurts the company.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sure, there’s a technical steering committee. 3/7 of them are Google employees, and the others are platforms: Microsoft, Twitter, Pinterest, and Pantheon (a web host, for some reason) - not the people actually making the content. Not the publishers like the New York Times, just the gatekeepers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-can-google-do-this&quot;&gt;Why can Google do this?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because they own the web. The top positions on Google’s results pages are highly lucrative. If you want to build a business around a website, you need to be up there. If you’re publishing news, you need to be in that Top Stories section. You can’t rely on hits from DuckDuckGo or Bing, you need Google. They own the web as much as they own Android’s Play Store. But at least on mobile you’ve got the option of choosing iPhone. For the web? You don’t. It’s only Google.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&quot;https://unlikekinds.com/article/how-google-is-getting-between-readers-and-publishers&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;instant answers&lt;/a&gt; where users read content scraped from your site without visiting it, to Google assistant reading your site with barely a nod in your direction, to AMP with plain, samey sites served on different coloured paper, and from a Google domain no less, they want people to visit Google. Not your site. Your site just feeds Google. All these recent initiatives see users consuming your content without even visiting your domain, and in some cases, without seeing your ads or your pleas to subscribe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If Google’s users were all served by scraped content in Instant Answers and Assistant answers, and dull, non-interactive websites served from Google’s domain, publishers become nothing more than a dumb pipe. But unlike ISPs, no one’s paying them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 23:13:57 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>luu</dc:creator>
<og:title>Google AMP lowered our page speed, and there's no choice but to use it</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:image>https://i.imgur.com/XFnI26x.jpg</og:image>
<og:url>https://unlikekinds.com/article/google-amp-page-speed</og:url>
<og:description>Google’s AMP project is supposed to speed up your web site. But what do you do when it makes your site slower? Do publishers have a real choice about using it?</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://unlikekinds.com/article/google-amp-page-speed</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Is Anyone Listening to You on Alexa? A Global Team Reviews Audio</title>
<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-04-10/is-anyone-listening-to-you-on-alexa-a-global-team-reviews-audio</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-04-10/is-anyone-listening-to-you-on-alexa-a-global-team-reviews-audio</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-04-10/is-anyone-listening-to-you-on-alexa-a-global-team-reviews-audio&quot;&gt;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-04-10/is-anyone-listening-to-you-on-alexa-a-global-team-reviews-audio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19629513&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19629513&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 315&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 187&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 22:53:03 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>minimaxir</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bloomberg.com/tosv2.html?vid=&amp;uuid=0ebca7f0-5c73-11e9-bb89-8d832aa42d57&amp;url=L25ld3MvYXJ0aWNsZXMvMjAxOS0wNC0xMC9pcy1hbnlvbmUtbGlzdGVuaW5nLXRvLXlvdS1vbi1hbGV4YS1hLWdsb2JhbC10ZWFtLXJldmlld3MtYXVkaW8=</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>996, GitHub, and China&amp;#039;s digital workers rights awakening</title>
<link>https://chanind.github.io/china/2019/04/10/github-996-china-digital-workers-rights.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://chanind.github.io/china/2019/04/10/github-996-china-digital-workers-rights.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://chanind.github.io/assets/fist.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Tech workers of the world, unite!&quot; width=&quot;150px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In China’s tech sector a peculiar uprising has begun: workers are demanding to be treated fairly. Even more fascinating is that the medium by which this movement is taking shape is via a single &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/996icu/996.ICU&quot;&gt;Github repo&lt;/a&gt;, which at the time of writing has over &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/996icu/996.ICU&quot;&gt;200,000 stars&lt;/a&gt; making it one of Github’s most popular repos of all time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;China’s tech sector is notorious for treating workers like machines, with extremely long working hours being the norm. The phrase &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/996_working_hour_system&quot;&gt;996&lt;/a&gt; refers to 9am - 9pm, 6 days per week, and is an unspoken rule in a lot of Chinese tech companies. The CEO of Youzan, a large Chinese e-commerce company, seemingly didn’t get the memo about keeping 996 as an “unspoken” rule, and surprised his employees at their 2019 yearly company party by telling them Youzan is officially &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.zhihu.com/question/309428750&quot;&gt;switching to 996&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ironically, given that China is a communist country, workers’ rights movements and unions are extremely uncommon, so it’s refreshing to see tech workers using their collective power to push back against abusive employers. The 996 Github page maintains a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/996icu/996.ICU/tree/master/blacklist&quot;&gt;blacklist&lt;/a&gt; of tech companies that use 996 working hours, and a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/996icu/996.ICU/tree/master/whitelist&quot;&gt;whitelist&lt;/a&gt; of companies that have reasonable working hours, and encourages tech workers to quit their jobs if their employers insist on the abusive 996 work schedule. The repo also has an &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/996icu/996.ICU/blob/master/LICENSE&quot;&gt;anti-996 software license&lt;/a&gt; which projects can use which bans the software from being used by a 996 company. The license appears to be a modified MIT license with the addition of clauses restricting use by companies violating standard labor laws. The 996 website also points out that the 996 work-week is illegal under Chinese law, despite being so commonplace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the time of writing, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://996.icu&quot;&gt;996 website&lt;/a&gt; isn’t blocked in China, but greedy tech companies have decided to block it themselves. Tencent’s Wechat refuses to open the site, as does Alibaba’s UC Browser and Qihoo’s 360 browser. It seems Chinese tech companies don’t want their employees getting the idea that they should be treated fairly. Given the popularity of the 996 repo, though, it seems that the word is getting out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;tech-workers-of-the-world-unite&quot;&gt;Tech workers of the world, unite!&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 22:45:50 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>chanind</dc:creator>
<og:title>996, Github, and China’s Digital Workers Rights Awakening</og:title>
<og:description>Javascript, Python, DevOps, and China</og:description>
<og:url>https://chanind.github.io/china/2019/04/10/github-996-china-digital-workers-rights.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://chanind.github.io/china/2019/04/10/github-996-china-digital-workers-rights.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>JQuery 3.4.0 Released</title>
<link>http://blog.jquery.com/2019/04/10/jquery-3-4-0-released/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://blog.jquery.com/2019/04/10/jquery-3-4-0-released/</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;entry-posted&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sep&quot;&gt;Posted on&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.jquery.com/2019/04/10/jquery-3-4-0-released/&quot; title=&quot;2:54 pm&quot; rel=&quot;bookmark&quot;&gt;&lt;time class=&quot;entry-date&quot; datetime=&quot;2019-04-10T14:54:43-05:00&quot; pubdate=&quot;&quot;&gt;April 10, 2019&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;by-author&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sep&quot;&gt;by&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;author vcard&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;url fn n&quot; href=&quot;http://blog.jquery.com/author/timmywil/&quot; title=&quot;View all posts by Timmy Willison&quot; rel=&quot;author&quot;&gt;Timmy Willison&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;jQuery has a new release! It’s been a while since our last release, but we expect this to be the last minor release in the 3.x branch, and then we will move on to the overhaul that will be jQuery 4.0. But before we get to 4.0, we’re excited to share the bug fixes and improvements included in jQuery 3.4.0. Here are some of the highlights:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Performance improvement in &lt;code&gt;.width&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;.height&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When getting and setting dimensions, there were certain cases where this could cause layout thrashing, which basically means that the browser calculated layout more times than necessary. We fixed this in all browsers except IE, where it can’t be avoided.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;code&gt;nonce&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;nomodule&lt;/code&gt; support&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To support adding script elements through methods like .html and .append, jQuery separates them and appends new script tags to load and execute the remote content. During this process, attributes such as &lt;code&gt;nonce&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;nomodule&lt;/code&gt; were ignored, but jQuery 3.4.0 now hangs onto them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Radio elements: expected state in event handlers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had already fixed the same issue with checkboxes, but accidentally left out radio inputs. In the following example, &lt;code&gt;true&lt;/code&gt; was logged the first time the element was clicked. We fixed it so that the &lt;code&gt;checked&lt;/code&gt; property is updated before the event handler is executed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Example&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;wp-block-code&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;var $radios = jQuery(&quot;.example&quot;);
var $firstRadio = $radios.first();
var firstCheckedState = $firstRadio.prop(&quot;checked&quot;);
$radio.on(&quot;click&quot;, function() {
  // true in &amp;lt;3.4.0
  console.log($firstRadio.prop(&quot;checked&quot;) === firstCheckedState);
});
$radios.eq(1).click();&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Minor vulnerability fix: Object.prototype pollution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;jQuery 3.4.0 includes a fix for some unintended behavior when using &lt;code&gt;jQuery.extend(true, {}, ...)&lt;/code&gt;. If an unsanitized source object contained an enumerable &lt;code&gt;__proto__&lt;/code&gt; property, it could extend the native Object.prototype. This fix is included in jQuery 3.4.0, but &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/DanielRuf/snyk-js-jquery-174006?files=1&quot;&gt;patch diffs&lt;/a&gt; exist to patch previous jQuery versions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Example&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;wp-block-code&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;jQuery.extend(true, {},
  JSON.parse('{&quot;__proto__&quot;: {&quot;test&quot;: true}}')
);
console.log( &quot;test&quot; in {} ); // true&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that while jQuery does its best to protect users from security vulnerabilities, jQuery is a DOM manipulation library that will generally do what you tell it to do. In this case, the behavior was likely unexpected, so &lt;code&gt;jQuery.extend&lt;/code&gt; will no longer write any properties named &lt;code&gt;__proto__&lt;/code&gt;. But guards such as this one are not replacements for good security practices such as user input sanitization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Deprecating positional selectors and the sunset of Sizzle&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The basic API of jQuery is to select something and then do something with what was selected. Sizzle, the selector engine in jQuery, handles the first half. It’s been a fast and efficient little engine that has paved the way for native selector APIs like &lt;code&gt;querySelectorAll&lt;/code&gt; and additional native JavaScript and CSS selectors. Now that many of these selectors have made their way into modern browsers, it’s almost time to say goodbye to Sizzle. But in order to remove Sizzle in jQuery 4.0, we will also need to remove what we refer to as positional selectors, which are non-standard selectors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Specifically, jQuery 3.4.0 is deprecating &lt;code&gt;:first&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;:last&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;:eq&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;:even&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;:odd&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;:lt&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;:gt&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;:nth&lt;/code&gt;. When we remove Sizzle, we’ll replace it with a small wrapper around &lt;code&gt;querySelectorAll&lt;/code&gt;, and it would be almost impossible to reimplement these selectors without a larger selector engine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We think this trade-off is worth it. Keep in mind we will still support the positional methods, such as &lt;code&gt;.first&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;.last&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;.eq&lt;/code&gt;. Anything you can do with positional selectors, you can do with positional methods instead. They perform better anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Upgrading&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There should be no compatibility issues if upgrading from jQuery 3.0+. If you haven’t yet upgraded to jQuery 3+, please have a look at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://jquery.com/upgrade-guide/3.0/&quot;&gt;3.0 Upgrade Guide&lt;/a&gt;. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jquery/jquery-migrate#migrate-older-jquery-code-to-jquery-30&quot;&gt;jQuery Migrate 3.0 plugin&lt;/a&gt; will help you to identify compatibility issues in your code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please try out this new release and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jquery/jquery/issues&quot;&gt;let us know about any issues you experienced&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Download&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can get the files from the jQuery CDN, or link to them directly:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://code.jquery.com/jquery-3.4.0.js&quot;&gt;https://code.jquery.com/jquery-3.4.0.js&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://code.jquery.com/jquery-3.4.0.min.js&quot;&gt;https://code.jquery.com/jquery-3.4.0.min.js&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also get this release from npm:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;npm install jquery@3.4.0&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Slim build&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you don’t need ajax, or you prefer to use one of the many standalone libraries that focus on ajax requests. And often it is simpler to use a combination of CSS and class manipulation for web animations. Along with the regular version of jQuery that includes the ajax and effects modules, we’ve released a “slim” version that excludes these modules. The size of jQuery is very rarely a load performance concern these days, but the slim build is about 6k gzipped bytes smaller than the regular version. These files are also available in the npm package and on the CDN:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://code.jquery.com/jquery-3.4.0.slim.js&quot;&gt;https://code.jquery.com/jquery-3.4.0.slim.js&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://code.jquery.com/jquery-3.4.0.slim.min.js&quot;&gt;https://code.jquery.com/jquery-3.4.0.slim.min.js&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These updates are already available as the current versions on npm and Bower. Information on all the ways to get jQuery is available at &lt;a href=&quot;https://jquery.com/download/&quot;&gt;https://jquery.com/download/&lt;/a&gt;. Public CDNs receive their copies today, please give them a few days to post the files. If you’re anxious to get a quick start, use the files on our CDN until they have a chance to update.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Thanks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you to all of you who participated in this release by submitting patches, reporting bugs, or testing, including &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/abnud1&quot;&gt;abnud1&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jbedard&quot;&gt;Jason Bedard&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/buddh4&quot;&gt;buddh4&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kborchers&quot;&gt;Kris Borchers&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Andrei15193&quot;&gt;Andrei Fangli&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/markelog&quot;&gt;Oleg Gaidarenko&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/gibson042&quot;&gt;Richard Gibson&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mgol&quot;&gt;Michal Golebiowski-Owczarek&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/marjakh&quot;&gt;Marja Hölttä&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/dmethvin&quot;&gt;Dave Methvin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/edg2s&quot;&gt;Ed S&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/emibloque&quot;&gt;Luis Emilio Velasco Sanchez&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/SaptakS&quot;&gt;Saptak Sengupta&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tmybr11&quot;&gt;tmybr11&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/enbo&quot;&gt;Bert Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, and the whole jQuery team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Changelog&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GitHub changelog:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jquery/jquery/issues?q=is%3Aissue+milestone%3A3.4.0+is%3Aclosed&quot;&gt;Issues fixed in 3.4.0&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jquery/jquery/compare/3.3.1..3.4.0&quot;&gt;All changes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Ajax&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Core&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Use isAttached to check for attachment of element (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jquery/jquery/commit/662083ed7bfea6bad5f9cd4060dab77c1f32aacd&quot;&gt;662083ed&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tiny efficiency fix to jQuery.extend / jQuery.fn.extend (#4246) (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jquery/jquery/issues/4245&quot;&gt;#4245&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jquery/jquery/commit/4ffb1df8e4738eb86bde429ec20efc7394e5e497&quot;&gt;4ffb1df8&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Preserve CSP nonce on scripts with src attribute in DOM manipulation (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jquery/jquery/issues/4323&quot;&gt;#4323&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jquery/jquery/commit/005040379d8b64aacbe54941d878efa6e86df1cc&quot;&gt;00504037&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Preserve CSP nonce on scripts in DOM manipulation (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jquery/jquery/issues/3541&quot;&gt;#3541&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jquery/jquery/commit/c7c2855ed13f23322c4064407c1ed84561b95738&quot;&gt;c7c2855e&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support passing nonce through jQuery.globalEval (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jquery/jquery/issues/4278&quot;&gt;#4278&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jquery/jquery/commit/5bdc85b82b84e5459462ddad9002f22d1ce74f21&quot;&gt;5bdc85b8&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recognize Shadow DOM in attachment checks (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jquery/jquery/issues/3504&quot;&gt;#3504&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jquery/jquery/commit/9b77def560212d12fef2d0b9c12aa50727e3e5d7&quot;&gt;9b77def5&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prevent Object.prototype pollution for $.extend( true, … ) (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jquery/jquery/commit/753d591aea698e57d6db58c9f722cd0808619b1b&quot;&gt;753d591a&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;CSS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Ensure camel- vs kebab-cased names are not collapsed for CSS vars (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jquery/jquery/commit/f8c1e9020c8fd0f0bb83019bfb12e9a7099599b2&quot;&gt;f8c1e902&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avoid filling jQuery.cssProps (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jquery/jquery/issues/3986&quot;&gt;#3986&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jquery/jquery/commit/2b5f5d5e90b37f4a735738a6d0b6f22affbea340&quot;&gt;2b5f5d5e&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Correctly detect scrollbox support with non-default zoom (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jquery/jquery/issues/4029&quot;&gt;#4029&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jquery/jquery/commit/821bf34353a6baf97f7944379a6459afb16badae&quot;&gt;821bf343&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t auto-append “px” to CSS variables (#4064) (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jquery/jquery/issues/4063&quot;&gt;#4063&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jquery/jquery/commit/75b77b4873abf9025b6ba60dec80aedd29df2bdd&quot;&gt;75b77b48&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Skip the px-appending logic for animations of non-element props (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jquery/jquery/commit/f5e36bd8f2c2b28231bbed926c6c3dead94db545&quot;&gt;f5e36bd8&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avoid forcing a reflow in width/height getters unless necessary (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jquery/jquery/issues/4322&quot;&gt;#4322&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jquery/jquery/commit/a0abd15b9e5aa9c1f36a9599e6095304825a7b9f&quot;&gt;a0abd15b&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t read styles.position in the width/height cssHook unless necessary (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jquery/jquery/issues/4185&quot;&gt;#4185&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jquery/jquery/commit/354f6036f251a3ce9b24cd7b228b4c7a79001520&quot;&gt;354f6036&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t auto-append “px” to possibly-unitless CSS grid properties (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jquery/jquery/issues/4007&quot;&gt;#4007&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jquery/jquery/commit/f997241f0011ed728be71002bc703c7a0d3f01e5&quot;&gt;f997241f&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Dimensions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;fix computing outerWidth on SVGs (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jquery/jquery/issues/3964&quot;&gt;#3964&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jquery/jquery/commit/e743cbd28553267f955f71ea7248377915613fd9&quot;&gt;e743cbd2&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;avoid fetching boxSizing when setting width/height – this avoids forcing a reflow in some cases (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jquery/jquery/issues/3991&quot;&gt;#3991&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jquery/jquery/commit/73d7e6259c63ac45f42c6593da8c2796c6ce9281&quot;&gt;73d7e625&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fall back to offsetWidth/Height for border-box in IE (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jquery/jquery/issues/4102&quot;&gt;#4102&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jquery/jquery/commit/315199c156c5b822a857ca236bda123f01a2da37&quot;&gt;315199c1&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Event&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Prevent leverageNative from double-firing focusin (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jquery/jquery/commit/fe5f04de8fde9c69ed48283b99280aa6df3795c7&quot;&gt;fe5f04de&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add “code” property to Event object (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jquery/jquery/issues/3978&quot;&gt;#3978&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jquery/jquery/commit/899c56f6ada26821e8af12d9f35fa039100e838e&quot;&gt;899c56f6&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Leverage native events for focus/blur/click; propagate additional data (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jquery/jquery/issues/1741&quot;&gt;#1741&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jquery/jquery/issues/3423&quot;&gt;#3423&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jquery/jquery/issues/3751&quot;&gt;#3751&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jquery/jquery/issues/4139&quot;&gt;#4139&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jquery/jquery/commit/669f720edc4f557dfef986db747c09ebfaa16ef5&quot;&gt;669f720e&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Respect script nomodule attribute in DOM manipulation (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jquery/jquery/issues/4281&quot;&gt;#4281&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jquery/jquery/commit/e4de8b4626f8872a4cb1ee241b60902653567503&quot;&gt;e4de8b46&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Restore _evalUrl jQuery.ajax calls to dataType: script (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jquery/jquery/commit/13de7c9ede1c49c30344b4347985eac341484b1e&quot;&gt;13de7c9e&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only evaluate HTTP-successful script src (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jquery/jquery/issues/4126&quot;&gt;#4126&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jquery/jquery/commit/c2026b117d1ca5b2e42a52c7e2a8ae8988cf0d4b&quot;&gt;c2026b11&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Manipulation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Properly detect HTML elements with single-character names (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jquery/jquery/issues/4124&quot;&gt;#4124&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jquery/jquery/commit/979809c5a80aaf26bf7e3406a2e361e809f9b132&quot;&gt;979809c5&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Misc&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Add config for lockbot (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jquery/jquery/commit/2348f3996748fc805903e45dbc598ec570d49bb0&quot;&gt;2348f399&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update license prolog/epilog to placate Github checker (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jquery/jquery/commit/29e76e254059f8c2b695f4e41054260b52a6910d&quot;&gt;29e76e25&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;README&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;add gitter badge to README.md (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jquery/jquery/commit/7869f83ddd5a3156a358284cbef6837b5e7a2a62&quot;&gt;7869f83d&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add FOSSA license scan status badge (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jquery/jquery/commit/45f085882597016e521436f01a8459daf3e4000e&quot;&gt;45f08588&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Selector&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Serialize&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;jQuery.param: return empty string when given null/undefined (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jquery/jquery/issues/2633&quot;&gt;#2633&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jquery/jquery/commit/0645099e027cd0e31a828572169a8c25474e2b5c&quot;&gt;0645099e&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Traversing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Internal&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Seasonal update of uglify and its options (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jquery/jquery/commit/09684ba3f210594e41ecddf369ac94c688d53ccb&quot;&gt;09684ba3&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove unnecessary ESLint exception (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jquery/jquery/commit/dc05f3c1d5a22d96d9d62c8ec0fde2782c38796b&quot;&gt;dc05f3c1&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run the basic test suite in jsdom (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jquery/jquery/commit/0ec25abba212efde462a8abcf3376f50116fd6c4&quot;&gt;0ec25abb&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove manual QUnit fixture resetting (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jquery/jquery/commit/84b6a0beb1de193520bb5541c841cbecc7195a5b&quot;&gt;84b6a0be&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make Promises/A+ tests use the dot reporter instead of the default (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jquery/jquery/commit/ca9356ecce0d45e80794e4fb1a94f283675526ba&quot;&gt;ca9356ec&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update QUnit from 1.23.1 to 2.9.2 (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jquery/jquery/commit/6ced2639b567ab4a5089f38a8e90efedc12801bf&quot;&gt;6ced2639&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run Karma browser tests on Node.js 10 instead of 8 (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jquery/jquery/commit/16ad9889f562e730a7f39df8a20938f6a3a04edc&quot;&gt;16ad9889&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update jsdom; migrate a test with Symbol polyfill to an iframe test (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jquery/jquery/commit/9cb124ed00aad8ac47690e31ad0bb8c3c365663d&quot;&gt;9cb124ed&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove obsolete globals from ESLint configuration (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jquery/jquery/commit/c10945d0e15c5048ae8b5b7e3f8241ad27671a7c&quot;&gt;c10945d0&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update most dependencies (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jquery/jquery/commit/8751e9ef86c007e55c9e4a2fe3c9212fb2cadcca&quot;&gt;8751e9ef&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update test code for compatibility with QUnit 2.x (#4297) (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jquery/jquery/commit/c3498187421d0a50ee0369163428481137a04b99&quot;&gt;c3498187&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advise to create test cases on JS Bin or CodePen, drop JSFiddle (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jquery/jquery/commit/da44ff39c2c3433e32b757b05b5643edb72fe786&quot;&gt;da44ff39&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 21:08:22 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mkurz</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://blog.jquery.com/2019/04/10/jquery-3-4-0-released/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>EU Agencies Falsely Report More Than 550 Archive.org URLs as Terrorist Content</title>
<link>https://blog.archive.org/2019/04/10/official-eu-agencies-falsely-report-more-than-550-archive-org-urls-as-terrorist-content/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.archive.org/2019/04/10/official-eu-agencies-falsely-report-more-than-550-archive-org-urls-as-terrorist-content/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The European Parliament is set to vote on legislation that would require websites that host user-generated content to take down material reported as terrorist content within one hour. We have some examples of current notices sent to the Internet Archive that we think illustrate very well why this requirement would be harmful to the free sharing of information and freedom of speech that the European Union pledges to safeguard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the past week, the Internet Archive has received a series of email notices from Europol’s European Union Internet Referral Unit (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.europol.europa.eu/about-europol/eu-internet-referal-unit-eu-iru&quot;&gt;EU IRU&lt;/a&gt;) falsely identifying hundreds of URLs on archive.org as “terrorist propaganda”. At least one of these mistaken URLs was also identified as terrorist content in a separate take down notice from the French government’s L’Office Central de Lutte contre la Criminalité liée aux Technologies de l’Information et de la Communication (OCLCTIC).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Internet Archive has a few staff members that process takedown notices from law enforcement who operate in the Pacific time zone. Most of the falsely identified URLs mentioned here (including the report from the French government) were sent to us in the middle of the night – between midnight and 3am Pacific – and all of the reports were sent outside of the business hours of the Internet Archive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The one-hour requirement essentially means that we would need to take reported URLs down automatically and do our best to review them after the fact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would be bad enough if the mistaken URLs in these examples were for a set of relatively obscure items on our site, but the EU IRU’s lists include some of the most visited pages on archive.org and materials that obviously have high scholarly and research value. See a summary below with specific examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EU IRU’s mistaken notices&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At least 550 archive.org URLs were falsely identified by the EU IRU in the past week as terrorist propaganda, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;major collection pages&lt;/strong&gt; (displaying millions of items), many pertaining only to material preserved and posted directly by the Internet Archive, others that include user-uploaded content, e.g.:
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;scholarly articles&lt;/strong&gt;, e.g.:
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;US Government-produced broadcasts and reports&lt;/strong&gt;, e.g.:
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;User-posted materials&lt;/strong&gt; that clearly do not fit the EU IRU notices’ description as terrorist propaganda, e.g.:
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Again, these examples are only a few of the some 550 falsely identified URLs. The erroneous reports continue to be sent to us by the EU IRU (the most recent example was sent a day prior to this post).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;French Government’s (OCLCTIC) mistaken notice&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The OCLCTIC emailed us a take down notice a few days ago (April 8&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt;) identifying an item making commentary on the Quran as including “provocation of acts of terrorism or apology for such acts”:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.org/details/002Baqarah_201712&quot;&gt;https://archive.org/details/002Baqarah_201712&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The report stated that blocking procedures may be implemented against us if we did not remove the content in 24 hours. This URL was also on one of the lists that the EU IRU reported to us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, we are left to ask – how can the proposed legislation realistically be said to honor freedom of speech if these are the types of reports that are currently coming from EU law enforcement and designated governmental reporting entities? It is not possible for us to process these reports using human review within a very limited timeframe like one hour. Are we to simply take what’s reported as “terrorism” at face value and risk the automatic removal of things like THE primary collection page for all books on archive.org?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 19:20:07 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jonah-archive</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.archive.org/2019/04/10/official-eu-agencies-falsely-report-more-than-550-archive-org-urls-as-terrorist-content/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Urgent Quest for Slower, Better News</title>
<link>https://www.newyorker.com/culture/annals-of-inquiry/the-urgent-quest-for-slower-better-news</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.newyorker.com/culture/annals-of-inquiry/the-urgent-quest-for-slower-better-news</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;SectionBreak SectionBreak__sectionBreak___1ppA7&quot; readability=&quot;180.91170925848&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last month, I decided to try an experiment with my media diet. Usually, in the morning, I skim e-mail newsletters in my in-box, scroll through my Twitter feed, and peruse the news apps on my phone; later, in the office, I tap through my notifications and monitor more than a dozen news-related apps, including Facebook and Twitter, while juggling other tasks. I usually feel as though I’m managing to stay abreast of the day’s biggest news stories, but my reading tends to be fragmentary—I’m only skimming a story or absorbing a partial update. Although I’m reading more than ever before, it often feels like I’m understanding less.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven’t stopped getting my news in this way, but I’m trying to change my ways to a certain extent. I’ve adopted a new ritual: reading the print edition of the New York &lt;em class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt; over breakfast and on my commute. Since the early two-thousands, when I was a cub reporter at the &lt;em class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt;, I’ve had the newspaper delivered daily to my door, but, as I’ve started getting more and more of my news online, I’ve been neglecting it. Having returned to spending uninterrupted time with the print newspaper each morning, I’m engaging with the news in a more focussed way. Certainly, I’m able to read more broadly. I’ve read articles that weren’t in my social-media feeds, or that I missed while scrolling through my apps: reporting on efforts to make Copenhagen a carbon-neutral city, on talks between the United States and the Taliban, on a new study that found that the size of bullets affects mortality rates in shootings. It seems to me that I’ve become better informed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many people have tried such experiments, of course. And much has been made of how being tethered to our phones affects everything from our attention spans to our psychological well-being. In his new book, “&lt;a class=&quot;ArticleBody__link___1FS03&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/dp/0525536515/?tag=thneyo0f-20&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Digital Minimalism: Choosing a Focused Life in a Noisy World&lt;/a&gt;,” Cal Newport, a computer-science professor at Georgetown University, marshals evidence that the addictive properties of our devices are not accidental but, rather, the product of careful thinking by tech companies about the feedback loops that will keep people returning to them. Newport’s main indictment is of social-media platforms, but he also argues that people need to rethink the way they consume news. Exposure to the online torrent of “incomplete, redundant, and often contradictory” information that now invariably follows a major news event is counterproductive and leaves us less informed, he writes. Even when nothing earth-shattering is happening on a given day, he continues, people follow a compulsive pattern of media consumption, triggered by any hint of boredom. “If you’re interested in politics, for example, and lean toward the left side of the political spectrum, this sequence might go from CNN.com, to the New York &lt;em class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt; homepage, to &lt;em class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Politico&lt;/em&gt;, to the &lt;em class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Atlantic&lt;/em&gt;, to your Twitter feed, and finally to your Facebook timeline,” he explains. Techies might add Hacker News and Reddit; sports fans, ESPN. Media companies profit from this “lucrative tic.” “Checking ten different sites ten times a day makes them money, even if it doesn’t leave you more informed than checking one good site once a day,” he concludes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2008, the &lt;em class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Columbia Journalism Review&lt;/em&gt; published an &lt;a class=&quot;ArticleBody__link___1FS03&quot; href=&quot;https://archives.cjr.org/feature/overload_1.php&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; with the headline “Overload!,” which examined news fatigue in “an age of too much information.” When “Overload!” was published, BlackBerrys still dominated the smartphone market, push notifications hadn’t yet to come to the iPhone, retweets weren’t built into Twitter, and BuzzFeed News did not exist. Looking back, the idea of suffering from information overload in 2008 seems almost quaint. Now, more than a decade later, a fresh reckoning seems to be upon us. Last year, Tim Cook, the chief executive officer of Apple, unveiled a new iPhone feature, Screen Time, which allows users to track their phone activity. During an &lt;a class=&quot;ArticleBody__link___1FS03&quot; href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/2018/06/26/apple-ceo-tim-cook-monitoring-his-own-iphone-usage-with-screen-time.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;interview&lt;/a&gt; at a &lt;em class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Fortune&lt;/em&gt; conference, Cook said that he was monitoring his own usage and had “slashed” the number of notifications he receives. “I think it has become clear to all of us that some of us are spending too much time on our devices,” Cook said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is worth considering how news organizations have contributed to the problems Newport and Cook describe. Media outlets have been reduced to fighting over a shrinking share of our attention online; as Facebook, Google, and other tech platforms have come to monopolize our digital lives, news organizations have had to assume a subsidiary role, relying on those sites for traffic. That dependence exerts a powerful influence on which stories are pursued, how they’re presented, and the speed and volume at which they’re turned out. In “&lt;a class=&quot;ArticleBody__link___1FS03&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/dp/1101981113/?tag=thneyo0f-20&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;World Without Mind: the Existential Threat of Big Tech&lt;/a&gt;,” published in 2017, Franklin Foer, the former editor-in-chief of &lt;em class=&quot;&quot;&gt;The New Republic&lt;/em&gt;, writes about “a mad, shameless chase to gain clicks through Facebook” and “a relentless effort to game Google’s algorithms.” Newspapers and magazines have long sought to command large readerships, but these efforts used to be primarily the province of circulation departments; newsrooms were insulated from these pressures, with little sense of what readers actually read. Nowadays, at both legacy news organizations and those that were born online, audience metrics are everywhere. At the &lt;em class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt;, everyone in the newsroom has access to an internal, custom-built &lt;a class=&quot;ArticleBody__link___1FS03&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/05/23/technology/personaltech/metrics-media.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;analytics tool&lt;/a&gt; that shows how many people are reading each story, where those people are coming from, what devices they are using, how the stories are being promoted, and so on. Additional, commercially built audience tools, such as Chartbeat and Google Analytics, are also widely available. As the editor of newyorker.com, I keep a browser tab open to Parse.ly, an application that shows me, in real time, various readership numbers for the stories on our Web site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even at news organizations committed to insuring that editorial values—and not commercial interests—determine coverage, it can be difficult for editors to decide how much attention should be paid to these metrics. In “&lt;a class=&quot;ArticleBody__link___1FS03&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/dp/0374279624/?tag=thneyo0f-20&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Breaking News: the Remaking of Journalism and Why It Matters&lt;/a&gt;,” Alan Rusbridger, the former editor-in-chief of the &lt;em class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Guardian&lt;/em&gt;, recounts the gradual introduction of metrics into his newspaper’s decision-making processes. The goal, he writes, is to have “a data-informed newsroom, not a data-led one.” But it’s hard to know when the former crosses over into being the latter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For digital-media organizations sustained by advertising, the temptations are almost irresistible. Each time a reader comes to a news site from a social-media or search platform, the visit, no matter how brief, brings in some amount of revenue. Foer calls this phenomenon “drive-by traffic.” As Facebook and Google have grown, they have pushed down advertising prices, and revenue-per-click from drive-by traffic has shrunk; even so, it continues to provide an incentive for any number of depressing modern media trends, including clickbait headlines, the proliferation of hastily written “hot takes,” and increasingly homogeneous coverage as everyone chases the same trending news stories, so as not to miss out on the traffic they will bring. Any content that is cheap to produce and has the potential to generate clicks on Facebook or Google is now a revenue-generating “audience opportunity.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In theory, a subscription-based model should be a dramatic improvement, substituting for the relentless pursuit of page views the superior goal of producing journalism that can’t be found anywhere else and is worth paying for. Foer asserts that subscription-based reader revenue is the only viable path for a media outlet seeking to maintain its editorial identity. There is a reassuring freedom in his imagined business model: instead of chasing legions of visitors who land on your site from a Google search on some trending topic and never return, a publication might focus on its true fans. “Media need to scale back their ambitions, to return to their niches, to reclaim the loyalty of core audiences,” Foer writes. “To rescue themselves, media will need to charge readers, and readers will need to pay.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the most common approach to subscription growth relies, to a fair extent, on many of the same tactics that ad-driven media businesses employ. Most news organizations pursuing consumer revenue have adopted a metered-paywall strategy, which gives readers access to a certain number of free articles per month before requiring a subscription for access. This allows nonsubscribers to get to know the publication, sampling a piece here and there, perhaps in the course of a few months or longer, before deciding to pay. And yet Facebook and Google remain essential gateways for getting readers into this so-called subscription funnel and pulling them through it. The tyranny of the trending story still holds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The work of transforming casual visitors into regular readers, moreover, creates its own set of incentives. The onslaught of news-related push notifications on our phones is due, in part, to the need to draw readers back, again and again. And enticing readers to subscribe requires the constant creation of new and varied material. It’s not enough for readers to immerse themselves in an article or two per month; they must develop &lt;a class=&quot;ArticleBody__link___1FS03&quot; href=&quot;https://www.americanpressinstitute.org/publications/reports/survey-research/paths-to-subscription/single-page/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;loyalty&lt;/a&gt; to a site, returning repeatedly until they hit the paywall. Quality is paramount—but it must also be produced at scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;SectionBreak SectionBreak__sectionBreak___1ppA7&quot; readability=&quot;126.15827338129&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lately, I have begun to wonder, like Newport, whether the sheer volume of online news actually runs counter to the goal of keeping people informed. Research on this question is surprisingly scant. “My hunch is that readers aren’t less informed than before,” Pablo Boczkowski, a professor of communication studies at Northwestern University, told me. “They’re differently informed.” Among Boczkowski’s areas of research is how young people interact with the news today. Most do not go online seeking the news; instead, they encounter it incidentally, on social media. They might get on their phones or computers to check for updates or messages from their friends, and, along the way, encounter a post from a news site. Few people sit down in the morning to read the print newspaper or make a point of watching the TV news in the evening. Instead, they are constantly “being touched, rubbed by the news,” Bockzkowski said. “It’s part of the environment.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How well can news be absorbed by osmosis? Studies have found that people bounce between tasks on their computers at stunning rates; a paper published last year found a median switch time of eleven seconds. Introduce mobile devices into the mix, and the switching is even faster. It’s no wonder that news is getting chopped up into smaller bits. “If you’re an average site, you have five to seven seconds to tell your story,” Boczkowski told me. It seems reasonable to guess, therefore, that people are now more aware, on a general level, of different topics in the news, but that they also have less depth of understanding in any one area. Even those readers who are inclined to engage deeply and broadly with the news are constrained by social-media filter bubbles, within which agreeable content, posted by people in their networks, is prioritized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A central purpose of journalism is the creation of an informed citizenry. And yet––especially in an environment of free-floating, ambient news––it’s not entirely clear what it means to be informed. In his book “&lt;a class=&quot;ArticleBody__link___1FS03&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/dp/0684827298/?tag=thneyo0f-20&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;The Good Citizen&lt;/a&gt;,” from 1998, Michael Schudson, a sociologist who now teaches at Columbia’s journalism school, argues that the ideal of the “informed citizen”––a person with the time, discipline, and expertise needed to steep him- or herself in politics and become fully engaged in our civic life—has always been an unrealistic one. The Founders, he writes, expected citizens to possess relatively little political knowledge; the ideal of the informed citizen didn’t take hold until more than a century later, when Progressive-era reformers sought to rein in the party machines and empower individual voters to make thoughtful decisions. (It was also during this period that the independent press began to emerge as a commercial phenomenon, and the press corps became increasingly professionalized.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Schudson proposes a model for citizenship that he believes to be more true to life: the “monitorial citizen”—a person who is watchful of what’s going on in politics but isn’t always fully engaged. “The monitorial citizen engages in environmental surveillance more than information-gathering,” he writes. “Picture parents watching small children at the community pool. They are not gathering information; they are keeping an eye on the scene. They look inactive, but they are poised for action if action is required.” Schudson contends that monitorial citizens might even be “better informed than citizens of the past in that, somewhere in their heads, they have more bits of information.” When the time is right, they will deploy this information—to vote a corrupt lawmaker out of office, say, or to approve an important ballot measure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In theory, the social-media age could make us better monitorial citizens. But Schudson’s model, which assumes that monitorial citizens will be activated at appropriate moments, didn’t anticipate the ease with which Facebook, Twitter, and other platforms can set off panics at the pool. The danger today—as phenomena such as Brexit and anti-vaccine activism demonstrate—is one of false alarms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2017, the cognitive scientists Steven Sloman and Philip Fernbach published the book “&lt;a class=&quot;ArticleBody__link___1FS03&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/dp/039918435X/?tag=thneyo0f-20&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;The Knowledge Illusion: Why We Never Think Alone&lt;/a&gt;.” Their book, which is about the perils of superficial knowledge, offers as good an explanation as any of how our social-media-based news ecosystem is leading to undesirable outcomes in our democracy. People vastly overestimate what they know, and their unjustifiably strong opinions are reinforced by other people who are similarly ill-informed, creating self-reinforcing communities of misinformation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When group members don’t know much but share a position, members of the group can reinforce one another’s sense of understanding, leading everyone to feel like their position is justified and their mission is clear, even when there is no real expertise to give it solid support. Everyone sees everyone else as justifying their view so that opinion rests on a mirage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That same year, my colleague Elizabeth Kolbert cited Sloman and Fernbach’s work in a piece called “&lt;a class=&quot;ArticleBody__link___1FS03&quot; href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2017/02/27/why-facts-dont-change-our-minds&quot;&gt;Why Facts Don’t Change Our Minds&lt;/a&gt;.” “If your position on, say, the Affordable Care Act is baseless and I rely on it, then my opinion is also baseless,” she explains. “When I talk to Tom and he decides he agrees with me, his opinion is also baseless, but now that the three of us concur we feel that much more smug about our views. If we all now dismiss as unconvincing any information that contradicts our opinion, you get, well, the Trump Administration.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As it turns out, there is a way to puncture this illusion of knowledge. It involves forcing people to explain in detail what would happen if their views on a specific public-policy issue were put into practice. It’s when we try to provide a “causal explanation,” Sloman and Ferbach write, that we realize how ignorant we are. That realization, in turn, leads us to become less extreme in our views. This insight has an obvious implication for media: depth matters. Journalism that engages with complexity, examines the implications of proposed policies, and offers the public rigorous analysis can lead to a more informed—and less polarized—citizenry. And yet, if Schudson is right, then only a small portion of readers will have the time, inclination, and disposition to become so ideally informed. Far more people will be monitorial, rather than informed, citizens—and, thanks to social media and high-volume news operations, they will be easily alarmed and distracted. Adding yet more stories to this maelstrom may make a certain economic sense for media organizations, but it won’t necessarily make us any better informed. It might only further fragment our knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;SectionBreak SectionBreak__sectionBreak___1ppA7&quot; readability=&quot;67.827951564077&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps we need to recalibrate our relationship with media—to rethink how we ought to consume information more generally and what it means to be informed. In the recent book “&lt;a class=&quot;ArticleBody__link___1FS03&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/dp/0190641797/?tag=thneyo0f-20&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Slow Media: Why ‘Slow’ is Satisfying, Sustainable, and Smart&lt;/a&gt;,” the journalist and media scholar Jennifer Rauch traces a movement that began to coalesce about a decade ago. In 2010, a document called “&lt;a class=&quot;ArticleBody__link___1FS03&quot; href=&quot;http://en.slow-media.net/manifesto&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Slow Media Manifesto&lt;/a&gt;” was published, online, by Sabria David, Jörg Blumtritt, and Benedikt Köhler—a trio of Germans with backgrounds in media and technology. It urged both journalists and readers to draw inspiration from the Slow Food movement, which emphasizes quality and timelessness. “Slow Media are not about fast consumption but about choosing the ingredients mindfully and preparing them in a concentrated manner,” the authors wrote. “Slow Media cannot be consumed casually, but provoke the full concentration of their users. As with the production of a good meal, which demands the full attention of all senses by the cook and his guests, Slow Media can only be consumed with pleasure in focused alertness.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rauch points to the U.K.-based quarterly &lt;a class=&quot;ArticleBody__link___1FS03&quot; href=&quot;https://www.slow-journalism.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Delayed Gratification&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which was established in 2011, as an example of Slow Media in action. &lt;em class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Delayed Gratification&lt;/em&gt;, which has a Web site but is primarily print-based, describes itself as “the world’s first Slow Journalism magazine.” It promises to revisit “the events of the previous three months to see what happened after the dust settled and the news agenda moved on” and declares itself “proud to be ‘Last to Breaking News.’ ” Meanwhile, earlier this year, James Harding, the former director of news and current affairs at the BBC; Katie Vanneck-Smith, the former president of Dow Jones; and Matthew Barzun, the former U.S. Ambassador to the United Kingdom, launched &lt;a class=&quot;ArticleBody__link___1FS03&quot; href=&quot;https://www.tortoisemedia.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Tortoise Media&lt;/a&gt;, which aims to publish five digital stories a day, along with a quarterly print magazine. Tortoise was formed as a direct response to the overwhelming amount of “daily noise” in the news ecosystem. “The problem isn’t just fake news or junk news,” a statement on the Web site says, “because there’s a lot of good—it’s just that there’s so much of it and so much of it is the same. In a hurry, partial, and confusing. Too many newsrooms chasing the news, but missing the story.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Could journalism in general get slower? As I read about the Slow Media movement—which, so far, seems to be a mostly European phenomenon—I inevitably thought about trends in the magazine industry in the United States, where publications are experimenting with paywalls and churning out digital content. The appeal of Slow Media is that it pushes back against the technological pressures that are shaping journalism more broadly. (Newport advocates Slow Media in a section of his book, urging readers to join “the attention resistance.”) It is an attempt to take back control of the way we experience the news. It is also about relinquishing the illusion of knowledge that the passive consumption of news on social media facilitates and bringing our best selves to the act of becoming informed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The challenge for all media organizations, slow or not, is to chart an economically sustainable, responsible course through this landscape of conflicting incentives and ideals. The pressures for speed and volume created by the digital age can’t be ignored—but they can be resisted. Even as publishers try to move more quickly, they can still ask themselves whether granular coverage in a given area is really making readers better informed. They can still consider sitting out certain trending stories, and they can do more, across the board, to engage with complexity. Readers, too, can begin to realize they’re being ill-served by the current media cacophony. Let’s hope that, when they search for alternatives, they will still be able to find journalism capable of rising above the din.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 18:35:19 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>hhs</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://media.newyorker.com/photos/5cad4161ece1841a020ad5ac/16:9/w_1200,h_630,c_limit/luo-slownews.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>The Urgent Quest for Slower, Better News</og:title>
<og:description>The current system for delivering news online is broken. Readers and journalists will need to work together to find a new one.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.newyorker.com/culture/annals-of-inquiry/the-urgent-quest-for-slower-better-news</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.newyorker.com/culture/annals-of-inquiry/the-urgent-quest-for-slower-better-news</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>