<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>In Baltimore and Beyond, a Stolen NSA Tool Wreaks Havoc</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/05/25/us/nsa-hacking-tool-baltimore.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2019/05/25/us/nsa-hacking-tool-baltimore.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;For nearly three weeks, Baltimore has struggled with a cyberattack by digital extortionists that has frozen thousands of computers, shut down email and disrupted real estate sales, water bills, health alerts and many other services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;But here is what frustrated city employees and residents do not know: A key component of the malware that cybercriminals used in the attack was developed at taxpayer expense a short drive down the Baltimore-Washington Parkway at the National Security Agency, according to security experts briefed on the case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Since 2017, when &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/11/12/us/nsa-shadow-brokers.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;the N.S.A. lost control of the tool&lt;/a&gt;, EternalBlue, it has been picked up by state hackers in North Korea, Russia and, more recently, China, to cut a path of destruction around the world, leaving billions of dollars in damage. But over the past year, the cyberweapon has boomeranged back and is now showing up in the N.S.A.’s own backyard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;It is not just in Baltimore. Security experts say EternalBlue attacks &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.welivesecurity.com/2019/05/17/eternalblue-new-heights-wannacryptor/&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;have reached a high&lt;/a&gt;, and cybercriminals are zeroing in on vulnerable American towns and cities, from Pennsylvania to Texas, paralyzing local governments and driving up costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The N.S.A. connection to the attacks on American cities has not been previously reported, in part because the agency has refused to discuss or even acknowledge the loss of its cyberweapon, dumped online in April 2017 by a still-unidentified group calling itself &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/03/28/us/politics/hal-martin-nsa-guilty-plea.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;the Shadow Brokers&lt;/a&gt;. Years later, the agency and the Federal Bureau of Investigation still do not know whether the Shadow Brokers are foreign spies or disgruntled insiders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Thomas Rid, a cybersecurity expert at Johns Hopkins University, called the Shadow Brokers episode “the most destructive and costly N.S.A. breach in history,” more damaging than the better-known leak in 2013 from Edward Snowden, the former N.S.A. contractor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“The government has refused to take responsibility, or even to answer the most basic questions,” Mr. Rid said. “Congressional oversight appears to be failing. The American people deserve an answer.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The N.S.A. and F.B.I. declined to comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Since that leak, foreign intelligence agencies and rogue actors have used EternalBlue to spread malware that has paralyzed hospitals, airports, rail and shipping operators, A.T.M.s and factories that produce critical vaccines. Now the tool is hitting the United States where it is most vulnerable, in local governments with aging digital infrastructure and fewer resources to defend themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-79elbk&quot; data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-wrapper&quot;&gt;

&lt;div data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-children&quot; class=&quot;css-1a48zt4 ehw59r15&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1xdhyk6 erfvjey0&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1tej78p0&quot;&gt;Image&lt;/span&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;css-1m50asq&quot; src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/05/25/multimedia/25nsa-03/merlin_155370108_694f5d1b-aed5-4e46-b409-a2ae6aff3f13-articleLarge.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;auto=webp&amp;amp;disable=upscale&quot; srcset=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/05/25/multimedia/25nsa-03/merlin_155370108_694f5d1b-aed5-4e46-b409-a2ae6aff3f13-articleLarge.jpg?quality=90&amp;amp;auto=webp 600w,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/05/25/multimedia/25nsa-03/merlin_155370108_694f5d1b-aed5-4e46-b409-a2ae6aff3f13-jumbo.jpg?quality=90&amp;amp;auto=webp 1024w,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/05/25/multimedia/25nsa-03/merlin_155370108_694f5d1b-aed5-4e46-b409-a2ae6aff3f13-superJumbo.jpg?quality=90&amp;amp;auto=webp 1126w&quot; sizes=&quot;((min-width: 600px) and (max-width: 1004px)) 84vw, (min-width: 1005px) 60vw, 100vw&quot; itemprop=&quot;url&quot; itemid=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/05/25/multimedia/25nsa-03/merlin_155370108_694f5d1b-aed5-4e46-b409-a2ae6aff3f13-articleLarge.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;auto=webp&amp;amp;disable=upscale&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;css-8i9d0s e13ogyst0&quot;&gt;On May 7, city workers in Baltimore had their computers frozen by hackers. Officials have refused to pay the $100,000 ransom.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot; class=&quot;css-vuqh7u e1z0qqy90&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1tej78p0&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Before it leaked, EternalBlue was one of the most useful exploits in the N.S.A.’s cyberarsenal. According to three former N.S.A. operators who spoke on the condition of anonymity, analysts spent almost a year finding a flaw in Microsoft’s software and writing the code to target it. Initially, they referred to it as EternalBluescreen because it often crashed computers — a risk that could tip off their targets. But it went on to become a reliable tool used in countless intelligence-gathering and counterterrorism missions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;EternalBlue was so valuable, former N.S.A. employees said, that the agency never seriously considered alerting Microsoft about the vulnerabilities, and held on to it for more than five years before the breach forced its hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/05/22/us/baltimore-ransomware.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Baltimore attack&lt;/a&gt;, on May 7, was a &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/03/29/us/atlanta-cyberattack-ransom.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;classic ransomware&lt;/a&gt; assault. City workers’ screens suddenly locked, and a message in flawed English demanded about $100,000 in Bitcoin to free their files: “We’ve watching you for days,” said the message, &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.baltimoresun.com/news/maryland/politics/bs-md-ci-it-outage-20190507-story.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;obtained by The Baltimore Sun&lt;/a&gt;. “We won’t talk more, all we know is MONEY! Hurry up!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Today, Baltimore remains handicapped as city officials refuse to pay, though workarounds have restored some services. Without EternalBlue, the damage would not have been so vast, experts said. The tool exploits a vulnerability in unpatched software that allows hackers to spread their malware faster and farther than they otherwise could.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;North Korea was the first nation to co-opt the tool, for an attack in 2017 — called WannaCry — that paralyzed the British health care system, German railroads and some 200,000 organizations around the world. Next was Russia, which used the weapon in an attack — called NotPetya — that was aimed at Ukraine but spread across major companies doing business in the country. The assault cost FedEx more than $400 million and Merck, the pharmaceutical giant, $670 million.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The damage didn’t stop there. In the past year, the same Russian hackers who targeted the 2016 American presidential election used EternalBlue to compromise hotel Wi-Fi networks. Iranian hackers have used it to spread ransomware and hack airlines in the Middle East, according to researchers at the security firms Symantec and FireEye.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“It’s incredible that a tool which was used by intelligence services is now publicly available and so widely used,” said Vikram Thakur, Symantec’s director of security response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;One month before the Shadow Brokers began dumping the agency’s tools online in 2017, the N.S.A. — aware of the breach — reached out to Microsoft and other tech companies to inform them of their software flaws. Microsoft released a patch, but hundreds of thousands of computers worldwide remain unprotected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-79elbk&quot; data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-wrapper&quot;&gt;

&lt;div data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-children&quot; class=&quot;css-1a48zt4 ehw59r15&quot;&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;css-8i9d0s e13ogyst0&quot;&gt;Microsoft employees reviewing malware data at the company’s offices in Redmond, Wash. EternalBlue exploits a flaw in unpatched Microsoft software.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot; class=&quot;css-vuqh7u e1z0qqy90&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1tej78p0&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Kyle Johnson for The New York Times&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Hackers seem to have found a sweet spot in Baltimore, Allentown, Pa., San Antonio and other local, American governments, where public employees oversee tangled networks that often use out-of-date software. Last July, the &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.us-cert.gov/ncas/alerts/TA18-201A&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Department of Homeland Security issued a dire warning&lt;/a&gt; that state and local governments were getting hit by particularly destructive malware that now, security researchers say, has started relying on EternalBlue to spread.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Microsoft, which tracks the use of EternalBlue, would not name the cities and towns affected, citing customer privacy. But other experts briefed on the attacks in Baltimore, Allentown and San Antonio confirmed the hackers used EternalBlue. Security responders said they were seeing EternalBlue pop up in attacks almost every day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Amit Serper, head of security research at Cybereason, said his firm had responded to EternalBlue attacks at three different American universities, and found vulnerable servers in major cities like Dallas, Los Angeles and New York.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The costs can be hard for local governments to bear. The Allentown attack, in February last year, disrupted city services for weeks and cost about $1 million to remedy — plus another $420,000 a year for new defenses, said Matthew Leibert, the city’s chief information officer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;He described the package of dangerous computer code that hit Allentown as “commodity malware,” sold on the dark web and used by criminals who don’t have specific targets in mind. “There are warehouses of kids overseas firing off phishing emails,” Mr. Leibert said, like thugs shooting military-grade weapons at random targets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The malware that hit San Antonio last September infected a computer inside Bexar County sheriff’s office and tried to spread across the network using EternalBlue, according to two people briefed on the attack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;This past week, researchers at the security firm Palo Alto Networks discovered that a Chinese state group, Emissary Panda, had hacked into Middle Eastern governments using EternalBlue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“You can’t hope that once the initial wave of attacks is over, it will go away,” said Jen Miller-Osborn, a deputy director of threat intelligence at Palo Alto Networks. “We expect EternalBlue will be used almost forever, because if attackers find a system that isn’t patched, it is so useful.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-79elbk&quot; data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-wrapper&quot;&gt;

&lt;div data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-children&quot; class=&quot;css-1a48zt4 ehw59r15&quot;&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;css-8i9d0s e13ogyst0&quot;&gt;Adm. Michael S. Rogers, who led the N.S.A. during the leak, has said the agency should not be blamed for the trail of damage.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot; class=&quot;css-vuqh7u e1z0qqy90&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1tej78p0&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Erin Schaff for The New York Times&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Until a decade or so ago, the most powerful cyberweapons belonged almost exclusively to intelligence agencies — N.S.A. officials used the term “NOBUS,” for “nobody but us,” for vulnerabilities only the agency had the sophistication to exploit. But that advantage has hugely eroded, not only because of the leaks, but because anyone can grab a cyberweapon’s code once it’s used in the wild.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Some F.B.I. and Homeland Security officials, speaking privately, said more accountability at the N.S.A. was needed. A former F.B.I. official likened the situation to a government failing to lock up a warehouse of automatic weapons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;In an interview in March, Adm. Michael S. Rogers, who was director of the N.S.A. during the Shadow Brokers leak, suggested in unusually candid remarks that the agency should not be blamed for the long trail of damage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“If Toyota makes pickup trucks and someone takes a pickup truck, welds an explosive device onto the front, crashes it through a perimeter and into a crowd of people, is that Toyota’s responsibility?” he asked. “The N.S.A. wrote an exploit that was never designed to do what was done.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;At Microsoft’s headquarters in Redmond, Wash., where thousands of security engineers have found themselves on the front lines of these attacks, executives reject that analogy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“I disagree completely,” said Tom Burt, the corporate vice president of consumer trust, insisting that cyberweapons could not be compared to pickup trucks. “These exploits are developed and kept secret by governments for the express purpose of using them as weapons or espionage tools. They’re inherently dangerous. When someone takes that, they’re not strapping a bomb to it. It’s already a bomb.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Brad Smith, Microsoft’s president, has called for a &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://blogs.microsoft.com/on-the-issues/2017/02/14/need-digital-geneva-convention/#sm.0001gnysbhjsod01z7q11hvz0xg2d&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;“Digital Geneva Convention”&lt;/a&gt; to govern cyberspace, including a pledge by governments to report vulnerabilities to vendors, rather than keeping them secret to exploit for espionage or attacks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Last year, Microsoft, along with Google and Facebook, joined 50 countries in signing on to a similar call by French President Emmanuel Macron — the Paris Call for Trust and Security in Cyberspace — to end “malicious cyber activities in peacetime.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Notably absent from the signatories were the world’s most aggressive cyberactors: China, Iran, Israel, North Korea, Russia — and the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2019 16:22:07 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>SREinSF</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/05/25/us/nsa-hacking-tool-baltimore.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>In Baltimore and Beyond, a Stolen N.S.A. Tool Wreaks Havoc</og:title>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/05/25/multimedia/25nsa-01/25nsa-01-facebookJumbo.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>American cities are being hijacked with an N.S.A. cyberweapon that has already done billions of dollars in damage overseas. The N.S.A. will say nothing.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/05/25/us/nsa-hacking-tool-baltimore.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Founder Books</title>
<link>https://postmake.io/books</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://postmake.io/books</guid>
<description>&lt;p data-v-188f004c=&quot;&quot;&gt;Postmake is a directory of curated tools and resources for your next projects. If you liked this list, check out the &lt;strong data-v-188f004c=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://postmake.io/#roadmap&quot; data-v-188f004c=&quot;&quot;&gt;full directory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for more tools and resources, or join the newsletter to be notified when we compile more cool stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-v-188f004c=&quot;&quot;&gt;Drop your email below to receive our weekly newsletter. Here's &lt;strong data-v-188f004c=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mailchi.mp/238e40221e1f/building-up-the-postmake-directory&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; data-v-188f004c=&quot;&quot;&gt;an example&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; of what you'll receive.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2019 13:32:23 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ashtavakra01</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://postmake.io/books</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Show HN: A renderless and extendable rich-text editor for Vue.js</title>
<link>https://github.com/scrumpy/tiptap</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/scrumpy/tiptap</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;Box-body&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;markdown-body entry-content p-5&quot; itemprop=&quot;text&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A renderless and extendable rich-text editor for &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/vuejs/vue&quot;&gt;Vue.js&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npmjs.com/package/tiptap&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/45640c7935966691ef69c2b4401a7ccb18dfc059/68747470733a2f2f696d672e736869656c64732e696f2f6e706d2f762f7469707461702e7376673f6c6162656c3d76657273696f6e&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/npm/v/tiptap.svg?label=version&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://npmcharts.com/compare/tiptap?minimal=true&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/300517580b224509195daeda531d3a8951b65376/68747470733a2f2f696d672e736869656c64732e696f2f6e706d2f646d2f7469707461702e737667&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/npm/dm/tiptap.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npmjs.com/package/tiptap&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/adb05aba2e592bd062bd1f188bc172fe9bc7946e/68747470733a2f2f696d672e736869656c64732e696f2f6e706d2f6c2f7469707461702e737667&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/npm/l/tiptap.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npmjs.com/package/tiptap&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/5a2f758524c9cbdd29a0c40689543051ed3c0ac1/68747470733a2f2f696d672e626164676573697a652e696f2f68747470733a2f2f756e706b672e636f6d2f7469707461702f646973742f7469707461702e6d696e2e6a733f636f6d7072657373696f6e3d677a6970266c6162656c3d73697a6526636f6c6f72423d303030303030&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://img.badgesize.io/https://unpkg.com/tiptap/dist/tiptap.min.js?compression=gzip&amp;amp;label=size&amp;amp;colorB=000000&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://travis-ci.org/scrumpy/tiptap&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/954d835e51da7119f87f6325c839cc1cbd71a7bc/68747470733a2f2f7472617669732d63692e6f72672f736372756d70792f7469707461702e7376673f6272616e63683d6d6173746572&quot; alt=&quot;Build Status&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://travis-ci.org/scrumpy/tiptap.svg?branch=master&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why I built tiptap&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was looking for a text editor for &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/vuejs/vue&quot;&gt;Vue.js&lt;/a&gt; and found some solutions that didn't really satisfy me. The editor should be easy to extend and not based on old dependencies such as jQuery. For React there is already a great editor called &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ianstormtaylor/slate&quot;&gt;Slate.js&lt;/a&gt;, which impresses with its modularity. I came across &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/prosemirror&quot;&gt;Prosemirror&lt;/a&gt; and decided to build on it. Prosemirror is a toolkit for building rich-text editors that are already in use at many well-known companies such as &lt;em&gt;Atlassian&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What does &lt;code&gt;renderless&lt;/code&gt; mean?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With renderless components you'll have (almost) full control over markup and styling. I don't want to tell you what a menu should look like or where it should be rendered in the DOM. That's all up to you. There is also a &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamwathan.me/renderless-components-in-vuejs/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;good article&lt;/a&gt; about renderless components by Adam Wathan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;How is the data stored under the hood?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can save your data as a raw &lt;code&gt;HTML&lt;/code&gt; string or can get a &lt;code&gt;JSON&lt;/code&gt;-serializable representation of your document. And of course, you can pass these two types back to the editor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Examples&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To check out some live examples, visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://tiptap.scrumpy.io/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;tiptap.scrumpy.io&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;npm install tiptap
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;or&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;yarn add tiptap
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Basic Setup&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-text-html-vue&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&amp;lt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-ent&quot;&gt;template&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-ent&quot;&gt;editor-content&lt;/span&gt; :&lt;span class=&quot;pl-e&quot;&gt;editor&lt;/span&gt;=&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;editor&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; /&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/&lt;span class=&quot;pl-ent&quot;&gt;template&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-ent&quot;&gt;script&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;//&lt;/span&gt; Import the editor&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; { &lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;Editor&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;EditorContent&lt;/span&gt; } &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;tiptap&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;export&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;default&lt;/span&gt; {&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;  components&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; {&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;    EditorContent,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;  },&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;data&lt;/span&gt;() {&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; {&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;      editor&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;null&lt;/span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;    }&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;  },&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;mounted&lt;/span&gt;() {&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;this&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;editor&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;Editor&lt;/span&gt;({&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;      content&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;This is just a boring paragraph&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;    })&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;  },&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;beforeDestroy&lt;/span&gt;() {&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;this&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;editor&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;destroy&lt;/span&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;  },&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/&lt;span class=&quot;pl-ent&quot;&gt;script&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Editor Properties&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Property&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Type&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Default&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;content&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Object|String&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;null&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The editor state object used by Prosemirror. You can also pass HTML to the &lt;code&gt;content&lt;/code&gt; slot. When used both, the &lt;code&gt;content&lt;/code&gt; slot will be ignored.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;editorProps&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Object&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;{}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A list of &lt;a href=&quot;https://prosemirror.net/docs/ref/#view.EditorProps&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Prosemirror editorProps&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;editable&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Boolean&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;true&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;When set to &lt;code&gt;false&lt;/code&gt; the editor is read-only.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;autoFocus&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Boolean&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;false&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Focus the editor on init.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;extensions&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Array&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;[]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A list of extensions used, by the editor. This can be &lt;code&gt;Nodes&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Marks&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;Plugins&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;useBuiltInExtensions&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Boolean&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;true&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;By default tiptap adds a &lt;code&gt;Doc&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Paragraph&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Text&lt;/code&gt; node to the Prosemirror schema.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;dropCursor&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Object&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;{}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Config for &lt;code&gt;prosemirror-dropcursor&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;parseOptions&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Object&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;{}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A list of &lt;a href=&quot;https://prosemirror.net/docs/ref/#model.ParseOptions&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Prosemirror parseOptions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;onInit&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Function&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;undefined&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;This will return an Object with the current &lt;code&gt;state&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;view&lt;/code&gt; of Prosemirror on init.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;onFocus&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Function&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;undefined&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;This will return an Object with the &lt;code&gt;event&lt;/code&gt; and current &lt;code&gt;state&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;view&lt;/code&gt; of Prosemirror on focus.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;onBlur&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Function&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;undefined&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;This will return an Object with the &lt;code&gt;event&lt;/code&gt; and current &lt;code&gt;state&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;view&lt;/code&gt; of Prosemirror on blur.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;onUpdate&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Function&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;undefined&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;This will return an Object with the current &lt;code&gt;state&lt;/code&gt; of Prosemirror, a &lt;code&gt;getJSON()&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;getHTML()&lt;/code&gt; function and the &lt;code&gt;transaction&lt;/code&gt; on every change.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Editor Methods&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Method&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Arguments&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;setContent&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;content, emitUpdate, parseOptions&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Replace the current content. You can pass an HTML string or a JSON document. &lt;code&gt;emitUpdate&lt;/code&gt; defaults to &lt;code&gt;false&lt;/code&gt;. &lt;code&gt;parseOptions&lt;/code&gt; defaults to those provided in constructor.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;clearContent&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;emitUpdate&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Clears the current content. &lt;code&gt;emitUpdate&lt;/code&gt; defaults to &lt;code&gt;false&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;setOptions&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;options&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Overwrites the current editor properties.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;registerPlugin&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;plugin&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Register a Prosemirror plugin.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;getJSON&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;–&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Get the current content as JSON.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;getHTML&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;–&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Get the current content as HTML.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;focus&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;–&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Focus the editor.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;blur&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;–&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Blur the editor.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;destroy&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;–&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Destroy the editor.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Components&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Name&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;editor-content /&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Here the content will be rendered.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;editor-menu-bar /&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Here a menu bar will be rendered.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;editor-menu-bubble /&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Here a menu bubble will be rendered.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;editor-floating-menu /&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Here a floating menu will be rendered.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;h3&gt;EditorMenuBar&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;editor-menu-bar /&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; component is renderless and will receive some properties through a scoped slot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Property&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Type&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;commands&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Array&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A list of all commands.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;isActive&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Object&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;An object of functions to check if your selected text is a node or mark. `isActive.{node&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;getMarkAttrs&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Function&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A function to get all mark attributes of your selection.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;focused&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Boolean&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Whether the editor is focused.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;focus&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Function&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A function to focus the editor.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Example&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-text-html-vue&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&amp;lt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-ent&quot;&gt;template&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-ent&quot;&gt;editor-menu-bar&lt;/span&gt; :&lt;span class=&quot;pl-e&quot;&gt;editor&lt;/span&gt;=&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;editor&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-e&quot;&gt;v-slot&lt;/span&gt;=&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;{ commands, isActive }&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-ent&quot;&gt;div&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-ent&quot;&gt;button&lt;/span&gt; :&lt;span class=&quot;pl-e&quot;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt;=&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;{ &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;is-active&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;isActive&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;bold&lt;/span&gt;() }&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; @&lt;span class=&quot;pl-e&quot;&gt;click&lt;/span&gt;=&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;commands&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;bold&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
        Bold
      &amp;lt;/&lt;span class=&quot;pl-ent&quot;&gt;button&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-ent&quot;&gt;button&lt;/span&gt; :&lt;span class=&quot;pl-e&quot;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt;=&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;{ &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;is-active&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;isActive&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;heading&lt;/span&gt;({ level&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt; }) }&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; @&lt;span class=&quot;pl-e&quot;&gt;click&lt;/span&gt;=&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;commands&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;heading&lt;/span&gt;({ level&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt; })&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
        H2
      &amp;lt;/&lt;span class=&quot;pl-ent&quot;&gt;button&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;/&lt;span class=&quot;pl-ent&quot;&gt;div&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;/&lt;span class=&quot;pl-ent&quot;&gt;editor-menu-bar&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/&lt;span class=&quot;pl-ent&quot;&gt;template&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;EditorMenuBubble&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;editor-menu-bubble /&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; component is renderless and will receive some properties through a scoped slot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Property&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Type&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;commands&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Array&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A list of all commands.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;isActive&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Object&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;An object of functions to check if your selected text is a node or mark. `isActive.{node&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;getMarkAttrs&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Function&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A function to get all mark attributes of your selection.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;focused&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Boolean&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Whether the editor is focused.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;focus&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Function&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A function to focus the editor.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;menu&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Object&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;An object for positioning your menu.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Example&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-text-html-vue&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&amp;lt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-ent&quot;&gt;template&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-ent&quot;&gt;editor-menu-bubble&lt;/span&gt; :&lt;span class=&quot;pl-e&quot;&gt;editor&lt;/span&gt;=&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;editor&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-e&quot;&gt;v-slot&lt;/span&gt;=&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;{ commands, isActive, menu }&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-ent&quot;&gt;div&lt;/span&gt;
      :&lt;span class=&quot;pl-e&quot;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt;=&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;{ &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;is-active&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;menu&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;isActive&lt;/span&gt; }&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
      :&lt;span class=&quot;pl-e&quot;&gt;style&lt;/span&gt;=&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;`&lt;/span&gt;left: &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pse&quot;&gt;${&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;menu&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;left&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pse&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;px; bottom: &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pse&quot;&gt;${&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;menu&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;bottom&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pse&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;px;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;`&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-ent&quot;&gt;button&lt;/span&gt; :&lt;span class=&quot;pl-e&quot;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt;=&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;{ &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;is-active&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;isActive&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;bold&lt;/span&gt;() }&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; @&lt;span class=&quot;pl-e&quot;&gt;click&lt;/span&gt;=&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;commands&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;bold&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
        Bold
      &amp;lt;/&lt;span class=&quot;pl-ent&quot;&gt;button&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-ent&quot;&gt;button&lt;/span&gt; :&lt;span class=&quot;pl-e&quot;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt;=&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;{ &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;is-active&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;isActive&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;heading&lt;/span&gt;({ level&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt; }) }&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; @&lt;span class=&quot;pl-e&quot;&gt;click&lt;/span&gt;=&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;commands&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;heading&lt;/span&gt;({ level&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt; })&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
        H2
      &amp;lt;/&lt;span class=&quot;pl-ent&quot;&gt;button&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;/&lt;span class=&quot;pl-ent&quot;&gt;div&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;/&lt;span class=&quot;pl-ent&quot;&gt;editor-menu-bubble&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/&lt;span class=&quot;pl-ent&quot;&gt;template&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;EditorFloatingMenu&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;editor-floating-menu /&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; component is renderless and will receive some properties through a scoped slot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Property&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Type&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;commands&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Array&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A list of all commands.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;isActive&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Object&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;An object of functions to check if your selected text is a node or mark. `isActive.{node&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;getMarkAttrs&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Function&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A function to get all mark attributes of your selection.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;focused&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Boolean&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Whether the editor is focused.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;focus&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Function&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A function to focus the editor.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;menu&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Object&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;An object for positioning your menu.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Example&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-text-html-vue&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&amp;lt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-ent&quot;&gt;template&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-ent&quot;&gt;editor-floating-menu&lt;/span&gt; :&lt;span class=&quot;pl-e&quot;&gt;editor&lt;/span&gt;=&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;editor&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-e&quot;&gt;v-slot&lt;/span&gt;=&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;{ commands, isActive, menu }&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-ent&quot;&gt;div&lt;/span&gt;
      :&lt;span class=&quot;pl-e&quot;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt;=&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;{ &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;is-active&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;menu&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;isActive&lt;/span&gt; }&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
      :&lt;span class=&quot;pl-e&quot;&gt;style&lt;/span&gt;=&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;`&lt;/span&gt;top: &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pse&quot;&gt;${&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;menu&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;top&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pse&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;px&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;`&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-ent&quot;&gt;button&lt;/span&gt; :&lt;span class=&quot;pl-e&quot;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt;=&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;{ &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;is-active&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;isActive&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;bold&lt;/span&gt;() }&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; @&lt;span class=&quot;pl-e&quot;&gt;click&lt;/span&gt;=&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;commands&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;bold&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
        Bold
      &amp;lt;/&lt;span class=&quot;pl-ent&quot;&gt;button&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-ent&quot;&gt;button&lt;/span&gt; :&lt;span class=&quot;pl-e&quot;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt;=&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;{ &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;is-active&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;isActive&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;heading&lt;/span&gt;({ level&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt; }) }&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; @&lt;span class=&quot;pl-e&quot;&gt;click&lt;/span&gt;=&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;commands&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;heading&lt;/span&gt;({ level&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt; })&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
        H2
      &amp;lt;/&lt;span class=&quot;pl-ent&quot;&gt;button&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;/&lt;span class=&quot;pl-ent&quot;&gt;div&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;/&lt;span class=&quot;pl-ent&quot;&gt;editor-floating-menu&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/&lt;span class=&quot;pl-ent&quot;&gt;template&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Extensions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By default, the editor will only support paragraphs. Other nodes and marks are available as &lt;strong&gt;extensions&lt;/strong&gt;. There is a package called &lt;code&gt;tiptap-extensions&lt;/code&gt; with the most basic nodes, marks, and plugins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Available Extensions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-text-html-vue&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&amp;lt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-ent&quot;&gt;template&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-ent&quot;&gt;div&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-ent&quot;&gt;editor-menu-bar&lt;/span&gt; :&lt;span class=&quot;pl-e&quot;&gt;editor&lt;/span&gt;=&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;editor&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-e&quot;&gt;v-slot&lt;/span&gt;=&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;{ commands, isActive }&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-ent&quot;&gt;button&lt;/span&gt; :&lt;span class=&quot;pl-e&quot;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt;=&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;{ &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;is-active&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;isActive&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;bold&lt;/span&gt;() }&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; @&lt;span class=&quot;pl-e&quot;&gt;click&lt;/span&gt;=&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;commands&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;bold&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
          Bold
        &amp;lt;/&lt;span class=&quot;pl-ent&quot;&gt;button&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;/&lt;span class=&quot;pl-ent&quot;&gt;editor-menu-bar&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-ent&quot;&gt;editor-content&lt;/span&gt; :&lt;span class=&quot;pl-e&quot;&gt;editor&lt;/span&gt;=&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;editor&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; /&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;/&lt;span class=&quot;pl-ent&quot;&gt;div&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/&lt;span class=&quot;pl-ent&quot;&gt;template&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-ent&quot;&gt;script&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; { &lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;Editor&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;EditorContent&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;EditorMenuBar&lt;/span&gt; } &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;tiptap&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; {&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;Blockquote&lt;/span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;CodeBlock&lt;/span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;HardBreak&lt;/span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;Heading&lt;/span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;OrderedList&lt;/span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;BulletList&lt;/span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;ListItem&lt;/span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;TodoItem&lt;/span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;TodoList&lt;/span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;Bold&lt;/span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;Code&lt;/span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;Italic&lt;/span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;Link&lt;/span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;Strike&lt;/span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;Underline&lt;/span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;History&lt;/span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;} &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;tiptap-extensions&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;export&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;default&lt;/span&gt; {&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;  components&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; {&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;    EditorMenuBar,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;    EditorContent,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;  },&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;data&lt;/span&gt;() {&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; {&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;      editor&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;Editor&lt;/span&gt;({&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;        extensions&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; [&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;          &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;Blockquote&lt;/span&gt;(),&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;          &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;CodeBlock&lt;/span&gt;(),&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;          &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;HardBreak&lt;/span&gt;(),&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;          &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;Heading&lt;/span&gt;({ levels&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; [&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;] }),&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;          &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;BulletList&lt;/span&gt;(),&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;          &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;OrderedList&lt;/span&gt;(),&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;          &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;ListItem&lt;/span&gt;(),&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;          &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;TodoItem&lt;/span&gt;(),&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;          &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;TodoList&lt;/span&gt;(),&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;          &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;Bold&lt;/span&gt;(),&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;          &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;Code&lt;/span&gt;(),&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;          &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;Italic&lt;/span&gt;(),&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;          &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;Link&lt;/span&gt;(),&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;          &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;Strike&lt;/span&gt;(),&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;          &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;Underline&lt;/span&gt;(),&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;          &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;History&lt;/span&gt;(),&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;        ],&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;        content&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;`&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;          &amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;Yay Headlines!&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;          &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;All these &amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;cool tags&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt; are working now.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;        &lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;`&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;      }),&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;    }&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;  },&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;beforeDestroy&lt;/span&gt;() {&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;this&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;editor&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;destroy&lt;/span&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;  },&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/&lt;span class=&quot;pl-ent&quot;&gt;script&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Create Custom Extensions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most powerful feature of tiptap is that you can create your own extensions. There are 3 types of extensions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Type&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;Extension&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The most basic type. It's useful to register some &lt;a href=&quot;https://prosemirror.net/docs/guide/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Prosemirror plugins&lt;/a&gt; or some input rules.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;Node&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Add a custom node. Nodes are block elements like a headline or a paragraph.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;Mark&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Add a custom mark. Marks are used to add extra styling or other information to inline content like a strong tag or links.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Extension Class&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Method&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Type&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Default&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;get name()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;String&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;null&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Define a name for your extension.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;get defaultOptions()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Object&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;{}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Define some default options. The options are available as &lt;code&gt;this.$options&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;get plugins()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Array&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;[]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Define a list of &lt;a href=&quot;https://prosemirror.net/docs/guide/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Prosemirror plugins&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;keys({ schema })&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Object&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;null&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Define some keybindings.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;commands({ schema, attrs })&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Object&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;null&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Define a command.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;inputRules({ schema })&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Array&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;[]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Define a list of input rules.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;pasteRules({ schema })&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Array&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;[]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Define a list of paste rules.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;get update()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Function&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;undefined&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Called when options of extension are changed via &lt;code&gt;editor.extensions.options&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Node|Mark Class&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Method&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Type&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Default&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;get name()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;String&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;null&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Define a name for your node or mark.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;get defaultOptions()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Object&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;{}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Define some default options. The options are available as &lt;code&gt;this.$options&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;get schema()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Object&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;null&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Define a &lt;a href=&quot;https://prosemirror.net/docs/guide/#schema&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;schema&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;get view()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Object&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;null&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Define a node view as a vue component.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;keys({ type, schema })&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Object&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;null&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Define some keybindings.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;commands({ type, schema, attrs })&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Object&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;null&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Define a command. For example this is used for menus to convert to this node or mark.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;inputRules({ type, schema })&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Array&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;[]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Define a list of input rules.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;pasteRules({ type, schema })&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Array&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;[]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Define a list of paste rules.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;get plugins()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Array&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;[]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Define a list of &lt;a href=&quot;https://prosemirror.net/docs/guide/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Prosemirror plugins&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Create a Node&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's take a look at a real example. This is basically how the default &lt;code&gt;blockquote&lt;/code&gt; node from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npmjs.com/package/tiptap-extensions&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;tiptap-extensions&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; looks like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-js&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; { &lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;Node&lt;/span&gt; } &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;tiptap&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; { &lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;wrappingInputRule&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;setBlockType&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;toggleWrap&lt;/span&gt; } &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;tiptap-commands&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;export&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;default&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;BlockquoteNode&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;extends&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-e&quot;&gt;Node&lt;/span&gt; {

  &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;//&lt;/span&gt; choose a unique name&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;get&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;() {
    &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;blockquote&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  }

  &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;//&lt;/span&gt; the prosemirror schema object&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;//&lt;/span&gt; take a look at https://prosemirror.net/docs/guide/#schema for a detailed explanation&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;get&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;schema&lt;/span&gt;() {
    &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; {
      content&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;block+&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;,
      group&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;block&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;,
      defining&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;,
      draggable&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;,
      &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;//&lt;/span&gt; define how the editor will detect your node from pasted HTML&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;//&lt;/span&gt; every blockquote tag will be converted to this blockquote node&lt;/span&gt;
      parseDOM&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; [
        { tag&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;blockquote&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; },
      ],
      &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;//&lt;/span&gt; this is how this node will be rendered&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;//&lt;/span&gt; in this case a blockquote tag with a class called `awesome-blockquote` will be rendered&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;//&lt;/span&gt; the '0' stands for its text content inside&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;toDOM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; () &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; [&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;blockquote&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, { class&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;awesome-blockquote&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; }, &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;],
    }
  }

  &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;//&lt;/span&gt; this command will be called from menus to add a blockquote&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;//&lt;/span&gt; `type` is the prosemirror schema object for this blockquote&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;//&lt;/span&gt; `schema` is a collection of all registered nodes and marks&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;commands&lt;/span&gt;({ type, schema }) {
    &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; () &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;toggleWrap&lt;/span&gt;(type)
  }

  &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;//&lt;/span&gt; here you can register some shortcuts&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;//&lt;/span&gt; in this case you can create a blockquote with `ctrl` + `&amp;gt;`&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;keys&lt;/span&gt;({ type }) {
    &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; {
      &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;Ctrl-&amp;gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;toggleWrap&lt;/span&gt;(type),
    }
  }

  &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;//&lt;/span&gt; a blockquote will be created when you are on a new line and type `&amp;gt;` followed by a space&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;inputRules&lt;/span&gt;({ type }) {
    &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; [
      &lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;wrappingInputRule&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;pl-sr&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;^&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;\s&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;\s&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, type),
    ]
  }

}
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Create a Node as a Vue Component&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The real power of the nodes comes in combination with Vue components. Let us build an iframe node, where you can change its URL (this can also be found in our &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scrumpy/tiptap/tree/master/examples/Components/Routes/Embeds&quot;&gt;examples&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-js&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; { &lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;Node&lt;/span&gt; } &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;tiptap&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;export&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;default&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;IframeNode&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;extends&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-e&quot;&gt;Node&lt;/span&gt; {

  &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;get&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;() {
    &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;iframe&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  }

  &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;get&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;schema&lt;/span&gt;() {
    &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; {
      &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;//&lt;/span&gt; here you have to specify all values that can be stored in this node&lt;/span&gt;
      attrs&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; {
        src&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; {
          default&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;null&lt;/span&gt;,
        },
      },
      group&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;block&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;,
      selectable&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;,
      &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;//&lt;/span&gt; parseDOM and toDOM is still required to make copy and paste work&lt;/span&gt;
      parseDOM&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; [{
        tag&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;iframe&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;,
        &lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;getAttrs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;dom&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; ({
          src&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;dom&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;getAttribute&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;src&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;),
        }),
      }],
      &lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;toDOM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;node&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; [&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;iframe&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, {
        src&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;node&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;attrs&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;src&lt;/span&gt;,
        frameborder&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;,
        allowfullscreen&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;true&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;,
      }],
    }
  }

  &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;//&lt;/span&gt; return a vue component&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;//&lt;/span&gt; this can be an object or an imported component&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;get&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;view&lt;/span&gt;() {
    &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; {
      &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;//&lt;/span&gt; there are some props available&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;//&lt;/span&gt; `node` is a Prosemirror Node Object&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;//&lt;/span&gt; `updateAttrs` is a function to update attributes defined in `schema`&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;//&lt;/span&gt; `view` is the ProseMirror view instance&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;//&lt;/span&gt; `options` is an array of your extension options&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;//&lt;/span&gt; `selected`&lt;/span&gt;
      props&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; [&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;node&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;updateAttrs&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;view&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;],
      computed&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; {
        src&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; {
          &lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;get&lt;/span&gt;() {
            &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;this&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;node&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;attrs&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;src&lt;/span&gt;
          },
          &lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;set&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;src&lt;/span&gt;) {
            &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;//&lt;/span&gt; we cannot update `src` itself because `this.node.attrs` is immutable&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;this&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;updateAttrs&lt;/span&gt;({
              src,
            })
          },
        },
      },
      template&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;`&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;        &amp;lt;div class=&quot;iframe&quot;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;          &amp;lt;iframe class=&quot;iframe__embed&quot; :src=&quot;src&quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/iframe&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;          &amp;lt;input class=&quot;iframe__input&quot; type=&quot;text&quot; v-model=&quot;src&quot; v-if=&quot;view.editable&quot; /&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;        &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;      &lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;`&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;,
    }
  }

}
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Development Setup&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, only Yarn is supported for development because of a feature called workspaces we are using here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt; install dependencies&lt;/span&gt;
yarn install

&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt; serve examples at localhost:3000&lt;/span&gt;
yarn start

&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt; build dist files for packages&lt;/span&gt;
yarn build:packages

&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt; build dist files for examples&lt;/span&gt;
yarn build:examples
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please see &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scrumpy/tiptap/blob/master/CONTRIBUTING.md&quot;&gt;CONTRIBUTING&lt;/a&gt; for details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Credits&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Packages Using Tiptap&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Love our work?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.paypal.me/philippkuehn&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Become a backer&lt;/a&gt; ❤️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The MIT License (MIT). Please see &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scrumpy/tiptap/blob/master/LICENSE.md&quot;&gt;License File&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2019 11:48:01 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>hanspagel</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://repository-images.githubusercontent.com/145464445/b5635d80-72a1-11e9-859e-72ff979f8106</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>scrumpy/tiptap</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/scrumpy/tiptap</og:url>
<og:description>A rich-text editor for Vue.js. Contribute to scrumpy/tiptap development by creating an account on GitHub.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/scrumpy/tiptap</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Details about MIDI 2.0</title>
<link>https://www.midi.org/articles-old/details-about-midi-2-0-midi-ci-profiles-and-property-exchange</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.midi.org/articles-old/details-about-midi-2-0-midi-ci-profiles-and-property-exchange</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Introduction to MIDI 2.0&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ebd-block&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; readability=&quot;19&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MIDI 2.0 is the largest set of additions to MIDI since the very first MIDI connection between 2 manufacturers was made at the 1983 NAMM Show. MIDI 1.0 has evolved with many new features over the past 36 years. MIDI 2.0 continues that ongoing evolution and creates a foundation for expansion for many years into the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The MIDI 2.0 updates MIDI with new auto-configuration, extended resolution, increased expressiveness, and tighter timing -- all while maintaining a high priority on backward compatibility. This major update of MIDI paves the way for a new generation of advanced interconnected MIDI devices, while still preserving interoperability with the millions of existing MIDI 1.0 devices. One of the core goals of MIDI 2.0 is to also enhance the MIDI 1.0 feature set whenever possible.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ebd-block&quot; data-type=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;eb-image style-clear&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;eb-image-figure is-responsive&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;eb-image-viewport&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.midi.org/images/easyblog_articles/413/b2ap3_large_MIDI-2.0.002.jpeg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;1.1 MIDI Capability Inquiry (MIDI-CI)&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ebd-block&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; readability=&quot;20&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The additional capabilities that MIDI 2.0 brings to devices are enabled by MIDI-CI. The basic idea is that if devices have a bidirectional connection, they can exchange their capabilities with each other. Devices can share their configuration and what MIDI functions are supported.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Devices use a bidirectional link to configure MIDI features when both devices agree to support that feature. MIDI-CI discovers and configures device features using 3 categories of inquiry: Profile Configuration, Property Exchange, and Protocol Negotiation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;If a device does not support any new features, it uses the MIDI 1.0 as usual. Devices connected to that device will continue to use MIDI 1.0 in communication with that device.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ebd-block&quot; data-type=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;eb-image style-clear&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;eb-image-figure is-responsive&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;eb-image-viewport&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.midi.org/images/easyblog_articles/413/b2ap3_large_MIDI-2.0.00_20190523-231717_1.jpeg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ebd-block&quot; data-type=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;eb-image style-clear&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;eb-image-figure is-responsive&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;eb-image-viewport&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.midi.org/images/easyblog_articles/413/b2ap3_large_MIDI-2.0-Environment-MIDI-CI-Overview-Diagram-9.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;1.2 PROFILE CONFIGURATION&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ebd-block&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; readability=&quot;35&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some common types of MIDI devices that all tend to do very similar things. We can define Profiles to define how MIDI controls the common features. MIDI-CI Profile Configuration allows devices to discover and turn on Profiles for better interoperability and ease of use while lowering the need for manual configuration of devices by users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To explain, let's consider MIDI controlled pianos. Pianos have a lot of characteristics in common and we can control those characteristics by a common set of MIDI messages. MIDI messages used by all pianos include Note On/Off and Sustain Pedal. A Piano Profile might define that Note Number 60 is Middle C, define a specific velocity response curve, define the use of a variable Sustain Pedal (not just On/Off) message, define a controller message for the angle of the lid opening, define a message to select the type of stretch tuning, and more. Any device that reports support for the Piano Profile would have to conform to that design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advanced MIDI users might be familiar with manually &quot;mapping&quot; all the controllers from one device to another device to make them talk to each other. If 2 devices agree to use a common Profile, MIDI-CI Profile Configuration can auto-configure the mappings. Profiles can be written for device types or for unique applications that are used across multiple device types. Profiles might be written for instruments such as pianos, electric pianos, drawbar organs, drum sets, analog synthesizers. Feature Profiles could define common messages to control orchestral articulation, direct pitch control models, or per-note expression. Profile can also serve non-musical applications such as lighting controllers or industrial machines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following video has a demonstration of how Profile Configuration works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ebd-block&quot; data-type=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;eb-image style-clear&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;eb-image-figure is-responsive&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;eb-image-viewport&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.midi.org/images/easyblog_articles/413/Screen-Shot-2018-01-30-at-5.37.17-PM.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ebd-block&quot; data-type=&quot;youtube&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/12gOn9GYatE?feature=oembed&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;270&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;1.3 PROPERTY EXCHANGE&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ebd-block&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; readability=&quot;29&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Property Exchange is a set of System Exclusive messages that devices can use discover, get, and set many properties of MIDI devices. The properties that can be exchanged include device configuration settings, a list of patches with names and other meta data, a list of controllers and their destinations, and much more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Property Exchange can allow for devices to auto map controllers, choose programs by name, change state and also provide visual editors to DAW's without any prior knowledge of the device or specially crafted software. This means that Devices could work on Windows, Mac, Linux, IOS and Web Browsers and may provide tighter integrations with DAW's and hardware controllers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Property Exchange uses JSON inside of the System Exclusive messages. JSON (JavaScript Object Notation) is a human readable format for exchanging data sets. The use of JSON expands MIDI with a whole new area of potential capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ebd-block&quot; data-type=&quot;youtube&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/CrjnMQI8XbE?feature=oembed&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;270&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;1.4 PROTOCOL NEGOTIATION &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ebd-block&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; readability=&quot;20&quot;&gt;MIDI-CI Protocol Negotiation allows devices to select between using the MIDI 1.0 Protocol or the MIDI 2.0 Protocol. Two devices that have established a 2-way MIDI-CI session can select a Protocol and features of that Protocol. &lt;span class=&quot;redactor-invisible-space&quot;&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;redactor-invisible-space&quot;&gt;A MIDI Protocol is the language of MIDI, or the set of messages that MIDI uses. Architectural concepts and semantics from MIDI 1.0 are the same in the MIDI 2.0 Protocol. Compatibility for translation to/from MIDI 1.0 Protocol is given high priority in the design of MIDI 2.0 Protocol.&lt;span class=&quot;redactor-invisible-space&quot;&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;redactor-invisible-space&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;redactor-invisible-space&quot;&gt;The MIDI 1.0 Protocol and the MIDI 2.0 Protocol have many messages in common, messages that are identical in both protocols. The MIDI 2.0 Protocol extends some MIDI 1.0 messages with higher resolution and new features. There are newly defined messages. Some can be used in both protocols and some are exclusive to the MIDI 2.0 Protocol. &lt;span class=&quot;redactor-invisible-space&quot;&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ebd-block&quot; data-type=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;eb-image style-clear&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;eb-image-figure is-responsive&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;eb-image-viewport&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.midi.org/images/easyblog_articles/413/b2ap3_thumbnail_Screen-Shot-2019-05-23-at-5.08.44-PM.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;       1.5 MIDI 1.0 Protocol, MIDI 2.0 Protocol and the Universal MIDI Packet&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ebd-block&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MIDI 2.0 has a new Universal MIDI Packet format for carrying MIDI 1.0 Protocol messages and MIDI 2.0 Protocol messages. A Universal MIDI Packet contains a MIDI message which consists of one to four 32-bit words.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ebd-block&quot; data-type=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;eb-image style-clear&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;eb-image-figure is-responsive&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;eb-image-viewport&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.midi.org/images/easyblog_articles/413/b2ap3_large_Universal-MIDI-Packet-32bit-Words.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ebd-block&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; readability=&quot;14&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Universal MIDI Packet format is suited to sending MIDI data over high speed transports such as USB or a network connection or between applications running inside a personal computer OS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The traditional 5 pin DIN transport from MIDI 1.0 uses a byte stream rather than packets. At the moment, there is no plan to use the Universal MIDI Packet on the 5 pin DIN transport. Unless/Until that plan changes, 5 pin DIN will only support the MIDI 1.0 Protocol.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;1.5.1 Message Types &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ebd-block&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first 4 bits of every message contain a Message Type. The Message Type is used as a classification of message functions.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ebd-block&quot; data-type=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;eb-image style-clear&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;eb-image-figure is-responsive&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;eb-image-viewport&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.midi.org/images/easyblog_articles/413/b2ap3_large_Screen-Shot-2019-05-23-at-4.17.32-PM.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ebd-block&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong data-redactor-tag=&quot;b&quot;&gt;Message Type Examples:&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ebd-block&quot; data-type=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;eb-image style-clear&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;eb-image-figure is-responsive&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;eb-image-viewport&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.midi.org/images/easyblog_articles/413/b2ap3_large_Messages-in-UMP-Examples-AB.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span&gt;1.5.2 Groups &lt;span class=&quot;redactor-invisible-space&quot;&gt;​&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ebd-block&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; readability=&quot;16&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Universal MIDI Packet carries 16 Groups of MIDI messages, each Group containing an independent set of System Messages and 16 MIDI Channels. Therefore, a single connection using the Universal MIDI Packet carries up to 16 sets of System Messages and up to 256 Channels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Each of the 16 Groups can carry either MIDI 1.0 Protocol or MIDI Protocol. Therefore, a single connection can carry both protocols simultaneously. MIDI 1.0 Protocol and MIDI Protocol messages cannot be mixed together within 1 Group.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;1.5.3 Jitter Reduction Timestamps &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ebd-block&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Universal MIDI Packet format adds a Jitter Reduction Timestamp mechanism. A Timestamp can be prepended to any MIDI 1.0 Protocol message or MIDI 2.0 Protocol message for improved timing accuracy.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;1.5.4 MIDI 1.0 Protocol Inside the Universal MIDI Packet &lt;span class=&quot;redactor-invisible-space&quot;&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ebd-block&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All existing MIDI 1.0 messages are carried in the Universal MIDI 1.0. As an example, this diagram from the protocol specification shows how MIDI 1.0 Channel Voice Messages are carried in 32-bit packets:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ebd-block&quot; data-type=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;eb-image style-clear&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;eb-image-figure is-responsive&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;eb-image-viewport&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.midi.org/images/easyblog_articles/413/b2ap3_large_MIDI-1.0-CVM-in-UMP-2.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ebd-block&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; readability=&quot;13&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;System messages, other than System Exclusive, are encoded similarly to Channel Voice Messages. System Exclusive messages vary in size, can be very large, and can span multiple Universal MIDI Packets.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;1.5.5 MIDI 2.0 Protocol Messages &lt;span class=&quot;redactor-invisible-space&quot;&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ebd-block&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The MIDI 2.0 Protocol uses the architecture of MIDI 1.0 Protocol to maintain backward compatibility and easy translation while offering expanded features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Extends the data resolution for all Channel Voice Messages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Makes some messages easier to use by aggregating combination messages into one atomic message.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adds new properties for several Channel Voice Messages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adds several new Channel Voice Messages to provide increased Per-Note control and musical expression.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adds New data messages include System Exclusive 8 and Mixed Data Set. The System Exclusive 8 message is very similar to MIDI 1.0 System Exclusive but with 8-bit data format. The Mixed Data Set Message is used to transfer large data sets, including non-MIDI data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keeps all System messages the same as in MIDI 1.0.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ebd-block&quot; data-type=&quot;heading&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Expanded Resolution and Expanded Capabilities&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ebd-block&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This example of a MIDI 2.0 Protocol Note message shows the expansions beyond the MIDI 1.0 Protocol equivalent. The MIDI 2.0 Protocol Note On has higher resolution Velocity. The 2 new fields, Attribute Type and Attribute data field, provide space for additional data such as articulation or tuning details &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ebd-block&quot; data-type=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;eb-image style-clear&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;eb-image-figure is-responsive&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;eb-image-viewport&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.midi.org/images/easyblog_articles/413/b2ap3_large_MIDI-2.0-Note-On.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ebd-block&quot; data-type=&quot;heading&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Easier to Use: Registered Controllers (RPN) and Assignable Controllers (NRPN)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ebd-block&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; readability=&quot;24&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;​&lt;span&gt;Creating and editing RPNs and NRPNs with MIDI 1.0 Protocol requires the use of compound messages. These can be confusing or difficult for both developers and users. MIDI 2.0 Protocol replaces RPN and NRPN compound messages with single messages. The new Registered Controllers and Assignable Controllers are much easier to use.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The MIDI 2.0 Protocol replaces RPN and NRPN with 16,384 Registered Controllers and 16,384 Assignable Controller that are as easy to use as Control Change messages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Managing so many controllers might be cumbersome. Therefore, Registered Controllers are organized in 128 Banks, each Bank having 128 controllers. Assignable Controllers are also organized in 128 Banks, each Bank having 128 controllers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Registered Controllers and Assignable Controllers support data values up to 32bits in resolution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ebd-block&quot; data-type=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;eb-image style-clear&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;eb-image-figure is-responsive&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;eb-image-viewport&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.midi.org/images/easyblog_articles/413/b2ap3_large_Registered-and-Assignable-Controllers.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;1.5.6 MIDI 2.0 Program Change Message&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ebd-block&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;​ MIDI 2.0 Protocol combines the Program Change and Bank Select mechanism from MIDI 1.0 Protocol into one message. The MIDI 1.0 mechanism for selecting Banks and Programs requires sending three MIDI messages. MIDI 2.0 changes the mechanism by replicating the Banks Select and Program Change in one new MIDI 2.0 Program Change message. Banks and Programs in MIDI 2.0 translate directly to Banks and Programs in MIDI 1.0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ebd-block&quot; data-type=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;eb-image style-clear&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;eb-image-figure is-responsive&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;eb-image-viewport&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.midi.org/images/easyblog_articles/413/b2ap3_large_Program-Change-with-Bank-Select.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ebd-block&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; readability=&quot;18&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The MIDI 2.0 Program Change message always selects a Program. A Bank Valid bit (B) determines whether a Bank Select is also performed by the message.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If Bank Valid = 0, then the receiver performs the Program Change without selecting a new Bank; The receiver keeps its currently selected Bank. Bank MSB and Bank LSB data fields are filled with zeroes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If Bank Valid = 1, then the receiver performs both Bank and Program Change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Other option flags that are not defined yet and are Reserved.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;1.5.7 New Data Messages for MIDI 1.0 Protocol and MIDI 2.0 Protocol &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ebd-block&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New data messages include System Exclusive 8 and Mixed Data Set. The System Exclusive 8 message is very similar to MIDI 1.0 System Exclusive but with 8-bit data format. The Mixed Data Set Message is used to transfer large data sets, including non-MIDI data. Both messages can be used when using the Universal MIDI Packet format for MIDI 1.0 Protocol or MIDI 2.0 Protocol.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;1.6 The Future of MIDI 1.0 &lt;span class=&quot;redactor-invisible-space&quot;&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ebd-block&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; readability=&quot;13&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MIDI 1.0 is not being replaced. Rather it is being extended and is expected to continue, well integrated with the new MIDI 2.0 environment. It is part of the Universal MIDI Packet, the fundamental MIDI data format. Many MIDI devices will not need any of the new features of MIDI 2.0 in order to perform all their functions. Some devices will continue to use the MIDI 1.0 Protocol while using other extensions of MIDI 2.0, such as Profile Configuration or Property Exchange.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span&gt;1.7 When? &lt;span class=&quot;redactor-invisible-space&quot;&gt;​&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ebd-block&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; readability=&quot;42&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;span&gt;The foundational specification, MIDI-CI has been published and is available for download. Other key MIDI 2.0 specifications are nearing completion in the MIDI Manufacturers Association. But it will take several years to write numerous Profile and Property Exchange specifications to follow.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The MMA put out a press release at the beginning of 2019 that listed just some of the companies that are already prototyping or making plans for products to come. Those that agreed to be mentioned include Ableton/Cycling '74, Art+Logic, Bome Software, Google, imitone, Native Instruments, Roland, ROLI, Steinberg, TouchKeys, and Yamaha.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, we do not expect any MIDI 2.0 products to be released in 2019. For MIDI to be fully useable, the industry needs devices, applications, operating systems, and DAWs to support these new specifications. It will take time for a whole system of devices to be available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, MIDI 1.0 works well. In fact, MIDI 2.0 is just more MIDI. As new features arrive on new instruments, they will work with existing devices and system. The same was true for long list of other additions made to MIDI since 1983. MIDI 2.0 is just part of the evolution of MIDI that has gone on for 36 years. The step by step evolution continues. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span&gt;1.8 Why Join the MMA (MIDI Manufacturers Association)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ebd-block&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are a developer of MIDI software or hardware, there are a lot of reasons to join the MIDI Manufacturers Association now.  This article includes some information about MIDI 2.0, but it is definitely not enough to start developing a MIDI 2.0 product.  The reason we do not release specification details before they are finally approved is that if information is released too early and then changes are made, it can lead to interoperability problems.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you join the MMA now, you not only get access to the current version of the full MIDI 2.0 specification, but will also have a voice in future MIDI specifications including Profiles and Property Exchange messages.   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;To implement MIDI-CI and MIDI 2.0, you need a manufactur&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;ers SysEx ID.  A SysEx ID by itself is $250 a year, but it is included with your MMA membership.  You will also&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;have access to the &lt;strong data-redactor-tag=&quot;strong&quot; data-verified=&quot;redactor&quot;&gt;MMA Github&lt;/strong&gt; which has code for MIDI 2.0 to MIDI 1.0 translation (and vis versa),  &lt;strong data-redactor-tag=&quot;strong&quot; data-verified=&quot;redactor&quot;&gt;MIDI 2.0 Scope, &lt;/strong&gt;a tool for sending and testing MIDI 2.0 messages developed by Art and Logic and &lt;strong data-redactor-tag=&quot;strong&quot; data-verified=&quot;redactor&quot;&gt;Property Exchange Work Bench&lt;/strong&gt;, an application developed by Yamaha for prototyping and testing Property Exchange. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;So we encourage you to join the MIDI Manufacturers Association now and get access to all the documents you will need to get a head start on MIDI 2.0. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span&gt;MIDI 2.0 FAQs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ebd-block&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; readability=&quot;74&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;We have been monitoring the comments on a number iof websites and wanted to provide some FAQs about MIDI 2.0 as well as videos of some requested MIDI 2.0 features. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong data-redactor-tag=&quot;b&quot;&gt;Will MIDI 2.0 devices need to use a new connector or cable?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, MIDI 2.0 is a transport agnostic protocol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Transport- To transfer or convey from one place to another&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Agnostic- designed to be compatible with different devices&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Protocol-a set of conventions governing the treatment and especially the formatting of data in an electronic communications system&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;That's engineering speak for MIDI 2.0 is a set of messages and those messages are not tied to any particular cable or connector.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When MIDI first started it could only run over the classic 5 Pin DIN cable and the definition of that connector and how it was built was described in the MIDI 1.0 spec.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However soon the MIDI Manufacturers Association and Association of Music Electronic Industries defined how to run MIDI over many different cables and connectors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So for many years, MIDI 1.0 has been a transport agnostic protocol.. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MIDI 1.0 messages currently run over 5 PIN Din&lt;strong data-redactor-tag=&quot;b&quot;&gt;,&lt;/strong&gt; serial ports, Tip Ring Sleeve 1/8&quot; cables, Firewire and Ethernet and all the different variations of USB cables,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong data-redactor-tag=&quot;b&quot;&gt;Can MIDI 2.0 run over those different MIDI 1.0 transports now?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, there needs to be new specifications written for each transport. There is a new Universal Packet Format that will be common to all modern transports that will help make this work move quicker. The new Universal Packet contains both MIDI 1 .0 messages and MIDI 2.0 messages plus some messages that can be used with both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most popular MIDI transport today is USB. The vast majority of MIDI products are connected to computers or hosts via USB. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;USB is the first target for MIDI 2.0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong data-redactor-tag=&quot;b&quot;&gt;Can MIDI 2.0 provide more reliable timing?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, and not only that the timing for MIDI 1.0 can also be improved. One of the new messages that can work with both MIDI 1.0 and MIDI 2.0 are Jitter Timestamps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goals of JR Timestamps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Capture a performance with accurate timing&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Transmit MIDI message with accurate timing over a system that is subject to jitter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Does not depend on system-wide synchronization, master clock, or explicit clock synchronization between Sender and Receiver&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Note: There are two different sources of error for timing: Jitter (precision) and Latency (sync). &lt;em data-redactor-tag=&quot;i&quot;&gt;The Jitter Reduction Timestamp mechanism only addresses the errors introduced by jitter. The problem of synchronization or time alignment across multiple devices in a system requires a measurement of latency. This is a complex problem and is not addressed by the JR Timestamping mechanism.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong data-redactor-tag=&quot;b&quot;&gt;Can MIDI 2.0 provide more resolution?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, MIDI 1.0 messages are usually 7 bit (14 bit is possible by not widely implmented because there are only 128 CC messages). In MIDI 2.0 velocity is 16 bit and the 128 control change messages, 16,384 Registered Controllers,  16,384 Assignable Controllers, Poly and channel pressure and Pitch Bend are 32 bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong data-redactor-tag=&quot;b&quot;&gt;Can MIDI 2.0 make it easier to have microtonal control and different non-western scales?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, MIDI 2.0 allows direct pitch control of notes ( see videos)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span&gt;Videos of the MIDI 2.0 prototyping session at Winter NAMM 2019 &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ebd-block&quot; data-type=&quot;youtube&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/UQx1L6nojGE?feature=oembed&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;270&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;ebd-block&quot; data-type=&quot;youtube&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/okrZYm5OJzo?feature=oembed&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;270&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;ebd-block&quot; data-type=&quot;youtube&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/x2QxFnsKWMQ?feature=oembed&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;270&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;ebd-block&quot; data-type=&quot;youtube&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/FWf2y7dzULQ?feature=oembed&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;270&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;ebd-block&quot; data-type=&quot;youtube&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/zOysm_lZJmg?feature=oembed&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;270&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;ebd-block&quot; data-type=&quot;image&quot; readability=&quot;6.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;eb-image style-clear&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;eb-image-figure is-responsive&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;eb-image-viewport&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.midi.org/images/easyblog_articles/413/IMG_036_20180131-234337_1.JPG&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Yutaka Hasegawa, Chairman of AMEI (the Japanese MIDI organization)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ebd-block&quot; data-type=&quot;quotes&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;eb-quote style-default&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The really exciting part of MIDI-CI is that Protocol Negotiation paves the way for a new industry standard MIDI protocol which could enable new features like higher resolution, more channels and improved performance and expressiveness (while still maintaining backwards compatibility with current MIDI 1.0 devices). A new MIDI protocol would offer a bridge between music technology and new emerging technologies in other industries and allow creators, performers, and consumers to enjoy new and exciting musical experiences in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;cite&gt;by Yutaka Hasegawa, chairman of AMEI&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;ebd-block&quot; data-type=&quot;youtube&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZAK62mn5-Yc?feature=oembed&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;270&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2019 07:44:10 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>dmoreno</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://www.midi.org/images/easyblog_articles/413/b2ap3_large_MIDI-2.0.003.jpeg</og:image>
<og:title>Details about MIDI 2.0, MIDI-CI, Profiles and Property Exchange</og:title>
<og:description>Introduction to MIDI 2.0 MIDI 2.0 is the largest set of additions to MIDI since the very first MIDI connection between 2 manufacturers was made at the 1983 NAMM Show. MIDI 1.0 has evolved with many new features over the past 36 years. MIDI 2.0 continues that ongoing evolution and creates a foundation for expansion for many years into the future. Th...</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.midi.org/articles-old/details-about-midi-2-0-midi-ci-profiles-and-property-exchange</og:url>
<dc:language>en-gb</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.midi.org/articles-old/details-about-midi-2-0-midi-ci-profiles-and-property-exchange</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The lingua franca of LaTeX</title>
<link>https://increment.com/open-source/the-lingua-franca-of-latex/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://increment.com/open-source/the-lingua-franca-of-latex/</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;ArticleLayout&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1976, Stanford University computer science professor Donald Knuth experienced firsthand a problem that had been plaguing the scientific community in recent years: how to ensure that research papers that included mathematical equations and scientific notation were formatted correctly for printing&lt;span class=&quot;mt-periodPullEnd&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Manual typesetting could produce excellent output, but it was expensive. If an author wanted to write mathematical or other technical notation, the author and a knowledgeable typesetter needed to work closely together&lt;span class=&quot;mt-periodPullEnd&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the 1968 edition of his book &lt;em&gt;The Art of Computer Programming&lt;/em&gt;, Knuth had provided thousands of handwritten manuscript pages to his publisher, Addison-Wesley, which used traditional metal equipment to typeset it. The book contained examples of computer programs, and Knuth explained to the typesetters in detail how he wanted these texts to look. He was happy with the results of that first edition. But eight years later, for the second edition of the expanded book’s second volume, Addison-Wesley had transitioned to cheaper, electronic typesetting methods, and Knuth found the galley proofs they sent him to be subpar&lt;span class=&quot;mt-periodPullEnd&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knuth knew that high-resolution digital typesetting machines could produce precise shapes, but the expertise of professional typesetters had been lost in the transition. What if, he wondered, computer software could do the same job? In 1977, Knuth spent the summer as well as part of his sabbatical year working on just such a digital typography program. With his students, he was able to write a program capable of typesetting the entire 700-page revised volume of his book by 1978. The program, called TeX, revolutionized how scientific papers are formatted and printed. It’s also one of the oldest &lt;span class=&quot;mt-abbrev&quot;&gt;OSS&lt;/span&gt; projects still in use&lt;span class=&quot;mt-periodPullEnd&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;ArticleLayout flipped&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TeX enabled authors to encode their precise intent into their manuscripts: This block of text is a computer program, while this word is a keyword in that program. The language it used, called TeX markup, formalized the slow, error-prone communication that is normally carried out with the printer over repeated galley proofs&lt;span class=&quot;mt-periodPullEnd&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To use TeX, the author writes in a plain-text document with no formatting and inserts TeX’s markup language commands directly into the material. For example, this text:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;The quadratic formula is
$$
&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-string&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-function&quot;&gt;-b&lt;/span&gt; \pm \sqrt&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-function&quot;&gt;{b^&lt;/span&gt;2 &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-function&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; 4&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-function&quot;&gt;ac}&lt;/span&gt;\over &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-function&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;2&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-function&quot;&gt;a}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
$$&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;produces this output:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;j-SmoothLoad&quot; src=&quot;https://increment.com/art/9/latex/example-2000-7e444bd2.jpeg&quot; sizes=&quot;2000px&quot; width=&quot;2000px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea of writing markup inside text wasn’t especially novel; it has been used from 1970’s runoff (the &lt;span class=&quot;mt-abbrev&quot;&gt;UNIX&lt;/span&gt; family of printer-preparation utilities) to today’s &lt;span class=&quot;mt-abbrev&quot;&gt;HTML&lt;/span&gt; tags. TeX was new in that it captured key concepts necessary for realistic typesetting and formalized them&lt;span class=&quot;mt-periodPullEnd&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knuth defined hundreds of typesetting commands. The typesetter that understands these commands is the TeX engine itself, which reads the author’s manuscript and produces a file that can be sent directly to a printer to produce typeset documents&lt;span class=&quot;mt-periodPullEnd&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the scheme of things, the TeX engine understands only a small set of primitive typesetting commands. Knuth also knew that no matter how many commands it understood, TeX could never hope to cover every possible typesetting need for authors. So he wrote TeX to be extensible by users. TeX can be given macros that define new commands in terms of existing commands, meaning people can create macro files to extend TeX without changing the TeX engine&lt;span class=&quot;mt-periodPullEnd&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knuth wrote it to be sufficient for typesetting his own writing. In 1984, he published &lt;em&gt;The TeXbook&lt;/em&gt;, detailing the meanings of all of TeX’s primitive and plain macro commands as well as the inner workings of the engine. The book was intended to enable developers to write their own macros and to make changes to the code&lt;span class=&quot;mt-periodPullEnd&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Knuth’s insistence, the TeX engine source code has been free for over 40 years, and anyone can modify it. But to protect authors’ manuscripts from breaking, Knuth forbade incompatible changed versions of the engine from being called TeX. He published a set of automated tests that must be passed by any modified version of the engine before it can use the name&lt;span class=&quot;mt-periodPullEnd&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TeX became a multiyear collaborative project spreading far beyond the university, as it had to be ported to different computer systems, languages, and printers to typeset manuscripts from other authors. The American Mathematical Society (&lt;span class=&quot;mt-abbrev&quot;&gt;AMS)&lt;/span&gt; in Rhode Island was an early adopter and promoter, and a periodic meeting of TeX users was organized in 1980 to collect user feedback and direct the development of TeX. The TeX Users Group (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mt-abbrev&quot;&gt;TUG&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;) was instrumental in packaging all of the documentation and programs needed to run TeX into a standard distribution, TeX Live. Knuth also frequently contributed to the &lt;span class=&quot;mt-abbrev&quot;&gt;TUG&lt;/span&gt; publication, &lt;em&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mt-abbrev&quot;&gt;TUGb&lt;/span&gt;oat&lt;/em&gt;, to answer in-depth questions and share his views on the future of the program&lt;span class=&quot;mt-periodPullEnd&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knuth revised TeX in 1982 (as TeX82) and again in 1989. Then, in 1992, he retired to focus on finishing the always-expanding book that had been TeX’s impetus: &lt;em&gt;The Art of Computer Programming.&lt;/em&gt; But the work continued&lt;span class=&quot;mt-periodPullEnd&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most users of word processors are happy with only a few dozen commands, like section, subsection, bold, italic, and so on. They would rather the engine made as many of the typesetting decisions as possible&lt;span class=&quot;mt-periodPullEnd&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because TeX’s &lt;code&gt;plain&lt;/code&gt; set of commands is fairly low-level, its best suited for authors who, like Knuth, desire detailed control over the typesetting of their material. But the idea of a high-level, easy-to-use markup language that separates the content from its presentation spurred the creation of Scribe, a program invented in 1980 by Brian Reid at Carnegie Mellon for his doctorate. Scribe gained popularity among technical authors in the early eighties, but it was not free, which limited its circulation&lt;span class=&quot;mt-periodPullEnd&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Sidebar large&quot;&gt;Precise typesetting is critical, particularly for conveying concepts using chemical and mathematical formulas, algorithms, and similar constructs&lt;span class=&quot;mt-periodPullEnd&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the users of Scribe was Leslie Lamport at &lt;span class=&quot;mt-abbrev&quot;&gt;SRI&lt;/span&gt; International. Lamport was already a famous computer scientist in the field of distributed systems, and he was writing a book. He was one of the early users of TeX and wanted to bring the ease of use of Scribe to TeX. He created an alternative macro file called &lt;code&gt;lplain&lt;/code&gt; (“l” for Lamport), with a set of much-easier-to-use commands. He gave this macro file away for free along with TeX. Users then could run a &lt;code&gt;latex&lt;/code&gt; program which made the engine read Lamport’s macros first. Lamport also wrote a book, &lt;em&gt;LaTeX: a Document Preparation System,&lt;/em&gt; to teach authors how to prepare their manuscripts using these commands. For more complex needs, authors could still use the underlying TeX commands&lt;span class=&quot;mt-periodPullEnd&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With these higher-level commands, the free TeX engine, and the LaTeX book, the use of TeX exploded. The macro file has since evolved and changed names, but authors still typically run the program called &lt;code&gt;latex&lt;/code&gt; or its variants. Hence, most people who write TeX manuscripts know the program as LaTeX and the commands they use as LaTeX commands&lt;span class=&quot;mt-periodPullEnd&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The effect of LaTeX on scientific and technical publishing has been profound. Precise typesetting is critical, particularly for conveying concepts using chemical and mathematical formulas, algorithms, and similar constructs. The sheer volume of papers, journals, books, and other publications generated in the modern world is far beyond the throughput possible via manual typesetting. And TeX enables automation without losing precision&lt;span class=&quot;mt-periodPullEnd&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to LaTeX, book authors can generate camera-ready copy on their own. Most academic and journal publishers accept article manuscripts written in LaTeX, and there’s even &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/&quot; null=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;an open archive maintained by Cornell University&lt;/a&gt; where authors of papers in physics, chemistry, and other disciplines can directly submit their LaTeX manuscripts for open viewing. Over 10,000 manuscripts are submitted to this archive every month from all over the world&lt;span class=&quot;mt-periodPullEnd&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LaTeX’s easy adaptability continues to win ardent followers. &lt;span class=&quot;mt-quotePull&quot;&gt;“&lt;/span&gt;I adore LaTeX because I can focus on writing instead of spending hours twiddling with getting the style just right,” says Mika McKinnon, a disaster researcher and geophysicist who started using LaTeX while writing her master’s thesis at the University of British Columbia. &lt;span class=&quot;mt-quotePull&quot;&gt;“&lt;/span&gt;If I do a good job with how I set up my LaTeX files, I can format and repurpose for any publication or style guide with minimum manual fixes.&lt;span class=&quot;mt-quotePullEnd&quot;&gt;”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Norbert Preining, a TeX user and fan in Japan, has even launched a Facebook group for users. &lt;span class=&quot;mt-quotePull&quot;&gt;“&lt;/span&gt;We are not yet sure how effective it will be, but I think of it as making information more accessible in different channels than the ones we classically use, such as mailing lists and printed information,” Preining says&lt;span class=&quot;mt-periodPullEnd&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While modern desktop publishing has benefited greatly from innovations first introduced by TeX decades ago, it has also largely taken over the typesetting of nontechnical material. In fact, most people have never heard of TeX&lt;span class=&quot;mt-periodPullEnd&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As free open-source software supported directly by its users, TeX doesn’t have any marketing push behind it. Since no one is making money off of it, there is no commercial incentive to make it popular. But that alone isn’t the whole story&lt;span class=&quot;mt-periodPullEnd&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because the TeX typesetting engine was developed before digital formats for typefaces had been standardized, Knuth had to invent his own format for font files; design a set of font families, Computer Modern; and invent his own typeface design program, Metafont. Along with TeX, Knuth also gave away his fonts, so that people could legally exchange documents without getting sued for using proprietary fonts&lt;span class=&quot;mt-periodPullEnd&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tech industry, meanwhile, was inventing, evolving, and protecting its own font formats: Adobe Type 1 and Type 3 (popularized in 1985 with the first PostScript printer), TrueType by Apple (1991), TrueType Open by Microsoft (1994), and OpenType by Microsoft and Adobe (1996). Even as TeX became successfully embedded in more and more manuscripts, the industry continued to evolve its designs in a different direction. To support the new font formats, TeX had to be modified&lt;span class=&quot;mt-periodPullEnd&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The disconnect between technical or scientific and nontechnical authors is also fundamental to understanding TeX’s mainstream obscurity: In nontechnical publishing, typesetting is usually not essential for conveying the author’s intent. Typesetting is considered ornamental; authors of popular material are content to send a Word document to their publisher and let professionals do the rest. Technical authors, on the other hand, need to convey their meaning precisely through glyphs, sizes, and placement. TeX lets them do that, as well as exchange their documents in a widely understood format&lt;span class=&quot;mt-periodPullEnd&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being a command-line tool, TeX is easy to integrate into automation workflows. A user comfortable with TeX can prepare their material once and then format it multiple times for different publications with their own formatting guidelines&lt;span class=&quot;mt-periodPullEnd&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For many users, a practical difficulty with typesetting using TeX is preparing the manuscripts. When TeX was first developed, technical authors were accustomed to using plain-text editors like WordStar, vi, or Emacs with a computer keyboard. The idea of marking up their text with commands and running the manuscript through a typesetting engine felt natural to them&lt;span class=&quot;mt-periodPullEnd&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today’s typesetters, particularly desktop publishers, have a different mental model. They expect to see the output in graphical form and then to visually make edits with a mouse and keyboard, as they would in any &lt;span class=&quot;mt-abbrev&quot;&gt;WYSIWYG&lt;/span&gt; program. They might not be too picky about the quality of the output, but they appreciate design capabilities, such as the ability to flow text around curved outlines. Many print products are now produced with tools like Microsoft Word for this very reason. TeX authors cannot do the same work as easily&lt;span class=&quot;mt-periodPullEnd&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, vendors of commercial typesetting and design products have every incentive to tout their own wares instead of a free program. Early on, their products incorporated some of TeX’s free algorithms: in particular, line-breaking and hyphenation added by Knuth’s students. Frank Liang wrote his doctoral thesis on how to hyphenate words in typesetting paragraphs; his code is in the TeX engine and is freely available&lt;span class=&quot;mt-periodPullEnd&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dave Walden, an active member of &lt;span class=&quot;mt-abbrev&quot;&gt;TUG,&lt;/span&gt; points out that &lt;span class=&quot;mt-quotePull&quot;&gt;“&lt;/span&gt;the world of TeX has always been somewhat out of sync with the commercial desktop publishing systems that began to come out in the mid-1980s and are now ubiquitous in the worlds of publishing and printing.&lt;span class=&quot;mt-quotePullEnd&quot;&gt;”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He adds, &lt;span class=&quot;mt-quotePull&quot;&gt;“&lt;/span&gt;Maybe it’s like the difference between starting a company to sell a commercial project and starting an eventually major open-source development project, although the phrase ‘open source’ didn’t exist when Knuth set things up as he did.&lt;span class=&quot;mt-quotePullEnd&quot;&gt;”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ArticleLayout&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1991, the LaTeX Project formally took over the maintenance and development of LaTeX 2.09 from Leslie Lamport. The team, led by Frank Mittelbach in Germany, is a core group of dedicated developers who greatly extended and effectively rewrote the LaTeX kernel, a core infrastructure now used by many packages that are continuously being added by developers around the world. LaTeX2e, a new version of LaTeX, was released in the early nineties, and is the version installed and used as LaTeX today&lt;span class=&quot;mt-periodPullEnd&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Sidebar large&quot;&gt;It remains the lingua franca for generations of students and researchers&lt;span class=&quot;mt-periodPullEnd&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, in responding to user requirements, the volunteer developers on TeX and related programs have extended the TeX engine itself to make changes easier. Multiple independent efforts have produced three modified engines: to read TrueType and OpenType fonts directly (XeTeX), to produce PostScript and &lt;span class=&quot;mt-abbrev&quot;&gt;PDF&lt;/span&gt; output (in earlier years, using a separate program called &lt;code&gt;dvips&lt;/code&gt;, and now through an extension called pdfTeX), and to read Unicode input (LuaTeX, as well as XeTeX). LuaTeX allows developers to write powerful extensions to the TeX engine in the programming language Lua. And, with desktop computers that are orders of magnitude faster than they were in the 1990s, it’s quite possible to make substantial extensions. These three slightly modified engines are now in use. A longer-term project called LaTeX3, Mittelbach adds, is underway&lt;span class=&quot;mt-periodPullEnd&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What lies in store for one of the oldest open-source projects still active?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mt-quotePull&quot;&gt;“&lt;/span&gt;LaTeX will stay with us for a long time, largely due to the quality of the underlying TeX engine, which even through its 40 years has not been surpassed by any other software,” Mittelbach says. &lt;span class=&quot;mt-quotePull&quot;&gt;“&lt;/span&gt;In scientific writing, it remains the lingua franca for generations of students and researchers.&lt;span class=&quot;mt-quotePullEnd&quot;&gt;”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2019 01:07:48 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>JohnHammersley</dc:creator>
<og:title>The lingua franca of LaTeX – Increment: Open Source</og:title>
<og:url>https://increment.com/open-source/the-lingua-franca-of-latex/</og:url>
<og:description>How Donald Knuth’s 1978 typesetting program became one of the oldest still-active open-source projects and revolutionized technical publishing along the way.</og:description>
<og:image>https://increment.com/art/9/latex/cover-1000-cd7315a4.jpeg</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://increment.com/open-source/the-lingua-franca-of-latex/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>First American Financial Corp. Leaked Hundreds of Millions of Insurance Records</title>
<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2019/05/first-american-financial-corp-leaked-hundreds-of-millions-of-title-insurance-records/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://krebsonsecurity.com/2019/05/first-american-financial-corp-leaked-hundreds-of-millions-of-title-insurance-records/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The Web site for Fortune 500 real estate title insurance giant &lt;strong&gt;First American Financial Corp.&lt;/strong&gt; [&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.marketbeat.com/stocks/NYSE/FAF/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;NYSE:FAF&lt;/a&gt;] leaked hundreds of millions of documents related to mortgage deals going back to 2003, until notified this week by KrebsOnSecurity. The digitized records — including bank account numbers and statements, mortgage and tax records, Social Security numbers, wire transaction receipts, and drivers license images — were available without authentication to anyone with a Web browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_47830&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot; wp-image-47830&quot; src=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/firstamericanfinancial.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;597&quot; height=&quot;355&quot; /&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;First American Financial Corp. Image: Linkedin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Santa Ana, Calif.-based &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/First_American_Corporation&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;First American&lt;/a&gt; is a leading provider of title insurance and settlement services to the real estate and mortgage industries. It employs some 18,000 people and brought in &lt;a href=&quot;http://fortune.com/fortune500/first-american-financial/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;more than $5.7 billion in 2018&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earlier this week, KrebsOnSecurity was contacted by a real estate developer in Washington state who said he’d had little luck getting a response from the company about what he found, which was that a portion of its Web site (firstam.com) was leaking tens if not hundreds of millions of records. He said anyone who knew the URL for a valid document at the Web site could view other documents just by modifying a single digit in the link.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this would potentially include anyone who’s ever been sent a document link via email by First American.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KrebsOnSecurity confirmed the real estate developer’s findings, which indicate that First American’s Web site exposed approximately 885 million files, the earliest dating back more than 16 years. No authentication was required to read the documents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of the exposed files are records of wire transactions with bank account numbers and other information from home or property buyers and sellers. &lt;strong&gt;Ben Shoval&lt;/strong&gt;, the developer who notified KrebsOnSecurity about the data exposure, said that’s because First American is one of the most widely-used companies for real estate title insurance and for closing real estate deals — where both parties to the sale meet in a room and sign stacks of legal documents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Closing agencies are supposed to be the only neutral party that doesn’t represent someone else’s interest, and you’re required to have title insurance if you have any kind of mortgage,” Shoval said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The title insurance agency collects all kinds of documents from both the buyer and seller, including Social Security numbers, drivers licenses, account statements, and even internal corporate documents if you’re a small business. &lt;span class=&quot;pullquote pqright&quot;&gt;You give them all kinds of private information and you expect that to stay private.&lt;/span&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shoval shared a document link he’d been given by First American from a recent transaction, which referenced a record number that was nine digits long and dated April 2019. Modifying the document number in his link by numbers in either direction yielded other peoples’ records before or after the same date and time, indicating the document numbers may have been issued sequentially.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The earliest document number available on the site – 000000075 — referenced a real estate transaction from 2003. From there, the dates on the documents get closer to real time with each forward increment in the record number.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_47843&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; readability=&quot;33&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;lightbox&quot; href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/sample-fa.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-47843&quot; src=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/sample-fa.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;585&quot; height=&quot;478&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;A redacted screenshot of one of many millions of sensitive records exposed by First American’s Web site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of the morning of May 24, firstam.com was returning documents up to the present day (885,000,000+), including many PDFs and post-dated forms for upcoming real estate closings. By 2 p.m. ET Friday, the company had disabled the site that served the records. It’s not yet clear how long the site remained in its promiscuous state, but archive.org shows documents available from the site dating back to at least March 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First American wouldn’t comment on the overall number of records potentially exposed via their site, or how long those records were publicly available. But a spokesperson for the company did share the following statement:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“First American has learned of a design defect in an application that made possible unauthorized access to customer data.  At First American, security, privacy and confidentiality are of the highest priority and we are committed to protecting our customers’ information. The company took immediate action to address the situation and shut down external access to the application. We are currently evaluating what effect, if any, this had on the security of customer information. We will have no further comment until our internal review is completed.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I should emphasize that these documents were merely available from First American’s Web site; I do not have any information on whether this fact was known to fraudsters previously, nor do I have any information to suggest the documents were somehow mass-harvested (although a low-and-slow or distributed indexing of this data would not have been difficult for even a novice attacker).&lt;span id=&quot;more-47813&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, the information exposed by First American would be a virtual gold mine for phishers and scammers involved in so-called Business Email Compromise (BEC) scams, which often impersonate real estate agents, closing agencies, title and escrow firms in a bid to &lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/2017/04/blind-trust-in-email-could-cost-you-your-home/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;trick property buyers into wiring funds to fraudsters&lt;/a&gt;. According to the FBI, BEC scams are the most costly form of cybercrime today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Armed with a single link to a First American document, BEC scammers would have an endless supply of very convincing phishing templates to use. A database like this also would give fraudsters a constant feed of new information about upcoming real estate financial transactions — &lt;em&gt;including the email addresses, names and phone numbers of the closing agents and buyers&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As noted in past stories here, these types of data exposures are some of the most common yet preventable. In December 2018, the parent company of &lt;strong&gt;Kay Jewelers&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Jared Jewelers&lt;/strong&gt; fixed a weakness in their site that &lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/2018/12/jared-kay-jewelers-parent-fixes-data-leak/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;exposed the order information for all of their online customers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In August 2018, financial industry giant &lt;strong&gt;Fiserv Inc.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/2018/08/fiserv-flaw-exposed-customer-data-at-hundreds-of-banks/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;fixed a bug reported by KrebsOnSecurity&lt;/a&gt; that exposed personal and financial details of countless customers across hundreds of bank Web sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In July 2018, identity theft protection service &lt;strong&gt;LifeLock&lt;/strong&gt; corrected an information disclosure flaw that &lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/2018/07/lifelock-bug-exposed-millions-of-customer-email-addresses/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;exposed the email address of millions of subscribers&lt;/a&gt;. And in April 2018, PaneraBread.com &lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/2018/04/panerabread-com-leaks-millions-of-customer-records/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;remedied a weakness&lt;/a&gt; exposing millions of customer names, email and physical addresses, birthdays and partial credit card numbers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;mid-banner&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.akamai.com/us/en/security.jsp?utm_source=krebsonsecurity&amp;amp;utm_medium=display&amp;amp;utm_id=F-MC-44701&amp;amp;utm_campaign=unifiedsecurity_digital_2019&amp;amp;utm_content=unifiedsecurity_global&amp;amp;utm_term=unifiedsecurity_ros&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/b-akamai/15.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;small&quot;&gt;Tags: &lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/tag/ben-shoval/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;Ben Shoval&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/tag/first-american-financial-corp/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;First American Financial Corp.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;postmetadata alt&quot;&gt;&lt;small&gt;This entry was posted on Friday, May 24th, 2019 at 4:47 pm and is filed under &lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/category/data-breaches/&quot; rel=&quot;category tag&quot;&gt;Data Breaches&lt;/a&gt;. You can follow any comments to this entry through the &lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/2019/05/first-american-financial-corp-leaked-hundreds-of-millions-of-title-insurance-records/feed/&quot;&gt;RSS 2.0&lt;/a&gt; feed. You can skip to the end and leave a comment. Pinging is currently not allowed.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2019 20:56:53 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>PatrolX</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2019/05/first-american-financial-corp-leaked-hundreds-of-millions-of-title-insurance-records/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why Does Windows Really Use Backslash as Path Separator?</title>
<link>http://www.os2museum.com/wp/why-does-windows-really-use-backslash-as-path-separator/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.os2museum.com/wp/why-does-windows-really-use-backslash-as-path-separator/</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.os2museum.com/wp/why-does-windows-really-use-backslash-as-path-separator/&quot;&gt;http://www.os2museum.com/wp/why-does-windows-really-use-backslash-as-path-separator/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=20004738&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=20004738&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 254&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 180&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2019 19:49:49 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Narishma</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2019/05/first-american-financial-corp-leaked-hundreds-of-millions-of-title-insurance-records/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Algorithm Solves Graph Isomorphism in Record Time (2015)</title>
<link>https://www.quantamagazine.org/algorithm-solves-graph-isomorphism-in-record-time-20151214/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.quantamagazine.org/algorithm-solves-graph-isomorphism-in-record-time-20151214/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;A theoretical computer scientist has presented an algorithm that is being hailed as a breakthrough in mapping the obscure terrain of complexity theory, which explores how hard computational problems are to solve. Last month, &lt;a href=&quot;http://people.cs.uchicago.edu/~laci/&quot;&gt;László Babai&lt;/a&gt;, of the University of Chicago, announced that he had come up with a new algorithm for the “graph isomorphism” problem, one of the most tantalizing mysteries in computer science. The new algorithm appears to be vastly more efficient than the previous best algorithm, which had held the record for more than 30 years. His &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/abs/1512.03547v1&quot;&gt;paper became available today&lt;/a&gt; on the scientific preprint site arxiv.org, and he has also submitted it to the Association for Computing Machinery’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://acm-stoc.org/stoc2016/&quot;&gt;48th Symposium on Theory of Computing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;January 15, 2017, update:&lt;/em&gt; On January 4, Babai retracted his claim that the new algorithm runs in quasi-polynomial time and then five days later announced that he had fixed the error. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.quantamagazine.org/20170114-graph-isomorphism-babai-fix/&quot;&gt;Read more on the Abstractions blog&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;simple_aside alignright&quot;&gt;

&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.quantamagazine.org/20170105-graph-isomorphism-retraction/&quot;&gt;Complexity Theory Problem Strikes Back&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The legendary graph isomorphism problem may be harder than a 2015 result seemed to suggest.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For decades, the graph isomorphism problem has held a special status within complexity theory. While thousands of other computational problems have meekly succumbed to categorization as either hard or easy, graph isomorphism has defied classification. It seems easier than the hard problems, but harder than the easy problems, occupying a sort of no man’s land between these two domains. It is one of the two most famous problems in this strange gray area, said &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.csail.mit.edu/user/1324&quot;&gt;Scott Aaronson&lt;/a&gt;, a complexity theorist at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology. Now, he said, “it looks as if one of the two may have fallen.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Babai’s announcement has electrified the theoretical computer science community. If his work proves correct, it will be “one of the big results of the decade, if not the last several decades,” said &lt;a href=&quot;http://tuvalu.santafe.edu/~jgrochow/&quot;&gt;Joshua Grochow&lt;/a&gt;, a computer scientist at the Santa Fe Institute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;podcast-aside&quot;&gt;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Computer scientists use the word “graph” to refer to a network of nodes with edges connecting some of the nodes. The graph isomorphism question simply asks when two graphs are really the same graph in disguise because there’s a one-to-one correspondence (an “isomorphism”) between their nodes that preserves the ways the nodes are connected. The problem is easy to state, but tricky to solve, since even small graphs can be made to look very different just by moving their nodes around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, Babai has taken what appears to be a major step forward in pinning down the problem’s difficulty level, by setting forth what he asserts is a “quasi-polynomial-time” algorithm to solve it. As Aaronson describes it, the algorithm places the problem within “the greater metropolitan area” of P, the class of problems that can be solved efficiently. While this new work is not the final word on how hard the graph isomorphism problem is, researchers see it as a game changer. “Before his announcement, I don’t think anyone, except maybe for him, thought this result was going to happen in the next 10 years, or perhaps even ever,” Grochow said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In recent weeks, Babai gave four talks outlining his algorithm. It will take time for his new paper to be thoroughly vetted by other experts, however. Babai has declined to speak to the press, writing in an email: “The integrity of science requires that new results be subjected to thorough review by expert colleagues before the results are publicized in the media.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other researchers are cautiously hopeful that his proof will pan out. “Babai has a sterling record,” Aaronson said. “He’s as trustworthy as they come.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I think people are pretty optimistic,” said &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.eecs.berkeley.edu/~luca/&quot;&gt;Luca Trevisan&lt;/a&gt;, a computer scientist at the University of California, Berkeley, after Babai’s second talk. Assuming the proof is correct, he said, “it’s a landmark result.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;A Blind Taste Test&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given two graphs, one way to check whether they are isomorphic is simply to consider every possible way to match up the nodes in one graph with the nodes in the other. But for graphs with &lt;em&gt;n&lt;/em&gt; nodes, the number of different matchings is &lt;em&gt;n&lt;/em&gt; factorial (1 * 2 * 3 * … * &lt;em&gt;n&lt;/em&gt;), which is so much larger than &lt;em&gt;n&lt;/em&gt; that this brute-force approach is hopelessly impractical for all but the smallest graphs. For graphs with just 10 nodes, for instance, there are already more than 3 million possible matchings to check. And for graphs with 100 nodes, the number of possible matchings far exceeds the estimated number of atoms in the observable universe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Computer scientists generally consider an algorithm to be efficient if its running time can be expressed not as a factorial but as a polynomial, such as &lt;em&gt;n&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; or &lt;em&gt;n&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;; polynomials grow much more slowly than factorials or exponential functions such as 2&lt;em&gt;&lt;sup&gt;n&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. Problems that have a polynomial-time algorithm are said to be in the class P, and over the decades since this class was first proposed, thousands of natural problems in all areas of science and engineering have been shown to belong to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Computer scientists think of the problems in P as relatively easy, and they think of the thousands of problems in another category, “NP-complete,” as hard. No one has ever found an efficient algorithm for an NP-complete problem, and most computer scientists believe no one ever will. The question of whether the NP-complete problems are truly harder than the ones in P is the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.claymath.org/millennium-problems/millennium-prize-problems&quot;&gt;million-dollar&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.quantamagazine.org/20150929-edit-distance-computational-complexity/&quot;&gt;P versus NP problem&lt;/a&gt;, widely regarded as one of the most important open questions in mathematics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The graph isomorphism problem is neither known to be in P nor known to be NP-complete; instead, it seems to hover between the two categories. It is one of only a tiny handful of natural problems that occupy this limbo; the only other such problem that’s as well-known as graph isomorphism is the problem of factoring a number into primes. “Lots of people have spent time working on graph isomorphism, because it’s a very natural, simple-to-state problem, but it’s also so mysterious,” Grochow said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are good reasons to suspect that graph isomorphism is not NP-complete. For example, it has a strange property that no NP-complete problem has ever been shown to have: It’s possible, in theory, for an all-knowing being (“Merlin”) to convince an ordinary person (“Arthur”) that two graphs are different without giving away any hints about where the differences lie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This “zero-knowledge” proof is similar to the way Merlin could convince Arthur that Coke and Pepsi have different formulas even if Arthur can’t taste the difference between them. All Merlin would have to do is take repeated blind taste tests; if he can always correctly identify Coke and Pepsi, Arthur must accept that the two drinks are different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, if Merlin told Arthur that two graphs are different, Arthur could test this assertion by putting the two graphs behind his back, moving their nodes around so that they looked very different from the way they started, and then showing them to Merlin and asking him which was which. If the two graphs are really isomorphic, there’s no way Merlin could tell. So if Merlin gets these questions right again and again, Arthur will eventually conclude that the two graphs must be different, even if he can’t spot the differences himself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No one has ever found a blind-taste-test protocol for any NP-complete problem. For that and other reasons, there’s a fairly strong consensus among theoretical computer scientists that graph isomorphism is probably not NP-complete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the reverse question — whether graph isomorphism is in P — the evidence is more mixed. On the one hand, there are practical algorithms for graph isomorphism that can’t solve the problem efficiently for every single graph, but that do well on almost any graph you might throw at them, even randomly chosen ones. Computer scientists have to work hard to come up with graphs that trip these algorithms up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, graph isomorphism is what computer scientists call a “universal” problem: Every possible problem about whether two “combinatorial structures” are isomorphic — for example, the question of whether two different Sudoku puzzles are really the same underlying puzzle — can be recast as a graph isomorphism problem. This means that a fast algorithm for graph isomorphism would solve all these problems at once. “Usually when you have that kind of universality, it implies some kind of hardness,” Grochow said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2012, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cs.umd.edu/users/gasarch/&quot;&gt;William Gasarch&lt;/a&gt;, a computer scientist at the University of Maryland, College Park, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cs.umd.edu/~gasarch/papers/poll2012.pdf&quot;&gt;informally polled&lt;/a&gt; theoretical computer scientists about the graph isomorphism problem and found that 14 people believed it belongs to P, while six believed that it does not. Before Babai’s announcement, many people didn’t expect the problem to be resolved anytime soon. “I kind of thought maybe it was not in P, or maybe it was but we wouldn’t know in my lifetime,” Grochow said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Paint by Numbers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Babai’s proposed algorithm doesn’t bring graph isomorphism all the way into P, but it comes close. It is quasi-polynomial, he asserts, which means that for a graph with &lt;em&gt;n&lt;/em&gt; nodes, the algorithm’s running time is comparable to &lt;em&gt;n&lt;/em&gt; raised not to a constant power (as in a polynomial) but to a power that grows very slowly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://dl.acm.org/citation.cfm?id=808746&quot;&gt;previous best algorithm&lt;/a&gt; — which Babai was also involved in creating in 1983 with Eugene Luks, now a professor emeritus at the University of Oregon — ran in “subexponential” time, a running time whose distance from quasi-polynomial time is nearly as big as the gulf between exponential time and polynomial time. Babai, who started working on graph isomorphism in 1977, “has been chipping away at this problem for about 40 years,” Aaronson said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Babai’s new algorithm starts by taking a small set of nodes in the first graph and virtually “painting” each one a different color. Then it begins to look for an isomorphism by making an initial guess about which nodes in the second graph might correspond to these nodes, and it paints those nodes the same colors as their corresponding nodes in the first graph. The algorithm eventually cycles through all possible guesses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the initial guess has been made, it constrains what other nodes may do: For example, a node that is connected to the blue node in the first graph must correspond to a node that is connected to the blue node in the second graph. To keep track of these constraints, the algorithm introduces new colors: It might paint nodes yellow if they are linked to a blue node and a red node, or green if they are connected to a red node and two yellow nodes, and so on. The algorithm keeps introducing more colors until there are no connectivity features left to capture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the graphs are colored, the algorithm can rule out all matchings that pair nodes of different colors. If the algorithm is lucky, the painting process will divide the graphs into many chunks of different colors, greatly reducing the number of possible isomorphisms the algorithm has to consider. If, instead, most of the nodes end up the same color, Babai has developed a different way to reduce the number of possible isomorphisms, which works except in one case: when the two graphs contain a structure related to a “Johnson graph.” These are graphs that have so much symmetry that the painting process and Babai’s further refinements just don’t give enough information to guide the algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=S5ovzZJ8vI8&quot;&gt;first of several talks on his new algorithm&lt;/a&gt;, on November 10, Babai called these Johnson graphs “a source of just unspeakable misery” to computer scientists working on painting schemes for the graph isomorphism problem. But Johnson graphs can be handled fairly easily by other methods, so by showing that these graphs are the only obstacle to his painting scheme, Babai was able to tame them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Babai’s approach is “a very natural strategy, very clean in some sense,” said &lt;a href=&quot;http://people.cs.uchicago.edu/~simon/&quot;&gt;Janos Simon&lt;/a&gt;, a computer scientist at the University of Chicago. “It’s very likely that it’s the correct one, but all mathematicians are cautious.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though the new algorithm has moved graph isomorphism much closer to P than ever before, Babai speculated in his first talk that the problem may lie just outside its borders, in the suburbs rather than the city center. That would be the most interesting possibility, Trevisan said, since it would make graph isomorphism the first natural problem to have a quasi-polynomial algorithm but no polynomial algorithm. “It would show that the landscape of complexity theory is much richer than we thought,” he said. If this is indeed the case, however, don’t expect a proof anytime soon: Proving it would amount to solving the P versus NP problem, since it would mean that graph isomorphism separates the problems in P from the NP-complete problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many computer scientists believe, instead, that graph isomorphism is now on a glide path that will eventually send it coasting into P. That is the usual trajectory, Trevisan said, once a quasi-polynomial algorithm has been found. Then again, “somehow this problem has surprised people many times,” he said. “Maybe there’s one more surprise coming.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article was reprinted on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wired.com/2015/12/landmark-algorithm-breaks-30-year-impasse/&quot;&gt;Wired.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2019 19:44:45 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>howard941</dc:creator>
<og:title>Algorithm Solves Graph Isomorphism in Record Time | Quanta Magazine</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.quantamagazine.org/algorithm-solves-graph-isomorphism-in-record-time-20151214/</og:url>
<og:image>https://d2r55xnwy6nx47.cloudfront.net/uploads/2015/11/MorphingShapes_613x343.gif</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.quantamagazine.org/algorithm-solves-graph-isomorphism-in-record-time-20151214/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>OKRs from a development team’s perspective</title>
<link>https://zafulabs.com/2019/05/24/okrs-from-a-development-teams-perspective/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://zafulabs.com/2019/05/24/okrs-from-a-development-teams-perspective/</guid>
<description>&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;182&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://zafulabs.com/adobestock_244902489/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://zafulabs.files.wordpress.com/2019/05/adobestock_244902489.png&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1000,667&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;adobestock_244902489&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://zafulabs.files.wordpress.com/2019/05/adobestock_244902489.png?w=300&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://zafulabs.files.wordpress.com/2019/05/adobestock_244902489.png?w=680&quot; src=&quot;https://zafulabs.files.wordpress.com/2019/05/adobestock_244902489.png?w=680&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-182&quot; srcset=&quot;https://zafulabs.files.wordpress.com/2019/05/adobestock_244902489.png?w=680 680w, https://zafulabs.files.wordpress.com/2019/05/adobestock_244902489.png?w=150 150w, https://zafulabs.files.wordpress.com/2019/05/adobestock_244902489.png?w=300 300w, https://zafulabs.files.wordpress.com/2019/05/adobestock_244902489.png?w=768 768w, https://zafulabs.files.wordpress.com/2019/05/adobestock_244902489.png 1000w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most of the companies I’ve worked for in the last 5 years have used the OKR system. Although this system was invented in the 70s, it has more recently become popular at Google and has spread through the tech world.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s a simple system where the company defines a number of Objectives, and each objective has one or more measurable Key Results. Those KRs are intended to track progress on that objective over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Objective – Increase Customer Retention&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Key Result #1 – Lifetime Customer value increase from $N to $N+5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Key Result #2 – Decrease Customer Churn Rate by 10%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most companies I’ve been at usually have 3-5 OKRs active at any given time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What OKRs are supposed to do for a company&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea is basically that everyone has some very clear, direct and measurable goals to align behind. Everything a team does should align to a specific OKR. In theory, that means everyone is rowing in the same direction(s).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It works great at certain levels and in certain ways. For the leadership team, it typically seems to be an excellent mechanism. It can put all the leaders on the same page(s) and provide a great starting point for the quarter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;wp-block-quote&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It can put all the leaders on the same page(s) and provide a great starting point for the quarter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;When it comes time for a dev team make decisions…&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where OKRs become less useful is within the decision making process for an individual team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;wp-block-quote&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where OKRs become less useful is within the decision making process for an individual team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;cite&gt;Joe Cannatti&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most common pattern I’ve seen goes like this&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;The team comes in with a backlog of things that they want to work on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They discuss each item and work out a basic list ordered by priority. The cut out things they know they aren’t going to get to any time soon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They go over the list and add a label to each task/project to specify the OKR to which it is most closely related.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For the most part, it’s usually works out to be possible to assign an OKR to anything without too much mental gymnastics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Wait a minute… Isn’t that backwards?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;wp-block-quote&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shouldn’t we be using the OKRs to drive coming up with ideas in the first place instead of just wedging them in afterwards?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah, I think that’s the idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Backlog&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It usually seems to me that the reason it works out this way is because teams generally have large backlogs of things they’ve decided they’d like to do. Most of the stuff in that backlog was written down long before the current OKRs where specified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So it makes sense that when the OKRs come out for the quarter, we just take what we already have and figure out how to fit it into the OKRs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Is there anything wrong with that?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes and no.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biggest problem seems to me to be that the team doesn’t end up feeling truly connected or committed to the OKRs. For example, as I write this, I can tell you every project we are going to attempt to work on this quarter, but I can’t even tell you what the OKRs for the quarter are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We did make them all fit in with OKRs, but it never felt like it was really what was driving us. Maybe that’s okay, but it doesn’t seem super useful to me. I think it gives leadership the justification they need to declare that everyone is working towards the same goals, but I don’t think it leads to dev teams actually feeling like that’s true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;wp-block-quote&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think it gives leadership the justification they need to declare that everyone is working towards the same goals, but I don’t think it leads to dev teams actually feeling like that’s true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Ideas to improve how this all works&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a couple ideas about how you can make this better for the next planning cycle for your team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Backlog Bankruptcy&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you start the planning for your next cycle, consider abandoning your current backlog. Instead of diving into the things your team has already defined as work that should be done, start totally from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drive downward from the OKRs and see if the team can come with ideas that have not already been thought of. Or if they can reframe their existing ideas in meaningful ways to make them truly feel like an extension of the OKRs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This isn’t easy to do. You will need to continually push people away from stuff that’s already in the backlog, but I think it can lead to better results in the end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Use OKRs to drive weekly team meetings&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use the OKRs as the starting point for your weekly sprint plannings and other checkin meetings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generally, these meetings will naturally follow a pattern of being shaped by the projects and tasks people are working on, but it’s possible to keep pushing the flow of the conversation back to the OKRs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What effect would this have on your team?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d love to hear how you think this could workout on your team. What do you expect would be different if you adopted these techniques? Comment below or reach me at joe@zafulabs.com&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;jp-post-flair&quot; class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-like-enabled sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;robots-nocontent sd-block sd-social sd-social-icon-text sd-sharing&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Share this:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-block sd-like jetpack-likes-widget-wrapper jetpack-likes-widget-unloaded&quot; id=&quot;like-post-wrapper-155107278-178-5ce9d767079f9&quot; data-src=&quot;//widgets.wp.com/likes/index.html?ver=20190321#blog_id=155107278&amp;amp;post_id=178&amp;amp;origin=zafulabs.wordpress.com&amp;amp;obj_id=155107278-178-5ce9d767079f9&amp;amp;domain=zafulabs.com&quot; data-name=&quot;like-post-frame-155107278-178-5ce9d767079f9&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Like this:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;likes-widget-placeholder post-likes-widget-placeholder&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;button&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Like&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;loading&quot;&gt;Loading...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2019 18:33:39 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>thinksocrates</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>OKRs from a development team’s perspective</og:title>
<og:url>https://zafulabs.com/2019/05/24/okrs-from-a-development-teams-perspective/</og:url>
<og:description>Most of the companies I’ve worked for in the last 5 years have used the OKR system. Although this system was invented in the 70s, it has more recently become popular at Google and has spread …</og:description>
<og:image>https://zafulabs.files.wordpress.com/2019/05/adobestock_244902489.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://zafulabs.com/2019/05/24/okrs-from-a-development-teams-perspective/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Murray Gell-Mann Has Died</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/05/24/obituaries/murray-gell-mann-died-.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2019/05/24/obituaries/murray-gell-mann-died-.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Murray Gell-Mann, who transformed physics with his preternatural ability to find hidden patterns among the tiny particles that make up the universe, earning a Nobel Prize, died on Friday at his home in Santa Fe. He was 89.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Jenna Marshall, a spokeswoman for the Santa Fe Institute, where he held the title of distinguished fellow, announced his death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Much as atoms can be slotted into the rows and columns of the periodic table of the elements, Dr. Gell-Mann found a way, in 1961, to classify their smaller pieces — subatomic particles like protons, neutrons, and mesons, which were being discovered by the dozen in cosmic rays and particle accelerator blasts. Arranged according to their properties, the particles clustered in groups of eight and 10.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;In a moment of whimsy, Dr. Gell-Mann, who hadn’t a mystical bone in his body, named his system the Eightfold Way after the Buddha’s eight-step path to enlightenment. He groaned ever after when people mistakenly inferred that particle physics was somehow related to Eastern philosophy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Looking deeper, Dr. Gell-Mann realized that the patterns of the Eightfold Way could be further divided into triplets of even smaller components. He decided to call them quarks after a line from James Joyce’s “Finnegans Wake”: “Three quarks for Muster Mark.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;With Dr. Gell-Mann at the forefront, physics took on a Joycean feel. Before long there were up quarks and down quarks, strange quarks and charm quarks, top quarks and bottom quarks, all stuck together with particles called gluons. The funny nomenclature was as much a Gell-Mann inspiration as the mathematics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“Murray Gell-Mann dominated theoretical particle physics during the 1950s and ′60s, a period with an abundance of new experimental discoveries,” his colleague David J. Gross, another Nobel laureate in physics, said in an interview for this obituary in 2010. “With almost magical intuition Gell-Mann discerned the patterns and symmetries connecting the many new particles that were found.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-79elbk&quot; data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-wrapper&quot;&gt;

&lt;div data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-children&quot; class=&quot;css-1a48zt4 ehw59r15&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1xdhyk6 erfvjey0&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1tej78p0&quot;&gt;Image&lt;/span&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;css-1m50asq&quot; src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/05/24/obituaries/24Gall-Mann2/24Gall-Mann2-articleLarge.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;auto=webp&amp;amp;disable=upscale&quot; srcset=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/05/24/obituaries/24Gall-Mann2/24Gall-Mann2-articleLarge.jpg?quality=90&amp;amp;auto=webp 600w,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/05/24/obituaries/24Gall-Mann2/24Gall-Mann2-jumbo.jpg?quality=90&amp;amp;auto=webp 725w,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/05/24/obituaries/24Gall-Mann2/24Gall-Mann2-superJumbo.jpg?quality=90&amp;amp;auto=webp 1359w&quot; sizes=&quot;((min-width: 600px) and (max-width: 1004px)) 84vw, (min-width: 1005px) 60vw, 100vw&quot; itemprop=&quot;url&quot; itemid=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/05/24/obituaries/24Gall-Mann2/24Gall-Mann2-articleLarge.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;auto=webp&amp;amp;disable=upscale&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;css-8i9d0s e13ogyst0&quot;&gt;Dr. Gell-Mann at the California Institute of Technology in an undated photo. He collaborated with the renowned physicist Richard Feynman at Caltech.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot; class=&quot;css-vuqh7u e1z0qqy90&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1tej78p0&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Caltech&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Conversant in several languages and fascinated by archaeology, linguistics, natural history and ornithology, Dr. Gell-Mann spotted and named subatomic phenomena as eagerly as if they were exotic birds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“Our work is a delightful game,” he said at the Nobel banquet in Stockholm, where he received the prize for physics in 1969. “I am frequently astonished that it so often results in correct predictions of experimental results.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;After comparing the simple structure of a mathematical formula to the rules of the sonnet, he surprised his hosts by finishing his speech in Swedish. (He later berated himself for mispronouncing a word.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;With his hyphenated surname and cosmopolitan ways, Dr. Gell-Mann liked to keep people wondering about his pedigree. The physicist Sheldon Glashow once recalled a party at which his colleague cagily spun a tale about the confluence in Scotland of the River Gell and the River Mann.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Dr. Gell-Mann also had a compulsion, upon meeting new people, to provide them with the etymology and proper pronunciation of their names, going on to expound on seemingly any subject under the sun. Some found him charming, others exasperating. No one doubted the immensity of his mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;He was born on Sept. 15, 1929, in Lower Manhattan to Arthur and Pauline (Reichstein) Gell-Mann, both Eastern European immigrants. At the time, his father operated a language school. (Born Isidore Gellmann in a small town in what was then Galicia, near the Russian border, the elder Mr. Gell-Mann had studied mathematics and philosophy in Vienna. He changed his name to Arthur and apparently added the hyphen sometime after 1911, when he was called to New York by his parents, who had emigrated earlier and were having financial problems.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;During the Depression, the language school failed and the family, which included an older son, Ben, moved to cheaper quarters on 188th Street in the Bronx, near the Bronx Zoo, and later to the Upper West Side of Manhattan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;This was long before the time when an apartment in the neighborhood conferred a prestigious address. In an oral history interview, Dr. Gell-Mann recalled living in hard times. His father, he said, though intellectually curious, struggled to make a living, finding a back-office job on Wall Street, working for a toy importer and, finally, securing a position at a bank “at a very low salary.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-79elbk&quot; data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-wrapper&quot;&gt;

&lt;div data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-children&quot; class=&quot;css-1a48zt4 ehw59r15&quot;&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;css-8i9d0s e13ogyst0&quot;&gt;Dr. Gell-Mann, second from left, was awarded the Nobel Prize in Physics in 1969. At ceremonies in Stockholm, he posed with other prize winners: from left, Max Delbruck (United States, medicine), Derek R. Barton (England, chemistry), Odd Hassel (Norway, chemistry), Alfred D. Hershey (U.S., medicine), Salvador E. Luria (U.S., medicine) and Jan Tinbergen (Netherlands, economics).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot; class=&quot;css-vuqh7u e1z0qqy90&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1tej78p0&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Associated Press&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“We had very little money,” Dr. Gell-Mann said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Young Murray was already showing signs of precociousness, multiplying large numbers in his head and correcting his elders on the pronunciation of foreign words. With the encouragement of his mother and help from a piano teacher who gave lessons at a local settlement house, he won a scholarship to Columbia Grammar, a private school on West 93rd Street, where he earned the nickname “the Walking Encyclopedia.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Graduating as valedictorian at age 14, he went to Yale, also on scholarship. But physics was not his first choice as a major area of study, he said in the oral history. He considered archaeology or a field related to natural history. His father, however, pushed him to choose engineering, saying it would lead to a well-paying job. Murray resisted, and they settled on physics as a compromise — “to please the old man,” Dr. Gell-Mann said — and he soon found that the subject fascinated him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“My father was absolutely right,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;After Dr. Gell-Mann earned his doctorate at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology, in 1951, J. Robert Oppenheimer, who had directed the Manhattan Project, brought him to the Institute for Advanced Study in Princeton, N.J. From there he went to the University of Chicago and worked under Enrico Fermi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The two decades after World War II were a golden age in physics, with experimenters discovering one new phenomenon after another for theorists to explain. Some particles bombarding the earth as cosmic rays seemed to defy the known laws of physics: They did not disintegrate nearly as quickly as the equations predicted. Dr. Gell-Mann showed that this behavior could be explained by positing a new physical quality, which he named “strangeness.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;As with energy, there is a law of conservation of strangeness. (It is conserved in strong interactions and electromagnetic interactions but not in weak interactions.) Once this was taken into account, physicists could explain the particle’s surprisingly slow decay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;In 1955 Dr. Gell-Mann married J. Margaret Dow, an archaeology assistant he had met during a visit back to Princeton. Lured by an offer from the California Institute of Technology, the couple moved to Pasadena, where they raised two children, Elizabeth and Nicholas. The renowned physicist Richard Feynman was also at Caltech, and the two men, their egos clashing, collaborated for a while before Dr. Gell-Mann struck out on his own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;As with strangeness, the Eightfold Way and quarks were independently discovered by other theorists, but the breadth of Dr. Gell-Mann’s accomplishments and his flare for nomenclature ensured that his would be the name most remembered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;His instincts weren’t infallible. At first he dismissed quarks as mathematical abstractions — an accounting device with no real correlate in the physical world. There was good reason for his skepticism: Quarks would have to have electrical charges measured in thirds, something that was never observed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-79elbk&quot; data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-wrapper&quot;&gt;

&lt;div data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-children&quot; class=&quot;css-1a48zt4 ehw59r15&quot;&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;css-8i9d0s e13ogyst0&quot;&gt;Dr. Gell-Mann at the Santa Fe Institute in 2003. He originally wanted to study archaeology or one of the natural sciences, he said,but chose physics “to please the old man.” He added, “My father was absolutely right.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot; class=&quot;css-vuqh7u e1z0qqy90&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1tej78p0&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Jane Bernard/Associated Press&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;After quarks were confirmed indirectly in an experiment at the Stanford Linear Accelerator Center, in Menlo Park, Calif., Dr. Gell-Mann denied that he had ever doubted their existence. He went on to help explain how the tiny particles are permanently stuck together, keeping their fractional charges hidden from view. A “green” quark, a “red” quark and a “blue” quark (the labels were arbitrary) blended to form a “colorless” proton. It was Dr. Gell-Mann who named the theory quantum chromodynamics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;By this time he was becoming known for his abrasive style, cutting down colleagues with withering remarks or saddling some of them with derisive names. The physicist &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2000/07/31/nyregion/dr-abraham-pais-82-physicist-and-science-historian-dies.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;Times obituary &quot;&gt;Abraham Pais&lt;/a&gt; became “the evil dwarf.” The renowned experimenter &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/10/03/science/leon-lederman-died-particle-accelerators.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;Times obituary &quot;&gt;Leon Lederman&lt;/a&gt; (who died last October) was “the plumber.” But those who could abide Dr. Gell-Mann’s prickliness found the intellectual pugilism exciting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“To work with him it helps first of all not to have too fragile an ego,” &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;http://web.physics.ucsb.edu/~hartle/&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;James Hartle&lt;/a&gt;, a former student and collaborator, said in a remembrance in 2014, when Dr. Gell-Mann received the prestigious Helmholtz Medal, established in 1892. (Past recipients included Lord Kelvin and Robert Bunsen.) “But despite the obvious differences in intellect and insight, Murray somehow makes you feel an equal partner when you are working with him.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Dr. Gell-Mann was an early champion of superstrings, hypothetical particles that, if ever verified, would be even more fundamental than quarks. Later in his career he began thinking in other directions, puzzling over the way simple laws of physics give rise to the beauty and intricacy of the living world. He explored the idea in a popular book, “The Quark and the Jaguar: Adventures in the Simple and the Complex” (1994).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;In 1992, a little more than a decade after his wife, Margaret, died of cancer, he married Marcia Southwick, a poet he had met in Aspen, Colo., where he had a summer home. After retiring from Caltech and being named a fellow at the Santa Fe Institute, he moved with her to New Mexico. The marriage ended in divorce. He is survived by his two children and by a stepson, Nicholas Southwick Levis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;By the time Dr. Gell-Mann learned he would receive the Helmholtz Medal from the Berlin-Brandenburg Academy of Sciences and Humanities, he was in a wheelchair accompanied by an attendant. So the academy came to him, bestowing the prize in a ceremony at the Santa Fe Institute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Afterward, Dr. Gell-Mann’s friend, the novelist Cormac McCarthy, raised a champagne toast. During the ceremony, Dr. Gell-Mann had been described as “one of the great physicists of the latter half of the 20th century.” Mr. McCarthy objected to the qualification. Dr. Gell-Mann, he said, is “undoubtedly one of &lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; great scientists of the 20th century.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;In a talk in 2007, Dr. Gell-Mann compared the last century of physics to pulling back the skins of an onion, finding at every layer that the same mathematics applies — and hinting that an objective reality can conceivably be explained someday by a universal set of laws.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-18icg9x evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“Somewhere on some other planet orbiting some very distant star, maybe in another galaxy, there could well be entities that are at least as intelligent as we are,” he said. “Suppose they have very different sensory apparatus — they have seven tentacles, and they have 14 funny-looking little compound eyes and a brain shaped like a pretzel.” Nevertheless, Dr. Gell-Mann said, we can be confident that these creatures would discover the same fundamental laws. Some people believe otherwise, he added, “and I think that is utter baloney.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2019 16:57:37 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>sajid</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/05/24/obituaries/murray-gell-mann-died-.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Murray Gell-Mann, Who Peered at Particles and Saw the Universe, Dies at 89</og:title>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/05/25/obituaries/25Gall-Mann-obit1/24Gall-Mann1-facebookJumbo.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>A Nobel winner, he found hidden patterns in the subatomic matter that forms the universe, evoking James Joyce in calling one kind of particle “quarks.”</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/05/24/obituaries/murray-gell-mann-died-.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>