<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Jeff Bezos&amp;#039;s phone &amp;#039;hacked by Saudi crown prince&amp;#039;</title>
<link>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2020/jan/21/amazon-boss-jeff-bezoss-phone-hacked-by-saudi-crown-prince</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2020/jan/21/amazon-boss-jeff-bezoss-phone-hacked-by-saudi-crown-prince</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The Amazon billionaire Jeff Bezos had his mobile phone “hacked” in 2018 after receiving a WhatsApp message that had apparently been sent from the personal account of the crown prince of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/saudiarabia&quot; data-link-name=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; data-component=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Saudi Arabia&lt;/a&gt;, sources have told the Guardian.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The encrypted message from the number used by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/mohammed-bin-salman&quot; data-link-name=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; data-component=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Mohammed bin Salman&lt;/a&gt; is believed to have included a malicious file that infiltrated the phone of the world’s richest man, according to the results of a digital forensic analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This analysis found it “highly probable” that the intrusion into the phone was triggered by an infected video file sent from the account of the Saudi heir to Bezos, the owner of the Washington Post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two men had been having a seemingly friendly WhatsApp exchange when, on 1 May of that year, the unsolicited file was sent, according to sources who spoke to the Guardian on the condition of anonymity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Large amounts of data were exfiltrated from Bezos’s phone within hours, according to a person familiar with the matter. The Guardian has no knowledge of what was taken from the phone or how it was used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The extraordinary revelation that the future king of Saudi Arabia may have had a personal involvement in the targeting of the American founder of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/amazon&quot; data-link-name=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; data-component=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; will send shockwaves from Wall Street to Silicon Valley.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It could also undermine efforts by “MBS” – as the crown prince is known – to lure more &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ft.com/content/19363bfc-dbc0-11e9-8f9b-77216ebe1f17&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;western investors&lt;/a&gt; to Saudi Arabia, where he has vowed to economically transform the kingdom even as he has overseen a crackdown on his critics and rivals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The disclosure is likely to raise difficult questions for the kingdom about the circumstances around how US tabloid the National Enquirer came to publish intimate details about Bezos’s private life – including text messages – nine months later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It may also lead to renewed scrutiny about what the crown prince and his inner circle were doing in the months prior to the murder of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/jamal-khashoggi&quot; data-link-name=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; data-component=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Jamal Khashoggi&lt;/a&gt;, the Washington Post journalist who was killed in October 2018 – five months after the alleged “hack” of the newspaper’s owner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;u-responsive-ratio&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;gu-image&quot; itemprop=&quot;contentUrl&quot; alt=&quot;Mohammed bin Salman&quot; src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/755aa78e69fcc4e3a32cbe5ac2919b28ba42beb2/0_118_2000_1200/master/2000.jpg?width=300&amp;amp;quality=85&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;fit=max&amp;amp;s=54b51b6fc9579f08a18ee269e5247b08&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

Mohammed bin Salman. One observer said the alleged targeting of Bezos reflected the ‘personality-based’ environment in which the crown prince operates. Photograph: Bandar Aljaloud/Saudi royal court/EPA
&lt;p&gt;Saudi Arabia has previously denied it targeted Bezos’s phone, and has insisted the murder of Khashoggi was the result of a “rogue operation”. In December, a Saudi court &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2019/dec/23/saudi-arabia-accused-of-mockery-of-justice-over-jamal-khashoggi-trial&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;convicted eight people&lt;/a&gt; of involvement in the murder after a secret trial that was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2019/dec/23/saudi-arabia-accused-of-mockery-of-justice-over-jamal-khashoggi-trial&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;criticised as a sham by human rights experts&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Digital forensic experts started examining Bezos’s phone following the publication last January by the National Enquirer of intimate details about his private life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story, which included his involvement in an extramarital relationship, set off a race by his security team to uncover how the CEO’s private texts were obtained by the supermarket tabloid, which was owned by American Media Inc (AMI).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thedailybeast.com/national-enquirer-says-saudis-didnt-help-on-bezos-story&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;AMI insisted it was tipped off&lt;/a&gt; about the affair by the estranged brother of Bezos’s girlfriend, the investigation by the billionaire’s own team found with “high confidence” that the Saudis had managed to “access” Bezos’s phone and had “gained private information” about him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bezos’s head of security, Gavin de Becker, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thedailybeast.com/jeff-bezos-investigation-finds-the-saudis-obtained-his-private-information&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;wrote in the Daily Beast last March&lt;/a&gt; he had provided details of his investigation to law enforcement officials, but did not publicly reveal any information on how the Saudis accessed the phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He also described “the close relationship” the Saudi crown prince had developed with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/media/2018/aug/06/david-pecker-donald-trump-national-enquirer-profile&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;David Pecker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/media/2018/aug/06/david-pecker-donald-trump-national-enquirer-profile&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;, the chief executive of the company that owned the Enquirer&lt;/a&gt;, in the months before the Bezos story was published. De Becker did not respond to calls and messages from the Guardian.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Guardian understands a forensic analysis of Bezos’s phone, and the indications that the “hack” began within an infected file from the crown prince’s account, has been reviewed by Agnès Callamard, the UN special rapporteur who investigates extrajudicial killings. It is understood that it is considered credible enough for investigators to be considering a formal approach to Saudi Arabia to ask for an explanation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Callamard, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2019/jun/19/jamal-khashoggi-killing-saudi-crown-prince-mohammed-bin-salman-evidence-un-report&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;whose own investigation into the murder of Khashoggi&lt;/a&gt; found “credible evidence” the crown prince and other senior Saudi officials were responsible for the killing, confirmed to the Guardian she was still pursuing “several leads” into the murder, but declined to comment on the alleged Bezos link.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When asked by the Guardian whether she would challenge Saudi Arabia about the new “hacking” allegation, Callamard said she followed all UN protocols that require investigators to alert governments about forthcoming public allegations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saudi experts – dissidents and analysts – told the Guardian they believed Bezos was probably targeted because of his ownership of the Post and its coverage of Saudi Arabia. Khashoggi’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/global-opinions/wp/2018/10/06/read-jamal-khashoggis-columns-for-the-washington-post/&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;critical columns about Mohammed bin Salman&lt;/a&gt; and his campaign of repression against activists and intellectuals rankled the crown prince and his inner circle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pomed.org/team/andrew-miller/&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Andrew Miller&lt;/a&gt;, a Middle East expert who served on the national security council under President Obama, said if Bezos had been targeted by the crown prince, it reflected the “personality-based” environment in which the crown prince operates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“He probably believed that if he got something on Bezos it could shape coverage of Saudi Arabia in the Post. It is clear that the Saudis have no real boundaries or limits in terms of what they are prepared to do in order to protect and advance MBS, whether it is going after the head of one of the largest companies in the world or a dissident who is on their own.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The possibility that the head of one of America’s leading companies was targeted by Saudi Arabia could pose a dilemma for the White House.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trump and his son-in-law Jared Kushner have maintained close ties with the crown prince despite a US intelligence finding – &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/national-security/cia-concludes-saudi-crown-prince-ordered-jamal-khashoggis-assassination/2018/11/16/98c89fe6-e9b2-11e8-a939-9469f1166f9d_story.html&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;reportedly with a medium–to–high degree of certainty&lt;/a&gt; – that Mohammed bin Salman &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/11/16/us/politics/cia-saudi-crown-prince-khashoggi.html&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;ordered Khashoggi’s&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/11/16/us/politics/cia-saudi-crown-prince-khashoggi.html&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;murder&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both Saudi Arabia and AMI have &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thedailybeast.com/national-enquirer-says-saudis-didnt-help-on-bezos-story&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;denied that the kingdom&lt;/a&gt; was involved in the publication of the Bezos story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lawyer for Bezos who was contacted by the Guardian said: “I have no comment on this except to say that Mr Bezos is cooperating with investigations.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Guardian asked the Saudi embassy in Washington about the claims. It did not immediately return a request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Have you got new information about this story? You can message Guardian investigations using Signal or WhatsApp: +447584640566. For the most secure communications, use &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/securedrop&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;SecureDrop&lt;/a&gt;. You can also email: &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:stephanie.kirchgaessner@theguardian.com&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;stephanie.kirchgaessner@theguardian.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 21:05:51 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mnem</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://www.theguardian.com/technology/2020/jan/21/amazon-boss-jeff-bezoss-phone-hacked-by-saudi-crown-prince</og:url>
<og:description>Exclusive: investigation suggests Washington Post owner was targeted five months before murder of Jamal Khashoggi</og:description>
<og:image>https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/682cb26b3475597eabe85f28d8ecf6464a157b03/44_458_1779_1068/master/1779.jpg?width=1200&amp;height=630&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=crop&amp;overlay-align=bottom%2Cleft&amp;overlay-width=100p&amp;overlay-base64=L2ltZy9zdGF0aWMvb3ZlcmxheXMvdGctZGVmYXVsdC5wbmc&amp;enable=upscale&amp;s=fb751413d61cef16dc0fe18139480c66</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Amazon boss Jeff Bezos's phone 'hacked by Saudi crown prince'</og:title>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2020/jan/21/amazon-boss-jeff-bezoss-phone-hacked-by-saudi-crown-prince</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>First Case of New Coronavirus Detected in U.S.</title>
<link>https://www.npr.org/sections/goatsandsoda/2020/01/21/798137962/china-tries-to-control-travel-in-and-out-of-wuhan-to-stem-coronavirus-spread</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.npr.org/sections/goatsandsoda/2020/01/21/798137962/china-tries-to-control-travel-in-and-out-of-wuhan-to-stem-coronavirus-spread</guid>
<description>&lt;div id=&quot;res798147927&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap image large&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;imagewrap&quot; data-crop-type=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2020/01/21/ap_20021249338334-d4019444db83b8d4a25a4bef291d7b85c453f88c-s1100-c15.jpg&quot; data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2020/01/21/ap_20021249338334-d4019444db83b8d4a25a4bef291d7b85c453f88c-s1100.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img lazyOnLoad&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;credit-caption&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-wrap&quot; readability=&quot;7.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image caption&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Staff in biohazard suits hold a metal stretcher on Tuesday by the inpatient department of Wuhan Medical Treatment Center, where some people infected with a novel coronavirus are being treated in China. &lt;strong class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Dake Kang/AP&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong class=&quot;hide-caption&quot;&gt;hide caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;strong class=&quot;toggle-caption&quot;&gt;toggle caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Dake Kang/AP&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;enlarge_measure&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img_wrap&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2020/01/21/ap_20021249338334-d4019444db83b8d4a25a4bef291d7b85c453f88c-s1200.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;enlarge_html&quot; readability=&quot;7.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image_data&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Staff in biohazard suits hold a metal stretcher on Tuesday by the inpatient department of Wuhan Medical Treatment Center, where some people infected with a novel coronavirus are being treated in China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Dake Kang/AP&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Updated at 3 p.m. ET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first case of an infection with the new coronavirus has been discovered in the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A man from Washington state returned home after a trip to Wuhan, China, on Jan. 15, sought medical attention on Jan. 19 and now is in isolation at Providence Regional Medical Center in Everett, Wash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;State health officials say his condition is quite good and even referred to him as &quot;healthy.&quot; But testing from the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention on Jan. 20 confirm that he is infected with the Wuhan coronavirus. The man arrived back in the U.S. prior to the implementation of screening at three domestic airports on Friday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About 300 cases of the virus and six deaths have been reported in China, and health officials there and around the world are ramping up precautions to stem the spread.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chinese authorities are trying to control the flow of people in and out of the eastern city of Wuhan, where a strain of the coronavirus was discovered last month. Wuhan's mayor has asked residents to stay in the city to try to prevent the spread of the virus, which can &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.who.int/china/news/detail/09-01-2020-who-statement-regarding-cluster-of-pneumonia-cases-in-wuhan-china&quot;&gt;cause&lt;/a&gt; respiratory symptoms such as pneumonia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id=&quot;ad-backstage-wrap&quot; aria-label=&quot;advertisement&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Cars may be randomly tested in case wild animals, a potential source for the virus, are transported, and tour groups are prohibited from leaving the city,&quot; NPR's Amy Cheng reports from Beijing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cases of coronavirus, named 2019-nCoV, have also been confirmed in Japan, Thailand and South Korea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many airports around the world, including three in the U.S. — JFK in New York, SFO in San Francisco and LAX in Los Angeles — are setting up additional security screenings for passengers coming from infected areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At a press conference on Tuesday afternoon, the CDC said that it's expanding the screenings to include Chicago's O'Hare and Atlanta's Hartsfield-Jackson international airports and that any passengers originating from Wuhan into the U.S. will be funneled to one of the five airports with screening, even if this requires rebooking them on different flights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other nations are taking similar precautions. Russia, India and North Korea have all started checking people for fever on inbound flights from China. Australia and the Philippines are also checking passengers and have quarantined some suspected cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rising international concern about the coronavirus comes ahead of Lunar New Year, a major holiday in China during which millions of people travel across the country and internationally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wuhan authorities are testing whether passengers have fevers at transportation terminals throughout the city using 35 stationary infrared thermometers and more 300 handheld ones, according to China's &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.xinhuanet.com/english/2020-01/21/c_138724009_2.htm&quot;&gt;Xinhua news agency&lt;/a&gt;. Passengers set to travel to Wuhan are being offered free ticket cancellations or changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;res798169818&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap internallink insettwocolumn inset2col&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bucket img&quot;&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;featuredStackSquareImage797926447&quot; href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/sections/goatsandsoda/2020/01/20/797926447/coronavirus-in-china-over-200-cases-human-to-human-transmission&quot; data-metrics=&quot;{&amp;quot;category&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Story to Story&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;action&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Click Internal Link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;label&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https:\/\/www.npr.org\/sections\/goatsandsoda\/2020\/01\/20\/797926447\/coronavirus-in-china-over-200-cases-human-to-human-transmission&amp;quot;}&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2020/01/20/gettyimages-1194134288_sq-1883cdcc9361ee6a845e7a7277b297a7f88c79ef-s100-c15.jpg&quot; data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2020/01/20/gettyimages-1194134288_sq-1883cdcc9361ee6a845e7a7277b297a7f88c79ef-s100.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img lazyOnLoad&quot; alt=&quot;Coronavirus In China: Over 200 Cases, Human-To-Human Transmission&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;The Wuhan airport, it's like a war zone because it's all controlled with all the security, all the medical staff,&quot; Linfa Wang, a virologist at Duke-National University of Singapore, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/2020/01/21/798088813/coronavirus-in-china-spreads-by-human-to-human-transmission&quot;&gt;tells NPR&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;You line up and then you go through group by group.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The World Health Organization says the virus likely first spread to humans through transmission from an animal at a live animal market in Wuhan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Monday, a Chinese government epidemiologist said there was evidence the virus could be &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/sections/goatsandsoda/2020/01/20/797926447/coronavirus-in-china-over-200-cases-human-to-human-transmission&quot;&gt;transmitted from human to human&lt;/a&gt;. The coronavirus is also raising concerns because it has spread in medical environments – among people who are likely taking appropriate precautions to avoid infection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;res798148479&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap image large&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;imagewrap&quot; data-crop-type=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2020/01/21/ap_20021423240585_custom-5c02755976dad03b08ffccabe523fdf92fc11f75-s1100-c15.jpg&quot; data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2020/01/21/ap_20021423240585_custom-5c02755976dad03b08ffccabe523fdf92fc11f75-s1100.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img lazyOnLoad&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;credit-caption&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-wrap&quot; readability=&quot;6.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image caption&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People wear face masks as they ride an escalator on Tuesday at the Hong Kong International Airport. &lt;strong class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Ng Han Guan/AP&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong class=&quot;hide-caption&quot;&gt;hide caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;strong class=&quot;toggle-caption&quot;&gt;toggle caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Ng Han Guan/AP&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chinese authorities have come up with a new test for diagnosing the virus and are calling on people to take measures to prevent its spread such as covering their mouths when coughing or wearing face masks. These masks are reportedly selling out in stores and online retailers in the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wang says this virus is also concerning because there are still many aspects that aren't well understood by health officials. &quot;The enemies are in the dark, and we don't know them,&quot; he says. &quot;This new coronavirus is in the same family as SARS, but it's different from SARS.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SARS, which is short for severe acute respiratory syndrome, killed &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cdc.gov/sars/about/fs-sars.html#outbreak&quot;&gt;nearly 800&lt;/a&gt; people during an outbreak in 2003.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;res798169508&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap internallink insettwocolumn inset2col&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bucket img&quot;&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;featuredStackSquareImage795343026&quot; href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/sections/goatsandsoda/2020/01/10/795343026/chinese-virologists-are-fighting-a-new-outbreak-heres-what-they-re-looking-for&quot; data-metrics=&quot;{&amp;quot;category&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Story to Story&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;action&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Click Internal Link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;label&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https:\/\/www.npr.org\/sections\/goatsandsoda\/2020\/01\/10\/795343026\/chinese-virologists-are-fighting-a-new-outbreak-heres-what-they-re-looking-for&amp;quot;}&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2020/01/17/gettyimages-634339100_sq-77d1795660c2354661b65a40fe2625f8b0957097-s100-c15.jpg&quot; data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2020/01/17/gettyimages-634339100_sq-77d1795660c2354661b65a40fe2625f8b0957097-s100.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img lazyOnLoad&quot; alt=&quot;CDC To Screen For New Strain Of Coronavirus At 3 U.S. Airports&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The World Health Organization has scheduled a &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/DrTedros/status/1219321726351396864?s=20&quot;&gt;meeting for Wednesday&lt;/a&gt; to weigh whether the coronavirus should be declared an international public health emergency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wang expects the idea of travel restrictions to be discussed. &quot;It'll be a tough decision, and I don't want to be the person to make that decision,&quot; he says, given the sheer number of people on the move during the Lunar New Year holiday.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 20:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>adenner</dc:creator>
<og:title>1st Case Of New Coronavirus Detected In U.S.</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.npr.org/sections/goatsandsoda/2020/01/21/798137962/china-tries-to-control-travel-in-and-out-of-wuhan-to-stem-coronavirus-spread</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>The individual had returned to his home in Washington state after a visit to Wuhan, China, where the virus was discovered in December.</og:description>
<og:image>https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2020/01/21/ap_20021249338334_wide-e700bd48b010ef5ee2599f1f7faaca7cbc62b049.jpg?s=1400</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.npr.org/sections/goatsandsoda/2020/01/21/798137962/china-tries-to-control-travel-in-and-out-of-wuhan-to-stem-coronavirus-spread</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>How to Kill a Startup Idea with Google Keyword Planner and AdWords: A Case Study</title>
<link>https://www.psl.com/feed-posts/psl-studio-kill-xylo</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.psl.com/feed-posts/psl-studio-kill-xylo</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;At PSL, we kill nine out of ten ideas that we test. We haven't talked much about these publicly before, but we wanted to share what it looks like when we make a &quot;kill&quot; decision. Our goal in publishing this is to help other founders think about how to do early validation the way that we do inside the studio.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea we tested was Xylo, which solved a problem that millions of parents in the U.S. experience: finding great teachers for music lessons. Our proposed solution was an online platform to connect these teachers with students for remote (or in-person) lessons with a great user experience. Sounds like a great idea, right? Let's dive in!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This email was sent by Peter Denton, our validation lead, to our whole team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.website-files.com/5d3152346d95065922960b3a/5e21f334a1866d2e79fb7717_Screen%20Shot%202020-01-17%20at%209.46.58%20AM.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;em&gt;A section of the test site for Xylo. Note that we typically use very basic landing pages so that the quality of the design doesn't affect results. Simple templates allow us to ensure our convesion data is attributable to resonance of the value propositions, not the site execution.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‍&lt;br/&gt;--------------------&lt;br/&gt;From: Peter Denton&lt;br/&gt;Date: Friday, January 10 2020&lt;br/&gt;Subject: Xylo investigation&lt;br/&gt;To: PSL Team&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey everyone,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been looking into Xylo this week and wanted to share my findings with you. To cut to the chase, &lt;strong&gt;I am recommending we kill this idea&lt;/strong&gt;, but of course want to share my methodology and see if anyone wants to keep going.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am working under the assumption this is marketplace business where we take a cut of the revenue in a booking.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we just start at the raw &lt;strong&gt;demand generation&lt;/strong&gt; around this, according to Google, over the next quarter, for the entire United States, we could get 36,000 clicks for $84,591 in marketing spend. I would look at this as the entire world of actionable intent-driven demand.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.website-files.com/5d3152346d95065922960b3a/5e1f421640b7110344ec341b_Screen%20Shot%202020-01-15%20at%209.46.02%20AM.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‍&lt;strong&gt;We ran tests on both Google and Facebook&lt;/strong&gt; to get real, in-the-wild numbers, which proved to be worse than Google's estimated models. (As I discuss later, it's probably due to high levels of competition both paid and organic).&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For &lt;strong&gt;Facebook&lt;/strong&gt; tests, the best CTR was 0.68% and the CPC was high with an average CPC of $3.75. That is really expensive, likely due to the holiday increase in competition and base CPM going up to reach consumers/parents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.website-files.com/5d3152346d95065922960b3a/5e1f4238b896dd585aab232a_Screen%20Shot%202020-01-15%20at%209.46.22%20AM.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.website-files.com/5d3152346d95065922960b3a/5e20c7cd5ad86c144a1f9696_image%20(23).png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The &quot;tech-enabled&quot; ad that ran on Facebook/Instagram&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For &lt;strong&gt;Google&lt;/strong&gt;, targeting the similar value props (affordable, convenient, tech-enabled, and exclusive) we are currently &lt;strong&gt;seeing just a 0.65% CTR&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.website-files.com/5d3152346d95065922960b3a/5e20c8ff84fda6e14282a7c3_ads.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Note: It is important to be sure each ad is clearly messaging a distinct core benefit to understand why people clicked through.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‍&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We saw the following funnel, using a blend of Google's model and our own CTR:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;3% CTR (of 900,000 searches) == 27,360 visitors&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and 20% conversion (for people &quot;signing up&quot; on the landing page)  - 5,400 registrations. &lt;em&gt;(Note: we saw 10%, and optimistically assumed we could double on-page conversion rate by optimizing over time, which we have seen with other companies)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and 10% of those paying == ~600 total possible customers in Q1.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;We are looking at 600 customers (which would cost around $80K to acquire). If those 600 customers took 3 lessons each, at $60 an hour, and we took a 20% commission, we are looking at &lt;strong&gt;only $21,600 of revenue&lt;/strong&gt;.  &lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for &lt;strong&gt;market size&lt;/strong&gt;, the best estimates from MakeMusic (a leading resource for music instructors), put the number of music educators in the US at about 100,000. I got to a similar number (154,000) building a bottoms-up estimate by running Google searches by market and taking the sum. (Also, many people believe there is a lot of under-the-table neighborhood activity going on, so the number is likely higher, but not sure that is actually addressable for us).&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Regarding competition:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;First off, there are a &lt;strong&gt;ton of enabled small businesses competing in this space&lt;/strong&gt; and I'm not sure there needs to be a middle man. For example, I get 4 ads from businesses in Seattle offering lessons for guitar on Google. Thus, they know how to market and get customers, they are offering free first lessons, and have availability. So I am &lt;strong&gt;unsure/doubt there is any real consumer problem&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TakeLessons&lt;/strong&gt; is the largest VC-backed lessons marketplace and has raised ~20MM over 3 rounds. TakeLessons charges 40% commission and has expanded out into &quot;all things lessons&quot;, which is likely an indicator that music lessons were too small to keep growing in.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;There is also &lt;strong&gt;Yousician&lt;/strong&gt;, which is an entirely tech-based way to teach you music. Think: guitar hero for music lessons. They have about 100 employees, so it's a sizeable tech team to keep building.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;And lastly there is &lt;strong&gt;YouTube,&lt;/strong&gt; where thousands of guitar instructors teach people a wide array of music-based education. While not the same as a 1:1 lesson this is completely for free for the consumer.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In conclusion:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;I do think there is a &lt;strong&gt;healthy demand&lt;/strong&gt; for this - 1MM people are looking for it every quarter.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;However, the &lt;strong&gt;supply side is mobilized&lt;/strong&gt; and there is a TON of competition, which is going to continually drive up costs perpetually. With 70% of consumers skipping AdWords, this means very limited early traffic.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It was not clear that you could create intent outside of Google&lt;/strong&gt;, so you would need some unique differentiator in GTM to get real market share.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lastly, &lt;strong&gt;I can't imagine that tech won't win&lt;/strong&gt; here with non-human based teaching. It's affordable, convenient, and scalable to any genre, language, right from home on many platforms.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please feel free to contest that, and I mean it. This is just my summary after a week of looking at the opportunity as if it were my company. I wouldn't proceed with it, but would love alternate opinions.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-Peter&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 18:44:42 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>treblig</dc:creator>
<og:title>PSL Studio Kill: Xylo</og:title>
<og:description>PSL Features</og:description>
<og:image>https://assets.website-files.com/5d3152346d95065922960b3a/5e2692145f16d0aef5429fd4_psl-feed-features-studio-kill-xylo.jpg</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.psl.com/feed-posts/psl-studio-kill-xylo</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Cloudflare is turning off the internet for me</title>
<link>https://blog.dijit.sh/cloudflare-is-turning-off-the-internet-for-me</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.dijit.sh/cloudflare-is-turning-off-the-internet-for-me</guid>
<description>&lt;time datetime=&quot;2020-01-21&quot; class=&quot;article_time&quot;&gt;January 21, 2020&lt;/time&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ok, I’ll admit, I’m not the largest fan of centralisation, but rarely do I so swiftly and effectively feel the crushing weight of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I happen to use a very nice &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.qutebrowser.org/&quot;&gt;Chromium-based web-browser&lt;/a&gt; which, when it opens has javascript disabled. Often I find that nothing works so I re-enable javascript and continue about my day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This morning I went to work, as normal, turned on my laptop and as my laptop dutifully reloaded all my tabs from the day before I saw a few sites error-ing out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is relatively common when I haven’t connected to the network yet, or some sites which don’t even attempt to load without javascript, so I check my connection, enable javascript and went about reloading the offending pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I noticed quite a few of the pages were the following:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/z0nm8un.png&quot; alt=&quot;bakadesuyo&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me copy that for those who don’t like to read images:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;16&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sorry, you have been blocked&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why have I been blocked?&lt;br/&gt;This website is using a security service to protect itself from online attacks. The action you just performed triggered the security solution. There are several actions that could trigger this block including submitting a certain word or phrase, a SQL command or malformed data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What can I do to resolve this?&lt;br/&gt;You can email the site owner to let them know you were blocked. Please include what you were doing when this page came up and the Cloudflare Ray ID found at the bottom of this page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, so I’ve been outright blocked, no captcha, and a suggestion to email the owners of the sites… which could be difficult given that I can’t actually reach the sites to find the site-owner for each one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I figured this might be because I had javascript disabled and tried to load a few pages, so I refreshed the page, noted that no captcha appeared and continued my day and figured the ban would eventually be lifted; Noting that I should keep my browser open so that it doesn’t happen again when I get home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;home_2&quot;&gt;home &lt;a class=&quot;head_anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://blog.dijit.sh/cloudflare-is-turning-off-the-internet-for-me#home_2&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, so I got home 30 minutes ago and I’m following some reddit links from /r/irc, when I get a “You have been blocked message”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Oh,”&lt;/em&gt; I thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“I forgot about that.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/QyVbHAh.png&quot; alt=&quot;more blocks&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So now I’m curious as to why, and what I can do about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any ideas? &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=22109969&quot;&gt;Please help&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EDIT:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;if my blog goes down; let it be known that I tried to read the docs on nginx.org but was not able:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/qzKnGEg.png&quot; alt=&quot;nginx also blocks me&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EDIT2:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;plot thickens, it seems to work fine in chrome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/Akq5mpH.png&quot; alt=&quot;chrome works&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EDIT3:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=22110878&quot;&gt;I had set a custom user agent string (D'OH!)&lt;/a&gt; some time ago, and forgot about it. Which is now biting me on the butt.&lt;br/&gt;Ironically I set that user agent string before &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/qutebrowser/qutebrowser/issues/5182&quot;&gt;because Google was not allowing me to log in to my account&lt;/a&gt; anymore, I got that working but now half the internet doesn’t work for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kudos to RyanK24 on HackerNews for following up. Much, much appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;prettyprint&quot;&gt; ¯\_(ツ)_/¯
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;


&lt;p&gt;99&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kudos&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;99&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kudos&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 18:41:49 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>dijit</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://blog.dijit.sh/cloudflare-is-turning-off-the-internet-for-me</og:url>
<og:title>Cloudflare is turning off the internet for me • Jan Harasym</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>Ok, I’ll admit, I’m not the largest fan of centralisation, but rarely do I so swiftly and effectively feel the crushing weight of it. I happen to use a very nice Chromium-based web-browser which, when it opens has javascript disabled. Often I find... | Jan Harasym | Designing highly scalable/resilient infrastructure by day; running hacker communities by night.</og:description>
<og:image>https://svbtleusercontent.com/AFgjxPvtKmnJ2LoJWNPXx62zgIE_large.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.dijit.sh/cloudflare-is-turning-off-the-internet-for-me</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Wine 5.0</title>
<link>https://source.winehq.org/git/wine.git/blob_plain/wine-5.0:/ANNOUNCE</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://source.winehq.org/git/wine.git/blob_plain/wine-5.0:/ANNOUNCE</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;meta http-equiv=&quot;Content-Type&quot; content=&quot;text/html; charset=UTF-8&quot; /&gt;&lt;title&gt;&lt;/title&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot; readability=&quot;87&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Wine team is proud to announce that the stable release Wine 5.0 is now available. This release represents a year of development effort and over 7,400 individual changes. It contains a large number of improvements that are listed in the release notes below. The main highlights are: - Builtin modules in PE format. - Multi-monitor support. - XAudio2 reimplementation. - Vulkan 1.1 support. This release is dedicated to the memory of Józef Kucia, who passed away in August 2019 at the young age of 30. Józef was a major contributor to Wine's Direct3D implementation, and the lead developer of the vkd3d project. His skills and his kindness are sorely missed by all of us. The source is available from the following locations: https://dl.winehq.org/wine/source/5.0/wine-5.0.tar.xz http://mirrors.ibiblio.org/wine/source/5.0/wine-5.0.tar.xz Binary packages for various distributions will be available from: https://www.winehq.org/download You will find documentation on https://www.winehq.org/documentation You can also get the current source directly from the git repository. Check https://www.winehq.org/git for details. Wine is available thanks to the work of many people. See the file AUTHORS in the distribution for the complete list. ---------------------------------------------------------------- What's new in Wine 5.0 ====================== *** PE modules - Most modules are built in PE format (Portable Executable, the Windows binary format) instead of ELF when the MinGW compiler is available. This helps various copy protection schemes that check that the on-disk and in-memory contents of system modules are identical. - The actual PE binaries are copied into the Wine prefix instead of the fake DLL files. This makes the prefix look more like a real Windows installation, at the cost of some extra disk space. - Modules that have been converted to PE can use standard wide-char C functions, as well as wide-char character constants like L&quot;abc&quot;. This makes the code easier to read. - Not all modules have been converted to PE yet; this is an ongoing process that will continue during the Wine 5.x development series. - The Wine C runtime is updated to support linking to MinGW-compiled binaries; it is used by default instead of the MinGW runtime when building DLLs. *** Graphics - Multiple display adapters and monitors are properly supported, including dynamic configuration changes. - The Vulkan driver supports up to version 1.1.126 of the Vulkan spec. - The WindowsCodecs library is able to convert more bitmap formats, including palette-indexed formats. *** Direct3D - Fullscreen Direct3D applications inhibit the screensaver. - DXGI swapchain presents inform the application when the corresponding window is minimized. This typically allows applications to reduce CPU usage while minimized, and is in some cases required to allow the application window to be restored again. - Switching between fullscreen and windowed modes using the standard Alt+Enter combination is implemented for DXGI applications. - The following features are implemented for Direct3D 12 applications: - Switching between fullscreen and windowed. - Changing display modes. - Scaled presents. - Swap intervals. These features were previously already implemented for earlier versions of the Direct3D API. - The handling of various edge cases is improved. Among others: - Out of range reference values for the alpha and stencil tests. - Sampling 2D resources with 3D samplers and vice versa. - Drawing with mapped textures and buffers. - Usage of invalid DirectDraw clipper objects. - Creating Direct3D devices on invalid Windows, like the desktop window. - Viewports with a minimum Z larger than or equal to the maximum Z. - Resources bound through both shader-resource views and render-target or depth-stencil views at the same time. - Blits between formats with and without alpha components. Since well-behaved applications don't rely on these edge cases, they typically only affect one or two applications each. There are nevertheless quite a number of them. - Dirty texture regions are tracked more accurately for Direct3D 8 and 9 texture uploads. - Uploads of S3TC-compressed 3D textures require less address space. Since 3D textures can be potentially large, and address space exhaustion is a concern for 32-bit applications, S3TC-compressed 3D textures are uploaded per-slice, instead of in a single upload. - The ID3D11Multithread interface is implemented. - Various lighting calculation fixes and improvements for older DirectDraw applications have been made. - Limited support for blits across swapchains is implemented. - More shader reflection APIs are implemented. - The wined3d CPU blitter can handle compressed source resources. Support for compressed destination resources was already implemented in a previous release. - The Direct3D graphics card database recognizes more graphics cards. - New HKEY_CURRENT_USER\Software\Wine\Direct3D registry keys: - &quot;shader_backend&quot; (REG_SZ) The shader backend to use. Possible values are &quot;glsl&quot; (default) for GLSL, &quot;arb&quot; for ARB vertex/fragment programs and &quot;none&quot; to disable shader support. - &quot;strict_shader_math&quot; (REG_DWORD) Enable (0x1) or disable (0x0, default) stricter translation of Direct3D shaders, potentially at a performance cost. This currently only makes a difference with the default GLSL shader backend in combination with the proprietary NVIDIA drivers. - Deprecated HKEY_CURRENT_USER\Software\Wine\Direct3D registry key: - &quot;UseGLSL&quot; This has been superseded by the &quot;shader_backend&quot; setting above. *** D3DX - Support for compressing textures using S3TC-compression is implemented. - Various operations, like e.g. texture fills, on unmappable surfaces are implemented more correctly. Previously their implementation relied on the underlying Direct3D implementation not enforcing mapping restrictions. - Various improvements and fixes have been made to the effect framework. *** Kernel - Most of the functions that used to be in Kernel32 are moved to KernelBase, to follow the architecture of recent Windows versions. - Libraries of the wrong 32/64-bitness are ignored when found in the search path, to enable loading the correct one if it's found further in the path. - Kernel objects are better emulated for device drivers that expect to manipulate objects from the kernel side. - The kernel-level synchronization objects like spin locks, fast mutexes, remove locks, and resource variables are implemented. - The system battery state is properly reported to applications. *** User interface - Minimized windows are displayed using their title bar instead of the old Windows 3.1-style icons. - The new button styles Split Buttons and Command Links are implemented. - The Edit control sets margins correctly also for CJK fonts. *** Desktop integration - Symbolic links to the corresponding Unix directories are created for the 'Downloads' and 'Templates' folders. *** Input devices - Plug &amp;amp; Play device drivers can be installed and loaded on startup. - Game controllers are better supported, including proper support for hat switch, wheel, gas and brake controls. - The old joystick API of Linux versions earlier than 2.2 is no longer supported. *** .NET - The Mono engine is updated to version 4.9.4, including parts of the Windows Presentation Foundation (WPF) framework. - The Gecko and Mono add-ons support shared installation, where the files are used directly from a global location under /usr/share/wine instead of being copied into every new prefix. *** Internet and networking - The Gecko engine is refreshed to support recent toolchains. - A number of new HTML APIs are implemented. - MSHTML supports some SVG elements. - Error object and exception propagation are supported in VBScript. - A number of VBScript builtin functions are implemented. - JScript EcmaScript compliant mode is extended to support more features. - JScript and VBScript script objects expose type info interfaces. - The HTTP proxy configuration can be retrieved through DHCP. - Passport HTTP redirects are supported. - The HTTP service and corresponding client-side library (HTTPAPI) are partially implemented. *** Cryptography - ECC (elliptic-curve) keys are supported when using GnuTLS. - Importing keys and certificates from PFX blobs is implemented. - The PBKDF2 key derivation algorithm is supported. *** Text and fonts - OpenType positioning features are supported in DirectWrite, and enabled for Latin script by default, including kerning. - Font data access is made safer by validating the various data tables before using them. - DirectWrite interfaces are updated to a recent SDK, implementing some of the latest API additions. *** Audio / Video - The XAudio2 libraries are reimplemented to use the external FAudio library, for better compatibility. - The Media Foundation libraries are fleshed out, including: - Support for builtin and user async work queues. - Ability to submit periodic callbacks, waiting, scheduled, and regular work items, with support for item priority. - Support for media event queues. - Various core API to handle media type objects, stream and presentation descriptors, object attributes, byte stream objects, samples and buffers. - Initial Source Resolver implementation. - Initial implementation of Source Reader API. - Implementation for Sample Grabber object. - Core support for building topology objects. - Builtin presentation clock implementation, started implementing Media Session functionality. - The video capture filter has been ported to use v4l2 instead of the deprecated v4l1 API, allowing the use of some cameras which do not support v4l1. - Support for YUV to RGB translation and reading from v4l2 devices using mmap() has been removed; we now depend on libv4l2 for both of these things. - The builtin AVI, MPEG-I, and WAVE decoders have been removed; we now depend on GStreamer or the Mac QuickTime Toolkit to decode such media files. - Some more VMR7 configuration APIs are implemented. - The sound drivers support per-channel volume adjustments. *** Internationalization - Unicode character tables are based on version 12.1.0 of the Unicode Standard. - Unicode normalization is implemented. - The geographic region id is automatically set in the registry based on the current locale. It can be modified if necessary under HKEY_CURRENT_USER\Control Panel\International\Geo. - The Sinhalese and Asturian locales are supported. - Codepage 28601 (Latin/Thai) is supported. *** RPC/COM - The typelib marshaller supports complex structs and arrays. - There is an initial implementation of the Windows Script runtime library. - There is an initial implementation of the Microsoft ActiveX Data Objects (ADO) library. *** Installers - Microsoft Installer (MSI) Patch Files are supported. - The WUSA tool (Windows Update Standalone Installer) supports installing .MSU update files. *** ARM platforms - Exception unwinding is implemented for ARM64, using the libunwind library. - OLE stubless proxies are supported on ARM64. *** Development tools / Winelib - The Visual Studio remote debugger can be used to debug applications running under Wine. - The Debug Engine library (DBGENG) is partially implemented. - Binaries built for a Windows target no longer depend on the libwine library, to enable them to run on Windows without any extra dependencies. The libwine library is no longer built for Windows at all. - The Resource Compiler and IDL Compiler support a '--sysroot' option to allow locating header files in cross-compile environments. - Winegcc supports the options '--target', '--wine-objdir', '--winebuild' and '-fuse-ld' that make it easier to use as a cross-compiler, or with custom toolchains. - The wine/unicode.h header is no longer available to applications, since the functions will ultimately be removed and replaced by the standard C runtime wide character functions. *** Build infrastructure - Test binaries are built in PE format if MinGW is available, so the same test binary can run on both Wine and Windows. The 'crosstest' make target is no longer needed or supported. - The 'fastcall' calling convention is supported in spec files. It uses the correct name mangling for Windows builds. - A '-import' entry point flag is supported in spec files, to mark functions that need a hotpatch code prefix to be generated for their import thunks. - Winebuild supports a '--builtin' option to add a special signature to PE binaries to mark them as Wine builtins. *** Builtin applications - The CHCP tool is implemented. It allows setting the console codepage. - The MSIDB tool is implemented. It allows manipulating MSI databases. *** Performance improvements - The various time functions use higher performance system clocks if available, to reduce the overhead in the rendering loop of many games. - File lookups take advantage of the ext4 filesystem case folding support if it's enabled on the directory being searched. - No-data style listboxes (LBS_NODATA) have better performance for large numbers of items. - Slim Reader/Writer locks, keyed events, and condition variables use futexes on Linux to avoid wineserver round trips. *** New external dependencies - The MinGW-w64 cross-compiler is used to build modules in PE format. - The FAudio library is used to implement XAudio2. - The Inotify library is used for file change notifications on BSD platforms. - The Unwind library is used for exception handling on ARM64. - The Video4Linux version 2 library is used instead of version 1. -- Alexandre Julliard julliard@winehq.org&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 17:15:19 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>coldpie</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/plain</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://source.winehq.org/git/wine.git/blob_plain/wine-5.0:/ANNOUNCE</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why Learn Awk? (2016)</title>
<link>https://blog.jpalardy.com/posts/why-learn-awk/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.jpalardy.com/posts/why-learn-awk/</guid>
<description>&lt;section class=&quot;byline&quot;&gt;March 16, 2016&lt;/section&gt;&lt;p&gt;Because of the arcane syntax?&lt;br/&gt;Because other languages can’t do the job?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I resisted AWK for a long time. Couldn’t I already do everything I needed with sed and grep? I felt that anything more complex should be done with a “real” language. AWK seemed like yet-another-thing to learn, with marginal benefits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-learn-awk&quot;&gt;Why Learn AWK?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me count the ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;you-are-working-too-hard&quot;&gt;You are working TOO HARD&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Too many times, I’ve seen people working &lt;em&gt;way&lt;/em&gt; too hard at the command-line trying to solve simple tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine programming without regular expressions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can you even &lt;em&gt;imagine&lt;/em&gt; the alternative? Would it entail building &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Finite-state_machine&quot;&gt;FSM&lt;/a&gt;s from scratch? Would it be easy to program? Would it be fun? Would it work the way you want?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s life without AWK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For simple tasks (“only print column 3” or “sum the numbers from column 2”) &lt;em&gt;almost&lt;/em&gt; falling in the “grep-and-sed” category, but where you feel you might need to open a man page, AWK is usually the solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if you think that creating a new script file (&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;column_3.py&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sum_col_2.rb&lt;/code&gt;), putting it somewhere on disk, and invoking it on your data isn’t bad – I’m telling you that you’re working too hard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;available-everywhere&quot;&gt;Available EVERYWHERE&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Linux, BSD, or Mac OS, AWK is already available. It is &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/POSIX#Overview&quot;&gt;required&lt;/a&gt; by any POSIX-compliant OS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More importantly, it will be the AWK you know. It has been around for a long time, and the way it works is stable. Any upgrade would not (could not) break your scripts – it’s the closest thing to “it just works”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contrast with BASH or Python … do you have the right version? Does it have &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; the language features you need? Is it backward and forward compatible?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I write a script in AWK, I know 2 things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;AWK is going to be anywhere I deploy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it’s going to work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;scope&quot;&gt;Scope&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You shouldn’t write anything complicated in AWK. That’s a &lt;strong&gt;feature&lt;/strong&gt; – it limits what you’re going to attempt with the language. You are not going to write a web server in AWK, and you know it wouldn’t be a good idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s something refreshing about knowing that you’re not going to import a library (let alone a framework), and worry about dependencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’re writing an AWK script, and you’re going to focus on what AWK is good at.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;language-features&quot;&gt;Language Features&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you want the following? (especially compared to BASH)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;hashes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;floating-point numbers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;modern (i.e. Perl) regular expressions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s all there, ready to go. Don’t worry about the version number, the bolted-on syntax, or the dependence on other tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;convenience-minimized-bureaucracy&quot;&gt;Convenience: minimized bureaucracy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a script sandwich, your logic is the “meat”, and the surrounding bureaucracy is the “bread”. In practice, bureaucracy means:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;opening and closing files&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;iterating over each line of each file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;parsing or breaking a line into fields&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;These things are &lt;em&gt;needed&lt;/em&gt; but they aren’t what your script is about. AWK takes care of all that, your code is implicitly surrounded by a loop that’s going to iterate over every input line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DISCLAIMER: This isn’t AWK, it’s JavaScript. It might as well be pseudocode. All code simplified and for illustrative purposes only.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-javascript&quot; data-lang=&quot;javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// open each file, assign content to &quot;lines&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;lines&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;forEach&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;line&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// the code you write goes here&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;});&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// close all the files&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AWK is going to break each line into “fields” or “columns” – for many people, that feature is the main reason to use AWK. By default, AWK breaks a line into fields based on whitespace (i.e. &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/\s+/&lt;/code&gt;) and ignores leading or trailing whitespace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, AWK is automatically going to set a bunch of useful variables for you:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;NF – how many fields in the current line&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NR – what the current line number is&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;$1, $2, $3 .. $9 .. – the value of each field on the current line&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;$0 – the content of the current line&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.math.utah.edu/docs/info/gawk_11.html#SEC108&quot;&gt;more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-javascript&quot; data-lang=&quot;javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// open each file, assign content to &quot;lines&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;NR&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;lines&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;forEach&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;line&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;NR&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;NR&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;fields&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;line&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;trim&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;().&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;split&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sr&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;se&quot;&gt;\s&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sr&quot;&gt;+/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;NF&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;fields&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;length&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// the code you write goes here&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;});&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// close all the files&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;convenience-automatic-conversions&quot;&gt;Convenience: automatic conversions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AWK does automatic string-to-number conversions. That’s something terrible in “real” programming languages, but very convenient within the scope of the things you should attempt with AWK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;convenience-automatic-variables&quot;&gt;Convenience: automatic variables&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Variables are automatically created when first used; you don’t need to declare variables.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-awk&quot; data-lang=&quot;awk&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;++&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s unpack it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;the variable &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;a&lt;/code&gt; is created&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;using &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;++&lt;/code&gt; treats it as a number – &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;a&lt;/code&gt; is initialized to 0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;++&lt;/code&gt; operator increments it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s even more useful with hashes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-awk&quot; data-lang=&quot;awk&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;things&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;++&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;things&lt;/code&gt; is created, as a hash&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;using dynamic key &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;$1&lt;/code&gt;, a value is initialized to 0 (implicit in &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;++&lt;/code&gt; use)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;++&lt;/code&gt; operator increments it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;convenience-built-in-functions&quot;&gt;Convenience: built-in functions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AWK has a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.math.utah.edu/docs/info/gawk_13.html#SEC123&quot;&gt;bunch&lt;/a&gt; of numeric and string functions at your disposal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;awk-is-perfect&quot;&gt;AWK is PERFECT*&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AWK is &lt;em&gt;PERFECT&lt;/em&gt; when you use it for what it’s meant to do:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;very powerful one-liners&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(or) short AND portable scripts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;now-what&quot;&gt;Now What?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe I’ve convinced you to reconsider AWK: good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do you learn AWK?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many possibilities:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.jpalardy.com/posts/awk-tutorial-part-1&quot;&gt;next post&lt;/a&gt;, I’ll explain everything you need to get you started with AWK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;meta&quot;&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Discuss on Twitter&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;section&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/share&quot; class=&quot;twitter-share-button&quot; data-count=&quot;none&quot; data-via=&quot;jpalardy&quot;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jpalardy&quot; class=&quot;twitter-follow-button&quot; data-show-count=&quot;false&quot;&gt;Follow @jpalardy&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/section&gt;&lt;/section&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 16:57:11 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>LinuxBender</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.jpalardy.com/posts/why-learn-awk/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Glenn Greenwald Charged with Cybercrimes in Brazil</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2020/01/21/world/americas/glenn-greenwald-brazil-cybercrimes.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2020/01/21/world/americas/glenn-greenwald-brazil-cybercrimes.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;RIO DE JANEIRO — Federal prosecutors in Brazil on Tuesday charged the American journalist &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/07/20/world/americas/brazil-bolsonaro-greenwald.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Glenn Greenwald&lt;/a&gt; with cybercrimes for his role in bringing to light cellphone messages that have embarrassed prosecutors and tarnished the image of an anti-corruption task force.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;In a criminal complaint made public on Tuesday, prosecutors in the capital, Brasília, accused Mr. Greenwald of being part of a “criminal organization” that hacked into the cellphones of several prosecutors and other public officials last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Mr. Greenwald, an &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/07/20/world/americas/brazil-bolsonaro-greenwald.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;ardent critic&lt;/a&gt; of Brazil’s far right president, Jair Bolsonaro, is a deeply polarizing figure in Brazil, where his work is lionized by leftists and condemned as partisan and heavy handed by officials in the Bolsonaro administration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The news organization Mr. Greenwald co-founded, The Intercept Brasil, published articles last year based on the leaked cellphone messages that &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/06/10/world/americas/brazil-car-wash-lava-jato.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;raised questions&lt;/a&gt; about the integrity and the motives of key members of Brazil’s justice system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-ew4tgv&quot; aria-label=&quot;companion column&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The articles cast doubt on the impartiality of a former judge, Sérgio Moro, and of some of the prosecutors who worked on a corruption investigation that landed several powerful political and business figures in prison.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Among those charged in connection with the corruption investigation was a former president, Luiz Inácio Lula da Silva, a popular leftist whose conviction paved the way for the &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/10/28/world/americas/jair-bolsonaro-brazil-election.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;election of Mr. Bolsonaro&lt;/a&gt;. Mr. Moro was the judge who handled that case, and he is now Mr. Bolsonaro’s minister of justice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The case raises concerns among journalists and advocates for a free press because journalists often rely on confidential or leaked information, sometimes obtained by whistle-blowers or hackers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;In fact, Mr. Greenwald has been part of a team that won some of the most important prizes in journalism — the &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2014/04/11/business/media/polk-award-winners-to-accept-in-person.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;George Polk Award&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.pulitzer.org/winners/guardian-us&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Pulitzer Prize for public service&lt;/a&gt; — for his role in reporting on documents describing government surveillance that were passed on to him by Edward J. Snowden, a former contractor with the National Security Agency of the United States who later faced espionage charges in connection with the leak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;In a statement Mr. Greenwald called the charges “an obvious attempt to attack a free press in retaliation for the revelations we reported about Minister Moro and the Bolsonaro government.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-ew4tgv&quot; aria-label=&quot;companion column&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Mr. Greenwald, who has not been detained, said he intended to continue publishing and cast the case against him as a test of Brazil’s democracy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“We will not be intimidated by these tyrannical attempts to silence journalists,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;In a 95-page criminal complaint, prosecutors say that The Intercept Brasil, the news organization Mr. Greenwald co-founded, did more than merely receive the hacked messages and oversee the publication of &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/07/25/world/americas/bolsonaro-brazil-phone-hack-corruption.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;newsworthy information&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Citing intercepted messages between Mr. Greenwald and the hackers, prosecutors say the journalist played a “clear role in facilitating the commission of a crime.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;For instance, prosecutors contend that Mr. Greenwald encouraged the hackers to delete archives that had already been shared with The Intercept Brasil, in order to cover their tracks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Prosecutors also say that Mr. Greenwald was communicating with the hackers while they were actively monitoring private chats on Telegram, a messaging app. The complaint charged six other individuals, including four who were detained last year in connection with the cellphone hacking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Legal experts and leftist politicians criticized the decision to charge Mr. Greenwald, calling the evidence outlined against him thin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Thiago Bottino, a legal expert at Fundação Getúlio Vargas University in Rio de Janeiro, said prosecutors have not described evidence that suggests Mr. Greenwald broke the law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-ew4tgv&quot; aria-label=&quot;companion column&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“There’s nothing in the complaint showing that he helped or guided” the hackers, he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Mr. Bottino said Brazil’s case law gives journalists broad protections. “You can’t punish a journalist for divulging a document that was obtained through criminal means,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Gleisi Hoffman, the president of the Workers’ Party, the largest opposition party, called the charge an abuse of power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“They want a police state, with more farces, illegalities and arbitrary acts,” she wrote in a message on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Mr. Greenwald moved to Brazil in 2005 after meeting David Miranda, a Brazilian man he later married and who became a &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/01/24/world/americas/jean-wyllys-brazil-gay-lawmaker.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;federal congressman&lt;/a&gt; last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Mr. Greenwald first became widely known for his role in the release of classified national security documents leaked by the former National Security Agency contractor Edward Snowden in 2013. He co-founded The Intercept Brasil in 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Mr. Greenwald expressed concern last year that the authorities might charge him criminally as a reprisal for The Intercept Brasil’s reporting based on the leaked messages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Mr. Bolsonaro left little doubt that he’d relish seeing the journalist punished. In late July, the president used a derisive term to refer to Mr. Greenwald and said the journalist &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://oglobo.globo.com/brasil/talvez-pegue-uma-cana-aqui-no-brasil-afirma-bolsonaro-sobre-glenn-greenwald-23837301&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;“might wind up in jail.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-ew4tgv&quot; aria-label=&quot;companion column&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Mr. Greenwald’s concerns were partly based on reports that federal officials were investigating his finances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Those reports led a Supreme Court justice, Gilmar Mendes, to issue an extraordinary order barring the federal police from investigating Mr. Greenwald’s role in the dissemination of the hacked messages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Prosecutors on Tuesday said they abided by that order until they found audio messages which, they argued, implicated Mr. Greenwald in criminal activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The charges came as a “huge surprise,” Mr. Greenwald said in an interview on Tuesday, because the Federal Police &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.metropoles.com/brasil/justica/spoofing-pf-buscou-crimes-em-conduta-de-glenn-mas-nao-encontrou&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;issued a report&lt;/a&gt; in December that cleared him of having engaged in criminal conduct related to the phone hacks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Mr. Greenwald said he had been methodical in his dealings with the source who gave him the leaked chats, mindful of the lessons he had learned in the Snowden case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“The one thing I could not do is give direction,” Mr. Greenwald said. “That’s crossing a line. I was very careful.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The prosecutor who filed the case, Wellington Oliveira, &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://politica.estadao.com.br/blogs/fausto-macedo/procuradoria-denuncia-felipe-santa-cruz-por-chamar-moro-de-chefe-de-quadrilha/&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;last month charged&lt;/a&gt; the president of Brazil’s bar association with libel for making disparaging remarks about Mr. Moro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-ew4tgv&quot; aria-label=&quot;companion column&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;A federal judge &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.migalhas.com.br/Quentes/17,MI318409,41046-Rejeitada+denuncia+do+MPF+contra+Felipe+Santa+Cruz+por+critica+a+Moro&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;recently dismissed the case&lt;/a&gt;, ruling that Mr. Oliveira’s argument lacked a solid legal base.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The Committee to Protect Journalists expressed alarm over the case against Mr. Greenwald.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“Charging journalists with criminal activity based on interactions with sources sends a chilling message to reporters working on sensitive stories at a time when the Brazilian media is increasingly under attack from officials in its own government,” said Natalie Southwick, the program coordinator at the committee who monitors press freedom in Latin America.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-jwz2nf etfikam0&quot;&gt;Manuela Andreoni contributed reporting from Rio de Janeiro, and Letícia Casado from Brasília.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-ew4tgv&quot; aria-label=&quot;companion column&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 16:19:15 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jmsflknr</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2020/01/21/world/americas/glenn-greenwald-brazil-cybercrimes.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Glenn Greenwald Charged With Cybercrimes in Brazil</og:title>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2020/01/21/world/21brazil/21brazil-facebookJumbo.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>Mr. Greenwald is accused of being part of a “criminal investigation” that hacked into the cellphones of prosecutors and public officials.</og:description>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2020/01/21/world/americas/glenn-greenwald-brazil-cybercrimes.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Every Google result now looks like an ad</title>
<link>https://twitter.com/craigmod/status/1219644556003565568</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://twitter.com/craigmod/status/1219644556003565568</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/craigmod/status/1219644556003565568&quot;&gt;https://twitter.com/craigmod/status/1219644556003565568&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=22107823&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=22107823&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 1794&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 624&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 15:38:22 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>cmod</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://mobile.twitter.com/craigmod/status/1219644556003565568</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>WikiHow’s art is made by a network of freelancers, mostly in the Philippines</title>
<link>https://onezero.medium.com/we-finally-figured-out-who-makes-wikihows-bizarre-art-6c5d69b71347</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://onezero.medium.com/we-finally-figured-out-who-makes-wikihows-bizarre-art-6c5d69b71347</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;19d1&quot; class=&quot;io ip dt ba iq b ir is it iu iv iw ix iy iz ja jb jc&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;r jd jm jg fl jn&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;In&quot; class=&quot;jo jp jq jr js jt dg t u hv ak&quot; src=&quot;https://miro.medium.com/max/158/1*MbVDtYdwH72TZxCGavl52Q.png&quot; width=&quot;79&quot; height=&quot;79&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;r jd je jf jg jh ji jj jk jl fl ht&quot;&gt;In&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; a 2015 presentation at LDV Vision Summit, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/thomscher/&quot; class=&quot;ge cf ik il im in&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;Tom Scher&lt;/a&gt;, who, according to LinkedIn, worked at wikiHow for four years and rose from a project manager to “Senior Director Marketing &amp;amp; Visual Content,” describes wikiHow’s visual content strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p id=&quot;a104&quot; class=&quot;io ip dt ba iq b ir is it iu iv iw ix iy iz ja jb&quot;&gt;Scher says in the presentation that, “about four years” previous to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ldv.co/visionsummit/2015/agenda&quot; class=&quot;ge cf ik il im in&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;May 2015 keynote&lt;/a&gt;, wikiHow’s graphics were mostly a motley assortment of user-created art and pictures sourced from Flickr. Around that time, he continues, wikiHow “started an initiative to start producing this visual content ourselves.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;3dc3&quot; class=&quot;io ip dt ba iq b ir is it iu iv iw ix iy iz ja jb&quot;&gt;The shift in strategy came the same year that Google released “Google Panda,” a major change to its search ranking algorithm, which an O’Reilly Media &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oreilly.com/radar/media-in-the-age-of-algorithms/&quot; class=&quot;ge cf ik il im in&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;report&lt;/a&gt; describes as being released in response “to the rise of low quality ‘content farms.’”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;0f3c&quot; class=&quot;io ip dt ba iq b ir is it iu iv iw ix iy iz ja jb&quot;&gt;One slide showing the “early days of the wikiVisual project” illustrates the evolution of a wikiHow post about how to cook macaroni and cheese. Scher comments that it once featured a “really bad illustration of blocks of yellow being put in water.”&lt;/p&gt;

Image: LDV Vision Summit
&lt;p id=&quot;7e0d&quot; class=&quot;io ip dt ba iq b ir is it iu iv iw ix iy iz ja jb&quot;&gt;“Here’s the thing though, it still led to an increase to traffic on the page,” Scher said, referring to the clip-art style graphic. “We were being rewarded for adding images, regardless of whether or not the images were crappy.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;ed30&quot; class=&quot;io ip dt ba iq b ir is it iu iv iw ix iy iz ja jb&quot;&gt;Scher notes during his talk that, in certain cases, wikiHow opted to commission original photography or create videos as opposed to drawings, as these often tested better for metrics like engagement, “helpfulness,” and “authority.” Regardless, the company leaned into making illustrations en masse in 2011.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;2515&quot; class=&quot;io ip dt ba iq b ir is it iu iv iw ix iy iz ja jb&quot;&gt;“It was so worth the cost, we did it at scale. Over four years we ended up doing 1.4 million custom visuals, and those are live on over 150,000 of our articles. That’s a lot, and it’s taken a lot of manpower to make it happen, and we’re constantly trying to move the needle even further on that visual content.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;10f2&quot; class=&quot;io ip dt ba iq b ir is it iu iv iw ix iy iz ja jb&quot;&gt;“This project kind of started as, frankly, something completely experimental in 2011,” Hadley told me. “We just wanted to see if we could find people to help us create custom images for our articles.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;83d0&quot; class=&quot;io ip dt ba iq b ir is it iu iv iw ix iy iz ja jb&quot;&gt;Hadley said the secrecy around wikiHow art exists partly because the system worked so well. “It was new, but we felt like we had something that was really special, so we kind of asked people to keep it a bit of a mystery,” he said. “And, over the years, kind of maintaining the enigma has been part of the fun… that mystery has been a part of why this stuff has gained traction.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;3b49&quot; class=&quot;io ip dt ba iq b ir is it iu iv iw ix iy iz ja jb&quot;&gt;Still, traces of the operation can be found online. Dozens of professional profiles on sites like LinkedIn and Behance mention freelance illustration for wikiHow. The vast majority list locations in the Philippines, with others based in countries including Argentina, Romania, Bulgaria, Macedonia, Turkey, India, Indonesia, and New Zealand. A search of the Philippines-specific job portal &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.onlinejobs.ph/&quot; class=&quot;ge cf ik il im in&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;onlinejobs.ph&lt;/a&gt; with a “Pro” account turned up a dozen more profiles who listed past freelance illustration experience at the site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;1bb6&quot; class=&quot;io ip dt ba iq b ir is it iu iv iw ix iy iz ja jb&quot;&gt;Two Philippines-based illustrators attached specific examples of art they created for wikiHow guides to their profiles or websites. Their work is currently featured on multiple live wikiHow articles. One of the artists noted that she’d “illustrated 3000+ articles” over a span of more than four years. Eight artists based in the Philippines, and one in the U.S., confirmed to &lt;em class=&quot;ju&quot;&gt;OneZero&lt;/em&gt; that they’d created art on a freelance basis at some point for wikiHow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;55b6&quot; class=&quot;io ip dt ba iq b ir is it iu iv iw ix iy iz ja jb&quot;&gt;LinkedIn profiles of wikiHow’s in-house team also indicate a worldwide illustration operation. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/chungdaisy/&quot; class=&quot;ge cf ik il im in&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;Daisy Chung&lt;/a&gt;, wikiHow’s current creative director, lists one of her responsibilities as “provid[ing] creative direction to a large global team of illustrators.” &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/brookemdesigns/&quot; class=&quot;ge cf ik il im in&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;Brooke Matthews&lt;/a&gt;, who, according to her LinkedIn, worked at wikiHow from 2012 to 2017, first as a “Project Manager of Visual Content” and eventually “Director of Visual Content,” notes that she “led the creation of over 2.5+ million custom digital media assets,” “traveled globally to meet with content producers and hold artist workshops,” as well as “mentored two in-house visual team project managers.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;0776&quot; class=&quot;io ip dt ba iq b ir is it iu iv iw ix iy iz ja jb&quot;&gt;“The artists on wikiHow really are people all over the globe,” said Hadley. “Probably the only place you won’t find some sort of wikiHow artist is in Antarctica.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p id=&quot;d756&quot; class=&quot;io ip dt ba iq b ir is it iu iv iw ix iy iz ja jb&quot;&gt;Contracts with nondisclosure agreements could potentially be to blame for how few artists mention working for wikiHow publicly relative to the site’s humongous volume of illustration work. For instance, one self-employed illustrator listed their work experience as “2 years as illustrator in WikiHow” on one online professional profile, but, on another, only said they’d been “hired in NDA contract with certain company as illustrator” for two years and 10 months. When contacted by &lt;em class=&quot;ju&quot;&gt;OneZero&lt;/em&gt;, this artist confirmed she’d signed an “NDA form (non disclosure agreement),” and asked which website listed the information so she could take it down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;e6bc&quot; class=&quot;io ip dt ba iq b ir is it iu iv iw ix iy iz ja jb&quot;&gt;The eight Philippines-based artists &lt;em class=&quot;ju&quot;&gt;OneZero&lt;/em&gt; interviewed said they found out about the wikiHow opportunity in a variety of ways. One former freelancer told me she’d started drawing for wikiHow after a “guy randomly went to my university and start[ed] asking around who’s good at drawing.” Another said he was referred to a hiring manager by a friend. Several more said that they found work at wikiHow via third-party companies, either by finding their listings on sites like Upwork and Indeed, or by being contacted by representatives from these groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;d8fd&quot; class=&quot;io ip dt ba iq b ir is it iu iv iw ix iy iz ja jb&quot;&gt;A company named “ArtLab Branding Solutions,” which appears to be based in Cagayan de Oro in the Philippines, is one of these middlemen. When reached for comment, the company’s CEO Freddie Ray Cornella confirmed that wikiHow was a client.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;1e99&quot; class=&quot;io ip dt ba iq b ir is it iu iv iw ix iy iz ja jb&quot;&gt;“We do bulk illustrations for them,” Cornella said in a Facebook message, adding that ArtLab is able to create hundreds of unique images per day, “even up to a thousand if the contract is long term.” He provided a document showing the kind of art the company creates, adding that, “Wiki illustrations are just very basic.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;d1bc&quot; class=&quot;io ip dt ba iq b ir is it iu iv iw ix iy iz ja jb&quot;&gt;When asked about the specifics of his business, Cornella declined to provide details, saying the information was “confidential.” &lt;em class=&quot;ju&quot;&gt;OneZero&lt;/em&gt; found details of ArtLab’s operation online. An onlinejobs.ph profile of one Philippines-based IT specialist lists that, in 2017, he’d been “working with for WikiHow for 3 years with ArtLab Branding Solutions as the middle man.” An Upwork profile of an artist working near Cagayan de Oro notes that he spent 2015 “simplifying instructions doing article illustrations for WikiHow under Artlab Branding Solutions.” Another graphic designer’s onlinejobs.ph profile simply stated that he’d “done quite a bit of articles for Wikihow from our Company Cornella Design Agency” in 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;9d97&quot; class=&quot;io ip dt ba iq b ir is it iu iv iw ix iy iz ja jb&quot;&gt;Cornella did offer an estimate of how many illustrations his company had provided to wikiHow in one word: “countless.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;5632&quot; class=&quot;io ip dt ba iq b ir is it iu iv iw ix iy iz ja jb&quot;&gt;Hadley said wikiHow “recruited initially through a variety of online platforms” but that most artists were now found via freelancers referring friends and classmates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;551a&quot; class=&quot;io ip dt ba iq b ir is it iu iv iw ix iy iz ja jb&quot;&gt;Once sourced, artists are required to complete a simple application exercise. “There’s a sample article where you have to do sample illustrations as a test,” a Manila-based illustrator who recently started freelancing for the company told me. &lt;em class=&quot;ju&quot;&gt;OneZero&lt;/em&gt; found an apparent example of this application from a different artist, a series of six sketches on a Behance account titled “Old Drawing Demo for HowTo / WikiHow Job Application.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;b2a9&quot; class=&quot;io ip dt ba iq b ir is it iu iv iw ix iy iz ja jb&quot;&gt;The current freelancer described an online platform where artists can choose a list of available articles that need illustrations. When the art is complete, he said, you simply email the art in a .zip file, and revisions come back via email. Hadley confirmed that wikiHow has “some internal CMS tools that allow people to reserve articles and submit them and get feedback,” and said that Chung oversees a team of three full-time project managers who focus on video and still images.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 14:40:57 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>pslattery</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>We Finally Figured Out Who Makes wikiHow’s Bizarre Art</og:title>
<og:description>Getting to the bottom of one of the internet’s most ridiculously drawn mysteries</og:description>
<og:url>https://onezero.medium.com/we-finally-figured-out-who-makes-wikihows-bizarre-art-6c5d69b71347</og:url>
<og:image>https://miro.medium.com/focal/900/474/76/49/1*dxoR-qLvFmawh-Ds3v4LkQ.jpeg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://onezero.medium.com/we-finally-figured-out-who-makes-wikihows-bizarre-art-6c5d69b71347?gi=3c86b625a469</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>How Germany is able to run the world’s second largest export economy</title>
<link>https://www.conradbastable.com/essays/the-germany-shock-the-largest-economy-nobody-understands</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.conradbastable.com/essays/the-germany-shock-the-largest-economy-nobody-understands</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-layout sqs-grid-12 columns-12&quot; data-layout-label=&quot;Post Body&quot; data-type=&quot;item&quot; data-updated-on=&quot;1579042179554&quot; id=&quot;item-5e1e3a51497e8e65ff957a1e&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row sqs-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col sqs-col-12 span-12&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block html-block sqs-block-html&quot; data-block-type=&quot;2&quot; id=&quot;block-5e218ac37917d71bf05e&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How Germany Is Able To Run The World’s Second Largest Export Economy In The Post-Industrial Era&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;“&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Germany Shock&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;” describes European growth &amp;amp; the efficiency-maximizing centralization of European manufacturing activity after the launch of the &lt;strong&gt;Single Market&lt;/strong&gt; and the &lt;strong&gt;Euro&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Two questions sparked this: &lt;strong&gt;1)&lt;/strong&gt; why did Europe only adopt the Euro &amp;amp; the Single Market &lt;em&gt;after&lt;/em&gt; its Cold War-era existential challenge was over, and &lt;strong&gt;2)&lt;/strong&gt; how has Germany maintained an export-oriented Industrial Manufacturing Powerhouse while every other developed nation is going &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Post-industrial_society&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;post-Industrial&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span&gt;“The Germany Shock” — a summary:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul data-rte-list=&quot;default&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Germany is a major outlier among high-GDP developed nations and nobody talks about it&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul data-rte-list=&quot;default&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;International trade is a &lt;em&gt;primary&lt;/em&gt; source of German economic prosperity&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul data-rte-list=&quot;default&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Only China runs a larger Surplus from Trade&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;No other nation has a customer base anywhere near as diversified as Germany &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;A China-USA Manufacturing Case Study:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul data-rte-list=&quot;default&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;i) &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;It is possible for a region to straight up lose at trade&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul data-rte-list=&quot;default&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;International competition &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; reduce employment in one geographic region without producing an offsetting increase in employment in that same region&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;ii) &lt;strong&gt;Manufacturing Network Effects: 3 - 1 = 0&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul data-rte-list=&quot;default&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;When the primary economic engine leaves a community, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;all the supporting economic activity leaves too&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, from barbershops to component suppliers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;iii) &lt;strong&gt;Exchange rates are a Cheat Code for selling stuff&lt;/strong&gt; — you might not be willing to cheat, but China is&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul data-rte-list=&quot;default&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;When China undervalues its currency, Chinese goods start looking real cheap&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul data-rte-list=&quot;default&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Foreigners then buy way more Chinese goods than they otherwise would have&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;iv) &lt;strong&gt;The price of your currency is a reflection of how desirable your whole nation’s economy is&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul data-rte-list=&quot;default&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The more successful your nation is, the more expensive it becomes for you to fight the free market and maintain the fiction of a cheap — undesirable — currency&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul data-rte-list=&quot;default&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;China deals with this via intense autocratic market interventions that are unthinkable in the West or — when tried in our free markets — lead immediately to failure&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Case Study Takeaway:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul data-rte-list=&quot;default&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;v) &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The price of industrial success is eventual failure:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Industrial Exporter nations tend to become stable, regionally dominant economies…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul data-rte-list=&quot;default&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;…their currencies then become highly sought-after “Reserve Currencies” &lt;em&gt;— making their products expensive and undermining the export-driven success that made their economies so great in the first place&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul data-rte-list=&quot;default&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;This spells doom for Germany because of how dependant they are on selling to other countries&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;The German Solution:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul data-rte-list=&quot;default&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;vi) &lt;strong&gt;The European Single Market functions to make German goods maximally attractive to trading partners &lt;em&gt;within&lt;/em&gt; the EU&lt;/strong&gt; by raising the effective-cost of imported goods&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;vii) &lt;strong&gt;The German Euro — the currency — then has its value suppressed via contamination with all the other&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(poorer-performing, non-Exporting)&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;European nations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul data-rte-list=&quot;default&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;This means German goods look cheaper than they otherwise would to non-EU markets&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Result:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul data-rte-list=&quot;default&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;viii) The Euro &amp;amp; the Single Market make it possible for Germany to pursue a strategy of Export-driven Wealth-creation that would be &lt;strong&gt;considered &lt;em&gt;impossible&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; in any other Western, high-GDP, high-population, high-wage-paying nation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul data-rte-list=&quot;default&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;European nations that have found a way to support the German Productivity Engine have built a symbiotic relationship that strengthens their union&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span&gt;Background: Nobody Ever Bothers To Look At The Data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here’s some data most people never see.&lt;/strong&gt; None of this essay makes sense if you aren’t familiar with it. It’s a bit academic at first, but you’ve got to understand it if you want to get to the entertaining stuff later. Given my focus on the Euro &lt;em&gt;(as a mechanism of exchange and therefore Trade)&lt;/em&gt; and the Single Market &lt;em&gt;(obviously about Trade)&lt;/em&gt; both being adopted &lt;em&gt;post&lt;/em&gt;-German-reunification, the data I want to see is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol data-rte-list=&quot;default&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who&lt;/strong&gt; is making money by Trading with other countries, and exactly how much?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How important&lt;/strong&gt; is that Trade to each nation?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;+some way to show the massive &lt;strong&gt;GDP differences&lt;/strong&gt; between nations — &lt;em&gt;some business models only work at a small scale&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Take a good look. The tagline here is &lt;em&gt;“Germany is a major outlier among high-GDP developed nations and nobody talks about it.”&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block image-block sqs-block-image&quot; data-block-type=&quot;5&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1579039247627_20878&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-outer-wrapper layout-caption-below design-layout-inline combination-animation-none individual-animation-none individual-text-animation-none&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;intrinsic&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-wrapper lightbox has-aspect-ratio&quot; data-animation-tier=&quot;1&quot; data-description=&quot;&amp;lt;p class=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;Barely legible, I know, let me zoom in&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&quot; data-lightbox-theme=&quot;dark&quot;&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579039682224-P51YYCXU0010QNWEJEPN/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kCnH0uKDFp8R-7zTqeMrWssUqsxRUqqbr1mOJYKfIPR7LoDQ9mXPOjoJoqy81S2I8N_N4V1vUb5AoIIIbLZhVYy7Mythp_T-mtop-vrsUOmeInPi9iDjx9w8K4ZfjXt2dozsLuMw3HfGXcT9D3AlGCAqBoA77B0ZNCn_pDh5xBzvCjLISwBs8eEdxAxTptZAUg/core_graph.png&quot; alt=&quot;Barely legible, I know, let me zoom in&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;thumb-image&quot; data-src=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579039682224-P51YYCXU0010QNWEJEPN/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kCnH0uKDFp8R-7zTqeMrWssUqsxRUqqbr1mOJYKfIPR7LoDQ9mXPOjoJoqy81S2I8N_N4V1vUb5AoIIIbLZhVYy7Mythp_T-mtop-vrsUOmeInPi9iDjx9w8K4ZfjXt2dozsLuMw3HfGXcT9D3AlGCAqBoA77B0ZNCn_pDh5xBzvCjLISwBs8eEdxAxTptZAUg/core_graph.png&quot; data-image=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579039682224-P51YYCXU0010QNWEJEPN/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kCnH0uKDFp8R-7zTqeMrWssUqsxRUqqbr1mOJYKfIPR7LoDQ9mXPOjoJoqy81S2I8N_N4V1vUb5AoIIIbLZhVYy7Mythp_T-mtop-vrsUOmeInPi9iDjx9w8K4ZfjXt2dozsLuMw3HfGXcT9D3AlGCAqBoA77B0ZNCn_pDh5xBzvCjLISwBs8eEdxAxTptZAUg/core_graph.png&quot; data-image-dimensions=&quot;1577x684&quot; data-image-focal-point=&quot;0.5,0.5&quot; alt=&quot;Barely legible, I know, let me zoom in&quot; data-load=&quot;false&quot; data-image-id=&quot;5e1e3bc226b74678877f12e5&quot; data-type=&quot;image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-caption-wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Barely legible, I know, let me zoom in&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block html-block sqs-block-html&quot; data-block-type=&quot;2&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1579039247627_25099&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;USA&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;China&lt;/strong&gt; are massive outliers in their own right, so I’m going to shrink the X-axis and exclude them for now so we can actually compare normal nations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block image-block sqs-block-image&quot; data-block-type=&quot;5&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1579039247627_25559&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-outer-wrapper layout-caption-below design-layout-inline combination-animation-none individual-animation-none individual-text-animation-none&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;intrinsic&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-wrapper lightbox has-aspect-ratio&quot; data-animation-tier=&quot;1&quot; data-description=&quot;&amp;lt;p class=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;Click to embiggen — &amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;The area of each bubble is &amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;based on each country’s GDP. &amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;See Notes &amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;[0]&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt; and &amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;[1]&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt; for data sourcing — I made zero adjustments, these are all World Trade Organization numbers&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&quot; data-lightbox-theme=&quot;dark&quot;&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579039748726-KEXJ94KGWCQU6AP7V35K/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kO9gmNQGGufCXoGqQe6AqagUqsxRUqqbr1mOJYKfIPR7LoDQ9mXPOjoJoqy81S2I8N_N4V1vUb5AoIIIbLZhVYy7Mythp_T-mtop-vrsUOmeInPi9iDjx9w8K4ZfjXt2dsdSFL0YtyZioS9aZBMaACsw5iSxd5NcVr-CC5zLmjTFCjLISwBs8eEdxAxTptZAUg/germany_focus_graph_2017.png&quot; alt=&quot;Click to embiggen — The area of each bubble is based on each country’s GDP. See Notes [0] and [1] for data sourcing — I made zero adjustments, these are all World Trade Organization numbers&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;thumb-image&quot; data-src=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579039748726-KEXJ94KGWCQU6AP7V35K/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kO9gmNQGGufCXoGqQe6AqagUqsxRUqqbr1mOJYKfIPR7LoDQ9mXPOjoJoqy81S2I8N_N4V1vUb5AoIIIbLZhVYy7Mythp_T-mtop-vrsUOmeInPi9iDjx9w8K4ZfjXt2dsdSFL0YtyZioS9aZBMaACsw5iSxd5NcVr-CC5zLmjTFCjLISwBs8eEdxAxTptZAUg/germany_focus_graph_2017.png&quot; data-image=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579039748726-KEXJ94KGWCQU6AP7V35K/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kO9gmNQGGufCXoGqQe6AqagUqsxRUqqbr1mOJYKfIPR7LoDQ9mXPOjoJoqy81S2I8N_N4V1vUb5AoIIIbLZhVYy7Mythp_T-mtop-vrsUOmeInPi9iDjx9w8K4ZfjXt2dsdSFL0YtyZioS9aZBMaACsw5iSxd5NcVr-CC5zLmjTFCjLISwBs8eEdxAxTptZAUg/germany_focus_graph_2017.png&quot; data-image-dimensions=&quot;1561x686&quot; data-image-focal-point=&quot;0.5,0.5&quot; alt=&quot;Click to embiggen — The area of each bubble is based on each country’s GDP. See Notes [0] and [1] for data sourcing — I made zero adjustments, these are all World Trade Organization numbers&quot; data-load=&quot;false&quot; data-image-id=&quot;5e1e3c04497e8e65ff95b8dd&quot; data-type=&quot;image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-caption-wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Click to embiggen —&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The area of each bubble is&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;based on each country’s GDP.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;See Notes&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;[0]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;[1]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;for data sourcing — I made zero adjustments, these are all World Trade Organization numbers&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block html-block sqs-block-html&quot; data-block-type=&quot;2&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1579039247627_29391&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;The X-axis here represents &lt;em&gt;“&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;money a country makes by Trading with other countries&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;”&lt;/em&gt;. Countries to the &lt;strong&gt;left&lt;/strong&gt; spend more money &lt;strong&gt;buying foreign products (imports &amp;gt; exports),&lt;/strong&gt; and countries to the &lt;strong&gt;right&lt;/strong&gt; make more money &lt;strong&gt;selling to foreign nations (exports &amp;gt; imports).&lt;/strong&gt; The X-axis therefore shows how profitable International Trade is to a country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;The Y-axis here is the “&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Importance of International Trade&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;”,&lt;/em&gt; reflected as the &lt;strong&gt;[ Absolute Value of Imports&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;+&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Absolute Value of Exports&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;] /&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;GDP&lt;/strong&gt;. The point of the Y-axis is to show the size of Trade flows in and out of a nation relative to its GDP. Not every nation actually profits directly from Trade, but that doesn’t make the imports less important to understanding what’s going on in each country. I define this axis as “&lt;em&gt;importance&lt;/em&gt;”, but you can substitute “&lt;em&gt;magnitude&lt;/em&gt;” for much of the same meaning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;The Y-axis exists to show how much Trade a nation engages in. The X-axis exists to show the profitability of that Trade. Putting them together helps understand a nation better than either data point in isolation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Take a country in the top-left — &lt;strong&gt;Singapore:&lt;/strong&gt; Singapore is a tiny trading outpost nation that serves as a primary gateway between East &amp;amp; West. Its total trade flows &lt;em&gt;(~$493B USD)&lt;/em&gt; dwarf its actual domestic productivity &lt;em&gt;(~$324B USD)&lt;/em&gt;, so &lt;em&gt;Singapore is the&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;highest nation on my Y-axis here&lt;/em&gt;. Those trade flows — &lt;em&gt;both the inflows and the outflows&lt;/em&gt; — are &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;absolutely critical&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to Singapore’s continued prosperity…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;…But producing goods themselves and selling them to foreign nations is &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; how they make their money. Singapore profits by making a market for other people to trade in, and by offering complex financial services to help those trades happen. And so &lt;strong&gt;Singapore, in aggregate, does not actually produce a Surplus directly from the Trade that flows in and out of its ports.&lt;/strong&gt; With 2017 Imports greater than 2017 Exports, they end up on the left-hand-side of the X-axis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Take a country in the bottom-left — the &lt;strong&gt;United Kingdom:&lt;/strong&gt; and you’ll note that &lt;strong&gt;direct trade with other countries is&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;less important to the UK than it is for any other European country&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (Y-axis) and that when it &lt;em&gt;does&lt;/em&gt; trade with others, it is not — in aggregate — a source of national Surplus (X-axis). &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;When it comes to Exports, the UK is not even in Europe’s top 5 Exporters, with Germany&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(230% more)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;, France&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(33% more)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;, Italy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(22% more)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;, and the Netherlands&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(15% more)&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;all coming out on top. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;For those familiar with British/European economic-history over the last 200 years, this should be surprising. Indeed, when the Single Market was adopted (1993), the UK was the 2nd largest Exporter in Europe. This essay is not about Brexit, don’t worry, but if you like connecting dots in economic data…start there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block image-block sqs-block-image&quot; data-block-type=&quot;5&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1579039247627_29859&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-outer-wrapper layout-caption-below design-layout-inline combination-animation-none individual-animation-none individual-text-animation-none&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;intrinsic&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-wrapper lightbox has-aspect-ratio&quot; data-animation-tier=&quot;1&quot; data-description=&quot;&amp;lt;p class=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;Pasted the same chart here to aid readability&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&quot; data-lightbox-theme=&quot;dark&quot;&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579039799638-RE5FEGKHRSH8Y76N8XZJ/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kO9gmNQGGufCXoGqQe6AqagUqsxRUqqbr1mOJYKfIPR7LoDQ9mXPOjoJoqy81S2I8N_N4V1vUb5AoIIIbLZhVYy7Mythp_T-mtop-vrsUOmeInPi9iDjx9w8K4ZfjXt2dsdSFL0YtyZioS9aZBMaACsw5iSxd5NcVr-CC5zLmjTFCjLISwBs8eEdxAxTptZAUg/germany_focus_graph_2017.png&quot; alt=&quot;Pasted the same chart here to aid readability&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;thumb-image&quot; data-src=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579039799638-RE5FEGKHRSH8Y76N8XZJ/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kO9gmNQGGufCXoGqQe6AqagUqsxRUqqbr1mOJYKfIPR7LoDQ9mXPOjoJoqy81S2I8N_N4V1vUb5AoIIIbLZhVYy7Mythp_T-mtop-vrsUOmeInPi9iDjx9w8K4ZfjXt2dsdSFL0YtyZioS9aZBMaACsw5iSxd5NcVr-CC5zLmjTFCjLISwBs8eEdxAxTptZAUg/germany_focus_graph_2017.png&quot; data-image=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579039799638-RE5FEGKHRSH8Y76N8XZJ/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kO9gmNQGGufCXoGqQe6AqagUqsxRUqqbr1mOJYKfIPR7LoDQ9mXPOjoJoqy81S2I8N_N4V1vUb5AoIIIbLZhVYy7Mythp_T-mtop-vrsUOmeInPi9iDjx9w8K4ZfjXt2dsdSFL0YtyZioS9aZBMaACsw5iSxd5NcVr-CC5zLmjTFCjLISwBs8eEdxAxTptZAUg/germany_focus_graph_2017.png&quot; data-image-dimensions=&quot;1561x686&quot; data-image-focal-point=&quot;0.5,0.5&quot; alt=&quot;Pasted the same chart here to aid readability&quot; data-load=&quot;false&quot; data-image-id=&quot;5e1e3c3710ae8105666d9310&quot; data-type=&quot;image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-caption-wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pasted the same chart here to aid readability&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block html-block sqs-block-html&quot; data-block-type=&quot;2&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1579039247627_33875&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Now take a country in the bottom-right — &lt;strong&gt;Japan:&lt;/strong&gt; and note while they make a considerable Surplus selling goods to other countries &lt;em&gt;(X-axis)&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;this is no longer all that important to them&lt;/strong&gt;, with only India falling below them on the Y-axis. Exports to other nations are only 14% of Japan’s GDP — &lt;em&gt;4th lowest in this data set&lt;/em&gt; — and at 11% of GDP, &lt;em&gt;Japanese imports are the lowest in the whole data set&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Those who’ve glanced at Japanese history will know they’re &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sakoku&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;no stranger to isolationism&lt;/a&gt;. Today’s state of affairs is not that extreme, but it’s worth noting that their domestic productivity engine and national standards of living are not particularly concerned with international trade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Which brings us to the top-right — &lt;strong&gt;Germany:&lt;/strong&gt; Total trade flows in &amp;amp; out of Germany are two-thirds the size of German GDP, dwarfing all other high-GDP economies on the Y-axis &lt;em&gt;(64%)&lt;/em&gt;. International trade is &lt;strong&gt;twice&lt;/strong&gt; as important to Germany as it is to China, and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;more than thrice&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; as important to Germany as to the USA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;And &lt;strong&gt;when it comes to GDP contributions, Germany is in a tier of its own&lt;/strong&gt; — it’s not just that the Trade is important &lt;em&gt;(remember Singapore?)&lt;/em&gt;, it’s that &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Germany runs the second largest Trade Surplus in the world&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, at $250 Billion in Surplus on $1.3 Trillion of Exports. Germany earns 7% of its GDP from that Surplus — only the tiny nations of Ireland and Hungary produce more of their GDP directly from Trade. For a large, developed nation, this is quite odd…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;…and it &lt;strong&gt;should be somewhat surprising given common Narratives that “&lt;em&gt;cost of labor&lt;/em&gt;” is a big driver of industrial capacity reallocation away from Western nations.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block image-block sqs-block-image&quot; data-block-type=&quot;5&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1579039247627_34337&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-outer-wrapper layout-caption-below design-layout-inline combination-animation-none individual-animation-none individual-text-animation-none&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;intrinsic&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-wrapper lightbox has-aspect-ratio&quot; data-animation-tier=&quot;1&quot; data-description=&quot;&amp;lt;p class=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;Re-pasted the same chart here to aid readability&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&quot; data-lightbox-theme=&quot;dark&quot;&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579039831791-605SMLPKDKRFR7I2B98V/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kO9gmNQGGufCXoGqQe6AqagUqsxRUqqbr1mOJYKfIPR7LoDQ9mXPOjoJoqy81S2I8N_N4V1vUb5AoIIIbLZhVYy7Mythp_T-mtop-vrsUOmeInPi9iDjx9w8K4ZfjXt2dsdSFL0YtyZioS9aZBMaACsw5iSxd5NcVr-CC5zLmjTFCjLISwBs8eEdxAxTptZAUg/germany_focus_graph_2017.png&quot; alt=&quot;Re-pasted the same chart here to aid readability&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;thumb-image&quot; data-src=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579039831791-605SMLPKDKRFR7I2B98V/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kO9gmNQGGufCXoGqQe6AqagUqsxRUqqbr1mOJYKfIPR7LoDQ9mXPOjoJoqy81S2I8N_N4V1vUb5AoIIIbLZhVYy7Mythp_T-mtop-vrsUOmeInPi9iDjx9w8K4ZfjXt2dsdSFL0YtyZioS9aZBMaACsw5iSxd5NcVr-CC5zLmjTFCjLISwBs8eEdxAxTptZAUg/germany_focus_graph_2017.png&quot; data-image=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579039831791-605SMLPKDKRFR7I2B98V/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kO9gmNQGGufCXoGqQe6AqagUqsxRUqqbr1mOJYKfIPR7LoDQ9mXPOjoJoqy81S2I8N_N4V1vUb5AoIIIbLZhVYy7Mythp_T-mtop-vrsUOmeInPi9iDjx9w8K4ZfjXt2dsdSFL0YtyZioS9aZBMaACsw5iSxd5NcVr-CC5zLmjTFCjLISwBs8eEdxAxTptZAUg/germany_focus_graph_2017.png&quot; data-image-dimensions=&quot;1561x686&quot; data-image-focal-point=&quot;0.5,0.5&quot; alt=&quot;Re-pasted the same chart here to aid readability&quot; data-load=&quot;false&quot; data-image-id=&quot;5e1e3c57497e8e65ff95c361&quot; data-type=&quot;image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-caption-wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Re-pasted the same chart here to aid readability&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block html-block sqs-block-html&quot; data-block-type=&quot;2&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1579039247627_38466&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;If you want the full data set, I put it &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1hepflfFDV-nP-INjpWw15NnKp-HZm_ZvE1kJDpimdGk/edit#gid=1531716412&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;in a Google sheet here&lt;/a&gt;. There’s too much to include in this section but feel free to explore it.&lt;strong&gt;[1]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;There’s one more piece of data to this puzzle: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;who&lt;/em&gt; the hell is Germany selling all these products to?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;German Export Partners, 2017&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block image-block sqs-block-image&quot; data-block-type=&quot;5&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1579039247627_38954&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-outer-wrapper layout-caption-below design-layout-inline combination-animation-none individual-animation-none individual-text-animation-none&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;intrinsic&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-wrapper lightbox has-aspect-ratio&quot; data-animation-tier=&quot;1&quot; data-description=&quot;&amp;lt;p class=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;Yes, I also think the chart on the left would look better as a pie chart, but the UN pays top dollar to produce these charts and it’d be a shame to recreate it in a more readable format &amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://wits.worldbank.org/CountryProfile/en/Country/DEU/Year/2017/TradeFlow/Export/Partner/by-country/Product/Total/Show/Partner%20Name;XPRT-TRD-VL;XPRT-PRDCT-SHR;/Sort/XPRT-TRD-VL/Chart/top10&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;source&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&quot; data-lightbox-theme=&quot;dark&quot;&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579039878545-8PRW1C19TFVDEXIZETVR/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kIOZu06F4-9wTJy2nribXcYUqsxRUqqbr1mOJYKfIPR7LoDQ9mXPOjoJoqy81S2I8N_N4V1vUb5AoIIIbLZhVYxCRW4BPu10St3TBAUQYVKchHc_0ILgMVHTcvuT8Rbbj8OuPHt-A9uiEASKe9oFZsdzvsNsqhVsD0eFsq8elS-e/german_export_partners.png&quot; alt=&quot;Yes, I also think the chart on the left would look better as a pie chart, but the UN pays top dollar to produce these charts and it’d be a shame to recreate it in a more readable format source&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;thumb-image&quot; data-src=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579039878545-8PRW1C19TFVDEXIZETVR/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kIOZu06F4-9wTJy2nribXcYUqsxRUqqbr1mOJYKfIPR7LoDQ9mXPOjoJoqy81S2I8N_N4V1vUb5AoIIIbLZhVYxCRW4BPu10St3TBAUQYVKchHc_0ILgMVHTcvuT8Rbbj8OuPHt-A9uiEASKe9oFZsdzvsNsqhVsD0eFsq8elS-e/german_export_partners.png&quot; data-image=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579039878545-8PRW1C19TFVDEXIZETVR/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kIOZu06F4-9wTJy2nribXcYUqsxRUqqbr1mOJYKfIPR7LoDQ9mXPOjoJoqy81S2I8N_N4V1vUb5AoIIIbLZhVYxCRW4BPu10St3TBAUQYVKchHc_0ILgMVHTcvuT8Rbbj8OuPHt-A9uiEASKe9oFZsdzvsNsqhVsD0eFsq8elS-e/german_export_partners.png&quot; data-image-dimensions=&quot;1123x461&quot; data-image-focal-point=&quot;0.5,0.5&quot; alt=&quot;Yes, I also think the chart on the left would look better as a pie chart, but the UN pays top dollar to produce these charts and it’d be a shame to recreate it in a more readable format source&quot; data-load=&quot;false&quot; data-image-id=&quot;5e1e3c866fd60b2cfe15404b&quot; data-type=&quot;image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-caption-wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Yes, I also think the chart on the left would look better as a pie chart, but the UN pays top dollar to produce these charts and it’d be a shame to recreate it in a more readable format&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://wits.worldbank.org/CountryProfile/en/Country/DEU/Year/2017/TradeFlow/Export/Partner/by-country/Product/Total/Show/Partner%20Name;XPRT-TRD-VL;XPRT-PRDCT-SHR;/Sort/XPRT-TRD-VL/Chart/top10&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;source&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block html-block sqs-block-html&quot; data-block-type=&quot;2&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1579039247627_43210&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The main takeaway here is how &lt;em&gt;diverse&lt;/em&gt; Germany’s customer base is&lt;/strong&gt; — how little customer concentration they see. The USA is their largest customer and the Czech Republic is down at number 12, but the gap between the two is shockingly small &lt;em&gt;(exports to the Czech Republic are ~37% of exports to the USA).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;For reference, this is how customer concentration looks for the next-largest trade-surplus-generating nation on the chart, &lt;strong&gt;Japan&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block image-block sqs-block-image&quot; data-block-type=&quot;5&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1579039247627_43672&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-outer-wrapper layout-caption-below design-layout-inline combination-animation-none individual-animation-none individual-text-animation-none&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;intrinsic&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-wrapper lightbox has-aspect-ratio&quot; data-animation-tier=&quot;1&quot; data-description=&quot;&amp;lt;p class=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;Note the &amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;10x delta&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt; between their top customer (USA) and their 12th customer (Indonesia) in the table on the right &amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://wits.worldbank.org/CountryProfile/en/Country/JPN/Year/2017/TradeFlow/Export/Partner/by-country/Product/Total/Show/Partner%20Name;XPRT-TRD-VL;XPRT-PRDCT-SHR;/Sort/XPRT-TRD-VL/Chart/top10&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;source&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&quot; data-lightbox-theme=&quot;dark&quot;&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579039970766-9XX8ETHMVIJED82MWMA8/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kKjro8yfaQogl3E2acYcn2gUqsxRUqqbr1mOJYKfIPR7LoDQ9mXPOjoJoqy81S2I8N_N4V1vUb5AoIIIbLZhVYxCRW4BPu10St3TBAUQYVKcm3iqJwLaGlN-BG-nOadTKx4DrECBl4uJiDOHp9l0ibrExgzRxdtFcS0zWGqd4Q5M/japan_export_partners.png&quot; alt=&quot;Note the 10x delta between their top customer (USA) and their 12th customer (Indonesia) in the table on the right source&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;thumb-image&quot; data-src=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579039970766-9XX8ETHMVIJED82MWMA8/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kKjro8yfaQogl3E2acYcn2gUqsxRUqqbr1mOJYKfIPR7LoDQ9mXPOjoJoqy81S2I8N_N4V1vUb5AoIIIbLZhVYxCRW4BPu10St3TBAUQYVKcm3iqJwLaGlN-BG-nOadTKx4DrECBl4uJiDOHp9l0ibrExgzRxdtFcS0zWGqd4Q5M/japan_export_partners.png&quot; data-image=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579039970766-9XX8ETHMVIJED82MWMA8/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kKjro8yfaQogl3E2acYcn2gUqsxRUqqbr1mOJYKfIPR7LoDQ9mXPOjoJoqy81S2I8N_N4V1vUb5AoIIIbLZhVYxCRW4BPu10St3TBAUQYVKcm3iqJwLaGlN-BG-nOadTKx4DrECBl4uJiDOHp9l0ibrExgzRxdtFcS0zWGqd4Q5M/japan_export_partners.png&quot; data-image-dimensions=&quot;1122x466&quot; data-image-focal-point=&quot;0.5,0.5&quot; alt=&quot;Note the 10x delta between their top customer (USA) and their 12th customer (Indonesia) in the table on the right source&quot; data-load=&quot;false&quot; data-image-id=&quot;5e1e3ce2cd1c0513b5bdc0ef&quot; data-type=&quot;image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-caption-wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note the&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;10x delta&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;between their top customer (USA) and their 12th customer (Indonesia) in the table on the right&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://wits.worldbank.org/CountryProfile/en/Country/JPN/Year/2017/TradeFlow/Export/Partner/by-country/Product/Total/Show/Partner%20Name;XPRT-TRD-VL;XPRT-PRDCT-SHR;/Sort/XPRT-TRD-VL/Chart/top10&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;source&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block html-block sqs-block-html&quot; data-block-type=&quot;2&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1579039247627_49749&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Intense customer concentration in their 5 largest customers.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intense customer concentration is the norm&lt;/strong&gt; here, and you can go to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://wits.worldbank.org/CountryProfile/en/Country/JPN/Year/2017/TradeFlow/Export/Partner/by-country/Product/Total/Show/Partner%20Name;XPRT-TRD-VL;XPRT-PRDCT-SHR;/Sort/XPRT-TRD-VL/Chart/top10&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;source I linked&lt;/a&gt;, change the country tag and play with the dropdown as much as you like. Again and again you’ll find Customer #12 is a much smaller fraction of Customer #1’s sales, whether you look at &lt;a href=&quot;https://wits.worldbank.org/CountryProfile/en/Country/ITA/Year/2017/TradeFlow/Export/Partner/by-country/Product/Total/Show/Partner%20Name;XPRT-TRD-VL;XPRT-PRDCT-SHR;/Sort/XPRT-TRD-VL/Chart/top10&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Italy&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;(Customer #12 is 17% of Customer #1)&lt;/em&gt;, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://wits.worldbank.org/CountryProfile/en/Country/GBR/Year/2017/TradeFlow/Export/Partner/by-country/Product/Total/Show/Partner%20Name;XPRT-TRD-VL;XPRT-PRDCT-SHR;/Sort/XPRT-TRD-VL/Chart/top10&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;United Kingdom&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;(15%)&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://wits.worldbank.org/CountryProfile/en/Country/FRA/Year/2017/TradeFlow/Export/Partner/by-country/Product/Total&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;France&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;(9%)&lt;/em&gt;, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://wits.worldbank.org/CountryProfile/en/Country/NLD/Year/2017/TradeFlow/Export/Partner/by-country/Product/Total&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Netherlands&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;(5%)&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://wits.worldbank.org/CountryProfile/en/Country/CHN/Year/2017/TradeFlow/Export/Partner/by-country/Product/Total/Show/Partner%20Name;XPRT-TRD-VL;XPRT-PRDCT-SHR;/Sort/XPRT-TRD-VL/Chart/top10&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;China&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;(10%)&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://wits.worldbank.org/CountryProfile/en/Country/KOR/Year/2017/TradeFlow/Export/Partner/by-country/Product/Total/Show/Partner%20Name;XPRT-TRD-VL;XPRT-PRDCT-SHR;/Sort/XPRT-TRD-VL/Chart/top10&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Korea&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;(6%)&lt;/em&gt;, or anyone else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Call it &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gravity_model_of_trade&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;gravity&lt;/a&gt;, call it policy, call it a multivariate fusion of all the factors that play into regional economies, the fact remains that &lt;strong&gt;Germany exports more goods, in absolute value terms, to it’s 12th largest partner than any other country I linked to.&lt;/strong&gt; Non-europeans might tend to lump “the EU” into a single trading bloc to make this stuff more digestible, much like we lump wildly differing US States into “the USA”, and that’s a fair move. In fact it’s a decent comparison. Either way, when Industrial Capacity reallocates, tens of millions of people are affected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;But unlike the USA, the winners &amp;amp; losers of Europe are not united under the same Federal umbrella.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In summary, Germany is an outlier, with huge international Trade surpluses that are integral to its GDP —&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;despite high costs of labor, high standards of living, high tax rates, and no good maritime ports&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;— and the most diverse customer base of any Exporter nation.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;The only country that looks remotely similar to Germany is Korea, and the last time I saw those two mentioned in the same sentence was when Korea knocked Germany out of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/football/live/2018/jun/27/world-cup-2018-south-korea-v-germany-live&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;2018 World Cup&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block html-block sqs-block-html&quot; data-block-type=&quot;2&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1579127104820_92288&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span&gt;A China-USA Manufacturing Case Study&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;The USA-China relationship is so hilariously distorting that you have to remove it from charts to be able to see anything interesting about other countries. Which makes it a perfect place to start a brief case study on what could potentially happen to a mature, high-GDP, high-wage-paying, high-standard-of-living industrial nation when it loses an Industrial Manufacturing competition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;(If this is already familiar to you, or if it gets too boring, skip ahead to section&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;iv&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you were a 1990s German minister&lt;/strong&gt; trying to plan for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dissolution_of_the_Soviet_Union&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;fall of the Soviet Union&lt;/a&gt; (1991), the loss of a common enemy that unites Europe, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/East_Germany&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;national-reunification&lt;/a&gt;, and the opening up of Trade Routes that had been behind the iron curtain, — &lt;em&gt;and if you could travel into the future and witness Chinese-American economic interactions&lt;/em&gt; — &lt;strong&gt;you’d learn exactly the right lessons to help you guide reunified-Germany to European prominence and national prosperity.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block image-block sqs-block-image&quot; data-block-type=&quot;5&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1579039247627_50679&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-outer-wrapper layout-caption-hidden design-layout-inline combination-animation-none individual-animation-none individual-text-animation-none&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;intrinsic&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-wrapper has-aspect-ratio&quot; data-animation-tier=&quot;1&quot; data-description=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579040064148-V5J9SKZTXJ6SN4699189/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kLooozh6tdwue4fu-A3SkMMUqsxRUqqbr1mOJYKfIPR7LoDQ9mXPOjoJoqy81S2I8N_N4V1vUb5AoIIIbLZhVYxCRW4BPu10St3TBAUQYVKcZYGrbCs8BMYoKwEpjdxxxnDT1Zx2SBLqPruZbW-dArbVgNMyATutzRPQ32V0ckTA/germany_china_usa_case_study_choice.png&quot; alt=&quot;germany_china_usa_case_study_choice.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;thumb-image&quot; data-src=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579040064148-V5J9SKZTXJ6SN4699189/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kLooozh6tdwue4fu-A3SkMMUqsxRUqqbr1mOJYKfIPR7LoDQ9mXPOjoJoqy81S2I8N_N4V1vUb5AoIIIbLZhVYxCRW4BPu10St3TBAUQYVKcZYGrbCs8BMYoKwEpjdxxxnDT1Zx2SBLqPruZbW-dArbVgNMyATutzRPQ32V0ckTA/germany_china_usa_case_study_choice.png&quot; data-image=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579040064148-V5J9SKZTXJ6SN4699189/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kLooozh6tdwue4fu-A3SkMMUqsxRUqqbr1mOJYKfIPR7LoDQ9mXPOjoJoqy81S2I8N_N4V1vUb5AoIIIbLZhVYxCRW4BPu10St3TBAUQYVKcZYGrbCs8BMYoKwEpjdxxxnDT1Zx2SBLqPruZbW-dArbVgNMyATutzRPQ32V0ckTA/germany_china_usa_case_study_choice.png&quot; data-image-dimensions=&quot;1035x519&quot; data-image-focal-point=&quot;0.5,0.5&quot; alt=&quot;germany_china_usa_case_study_choice.png&quot; data-load=&quot;false&quot; data-image-id=&quot;5e1e3d3ecd1c0513b5bdcec3&quot; data-type=&quot;image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block html-block sqs-block-html&quot; data-block-type=&quot;2&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1579039247627_54998&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Cue dry academic intro quote:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mainstream economists have long argued that international trade improves welfare. While trade may redistribute income, theory assures us that&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;under standard conditions the gains to winners are more than sufficient to offset any losses incurred by those suffering adverse effects from foreign competition…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Paul Krugman states this view vividly…“If economists ruled the world, there would be no need for a World Trade Organization. The economist's case for free trade is essentially a unilateral case: a country serves its own interests by pursuing free trade regardless of what other countries may do.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;The above is the introductory paragraph to the 2016 paper by Autor &lt;em&gt;(MIT)&lt;/em&gt;, Dorn &lt;em&gt;(University of Zurich)&lt;/em&gt;, and Hanson &lt;em&gt;(UCSD)&lt;/em&gt; titled: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nber.org/papers/w21906.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The China Shock: Learning from Labor Market Adjustment to Large Changes in Trade.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;The paper is focused on understanding the effect China’s rapid industrialization+globalization had on US labor markets. I’m going to quote &lt;strong&gt;(3)&lt;/strong&gt; sections from it, labeled with a number just like that, and you’ll have to trust me that they’re fair summaries because I want to get the lessons over with quickly &lt;strong&gt;so we can apply them to Europe, the Euro, and the Single Market.&lt;/strong&gt; Read the whole paper if you want to learn more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;i) &lt;span&gt;It Is &lt;em&gt;Possible&lt;/em&gt; To Straight Up Lose At Trade&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(1)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The reduced-form analysis suggests that&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;the reallocation of labor across U.S. industries and regions in response to increased competition from China does not produce an offsetting increase in employment by other U.S. traded-good industries&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;, as the simple logic of neoclassical trade theory would have predicted&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;While no economic theory is perfectly able to capture the complexity of reality, neoclassical models are useful because they’ve proven mostly accurate at describing the modern global economy. When reality fails to conform to those models we have two options: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;i)&lt;/strong&gt; the models lacked data that would have changed their predictions or…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ii)&lt;/strong&gt; the models’ fundamental assumptions about reality were not true in this case &lt;em&gt;(despite being true in the general case).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;What we &lt;em&gt;can’t&lt;/em&gt; do is ignore the mismatch between reality and our expectations. We expected Trade to be Net Good, because it is in the general case. For vast swathes of America, the reality was Net Bad. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Suffice it for this section to note the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;possibility&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; that &lt;strong&gt;international competition can reduce employment in one geographic region without producing an offsetting increase in employment in that same region.&lt;/strong&gt; That shouldn’t be &lt;em&gt;too&lt;/em&gt; controversial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;ii) &lt;span&gt;Manufacturing Network Effects: 1 + 1 = 3, but 3 - 1 = 0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Everyone in Tech knows all about the magical power of &lt;a href=&quot;https://a16z.com/2016/03/07/all-about-network-effects/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Network Effects&lt;/a&gt;. People have been writing books about it since before Facebook took over the internet. But comparatively little has been written about what happens when those exact same effects run in the opposite direction:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(2)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Employment has certainly fallen in U.S. industries more exposed to import competition. But&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;so too has overall employment in the local labor markets in which these industries were concentrated.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Offsetting employment gains either in export-oriented tradables or in non-tradables have, for the most part, failed to materialize.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Input-output linkages between sectors appear to have magnified rather than dampened the employment effects of trade both within regions and nationally.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;And they include this helpful graphic:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block image-block sqs-block-image&quot; data-block-type=&quot;5&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1579039247627_56975&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-outer-wrapper layout-caption-below design-layout-inline combination-animation-none individual-animation-none individual-text-animation-none&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;intrinsic&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-wrapper lightbox has-aspect-ratio&quot; data-animation-tier=&quot;1&quot; data-description=&quot;&amp;lt;p class=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;“Geographic Exposure to Trade Shocks at the Commuting Zone (CZ) Level” Note that those brown areas are bigger than most European countries.&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&quot; data-lightbox-theme=&quot;dark&quot;&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579040303652-4NGME4CHIBXVHII6C1WP/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kLPJwD_fY74KBqeuhGpURV0UqsxRUqqbr1mOJYKfIPR7LoDQ9mXPOjoJoqy81S2I8N_N4V1vUb5AoIIIbLZhVYxCRW4BPu10St3TBAUQYVKcIlOgOcRXZ9PIpBK0oDxGp0yitLIqHGNH8esaKYGdG4IdGnYoNn3BAve384TwyZbW/manufacturing_exposure.png&quot; alt=&quot;“Geographic Exposure to Trade Shocks at the Commuting Zone (CZ) Level” Note that those brown areas are bigger than most European countries.&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;thumb-image&quot; data-src=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579040303652-4NGME4CHIBXVHII6C1WP/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kLPJwD_fY74KBqeuhGpURV0UqsxRUqqbr1mOJYKfIPR7LoDQ9mXPOjoJoqy81S2I8N_N4V1vUb5AoIIIbLZhVYxCRW4BPu10St3TBAUQYVKcIlOgOcRXZ9PIpBK0oDxGp0yitLIqHGNH8esaKYGdG4IdGnYoNn3BAve384TwyZbW/manufacturing_exposure.png&quot; data-image=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579040303652-4NGME4CHIBXVHII6C1WP/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kLPJwD_fY74KBqeuhGpURV0UqsxRUqqbr1mOJYKfIPR7LoDQ9mXPOjoJoqy81S2I8N_N4V1vUb5AoIIIbLZhVYxCRW4BPu10St3TBAUQYVKcIlOgOcRXZ9PIpBK0oDxGp0yitLIqHGNH8esaKYGdG4IdGnYoNn3BAve384TwyZbW/manufacturing_exposure.png&quot; data-image-dimensions=&quot;1044x415&quot; data-image-focal-point=&quot;0.5,0.5&quot; alt=&quot;“Geographic Exposure to Trade Shocks at the Commuting Zone (CZ) Level” Note that those brown areas are bigger than most European countries.&quot; data-load=&quot;false&quot; data-image-id=&quot;5e1e3e2e11030b46c080d12d&quot; data-type=&quot;image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-caption-wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Geographic Exposure to Trade Shocks at the Commuting Zone (CZ) Level” Note that those brown areas are bigger than most European countries.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block html-block sqs-block-html&quot; data-block-type=&quot;2&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1579039247627_60794&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;It’s academic, I know, but there are 3 core points expressed in that one quoted paragraph that explain how &lt;strong&gt;3 - 1&lt;/strong&gt; can equal &lt;strong&gt;0&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol data-rte-list=&quot;default&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Manufacturing productivity can generate enough geographically-localized Surplus to support a range of supporting business &amp;amp; employment. When the primary “Surplus Engine” is removed from a local community, &lt;strong&gt;the surrounding non-Manufacturing businesses lose all their customers too&lt;/strong&gt;. This effect is &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;intensely localized&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, with dark-brown regions in the graphic above experiencing the brunt of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Increased Consumer Surplus thanks to lower prices from foreign goods can increasingly only be spent on &lt;strong&gt;purchasing even more imported goods &lt;em&gt;or&lt;/em&gt; on domestic services-based industries&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;accelerating the relocation of productive Manufacturing&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Manufactured goods are made up of other manufactured inputs &lt;em&gt;(consider: a car, an iPhone)&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;Network effects&lt;/strong&gt; between firms create healthy local economies, drive wages up due to competition for labor, and provide entire geographic regions with economies of scale. When lynchpin firms are somehow replaced by more competitive foreign offerings, they take that entire Manufacturing Network with them too — &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;their suppliers and manufacturing peers&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Poof&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;Magical Network Effects magnify all effects, positive and negative.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Regional economies tend to grow around a handful of businesses in a single industry, with hundreds of thousands of jobs and literally-millions of years of work-experience dedicated to supporting that industry, both directly &lt;em&gt;(suppliers, accountants, lawyers)&lt;/em&gt; and indirectly &lt;em&gt;(restaurants, taxis, barbershops)&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Someone&lt;/em&gt; in a region must Produce a large Surplus in order to support all the other economic activity.[2]&lt;/strong&gt; When that ceases to be true, when the dominant industry is removed, you get a gaping hole at the center of your local economy’s Network — those who &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; emigrate to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.investopedia.com/terms/g/greenback.asp&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;greener&lt;/a&gt; pastures do, and the Government has to step in to support those who can’t via social safety nets:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block image-block sqs-block-image&quot; data-block-type=&quot;5&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1579039247627_61266&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-outer-wrapper layout-caption-below design-layout-inline combination-animation-none individual-animation-none individual-text-animation-none&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;intrinsic&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-wrapper lightbox has-aspect-ratio&quot; data-animation-tier=&quot;1&quot; data-description=&quot;&amp;lt;p class=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;sourced from the same paper&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&quot; data-lightbox-theme=&quot;dark&quot;&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579040429978-SE2EJYX11AKD149KB1B9/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kFhhSFl67GmH9k3S45g9kttZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZUJFbgE-7XRK3dMEBRBhUpxrwkNV57MwqHYu228dxApmRRv8KcmMgQ5m-_mm4uA4OdHFJi49LflKFtbBaggINJg/government_transfer_receipts.png&quot; alt=&quot;sourced from the same paper&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;thumb-image&quot; data-src=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579040429978-SE2EJYX11AKD149KB1B9/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kFhhSFl67GmH9k3S45g9kttZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZUJFbgE-7XRK3dMEBRBhUpxrwkNV57MwqHYu228dxApmRRv8KcmMgQ5m-_mm4uA4OdHFJi49LflKFtbBaggINJg/government_transfer_receipts.png&quot; data-image=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579040429978-SE2EJYX11AKD149KB1B9/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kFhhSFl67GmH9k3S45g9kttZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZUJFbgE-7XRK3dMEBRBhUpxrwkNV57MwqHYu228dxApmRRv8KcmMgQ5m-_mm4uA4OdHFJi49LflKFtbBaggINJg/government_transfer_receipts.png&quot; data-image-dimensions=&quot;641x489&quot; data-image-focal-point=&quot;0.5,0.5&quot; alt=&quot;sourced from the same paper&quot; data-load=&quot;false&quot; data-image-id=&quot;5e1e3ead0700a84fb32f8c4c&quot; data-type=&quot;image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-caption-wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;sourced from the same paper&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block html-block sqs-block-html&quot; data-block-type=&quot;2&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1579039247627_65243&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Translation:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;For every $100 in products imported from China per person, the US Government had to hand out $6 in incremental social safety net benefits.&lt;/em&gt; They call them “Transfer Receipts” because that $6 ultimately had to be produced by &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;someone&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; doing something productive elsewhere — which makes it a “Transfer”. Governments are powerful, but they can’t wish money into being. &lt;em&gt;(Not sustainably, anyway)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;3 - 1 = 0.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;iii) &lt;span&gt;Exchange Rates Are A Cheat Code For Selling Stuff — You Might Not Be Willing To Cheat, But China Is&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;But if Networks are so god damn powerful, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;how did China overcome the inherent stickiness&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; of US Manufacturing Networks &lt;em&gt;and reroute global manufacturing &amp;amp; its associated trade flows to Chinese firms?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;The undercurrent to that question of course being: &lt;em&gt;“how might Germany circa 1990 avoid being undercut by Chinese firms and build an Export-driven Manufacturing Network of their own, despite high-wages, high-living standards, and high tax rates?”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(3)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;A third distortion advanced by think tanks and politicians in Washington, D.C. (see, e.g., Cline, 2010) is that&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;China has consciously undervalued its nominal exchange rate so as to promote its exports&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When China undervalues its currency, Chinese goods start looking real cheap.&lt;/strong&gt; Foreigners then buy way more Chinese goods than they otherwise would have, &lt;strong&gt;bootstrapping China’s Industrial Manufacturing abilities&lt;/strong&gt; with cash, customers, supply chains, and technical knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It’s hard to understate how impactful this is. Seriously, it’s like a Cheat Code for Selling stuff.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;40-Year US Dollar-Chinese Yuan Exchange Rate:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block image-block sqs-block-image&quot; data-block-type=&quot;5&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1579039247627_66296&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-outer-wrapper layout-caption-below design-layout-inline combination-animation-none individual-animation-none individual-text-animation-none&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;intrinsic&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-wrapper has-aspect-ratio&quot; data-animation-tier=&quot;1&quot; data-description=&quot;&amp;lt;p class=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;In case you’re unfamiliar with this stuff, normal 40-year exchange rate graphs don’t have this many straight lines &amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://www.macrotrends.net/2575/us-dollar-yuan-exchange-rate-historical-chart&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;source&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&quot;&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579040510134-H04LDX93Z5JLEUO2BM56/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kIkakhmyxViTRg2GA0-ZyFFZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZamWLI2zvYWH8K3-s_4yszcp2ryTI0HqTOaaUohrI8PIiUTQLHSG8VXNvpdGoKVhJGQ6mD5z2aYe00V0phJDfco/yuan_usd_exchange_rates.png&quot; alt=&quot;In case you’re unfamiliar with this stuff, normal 40-year exchange rate graphs don’t have this many straight lines source&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;thumb-image&quot; data-src=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579040510134-H04LDX93Z5JLEUO2BM56/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kIkakhmyxViTRg2GA0-ZyFFZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZamWLI2zvYWH8K3-s_4yszcp2ryTI0HqTOaaUohrI8PIiUTQLHSG8VXNvpdGoKVhJGQ6mD5z2aYe00V0phJDfco/yuan_usd_exchange_rates.png&quot; data-image=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579040510134-H04LDX93Z5JLEUO2BM56/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kIkakhmyxViTRg2GA0-ZyFFZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZamWLI2zvYWH8K3-s_4yszcp2ryTI0HqTOaaUohrI8PIiUTQLHSG8VXNvpdGoKVhJGQ6mD5z2aYe00V0phJDfco/yuan_usd_exchange_rates.png&quot; data-image-dimensions=&quot;833x518&quot; data-image-focal-point=&quot;0.5,0.5&quot; alt=&quot;In case you’re unfamiliar with this stuff, normal 40-year exchange rate graphs don’t have this many straight lines source&quot; data-load=&quot;false&quot; data-image-id=&quot;5e1e3efecbeb144b40fa0423&quot; data-type=&quot;image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-caption-wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;In case you’re unfamiliar with this stuff, normal 40-year exchange rate graphs don’t have this many straight lines&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.macrotrends.net/2575/us-dollar-yuan-exchange-rate-historical-chart&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;source&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block html-block sqs-block-html&quot; data-block-type=&quot;2&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1579039247627_70390&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;But undervaluing your currency ain’t easy. You can’t just wave a magic wand and &lt;em&gt;decree&lt;/em&gt; the value of your coin. You have to put real, tangible money to work counteracting the natural market forces, and you can’t ever stop because one correction will undo all your spending. In many ways &lt;strong&gt;the price of your currency is a reflection of how desirable your whole nation’s economy is&lt;/strong&gt; — when you &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.paulgraham.com/good.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;make something people want&lt;/a&gt;, the free market bids up the price. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;So the tricky thing about messing with currency markets is that &lt;strong&gt;the more successful your nation is, the more expensive it becomes to fight the free market and maintain the fiction of a cheap —&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;undesirable&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;— currency.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How have the Chinese been able to maintain their fiction?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Many nations have tried and failed to manipulate their currency’s exchange rate, most notably &lt;em&gt;(to me, personally)&lt;/em&gt; the British &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Black_Wednesday&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;in 1992&lt;/a&gt;, who hoped to maintain an &lt;em&gt;over&lt;/em&gt;valued currency for reasons of national pride and politics. To do this the Bank of England bought billions of Pounds and then held them, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;doing nothing with the money,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; mimicking market demand for their currency that did not exist. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block image-block sqs-block-image&quot; data-block-type=&quot;5&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1579039247627_70855&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-outer-wrapper layout-caption-below design-layout-inline combination-animation-none individual-animation-none individual-text-animation-none&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;intrinsic&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-wrapper has-aspect-ratio&quot; data-animation-tier=&quot;1&quot; data-description=&quot;&amp;lt;p class=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;I’m not kidding, this was actually their whole strategy. Unironically. Also, note how ripe for &amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;political&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt; abuse this sort of &amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;fiscal&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt; policy can be in a democracy — voters can be fooled that your &amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;policies&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt; are working by the actions of a few bankers and couple of newspaper headlines&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&quot;&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579040547895-31WUXPG1SMBR2ILMJH0T/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kPznaHJszYiAOzUvRU_8sjxZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWEtT5uBSRWt4vQZAgTJucoTqqXjS3CfNDSuuf31e0tVH7fg1XUpnNRhI7a1yyIo8qBmHuwTC1BbaYgJFI95f2BRur-lC0WofN0YB1wFg-ZW0/scrooge.png&quot; alt=&quot;I’m not kidding, this was actually their whole strategy. Unironically. Also, note how ripe for political abuse this sort of fiscal policy can be in a democracy — voters can be fooled that your policies are working by the actions of a few bankers and couple of newspaper headlines&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;thumb-image&quot; data-src=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579040547895-31WUXPG1SMBR2ILMJH0T/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kPznaHJszYiAOzUvRU_8sjxZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWEtT5uBSRWt4vQZAgTJucoTqqXjS3CfNDSuuf31e0tVH7fg1XUpnNRhI7a1yyIo8qBmHuwTC1BbaYgJFI95f2BRur-lC0WofN0YB1wFg-ZW0/scrooge.png&quot; data-image=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579040547895-31WUXPG1SMBR2ILMJH0T/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kPznaHJszYiAOzUvRU_8sjxZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWEtT5uBSRWt4vQZAgTJucoTqqXjS3CfNDSuuf31e0tVH7fg1XUpnNRhI7a1yyIo8qBmHuwTC1BbaYgJFI95f2BRur-lC0WofN0YB1wFg-ZW0/scrooge.png&quot; data-image-dimensions=&quot;482x360&quot; data-image-focal-point=&quot;0.5,0.5&quot; alt=&quot;I’m not kidding, this was actually their whole strategy. Unironically. Also, note how ripe for political abuse this sort of fiscal policy can be in a democracy — voters can be fooled that your policies are working by the actions of a few bankers and couple of newspaper headlines&quot; data-load=&quot;false&quot; data-image-id=&quot;5e1e3f2390eeff123a5de32e&quot; data-type=&quot;image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-caption-wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;I’m not kidding, this was actually their whole strategy. Unironically. Also, note how ripe for&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;political&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;abuse this sort of&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;fiscal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;policy can be in a democracy — voters can be fooled that your&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;policies&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;are working by the actions of a few bankers and couple of newspaper headlines&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block html-block sqs-block-html&quot; data-block-type=&quot;2&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1579039247627_74890&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;George Soros&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thebalance.com/black-wednesday-george-soros-bet-against-britain-1978944&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;famously&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong&gt;bet against the Bank of England&lt;/strong&gt;, by borrowing British Pounds from private lenders and immediately converting them to German &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Deutsche_Mark&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Deutsche Mark&lt;/a&gt; at the insanely inflated exchange rate being offered by the Bank of England. When the Bank could no longer afford to keep buying Pounds and stashing them in the basement, the exchange rate collapsed — and Soros made $1 Billion by converting just a few of his German Marks back into tons of British Pounds, &lt;em&gt;way more than he originally borrowed&lt;/em&gt;, paying off all his British loans, and pocketing all the left-over Marks. Smart guy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The German economy was booming. Britain’s was floundering. Nobody wanted Pounds and the Bank of England broke itself trying to pretend otherwise.[3]&lt;/strong&gt; The day it happened is known as “&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Black_Wednesday&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Black Wednesday&lt;/a&gt;” in the UK — incidentally my 1st birthday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;But China is not Great Britain and they want the opposite thing — an &lt;em&gt;under&lt;/em&gt;valued currency, not an &lt;em&gt;over&lt;/em&gt;valued one. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So they need to do the opposite to the Bank of England&lt;/strong&gt; —  they need to stash &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;foreign&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; currency in their basement instead of their own currency:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block image-block sqs-block-image&quot; data-block-type=&quot;5&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1579039247627_75355&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-outer-wrapper layout-caption-below design-layout-inline combination-animation-none individual-animation-none individual-text-animation-none&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;intrinsic&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-wrapper has-aspect-ratio&quot; data-animation-tier=&quot;1&quot; data-description=&quot;&amp;lt;p class=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;You read that as “Trillions”, by the way&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&quot;&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579040655696-0KSLVN3H1REEHSSYSNPT/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kMv_YacdTXfR9056rtLp7o1Zw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZUJFbgE-7XRK3dMEBRBhUpyNfe1evbkO-ZLE4-HcWG2VYtiZP0UUc8uV4W7Or4Kd23vNHBmXwoDN7m7EEGnPf9M/foreign_exchange_reserves.png&quot; alt=&quot;You read that as “Trillions”, by the way&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;thumb-image&quot; data-src=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579040655696-0KSLVN3H1REEHSSYSNPT/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kMv_YacdTXfR9056rtLp7o1Zw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZUJFbgE-7XRK3dMEBRBhUpyNfe1evbkO-ZLE4-HcWG2VYtiZP0UUc8uV4W7Or4Kd23vNHBmXwoDN7m7EEGnPf9M/foreign_exchange_reserves.png&quot; data-image=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579040655696-0KSLVN3H1REEHSSYSNPT/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kMv_YacdTXfR9056rtLp7o1Zw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZUJFbgE-7XRK3dMEBRBhUpyNfe1evbkO-ZLE4-HcWG2VYtiZP0UUc8uV4W7Or4Kd23vNHBmXwoDN7m7EEGnPf9M/foreign_exchange_reserves.png&quot; data-image-dimensions=&quot;644x423&quot; data-image-focal-point=&quot;0.5,0.5&quot; alt=&quot;You read that as “Trillions”, by the way&quot; data-load=&quot;false&quot; data-image-id=&quot;5e1e3f8fcbeb144b40fa17fb&quot; data-type=&quot;image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-caption-wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;You read that as “Trillions”, by the way&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block html-block sqs-block-html&quot; data-block-type=&quot;2&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1579039247627_79269&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Like the Bank of England “buying” up Pounds and stashing them in a vault, &lt;strong&gt;the Chinese have 3 Trillion dollars-worth of currency from their&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;“Customer-nations” stuck in a mattress.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Exactly how much of the $3 Trillion is actually held in Dollars vs. Euros vs. Yen is a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Foreign-exchange_reserves_of_China&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;classified state secret&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, but the expert consensus is ~2/3rds are Dollars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Is &lt;strong&gt;$2 Trillion&lt;/strong&gt; enough to meaningfully support an &lt;em&gt;under&lt;/em&gt;valued currency? &lt;strong&gt;Perhaps not by itself — it’s just one part of a holistic strategy. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;They also &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fixed_exchange_rate_system#Fiat&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;make it a serious crime&lt;/a&gt; to trade Yuan outside of their published Peg.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;And they increase the total supply of Yuan each year by more than double the increase in US Dollars. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;When you make more of something, it gets cheaper, and China makes sure there are many more Yuan than Dollars produced each year:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Chinese Money Supply (Yuan):&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block image-block sqs-block-image&quot; data-block-type=&quot;5&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1579039247627_80217&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-outer-wrapper layout-caption-below design-layout-inline combination-animation-none individual-animation-none individual-text-animation-none&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;intrinsic&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-wrapper has-aspect-ratio&quot; data-animation-tier=&quot;1&quot; data-description=&quot;&amp;lt;p class=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;~4x increase in Chinese Money Supply since 2009. Some critics have noted that the Chinese response to the 2008 crisis was to print their way out of trouble. I leave whether or not there’s an inflection point here to the reader to decide &amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://tradingeconomics.com/china/money-supply-m2&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;source&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&quot;&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579040701542-JR5L8FNNPN8D5JV7BRSF/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kLA1Ssic4ttvhRfxfwMBx9hZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZamWLI2zvYWH8K3-s_4yszcp2ryTI0HqTOaaUohrI8PINMPQet9jgnxRNkyBfCUhzduVpE8MKSScVpJiqkHZTeU/chinese_money_supply.png&quot; alt=&quot;~4x increase in Chinese Money Supply since 2009. Some critics have noted that the Chinese response to the 2008 crisis was to print their way out of trouble. I leave whether or not there’s an inflection point here to the reader to decide source&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;thumb-image&quot; data-src=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579040701542-JR5L8FNNPN8D5JV7BRSF/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kLA1Ssic4ttvhRfxfwMBx9hZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZamWLI2zvYWH8K3-s_4yszcp2ryTI0HqTOaaUohrI8PINMPQet9jgnxRNkyBfCUhzduVpE8MKSScVpJiqkHZTeU/chinese_money_supply.png&quot; data-image=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579040701542-JR5L8FNNPN8D5JV7BRSF/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kLA1Ssic4ttvhRfxfwMBx9hZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZamWLI2zvYWH8K3-s_4yszcp2ryTI0HqTOaaUohrI8PINMPQet9jgnxRNkyBfCUhzduVpE8MKSScVpJiqkHZTeU/chinese_money_supply.png&quot; data-image-dimensions=&quot;770x395&quot; data-image-focal-point=&quot;0.5,0.5&quot; alt=&quot;~4x increase in Chinese Money Supply since 2009. Some critics have noted that the Chinese response to the 2008 crisis was to print their way out of trouble. I leave whether or not there’s an inflection point here to the reader to decide source&quot; data-load=&quot;false&quot; data-image-id=&quot;5e1e3fbdcbeb144b40fa1dda&quot; data-type=&quot;image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-caption-wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;~4x increase in Chinese Money Supply since 2009. Some critics have noted that the Chinese response to the 2008 crisis was to print their way out of trouble. I leave whether or not there’s an inflection point here to the reader to decide&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://tradingeconomics.com/china/money-supply-m2&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;source&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block html-block sqs-block-html&quot; data-block-type=&quot;2&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1579039247627_84140&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;US Money Supply (USD):&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block image-block sqs-block-image&quot; data-block-type=&quot;5&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1579039247627_86290&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-outer-wrapper layout-caption-below design-layout-inline combination-animation-none individual-animation-none individual-text-animation-none&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;intrinsic&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-wrapper has-aspect-ratio&quot; data-animation-tier=&quot;1&quot; data-description=&quot;&amp;lt;p class=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;&amp;amp;lt;2x increase in US Money Supply since 2009 &amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://tradingeconomics.com/united-states/money-supply-m2&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;source&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&quot;&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579040742335-ORT2QVZDLN156Z3HKEEN/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kC0ao1XpKQcaN2vE3DuRTw1Zw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZamWLI2zvYWH8K3-s_4yszcp2ryTI0HqTOaaUohrI8PIizZgrE6hlKaPPd1dJYb-tjIo5idOE2AY-Lk5ZUcZaG4/us_money_supply.png&quot; alt=&quot;&amp;amp;lt;2x increase in US Money Supply since 2009 source&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;thumb-image&quot; data-src=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579040742335-ORT2QVZDLN156Z3HKEEN/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kC0ao1XpKQcaN2vE3DuRTw1Zw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZamWLI2zvYWH8K3-s_4yszcp2ryTI0HqTOaaUohrI8PIizZgrE6hlKaPPd1dJYb-tjIo5idOE2AY-Lk5ZUcZaG4/us_money_supply.png&quot; data-image=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579040742335-ORT2QVZDLN156Z3HKEEN/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kC0ao1XpKQcaN2vE3DuRTw1Zw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZamWLI2zvYWH8K3-s_4yszcp2ryTI0HqTOaaUohrI8PIizZgrE6hlKaPPd1dJYb-tjIo5idOE2AY-Lk5ZUcZaG4/us_money_supply.png&quot; data-image-dimensions=&quot;791x393&quot; data-image-focal-point=&quot;0.5,0.5&quot; alt=&quot;&amp;amp;lt;2x increase in US Money Supply since 2009 source&quot; data-load=&quot;false&quot; data-image-id=&quot;5e1e3fe621056e4db66a8e48&quot; data-type=&quot;image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-caption-wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;lt;2x increase in US Money Supply since 2009&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://tradingeconomics.com/united-states/money-supply-m2&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;source&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block html-block sqs-block-html&quot; data-block-type=&quot;2&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1579039247627_90143&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;I’m not here to argue about the exact money supply numbers, and it seems certain that Chinese interest rates &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.investopedia.com/ask/answers/040315/how-do-changes-national-interest-rates-affect-currencys-value-and-exchange-rate.asp&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;should not be the same as US interest rates.&lt;/a&gt; Though I doubt it, it’s possible that these two sets of figures are &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;exactly&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; optimal for both nations and are unrelated to exchange-rate-games — I just want to show that &lt;strong&gt;China is executing a consistent strategy at all levels of the Currency game.[4]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you’re a magical time traveling German minister from 1990, this entire section should be a terrifying glimpse of the potential future that awaits you when you try to build your manufacturing industry — you best start thinking of a plan to avert it.&lt;/strong&gt; China and those who would play China’s game — &lt;em&gt;playing to win&lt;/em&gt; — are coming for your Exports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block html-block sqs-block-html&quot; data-block-type=&quot;2&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1579127104820_93125&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;iv) &lt;span&gt;The Currency Problem: Trade Isn’t All That Matters&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block markdown-block sqs-block-markdown&quot; data-block-type=&quot;44&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1579039247627_92867&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Germany has a much bigger problem than Chinese&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;del&gt;cheating&lt;/del&gt; &lt;strong&gt;policy efforts.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block html-block sqs-block-html&quot; data-block-type=&quot;2&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1579039247627_93897&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Any armchair student of today’s macro economic / geopolitical environment should know that exchange rates are &lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt; more complex than a 1:1 correlation with demand for manufactured goods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block markdown-block sqs-block-markdown&quot; data-block-type=&quot;44&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1579039247627_94345&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even non-students should be familiar with the term &lt;strong&gt;‘Reserve Currency’&lt;/strong&gt; — and know that it refers to currencies that the market views as &lt;strong&gt;stable, secure, and a sensible place to park your cash&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;amp; investments. Today that means: US Dollars &lt;em&gt;(62% of all global reserve holdings)&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;del&gt;Deutsche Marks (16%)&lt;/del&gt; German Euros &lt;em&gt;(20%)&lt;/em&gt;, Japanese Yen &lt;em&gt;(5%)&lt;/em&gt;, and British Pounds &lt;em&gt;(4%)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block image-block sqs-block-image&quot; data-block-type=&quot;5&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1579039247627_95662&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-outer-wrapper layout-caption-below design-layout-inline combination-animation-none individual-animation-none individual-text-animation-none&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;intrinsic&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-wrapper lightbox has-aspect-ratio&quot; data-animation-tier=&quot;1&quot; data-description=&quot;&amp;lt;p class=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;Compare 1995 Pound/Franc/Mark Reserve Holdings to today’s Euro holdings to put 2 + 2 together (click to embiggen)&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&quot; data-lightbox-theme=&quot;dark&quot;&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579040918458-P6E15F6VMGKW0CMNCBP1/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kDX8i5UTHMue46GB6BP2zC8UqsxRUqqbr1mOJYKfIPR7LoDQ9mXPOjoJoqy81S2I8N_N4V1vUb5AoIIIbLZhVYxCRW4BPu10St3TBAUQYVKciulo-1UHT6dSwc0UDx_RxXTe4YP9QnngY69aIYQlS61x38vYSFDFiwEpwMyuBnxi/reserve_currencies.png&quot; alt=&quot;Compare 1995 Pound/Franc/Mark Reserve Holdings to today’s Euro holdings to put 2 + 2 together (click to embiggen)&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;thumb-image&quot; data-src=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579040918458-P6E15F6VMGKW0CMNCBP1/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kDX8i5UTHMue46GB6BP2zC8UqsxRUqqbr1mOJYKfIPR7LoDQ9mXPOjoJoqy81S2I8N_N4V1vUb5AoIIIbLZhVYxCRW4BPu10St3TBAUQYVKciulo-1UHT6dSwc0UDx_RxXTe4YP9QnngY69aIYQlS61x38vYSFDFiwEpwMyuBnxi/reserve_currencies.png&quot; data-image=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579040918458-P6E15F6VMGKW0CMNCBP1/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kDX8i5UTHMue46GB6BP2zC8UqsxRUqqbr1mOJYKfIPR7LoDQ9mXPOjoJoqy81S2I8N_N4V1vUb5AoIIIbLZhVYxCRW4BPu10St3TBAUQYVKciulo-1UHT6dSwc0UDx_RxXTe4YP9QnngY69aIYQlS61x38vYSFDFiwEpwMyuBnxi/reserve_currencies.png&quot; data-image-dimensions=&quot;1410x193&quot; data-image-focal-point=&quot;0.5,0.5&quot; alt=&quot;Compare 1995 Pound/Franc/Mark Reserve Holdings to today’s Euro holdings to put 2 + 2 together (click to embiggen)&quot; data-load=&quot;false&quot; data-image-id=&quot;5e1e4096cbeb144b40fa3818&quot; data-type=&quot;image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-caption-wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Compare 1995 Pound/Franc/Mark Reserve Holdings to today’s Euro holdings to put 2 + 2 together (click to embiggen)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block html-block sqs-block-html&quot; data-block-type=&quot;2&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1579039247627_99792&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Many folks are also familiar with the fact that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.investopedia.com/articles/forex/092415/oil-currencies-understanding-their-correlation.asp&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Oil is priced by OPEC in US Dollars&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, not their respective national currencies. Super carriers &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.conradbastable.com/essays/mercantilism-a-new-path-to-wealth-through-imperfect-competition&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;parked off Saudi Arabia’s coast&lt;/a&gt; help maintain &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; particular fiction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;If you want to buy Oil, you must first visit your local exchange agent and buy some Dollars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Which means the &lt;strong&gt;demand for US Dollars is pushed up by non-manufacturing-related causes. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;High demand for Dollars means Dollars are expensive.&lt;/strong&gt; That makes products Manufactured in the US expensive for foreigners — and therefore hurts US Industrialist Exporters, regardless of US industrial policy efforts.&lt;strong&gt;[5]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;This is super great for China, as it provides an &lt;em&gt;external&lt;/em&gt; source &lt;strong&gt;constantly applying upwards pressure on the value of the Dollar/Euro/Yen/Pound&lt;/strong&gt; — i.e. all of their customers! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;And it’s super frustrating for &lt;a href=&quot;https://mattstoller.substack.com/p/trumps-surprising-embrace-of-industrial&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Trump&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pm5xxlajTW0&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Bannon&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; crew, who’d like to spark some sort of US-based Industrial Manufacturing revival via Federal policy — which is like throwing gas on a fire in the midst of a rain storm and planning to stay warm and dry. &lt;em&gt;Whoosh&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;Bang&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Still gonna get wet.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block image-block sqs-block-image&quot; data-block-type=&quot;5&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1579039247627_100257&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-outer-wrapper layout-caption-below design-layout-inline combination-animation-none individual-animation-none individual-text-animation-none&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;intrinsic&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-wrapper has-aspect-ratio&quot; data-animation-tier=&quot;1&quot; data-description=&quot;&amp;lt;p class=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;You might get a big spark, but those trees are gonna stay wet — too wet to catch fire&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&quot;&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579041005073-THX1LDY0BL7VRSP7WWY1/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kB_Ea-jPUNLkFL04ODRRFJhZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWEtT5uBSRWt4vQZAgTJucoTqqXjS3CfNDSuuf31e0tVHfBR82PpMM9rQ-xw5_ejvSA_OL2Lg60jv9Ci9whuq6gmQ6l2WM7tn7mqHTODzkmeM/water_fire.gif&quot; alt=&quot;You might get a big spark, but those trees are gonna stay wet — too wet to catch fire&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;thumb-image&quot; data-src=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579041005073-THX1LDY0BL7VRSP7WWY1/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kB_Ea-jPUNLkFL04ODRRFJhZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWEtT5uBSRWt4vQZAgTJucoTqqXjS3CfNDSuuf31e0tVHfBR82PpMM9rQ-xw5_ejvSA_OL2Lg60jv9Ci9whuq6gmQ6l2WM7tn7mqHTODzkmeM/water_fire.gif&quot; data-image=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579041005073-THX1LDY0BL7VRSP7WWY1/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kB_Ea-jPUNLkFL04ODRRFJhZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWEtT5uBSRWt4vQZAgTJucoTqqXjS3CfNDSuuf31e0tVHfBR82PpMM9rQ-xw5_ejvSA_OL2Lg60jv9Ci9whuq6gmQ6l2WM7tn7mqHTODzkmeM/water_fire.gif&quot; data-image-dimensions=&quot;480x272&quot; data-image-focal-point=&quot;0.5,0.5&quot; alt=&quot;You might get a big spark, but those trees are gonna stay wet — too wet to catch fire&quot; data-load=&quot;false&quot; data-image-id=&quot;5e1e40d011030b46c0812d89&quot; data-type=&quot;image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-caption-wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;You might get a big spark, but those trees are gonna stay wet — too wet to catch fire&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block html-block sqs-block-html&quot; data-block-type=&quot;2&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1579039247627_104177&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;That same upwards pressure exists for all Reserve Currencies. Japanese Electronics Manufacturers were &lt;a href=&quot;https://voxeu.org/article/why-japan-lost-its-comparative-advantage-producing-electronic-parts-and-components&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;crushed&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; by the 2008 crisis&lt;/a&gt; response — when the rest of Asia perceived the Japanese economy as a &lt;em&gt;relatively&lt;/em&gt; stable safe haven and bought Yen in response, it naturally pushed Relative-Demand for Yen up and &lt;strong&gt;made the currency more expensive&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;Japanese manufacturers had to lower their prices&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(and thus profits)&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;to remain competitive internationally or go out of business:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block image-block sqs-block-image&quot; data-block-type=&quot;5&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1579039247627_104637&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-outer-wrapper layout-caption-below design-layout-inline combination-animation-none individual-animation-none individual-text-animation-none&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;intrinsic&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-wrapper lightbox has-aspect-ratio&quot; data-animation-tier=&quot;1&quot; data-description=&quot;&amp;lt;p class=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;Red line = what it costs to make stuff, Blue line = what you sell it for. &amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;Gap between the two == the opposite of profit. &amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://voxeu.org/article/why-japan-lost-its-comparative-advantage-producing-electronic-parts-and-components&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;source&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&quot; data-lightbox-theme=&quot;dark&quot;&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579041056073-948NJTQ4V3OGKTBIEJZQ/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kC3xiSH27tglWSH5S8MApzRZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZUJFbgE-7XRK3dMEBRBhUpwMWMTM-iwr-wvsatoiYtwWr-6ykZsZn5p3Y3szY1rMZ6vG94qkb1I7R5QWIx_VooI/yen_dollar_exchange_rates.png&quot; alt=&quot;Red line = what it costs to make stuff, Blue line = what you sell it for. Gap between the two == the opposite of profit. source&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;thumb-image&quot; data-src=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579041056073-948NJTQ4V3OGKTBIEJZQ/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kC3xiSH27tglWSH5S8MApzRZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZUJFbgE-7XRK3dMEBRBhUpwMWMTM-iwr-wvsatoiYtwWr-6ykZsZn5p3Y3szY1rMZ6vG94qkb1I7R5QWIx_VooI/yen_dollar_exchange_rates.png&quot; data-image=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579041056073-948NJTQ4V3OGKTBIEJZQ/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kC3xiSH27tglWSH5S8MApzRZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZUJFbgE-7XRK3dMEBRBhUpwMWMTM-iwr-wvsatoiYtwWr-6ykZsZn5p3Y3szY1rMZ6vG94qkb1I7R5QWIx_VooI/yen_dollar_exchange_rates.png&quot; data-image-dimensions=&quot;686x418&quot; data-image-focal-point=&quot;0.5,0.5&quot; alt=&quot;Red line = what it costs to make stuff, Blue line = what you sell it for. Gap between the two == the opposite of profit. source&quot; data-load=&quot;false&quot; data-image-id=&quot;5e1e41202cb28d72a7683eee&quot; data-type=&quot;image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-caption-wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Red line = what it costs to make stuff, Blue line = what you sell it for.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Gap between the two == the opposite of profit.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://voxeu.org/article/why-japan-lost-its-comparative-advantage-producing-electronic-parts-and-components&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;source&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block html-block sqs-block-html&quot; data-block-type=&quot;2&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1579039247627_108558&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Lower profits mean lower investments, because no sane firm would pour more money into a money-losing enterprise, which means Japanese firms fall behind technically as well, and &lt;strong&gt;at that point you’re in a market-share-losing death spiral with no capital, no technology, and no profits:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block image-block sqs-block-image&quot; data-block-type=&quot;5&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1579039247627_109016&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-outer-wrapper layout-caption-below design-layout-inline combination-animation-none individual-animation-none individual-text-animation-none&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;intrinsic&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-wrapper lightbox has-aspect-ratio&quot; data-animation-tier=&quot;1&quot; data-description=&quot;&amp;lt;p class=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Pictured: &amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;(╯°□°）╯︵ ┻━┻&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt; &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://voxeu.org/article/why-japan-lost-its-comparative-advantage-producing-electronic-parts-and-components&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;source&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&quot; data-lightbox-theme=&quot;dark&quot;&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579041094246-0R0JEZ4VI8YINQMIJLQR/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kAYko24dci6TM5MW948IH2dZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZUJFbgE-7XRK3dMEBRBhUpwA2zRENL8S01QIlG2r9yuuURfqhH0-V1C1dwnzsnrdvNH-KzW1LySk9cPJIBCw0eI/japanese_electronics_industry_collapse.png&quot; alt=&quot;Pictured: (╯°□°）╯︵ ┻━┻ source&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;thumb-image&quot; data-src=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579041094246-0R0JEZ4VI8YINQMIJLQR/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kAYko24dci6TM5MW948IH2dZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZUJFbgE-7XRK3dMEBRBhUpwA2zRENL8S01QIlG2r9yuuURfqhH0-V1C1dwnzsnrdvNH-KzW1LySk9cPJIBCw0eI/japanese_electronics_industry_collapse.png&quot; data-image=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579041094246-0R0JEZ4VI8YINQMIJLQR/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kAYko24dci6TM5MW948IH2dZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZUJFbgE-7XRK3dMEBRBhUpwA2zRENL8S01QIlG2r9yuuURfqhH0-V1C1dwnzsnrdvNH-KzW1LySk9cPJIBCw0eI/japanese_electronics_industry_collapse.png&quot; data-image-dimensions=&quot;694x381&quot; data-image-focal-point=&quot;0.5,0.5&quot; alt=&quot;Pictured: (╯°□°）╯︵ ┻━┻ source&quot; data-load=&quot;false&quot; data-image-id=&quot;5e1e41460700a84fb32fe1aa&quot; data-type=&quot;image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-caption-wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Pictured: &lt;strong&gt;(╯°□°）╯︵ ┻━┻&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://voxeu.org/article/why-japan-lost-its-comparative-advantage-producing-electronic-parts-and-components&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block html-block sqs-block-html&quot; data-block-type=&quot;2&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1579039247627_112921&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;The tendency of major Industrial Manufacturing Powerhouses to become mature, stable, regionally dominant economies leads inevitably to their currencies becoming Reserve Currencies — &lt;strong&gt;undermining the manufacturing success that made their economies so great in the first place.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Thus: “Currency &lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Problem&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;For Germany — &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; Reserve Currency of Europe, &lt;em&gt;20% of all Global Reserve Holdings in 1990&lt;/em&gt; — the inevitable wrath of currency markets are prosperity-destroying bad news.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block image-block sqs-block-image&quot; data-block-type=&quot;5&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1579039247627_113380&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-outer-wrapper layout-caption-hidden design-layout-inline combination-animation-none individual-animation-none individual-text-animation-none&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;intrinsic&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-wrapper has-aspect-ratio&quot; data-animation-tier=&quot;1&quot; data-description=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579041149339-VZ99FMIRBVFXUBFMI0VU/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kMLmgV6F9fa5EJoYeTGMPd9Zw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZamWLI2zvYWH8K3-s_4yszcp2ryTI0HqTOaaUohrI8PIGPEOcEJ3bhSHmmt8XKKaQTcs810m3qTe-kUhIGokcKY/inevitable.png&quot; alt=&quot;inevitable.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;thumb-image&quot; data-src=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579041149339-VZ99FMIRBVFXUBFMI0VU/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kMLmgV6F9fa5EJoYeTGMPd9Zw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZamWLI2zvYWH8K3-s_4yszcp2ryTI0HqTOaaUohrI8PIGPEOcEJ3bhSHmmt8XKKaQTcs810m3qTe-kUhIGokcKY/inevitable.png&quot; data-image=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579041149339-VZ99FMIRBVFXUBFMI0VU/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kMLmgV6F9fa5EJoYeTGMPd9Zw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZamWLI2zvYWH8K3-s_4yszcp2ryTI0HqTOaaUohrI8PIGPEOcEJ3bhSHmmt8XKKaQTcs810m3qTe-kUhIGokcKY/inevitable.png&quot; data-image-dimensions=&quot;829x440&quot; data-image-focal-point=&quot;0.5,0.5&quot; alt=&quot;inevitable.png&quot; data-load=&quot;false&quot; data-image-id=&quot;5e1e417c21056e4db66abd33&quot; data-type=&quot;image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block html-block sqs-block-html&quot; data-block-type=&quot;2&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1579132858405_243395&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;The interesting thing about this perspective is that it suggests &lt;strong&gt;the location of productive manufacturing activity is not driven by the cost of labour&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(supply-side)&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;but by the ability of eventual-customers to actually purchase your finished products&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(demand-side)&lt;/em&gt;. Because these two separate items are usually aligned with each other it’s easy to mistake one for the other, and there’s definitely much truth to the supply-side Narrative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;But the example of Germany — the second largest Export economy in the world, despite high costs of labor and modern Western standards of living — speaks to a bigger picture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span&gt;Changing Lenses — The Corporate View&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;The value of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.conradbastable.com/essays/the-panopticon-prism-all-facts-serve-a-narrative&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Narratives&lt;/a&gt; and Lenses is in switching them out and seeing how different the same phenomena look. So take 250 words and 1 image to swap the National Lens out for the Corporate Lens here: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block image-block sqs-block-image&quot; data-block-type=&quot;5&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1579039247627_117761&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-outer-wrapper layout-caption-below design-layout-inline combination-animation-none individual-animation-none individual-text-animation-none&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;intrinsic&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-wrapper has-aspect-ratio&quot; data-animation-tier=&quot;1&quot; data-description=&quot;&amp;lt;p class=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;Pictured: you for the next 250 words&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&quot;&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579041194034-4UCYEAQDGCYVRLE2TDAH/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kGydOMGoOGAutpXyowOci4AUqsxRUqqbr1mOJYKfIPR7LoDQ9mXPOjoJoqy81S2I8N_N4V1vUb5AoIIIbLZhVYxCRW4BPu10St3TBAUQYVKcU4ZOlSvImkBL14PmasPRKffQE7YAOLrWbRv3cy7mlviT6keH4KLPdfeF5-z3-6a7/musky.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Pictured: you for the next 250 words&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;thumb-image&quot; data-src=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579041194034-4UCYEAQDGCYVRLE2TDAH/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kGydOMGoOGAutpXyowOci4AUqsxRUqqbr1mOJYKfIPR7LoDQ9mXPOjoJoqy81S2I8N_N4V1vUb5AoIIIbLZhVYxCRW4BPu10St3TBAUQYVKcU4ZOlSvImkBL14PmasPRKffQE7YAOLrWbRv3cy7mlviT6keH4KLPdfeF5-z3-6a7/musky.jpeg&quot; data-image=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579041194034-4UCYEAQDGCYVRLE2TDAH/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kGydOMGoOGAutpXyowOci4AUqsxRUqqbr1mOJYKfIPR7LoDQ9mXPOjoJoqy81S2I8N_N4V1vUb5AoIIIbLZhVYxCRW4BPu10St3TBAUQYVKcU4ZOlSvImkBL14PmasPRKffQE7YAOLrWbRv3cy7mlviT6keH4KLPdfeF5-z3-6a7/musky.jpeg&quot; data-image-dimensions=&quot;1000x523&quot; data-image-focal-point=&quot;0.5,0.5&quot; alt=&quot;Pictured: you for the next 250 words&quot; data-load=&quot;false&quot; data-image-id=&quot;5e1e41aa0700a84fb32fee47&quot; data-type=&quot;image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-caption-wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pictured: you for the next 250 words&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block html-block sqs-block-html&quot; data-block-type=&quot;2&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1579039247627_121680&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The modern corporation is distinctly non-Nationalistic.&lt;/strong&gt; Dollars are dollars, profits are profits, trade routes are open, labor is fungible, and tax havens are just offshore of every major market. Don’t hate corporations for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sirlin.net/articles/playing-to-win&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;playing to win&lt;/a&gt; — they don’t make the rules, you do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Which means…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Expensive US Dollars can be invested into Cheap Chinese Yuan, turned into factories, turned into finished goods, capturing huge market share and profits and increasing Firm Value. &lt;strong&gt;And then the Chinese government will spend thousands of man hours from their brightest minds and literally-Trillions-of-Dollars to maintain the competitiveness of &lt;em&gt;your&lt;/em&gt; firm&lt;/strong&gt; and prevent another geographical location from lowering the value of your investments by outcompeting you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Imagine you’re a company executive and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;read that bold part again.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;No investments are sure things, and we of course &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; see some labor reallocating away from China despite the CCP’s best efforts, but then the same rules will eventually apply to those other countries as &lt;em&gt;they&lt;/em&gt; industrialize and reach parity, and then &lt;em&gt;they&lt;/em&gt; will see their own markets undercut in turn. China at least offers (the allure of) unmatched stability and the closest any Industrialist can come in 2020 to a “guaranteed” annuity cash flow — so long as you remain in the CCP’s good graces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Refer to the graph above of Japanese Exchange Rates vs. Prices to see an Industrialist’s worst nightmare — caused by factors &lt;em&gt;entirely&lt;/em&gt; outside their control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This gives the&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Communist_Party_of_China&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CCP&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong&gt;a lot more leverage over company execs than folks realize.&lt;/strong&gt; South Park was right, but it’s not &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; about the revenue opportunity that comes from selling &lt;em&gt;into&lt;/em&gt; the Chinese market. They’ve been running a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Full-court_press&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;full court press&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.conradbastable.com/essays/industrialism-mercantilism-but-with-production-brought-in-house&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;mercantilist-industrialism&lt;/a&gt; for ~4 decades in order to build the largest Manufacturing Network in history — and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; equity holder who wants to can &lt;em&gt;personally&lt;/em&gt; benefit from CCP protectionism if they ante up.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block image-block sqs-block-image&quot; data-block-type=&quot;5&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1579039247627_122142&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-outer-wrapper layout-caption-below design-layout-inline combination-animation-none individual-animation-none individual-text-animation-none&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;intrinsic&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-wrapper has-aspect-ratio&quot; data-animation-tier=&quot;1&quot; data-description=&quot;&amp;lt;p class=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;Spoiler:&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt; if you’ve got a 401k, your retirement money is invested in the stocks of US companies that have been doing exactly this, which makes &amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;you an equity holder in CCP Protectionism&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt; — make sure to vote in your own best interest! &amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/07/10/business/tesla-china-shanghai.html&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;source&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&quot;&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579041235639-E5KFV1E0ZZLLM7LFC8UD/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kHpX1V_Ak4Z5hJgUlkA_3ulZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZamWLI2zvYWH8K3-s_4yszcp2ryTI0HqTOaaUohrI8PIdR8CinrMer1tDoL1TYhCvJ95eJpplPpsag1-7LbTp40/tesla_electric_cars_in_china.png&quot; alt=&quot;Spoiler: if you’ve got a 401k, your retirement money is invested in the stocks of US companies that have been doing exactly this, which makes you an equity holder in CCP Protectionism — make sure to vote in your own best interest! source&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;thumb-image&quot; data-src=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579041235639-E5KFV1E0ZZLLM7LFC8UD/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kHpX1V_Ak4Z5hJgUlkA_3ulZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZamWLI2zvYWH8K3-s_4yszcp2ryTI0HqTOaaUohrI8PIdR8CinrMer1tDoL1TYhCvJ95eJpplPpsag1-7LbTp40/tesla_electric_cars_in_china.png&quot; data-image=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579041235639-E5KFV1E0ZZLLM7LFC8UD/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kHpX1V_Ak4Z5hJgUlkA_3ulZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZamWLI2zvYWH8K3-s_4yszcp2ryTI0HqTOaaUohrI8PIdR8CinrMer1tDoL1TYhCvJ95eJpplPpsag1-7LbTp40/tesla_electric_cars_in_china.png&quot; data-image-dimensions=&quot;804x492&quot; data-image-focal-point=&quot;0.5,0.5&quot; alt=&quot;Spoiler: if you’ve got a 401k, your retirement money is invested in the stocks of US companies that have been doing exactly this, which makes you an equity holder in CCP Protectionism — make sure to vote in your own best interest! source&quot; data-load=&quot;false&quot; data-image-id=&quot;5e1e41d32cb28d72a76853f9&quot; data-type=&quot;image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-caption-wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Spoiler:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;if you’ve got a 401k, your retirement money is invested in the stocks of US companies that have been doing exactly this, which makes&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;you an equity holder in CCP Protectionism&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;— make sure to vote in your own best interest!&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/07/10/business/tesla-china-shanghai.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;source&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block html-block sqs-block-html&quot; data-block-type=&quot;2&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1579039247627_126368&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;It’d be a borderline-criminal violation of fiduciary duty to ignore these sorts of incentives!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;v) &lt;span&gt;Germany’s Doom: The Inevitable Cost Of Success&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;I’m not China and I’m not the USA. I’m not Conrad Bastable. I’m a time-traveling German minister from the end of the Cold War (&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dissolution_of_the_Soviet_Union&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;1991&lt;/a&gt;). I’m here looking for &lt;em&gt;practical&lt;/em&gt; lessons because I manage Europe’s fastest growing and most efficient Industrial Manufacturing Powerhouse. &lt;strong&gt;I wish to learn from the&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(future)&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;fall of US manufacturing and avoid such a miserable fate.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;I’m not so worried about our ability to &lt;em&gt;produce&lt;/em&gt; — Germany has been Europe’s industrial powerhouse for 200+ years. Making stuff is what we do. We don’t &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt; Foreign Investment, we’ve got enough domestic capital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;I’m worried about the effect that our &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;inevitable success&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; will have on the relative attractiveness of our exports. As we rebuild, we will produce. As we produce, our economy will become the strongest in Europe. &lt;strong&gt;Which will make our &lt;em&gt;currency&lt;/em&gt; the strongest in Europe —&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;— which will make our Exports &lt;em&gt;expensive,&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;and then it becomes &lt;em&gt;capital-efficient&lt;/em&gt; for our corporations to export their productive capacity —&lt;/strong&gt; their factories &amp;amp; jobs &lt;strong&gt;— to our neighbouring states, who will have cheaper currencies and cheaper labor.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;The “&lt;span&gt;Currency &lt;strong&gt;Problem&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;And reunification means that our immediate Eastern neighbors are about to have a &lt;em&gt;direct&lt;/em&gt; pipeline through all of mainland Europe. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Inconveniently, those same states are where the USSR focused its industrialization efforts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block image-block sqs-block-image&quot; data-block-type=&quot;5&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1579039247627_127291&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-outer-wrapper layout-caption-below design-layout-inline combination-animation-none individual-animation-none individual-text-animation-none&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;intrinsic&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-wrapper has-aspect-ratio&quot; data-animation-tier=&quot;1&quot; data-description=&quot;&amp;lt;p class=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;Circled: lots of cheap labour &amp;amp;amp; idle factories&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&quot;&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579041287110-72XU9VHI03RN453YE1MG/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kPxueaw56okAYW68L_GDaV9Zw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZamWLI2zvYWH8K3-s_4yszcp2ryTI0HqTOaaUohrI8PI0Ia7sEUWl4eDn8S1ySYvPbyaS7ELRq96nA6Ygt2q1Ps/industrial_ussr.png&quot; alt=&quot;Circled: lots of cheap labour &amp;amp;amp; idle factories&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;thumb-image&quot; data-src=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579041287110-72XU9VHI03RN453YE1MG/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kPxueaw56okAYW68L_GDaV9Zw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZamWLI2zvYWH8K3-s_4yszcp2ryTI0HqTOaaUohrI8PI0Ia7sEUWl4eDn8S1ySYvPbyaS7ELRq96nA6Ygt2q1Ps/industrial_ussr.png&quot; data-image=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579041287110-72XU9VHI03RN453YE1MG/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kPxueaw56okAYW68L_GDaV9Zw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZamWLI2zvYWH8K3-s_4yszcp2ryTI0HqTOaaUohrI8PI0Ia7sEUWl4eDn8S1ySYvPbyaS7ELRq96nA6Ygt2q1Ps/industrial_ussr.png&quot; data-image-dimensions=&quot;870x611&quot; data-image-focal-point=&quot;0.5,0.5&quot; alt=&quot;Circled: lots of cheap labour &amp;amp;amp; idle factories&quot; data-load=&quot;false&quot; data-image-id=&quot;5e1e42062cb28d72a76859a8&quot; data-type=&quot;image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-caption-wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Circled: lots of cheap labour &amp;amp; idle factories&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block html-block sqs-block-html&quot; data-block-type=&quot;2&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1579039247627_131260&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All we need is for our goods to be attractive throughout Europe&lt;/strong&gt;, regardless of how other nations’ economies are performing relative to ours &lt;em&gt;(and they will underperform)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;,&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;regardless of how many Cheat Codes other countries try to run.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;And we &lt;strong&gt;need to offer a Trade framework&lt;/strong&gt; which makes it Economically Efficient to maintain Industrial capacity — factories &amp;amp; jobs — &lt;em&gt;within&lt;/em&gt; our borders rather than reallocate it to other Eurasian nations. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;We need &lt;strong&gt;a Trade framework that lets &lt;em&gt;our&lt;/em&gt; goods move freely to &lt;em&gt;our&lt;/em&gt; customers&lt;/strong&gt;, but puts just enough obstacles in front of Chinese goods that it makes sense for our corporations to keep their industrial capacity here, in Germany.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Enter stage left:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;vi) &lt;span&gt;A Solution To Currency Problems and Trade Cheats&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block html-block sqs-block-html&quot; data-block-type=&quot;2&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1579039247627_146120&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Both of the above were introduced, formalized, and adopted in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Maastricht_Treaty#The_Maastricht_criteria&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Maastricht Treaty of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;1992&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;The explicit 3rd criteria of joining the treaty was &lt;em&gt;not having devalued your currency during the prior two years.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Seriously, no Cheat Codes allowed. Other criteria included: ultra-low inflation, low government debt-to-GDP ratios, and low interest rates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;These are all reasonable criteria to achieve the stated goal: &lt;em&gt;“&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;maintain price stability&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;within the Eurozone even with the inclusion of new member states.”&lt;/em&gt; I’m not knocking them. I’m just pointing out that &lt;strong&gt;the criteria preclude anyone running even half of China’s playbook from joining.&lt;/strong&gt; Government-funded winners? Cheap exports? Printing currency? Strike, strike, and strike.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Price stability, of course, explicitly favors the existing market equilibrium. &lt;strong&gt;It is exactly by radically disrupting “price stability” that China was initially able to build its international Manufacturing Powerhouse. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It is a failure to maintain “price stability” that so wounded Japan’s electronics industry.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nobody wants &quot;price stability” until they are on top — and then they want it &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; badly.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Obviously there’s plenty of good to stable prices &lt;em&gt;(see: the Corporate Lens section above)&lt;/em&gt;, and uncontrollably high prices have precipitated many of Europe’s prior woes. You can see why it was picked as a goalpost by glancing at Germany’s history lessons from the 1920s:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block image-block sqs-block-image&quot; data-block-type=&quot;5&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1579039247627_146589&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-outer-wrapper layout-caption-below design-layout-inline combination-animation-none individual-animation-none individual-text-animation-none&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;intrinsic&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-wrapper has-aspect-ratio&quot; data-animation-tier=&quot;1&quot; data-description=&quot;&amp;lt;p class=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;Pictured: &amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hyperinflation_in_the_Weimar_Republic&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;unstable prices&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;. Not pictured: what came next.&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&quot;&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579041421347-YML1JST7NPQHCOX58SIW/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kOgFdYlW4bft0JX0-bWszLlZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWhcwhEtWJXoshNdA9f1qD7a3IG1vtna7BEUjBtarIuovrmw2XITjfJnCaU9fLTX8gBcLDHpzSOnW29sEEq2H14A/hyperinflation_is_fun.png&quot; alt=&quot;Pictured: unstable prices . Not pictured: what came next.&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;thumb-image&quot; data-src=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579041421347-YML1JST7NPQHCOX58SIW/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kOgFdYlW4bft0JX0-bWszLlZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWhcwhEtWJXoshNdA9f1qD7a3IG1vtna7BEUjBtarIuovrmw2XITjfJnCaU9fLTX8gBcLDHpzSOnW29sEEq2H14A/hyperinflation_is_fun.png&quot; data-image=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579041421347-YML1JST7NPQHCOX58SIW/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kOgFdYlW4bft0JX0-bWszLlZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWhcwhEtWJXoshNdA9f1qD7a3IG1vtna7BEUjBtarIuovrmw2XITjfJnCaU9fLTX8gBcLDHpzSOnW29sEEq2H14A/hyperinflation_is_fun.png&quot; data-image-dimensions=&quot;250x336&quot; data-image-focal-point=&quot;0.5,0.5&quot; alt=&quot;Pictured: unstable prices . Not pictured: what came next.&quot; data-load=&quot;false&quot; data-image-id=&quot;5e1e428d90eeff123a5e5192&quot; data-type=&quot;image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block html-block sqs-block-html&quot; data-block-type=&quot;2&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1579039247627_150753&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;I just want to make it clear that &lt;strong&gt;“stability” implies some measure of continuing the status quo and makes China-style competition much harder.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;vii) &lt;span&gt;The Single Market Prefers A Single Producer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Single Market functions to maximize Free Trade and eradicate barriers to competition — &lt;em&gt;within&lt;/em&gt; Europe.&lt;/strong&gt; Meanwhile, selling &lt;em&gt;into&lt;/em&gt; the Single Market from outside Europe is met with a slew of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/European_emission_standards#Toxic_emission:_stages_and_legal_framework&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;regulations&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://madb.europa.eu/madb/euTariffs.htm?productCode=8703601090&amp;amp;country=US&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;tariffs&lt;/a&gt;, and general headaches. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This setup allows European nations to compete with each other on their capabilities and the efficiency of their productive capacity, while sheltering the continent from external producers.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Any student or practitioner of business knows that an easy way to make an industry more “efficient” is to remove “shared costs” by rolling up a few players under the same corporate umbrella: In order to run a big business, you need an accounting department. In order to run two big businesses in the same industry, you need &lt;em&gt;two&lt;/em&gt; accounting departments. That’s obviously grossly inefficient &lt;em&gt;(sorry accountants)&lt;/em&gt;, and so &lt;a href=&quot;https://hbr.org/2002/12/the-consolidation-curve&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;the tendency of most major industries is to consolidate&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block image-block sqs-block-image&quot; data-block-type=&quot;5&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1579039247627_151679&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-outer-wrapper layout-caption-below design-layout-inline combination-animation-none individual-animation-none individual-text-animation-none&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;intrinsic&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-wrapper has-aspect-ratio&quot; data-animation-tier=&quot;1&quot; data-description=&quot;&amp;lt;p class=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;I hope the parallel between “Industry Deregulation Promotes Company Consolidation” and “National-trade Deregulation Promotes Geographic Consolidation” is somewhat clear. &amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://hbr.org/2002/12/the-consolidation-curve&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;Source &amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;here is the Harvard Business Review, so this is pretty mainstream stuff&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&quot;&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579041475982-KPT523GNU3STGXKGS8UO/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kEz238fZinknCKefTArYEHpZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZUJFbgE-7XRK3dMEBRBhUpxLsKdp8YhLMOUEshTdt9CdblardyVc-a1IkvP4bQkvVsY7KvqiMh2gip_Ra8fshT0/industry_consolidation.png&quot; alt=&quot;I hope the parallel between “Industry Deregulation Promotes Company Consolidation” and “National-trade Deregulation Promotes Geographic Consolidation” is somewhat clear. Source here is the Harvard Business Review, so this is pretty mainstream stuff&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;thumb-image&quot; data-src=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579041475982-KPT523GNU3STGXKGS8UO/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kEz238fZinknCKefTArYEHpZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZUJFbgE-7XRK3dMEBRBhUpxLsKdp8YhLMOUEshTdt9CdblardyVc-a1IkvP4bQkvVsY7KvqiMh2gip_Ra8fshT0/industry_consolidation.png&quot; data-image=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579041475982-KPT523GNU3STGXKGS8UO/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kEz238fZinknCKefTArYEHpZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZUJFbgE-7XRK3dMEBRBhUpxLsKdp8YhLMOUEshTdt9CdblardyVc-a1IkvP4bQkvVsY7KvqiMh2gip_Ra8fshT0/industry_consolidation.png&quot; data-image-dimensions=&quot;725x398&quot; data-image-focal-point=&quot;0.5,0.5&quot; alt=&quot;I hope the parallel between “Industry Deregulation Promotes Company Consolidation” and “National-trade Deregulation Promotes Geographic Consolidation” is somewhat clear. Source here is the Harvard Business Review, so this is pretty mainstream stuff&quot; data-load=&quot;false&quot; data-image-id=&quot;5e1e42c321056e4db66ae509&quot; data-type=&quot;image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-caption-wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;I hope the parallel between “Industry Deregulation Promotes Company Consolidation” and “National-trade Deregulation Promotes Geographic Consolidation” is somewhat clear.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://hbr.org/2002/12/the-consolidation-curve&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;here is the Harvard Business Review, so this is pretty mainstream stuff&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block html-block sqs-block-html&quot; data-block-type=&quot;2&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1579039247627_155785&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;What is true of Companies is true of Industries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block markdown-block sqs-block-markdown&quot; data-block-type=&quot;44&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1579039247627_156231&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so when we look at the USA, we see: Tech consolidates in &lt;strong&gt;Silicon Valley&lt;/strong&gt;. Media consolidates in &lt;strong&gt;LA&lt;/strong&gt;. Finance consolidates in &lt;strong&gt;New York&lt;/strong&gt; (advisory) and &lt;strong&gt;Chicago&lt;/strong&gt; (trading). And Manufacturing consolidates in the &lt;del&gt;Midwest&lt;/del&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Rust Belt:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block html-block sqs-block-html&quot; data-block-type=&quot;2&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1579039247627_170248&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;The same is true of a Europe that operates under a Single Market. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Geographic consolidation is an expected outcome of free trade&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; — the efficiency gains from consolidating regional knowledge, workplace culture, education systems, financial networks, transportation networks, distribution networks, and removing duplicative cost centers are far too great to ignore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Look, I — &lt;em&gt;Conrad, not the German minister&lt;/em&gt; — have had 3 cups of tea while writing this, and plenty of chocolate, so I know it sounds conspiratorial to suggest this was at all pre-planned. Obviously much — &lt;em&gt;most&lt;/em&gt; — of what happened here was happy accidents of fate and a wise studying of history, not the magical action of a time traveling financial &amp;amp; industrial wizard. You’ve got to squint to see a single Narrative with clarity when reality is multivariate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;But consider this sentence, at the very top of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/European_Single_Market&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;wiki&lt;/a&gt; describing the European Single Market:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The market is intended to be&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;conducive to increased competition&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;, increased specialisation, larger economies of scale,&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;allowing goods and factors of production to move to the area where they are most valued&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;, thus improving the efficiency of the allocation of resources.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;The direct implication of increased competition is larger economies of scale and geographic consolidation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block markdown-block sqs-block-markdown&quot; data-block-type=&quot;44&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1579039247627_170753&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That incident I described a few thousand words ago — where George Soros justly broke the Bank of England for the sin of trying to lie about the value of their &lt;del&gt;economy&lt;/del&gt; currency — happened September 16th, &lt;strong&gt;1992&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block html-block sqs-block-html&quot; data-block-type=&quot;2&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1579039247627_171900&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Single Market launched just four months later&lt;/strong&gt;, in January 1993, though something like it had been in the works for a while. But on that launch date was there anyone in Europe with any doubts about which nation — which “&lt;em&gt;area&lt;/em&gt;” — was ascendant, economically speaking?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Any doubt about &lt;em&gt;where&lt;/em&gt; the “goods and factors of production” would move when they were allowed to move freely?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;In the words of a famous German:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block image-block sqs-block-image&quot; data-block-type=&quot;5&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1579039247627_172365&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-outer-wrapper layout-caption-below design-layout-inline combination-animation-none individual-animation-none individual-text-animation-none&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;intrinsic&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-wrapper has-aspect-ratio&quot; data-animation-tier=&quot;1&quot; data-description=&quot;&amp;lt;p class=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Germany: “Yes.”&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&quot;&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579041704089-I8CD8RLMKYT2I8I5JOV4/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kApS7w3pg5DlpCswh2KUzVhZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWEtT5uBSRWt4vQZAgTJucoTqqXjS3CfNDSuuf31e0tVE7ARNlA0DZM3aioc-XFBM4pWQNPKpR72Z_f1rAYQnmK_xnoNNWytR0jD2ucwP4NRU/memes_of_production.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Germany: “Yes.”&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;thumb-image&quot; data-src=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579041704089-I8CD8RLMKYT2I8I5JOV4/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kApS7w3pg5DlpCswh2KUzVhZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWEtT5uBSRWt4vQZAgTJucoTqqXjS3CfNDSuuf31e0tVE7ARNlA0DZM3aioc-XFBM4pWQNPKpR72Z_f1rAYQnmK_xnoNNWytR0jD2ucwP4NRU/memes_of_production.jpeg&quot; data-image=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579041704089-I8CD8RLMKYT2I8I5JOV4/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kApS7w3pg5DlpCswh2KUzVhZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWEtT5uBSRWt4vQZAgTJucoTqqXjS3CfNDSuuf31e0tVE7ARNlA0DZM3aioc-XFBM4pWQNPKpR72Z_f1rAYQnmK_xnoNNWytR0jD2ucwP4NRU/memes_of_production.jpeg&quot; data-image-dimensions=&quot;425x393&quot; data-image-focal-point=&quot;0.5,0.5&quot; alt=&quot;Germany: “Yes.”&quot; data-load=&quot;false&quot; data-image-id=&quot;5e1e43a8cbeb144b40fa9934&quot; data-type=&quot;image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-caption-wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Germany: “Yes.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block html-block sqs-block-html&quot; data-block-type=&quot;2&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1579039247627_176255&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: don’t read my tone wrong here, I’ve nothing but intense admiration for the political and economic leaders of Germany, who guided the state back to profitable Industrial Exporting preeminence when its future was deeply uncertain and&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;providing growth was necessary to the successful reunification of their divided nation.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The British, French, and other major European states took their industrial capacity for granted, treated it with neglect &amp;amp; contempt for decades post-WW2, and don’t seem much keen on having it back. In the words of another famous European: never interfere with your neighbour when he is making a mistake.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;viii) &lt;span&gt;An Economic Union Beats Cheating at the Currency Game&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The German Euro — the currency — has its value suppressed via contamination with all the other&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(poorer-performing, non-Exporting)&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;European nations.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;This means German goods look &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; more attractive than they otherwise would &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;to non-EU markets&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(i.e. USA &amp;amp; China, Germany’s #1 &amp;amp; #3 customers, respectively)…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;…Providing a positive feedback loop on the existing Single Market incentive to centralize the location of manufacturing activity.&lt;strong&gt;[6]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;The Euro allows workers in Spain to use their own Euro-denominated wages to purchase German Euro-denominated goods &lt;strong&gt;without the tricky fact that the German economy is massively outperforming theirs getting in the way of the exchange.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Remember what happened to the Japanese electronics industry when the Japanese economy was seen as outperforming its neighbours?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block image-block sqs-block-image&quot; data-block-type=&quot;5&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1579039247627_177187&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-outer-wrapper layout-caption-below design-layout-inline combination-animation-none individual-animation-none individual-text-animation-none&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;intrinsic&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-wrapper has-aspect-ratio&quot; data-animation-tier=&quot;1&quot; data-description=&quot;&amp;lt;p class=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;Pictured: just a meme that made me laugh&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&quot;&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579041770989-BHZZTE66BNNHIZ00DJE0/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kC51G5dVUZXhHkFFDoj06UB7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QHyNOqBUUEtDDsRWrJLTmG94TGNuzCcCPVStE9JyN8GyinGJJMtkvEZSddKPzQ9ZzPkyOeqvY2wjDr8p46NO8/the_euro.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Pictured: just a meme that made me laugh&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;thumb-image&quot; data-src=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579041770989-BHZZTE66BNNHIZ00DJE0/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kC51G5dVUZXhHkFFDoj06UB7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QHyNOqBUUEtDDsRWrJLTmG94TGNuzCcCPVStE9JyN8GyinGJJMtkvEZSddKPzQ9ZzPkyOeqvY2wjDr8p46NO8/the_euro.jpeg&quot; data-image=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579041770989-BHZZTE66BNNHIZ00DJE0/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kC51G5dVUZXhHkFFDoj06UB7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QHyNOqBUUEtDDsRWrJLTmG94TGNuzCcCPVStE9JyN8GyinGJJMtkvEZSddKPzQ9ZzPkyOeqvY2wjDr8p46NO8/the_euro.jpeg&quot; data-image-dimensions=&quot;1173x1772&quot; data-image-focal-point=&quot;0.5,0.5&quot; alt=&quot;Pictured: just a meme that made me laugh&quot; data-load=&quot;false&quot; data-image-id=&quot;5e1e43ea2cb28d72a76896bc&quot; data-type=&quot;image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-caption-wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pictured: just a meme that made me laugh&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block html-block sqs-block-html&quot; data-block-type=&quot;2&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1579039247627_181121&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;And it means those same workers in Spain are less equipped to compete for Manufacturing jobs — because Elon Musk has to pay them in German Euros instead of cheap &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spanish_peseta&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Spanish Peseta&lt;/a&gt;. If you’ve got to pay everyone in German Euros, you might as well get the most productive workers for your “buck”, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;I don’t think they have&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Siesta&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;siestas&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;in Germany…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Germany doesn’t need to cheat at Currency games in order to build their exports when their economy is averaged with the likes of Greece and Spain.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;And so our favorite Industrialist Capitalist — who cares nothing for national politics and everything for delivering good physical product on time with good profit margins — makes the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;obvious&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; choice when it comes to Europe:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block image-block sqs-block-image&quot; data-block-type=&quot;5&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1579039247627_181588&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-outer-wrapper layout-caption-below design-layout-inline combination-animation-none individual-animation-none individual-text-animation-none&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;intrinsic&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-wrapper has-aspect-ratio&quot; data-animation-tier=&quot;1&quot; data-description=&quot;&amp;lt;p class=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1009014824280342529?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1009014824280342529&amp;amp;amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Ffortune.com%2F2018%2F08%2F01%2Ftesla-china-factory-5-billion-elon-musk-shanghai%2F&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;source&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&quot;&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579041814286-VUBI6FOXH5D1ABVMJU4W/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kIIJn-XZZc089Rm6vYi5SdJZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZUJFbgE-7XRK3dMEBRBhUpy27WB7b7s4TpfVTtOUQboQSRaOoic8S7X7B7vdV4c58DvmRWs4qceklkdWG9GVlCw/tesla_electric_cars_in_germany.png&quot; alt=&quot;source&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;thumb-image&quot; data-src=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579041814286-VUBI6FOXH5D1ABVMJU4W/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kIIJn-XZZc089Rm6vYi5SdJZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZUJFbgE-7XRK3dMEBRBhUpy27WB7b7s4TpfVTtOUQboQSRaOoic8S7X7B7vdV4c58DvmRWs4qceklkdWG9GVlCw/tesla_electric_cars_in_germany.png&quot; data-image=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579041814286-VUBI6FOXH5D1ABVMJU4W/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kIIJn-XZZc089Rm6vYi5SdJZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZUJFbgE-7XRK3dMEBRBhUpy27WB7b7s4TpfVTtOUQboQSRaOoic8S7X7B7vdV4c58DvmRWs4qceklkdWG9GVlCw/tesla_electric_cars_in_germany.png&quot; data-image-dimensions=&quot;615x249&quot; data-image-focal-point=&quot;0.5,0.5&quot; alt=&quot;source&quot; data-load=&quot;false&quot; data-image-id=&quot;5e1e441690eeff123a5e8223&quot; data-type=&quot;image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block html-block sqs-block-html&quot; data-block-type=&quot;2&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1579039247627_185706&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anywhere else would be foolish&lt;/strong&gt;. The CEO has a fiduciary duty to uphold, and his institutional shareholders represent &lt;em&gt;real people’s&lt;/em&gt; pensions that cannot be allowed to go bankrupt. That means you &amp;amp; me. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nasdaq.com/market-activity/stocks/tsla/institutional-holdings&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Tesla’s largest shareholder&lt;/a&gt; manages &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Baillie_Gifford&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;5 of the 7&lt;/a&gt; largest pension funds in the USA. So say &lt;em&gt;thank you&lt;/em&gt; to Elon for making the profit-maximizing choice here — just like &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/david_perell/status/1215306715790487555?s=12&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;everyone else did&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span&gt;25 Years Later — How The Data Changed&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Multiply this same choice across a thousand firms, a million employees, a few billion in combined Enterprise Value…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;And you get Germany.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;The world’s second largest Export economy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Able to support the most &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Immigration_to_Germany&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;immigration of any EU nation&lt;/a&gt; with jobs a-plenty, a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tatsachen-ueber-deutschland.de/en/chapter/society/strong-welfare-state&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;large welfare state&lt;/a&gt;, an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.globalfirepower.com/countries-listing.asp&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;efficient &amp;amp; strong military&lt;/a&gt;, a currency that functions as the world’s second-choice reserve currency, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Greek_government-debt_crisis#Bailout_programmes&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;bailouts for their neighbours&lt;/a&gt; who flounder, &lt;a href=&quot;https://tradingeconomics.com/germany/unemployment-rate&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;low &amp;amp; still decreasing&lt;/a&gt; unemployment, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.numbeo.com/quality-of-life/rankings_by_country.jsp&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;high standards of living&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;a thorough integration of Finance, Trade, and Industrial Production that no other modern Western democracy has managed.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Able to build &lt;strong&gt;this in 2017&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block image-block sqs-block-image&quot; data-block-type=&quot;5&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1579039247627_186639&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-outer-wrapper layout-caption-below design-layout-inline combination-animation-none individual-animation-none individual-text-animation-none&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;intrinsic&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-wrapper lightbox has-aspect-ratio&quot; data-animation-tier=&quot;1&quot; data-description=&quot;&amp;lt;p class=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;This is the chart from the beginning of this essay&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&quot; data-lightbox-theme=&quot;dark&quot;&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579041874407-CP0ESJOH9KAB61AJIUCO/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kO9gmNQGGufCXoGqQe6AqagUqsxRUqqbr1mOJYKfIPR7LoDQ9mXPOjoJoqy81S2I8N_N4V1vUb5AoIIIbLZhVYy7Mythp_T-mtop-vrsUOmeInPi9iDjx9w8K4ZfjXt2dsdSFL0YtyZioS9aZBMaACsw5iSxd5NcVr-CC5zLmjTFCjLISwBs8eEdxAxTptZAUg/germany_focus_graph_2017.png&quot; alt=&quot;This is the chart from the beginning of this essay&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;thumb-image&quot; data-src=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579041874407-CP0ESJOH9KAB61AJIUCO/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kO9gmNQGGufCXoGqQe6AqagUqsxRUqqbr1mOJYKfIPR7LoDQ9mXPOjoJoqy81S2I8N_N4V1vUb5AoIIIbLZhVYy7Mythp_T-mtop-vrsUOmeInPi9iDjx9w8K4ZfjXt2dsdSFL0YtyZioS9aZBMaACsw5iSxd5NcVr-CC5zLmjTFCjLISwBs8eEdxAxTptZAUg/germany_focus_graph_2017.png&quot; data-image=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579041874407-CP0ESJOH9KAB61AJIUCO/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kO9gmNQGGufCXoGqQe6AqagUqsxRUqqbr1mOJYKfIPR7LoDQ9mXPOjoJoqy81S2I8N_N4V1vUb5AoIIIbLZhVYy7Mythp_T-mtop-vrsUOmeInPi9iDjx9w8K4ZfjXt2dsdSFL0YtyZioS9aZBMaACsw5iSxd5NcVr-CC5zLmjTFCjLISwBs8eEdxAxTptZAUg/germany_focus_graph_2017.png&quot; data-image-dimensions=&quot;1561x686&quot; data-image-focal-point=&quot;0.5,0.5&quot; alt=&quot;This is the chart from the beginning of this essay&quot; data-load=&quot;false&quot; data-image-id=&quot;5e1e445290eeff123a5e8b41&quot; data-type=&quot;image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-caption-wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is the chart from the beginning of this essay&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block html-block sqs-block-html&quot; data-block-type=&quot;2&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1579039247627_190764&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Out of &lt;strong&gt;this&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(same chart, same data, same nations, but ~&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;25 years ago in 1993&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;, in the first year that the European Single Market launched, expressed in constant $USD-2017):&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block image-block sqs-block-image&quot; data-block-type=&quot;5&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1579039247627_191226&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-outer-wrapper layout-caption-below design-layout-inline combination-animation-none individual-animation-none individual-text-animation-none&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;intrinsic&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-wrapper lightbox has-aspect-ratio&quot; data-animation-tier=&quot;1&quot; data-description=&quot;&amp;lt;p class=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;Note &amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;[7] &amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;on why Japan had to be cut from the picture (&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lost_Decade_(Japan)&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;the ’90s weren’t so good for them&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;)&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&quot; data-lightbox-theme=&quot;dark&quot;&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579041936534-FES2MHD2HGZZ059Z4GI1/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kIizCKiUUYYx0cwZ7Py_S_AUqsxRUqqbr1mOJYKfIPR7LoDQ9mXPOjoJoqy81S2I8N_N4V1vUb5AoIIIbLZhVYy7Mythp_T-mtop-vrsUOmeInPi9iDjx9w8K4ZfjXt2dnvBE0L6L6XkWwtiLQTowIuZlzZHpJ2FPd-QuEAHidGsCjLISwBs8eEdxAxTptZAUg/germany_focus_graph_1993.png&quot; alt=&quot;Note [7] on why Japan had to be cut from the picture ( the ’90s weren’t so good for them )&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;thumb-image&quot; data-src=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579041936534-FES2MHD2HGZZ059Z4GI1/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kIizCKiUUYYx0cwZ7Py_S_AUqsxRUqqbr1mOJYKfIPR7LoDQ9mXPOjoJoqy81S2I8N_N4V1vUb5AoIIIbLZhVYy7Mythp_T-mtop-vrsUOmeInPi9iDjx9w8K4ZfjXt2dnvBE0L6L6XkWwtiLQTowIuZlzZHpJ2FPd-QuEAHidGsCjLISwBs8eEdxAxTptZAUg/germany_focus_graph_1993.png&quot; data-image=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579041936534-FES2MHD2HGZZ059Z4GI1/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kIizCKiUUYYx0cwZ7Py_S_AUqsxRUqqbr1mOJYKfIPR7LoDQ9mXPOjoJoqy81S2I8N_N4V1vUb5AoIIIbLZhVYy7Mythp_T-mtop-vrsUOmeInPi9iDjx9w8K4ZfjXt2dnvBE0L6L6XkWwtiLQTowIuZlzZHpJ2FPd-QuEAHidGsCjLISwBs8eEdxAxTptZAUg/germany_focus_graph_1993.png&quot; data-image-dimensions=&quot;1559x688&quot; data-image-focal-point=&quot;0.5,0.5&quot; alt=&quot;Note [7] on why Japan had to be cut from the picture ( the ’90s weren’t so good for them )&quot; data-load=&quot;false&quot; data-image-id=&quot;5e1e44902cb28d72a768b02f&quot; data-type=&quot;image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block html-block sqs-block-html&quot; data-block-type=&quot;2&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1579039247627_195094&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;It’s the same chart, you read it the same way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Moving &lt;strong&gt;up&lt;/strong&gt; the Y-axis since 1993 means Trade became more important to a nation relative to their GDP. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Almost&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; e&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;veryone moved up by 2017&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, some more than others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Moving &lt;strong&gt;right&lt;/strong&gt; on the X-axis since 1993 means a nation makes more of its money from selling to others than they used to. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Some folks moved right, some moved left.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;The cynical reading of these two charts — of the history of the last ~25 years in Europe — is:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Germany&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Italy&lt;/strong&gt; have done very well for themselves since the adoption of the Euro and its Single Market, turning regional manufacturing dominance into maintainable Trade surpluses. No further comment on that duo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ireland&lt;/strong&gt; too — who now runs a $100B Trade Surplus &lt;em&gt;(5th largest in the world!)&lt;/em&gt; thanks to its location and “unique” relationships with the USA, the UK, &amp;amp; Europe’s Single Market &lt;em&gt;(&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.conradbastable.com/essays/industrialism-mercantilism-but-with-production-brought-in-house&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;ctrl-f for “Ireland” in this piece for a laugh&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;United Kingdom,&lt;/strong&gt; the &lt;strong&gt;Netherlands&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Belgium&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Spain&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;Greece…&lt;/strong&gt;have fared poorly when it comes to &lt;em&gt;direct&lt;/em&gt; benefits from the shared currency &amp;amp; its single market. Those nations all used to run some of the largest Trade Surpluses in the world — yes, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.com/news/world-europe-45245969&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;even Greece&lt;/a&gt;. Economic interactions with the rest of the continent were a source of national profit…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Competing against Germany is a losing play for anyone who’s ever tried to make stuff, and we should continue to expect industrial capacity &lt;em&gt;(jobs/factories/capital)&lt;/em&gt; to flow out of the UK/Netherlands/Belgium/Spain/Greece/France and into Germany — &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;“where they are most valued”.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note that “flow” implies new Capacity is built in Germany (see: Tesla tweet above) more than a literal movement of existing physical locations.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;The &lt;em&gt;less&lt;/em&gt; cynical reading is:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Non-German, non-Italian European nations have found meaningful alternative domestic engines of GDP-growth that do not include profiting from selling things to other countries!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block image-block sqs-block-image&quot; data-block-type=&quot;5&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1579039247627_196024&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-outer-wrapper layout-caption-below design-layout-inline combination-animation-none individual-animation-none individual-text-animation-none&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;intrinsic&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-wrapper has-aspect-ratio&quot; data-animation-tier=&quot;1&quot; data-description=&quot;&amp;lt;p class=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;Pictured: The Spanish/Greek/Dutch/UK/French strategy&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&quot;&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579041995574-OVMILXM9ZUEVI68ZTIBU/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kAdnsR247ybOAXqkYonu-StZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZamWLI2zvYWH8K3-s_4yszcp2ryTI0HqTOaaUohrI8PIcWeZH4q77me8pAQBfrRLGCCnlC5dklo8mj1Pbhp3OQU/magic_money_printer.png&quot; alt=&quot;Pictured: The Spanish/Greek/Dutch/UK/French strategy&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;thumb-image&quot; data-src=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579041995574-OVMILXM9ZUEVI68ZTIBU/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kAdnsR247ybOAXqkYonu-StZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZamWLI2zvYWH8K3-s_4yszcp2ryTI0HqTOaaUohrI8PIcWeZH4q77me8pAQBfrRLGCCnlC5dklo8mj1Pbhp3OQU/magic_money_printer.png&quot; data-image=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579041995574-OVMILXM9ZUEVI68ZTIBU/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kAdnsR247ybOAXqkYonu-StZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZamWLI2zvYWH8K3-s_4yszcp2ryTI0HqTOaaUohrI8PIcWeZH4q77me8pAQBfrRLGCCnlC5dklo8mj1Pbhp3OQU/magic_money_printer.png&quot; data-image-dimensions=&quot;933x485&quot; data-image-focal-point=&quot;0.5,0.5&quot; alt=&quot;Pictured: The Spanish/Greek/Dutch/UK/French strategy&quot; data-load=&quot;false&quot; data-image-id=&quot;5e1e44ca21056e4db66b2aaf&quot; data-type=&quot;image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-caption-wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pictured: The Spanish/Greek/Dutch/UK/French strategy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block html-block sqs-block-html&quot; data-block-type=&quot;2&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1579039247627_200018&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;I know I usually go all-in on the cynical readings, and the meme doesn’t help, but it’s worth expanding on that for a moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;When it comes to the &lt;strong&gt;United Kingdom&lt;/strong&gt;, this should make some sense given it’s a “&lt;strong&gt;Reserve Currency&lt;/strong&gt;” nation operating as the defacto financial capital of &lt;strong&gt;[&lt;/strong&gt; Europe &lt;strong&gt;+&lt;/strong&gt; the Middle East &lt;strong&gt;+&lt;/strong&gt; Northern Africa &lt;strong&gt;+&lt;/strong&gt; Russia &lt;strong&gt;]&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We would expect all the finance-industry activity to drive the price of the Pound up much higher than it otherwise would be, and therefore to push United Kingdom-based Industrial activity right out of the United Kingdom&lt;/strong&gt;, regardless of any Euro-based shenanigans. This also matches with the observation that, economically-speaking, the United Kingdom has become a one-city nation &lt;em&gt;(London, i.e. Finance)&lt;/em&gt;, with prior hubs of maritime trade and/or manufacturing fallen to irrelevance &lt;em&gt;(&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Liverpool#19th_century&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Liverpool&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Birmingham#Industrial_Revolution&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Birmingham&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Manchester#Industrial_Revolution&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Manchester&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, etc., don’t follow those links if you’re in a cheery mood)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;strong&gt;[8]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;British expats in America &lt;em&gt;(hi that’s me)&lt;/em&gt; are sometimes asked &lt;em&gt;“what part of London are you from?”&lt;/em&gt; — and while the question might be irksome, it reveals a deep economic truth:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;United Kingdom&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;has&lt;/em&gt; found another path to GDP generation, and it’s to the economic benefit of 4 continents &amp;amp; 1 city that London’s financial center remains undiluted by weaker European nations — that they have somewhere strong and stable to park their currency, outside the long arm of EU bureaucrats, and whose economic value is not subject to the fluctuations of trade flows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Remember Singapore? You don’t need to profit from the Trade itself so long as you can attract the movement of goods, services, and&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;capital&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;to your borders.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Likewise, the &lt;strong&gt;Netherlands&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Belgium&lt;/strong&gt; have both found alternative paths to prosperity by structuring their economies around tremendous volumes of Imports &amp;amp; Exports relative to their GDP. “&lt;em&gt;The Singapore of Europe&lt;/em&gt;” is an apt description:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block image-block sqs-block-image&quot; data-block-type=&quot;5&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1579039247627_200487&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-outer-wrapper layout-caption-below design-layout-inline combination-animation-none individual-animation-none individual-text-animation-none&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;intrinsic&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-wrapper has-aspect-ratio&quot; data-animation-tier=&quot;1&quot; data-description=&quot;&amp;lt;p class=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;The &amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;density of roads&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt; (transportation networks) should tell you how German Imports &amp;amp;amp; Exports are getting in and out of Germany — and who is able to benefit by making a market for them and taking a small slice. The &amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;number of cities&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt; that Google’s algorithms choose to show for each nation at the same level of zoom is also deeply revealing about the distribution of economic-relevance. Paris looks lonely indeed.&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&quot;&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579042055301-JWUDKP713Z1UEYD3WW5N/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kKciE9F5vTWFRvGJb5eHk69Zw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZamWLI2zvYWH8K3-s_4yszcp2ryTI0HqTOaaUohrI8PIjVdVvX1ZNaWsS5zaxdpVvOxbSRlevZzNJcgzzczddy8/image-asset.png&quot; alt=&quot;The density of roads (transportation networks) should tell you how German Imports &amp;amp;amp; Exports are getting in and out of Germany — and who is able to benefit by making a market for them and taking a small slice. The number of cities that Google’s algorithms choose to show for each nation at the same level of zoom is also deeply revealing about the distribution of economic-relevance. Paris looks lonely indeed.&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;thumb-image&quot; data-src=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579042055301-JWUDKP713Z1UEYD3WW5N/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kKciE9F5vTWFRvGJb5eHk69Zw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZamWLI2zvYWH8K3-s_4yszcp2ryTI0HqTOaaUohrI8PIjVdVvX1ZNaWsS5zaxdpVvOxbSRlevZzNJcgzzczddy8/image-asset.png&quot; data-image=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579042055301-JWUDKP713Z1UEYD3WW5N/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kKciE9F5vTWFRvGJb5eHk69Zw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZamWLI2zvYWH8K3-s_4yszcp2ryTI0HqTOaaUohrI8PIjVdVvX1ZNaWsS5zaxdpVvOxbSRlevZzNJcgzzczddy8/image-asset.png&quot; data-image-dimensions=&quot;951x636&quot; data-image-focal-point=&quot;0.5,0.5&quot; alt=&quot;The density of roads (transportation networks) should tell you how German Imports &amp;amp;amp; Exports are getting in and out of Germany — and who is able to benefit by making a market for them and taking a small slice. The number of cities that Google’s algorithms choose to show for each nation at the same level of zoom is also deeply revealing about the distribution of economic-relevance. Paris looks lonely indeed.&quot; data-load=&quot;false&quot; data-image-id=&quot;5e1e450690eeff123a5ea39a&quot; data-type=&quot;image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-caption-wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;density of roads&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(transportation networks) should tell you how German Imports &amp;amp; Exports are getting in and out of Germany — and who is able to benefit by making a market for them and taking a small slice. The&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;number of cities&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;that Google’s algorithms choose to show for each nation at the same level of zoom is also deeply revealing about the distribution of economic-relevance. Paris looks lonely indeed.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block html-block sqs-block-html&quot; data-block-type=&quot;2&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1579039247627_204211&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;China &lt;strong&gt;::&lt;/strong&gt; Singapore as Germany &lt;strong&gt;::&lt;/strong&gt; the Netherlands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The takeaway&lt;/strong&gt; — from this whole 6,000 word essay — is that &lt;strong&gt;Germany has done insanely well for itself since the creation and adoption of the Euro and the European Single Market by pursuing a strategy of Export-driven Industrial production that is &lt;em&gt;considered impossible&lt;/em&gt; in any other developed, high-GDP, high-population, high-wage-paying nation.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Indeed, it would not be possible without the existence of the Euro and the Single Market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;The German economic engine sits at the economic-center of the continent, generating growth for the whole entity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Winners and losers might net-out, and in aggregate the gains to winners might even outweigh the losses experienced by losers &lt;em&gt;(shoutout to Econ 101)&lt;/em&gt;, but the nature of Distance / Time — the nature of geography — is that &lt;strong&gt;“losers” can encompass regions the size of European nations and populations of 10s of millions. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;When it comes to Europe, those regions are usually not under the same Federal umbrella as the winners. &lt;strong&gt;They do not have the same tax base. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;How that plays out — politically and economically and culturally — over the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;next&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; 25 years is for the pundits &amp;amp; prognosticators to guess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;How it &lt;em&gt;has&lt;/em&gt; played out over the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;previous&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; 25 years is described by the intersection of uncontested Facts and hotly contested Narratives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;In today’s world of post-truth propagandizing, you can choose your own Facts and you can choose your own Narrative. What you can’t choose is your nation’s bank account balance. If you care about increasing it, you should know how others have succeeded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Consider the lessons of this case study carefully — who has won, who has lost, and how they ended up where they did — and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/science/archive/2019/07/we-need-new-science-progress/594946/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;choose your own adventure&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block image-block sqs-block-image&quot; data-block-type=&quot;5&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1579039247627_204678&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-outer-wrapper layout-caption-below design-layout-inline combination-animation-none individual-animation-none individual-text-animation-none&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;intrinsic&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-block-wrapper has-aspect-ratio&quot; data-animation-tier=&quot;1&quot; data-description=&quot;&amp;lt;p class=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;“Germany: Master of the Industrial Arts”&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&quot;&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579042097476-T8YWLYDCJ740CP7QSNC9/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kOaDxNCAwIJHRT5yNosUtwtZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZUJFbgE-7XRK3dMEBRBhUpwXU3dXNt8YEGk5SRjuz3sa6r3Yg1osnakXiVLJzQX9wGfGsW_We5QFJnDCyKJu5eQ/science_of_progress.png&quot; alt=&quot;“Germany: Master of the Industrial Arts”&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;thumb-image&quot; data-src=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579042097476-T8YWLYDCJ740CP7QSNC9/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kOaDxNCAwIJHRT5yNosUtwtZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZUJFbgE-7XRK3dMEBRBhUpwXU3dXNt8YEGk5SRjuz3sa6r3Yg1osnakXiVLJzQX9wGfGsW_We5QFJnDCyKJu5eQ/science_of_progress.png&quot; data-image=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/1579042097476-T8YWLYDCJ740CP7QSNC9/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kOaDxNCAwIJHRT5yNosUtwtZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZUJFbgE-7XRK3dMEBRBhUpwXU3dXNt8YEGk5SRjuz3sa6r3Yg1osnakXiVLJzQX9wGfGsW_We5QFJnDCyKJu5eQ/science_of_progress.png&quot; data-image-dimensions=&quot;734x640&quot; data-image-focal-point=&quot;0.5,0.5&quot; alt=&quot;“Germany: Master of the Industrial Arts”&quot; data-load=&quot;false&quot; data-image-id=&quot;5e1e453190eeff123a5ea954&quot; data-type=&quot;image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-caption-wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Germany: Master of the Industrial Arts”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block newsletter-block sqs-block-newsletter&quot; data-block-type=&quot;51&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1579042182561_1113577&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;newsletter-form-wrapper newsletter-form-wrapper--layoutFloat newsletter-form-wrapper--alignCenter&quot;&gt;
&lt;form class=&quot;newsletter-form&quot; data-form-id=&quot;5e1e4bdacbeb144b40fbb480&quot; autocomplete=&quot;on&quot; method=&quot;post&quot; onsubmit=&quot;return (function (form) { Y.use('squarespace-form-submit', 'node', function usingFormSubmit(Y) { (new Y.Squarespace.FormSubmit(form)).submit({ formId: '5e1e4bdacbeb144b40fbb480', collectionId: '5b7dc2f9032be4fd52b63a13', objectName: 'item-5e1e3a51497e8e65ff957a1e' }); }); return false; })(this);&quot;&gt;
&lt;header class=&quot;newsletter-form-header&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;newsletter-form-header-title&quot;&gt;Hi! I'm Conrad. Thanks for reading!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;newsletter-form-header-description&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;There’s more coming! Drop your email below to get a fresh perspective on Wealth, Technology, History, and (Pop) Culture&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/header&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;hidden form-submission-text&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Thanks for signing up to get more thoughts from me in the future. I try to reply to everyone who reaches out to me, publicly or privately, so leave a comment, DM me on Twitter, or shoot me an email if you want to talk more, provide counterpoints, or just say &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;“hi!”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/form&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block html-block sqs-block-html&quot; data-block-type=&quot;2&quot; id=&quot;block-yui_3_17_2_1_1579039247627_209021&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sqs-block-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span&gt;Notes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[0]&lt;/strong&gt; Note: I excluded a handful (5) South-East-Asian &amp;amp; South American nations to aid clarity of reading and because this essay is about the USA, Europe &amp;amp; Asia. You’ll also note that the USA and China both had to be cut from this image because the sheer size of their GDP made the rest of the chart unreadable. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[1]&lt;/strong&gt; Everything is sourced directly from the UN &amp;amp; WTO’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://wits.worldbank.org/about_wits.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;official data repository&lt;/a&gt;, including GDP numbers, and expressed in constant 2017 USD, which is great because one of the worst things about this sort of data is trying to unwind different people’s adjustment factors that never quite tie&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[2]&lt;/strong&gt; The alternative is subsistence, and that’s no fun at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What does the decline of manufacturing regions due to foreign competition look like in practice?&lt;/strong&gt; US residents — real individual people — whose personal income is &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; threatened by a reallocation of trade to foreign firms might perhaps see large increases in their personal standard of living thanks to their additional consumer surplus. Well-positioned Economic Rent-Seekers might then raise their prices steeply to take advantage of the extra cash in the pockets of consumers. &lt;em&gt;Consider:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.conradbastable.com/essays/the-bermuda-triangle-of-wealth&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;housing, health care&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.conradbastable.com/essays/the-uncharity-of-college-the-big-business-nobody-understands&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;education&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;US residents — again, real people — whose real personal income &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; reduced by a reallocation of trade to foreign firms can choose to retrain &lt;em&gt;(“&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://knowyourmeme.com/memes/learn-to-code&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Learn to Code&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;”)&lt;/em&gt;, enter the workforce in non-scalable Services-based industries, and relocate to urban centers or else commit to a permanently lowered standard of living thanks to their inability to compete in the aforementioned Rent-Seek’d areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Expectations: bifurcation, urbanization, increased polarization along rural-urban divides, increased Wealth inequality, increased Debt chasing non-productive assets, increased government assistance, increased competition for a smaller number of Wealth-generating jobs, etc.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;This loosely matches my mental model of the Industrial world, not completely, but enough that I can see the shape of a viable &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.conradbastable.com/essays/the-panopticon-prism-all-facts-serve-a-narrative&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Narrative&lt;/a&gt; beginning to build. I wrote earlier about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.conradbastable.com/essays/industrialism-mercantilism-but-with-production-brought-in-house&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;the dramatic rise of Industrialism&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Consequential path dependence in the location of economic activity”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;isn’t exclusive to Feudal Rome. To spell my point out more clearly: The Town is to Feudalism as the Trade Route is to Industrialism. Sticky, self-perpetuating, network-effect-creating, often a&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nash_equilibrium&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nash Equilibrium&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, and increasing of market Imperfection in a way that allows existing-participants to Capture Wealth. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;“Stickiness” is great when you’re building something, but if you’re a legacy incumbent and a new market entrant &lt;em&gt;is somehow&lt;/em&gt; able to pry a lynchpin node away from you, that same “stickiness” can unravel your whole local economy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[3]&lt;/strong&gt; Chasing money gets you both money and prestige. Chasing prestige gets you neither.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[4]&lt;/strong&gt; What I mean is that it’s possible to show that the Chinese Money Supply is in fact not expanding fast enough to handle their economy’s growth, and that the mismatch in US-China money supply growth is such that the US dollar would actually tend to get cheaper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;I dislike these sorts of arguments because they are so many levels removed from a core base of agreed-upon axioms &lt;em&gt;(i.e. cause and effect relationships at the macro level are tenuous, multi-variate, often mislabeled, and lagging)&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;If this were the sole exhibit in my “case”, I’d dismiss my own case — but then that goes for everything else in the essay too. Each example is just one tiny lens in the Narrative — insufficient alone to build a Manufacturing Powerhouse in the face of network effects…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;…but when you stack them all together, a picture begins to resolve itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[5]&lt;/strong&gt; Fun fact, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-12-06/u-s-becomes-a-net-oil-exporter-for-the-first-time-in-75-years&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;the US just became a Net Oil Exporter for the first time in 75 years&lt;/a&gt;. We produced more Oil here at home and sold it to other nations than we imported.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;The fact that Middle-Eastern Oil is priced in Dollars — and therefore foreign-produced Oil cannot be sold more cheaply via exchange-rate manipulation — really helps smooth out geopolitical instability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If foreign Oil wasn’t priced in Dollars, the Oil we produce here in the good ol’ US-of-A would not sell nearly so well on the open market.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[6]&lt;/strong&gt; Per the US-China case study, this implies some amount of “Transfer Receipts” — i.e. Government assistance — will be required for citizens of the regions that see said Industrial Capacity move itself too Germany.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Are those citizens located in regions where social safety nets are politically favorable?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Are those citizens located in regions that have another source of Economic Surplus that &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; be taxed and redistributed easily — without encouraging that source of Surplus to move as well?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;One hopes the answers are &lt;strong&gt;Yes&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;Yes&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;But I’ve been to Liverpool, Birmingham, and Manchester…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[7]&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Note: I had to change the axes otherwise the chart was unreadable in 1993, just a big clump of dots. Note how tiny the X-axis is now — 1/10th.  Also note that TRADE in general is now larger relative to GDP for every single country in this list — except Singapore, who had to be cut from this 1993 chart because they tripled the Y-axis. Lastly, Japan also had to be removed because they ran a Trade Deficit of -$158B in 1993. Look where negative-$158B would be on this X-axis relative to all the other dots and you’ll see why…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[8]&lt;/strong&gt; A small irony is that if the &lt;strong&gt;United Kingdom&lt;/strong&gt; had gone full Euro-fanatic 30 years ago, they &lt;em&gt;might&lt;/em&gt; have weathered the German Industrial storm better as they would’ve benefited from all the Euro-based currency-dilution in all the same ways Germany has. When it comes to making stuff, I wouldn’t bet against Germany, but it’s worth noting the possibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 14:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>izhak</dc:creator>
<og:title>The Germany Shock: The Largest Economy Nobody Understands | Conrad Bastable</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.conradbastable.com/essays/the-germany-shock-the-largest-economy-nobody-understands</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>How Germany Is Able To Run The World’s Second Largest Export Economy In The Post-Industrial Era “ The Germany Shock ” describes European growth &amp;amp; the efficiency-maximizing centralization of European manufacturing activity after the launch of the Single Market and the Euro . Two questi</og:description>
<og:image>http://static1.squarespace.com/static/5a571a7d80bd5e91de77e8e6/t/5e1e4c4b90eeff123a5f92b7/1579043920197/germany_china_usa_case_study_choice.png?format=1500w</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.conradbastable.com/essays/the-germany-shock-the-largest-economy-nobody-understands</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>