<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Updated to High Sierra, all Admin accounts now Standard</title>
<link>https://forums.developer.apple.com/thread/79235#</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://forums.developer.apple.com/thread/79235#</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Note: This solution might be specific to High Sierra&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Try this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solution 1:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On startup, click on &quot;Other&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enter username: root and leave the password empty. Press enter. (Try twice)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're able to log in (hurray, you're the admin now), then head over to System Preferences&amp;gt;Users &amp;amp; Groups and create a new Admin account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now restart and login to the new Admin Account (you may need a new Apple Id). Once you're logged into this new Admin Id, you can again proceed to your System Preferences&amp;gt;Users &amp;amp; Groups. Open the Lock Icon with your new Admin ID/Password. Assign &quot;Allow user to administer this computer&quot; to your original Apple ID. Restart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Now login with your original Apple Id. (In case you wish to remove the &quot;Other&quot; login option on startup read this: &lt;a class=&quot;jive-link-external-small&quot; href=&quot;https://support.apple.com/en-in/HT204012&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://support.apple.com/en-in/HT204012&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solution 2:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're unable to login at startup using username: root and empty password, then login with your existing account (standard user).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, head over to System Preferences&amp;gt;Users &amp;amp; Groups. Click on the Lock Icon. When prompted for username and password, type username: root and leave the password empty. Press enter. This might throw an error, but try again immediately with the same username: root and empty password. This should unlock the Lock Icon. If it does, try Solution 1 next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S. Solution 2 worked for me. No idea how or why. Hope this helps.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2017 05:10:49 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>JoshTriplett</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://forums.developer.apple.com/thread/79235</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>EC2 Bare Metal Instances with Direct Access to Hardware</title>
<link>https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/aws/new-amazon-ec2-bare-metal-instances-with-direct-access-to-hardware/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/aws/new-amazon-ec2-bare-metal-instances-with-direct-access-to-hardware/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;When customers come to us with new and unique requirements for AWS, we listen closely, ask lots of questions, and do our best to understand and address their needs. When we do this, we make the resulting service or feature generally available; we do not build one-offs or “snowflakes” for individual customers. That model is messy and hard to scale and is not the way we work.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Instead, every AWS customer has access to whatever it is that we build, and everyone benefits. &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/aws/vmware-cloud-on-aws-now-available/&quot;&gt;VMware Cloud on AWS&lt;/a&gt; is a good example of this strategy in action. They told us that they wanted to run their virtualization stack directly on the hardware, within the &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;AWS Cloud&lt;/a&gt;, giving their customers access to the elasticity, security, and reliability (not to mention the broad array of services) that AWS offers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We knew that other customers also had interesting use cases for bare metal hardware and didn’t want to take the performance hit of nested virtualization. They wanted access to the physical resources for applications that take advantage of low-level hardware features such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.intel.com/content/www/us/en/architecture-and-technology/resource-director-technology.html&quot;&gt;performance counters&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.intel.com/content/www/us/en/virtualization/virtualization-technology/intel-virtualization-technology.html&quot;&gt;Intel&lt;sup&gt;®&lt;/sup&gt; VT&lt;/a&gt; that are not always available or fully supported in virtualized environments, and also for applications intended to run directly on the hardware or licensed and supported for use in non-virtualized environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our multi-year effort to move networking, storage, and other EC2 features out of our virtualization platform and into dedicated hardware was already well underway and provided the perfect foundation for a possible solution. This work, as I described in &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/aws/now-available-compute-intensive-c5-instances-for-amazon-ec2/&quot;&gt;Now Available – Compute-Intensive C5 Instances for Amazon EC2&lt;/a&gt;, includes a set of dedicated hardware accelerators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that we have provided VMware with the bare metal access that they requested, we are doing the same for all AWS customers. I’m really looking forward to seeing what you can do with them!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Bare Metal Instances&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Today we are launching a public preview the &lt;strong&gt;i3.metal&lt;/strong&gt; instance, the first in a series of EC2 instances that offer the best of both worlds, allowing the operating system to run directly on the underlying hardware while still providing access to all of the benefits of the cloud. The instance gives you direct access to the processor and other hardware, and has the following specifications:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Processing&lt;/strong&gt; – Two Intel Xeon E5-2686 v4 processors running at 2.3 GHz, with a total of 36 hyperthreaded cores (72 logical processors).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Memory&lt;/strong&gt; – 512 GiB.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Storage&lt;/strong&gt; – 15.2 terabytes of local, SSD-based NVMe storage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Network&lt;/strong&gt; – 25 Gbps of ENA-based enhanced networking.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bare Metal instances are full-fledged members of the EC2 family and can take advantage of &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/elasticloadbalancing&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Elastic Load Balancing&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/autoscaling&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Auto Scaling&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/cloudwatch/&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Amazon CloudWatch&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/aws/new-auto-recovery-for-amazon-ec2/&quot;&gt;Auto Recovery&lt;/a&gt;, and so forth. They can also access the full suite of AWS &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/products/databases/&quot;&gt;database&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/iot/&quot;&gt;IoT&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/mobile/&quot;&gt;mobile&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/products/analytics/&quot;&gt;analytics&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/amazon-ai/&quot;&gt;artificial intelligence&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/security/&quot;&gt;security&lt;/a&gt; services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;Previewing Now&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;We are launching a public preview of the Bare Metal instances today; please &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.awscloud.com/amazon-ec2-bare-metal-instances-preview.html&quot;&gt;sign up now&lt;/a&gt; if you want to try them out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can now bring your specialized applications or your own stack of virtualized components to AWS and run them on Bare Metal instances. If you are using or thinking about using containers, these instances make a great host for &lt;a href=&quot;https://coreos.com/&quot;&gt;CoreOS&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An AMI that works on one of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/aws/now-available-compute-intensive-c5-instances-for-amazon-ec2/&quot;&gt;new C5 instances&lt;/a&gt; should also work on an I3 Bare Metal Instance. It must have the ENA and NVMe drivers, and must be tagged for ENA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jeffbarr&quot;&gt;Jeff&lt;/a&gt;;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2017 04:50:35 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jeffbarr</dc:creator>
<og:title>Amazon EC2 Bare Metal Instances with Direct Access to Hardware | Amazon Web Services</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/aws/new-amazon-ec2-bare-metal-instances-with-direct-access-to-hardware/</og:url>
<og:description>When customers come to us with new and unique requirements for AWS, we listen closely, ask lots of questions, and do our best to understand and address their needs. When we do this, we make the resulting service or feature generally available; we do not build one-offs or “snowflakes” for individual customers. That model is […]</og:description>
<og:image>https://d2908q01vomqb2.cloudfront.net/356a192b7913b04c54574d18c28d46e6395428ab/2017/06/23/6288c174-a286-4b65-9b3b-6199bfdaa1e0.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/aws/new-amazon-ec2-bare-metal-instances-with-direct-access-to-hardware/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Bitcoin hits $10,000</title>
<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2017-11-29/bitcoin-leaves-skeptics-behind-while-blasting-to-record-10-000</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2017-11-29/bitcoin-leaves-skeptics-behind-while-blasting-to-record-10-000</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin surpassed $11,000 in a matter of hours after hitting the $10,000 milestone, taking this year’s price surge to almost 12-fold as buyers shrugged off increased warnings that the largest digital currency is an asset bubble.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The euphoria is bringing to the mainstream what was once considered the provenance of computer developers, futurists and libertarians seeking to create an alternative to central bank-controlled monetary systems. While the actual volume of transactions conducted in cryptocurrencies is relatively small, the optimism surrounding the technology continues to drive it to new highs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some on Wall Street are embracing the run, with more than 100 hedge funds now dedicated to digital currencies. Others are issuing dire warnings, with Nobel Prize winner Joseph Stiglitz saying it ought to be &lt;a itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/videos/2017-11-29/joseph-stiglitz-bitcoin-ought-to-be-outlawed-video&quot; title=&quot;Joseph Stiglitz: Bitcoin ’Ought to Be Outlawed’ (Video)&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;outlawed&lt;/a&gt; as it “doesn’t serve any socially useful function.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;lazy-img-320998804&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/i2dsW2t7FMz8/v2/60x-1.png&quot; data-native-src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/i2dsW2t7FMz8/v2/-1x-1.png&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img__image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin has risen by about 75 percent since October alone, after developers agreed to cancel a technology update that threatened to split the digital currency. Even as analysts disagree on whether the largest cryptocurrency by market capitalization is truly an asset, its $178 billion value already exceeds that of about 95 percent of the S&amp;amp;P 500 Index members and is driving the debate about where financial technology is headed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It feels frothy, of course,” said Bob Diamond, chief executive officer of Atlas Merchant Capital, said in a Bloomberg &lt;a itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/videos/2017-11-29/bob-diamond-says-bitcoin-feels-frothy-video&quot; title=&quot;Bob Diamond Says Bitcoin Feels Frothy (Video)&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;television interview&lt;/a&gt; with Francine Lacqua. “I think the issue here is the disruptive nature of technology” for banks. “Whether it’s the application of blockchain, or their core processing, or delivery to customers or clients, financial services today is being disrupted by technology.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fed Nominee Comments&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rising profile of digital currencies even saw bitcoin feature in the Senate confirmation hearing Tuesday for Federal Reserve chairman nominee Jerome Powell, who’s a current board member. Answering a senator’s question, he said that “cryptocurrencies are something we monitor very carefully,” and that at some point their volumes “could matter” for monetary policy, though not today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It really is a validation of the fact there’s real enthusiasm, real value and maybe a use case for bitcoin and other cryptocurrencies,” said Arthur Hayes, co-founder and chief executive officer with BitMEX, a Hong Kong-based cryptocurrency derivatives venue. “It’s the start of broader attention and adoption by the investing public.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;inline-newsletter&quot; data-state=&quot;ready&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;There’s no agreed authority for the price of bitcoin, and quotes can vary significantly across exchanges. In Zimbabwe, where there’s a lack of confidence in the local financial system, the cryptocurrency has traded at a &lt;a itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2017-11-15/bitcoin-surges-in-zimbabwe-after-military-moves-to-seize-power&quot; title=&quot;Bitcoin Surges in Zimbabwe After Armed Forces Seize Power (2)&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;persistent&lt;/a&gt; premium over $10,000. Volumes are also difficult to assess. Bloomberg publishes a price that draws on several large bitcoin trading venues. It was at $11,254.75, up 13 percent, as of 9:16 a.m. New York time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From Wall Street executives to venture capitalists, observers have been &lt;a itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2017-11-21/mike-novogratz-says-bitcoin-will-end-the-year-at-10-000&quot; title=&quot;Mike Novogratz Says Bitcoin Will End the Year at $10,000 (2)&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;weighing in&lt;/a&gt;, with some more skeptical than others as bitcoin’s rise has grown steeper, sweeping along individual investors. The number of accounts at Coinbase, one of the largest platforms for trading bitcoin and rival ethereum, has almost tripled to 13 million in the past year, according to Bespoke Investment Group LLC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;video-player&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;video-player__curtain&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/iQ7MJpMGo8gI/v5/640x-1.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/iQ7MJpMGo8gI/v5/640x-1.jpg 640w, https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/iQ7MJpMGo8gI/v5/680x-1.jpg 680w, https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/iQ7MJpMGo8gI/v5/740x-1.jpg 740w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width:761px) and (max-width:1020px) 680px, (min-width:1021px) and (max-width:1280px) 640px, (min-width:1281px) 740px, 100vw&quot;/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;video-player__overlay&quot; data-playerid=&quot;player-JUc1nFT&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;video-player__play-icon&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/s3/javelin/public/javelin/images/play-076012604d.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;news-figure-caption-text&quot; readability=&quot;34&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joseph Stiglitz, Nobel Laureate and Columbia University Professor, discusses Bitcoin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Source: Bloomberg)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-tout-type=&quot;story&quot;&gt;&lt;a itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/features/bitcoin-bulls-bears/&quot; title=&quot;Click for full story&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Read more: Bitcoin’s Most-Famous Lovers and Haters Speak Out on the Rally&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a move toward mainstream investing, CME Group Inc. has said it plans to start offering &lt;a itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2017-10-31/cme-group-world-s-biggest-exchange-plans-bitcoin-futures&quot; title=&quot;Bitcoin Allure Too Much for CME, Now Eyeing Futures Contract (2)&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;futures contracts&lt;/a&gt; for bitcoin, which could begin trading in December. JPMorgan Chase &amp;amp; Co., the largest U.S. bank, was weighing last week whether to help clients bet on bitcoin via the proposed futures contracts, according to a person with knowledge of the situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This is going to be the biggest bubble of our lifetimes,” hedge fund manager Mike Novogratz said at a cryptocurrency conference Tuesday in New York.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Novogratz, who’s says he began investing in bitcoin when it was at $90, is starting a $500 million fund because of the potential for the technology to eventually transform financial markets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-tout-type=&quot;story&quot;&gt;&lt;a itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2017-11-14/the-forks-and-fights-behind-bitcoin-s-turbulence-quicktake-q-a&quot; title=&quot;Click for full story&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Forks and Fights Behind Bitcoin’s Turbulence: QuickTake Q&amp;amp;A&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The total market cap of digital currencies now sits north of $330 billion, according to data on Coinmarketcap.com’s &lt;a itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; href=&quot;https://coinmarketcap.com&quot; title=&quot;market cap&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Peter Rosenstreich, head of market strategy at online trading firm Swissquote Bank SA, bitcoin’s surge harks back to the surprises of the U.K. referendum on European Union membership and President Donald Trump’s election.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We have underestimated the populist movements,” he said. “There is growing unease on how central banks and governments are managing fiat currencies. Ordinary people globally understand why a decentralized asset is the ultimate safe haven.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;— With assistance by Dave Liedtka, and Francine Lacqua&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2017 01:36:37 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>giacaglia</dc:creator>
<og:description>Bitcoin surpassed $11,000 in a matter of hours after hitting the $10,000 milestone, taking this year’s price surge to almost 12-fold as buyers shrugged off increased warnings that the largest digital currency is an asset bubble.</og:description>
<og:image>https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/i0YawYVmeCsM/v1/1200x800.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>Bitcoin Surges Past $11,000 as Bubble Warnings Can't Cool Market</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2017-11-29/bitcoin-leaves-skeptics-behind-while-blasting-to-record-10-000</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2017-11-29/bitcoin-leaves-skeptics-behind-while-blasting-to-record-10-000</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>What&amp;#039;s a reference in Rust?</title>
<link>https://jvns.ca/blog/2017/11/27/rust-ref/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://jvns.ca/blog/2017/11/27/rust-ref/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Hello! Recently I am trying to learn Rust (because I am going to do a project in Rust, and to do that I need to learn Rust better). I’ve written a few hundred lines of Rust over the last 4 years, but I’m honestly still pretty bad at Rust and so my goal is to learn enough that I don’t get confused while writing very simple programs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The audience I’m writing for in this post is a little specific – it’s something like “people who have read the &lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.rust-lang.org/1.9.0/book/lifetimes.html&quot;&gt;lifetimes chapter in the Rust book&lt;/a&gt; and sorta understand it in principle but are still confused about a lot of pretty basic Rust things.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;we are going to talk about&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;What even is a reference in Rust?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is a boxed pointer / string / vec and how do they relate to references?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why is my struct complaining about lifetime parameters and what should I do about it?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;We are not going to talk about ownership / the borrow checker. If you want to know about ownership you should read &lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.rust-lang.org/book/second-edition/ch04-01-what-is-ownership.html&quot;&gt;the rust book&lt;/a&gt;. Also there is probably at least one mistake in this post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s start with something extremely basic: defining a struct in Rust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-rust&quot;&gt;struct Container {
    my_cool_pointer: &amp;amp;u8,
} 
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pretty simple, right? When I try to compile it, the compiler gives me this error message:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;2 |     my_cool_pointer: &amp;amp;u8,
  |                      ^ expected lifetime parameter``
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-doesn-t-this-compile&quot;&gt;Why doesn’t this compile?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Digging into why this simple program doesn’t compile is interesting and helped me understand some things about Rust a tiny bit better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a straightforward answer (“it’s missing a lifetime parameter”), but that answer is not that useful. So let’s ask another better question instead!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-does-mean&quot;&gt;What does &lt;code&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/code&gt; mean?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn’t fully appreciate what &lt;code&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/code&gt; meant in Rust until yesterday. A &lt;code&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/code&gt; is called a “reference” and it is very interesting! You might be thinking “julia, this is boring, I KNOW what a reference is, it is like a pointer in C, I know what that is”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BUT DO YOU REALLY??&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, so let’s say you have a pointer/reference to some memory, &lt;code&gt;&amp;amp;my_cool_pointer&lt;/code&gt;. That memory could be in one of 3 places:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;on the heap&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;on the stack&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;in the data segment of your program&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;The most important thing about Rust (and the thing that makes programming in Rust confusing) is that it needs to decide &lt;strong&gt;at compile time&lt;/strong&gt; when all the memory in the program needs to be freed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So: let’s say I’ve written a program like this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;fn blah () {
    let x: Container = whatever();
    return;
}
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the function &lt;code&gt;blah&lt;/code&gt; returns, &lt;code&gt;x&lt;/code&gt; goes out of scope, and we need to figure out what to do with its &lt;code&gt;my_cool_pointer&lt;/code&gt; member. But how can Rust know what &lt;strong&gt;kind&lt;/strong&gt; of reference &lt;code&gt;my_cool_pointer&lt;/code&gt; is? Is it on the heap? Who knows??&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this is no good, Rust can’t compile this program because it doesn’t have enough information about what kind of reference our reference is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(to understand what references are it is also helpful to read the &lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.rust-lang.org/book/second-edition/ch04-02-references-and-borrowing.html&quot;&gt;rust book on references &amp;amp; borrowing&lt;/a&gt;, that chapter says different things about references which are also true and useful)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;making-our-struct-compile-with-a-box&quot;&gt;making our struct compile with a &lt;code&gt;Box&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we &lt;strong&gt;knew&lt;/strong&gt; that &lt;code&gt;my_cool_pointer&lt;/code&gt; was allocated on the heap, then we would know what to do when it goes out of scope: free it! The way to tell the Rust compiler that a pointer is allocated on the heap is using a type called &lt;code&gt;Box&lt;/code&gt;. So a &lt;code&gt;Box&amp;lt;u8&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; is a pointer to a byte on the heap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This code compiles!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;struct Container {
    my_cool_pointer: Box&amp;lt;u8&amp;gt;,
} 
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can now use our Container struct in a program and run it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;struct Container {
    bytes: Box&amp;lt;u8&amp;gt;,
} 

fn test() -&amp;gt; Container {
    // this is where we allocate a byte of memory
    return Container{bytes: Box::new(23)}; 
}

fn main() {
    let x = test();
    // when `main` exits, the memory we allocated gets freed!
}
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;boxes-in-rust-vs-boxes-in-java&quot;&gt;boxes in Rust vs boxes in Java&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an aside – I got a bit confused by the word “box”. I know in Java you have boxed pointer versions of primitive types, like &lt;code&gt;Integer&lt;/code&gt; instead of &lt;code&gt;int&lt;/code&gt;. And you can’t really have non-boxed pointers in Java, basically every pointer is allocated on the heap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rust boxed pointers (&lt;code&gt;Box&amp;lt;T&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;) are a bit different from Java boxed pointers though!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Java, a boxed pointer includes an extra word of data (not sure what it’s for exactly, but I know there’s an extra word for something).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Rust, a boxed pointer &lt;strong&gt;sometimes&lt;/strong&gt; includes an extra word (a “vtable pointer”) and sometimes don’t. It depends on whether the &lt;code&gt;T&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code&gt;Box&amp;lt;T&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; is a type or a trait. Don’t ask me more, I do not know more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, when you have a boxed pointer, the compiler uses the information that it’s allocated on the heap in order to decide where in the compiled code to free the memory. In our example above, the compiler would insert a &lt;code&gt;free&lt;/code&gt; at the end of the &lt;code&gt;main&lt;/code&gt; function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-if-you-want-to-point-to-existing-memory&quot;&gt;what if you want to point to existing memory?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, so now we know how to allocate new memory and refer to it (use a boxed pointer!). But what if you want to refer to some &lt;strong&gt;existing&lt;/strong&gt; memory somewhere and point to that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good example of this is – I’ve used this DWARF parser called &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/gimli-rs/gimli&quot;&gt;gimli&lt;/a&gt;. It doesn’t do basically any allocations – it just loads all the DWARF data for your program into memory and then points into that data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where you use lifetimes. I’m not going to explain lifetimes because they’re &lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.rust-lang.org/1.9.0/book/lifetimes.html&quot;&gt;explained in the Rust book&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This program also compiles:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-rust&quot;&gt;struct Container&amp;lt;'a&amp;gt; {
    my_cool_pointer: &amp;amp;'a u8,
} 
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So now we have made our struct compile in 2 different ways: by adding a lifetime parameter to our struct definition, and by using a boxed pointer instead of a reference. Great!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s talk about things that are allocated on the heap a little more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-do-you-know-if-a-rust-variable-is-allocated-on-the-heap&quot;&gt;How do you know if a Rust variable is allocated on the heap?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, we learned in this post that if a variable has type &lt;code&gt;Box&amp;lt;T&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;, then it’s a pointer to some memory on the heap. Are there other types that are always on the heap? It turns out there are!! Here they are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Vec&amp;lt;T&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; (an array on the heap)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;String&lt;/code&gt; (a string on the heap)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Box&amp;lt;T&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; (just a pointer).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;These 3 types all have equivalent reference types (again: a reference is a pointer to memory in an unknown place): &lt;code&gt;&amp;amp;[T]&lt;/code&gt; for &lt;code&gt;Vec&amp;lt;T&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;&amp;amp;str&lt;/code&gt; for &lt;code&gt;String&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;&amp;amp;T&lt;/code&gt; for &lt;code&gt;Box&amp;lt;T&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think these 3 types (&lt;code&gt;Vec&amp;lt;T&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;String&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;Box&amp;lt;T&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;) are very important in Rust and undersanding the relationship between them and their reference version (&lt;code&gt;&amp;amp;[T]&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;&amp;amp;str&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;&amp;amp;T&lt;/code&gt;) is extremely important when writing Rust programs. Like I didn’t understand before and I think that has been part of why I was so confused about Rust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Converting from a &lt;code&gt;Vec&amp;lt;T&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; to a &lt;code&gt;&amp;amp;[T]&lt;/code&gt; is really easy – you just run &lt;code&gt;vec.as_ref()&lt;/code&gt;. The reason you can do this conversion is that you’re just “forgetting” that that variable is allocated on the heap and saying “who cares, this is just a reference”. &lt;code&gt;String&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Box&amp;lt;T&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; also has an &lt;code&gt;.as_ref()&lt;/code&gt; method that convert to the reference version of those types in the same way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can’t as easily convert back from a &lt;code&gt;&amp;amp;[T]&lt;/code&gt; to a &lt;code&gt;Vec&amp;lt;T&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; though (because a &lt;code&gt;&amp;amp;[T]&lt;/code&gt; could be a pointer to memory on the stack, so it doesn’t make sense to just say “this is something on the heap”)! To convert back, you’d need to make a clone and allocate new memory on the heap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;there-are-2-kinds-of-structs-those-with-lifetimes-and-those-without-lifetimes&quot;&gt;there are 2 kinds of structs: those with lifetimes and those without lifetimes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So we have arrived at a useful fact about Rust!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every struct (or at least every useful struct!) refers to data. Some structs have lifetimes as part of their type, and some don’t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s another example of a struct with no lifetime:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;struct NoLifetime {
    x: Vec&amp;lt;u8&amp;gt;,
    y: String,
    z: Box&amp;lt;u8&amp;gt;
}
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This struct has pointers to an array, a string, and a byte on the heap. When an instance of this struct goes out of scope all that memory will be freed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, here’s a struct with a lifetime! This struct also has pointers to an array, a string, and a byte. We have no idea from this struct definition where the data this is pointing to will be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;struct Lifetime&amp;lt;'a&amp;gt; {
    x: &amp;amp;'a [u8],
    y: &amp;amp;'a str,
    z: &amp;amp;'a u8
}
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can’t tell you which kind of struct to make your Rust structs because I don’t know yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;do-structs-in-rust-usually-have-lifetimes-or-not&quot;&gt;do structs in Rust usually have lifetimes or not?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One question I have (that I think I will just resolve by getting more Rust experience!) is – when I write a Rust struct, how often will I be using lifetimes vs making the struct own all its own data?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I looked in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/BurntSushi/ripgrep&quot;&gt;https://github.com/BurntSushi/ripgrep&lt;/a&gt;, and most of the struct definitions there do not have lifetimes. I don’t know what that tells me!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;that-s-all-for-now&quot;&gt;that’s all for now&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I learned a lot of useful things by writing this blog post! Now I am going to go back to writing Rust programs and see if all this newfound knowledge helps me write them in a less confused way.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2017 23:14:46 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>giacaglia</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://jvns.ca/blog/2017/11/27/rust-ref/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Samsung Develops Battery Material with 5x Faster Charging Speed</title>
<link>https://news.samsung.com/global/samsung-develops-battery-material-with-5x-faster-charging-speed</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://news.samsung.com/global/samsung-develops-battery-material-with-5x-faster-charging-speed</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, a team of researchers at the Samsung Advanced Institute of Technology (SAIT) developed a “&lt;strong&gt;graphene&lt;/strong&gt;* ball,” a unique battery material that enables a 45% increase in capacity, and five times faster charging speeds than standard lithium-ion batteries. The breakthrough provides promise for the next generation secondary battery market, particularly related to mobile devices and electric vehicles. In its research, SAIT collaborated closely with Samsung SDI as well as a team from Seoul National University’s School of Chemical and Biological Engineering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-95854&quot; src=&quot;https://img.global.news.samsung.com/global/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/Nature-Comm-Battery-Material_main_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;705&quot; height=&quot;529&quot; srcset=&quot;https://img.global.news.samsung.com/global/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/Nature-Comm-Battery-Material_main_1.jpg 705w, https://img.global.news.samsung.com/global/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/Nature-Comm-Battery-Material_main_1-544x408.jpg 544w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 705px) 100vw, 705px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exploring Next Generation Battery Technology&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lithium-ion batteries were first commercialized in 1991, and widely applied to markets for mobile devices and electric vehicles. However, with standard lithium batteries requiring charging times of at least an hour to fully charge, even with quick charging technology, and considered to have reached their limit for capacity expansion, there have been numerous attempts to explore use of new innovative materials. Among the materials looked at, graphene has widely become the primary source of interest as the representative next generation material.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In theory, a battery based on the “graphene ball” material requires only 12 minutes to fully charge. Additionally, the battery can maintain a highly stable 60 degree Celsius temperature, with stable battery temperatures particularly key for electric vehicles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In its research, SAIT sought for an approach to apply graphene, a material with high strength and conductivity to batteries, and discovered a mechanism to mass synthesize graphene into a 3D form like popcorn using affordable silica (SiO2). This “graphene ball” was utilized for both the anode protective layer and cathode materials in lithium-ion batteries. This ensured an increase of charging capacity, decrease of charging time as well as stable temperatures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Son In-hyuk, who led the project on behalf of SAIT, said, “Our research enables mass synthesis of multifunctional composite material graphene at an affordable price. At the same time, we were able to considerably enhance the capabilities of lithium-ion batteries in an environment where the markets for mobile devices and electric vehicles is growing rapidly. Our commitment is to continuously explore and develop secondary battery technology in light of these trends.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SAIT’s research results are covered in-depth in this month’s edition of the science journal &lt;em&gt;Nature Communications&lt;/em&gt; in an article entitled, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-017-01823-7&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;“Graphene balls for lithium rechargeable batteries with fast charging and high volumetric energy densities.”&lt;/a&gt; SAIT has also filed two applications for the “graphene ball” technology patent in the US and Korea.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;em&gt;*Graphene is a single layer of carbon atoms from graphite, and is receiving much attention in the battery and display industry due to its physical, chemical stability. Graphene is 100 times more effective than copper in conducting electricity and displays remarkable electron mobility – 140 times faster than silicon – which makes it an ideal material for fast charge.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2017 21:13:20 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>nielsbjerg</dc:creator>
<og:title>Samsung Develops Battery Material with 5x Faster Charging Speed</og:title>
<og:image>https://img.global.news.samsung.com/global/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/Nature-Comm-Battery-Material_thumb704.jpg</og:image>
<og:url>https://news.samsung.com/global/samsung-develops-battery-material-with-5x-faster-charging-speed</og:url>
<og:description>Samsung Newsroom</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://news.samsung.com/global/samsung-develops-battery-material-with-5x-faster-charging-speed</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Astonishing OS X bug lets anyone log into a High Sierra machine</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2017/11/28/astonishing-os-x-bug-lets-anyone-log-into-a-high-sierra-machine/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2017/11/28/astonishing-os-x-bug-lets-anyone-log-into-a-high-sierra-machine/</guid>
<description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/technicaldiff.jpg?w=738&quot; class=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;p id=&quot;speakable-summary&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt;: Apple has acknowledged the issue and is working on it. Statement and workaround below.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wow, this is a bad one. On Macs running the latest version of High Sierra — 10.13.1 (17B48) — it appears that anyone can log in just by putting “root” in the user name field. This is a huge, &lt;em&gt;huge&lt;/em&gt; problem. Apple will fix it probably within hours, but holy moly. &lt;strong&gt;Do not leave your Mac unattended until this is resolved.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bug is most easily accessed by going to Preferences and then entering one of the panels that has a lock in the lower left-hand corner. Normally you’d click that to enter your user name and password, which are required to change important settings like those in Security &amp;amp; Privacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No need to do that any more! Just enter “root” instead of your user name and hit enter. After a few tries, it should log right in. &lt;strong&gt;There’s no need to do this yourself to verify it. Doing so creates a “root” account that others may be able to take advantage of if you don’t disable it.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/ooooooh-dear.gif&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-1571932&quot; src=&quot;https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/ooooooh-dear.gif?w=712&amp;amp;h=436&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;712&quot; height=&quot;436&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bug appears to have been first noticed by &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/lemiorhan/status/935578694541770752&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Lemi Orhan Ergin&lt;/a&gt;, founder of Software Craftsman Turkey, who noted it publicly on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Needless to say, this is incredibly, incredibly bad. Once you log in, you’ve essentially authenticated yourself as the owner of the computer. You can add administrators, change critical settings, lock out the current owner, and so on. &lt;strong&gt;Do not leave your Mac unattended until this is resolved.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far this has worked on every preference panel we’ve tried, and when I used “root” at the login screen it immediately created and pulled up a new user with system administrator privileges. It didn’t work on a 10.13 (17A365) machine, but that one is also loaded up with AOL bloatware — sorry, &lt;em&gt;Oath&lt;/em&gt; bloatware — which may affect things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple offered the following statement:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;10.851674641148&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are working on a software update to address this issue. In the meantime, setting a root password prevents unauthorized access to your Mac. To enable the Root User and set a password, please follow the instructions here: &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT204012&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT204012&lt;/a&gt;. If a Root User is already enabled, to ensure a blank password is not set, please follow the instructions from the ‘Change the root password’ section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find Directory Utility via the instructions in that link, but you can also hit command-space now to open Spotlight and just type it in. Once it opens, click the lock and enter your password and then under the Edit menu you’ll have the option to change the root password. It looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/screen-shot-2017-11-28-at-2-30-04-pm.png&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-1572076&quot; src=&quot;https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/screen-shot-2017-11-28-at-2-30-04-pm.png?w=1024&amp;amp;h=549&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;549&quot; srcset=&quot;https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/screen-shot-2017-11-28-at-2-30-04-pm.png?w=1024&amp;amp;h=549 1024w, https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/screen-shot-2017-11-28-at-2-30-04-pm.png?w=150&amp;amp;h=80 150w, https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/screen-shot-2017-11-28-at-2-30-04-pm.png?w=300&amp;amp;h=161 300w, https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/screen-shot-2017-11-28-at-2-30-04-pm.png?w=768&amp;amp;h=412 768w, https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/screen-shot-2017-11-28-at-2-30-04-pm.png?w=680&amp;amp;h=364 680w, https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/screen-shot-2017-11-28-at-2-30-04-pm.png 1952w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Anything’s better than nothing, which is the password the root user has now, but make it strong just in case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hope Apple has a fix soon because even though this workaround exists, we can’t be sure of the extent of this particular flaw until Apple takes a look. &lt;strong&gt;No one should leave their Mac unattended until this is resolved.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2017 20:42:30 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>wyc</dc:creator>
<og:title>Huge security flaw lets anyone log into a High Sierra Mac</og:title>
<og:description>Wow, this is a bad one. On Macs running the latest version of High Sierra (10.13.1 (17B48)), it appears that anyone can log in just by putting &quot;root&quot; in the..</og:description>
<og:image>https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/technicaldiff.jpg</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2017/11/28/astonishing-os-x-bug-lets-anyone-log-into-a-high-sierra-machine/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2017/11/28/astonishing-os-x-bug-lets-anyone-log-into-a-high-sierra-machine/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>AWS AppSync – Build data-driven apps with real-time and off-line capabilities</title>
<link>https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/aws/introducing-amazon-appsync/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/aws/introducing-amazon-appsync/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;In this day and age, it is almost impossible to do without our mobile devices and the applications that help make our lives easier. As our dependency on our mobile phone grows, the mobile application market has exploded with millions of apps vying for our attention. For mobile developers, this means that we must ensure that we build applications that provide the quality, real-time experiences that app users desire.  Therefore, it has become essential that mobile applications are developed to include features such as multi-user data synchronization, offline network support, and data discovery, just to name a few.  According to several articles, I read recently about mobile development trends on publications like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.infoq.com/articles/latest-mobile-app-development-trends/&quot;&gt;InfoQ&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://dzone.com/articles/11-mobile-app-development-trends-to-stay-in-2017&quot;&gt;DZone&lt;/a&gt;, and the mobile development blog &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alleviatetech.com/blog/top-class-mobile-app-development-trends-will-rule-2018/&quot;&gt;AlleviateTech&lt;/a&gt;, one of the key elements in of delivering the aforementioned capabilities is with cloud-driven mobile applications.  It seems that this is especially true, as it related to mobile data synchronization and data storage.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That being the case, it is a perfect time for me to announce a new service for building innovative mobile applications that are driven by data-intensive services in the cloud; &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/appsync/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AWS AppSync&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;AWS AppSync&lt;/strong&gt; is a fully managed serverless &lt;a href=&quot;http://graphql.org/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GraphQL&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; service for real-time data queries, synchronization, communications and offline programming features. For those not familiar, let me briefly share some information about the open &lt;a href=&quot;http://facebook.github.io/graphql/&quot;&gt;GraphQL specification&lt;/a&gt;. GraphQL is a responsive data query language and server-side runtime for querying data sources that allow for real-time data retrieval and dynamic query execution. You can use GraphQL to build a responsive API for use in when building client applications. GraphQL works at the application layer and provides a type system for defining schemas. These schemas serve as specifications to define how operations should be performed on the data and how the data should be structured when retrieved. Additionally, GraphQL has a declarative coding model which is supported by many client libraries and frameworks including React, React Native, iOS, and Android.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now the power of the GraphQL open standard query language is being brought to you in a rich managed service with &lt;strong&gt;AWS AppSync. &lt;/strong&gt; With &lt;strong&gt;AppSync&lt;/strong&gt; developers can simplify the retrieval and manipulation of data across multiple data sources with ease, allowing them to quickly prototype, build and create robust, collaborative, multi-user applications. AppSync keeps data updated when devices are connected, but enables developers to build solutions that work offline by caching data locally and synchronizing local data when connections become available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s discuss some key concepts of AWS AppSync and how the service works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AppSync Concepts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AWS AppSync Client&lt;/strong&gt;: service client that defines operations, wraps authorization details of requests, and manage offline logic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data Source&lt;/strong&gt;: the data storage system or a trigger housing data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Identity&lt;/strong&gt;: a set of credentials with permissions and identification context provided with requests to GraphQL proxy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GraphQL Proxy&lt;/strong&gt;: the GraphQL engine component for processing and mapping requests, handling conflict resolution, and managing Fine Grained Access Control&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Operation:&lt;/strong&gt; one of three GraphQL operations supported in AppSync
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Query: a read-only fetch call to the data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mutation: a write of the data followed by a fetch,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Subscription: long-lived connections that receive data in response to events.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Action&lt;/strong&gt;: a notification to connected subscribers from a GraphQL subscription.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resolver:&lt;/strong&gt; function using request and response mapping templates that converts and executes payload against data source&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;How It Works&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A schema is created to define types and capabilities of the desired GraphQL API and tied to a &lt;strong&gt;Resolver&lt;/strong&gt; function.  The schema can be created to mirror existing data sources or AWS AppSync can create tables automatically based the schema definition. Developers can also use GraphQL features for data discovery without having knowledge of the backend data sources. After a schema definition is established, an &lt;strong&gt;AWS AppSync&lt;/strong&gt; client can be configured with an operation request, like a Query operation. The client submits the operation request to &lt;strong&gt;GraphQL Proxy&lt;/strong&gt; along with an identity context and credentials. The &lt;strong&gt;GraphQL Proxy&lt;/strong&gt; passes this request to the &lt;strong&gt;Resolver&lt;/strong&gt; which maps and executes the request payload against pre-configured AWS data services like an &lt;strong&gt;Amazon DynamoDB&lt;/strong&gt; table, an &lt;strong&gt;AWS Lambda&lt;/strong&gt; function, or a search capability using &lt;strong&gt;Amazon Elasticsearch&lt;/strong&gt;. The &lt;strong&gt;Resolver&lt;/strong&gt; executes calls to one or all of these services within a single network call minimizing CPU cycles and bandwidth needs and returns the response to the client. Additionally, the client application can change data requirements in code on demand and the &lt;strong&gt;AppSync GraphQL API&lt;/strong&gt; will dynamically map requests for data accordingly, allowing prototyping and faster development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to take a quick peek at the service, I’ll go to the &lt;strong&gt;AWS AppSync&lt;/strong&gt; console. I’ll click the &lt;strong&gt;Create API&lt;/strong&gt; button to get started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://media.amazonwebservices.com/blog/2017/AWS%20AppSync-01-Console-3.png&quot; width=&quot;850&quot; height=&quot;417&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the &lt;strong&gt;Create new API&lt;/strong&gt; screen opens, I’ll give my new API a name, &lt;strong&gt;TarasTestApp&lt;/strong&gt;, and since I am just exploring the new service I will select the &lt;strong&gt;Sample schema&lt;/strong&gt; option.  You may notice from the informational dialog box on the screen that in using the sample schema, AWS AppSync will automatically create the DynamoDB tables and the IAM roles for me.It will also deploy the &lt;strong&gt;TarasTestApp&lt;/strong&gt; API on my behalf.  After review of the sample schema provided by the console, I’ll click the &lt;strong&gt;Create button&lt;/strong&gt; to create my test API.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://media.amazonwebservices.com/blog/2017/AWS%20AppSync-02-CreateAPI.png&quot; width=&quot;850&quot; height=&quot;407&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://media.amazonwebservices.com/blog/2017/AWS%20AppSync-03-SampleSchema.png&quot; width=&quot;850&quot; height=&quot;697&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the &lt;strong&gt;TaraTestApp&lt;/strong&gt; API has been created and the associated AWS resources provisioned on my behalf, I can make updates to the schema, data source, or connect my data source(s) to a resolver. I also can integrate my GraphQL API into an iOS, Android, Web, or React Native application by cloning the sample repo from GitHub and downloading the accompanying GraphQL schema.  These application samples are great to help get you started and they are pre-configured to function in offline scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://media.amazonwebservices.com/blog/2017/AWS%20AppSync-04-APIDetails.png&quot; width=&quot;850&quot; height=&quot;396&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://media.amazonwebservices.com/blog/2017/AWS%20AppSync-05-AppDownload.png&quot; width=&quot;850&quot; height=&quot;370&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I select the &lt;strong&gt;Schema&lt;/strong&gt; menu option on the console, I can update and view the &lt;strong&gt;TarasTestApp&lt;/strong&gt; GraphQL API schema.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://media.amazonwebservices.com/blog/2017/AWS%20AppSync-06-SchemaDetails.png&quot; width=&quot;850&quot; height=&quot;395&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Additionally, if I select the Data Sources menu option in the console, I can see the existing data sources.  Within this screen, I can update, delete, or add data sources if I so desire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://media.amazonwebservices.com/blog/2017/AWS%20AppSync-07-DataSource.png&quot; width=&quot;850&quot; height=&quot;448&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, I will select the &lt;strong&gt;Query&lt;/strong&gt; menu option which takes me to the console tool for writing and testing queries. Since I chose the sample schema and the &lt;strong&gt;AWS AppSync&lt;/strong&gt; service did most of the heavy lifting for me, I’ll try a query against my new GraphQL API.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll use a mutation to add data for the event type in my schema. Since this is a mutation and it first writes data and then does a read of the data, I want the query to return values for name and where.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://media.amazonwebservices.com/blog/2017/AWS%20AppSync-08-Queries.png&quot; width=&quot;850&quot; height=&quot;381&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://media.amazonwebservices.com/blog/2017/AWS%20AppSync-09-QueryExecution.png&quot; width=&quot;850&quot; height=&quot;478&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I go to the DynamoDB table created for the event type in the schema, I will see that the values from my query have been successfully written into the table. Now that was a pretty simple task to write and retrieve data based on a GraphQL API schema from a data source, don’t you think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://media.amazonwebservices.com/blog/2017/AWS%20AppSync-10-DynamoDBData.png&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;381&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt; &lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Summary&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AWS AppSync&lt;/strong&gt; is currently in AWS AppSync is in Public Preview and you can &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.awscloud.com/awsappsyncpreview.html&quot;&gt;sign up today&lt;/a&gt;. It supports development for iOS, Android, and JavaScript applications. You can take advantage of this managed GraphQL service by going to the &lt;strong&gt;AWS&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;AppSync&lt;/strong&gt; console or learn more by reviewing more details about the service by reading a tutorial in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/appsync/resources/&quot;&gt;AWS documentation&lt;/a&gt; for the service or checking out our &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.aws.amazon.com/appsync/latest/devguide/welcome.html&quot;&gt;AWS AppSync Developer Guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;– &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/taraw&quot;&gt;Tara&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2017 20:35:08 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>marvinpinto</dc:creator>
<og:title>Introducing AWS AppSync – Build data-driven apps with real-time and off-line capabilities | Amazon Web Services</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/aws/introducing-amazon-appsync/</og:url>
<og:description>In this day and age, it is almost impossible to do without our mobile devices and the applications that help make our lives easier. As our dependency on our mobile phone grows, the mobile application market has exploded with millions of apps vying for our attention. For mobile developers, this means that we must ensure […]</og:description>
<og:image>https://d2908q01vomqb2.cloudfront.net/da4b9237bacccdf19c0760cab7aec4a8359010b0/2017/11/28/AWS-AppSync-01-Console-3.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/aws/introducing-amazon-appsync/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Charging for our product originally hurt but ultimately saved our startup</title>
<link>https://medium.com/initialized-capital/how-charging-for-our-product-originally-hurt-but-ultimately-saved-our-startup-391e69ae42ba</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://medium.com/initialized-capital/how-charging-for-our-product-originally-hurt-but-ultimately-saved-our-startup-391e69ae42ba</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*cpNKK0eM7LX5cURLtyUDRw.jpeg&quot; data-width=&quot;680&quot; data-height=&quot;578&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*cpNKK0eM7LX5cURLtyUDRw.jpeg&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*cpNKK0eM7LX5cURLtyUDRw.jpeg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;d3dd&quot; id=&quot;d3dd&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;Five years ago, my co-founder &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@clairethere&quot; data-href=&quot;https://medium.com/@clairethere&quot; data-anchor-type=&quot;2&quot; data-user-id=&quot;39c1354d911d&quot; data-action-value=&quot;39c1354d911d&quot; data-action=&quot;show-user-card&quot; data-action-type=&quot;hover&quot; class=&quot;markup--user markup--p-user&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Claire McDonnell&lt;/a&gt; and I founded &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.truelinkfinancial.com/&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.truelinkfinancial.com/&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;True Link Financial&lt;/a&gt;, and did two things that that were totally unorthodox for the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;1045&quot; id=&quot;1045&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;First, we didn’t build a startup for teenagers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;c20a&quot; id=&quot;c20a&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;We built it for seniors. (We’re a financial services firm that offers debit and Visa cards and investments management for aging Americans.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;f41f&quot; id=&quot;f41f&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Secondly, we charged our customers actual, real money for what we had built.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;0739&quot; id=&quot;0739&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;This was not common practice at the time. Around 2012, we and a whole cohort of other startups — Simple, Plastc, Swyp, Coin, Final, Stratos, Clinkle, and others — were getting card-issuing companies off the ground.¹ We also launched a Visa card — but our goal was to protect older folks from fraud, a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.truelinkfinancial.com/research&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.truelinkfinancial.com/research&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;$36 billion problem&lt;/a&gt; that affects millions of Americans, including my grandmother. Our cards would automatically decline scammy transactions so seniors like my grandmother would be able to still carry a credit card, preserve their independence, and spend their own money — and in order to decline the transactions we had to become the issuer of the card.²&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;eb7a&quot; id=&quot;eb7a&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;The other companies offered a no-fees, high-end products with attractive features like extra security for online purchases, easier access to customer support, or perks and rewards. With expensive technology and support costs, we knew the companies offering free cards were losing money on every card they issued.³ In contrast, we charged $10 a month for each card.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*TiTWqPfN2shoQG5sRiD6PQ.png&quot; data-width=&quot;386&quot; data-height=&quot;438&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*TiTWqPfN2shoQG5sRiD6PQ.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;68d6&quot; id=&quot;68d6&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;With splashy videos and tons of press, some of our peers had waiting lists of 50,000 customers or more by the time they launched.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;021e&quot; id=&quot;021e&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;That wasn’t us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;0f25&quot; id=&quot;0f25&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;When we launched our product we probably had a waitlist of 50. If you took me, my roommate, my mom, my dad, my co-founder, and my best friend out, it was more like 44. By our first year in market it had grown to about 1,000 customers — about 2 percent of where competitors got to &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;before they had even launched&lt;/em&gt;. The two VC funds we wanted to work with the most said, “True Link would be so great if you just knew how to get customers,” and even better, “So, how come nobody wants it?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;28a1&quot; id=&quot;28a1&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@garrytan&quot; data-href=&quot;https://medium.com/@garrytan&quot; data-anchor-type=&quot;2&quot; data-user-id=&quot;f455e8ea861d&quot; data-action-value=&quot;f455e8ea861d&quot; data-action=&quot;show-user-card&quot; data-action-type=&quot;hover&quot; class=&quot;markup--user markup--p-user&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Garry Tan&lt;/a&gt;, one of our first investors, sent &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@ashrust&quot; data-href=&quot;https://medium.com/@ashrust&quot; data-anchor-type=&quot;2&quot; data-user-id=&quot;582c1c98356d&quot; data-action-value=&quot;582c1c98356d&quot; data-action=&quot;show-user-card&quot; data-action-type=&quot;hover&quot; class=&quot;markup--user markup--p-user&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Ash Rust&lt;/a&gt; over to our office to deliver a message: “You need to raise more money now, not later.” He thought that our strategy was going to be a long slog and that we didn’t have room to cut it close.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 name=&quot;7b2a&quot; id=&quot;7b2a&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--h3-strong&quot;&gt;Charging for your product instills discipline&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;8cb4&quot; id=&quot;8cb4&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;We made the case to our investors and potential investors that what we had done was actually more difficult and more impressive. Just ask the promoters handing out energy drink samples at the BART entrances: getting 50 people to accept something for free is easier than getting one person to pay $10 for it. If the other companies asked everyone on their waitlist to pay for their product, how many would stick with it? We argued that our 1,000 customers were better signal than the other companies’ 50,000 customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;3f42&quot; id=&quot;3f42&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--pullquote graf--startsWithDoubleQuote graf-after--p&quot; readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We didn’t want to teach ourselves how to find money-losing customers.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;7430&quot; id=&quot;7430&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--pullquote&quot;&gt;Right or wrong about the signal, what was more important was the discipline it created internally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;e83c&quot; id=&quot;e83c&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;We didn’t want to teach ourselves how to find money-losing customers. We wanted to teach ourselves how to find customers that would sustain the business. We knew it would be harder and we would have to try more things. But while huge backlogs of money-losing customers might be good for raising capital, ultimately we wanted to build a product worth purchasing — and, a business that could last. Issuing and servicing cards actually costs money, and it doesn’t help either us &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;or&lt;/em&gt; our customers to sign them up for a money-losing business and then disappear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;b64b&quot; id=&quot;b64b&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;We found that what other card startups were doing — press, Facebook ads, and punchy video content — didn’t generate paid signups. It was enough to generate &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;weak&lt;/em&gt; interest — “Sure, I’d try that” — from early adopters, but not enough to generate &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;strong&lt;/em&gt; interest — “I’ve decided to close my other credit cards and use this instead.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;205e&quot; id=&quot;205e&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;The people with the massive waitlists, it turns out, hadn’t really &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;sold&lt;/em&gt; their product yet, they just convinced people to take a free trial. And not only does this not build a sustainable business, but the impact we were looking to have — protecting seniors from billions of dollars of fraud &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;— required&lt;/em&gt; people to close their other credit cards and use ours instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*dXzH5K69uP4LNgqUboDSfg.png&quot; data-width=&quot;1292&quot; data-height=&quot;252&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*dXzH5K69uP4LNgqUboDSfg.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*dXzH5K69uP4LNgqUboDSfg.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;27ca&quot; id=&quot;27ca&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;In contrast, we found that word of mouth convinced people to actually buy and use the product. If someone you trust says it worked for them or someone they know, you’re ready to believe it’s a real solution, worth paying for. Everyone wants viral growth, but building for referrals is a very different thing — and it sometimes means foregoing paid channels that produce quicker results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 name=&quot;7ad9&quot; id=&quot;7ad9&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--h3-strong&quot;&gt;Without charging, we would have built the wrong company&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;f40f&quot; id=&quot;f40f&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;Today, 95 percent of our cards and investment products are set up as a result of an in-person conversation — either with a family member, friend, or trusted professional like an in-home care provider — who already has experience with the product. And remarkably, in 85 percent of those cases we know &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;who&lt;/em&gt; helped the customer sign up and how that person heard about us. We can trace dollars of revenue, for example, back to conferences we presented at to find experts in the aging market, and how those influencers spread the word.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;acec&quot; id=&quot;acec&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Everything internally looks different as a result. Because our existing customers are our marketing engine, we’ve found from internal surveys that our customer support has a 99 percent satisfaction rating. Our customers are the primary way that we grow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;92f7&quot; id=&quot;92f7&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;We’ve built software to make it easy for different types of key players to start the on-boarding process. And our marketing relies on a detailed set of referral analytics tools that few other card issuers have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;1cc1&quot; id=&quot;1cc1&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Suppose, early on, our twenty word-of-mouth customers had been thrown in with a thousand free customers coming in off a good Facebook video ad. Would we have built marketing tools to find more word-of-mouth customers?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;5ef8&quot; id=&quot;5ef8&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;The point is, if we’d built for an audience of free customers rather than an audience of paying customers, it would have been a different marketing strategy and team, different technology, different support, different analytics, different everything. We would have built the &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;wrong company&lt;/em&gt;, and when it came time to make money we would be starting from square one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 name=&quot;76b7&quot; id=&quot;76b7&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Instead, we built the right business&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;33cc&quot; id=&quot;33cc&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;We always believed that the marketing experiments we were running were tougher but more valuable. There is no dodging the fact that it sucked being compared to companies with a waiting list a thousand times longer. Some days, the early successes felt like tiny sparks, but over time we found we could turn the sparks into fires. Most things that could generate unpaid sign-ups failed to generate paid sign-ups, but we doubled down on the exceptions and iterated rapidly, quickly setting aside what wasn’t working.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;fce5&quot; id=&quot;fce5&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;We’d planned all along to do something different and more difficult than everyone else. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.echohealthventures.com/matt-karls&quot; data-href=&quot;http://www.echohealthventures.com/matt-karls&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Matt Karls&lt;/a&gt;, our board member from healthcare-focused venture fund Cambia, told his coworkers about how we put lines of tape across on the floor every month to show how much of our rent we were paying out of revenue and how fast that was growing. To us, it was obvious — companies that can’t pay their rent cease to exist. And at True Link, we wanted to keep existing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*0m91zzCeondgEC7hYMtfLA.png&quot; data-width=&quot;285&quot; data-height=&quot;466&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*0m91zzCeondgEC7hYMtfLA.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--figure-em&quot;&gt;Revenue and profit of our cards division since launch&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;5c9c&quot; id=&quot;5c9c&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;Our cards division hit profitability earlier this year. Just three years after we were getting beat up for not having the traction our peers had, we were the first among them to break even — and by a huge margin. If we’d been selling a thousand free cards a week, we probably would never have noticed the twenty customers that actually cared enough to pay for our product — the customers who ended up making True Link a sustainable, long-term business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;8aff&quot; id=&quot;8aff&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.truelinkfinancial.com/&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.truelinkfinancial.com/&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;True Link Financial&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;provides Visa cards and investment portfolios for the aging population with a focus on financial protection. The company&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.truelinkfinancial.com/true-link-financial-secures-8-million-series-a-round&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.truelinkfinancial.com/true-link-financial-secures-8-million-series-a-round&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;announced&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;its Series A financing on October 11.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;eff8&quot; id=&quot;eff8&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;— — — — — — —&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;3fe4&quot; id=&quot;3fe4&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;[1] Note that some were issuers and others were wrappers around other issuers, and some mixed a little of both or were using one as a launchpad into the other. We’re friends with people at Simple, Coin, Final, and Plastc. Each of them — and likely the others we don’t know — are great entrepreneurs, we shared our lessons both ways freely and openly, and hopefully they learned from us just like we learned from them. Simple got an awesome acquisition and is still growing, Final has just finished launching a credit product as a startup which is an incredible feat, and Coin and Plastc did amazing hardware innovations and each gave us really valuable advice. I’d love to see each of them write a blog post like this one about the times they got kicked in the teeth and bounced back — their stories are at least as good as ours and in some cases better. Nothing in here is intended as a knock against anyone. Except for Clinkle, which, I mean….&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;6c79&quot; id=&quot;6c79&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;[2] An important technical distinction: these startups do not &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;issue the card&lt;/em&gt;, but rather &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;manage the card issuing program&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;a1f3&quot; id=&quot;a1f3&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p graf--trailing&quot;&gt;[3] For context, credit cards make money in four ways: monthly or annual fees, usage fees (like at ATMs, or for overdrafts), interest, and what’s called “interchange” — when you swipe your credit card, merchants get 97¢ on the dollar and interchange is the one cent that the card issuer gets. Mature card issuers carefully model their revenues to exceed their costs on average at scale — for example, for high-end cards, points and miles almost equal revenue from interchange, credit defaults almost equal the revenue from interest, and the issuer gets a tiny slice of both and makes money on the annual fee. If you omit an annual or monthly fee, you’re banking on a slim, slim slice of interchange adding up at scale, and if you are a debit card (no interest) and don’t charge overdraft fees (for example) you are betting on a miracle level of scale, as well as patient and plentiful capital to get there.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2017 20:20:57 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>evilsimon</dc:creator>
<og:title>How charging for our product originally hurt — but ultimately saved — our startup</og:title>
<og:url>https://medium.com/initialized-capital/how-charging-for-our-product-originally-hurt-but-ultimately-saved-our-startup-391e69ae42ba</og:url>
<og:image>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*cpNKK0eM7LX5cURLtyUDRw.jpeg</og:image>
<og:description>Five years ago, my co-founder Claire McDonnell and I founded True Link Financial, and did two things that that were totally unorthodox for…</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://medium.com/initialized-capital/how-charging-for-our-product-originally-hurt-but-ultimately-saved-our-startup-391e69ae42ba</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Western Digital Plans to Ship More Than One Billion RISC-V Cores a Year</title>
<link>https://www.wdc.com/about-wd/newsroom/press-room/2017-11-28-western-digital-to-accelerate-the-future-of-next-generation-computing-architectures-for-big-data-and-fast-data-environments.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.wdc.com/about-wd/newsroom/press-room/2017-11-28-western-digital-to-accelerate-the-future-of-next-generation-computing-architectures-for-big-data-and-fast-data-environments.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Company to Transition Consumption of Over One Billion Cores Per Year to RISC-V to Drive Momentum of Open Source Processors for Data Center and Edge Computing&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;90%&quot; alt=&quot;RISC-V&quot; src=&quot;https://www.wdc.com/content/dam/wdc/website/about-wd/press-room/2017/WDC-Big-Data-Fast-Data-RISCV.jpg&quot; hspace=&quot;5&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wdc.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Western Digital Corp.&lt;/a&gt; (NASDAQ: WDC) announced today at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://riscv.org/2017/10/7th-risc-v-workshop-showcases-breadth-risc-v-ecosystem-45-sessions-featuring-technology-leaders/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;7th RISC-V Workshop&lt;/a&gt; that the company intends to lead the industry transition toward open, purpose-built compute architectures to meet the increasingly diverse application needs of a data-centric world. In his keynote address, Western Digital’s Chief Technology Officer &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wdc.com/en-um/about-wd/corporate-officers/corp-bios.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Martin Fink&lt;/a&gt; expressed the company’s commitment to help lead the advancement of data-centric compute environments through the work of the RISC-V Foundation. RISC-V is an open and scalable compute architecture that will enable the diversity of Big Data and Fast Data applications and workloads proliferating in core cloud data centers and in remote and mobile systems at the edge. Western Digital’s leadership role in the RISC-V initiative is significant in that it aims to accelerate the advancement of the technology and the surrounding ecosystem by transitioning its own consumption of processors – over one billion cores per year – to RISC-V.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Big Data and Fast Data environments proliferate, they break the boundaries of traditional infrastructure and system architecture. The “general-purpose” technologies and architectures that have been in place for decades are reaching their limits of scalability, performance and efficiency. General-purpose workloads that are supported by general-purpose architectures typically have a uniform ratio of processing resources, such as operating system (OS) processing, specialty offload processing, memory, data storage and interconnect. As Big Data gets bigger and faster, and Fast Data gets faster and bigger, the &quot;one size fits all&quot; approach of general-purpose computing is failing to meet the increasingly diverse application workloads of our data-centric world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data-Centric Environments&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the diversity of Big Data and Fast Data workloads expand, data-centric compute architectures will need the ability to scale resources independent of one another. The architectures for tomorrow will need to go beyond the limited, standard resource ratios of general purpose compute architectures and enable purpose-built solutions with data-optimized levels of OS processing, specialty processing, memory, storage and interconnect. The extreme data and compute workloads for analytics, machine learning, artificial intelligence and smart systems demand purpose-built environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Western Digital is a leader in storage products and technologies, and we are now expanding that leadership to open, data-centric compute architectures,” said Mike Cordano, president and chief operating officer, Western Digital. “RISC-V will allow the entire industry to realize the benefits of next-generation architectures while also enabling us to create more purpose-built devices, platforms and storage systems for Big Data and Fast Data applications. We are moving beyond just storing data to now creating entire environments that will enable users to realize the value and possibilities of their data.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Moving Compute Closer to Data&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Western Digital is a leading provider of solutions to capture, preserve, access and transform data. RISC-V will enable the company to participate in, and leverage a broad community of inventors focused on bringing increasing amounts of processing power closer to data. As we bring compute power closer to data, customers will be able to minimize data movement at the edge and within their data centers, optimizing processing that is based on location, workload or a time-value need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Accelerating the RISC-V Ecosystem&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contribute toward the advancement and success of the RISC-V ecosystem, Western Digital plans to transition future core, processor, and controller development to the RISC-V architecture. The company currently consumes over one billion processor cores on an annual basis across its product portfolio. The transition will occur gradually and once completely transitioned, Western Digital expects to be shipping two billion RISC-V cores annually. The company is committed to advancing RISC-V technology for use in mission-critical applications so that it can be deployed in its products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Western Digital is engaged in active partnerships and investments in RISC-V ecosystem partners. The company recently completed a strategic investment in Esperanto Technologies, a developer of high-performance, energy-efficient computing solutions based on the open RISC-V architecture. Esperanto, which is headquartered in Mountain View, Calif., includes a seasoned team of experienced processor and software engineers with the goal of making RISC-V the architecture of choice for compute-intensive applications, such as machine learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The open source movement has demonstrated to the world that innovation is maximized with a large community working toward a common goal,” said Fink. “For that reason, we are providing all of our RISC-V logic work to the community. We also encourage open collaboration among all industry participants, including our customers and partners, to help amplify and accelerate our efforts. Together we can drive data-focused innovation and ensure that RISC-V becomes the next Linux success story.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For further information on today’s RISC-V announcement or to view a webcast replay of Martin Fink’s keynote at the 7th RISC-V Workshop, visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://innovation.wdc.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://innovation.wdc.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information on the RISC-V Foundation and the 7th RISC-V Workshop, visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://riscv.org&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://riscv.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About Western Digital&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Western Digital creates environments for data to thrive. The company is driving the innovation needed to help customers capture, preserve, access, and transform an ever-increasing diversity of data. Everywhere data lives, from advanced data centers to mobile sensors to personal devices, our industry-leading solutions deliver the possibilities of data. Western Digital data-centric solutions are marketed under the G-Technology, HGST, SanDisk, Tegile, UpThere and WD brands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Forward-Looking Statements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This news release contains certain forward-looking statements, including statements regarding the RISC-V Foundation and its initiatives; our contributions to and investments in the RISC-V ecosystem; the transition of our devices, platforms and systems to RISC-V architectures; shipments of RISC-V processor cores; our market positioning, business strategy and technology development efforts; market trends and data growth and its drivers. There are a number of risks and uncertainties that may cause these forward-looking statements to be inaccurate including, among others: volatility in global economic conditions; business conditions and growth in the storage ecosystem; impact of competitive products and pricing; market acceptance and cost of commodity materials and specialized product components; actions by competitors; unexpected advances in competing technologies; our development and introduction of products based on new technologies and expansion into new data storage markets; risks associated with acquisitions, mergers and joint ventures; difficulties or delays in manufacturing; and other risks and uncertainties listed in the company's filings with the Securities and Exchange Commission (the &quot;SEC&quot;), including the company's Form 10-Q filed with the SEC on Nov. 7, 2017, to which your attention is directed. You should not place undue reliance on these forward-looking statements, which speak only as of the date hereof, and the company undertakes no obligation to update these forward-looking statements to reflect subsequent events or circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;###&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Western Digital and the Western Digital logo are registered trademarks or trademarks of Western Digital Corporation or its affiliates in the U.S. and/or other countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;© 2017 Western Digital Corporation or its affiliates. All rights reserved.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2017 20:18:43 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>deepnotderp</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:title>Western Digital To Accelerate The Future Of Next-Generation Computing Architectures For Big Data And Fast Data Environments | Western Digital (WD)</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.wdc.com/about-wd/newsroom/press-room/2017-11-28-western-digital-to-accelerate-the-future-of-next-generation-computing-architectures-for-big-data-and-fast-data-environments.html</og:url>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.wdc.com/about-wd/newsroom/press-room/2017-11-28-western-digital-to-accelerate-the-future-of-next-generation-computing-architectures-for-big-data-and-fast-data-environments.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>macOS High Sierra: Anyone can login as “root” with empty password</title>
<link>https://twitter.com/lemiorhan/status/935578694541770752</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://twitter.com/lemiorhan/status/935578694541770752</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/lemiorhan/status/935578694541770752&quot;&gt;https://twitter.com/lemiorhan/status/935578694541770752&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=15800676&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=15800676&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Points: 2756&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 750&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2017 19:41:10 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>vladikoff</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://mobile.twitter.com/lemiorhan/status/935578694541770752</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>