<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>WhatsApp delays privacy changes following backlash</title>
<link>https://p.dw.com/p/3nzYg</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://p.dw.com/p/3nzYg</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The WhatsApp messaging service announced on Friday that it would delay &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dw.com/en/whatsapp-update-to-expand-data-sharing-sparks-criticism/a-56164619&quot;&gt;changes to new business features&lt;/a&gt; after people around the world criticized the new policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Facebook-owned company said it is &quot;going to do a lot more to clear up misinformation around how privacy and security works on WhatsApp.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Privacy rights activists heavily criticized the WhatsApp changes, saying it was the latest step showing Facebook's poor handling of user data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Users looking for other messaging options&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following WhatsApp's initial announcement many users have signed up for other messaging services, including privacy-minded Signal and Telegram. Signal said that a massive influx of users had led to technical difficulties in delivering some messages on Friday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WhatsApp also canceled its February 8 deadline for accepting the tweak to its terms of service, involving sharing data with Facebook servers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;We're now moving back the date on which people will be asked to review and accept the terms,&quot; the company said in a blog post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The delay could pose a hurdle to WhatsApp's plan to generate revenue by making it easier to engage in commercial exchanges on the messaging app. Facebook bought WhatsApp for $19 billion in 2014 but the messaging service has been slow to make money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;sms/dj (Reuters, AFP)&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 20:02:08 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>tchalla</dc:creator>
<og:description>Facebook-owned WhatsApp said they would delay the rollout of a change to its data sharing practice and work to &quot;clear up misinformation&quot; around its privacy policy.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.dw.com/en/whatsapp-delays-privacy-changes-following-backlash/a-56243714</og:url>
<og:title>WhatsApp delays privacy changes following backlash | DW | 15.01.2021</og:title>
<og:image>https://static.dw.com/image/52141889_6.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.dw.com/en/whatsapp-delays-privacy-changes-following-backlash/a-56243714</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Amazon Warehouse Workers to Decide Whether to Form Company&amp;#039;s First U.S. Union</title>
<link>https://www.npr.org/2021/01/15/948819324/amazon-warehouse-workers-to-decide-whether-to-form-companys-first-u-s-union</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.npr.org/2021/01/15/948819324/amazon-warehouse-workers-to-decide-whether-to-form-companys-first-u-s-union</guid>
<description>&lt;div id=&quot;res948822951&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap image large&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;imagewrap&quot; data-crop-type=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2020/12/21/gettyimages-1124819752-a7ffa79120b70111d9840a56fc3ed7d44cda47f1-s1100-c15.jpg&quot; data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2020/12/21/gettyimages-1124819752-a7ffa79120b70111d9840a56fc3ed7d44cda47f1-s1100.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img lazyOnLoad&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;credit-caption&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-wrap&quot; readability=&quot;6.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image caption&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Workers at an Amazon fulfillment center on Staten Island in New York City and across the U.S. have not been unionized. That could change in Alabama. &lt;strong class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Johannes Eisele/AFP via Getty Images&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong class=&quot;hide-caption&quot;&gt;hide caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;strong class=&quot;toggle-caption&quot;&gt;toggle caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Johannes Eisele/AFP via Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;enlarge_measure&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img_wrap&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2020/12/21/gettyimages-1124819752-a7ffa79120b70111d9840a56fc3ed7d44cda47f1-s1200.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;enlarge_html&quot; readability=&quot;6.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image_data&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Workers at an Amazon fulfillment center on Staten Island in New York City and across the U.S. have not been unionized. That could change in Alabama.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Johannes Eisele/AFP via Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Updated at 7:25 p.m. ET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some 6,000 workers at Amazon's warehouse in Bessemer, Ala., will begin voting next month on a groundbreaking possibility: the first union in the company's U.S. history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The National Labor Relations Board on Friday &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nlrb.gov/cases-decisions/decisions/regional-election-decisions&quot;&gt;scheduled the vote&lt;/a&gt; by mail because of coronavirus concerns. It will begin Feb. 8 and continue through March 29. Workers at one of Amazon's newest facilities are deciding whether to join the Retail, Wholesale and Department Store Union.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Friday's ruling came after the agency facilitated a hearing in which Amazon and the retail workers union hashed out who should be included in the bargaining unit and how the vote should take place. Both parties agreed that hundreds of seasonal workers should be eligible to cast ballots. The NLRB rejected Amazon's calls for a traditional in-person vote in favor of balloting by mail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;res948826945&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap internallink insettwocolumn inset2col&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bucket img&quot;&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;featuredStackSquareImage947632289&quot; href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/2020/12/18/947632289/amazon-warehouse-workers-in-alabama-plan-vote-on-1st-u-s-union&quot; data-metrics=&quot;{&amp;quot;category&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Story to Story&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;action&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Click Internal Link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;label&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https:\/\/www.npr.org\/2020\/12\/18\/947632289\/amazon-warehouse-workers-in-alabama-plan-vote-on-1st-u-s-union&amp;quot;}&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2020/12/17/gettyimages-969617114_sq-402f2ffb2bad0ffb1501c4842780c2e3ed3945ed-s100-c15.jpg&quot; data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2020/12/17/gettyimages-969617114_sq-402f2ffb2bad0ffb1501c4842780c2e3ed3945ed-s100.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img lazyOnLoad&quot; alt=&quot;Amazon Warehouse Workers In Alabama Plan Vote On 1st U.S. Union &quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;The biggest thing is Amazon is one of the biggest employers in the United States, and they're heavily, heavily anti-union,&quot; said Arthur Wheaton of the Worker Institute at Cornell University. &quot;So if you can start to get some of their U.S.-based (workers) successfully organized with the union, then that could lead to other cities also doing that.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unions are a prominent presence at Amazon in Europe, but for years, the company successfully fought off labor organizing efforts in the United States. The last vote on unionization at the company happened in 2014, when a small group of maintenance and repair techs at a Delaware warehouse &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/BL-DGB-32039?mod=article_inline&quot;&gt;voted against&lt;/a&gt; joining the International Association of Machinists and Aerospace Workers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id=&quot;ad-backstage-wrap&quot; aria-label=&quot;advertisement&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a statement on Friday, Amazon spokesperson Heather Knox said the company maintained that &quot;a valid, fair and successful&quot; unionization election was one conducted in person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;The onsite voting proposal, which is in the best interest of all parties — associate convenience, vote fidelity, and timeliness of vote count — was not accepted,&quot; Knox said. &quot;We will continue to insist on measures for a fair election, and we want everyone to vote, so our focus is ensuring that's possible.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Retail, Wholesale and Department Store Union representative declined comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazon &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aboutamazon.com/news/operations/update-on-covid-19-testing&quot;&gt;has said&lt;/a&gt; that between March and mid-September, it employed almost 1.4 million front-line workers across Amazon and Whole Foods in the United States. The company earlier argued the petitioners did not represent &quot;the majority of our employees' views&quot; and touted the warehouse facility's pay and benefits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hundreds of Bessemer workers &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/2020/11/25/938863818/amazon-warehouse-workers-in-alabama-petition-to-unionize&quot;&gt;in November&lt;/a&gt; signed cards to petition federal labor authorities for a unionization vote, quickly &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/BernieSanders/status/1331327657007517700?s=20&quot;&gt;gaining support&lt;/a&gt; of longtime Amazon critic Sen. Bernie Sanders of Vermont. The workers' union-backed website &lt;a href=&quot;https://bamazonunion.org/whyunion&quot;&gt;calls for changes&lt;/a&gt; to procedures in disciplining, dismissals and safety.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Editor's note:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Amazon is among NPR's recent financial supporters.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 19:16:05 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jimmy2020</dc:creator>
<og:title>Amazon Warehouse Workers To Decide Whether To Form Company's 1st U.S. Union</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.npr.org/2021/01/15/948819324/amazon-warehouse-workers-to-decide-whether-to-form-companys-first-u-s-union</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>Although the company has unionized workers in Europe, it has held off organizing efforts here. About 6,000 workers at an Amazon facility in Alabama can cast a mail-in ballot starting Feb. 8.</og:description>
<og:image>https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2020/12/21/gettyimages-1124819752_wide-7c3600c4ac93e0f78f09f68cc366fd4023fc4acd.jpg?s=1400</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.npr.org/2021/01/15/948819324/amazon-warehouse-workers-to-decide-whether-to-form-companys-first-u-s-union</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Signal is having technical difficulties</title>
<link>HTTPS://status.signal.org/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >HTTPS://status.signal.org/</guid>
<description>&lt;meta http-equiv=&quot;Content-Type&quot; content=&quot;text/html; charset=UTF-8&quot; /&gt;&lt;link href=&quot;https://fonts.googleapis.com/css?family=Open+Sans:300&quot; rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot; /&gt;&lt;title&gt;Signal Status&lt;/title&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;9.4666666666667&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;symbol&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;cross;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Signal is experiencing technical difficulties. We are working hard to restore service as quickly as possible.&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; readability=&quot;6.3846153846154&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot; xml:lang=&quot;en&quot; xml:lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;We are making progress towards getting the service back online. Privacy is our top priority, but adding capacity is a close second right now.&lt;/p&gt;
— Signal (@signalapp) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/signalapp/status/1350185818527211521?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;January 15, 2021&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 17:33:07 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>tonymet</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>HTTPS://status.signal.org/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Be My Eyes</title>
<link>https://www.bemyeyes.com/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bemyeyes.com/</guid>
<description>&lt;div readability=&quot;14&quot;&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;heading-41-copy&quot;&gt;Blind or low-vision person requests assistance&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-small-16-copy&quot;&gt;As a blind or low-vision person, whenever you need visual assistance, our volunteers are happy to help. Through the live video call, you and a volunteer can communicate directly and solve a problem. The volunteer will help guide which direction to point your camera, what to focus on or when to turn on your torch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;heading-41-copy&quot;&gt;Sighted volunteer receives video call&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p-small-16-copy&quot;&gt;As a sighted volunteer you can help just by installing the Be My Eyes app. A blind or a low-vision user may need help with anything from checking expiry dates, distinguishing colors, reading instructions or navigating new surroundings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 17:08:21 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>EndXA</dc:creator>
<og:title>Be My Eyes - See the world together</og:title>
<og:description>Whether you need a pair of sharp eyes or have some sight to lend, Be My Eyes is a simple, free tool to help people see the world better, together.</og:description>
<og:image>https://bemyeyes-assets.s3.amazonaws.com/website/OG/BME-illustration-tagline-01.png</og:image>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bemyeyes.com/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Thanks HN: You helped save a company that now helps thousands make a living</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25792719</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25792719</guid>
<description>Dear HN,
&lt;p&gt;I’m feeling a deep sense of gratitude this morning, and wanted to share it with you all.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On this day in 2013, the Webflow co-founders were huddled around our usual desk that we claimed every early morning at the Hacker Dojo (a co-working space) in Mountain View, working like hell into the evenings to get something off the ground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had quit our jobs about 6 months prior, and totally underestimated how long it would take to build even a beta. I had personally convinced my wife that we’d only have to be income-less for 3 months – the amount of savings we had in the bank – but that time had now doubled, and those savings were long gone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Kickstarter campaign we had poured all of our savings into producing had fallen through, never even making it live because we hadn’t read the Terms of Service to learn that they didn’t allow SaaS subscriptions to be funded. We had high hopes about getting into YC for the winter batch, but were rejected since we only had a non-functional demo of a product and zero traction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On top of all that, my oldest daughter (3yo then) was diagnosed with a life-threatening condition, requiring expensive surgery that didn’t get much help from our cheap “catastrophic” health insurance plan with an ultra-high deductible. Credit card cash advances became the way we were paying for rent and food.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So with all this, we started contingency planning to try to get our old jobs back. As a last ditch effort, we sold two of our cars and pulled out what equity we had in them to buy a little more runway. Then we had to come to terms that we couldn’t actually build a full product in the time we had left, and decided that the best we could do was to create a demo or playground that could hint at what the future product could be – and hope for the best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In March of 2013, we finally finished that demo and put it up live. It’s still there: &lt;a href=&quot;http://playground.webflow.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://playground.webflow.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now came the time to get users. We were targeting mostly designers and non-technical folks – so we posted it on Digg (heh, remember those days?), Reddit, and several designer-centric forums. But none of those posts got any meaningful traction. We were at a loss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, with tempered expectations about how a visual development tool for designers would be received in the hacker community, we posted here to HN. The title was “Show HN: Webflow – design responsive websites visually” [1] and we crossed our fingers really hard at this last-ditch effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What happened next was nothing short of life-changing. The post took off like wildfire, staying at #1 for the entire day. Incredible words of encouragement were all over the comments. Over 25,000 people signed up for our beta list. VentureBeat wrote a story about us that same day. Tons of people started talking about Webflow on Twitter, Reddit, etc as a result. This led to a ton of word of mouth and even more signups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This amazing traction helped us get into YC several months later, gave us momentum to raise some funding from some angel investors, and most importantly gave us the confidence that we were truly on to something that can be really valuable for the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since then, Webflow has grown to millions of users, over a hundred thousand customers, and over 200 team members. I still have to pinch myself when I see that Webflow has somehow become one of the top YC companies of all time. Out of our customers, tens of thousands use Webflow exclusively to make a living – to run an agency, build websites and light applications, create websites for clients, or for their own startups. Tons of YC startups (e.g. lattice.com, hellosign.com, many many more) now use Webflow to run their marketing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m 1000% convinced that if that HN post did not take off, we would have gone back to our jobs and that early Webflow demo would have been a mere mention on our resumes somewhere. Thousands of people wouldn’t be empowered to build for the web the way they can now. I can’t imagine what that alternate future would be like, and it hinged seemingly on just one submission to this community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this is a very belated, but very huge THANK YOU to HN for being kind to a trio of co-founders who wanted to make something valuable for the world, and were at the end of their rope in many ways. You gave us confidence, hope, encouragement, and a lifeline that got us through the lows of building a startup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you, thank you, thank you!!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=5407499&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=5407499&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 16:36:47 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>callmevlad</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25792719</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The unsettling truth about the ‘Mostly Harmless’ hiker</title>
<link>https://www.wired.com/story/unsettling-truth-mostly-harmless-hiker/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.wired.com/story/unsettling-truth-mostly-harmless-hiker/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;According to Godso, Rodriguez didn’t graduate. But people with computer skills usually don’t have a hard time finding a job. Eventually, he started work at an ecommerce company based in Baton Rouge called Shoppers Choice, where he was recognized by many as the most talented engineer on the team. The company’s codebase is still filled with notations of “VR,” for code that Rodriguez wrote. Marie, who works in IT, told me, “He was a crazy good coder. Except he would always code everything the hardest way possible, kind of like you hired Rembrandt to paint your bathroom. You know it is going to be lit, but over the top.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He wasn’t particularly collaborative, but he would sit down, put on his headphones—&lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.last.fm/user/vaejor/loved&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.last.fm/user/vaejor/loved&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;listening to&lt;/a&gt; Temple of the Dog and Rage Against the Machine—and solve problems. As the problems got more complex, he got more comfortable. He was quiet but not, to his coworkers, perversely so. “If you’re asking me if he is the guy who shows up at the party in a clown suit blasting things out of a cannon, that’s not him,” says a former colleague named Corey Tisdale. “But he would go to holiday parties and not look miserable.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He ate once a day, often pizza from Walmart or lasagna from Pasta Kitchen. He wore black jeans, a black shirt, and a black trench coat. He had long, dark hair almost down to his waist. One day he cut it all off and gave it to Locks of Love. He &lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;http://archive.looneylabs.com/mailing-lists/rabbits/msg02489.html?fbclid=IwAR39ad8xd4ZsxbqlHnH6bg0sVFAI5K8L2kygL_JMBWZm2Pyjj-9dX97hSWA&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;http://archive.looneylabs.com/mailing-lists/rabbits/msg02489.html?fbclid=IwAR39ad8xd4ZsxbqlHnH6bg0sVFAI5K8L2kygL_JMBWZm2Pyjj-9dX97hSWA&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;attended&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.dragoncon.org/&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.dragoncon.org/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Dragon Con&lt;/a&gt;. He appeared to suffer from some mental health issues, but, according to Marie, he refused conventional medicine. “He self-medicated with drinking and chocolate,” she says. He would go on what Marie and other friends called “outages,” where he lay immobile for days, refusing food and all human contact. But eventually he would snap out of it. “He wore his sadness like an extra layer of skin,” Marie recalls. But, she adds, “I truly dug his imperfectly perfect solitary singular self.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this time in Baton Rouge Rodriguez started a relationship that would last for five years. But it ended quite badly. When it was over, the woman he had dated wrote on her Facebook page, “Apartment 950 a month / bills 300 a month / Standing up to the monster that beat you up emotionally and physically for 5 years? Priceless.” After Rodriguez was identified as the hiker, the woman’s mother commented on Facebook, “This man was so abusive to my daughter, he changed her.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His colleagues from that time, learning of his story now, seemed saddened. But not entirely surprised. “He was always very introverted, kept to himself. His jokes were usually obscure,” says a colleague named Keith Parent. “None of this is surprising, except for the fact that, in the end, he died.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I looked for Vance in mid-2017 to hire him to build an app for a client of mine,” says another coworker from Shoppers Choice named David Blazier. “And I would have paid him literally anything he asked. I never found him.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lead-in-text-callout&quot;&gt;In 2013, Rodriguez&lt;/span&gt; moved to New York City. He’d met a woman, whom I’ll call K, in an online chat room. K, who asked for anonymity because of the public obsession about the hiker, was then finishing college in upstate New York. They traveled back and forth to visit each other. As their relationship evolved, they decided to both move to New York City and live together. She was going into fashion and had to be there. He had spent his life in Louisiana and welcomed the change. He’d never seen snow before. At first, he was romantic and sweet. But soon he started to clam up and shut her out. “If something upset him, he would stop talking to me completely. Which can be lonely when you share a 500-square-foot apartment,” she says.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 16:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>spking</dc:creator>
<og:description>His emaciated body was discovered in a tent, just a few miles from a major Florida highway. His identity—and troubled past—were discovered by the internet.</og:description>
<og:image>https://media.wired.com/photos/5ff8e9cafff1735ab957fa1b/191:100/w_1280,c_limit/Identified-Hiker.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>The Unsettling Truth About the ‘Mostly Harmless’ Hiker</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.wired.com/story/unsettling-truth-mostly-harmless-hiker/</og:url>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.wired.com/story/unsettling-truth-mostly-harmless-hiker/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why cancer cells waste so much energy</title>
<link>https://news.mit.edu/2021/cancer-cells-waste-energy-0115</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://news.mit.edu/2021/cancer-cells-waste-energy-0115</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;news-article--content--body--inner&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph paragraph--type--content-block-text paragraph--view-mode--default&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the 1920s, German chemist Otto Warburg discovered that cancer cells don’t metabolize sugar the same way that healthy cells usually do. Since then, scientists have tried to figure out why cancer cells use this alternative pathway, which is much less efficient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MIT biologists have now found a possible answer to this longstanding question. In a study appearing in &lt;em&gt;Molecular&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Cell&lt;/em&gt;, they showed that this metabolic pathway, known as fermentation, helps cells to regenerate large quantities of a molecule called NAD+, which they need to synthesize DNA and other important molecules. Their findings also account for why other types of rapidly proliferating cells, such as immune cells, switch over to fermentation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This has really been a hundred-year-old paradox that many people have tried to explain in different ways,” says Matthew Vander Heiden, an associate professor of biology at MIT and associate director of MIT’s Koch Institute for Integrative Cancer Research. “What we found is that under certain circumstances, cells need to do more of these electron transfer reactions, which require NAD+, in order to make molecules such as DNA.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vander Heiden is the senior author of the new study, and the lead authors are former MIT graduate student and postdoc Alba Luengo PhD ’18 and graduate student Zhaoqi Li.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inefficient metabolism&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fermentation is one way that cells can convert the energy found in sugar to ATP, a chemical that cells use to store energy for all of their needs. However, mammalian cells usually break down sugar using a process called aerobic respiration, which yields much more ATP. Cells typically switch over to fermentation only when they don’t have enough oxygen available to perform aerobic respiration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since Warburg’s discovery, scientists have put forth many theories for why cancer cells switch to the inefficient fermentation pathway. Warburg originally proposed that cancer cells’ mitochondria, where aerobic respiration occurs, might be damaged, but this turned out not to be the case. Other explanations have focused on the possible benefits of producing ATP in a different way, but none of these theories have gained widespread support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this study, the MIT team decided to try to come up with a solution by asking what would happen if they suppressed cancer cells’ ability to perform fermentation. To do that, they treated the cells with a drug that forces them to divert a molecule called pyruvate from the fermentation pathway into the aerobic respiration pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They saw, as others have previously shown, that blocking fermentation slows down cancer cells’ growth. Then, they tried to figure out how to restore the cells’ ability to proliferate, while still blocking fermentation. One approach they tried was to stimulate the cells to produce NAD+, a molecule that helps cells to dispose of the extra electrons that are stripped out when cells make molecules such as DNA and proteins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the researchers treated the cells with a drug that stimulates NAD+ production, they found that the cells started rapidly proliferating again, even though they still couldn’t perform fermentation. This led the researchers to theorize that when cells are growing rapidly, they need NAD+ more than they need ATP. During aerobic respiration, cells produce a great deal of ATP and some NAD+. If cells accumulate more ATP than they can use, respiration slows and production of NAD+ also slows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We hypothesized that when you make both NAD+ and ATP together, if you can't get rid of ATP, it's going to back up the whole system such that you also cannot make NAD+,” Li says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, switching to a less efficient method of producing ATP, which allows the cells to generate more NAD+, actually helps them to grow faster. “If you step back and look at the pathways, what you realize is that fermentation allows you to generate NAD+ in an uncoupled way,” Luengo says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solving the paradox&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers tested this idea in other types of rapidly proliferating cells, including immune cells, and found that blocking fermentation but allowing alternative methods of NAD+ production enabled cells to continue rapidly dividing. They also observed the same phenomenon in nonmammalian cells such as yeast, which perform a different type of fermentation that produces ethanol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Not all proliferating cells have to do this,” Vander Heiden says. “It’s really only cells that are growing very fast. If cells are growing so fast that their demand to make stuff outstrips how much ATP they’re burning, that’s when they flip over into this type of metabolism. So, it solves, in my mind, many of the paradoxes that have existed.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The findings suggest that drugs that force cancer cells to switch back to aerobic respiration instead of fermentation could offer a possible way to treat tumors. Drugs that inhibit NAD+ production could also have a beneficial effect, the researchers say.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The research was funded by the Ludwig Center for Molecular Oncology, the National Science Foundation, the National Institutes of Health, the Howard Hughes Medical Institute, the Medical Research Council, NHS Blood and Transplant, the Novo Nordisk Foundation, the Knut and Alice Wallenberg Foundation, Stand Up 2 Cancer, the Lustgarten Foundation, and the MIT Center for Precision Cancer Medicine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 13:11:22 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>chmaynard</dc:creator>
<og:title>Why cancer cells waste so much energy</og:title>
<og:image>https://news.mit.edu/sites/default/files/images/202101/MIT-Warburg-Effect-01-press.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>MIT biologists have found a possible explanation for the Warburg effect, first seen in cancer cells in the 1920s. They found cancer cells use fermentation, an inefficient metabolic pathway, because it helps them to generate large quantities of a molecule called NAD+, which they need to synthesize DNA and other important molecules.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://news.mit.edu/2021/cancer-cells-waste-energy-0115</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://news.mit.edu/2021/cancer-cells-waste-energy-0115</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>How I hijacked the top-level domain of a sovereign state</title>
<link>https://labs.detectify.com/2021/01/15/how-i-hijacked-the-top-level-domain-of-a-sovereign-state/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://labs.detectify.com/2021/01/15/how-i-hijacked-the-top-level-domain-of-a-sovereign-state/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: This issue has been resolved and the .cd ccTLD no longer sends NS delegations to the compromised domain.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TL;DR: Imagine what could happen if the country-code top-level domain (ccTLD) of a sovereign state fell into the wrong hands. Here’s how I (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/almroot&quot;&gt;@Almroot&lt;/a&gt;) bought the domain name used in the NS delegations for the ccTLD of the Democratic Republic of Congo (.cd) and temporarily took over 50% of all DNS traffic for the TLD that could have been exploited for MITM or other abuse.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; class=&quot;alignnone wp-image-653 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://labs.detectify.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/210114_Labs_DNS_Kongo_Hijack.png&quot; alt=&quot;dns hijack hero labs&quot; width=&quot;2400&quot; height=&quot;1260&quot; srcset=&quot;https://labs.detectify.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/210114_Labs_DNS_Kongo_Hijack.png 2400w, https://labs.detectify.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/210114_Labs_DNS_Kongo_Hijack-300x158.png 300w, https://labs.detectify.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/210114_Labs_DNS_Kongo_Hijack-1024x538.png 1024w, https://labs.detectify.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/210114_Labs_DNS_Kongo_Hijack-768x403.png 768w, https://labs.detectify.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/210114_Labs_DNS_Kongo_Hijack-1536x806.png 1536w, https://labs.detectify.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/210114_Labs_DNS_Kongo_Hijack-2048x1075.png 2048w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 2400px) 100vw, 2400px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‘Twas the week before Christmas 2020 and I decided to run an analysis of all NS records used by all the TLDs globally. However one thing caught my attention. The domain name “scpt-network.com” had the EPP status code “redemptionPeriod”, which meant that someone had failed to renew their domain (pay their invoice?) in time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is quite problematic as the name servers managing &lt;code&gt;.cd&lt;/code&gt; are the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
almroot@x:~$ dig NS +trace cd | grep &quot;cd.&quot;
cd.                     172800  IN      NS      ns-root-5.scpt-network.com.
cd.                     172800  IN      NS      igubu.saix.net.
cd.                     172800  IN      NS      sangoma.saix.net.
cd.                     172800  IN      NS      ns-root-2.scpt-network.com.
cd.                     172800  IN      NS      sabela.saix.net.
cd.                     172800  IN      NS      ns-root-1.scpt-network.com.
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I figured I might as well make a bash script to ping me of any EPP status change of the domain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To my surprise, about a week or so later, I got a ping that the domain had reached status “pendingDelete”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I realized the severity of this.&lt;/strong&gt; The domain name would soon be available for purchase by anyone on the Internet, meaning that the person who gets hold of that domain name would also get the NS capabilities of &lt;code&gt;.cd&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I modified the script, and started probing the registrar on a minute basis for any further status changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the evening of December 30, I got a ping. &lt;strong&gt;I opened my laptop and purchased the domain name to keep it from falling into the wrong hands.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-648&quot; src=&quot;https://labs.detectify.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cd-zone.png&quot; alt=&quot;scpt-network.com CD domain hack&quot; width=&quot;1845&quot; height=&quot;1796&quot; srcset=&quot;https://labs.detectify.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cd-zone.png 1845w, https://labs.detectify.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cd-zone-300x292.png 300w, https://labs.detectify.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cd-zone-1024x997.png 1024w, https://labs.detectify.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cd-zone-768x748.png 768w, https://labs.detectify.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cd-zone-1536x1495.png 1536w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1845px) 100vw, 1845px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the three remaining delegations pointing to SAIX (&lt;a href=&quot;https://saix.net/&quot;&gt;the South African Internet eXchange&lt;/a&gt;) were still working, the TLD remained operable throughout this time (albeit with a slight performance impact on any domain lookups).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I owned &lt;code&gt;&lt;span&gt;scpt-network.com&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;, I could configure any subdomain under the zone at will. If I created a new subdomain (like &lt;code&gt;ns-root-1&lt;/code&gt;) with an A-pointer to IP &lt;code&gt;1.3.3.7&lt;/code&gt;, then &lt;code&gt;1.3.3.7&lt;/code&gt; would get legitimate incoming DNS queries meant for &lt;code&gt;.cd&lt;/code&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;Any DNS response to those queries would be accepted by the caller&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-649&quot; src=&quot;https://labs.detectify.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cd-dns-hijack.png&quot; alt=&quot;cd dns hijack&quot; width=&quot;1280&quot; height=&quot;1211&quot; srcset=&quot;https://labs.detectify.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cd-dns-hijack.png 1280w, https://labs.detectify.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cd-dns-hijack-300x284.png 300w, https://labs.detectify.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cd-dns-hijack-1024x969.png 1024w, https://labs.detectify.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cd-dns-hijack-768x727.png 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1280px) 100vw, 1280px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To not reply would cause the caller to reach a timeout, and the status code SERVFAIL would be assumed. This is good as a SERVFAIL will force the caller to try reaching any other name server (NS record) for the zone (&lt;code&gt;.cd&lt;/code&gt;). That is, the caller would eventually hit one of the legitimate SAIX records and be routed appropriately to the correct destination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Potential impact&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hijacking the country-code top-level domain of a sovereign state has serious negative implications, especially if the domain were to fall into the hands of cybercriminals or a foreign adversary. The Democratic Republic of Congo (DRC) is not a small country. There are roughly &lt;a href=&quot;http://data.un.org/en/iso/cd.html&quot;&gt;90 million people&lt;/a&gt;, not to mention many international companies and organizations operating with a &lt;code&gt;.cd&lt;/code&gt; website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DNS hijacking involving the TLD of an entire country is rare but not unheard of. For example, the ccTLD of the former &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2013/may/31/ussr-cybercriminals-su-domain-space&quot;&gt;Soviet Union (.su)&lt;/a&gt; has been hijacked by cybercriminals in the past, and the Lenovo and Google websites for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pcworld.com/article/2889392/like-google-in-vietnam-lenovo-tripped-up-by-a-dns-attack.html&quot;&gt;Vietnam (.vn)&lt;/a&gt; also fell prey to DNS hijacking in 2015. Redirecting DNS traffic from legitimate &lt;code&gt;.cd&lt;/code&gt; websites to a phishing site is one clear potential for abuse, but there’s more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I had operated with malicious intent, I could have also:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Passively intercepted DNS traffic&lt;span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;– which could be used for surveillance or data exfiltration&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Made new domain names “out of thin air”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;– imagine the capabilities if leveraged for &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fast_flux&quot;&gt;Fast Fluxing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Launched remote code execution (RCE) attacks on local networks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;– and target companies that use WPAD to query public DNS servers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Replied to legitimate DNS queries with bogus DNS responses&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;– and completely took over targeted apex domains for companies or institutions with a &lt;code&gt;.cd&lt;/code&gt; website or even launched a DDoS attack.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;For example, I could have crafted an exploit that completely hijacked a specific apex domain under &lt;code&gt;.cd&lt;/code&gt;. Let’s imagine that I always reply with NS &lt;code&gt;ns-root-1.scpt-network.com&lt;/code&gt; (instead of these four: &lt;code&gt;[ns1,ns2,n3,ns4].google.com&lt;/code&gt;) for any NS requests to &lt;code&gt;google.cd&lt;/code&gt;. Now the caller will see this, and then carry out any subsequent DNS requests to &lt;code&gt;ns-root-1.scpt-network.com&lt;/code&gt; which I control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This also got me thinking, what if I replied to all NS queries with a reference back to myself. Then for any A question replied with &lt;code&gt;1.3.3.7&lt;/code&gt;, all domain lookups for any apex or subdomain would eventually hit my manipulated A pointer. All subsequent network traffic would then be redirected to &lt;code&gt;1.3.3.7&lt;/code&gt; and lead in a &lt;strong&gt;DDoS&lt;/strong&gt; attack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In fact, this would also affect the availability of the entire TLD. 50% of the DNS traffic would become faulty, and the impact of (both) DoS attacks could be amplified by setting a high TTL in the DNS replies.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taking this a step further, say I were to explicitly target TXT records served for &lt;code&gt;google.cd&lt;/code&gt;. Then I would be able to abuse the Let’s Encrypts &lt;a href=&quot;https://letsencrypt.org/docs/challenge-types/#dns-01-challenge&quot;&gt;DNS-01 challenge&lt;/a&gt; to issue a valid certificate for &lt;code&gt;google.cd&lt;/code&gt; and effectively &lt;strong&gt;undermine SSL/TLS&lt;/strong&gt; communications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I could control the NS delegations of any &lt;code&gt;.cd&lt;/code&gt; apex domain, and &lt;strong&gt;get valid certificates&lt;/strong&gt;, I would have been able to perform a &lt;a href=&quot;https://labs.detectify.com/2018/11/29/abuse-mitm-regardless-of-https/&quot;&gt;MITM&lt;/a&gt; attack even when SSL/TLS is enforced by the target.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Google has various counter measures and mitigations for this kind of abuse, it’s safe to say this is not the case for &lt;em&gt;all apex domain names&lt;/em&gt; under &lt;code&gt;.cd&lt;/code&gt;. Further information on how CA’s verify the ownership of domain names can be found in &lt;a href=&quot;https://cabforum.org/wp-content/uploads/CA-Browser-Forum-BR-1.7.3.pdf&quot;&gt;BR 1.7.3&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last but not least, with privileged access on an upstream host with DNS control, I could even &lt;strong&gt;infiltrate the local networks of companies&lt;/strong&gt; (redacted in screenshot below) that send DNS lookups for WPAD by monitoring their queries, spoofing a reply, and redirecting the local network caller to download and &lt;strong&gt;execute malicious JS-based proxy configuration over the Internet&lt;/strong&gt;. The WPAD protocol has had its share of issues, including RCE vulnerabilities as discussed by &lt;a href=&quot;https://googleprojectzero.blogspot.com/2017/12/apacolypse-now-exploiting-windows-10-in_18.html&quot;&gt;Google’s Project Zero&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-650&quot; src=&quot;https://labs.detectify.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/wpad-dns-hijack.png&quot; alt=&quot;wpad dns hijack&quot; width=&quot;1058&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; srcset=&quot;https://labs.detectify.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/wpad-dns-hijack.png 1058w, https://labs.detectify.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/wpad-dns-hijack-300x142.png 300w, https://labs.detectify.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/wpad-dns-hijack-1024x484.png 1024w, https://labs.detectify.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/wpad-dns-hijack-768x363.png 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1058px) 100vw, 1058px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Mitigation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On January 7th, I reached out to the Administrative and Technical contacts listed for &lt;code&gt;.cd&lt;/code&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.iana.org/domains/root/db/cd.html&quot;&gt;IANA’s webpage&lt;/a&gt;. My initial thought was to transfer back the ownership of the domain name to the entity operating &lt;code&gt;.cd&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although one of the contacts replied and delegated to their colleague, as of this writing, I haven’t received any follow-up confirmation that they fixed the issue. Nonetheless, the issue seems to have been patched shortly after I contacted them as the DNS traffic I previously controlled for &lt;code&gt;.cd&lt;/code&gt; has since been redirected to &lt;code&gt;scpt-network&lt;span&gt;.net&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also submitted a report on January 8th to the Internet Bug Bounty on HackerOne, and I’m looking forward to seeing how they respond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The potential implications for DNS hijacking of a ccTLD are widespread and have extreme negative consequences, especially if the attacker has bad intentions. This vulnerability affects more than a single website, &lt;a href=&quot;https://labs.detectify.com/2014/10/21/hostile-subdomain-takeover-using-herokugithubdesk-more/&quot;&gt;subdomain&lt;/a&gt;, or even a single apex domain. All &lt;code&gt;.cd&lt;/code&gt; websites, including those for major international companies, financial institutions, and other organizations that have a &lt;code&gt;.cd&lt;/code&gt; domain in Africa’s second most populous country could have fallen victim to abuse, including phishing, MITM, or DDoS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of this writing, I still own the domain name for &lt;code&gt;scpt-network.com&lt;/code&gt; although NS delegations from the ccTLD &lt;code&gt;.cd&lt;/code&gt; seemed to have stopped around January 8, 2021 after I reached out to the ccTLD contacts on January 7th. I did this to prevent malicious actors from hijacking the ccTLD of the Democratic Republic of Congo within the narrow window of time the domain name for one of the name servers managing the &lt;code&gt;.cd&lt;/code&gt; TLD could’ve been taken over by anyone. Luckily, in this case, no damage appears to have been done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How can companies benefit from ethical hacker security research? &lt;a href=&quot;https://detectify.com/crowdsource/crowdsource-for-companies&quot;&gt;Find out here!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interested in joining me in the Detectify Crowdsource ethical hacker community? Take our challenge and find out if you got what it takes at &lt;a href=&quot;https://cs.detectify.com/apply&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;https://cs.detectify.com/apply.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 12:24:27 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Berg0X00</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>How I hijacked the top-level domain of a sovereign state | Detectify Labs</og:title>
<og:description>Here’s how I temporariliy took over 50% of all DNS traffic for the TLD of the Democratic Republic of Congo.</og:description>
<og:url>https://labs.detectify.com/2021/01/15/how-i-hijacked-the-top-level-domain-of-a-sovereign-state/</og:url>
<og:image>https://labs.detectify.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/210114_Labs_DNS_Kongo_Hijack.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://labs.detectify.com/2021/01/15/how-i-hijacked-the-top-level-domain-of-a-sovereign-state/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Tell HN: Dropbox now requires access to contacts for Google login</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25789603</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25789603</guid>
<description>&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.58823529411765&quot;&gt;&lt;td bgcolor=&quot;#FF6600&quot;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr id=&quot;pagespace&quot; title=&quot;Tell HN: Dropbox now requires access to contacts for Google login&quot;&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.109375&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table class=&quot;fatitem&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.6984375&quot;&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing&quot; id=&quot;25789603&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;right&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;title&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25789603&quot; class=&quot;storylink&quot;&gt;Tell HN: Dropbox now requires access to contacts for Google login&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.71052631578947&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;subtext&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;score&quot; id=&quot;score_25789603&quot;&gt;569 points&lt;/span&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/user?id=poxobloc&quot; class=&quot;hnuser&quot;&gt;poxobloc&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;age&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25789603&quot;&gt;13 hours ago&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span id=&quot;unv_25789603&quot;/&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/hide?id=25789603&amp;amp;goto=item%3Fid%3D25789603&quot;&gt;hide&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://hn.algolia.com/?query=Tell%20HN%3A%20Dropbox%20now%20requires%20access%20to%20contacts%20for%20Google%20login&amp;amp;sort=byDate&amp;amp;dateRange=all&amp;amp;type=story&amp;amp;storyText=false&amp;amp;prefix&amp;amp;page=0&quot; class=&quot;hnpast&quot;&gt;past&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/fave?id=25789603&amp;amp;auth=b7f4daff66994eb946b90388b94e5a79f6062abe&quot;&gt;favorite&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25789603&quot;&gt;354 comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;I remember I was using Google login to login to my Dropbox and in the last year or so Dropbox started asking me to access my contacts in Google. I would always deny access and still manage to successfully login. Yesterday I tried the same but with no luck. I contacted Dropbox support and this is their reply:
&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; I'm afraid that is not possible at the time. I apologize for any inconvenience this may cause.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interesting that they chose this route when users are getting more and more privacy-aware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td&gt;

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.71604938271605&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;yclinks&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/newsguidelines.html&quot;&gt;Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/newsfaq.html&quot;&gt;FAQ&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/lists&quot;&gt;Lists&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/HackerNews/API&quot;&gt;API&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/security.html&quot;&gt;Security&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ycombinator.com/legal/&quot;&gt;Legal&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ycombinator.com/apply/&quot;&gt;Apply to YC&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:hn@ycombinator.com&quot;&gt;Contact&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 11:27:47 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>poxobloc</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25789603</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Bit Short: Inside Crypto’s Doomsday Machine</title>
<link>https://crypto-anonymous-2021.medium.com/the-bit-short-inside-cryptos-doomsday-machine-f8dcf78a64d3</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://crypto-anonymous-2021.medium.com/the-bit-short-inside-cryptos-doomsday-machine-f8dcf78a64d3</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;cs&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;n cf go gp gq&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;o n&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener&quot; href=&quot;https://crypto-anonymous-2021.medium.com/?source=post_page-----f8dcf78a64d3--------------------------------&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Crypto Anonymous&quot; class=&quot;s gr gs gt&quot; src=&quot;https://miro.medium.com/fit/c/56/56/1*X9n8NIN4NQdsxqUaB03rNQ.png&quot; width=&quot;28&quot; height=&quot;28&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p id=&quot;5c2e&quot; class=&quot;hx hy fr hz b ia ib ic id ie if ig ih ii ij ik il im in io ip iq ir is it iu di gn&quot;&gt;This is the story of a Bitcoin trade — the most financially impactful trade I’ve ever made in my life. It’s also the story of the deep-yet-frantic investigation of the crypto ecosystem that led me to &lt;em class=&quot;iv&quot;&gt;make&lt;/em&gt; that trade. And it’s the story of what’s really going on in crypto — and what we should do about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;68be&quot; class=&quot;hx hy fr hz b ia ib ic id ie if ig ih ii ij ik il im in io ip iq ir is it iu di gn&quot;&gt;If you own meaningful amounts of cryptocurrency or you’re considering buying some, you’re the reason I wrote this. Please do read to the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p id=&quot;591a&quot; class=&quot;hx hy fr hz b ia js ic id ie jt ig ih ii ju ik il im jv io ip iq jw is it iu di gn&quot;&gt;Before I begin this story, there’s a bit of background you need to know first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;6f4d&quot; class=&quot;hx hy fr hz b ia ib ic id ie if ig ih ii ij ik il im in io ip iq ir is it iu di gn&quot;&gt;The&lt;span id=&quot;rmm&quot;&gt;r&lt;/span&gt;e are things in crypto right now called &lt;strong class=&quot;hz cv&quot;&gt;Tethers&lt;/strong&gt;. To simplify a bit, Tethers are issued by a crypto company called &lt;a href=&quot;https://tether.to/&quot; class=&quot;do jx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;Tether Ltd.&lt;/a&gt; — meaning that if Tether Ltd. says you own a Tether, then you do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;5198&quot; class=&quot;hx hy fr hz b ia ib ic id ie if ig ih ii ij ik il im in io ip iq ir is it iu di gn&quot;&gt;Tether Ltd. also says one Tether is worth exactly one US dollar. Can they do that? Well they say they can, because &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-10-14/why-crypto-traders-are-so-worried-about-tether-quicktake-q-a&quot; class=&quot;do jx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;they hold $1 worth of assets for each Tether&lt;/a&gt;. But are those assets &lt;em class=&quot;iv&quot;&gt;actual&lt;/em&gt; dollars? &lt;a href=&quot;http://media.kalzumeus.com/tether-docs/bitfinex-response-to-nyag.pdf&quot; class=&quot;do jx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;No, they are not&lt;/a&gt;. So what if the assets go down in value? &lt;a href=&quot;https://equity.guru/2020/12/30/the-bitcoin-bubble-is-tether-too-big-to-fail/&quot; class=&quot;do jx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;Don’t worry; they will not&lt;/a&gt;. Okay, but can we at least see the assets? &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coindesk.com/tether-confirms-relationship-auditor-dissolved&quot; class=&quot;do jx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;No, you may not&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;5163&quot; class=&quot;hx hy fr hz b ia ib ic id ie if ig ih ii ij ik il im in io ip iq ir is it iu di gn&quot;&gt;Who in their right mind would &lt;em class=&quot;iv&quot;&gt;use&lt;/em&gt; something like Tether? Well, the short answer is that many people use Tethers to buy Bitcoin and other cryptocurrencies. The long answer, though, is &lt;em class=&quot;iv&quot;&gt;astounding&lt;/em&gt; — but more on that later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;92d0&quot; class=&quot;hx hy fr hz b ia ib ic id ie if ig ih ii ij ik il im in io ip iq ir is it iu di gn&quot;&gt;Because Tether sounds exactly like a currency fraud, it may not surprise you to learn that Tether Ltd. is &lt;a href=&quot;https://ag.ny.gov/press-release/2019/attorney-general-james-announces-court-order-against-crypto-currency-company&quot; class=&quot;do jx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;currently under investigation&lt;/a&gt; by the Office of the Attorney General for the Southern District of New York. That investigation was announced to the public on April 25th, 2019.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p id=&quot;92f3&quot; class=&quot;hx hy fr hz b ia js ic id ie jt ig ih ii ju ik il im jv io ip iq jw is it iu di gn&quot;&gt;Now fast-forward one year. In March of 2020, I bought a large amount of Bitcoin. At the time, I saw a market dislocation and the likelihood of significant dollar inflation due to the US Government’s likely response to the unfolding pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;8ad8&quot; class=&quot;hx hy fr hz b ia ib ic id ie if ig ih ii ij ik il im in io ip iq ir is it iu di gn&quot;&gt;I suspected Bitcoin would be inflation-resistant because of its enforced scarcity. To the extent that I thought about Tether at all, I remembered the OAG’s investigation, assumed Tether was now old news and would surely have been pulled from the markets, and dismissed it as a factor in my buying decision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;e113&quot; class=&quot;hx hy fr hz b ia ib ic id ie if ig ih ii ij ik il im in io ip iq ir is it iu di gn&quot;&gt;That was a huge mistake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p id=&quot;463d&quot; class=&quot;hx hy fr hz b ia js ic id ie jt ig ih ii ju ik il im jv io ip iq jw is it iu di gn&quot;&gt;For the rest of 2020, my inflationary thesis looked right. Unrest in the United States, combined with anticipated high levels of lending and consumer spending post-pandemic, seemed likely to fuel substantial USD inflation in real terms through the end of 2021. During the same period, &lt;a href=&quot;https://decrypt.co/resources/gbtc-everything-you-need-to-know-about-the-grayscale-bitcoin-trust&quot; class=&quot;do jx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;Bitcoin was becoming increasingly scarce on a secular basis&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;6fb6&quot; class=&quot;hx hy fr hz b ia ib ic id ie if ig ih ii ij ik il im in io ip iq ir is it iu di gn&quot;&gt;The market appeared to agree with my thesis. My Bitcoin position doubled in value, then doubled again. By the end of the year I was sitting on a 600% gain, and decently wealthy in nominal dollars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;f3c2&quot; class=&quot;hx hy fr hz b ia ib ic id ie if ig ih ii ij ik il im in io ip iq ir is it iu di gn&quot;&gt;I had intended to hold my Bitcoin for the very long term — it never even crossed my mind to sell it, regardless of its day-to-day price variations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;5e05&quot; class=&quot;hx hy fr hz b ia ib ic id ie if ig ih ii ij ik il im in io ip iq ir is it iu di gn&quot;&gt;And then, in early January, a forum post caught my eye.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p id=&quot;2fd5&quot; class=&quot;hx hy fr hz b ia js ic id ie jt ig ih ii ju ik il im jv io ip iq jw is it iu di gn&quot;&gt;On January 8th, I saw &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25683586&quot; class=&quot;do jx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;this post&lt;/a&gt; on Hacker News about Tether manipulating the price of Bitcoin. That shook me: I’d assumed Tether had been purged from the crypto markets, yet apparently it was still around. But how much Tether could there really be in the crypto markets? Surely not that much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;72b7&quot; class=&quot;hx hy fr hz b ia ib ic id ie if ig ih ii ij ik il im in io ip iq ir is it iu di gn&quot;&gt;Still, I took a look. The answer, I was surprised to see, was &lt;em class=&quot;iv&quot;&gt;a lot&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

Source: Coinlib &lt;a href=&quot;https://coinlib.io/coin/BTC/Bitcoin&quot; class=&quot;do jx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;BTC&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;p id=&quot;498d&quot; class=&quot;hx hy fr hz b ia ib ic id ie if ig ih ii ij ik il im in io ip iq ir is it iu di gn&quot;&gt;The left-hand side of this chart shows which currencies are flowing &lt;em class=&quot;iv&quot;&gt;into&lt;/em&gt; Bitcoin (that is, are being used to buy Bitcoin) across all crypto exchanges. The right-hand side shows which currencies are flowing &lt;em class=&quot;iv&quot;&gt;out&lt;/em&gt; of Bitcoin (that is, that Bitcoin is being used to buy). The chart is showing typical numbers for early January 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;a64a&quot; class=&quot;hx hy fr hz b ia ib ic id ie if ig ih ii ij ik il im in io ip iq ir is it iu di gn&quot;&gt;The upshot: over two-thirds of all Bitcoin — $10 billion worth of it — that was bought in the previous 24 hours, was being purchased with Tethers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;5f2c&quot; class=&quot;hx hy fr hz b ia ib ic id ie if ig ih ii ij ik il im in io ip iq ir is it iu di gn&quot;&gt;What’s more, this pattern wasn’t unique to Bitcoin. I saw the same thing for all the other popular cryptocurrencies:&lt;/p&gt;

Source: Coinlib &lt;a href=&quot;https://coinlib.io/coin/ETH/Ethereum&quot; class=&quot;do jx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;ETH&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://coinlib.io/coin/LTC/Litecoin&quot; class=&quot;do jx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;LTC&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://coinlib.io/coin/ADA/Cardano&quot; class=&quot;do jx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;ADA&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://coinlib.io/coin/BCH/Bitcoin+Cash&quot; class=&quot;do jx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;BCH&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;p id=&quot;079b&quot; class=&quot;hx hy fr hz b ia ib ic id ie if ig ih ii ij ik il im in io ip iq ir is it iu di gn&quot;&gt;It seemed I’d been wrong to dismiss Tether. Tether wasn’t just &lt;em class=&quot;iv&quot;&gt;in&lt;/em&gt; the crypto markets — Tether &lt;em class=&quot;iv&quot;&gt;was&lt;/em&gt; the crypto markets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p id=&quot;3d6e&quot; class=&quot;hx hy fr hz b ia js ic id ie jt ig ih ii ju ik il im jv io ip iq jw is it iu di gn&quot;&gt;This worried me. Most of my wealth was exposed in the form of Bitcoin, and Bitcoin seemed like it might be exposed to Tether. And Tether’s issuing company was under active investigation. I urgently needed to find out if this risk was real.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;7485&quot; class=&quot;hx hy fr hz b ia ib ic id ie if ig ih ii ij ik il im in io ip iq ir is it iu di gn&quot;&gt;I cleared my schedule and started digging. Right away it was obvious that if Tether flows were partly or wholly fraudulent, that would have a significant effect on the correct market price of Bitcoin. (Even though $10B of Tether flows only constitutes 1.4% of Bitcoin’s $700B nominal market cap, all that really matters is what fraction of Bitcoin’s &lt;em class=&quot;iv&quot;&gt;daily buying volume&lt;/em&gt; Tether accounts for — and &lt;em class=&quot;iv&quot;&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; number is closer to 70%.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;98ff&quot; class=&quot;hx hy fr hz b ia ib ic id ie if ig ih ii ij ik il im in io ip iq ir is it iu di gn&quot;&gt;How could I find out if Tether was fraudulent? One quick proxy might be what kinds of exchanges it traded on. I knew that some exchanges, like &lt;a href=&quot;http://coinbase.com/&quot; class=&quot;do jx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;Coinbase&lt;/a&gt;, used solid due diligence to curb money laundering, while many other exchanges weren’t as well-run. Was there a pattern to which exchanges supported Tether and which didn’t?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;00a9&quot; class=&quot;hx hy fr hz b ia ib ic id ie if ig ih ii ij ik il im in io ip iq ir is it iu di gn&quot;&gt;There was. Here’s how crypto trades flow through Coinbase Pro in a typical 24-hour period:&lt;/p&gt;

Source: Coinlib &lt;a href=&quot;https://coinlib.io/exchange/coinbase%20pro&quot; class=&quot;do jx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;Coinbase Pro&lt;/a&gt; data.
&lt;p id=&quot;e6d8&quot; class=&quot;hx hy fr hz b ia ib ic id ie if ig ih ii ij ik il im in io ip iq ir is it iu di gn&quot;&gt;Notice that the money going &lt;em class=&quot;iv&quot;&gt;into&lt;/em&gt; crypto is almost all dollars, Euros and British pounds — currencies that are subject to rigorous controls by their countries’ respective authorities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;6625&quot; class=&quot;hx hy fr hz b ia ib ic id ie if ig ih ii ij ik il im in io ip iq ir is it iu di gn&quot;&gt;And here are the flows of crypto trades through &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.binance.com/&quot; class=&quot;do jx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;Binance&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bitz.ai/&quot; class=&quot;do jx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;Bit-Z&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://hitbtc.com/&quot; class=&quot;do jx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;HitBTC&lt;/a&gt; — the &lt;a href=&quot;https://coinlib.io/exchanges&quot; class=&quot;do jx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;three biggest crypto exchanges&lt;/a&gt; in the world by nominal volume:&lt;/p&gt;

Source: Coinlib &lt;a href=&quot;https://coinlib.io/exchange/binance&quot; class=&quot;do jx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;Binance&lt;/a&gt; data. (Note: Excludes &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.binance.us/&quot; class=&quot;do jx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;Binance US&lt;/a&gt;.)

Source: Coinlib &lt;a href=&quot;https://coinlib.io/exchange/bit-z&quot; class=&quot;do jx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;Bit-Z&lt;/a&gt; data.

Source: Coinlib &lt;a href=&quot;https://coinlib.io/exchange/hitbtc&quot; class=&quot;do jx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;HitBTC&lt;/a&gt; data.
&lt;p id=&quot;cdbd&quot; class=&quot;hx hy fr hz b ia ib ic id ie if ig ih ii ij ik il im in io ip iq ir is it iu di gn&quot;&gt;The pattern was obvious. Practically &lt;em class=&quot;iv&quot;&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; the crypto sold on these three exchanges was being bought with Tethers. None at all was being bought with USD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;7249&quot; class=&quot;hx hy fr hz b ia ib ic id ie if ig ih ii ij ik il im in io ip iq ir is it iu di gn&quot;&gt;And the volumes were huge. Coinbase Pro is &lt;a href=&quot;https://coinmarketcap.com/exchanges/coinbase-pro/&quot; class=&quot;do jx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;responsible&lt;/a&gt; for around $4B in crypto trades each day. But Binance &lt;em class=&quot;iv&quot;&gt;alone&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://coinmarketcap.com/exchanges/binance/&quot; class=&quot;do jx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;accounts&lt;/a&gt; for over &lt;strong class=&quot;hz cv&quot;&gt;$50B&lt;/strong&gt; worth of crypto volume, and &lt;em class=&quot;iv&quot;&gt;each&lt;/em&gt; of the other two exchanges is bigger than Coinbase. &lt;em class=&quot;iv&quot;&gt;Most of the crypto that gets bought each day, is getting traded for Tethers on those three exchanges&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;67a5&quot; class=&quot;hx hy fr hz b ia ib ic id ie if ig ih ii ij ik il im in io ip iq ir is it iu di gn&quot;&gt;Binance, Bit-Z and HitBTC are “unbanked” exchanges. That means they don’t have direct access to the US financial system — most likely because no US institution is willing to serve as their &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.investopedia.com/terms/c/correspondent-bank.asp&quot; class=&quot;do jx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;correspondent bank&lt;/a&gt; domestically. (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.binance.us/&quot; class=&quot;do jx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;Binance US&lt;/a&gt;, an affiliate of Binance, does allow dollar purchases. But its daily volume is only &lt;a href=&quot;https://coinmarketcap.com/exchanges/binance-us/&quot; class=&quot;do jx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;10%&lt;/a&gt; that of Coinbase — and less than 1% that of its offshore counterpart — so its effect on the crypto markets is negligible.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;2d07&quot; class=&quot;hx hy fr hz b ia ib ic id ie if ig ih ii ij ik il im in io ip iq ir is it iu di gn&quot;&gt;It’s hard for crypto exchanges to get banked, but Coinbase, Bitstamp, and several other high-quality exchanges manage it by maintaining strong know-your-customer (KYC) and anti-money-laundering (AML) controls internally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;ac31&quot; class=&quot;hx hy fr hz b ia ib ic id ie if ig ih ii ij ik il im in io ip iq ir is it iu di gn&quot;&gt;But what I found most alarming was that &lt;em class=&quot;iv&quot;&gt;neither&lt;/em&gt; of the two most reputable USD-banked exchanges — Coinbase and Bitstamp — supported Tether trades &lt;em class=&quot;iv&quot;&gt;at all&lt;/em&gt;. If Tether was on the level, there’d be no reason for them to forego the fees on that trading pair — unless their risk and compliance departments had deemed the token too much of a liability to carry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p id=&quot;4c00&quot; class=&quot;hx hy fr hz b ia js ic id ie jt ig ih ii ju ik il im jv io ip iq jw is it iu di gn&quot;&gt;By now, I was concerned that my Bitcoin position might be too risky to hold. But I still needed more evidence before I unwound such a big trade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;9778&quot; class=&quot;hx hy fr hz b ia ib ic id ie if ig ih ii ij ik il im in io ip iq ir is it iu di gn&quot;&gt;I had to get more context on Tether — context that was as free of marketing distortion as possible. I found what I was looking for in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://iapps.courts.state.ny.us/nyscef/DocumentList?docketId=npvulMdOYzFDYIAomW_PLUS_elw==&amp;amp;display=all&quot; class=&quot;do jx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;case docket&lt;/a&gt; for the New York OAG’s ongoing investigation of Tether Ltd. (Note that the inquiry’s respondent is listed as “iFinex Inc., et al” rather than “Tether Ltd.” on the docket, for reasons that aren’t worth getting into here.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;7fea&quot; class=&quot;hx hy fr hz b ia ib ic id ie if ig ih ii ij ik il im in io ip iq ir is it iu di gn&quot;&gt;I’ll skip most of the content — I strongly urge you to review the files for yourself — and just list the three biggest takeaways that jumped out at me:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;li id=&quot;f1ad&quot; class=&quot;hx hy fr hz b ia ib ic id ie if ig ih ii ij ik il im in io ip iq ir is it iu kx ky kz gn&quot;&gt;On &lt;a href=&quot;https://iapps.courts.state.ny.us/nyscef/ViewDocument?docIndex=GknBw4wwWkCUHzib_PLUS_0O4rA==&quot; class=&quot;do jx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;February 26, 2019&lt;/a&gt; — two months before opening its official investigation — the OAG requests a large number of documents from Tether Ltd. The purpose of the request is to help the OAG understand how Tethers are being issued, backed, and accounted for, and how Tethers are flowing through the crypto ecosystem.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;d0c1&quot; class=&quot;hx hy fr hz b ia la ic id ie lb ig ih ii lc ik il im ld io ip iq le is it iu kx ky kz gn&quot;&gt;From the beginning of the official investigation on April 25, 2019, through to July 9, 2020 — a period of nearly 15 (!) months — Tether Ltd. issues a series of legal challenges to the investigation that appear designed to delay their response to the OAG’s document request.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;1c8d&quot; class=&quot;hx hy fr hz b ia la ic id ie lb ig ih ii lc ik il im ld io ip iq le is it iu kx ky kz gn&quot;&gt;On &lt;a href=&quot;https://iapps.courts.state.ny.us/nyscef/ViewDocument?docIndex=W_PLUS_AogKZjvOfCZeMc/4l3PQ==&quot; class=&quot;do jx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;July 9, 2020&lt;/a&gt;, the New York Supreme Court dismisses Tether Ltd.’s final challenge on appeal, effectively forcing Tether Ltd. to comply with the OAG’s document request. What’s more, Justice J. Gesmer’s opinion &lt;em class=&quot;iv&quot;&gt;eviscerates&lt;/em&gt; all aspects of Tether Ltd.’s arguments (good commentary &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/BennettTomlin/status/1335784240047255553&quot; class=&quot;do jx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;), suggesting that Tether Ltd.’s appeal was never intended as a realistic challenge to the documentation request at all. But it could, plausibly, have been part of a strategy to &lt;em class=&quot;iv&quot;&gt;delay&lt;/em&gt; the document disclosure by any possible means.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p id=&quot;3a74&quot; class=&quot;hx hy fr hz b ia ib ic id ie if ig ih ii ij ik il im in io ip iq ir is it iu di gn&quot;&gt;Things were looking bad. But then a question suddenly occurred to me: did any other significant event happen to Tether on or around July 9th, 2020?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;36e9&quot; class=&quot;hx hy fr hz b ia ib ic id ie if ig ih ii ij ik il im in io ip iq ir is it iu di gn&quot;&gt;So I looked. And I found something.&lt;/p&gt;

Source: Coinmarketcap &lt;a href=&quot;https://coinmarketcap.com/currencies/tether/&quot; class=&quot;do jx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;USDT&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;p id=&quot;af00&quot; class=&quot;hx hy fr hz b ia ib ic id ie if ig ih ii ij ik il im in io ip iq ir is it iu di gn&quot;&gt;The chart above shows the market cap of all issued Tethers between January 13, 2019 and January 13, 2021 (the blue curve). Because one Tether nominally equals $1, the total market cap of Tether in dollars is always equal to the total number of Tethers. (The numbers on the y-axis don’t refer to the market cap. But for scale, the highest point of the blue curve corresponds to about $25B.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;d79a&quot; class=&quot;hx hy fr hz b ia ib ic id ie if ig ih ii ij ik il im in io ip iq ir is it iu di gn&quot;&gt;The first red arrow on the chart points to &lt;strong class=&quot;hz cv&quot;&gt;April 25th, 2019&lt;/strong&gt;: the announcement of the OAG’s investigation. Notice how, as the investigation progresses, the issuance rate of Tether begins to rise — initially in large single blocks, of around $1B, every few months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;e38c&quot; class=&quot;hx hy fr hz b ia ib ic id ie if ig ih ii ij ik il im in io ip iq ir is it iu di gn&quot;&gt;The second arrow on the chart is &lt;strong class=&quot;hz cv&quot;&gt;July 9th, 2020&lt;/strong&gt;: the date of the New York court ruling forcing Tether Ltd. to begin the process of disclosing its documents to the OAG. Two weeks after that ruling, Tether Ltd. issues one more large block of Tethers, nominally worth about $800M. And shortly after that — on September 1st — the issuance pattern for Tethers changes completely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;2f28&quot; class=&quot;hx hy fr hz b ia ib ic id ie if ig ih ii ij ik il im in io ip iq ir is it iu di gn&quot;&gt;Beginning in September, Tether Ltd. begins to issue multiple large blocks of Tethers &lt;em class=&quot;iv&quot;&gt;per day&lt;/em&gt;. The pace accelerates, with $2.3 billion worth of Tether issued in the first week of 2021 alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;50c9&quot; class=&quot;hx hy fr hz b ia ib ic id ie if ig ih ii ij ik il im in io ip iq ir is it iu di gn&quot;&gt;This was consistent with the possibility that, as Tether Ltd.’s various legal challenges failed one after another in the New York courts, Tether Ltd. was choosing to issue Tethers faster and faster to maximize the amount of value it could extract from the crypto ecosystem before being shut down. The pace accelerates closer to Tether Ltd.’s final disclosure deadline — &lt;a href=&quot;https://iapps.courts.state.ny.us/nyscef/ViewDocument?docIndex=2AsYgvjJAsSdalpfkInbHA==&quot; class=&quot;do jx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;January 15th, 2021&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;e820&quot; class=&quot;hx hy fr hz b ia ib ic id ie if ig ih ii ij ik il im in io ip iq ir is it iu di gn&quot;&gt;I still needed to answer one last question. Did Tether issuance actually correlate with the price of Bitcoin? A glance at the charts gave me a clear affirmative answer:&lt;/p&gt;

Source: Coinmarketcap &lt;a href=&quot;https://coinmarketcap.com/currencies/bitcoin/&quot; class=&quot;do jx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;BTC&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;p id=&quot;47d7&quot; class=&quot;hx hy fr hz b ia ib ic id ie if ig ih ii ij ik il im in io ip iq ir is it iu di gn&quot;&gt;There are three major periods of high relative Tether issuance on this graph: 1) April 2019 through July 2019; 2) April 2020 through July 2020; and 3) September 2020 through to the present. All three periods overlap with visible increases in Bitcoin’s market price. (The red arrows here point to the same two dates as on the Tether chart above.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;2f08&quot; class=&quot;hx hy fr hz b ia ib ic id ie if ig ih ii ij ik il im in io ip iq ir is it iu di gn&quot;&gt;This wasn’t a conclusive pattern: it still didn’t prove that Tether issuance was &lt;em class=&quot;iv&quot;&gt;causing&lt;/em&gt; Bitcoin’s price increases. It was still possible that retail demand for Bitcoin was driving real USD into Tether Ltd. through some unknown mechanism; that Tether Ltd. was issuing Tethers in exchange for those dollars; and that those issued Tethers were &lt;em class=&quot;iv&quot;&gt;then&lt;/em&gt; being used to buy Bitcoin. Under that scenario, Tether’s rise was &lt;em class=&quot;iv&quot;&gt;being&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em class=&quot;iv&quot;&gt;caused&lt;/em&gt; by Bitcoin’s demand, and Tether might be fully backed by dollars after all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;d24f&quot; class=&quot;hx hy fr hz b ia ib ic id ie if ig ih ii ij ik il im in io ip iq ir is it iu di gn&quot;&gt;Nonetheless, based on this evidence, I concluded my risk was now too great. I was long Bitcoin up to my eyeballs; Bitcoin was clearly correlated with Tether; Tether was clearly being issued at a frantic rate; and that issuance had a high probability of being backed by nothing at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;c77d&quot; class=&quot;hx hy fr hz b ia ib ic id ie if ig ih ii ij ik il im in io ip iq ir is it iu di gn&quot;&gt;I made the call: it was time to get out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p id=&quot;2204&quot; class=&quot;hx hy fr hz b ia js ic id ie jt ig ih ii ju ik il im jv io ip iq jw is it iu di gn&quot;&gt;On January 9th, 2021, I liquidated my crypto position for USD. In the process, I locked in a dollar-denominated gain that — in the interest of full disclosure — I can only describe as life-changing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;12a9&quot; class=&quot;hx hy fr hz b ia ib ic id ie if ig ih ii ij ik il im in io ip iq ir is it iu di gn&quot;&gt;At this point, I still didn’t grasp the entire picture. For example, I still thought there was a &lt;em class=&quot;iv&quot;&gt;chance&lt;/em&gt; Tether could be backed by real assets. My state of belief was something like: “Of the 70% of Tether flows into Bitcoin, some fraction is real; some fraction is real-but-illicit (e.g., buying drugs); and some fraction is pure fiction. I have no clue what the respective fractions of each are, but I do know that my personal risk threshold has been exceeded.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;c78f&quot; class=&quot;hx hy fr hz b ia ib ic id ie if ig ih ii ij ik il im in io ip iq ir is it iu di gn&quot;&gt;I was still a bit concerned that I’d miscalculated. Tether might yet be largely real — and if it turned out it was, I’d have missed the boat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;4942&quot; class=&quot;hx hy fr hz b ia ib ic id ie if ig ih ii ij ik il im in io ip iq ir is it iu di gn&quot;&gt;And then, by pure luck, I had a conversation that blew my mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p id=&quot;213c&quot; class=&quot;hx hy fr hz b ia js ic id ie jt ig ih ii ju ik il im jv io ip iq jw is it iu di gn&quot;&gt;I was catching up with my friend Bob (pseudonym) over video chat. I’d just sold my Bitcoin position and was nervously awaiting confirmation from my bank that my USD wire transfer out of the exchange had cleared. Crypto was on my mind, so I asked Bob about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;319c&quot; class=&quot;hx hy fr hz b ia ib ic id ie if ig ih ii ij ik il im in io ip iq ir is it iu di gn&quot;&gt;The conversation went something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;a13a&quot; class=&quot;hx hy fr hz b ia ib ic id ie if ig ih ii ij ik il im in io ip iq ir is it iu di gn&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;hz cv&quot;&gt;Me:&lt;/strong&gt; You don’t own any crypto do you? I’m concerned some of the exchanges in the ecosystem might be fraudulent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;4e35&quot; class=&quot;hx hy fr hz b ia ib ic id ie if ig ih ii ij ik il im in io ip iq ir is it iu di gn&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;hz cv&quot;&gt;Bob:&lt;/strong&gt; I actually have a whole bunch of crypto on this exchange called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bybit.com/&quot; class=&quot;do jx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;Bybit&lt;/a&gt;. Do you know if that’s one of the risky ones?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;e2af&quot; class=&quot;hx hy fr hz b ia ib ic id ie if ig ih ii ij ik il im in io ip iq ir is it iu di gn&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;hz cv&quot;&gt;Me:&lt;/strong&gt; I’m not sure. Does it let you trade in USD?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;6b8e&quot; class=&quot;hx hy fr hz b ia ib ic id ie if ig ih ii ij ik il im in io ip iq ir is it iu di gn&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;hz cv&quot;&gt;Bob:&lt;/strong&gt; No, but a lot of other exchanges don’t either. In fact, you can’t even deposit USD directly into a Bybit account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;9365&quot; class=&quot;hx hy fr hz b ia ib ic id ie if ig ih ii ij ik il im in io ip iq ir is it iu di gn&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;hz cv&quot;&gt;Me:&lt;/strong&gt; Really? But then how do you get your money onto their exchange at all if they don’t accept USD deposits?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;5810&quot; class=&quot;hx hy fr hz b ia ib ic id ie if ig ih ii ij ik il im in io ip iq ir is it iu di gn&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;hz cv&quot;&gt;Bob:&lt;/strong&gt; You send your USD to Coinbase and buy Bitcoin with it. Then you move your Bitcoin onto Bybit and trade with it there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;aa8c&quot; class=&quot;hx hy fr hz b ia ib ic id ie if ig ih ii ij ik il im in io ip iq ir is it iu di gn&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;hz cv&quot;&gt;Me:&lt;/strong&gt; Hang on. If that’s the case, then why would anybody ever use an unbanked offshore exchange that trades purely in crypto? What does Bybit offer you that Coinbase doesn’t?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;6bc1&quot; class=&quot;hx hy fr hz b ia ib ic id ie if ig ih ii ij ik il im in io ip iq ir is it iu di gn&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;hz cv&quot;&gt;Bob:&lt;/strong&gt; Leverage. I personally only use 2–3X leverage, but they let you leverage your positions up to 100X if you want. You can’t do that on Coinbase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;7abd&quot; class=&quot;hx hy fr hz b ia ib ic id ie if ig ih ii ij ik il im in io ip iq ir is it iu di gn&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;hz cv&quot;&gt;Me:&lt;/strong&gt; *Gasps audibly*&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;7d34&quot; class=&quot;hx hy fr hz b ia ib ic id ie if ig ih ii ij ik il im in io ip iq ir is it iu di gn&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;hz cv&quot;&gt;Bob:&lt;/strong&gt; They also do a ton of promotions. They’ve got a bunch of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bybit.com/en-US/wsot_planet/&quot; class=&quot;do jx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;timed missions&lt;/a&gt; where you can earn Tethers for doing stuff like inviting friends onto the exchange, joining their Telegram group, or trading on their platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;20b9&quot; class=&quot;hx hy fr hz b ia ib ic id ie if ig ih ii ij ik il im in io ip iq ir is it iu di gn&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;hz cv&quot;&gt;Me:&lt;/strong&gt; HOLY $#!@&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;e80f&quot; class=&quot;hx hy fr hz b ia ib ic id ie if ig ih ii ij ik il im in io ip iq ir is it iu di gn&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;hz cv&quot;&gt;Bob:&lt;/strong&gt; But thanks for the warning! I’ll pull my crypto out as quick as I can. It might take me a few minutes though, I’ll need to fire up my VPN first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;dd4c&quot; class=&quot;hx hy fr hz b ia ib ic id ie if ig ih ii ij ik il im in io ip iq ir is it iu di gn&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;hz cv&quot;&gt;Me:&lt;/strong&gt; A VPN? But why, for the love of God?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;ac47&quot; class=&quot;hx hy fr hz b ia ib ic id ie if ig ih ii ij ik il im in io ip iq ir is it iu di gn&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;hz cv&quot;&gt;Bob:&lt;/strong&gt; Because I need to spoof a Bolivian ISP to access the exchange. They’re illegal to use if you’re based in America.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;d2ef&quot; class=&quot;hx hy fr hz b ia ib ic id ie if ig ih ii ij ik il im in io ip iq ir is it iu di gn&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;hz cv&quot;&gt;Me:&lt;/strong&gt; *Head explodes*&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 08:35:12 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>tim333</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>The Bit Short: Inside Crypto’s Doomsday Machine</og:title>
<og:description>This is the story of a Bitcoin trade — the most financially impactful trade I’ve ever made in my life. It’s also the story of the…</og:description>
<og:url>https://crypto-anonymous-2021.medium.com/the-bit-short-inside-cryptos-doomsday-machine-f8dcf78a64d3</og:url>
<og:image>https://miro.medium.com/max/546/1*OgRN5NjsgNder22o8WCO-g.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://crypto-anonymous-2021.medium.com/the-bit-short-inside-cryptos-doomsday-machine-f8dcf78a64d3</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>