<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>“Illegal” Lego Builds (2006) [pdf]</title>
<link>http://bramlambrecht.com/tmp/jamieberard-brickstress-bf06.pdf</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://bramlambrecht.com/tmp/jamieberard-brickstress-bf06.pdf</guid>
<description>&lt;a href=&quot;http://bramlambrecht.com/tmp/jamieberard-brickstress-bf06.pdf&quot;&gt;Download PDF&lt;/a&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2019 00:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>nvr219</dc:creator>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://bramlambrecht.com/tmp/jamieberard-brickstress-bf06.pdf</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Chevy Volt discontinued: Chevrolet&amp;#039;s last Volt rolls off the assembly line</title>
<link>https://www.cbsnews.com/news/chevy-volt-discontinued-chevrolets-last-volt-rolls-off-the-assembly-line/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.cbsnews.com/news/chevy-volt-discontinued-chevrolets-last-volt-rolls-off-the-assembly-line/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;As their company was swirling around the financial drain in the early 2000s, General Motors executives came up with an idea to counter its gas-guzzling image and point the way to transportation of the future: an electric car with a gas-engine backup that could travel anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At Detroit's auto show in 2007, they unveiled the Chevrolet Volt concept car, not knowing yet whether they had the technology to pull off a major breakthrough in battery-powered vehicles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It took nearly four more years, but the first Volt — a longer-range version of a plug-in hybrid — rolled off the assembly line late in 2010. GM had hopes that customers would be ready for a car that could go 38 miles on electricity before a small internal combustion generator kicked in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They weren't. On Tuesday, the last Volt was built with little ceremony at a Detroit factory that's now slated to close. Sales averaged less than 20,000 per year, not enough to sustain the costly undertaking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Volt wasn't the first electric car, but it was the first to conquer anxiety over range at a reasonable cost. GM's limited-range EV1 came out in the 1990s, and Tesla put out its 200-plus-mile Roadster in 2008 for more than $100,000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Plug-in hybrids&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Volt was among the first plug-in hybrids, many of which can go only 20 or so miles on electricity and haven't gained much popularity among consumers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet the Volt did serve a purpose. It led to advances in lithium-ion batteries similar to those that power smart phones and computers. But such advances ultimately led to the Volt's demise as GM and other manufacturers developed fully electric vehicles that can go 200 more miles per charge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;While it was a financial loser, it did what was intended,&quot; said retired GM Vice Chairman Bob Lutz, who shepherded the Volt into production. &quot;We viewed it as a stepping stone to full electrics, which were totally out of reach due to the then-astronomical cost of lithium-ion batteries.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GM now has the Chevrolet Bolt, which can go 238 miles on a single charge, and it has promised many more electric vehicles in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Volt did develop a loyal fan base, many of whom are upset with the company for scrubbing the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Richard Winters, a 65-year-old physician from Poteau, Oklahoma, said the Volt still is useful in areas like Oklahoma and Arkansas where electric vehicle charging stations are few. He bought his first Volt in 2016 for the 120-mile round-trip commute from home to the Arkansas hospital where he works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He bought another one last year, a revamped model that can go 50 miles on electricity before the gas generator starts. Because he can recharge at work, most of his commute is done on battery power. Winters routinely goes 1,400 miles between gas station fill-ups, which he likes. And it costs only around $1 worth of electricity to charge the battery, he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Winters had always wanted an electric car, but like many, was afraid he'd run out of juice and get stranded. &quot;When the Volt came out I was happy,&quot; he said of its nearly unlimited range.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GM, he said, should have spent more to promote the car. &quot;I've been really surprised at the lack of marketing,&quot; he said. &quot;I would not have an electric car if I did not have that gas engine.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Scaled-back project&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Originally, the Volt was to be a sleek, futuristic five-seat vehicle built to hold a battery and a new three-cylinder engine to generate electricity, said Navigant Research analyst Sam Abuelsamid. But because of GM's financial problems, the project was scaled back and became a modified version of the Chevrolet Cruze compact car with only four seats and many parts from other GM vehicles, he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;They made some huge strides with that car, but it wasn't all that it could have been and certainly not what they envisioned when they unveiled the concept,&quot; Abuelsamid said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although it would be nice to continue producing the Volt, GM needed to stop making it due in part to changing consumer preferences for SUVs, he said. The company also lost money on every Volt, cash that is needed for research on autonomous vehicles and more advanced electric cars, he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;It's not the right vehicle for the market today,&quot; said Abuelsamid. &quot;It doesn't really make sense to keep it going. As much as you'd like to, it's probably better to let it go.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2019 00:09:20 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>curtis</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.cbsnews.com/news/chevy-volt-discontinued-chevrolets-last-volt-rolls-off-the-assembly-line/</og:url>
<og:title>Chevy Volt discontinued: Chevrolet's last Volt rolls off the assembly line</og:title>
<og:description>The last Chevrolet Volt was built on Tuesday, ending a decade-long quest to make a breakthrough battery-powered car</og:description>
<og:image>https://cbsnews3.cbsistatic.com/hub/i/r/2010/07/27/822c8501-a642-11e2-a3f0-029118418759/thumbnail/1200x630/fb319b4a5bbd3435faa88d74e08486a5/volt..jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.cbsnews.com/news/chevy-volt-discontinued-chevrolets-last-volt-rolls-off-the-assembly-line/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>C++20 Design Is Complete: Modules, Coroutines in C++20</title>
<link>https://www.reddit.com/r/cpp/comments/au0c4x/201902_kona_iso_c_committee_trip_report_c20/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.reddit.com/r/cpp/comments/au0c4x/201902_kona_iso_c_committee_trip_report_c20/</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;The ISO C++ Committee met in Kona, Hawaii 🏄‍♂️ 🌊 🇺🇸 last week to finalize the feature set for the next International Standard (IS), C++20. &lt;strong class=&quot;s90z9tc-14 juBaow&quot;&gt;The design of C++20 is now feature complete&lt;/strong&gt;. At the upcoming July 2019 meeting in Cologne 🇩🇪, we’ll finish the specification for C++20 and send out a Committee Draft for review.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;This week, we added the following features to the C++20 draft:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;The following features have been approved for C++20, either at this meeting or a prior meeting, but have not been added to C++20 yet because we're still completing the specification. Hopefully they'll be added at the July 2019 Cologne 🇩🇪 meeting, but we may not get to everything due to time constraints.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;The following notable features have been approved for C++20 at prior meetings:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;s90z9tc-15 kRPwUl&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;s90z9tc-14 juBaow&quot;&gt;TL;DR: C++20 may well be as big a release as C++11.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://wg21.link/N4766&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;s90z9tc-14 juBaow&quot;&gt;The Reflection Technical Specification Version 1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong class=&quot;s90z9tc-14 juBaow&quot;&gt;is now finalized and will be sent for publication.&lt;/strong&gt; At the &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/cpp/comments/8prqzm/2018_rapperswil_iso_c_committee_trip_report/&quot;&gt;June 2018 Rapperswil meeting&lt;/a&gt; earlier this year, we sent a draft out for national body balloting and feedback (&quot;beta testing&quot;). This week, we reviewed their feedback (86 individual comments) and finalized the TS. While we expect a major update to improve the compile time programming model used (by moving towards a &lt;code class=&quot;s90z9tc-7 cMUrmP&quot;&gt;constexpr&lt;/code&gt; model instead of type-based metaprogramming), this TS will help encourage early implementation and usage experiments to verify and improve the underlying technology and designs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;The Tooling Study Group, SG15, has decided to explore creating a &lt;strong class=&quot;s90z9tc-14 juBaow&quot;&gt;a C++ Ecosystem Technical Report&lt;/strong&gt;, which will describe the best practices and state of the art for tools (build systems, etc) in the new modular C++ world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;s90z9tc-6 jgOjch&quot;/&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;s90z9tc-6 jgOjch&quot;/&gt;&lt;h3 class=&quot;s90z9tc-2 kErgRC&quot;&gt;Evolution Working Group Incubator (EWGI) Progress&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;The evolution incubator’s goal is to help EWG get higher quality papers. To that end, we saw 27 papers over 3 days:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;s90z9tc-12 drWKKm&quot; readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;s90z9tc-11 irlrft&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;Forwarded 5 to EWG.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;s90z9tc-11 irlrft&quot; readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;2 were sent to other groups to get feedback (will be seen again by EWGI).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;s90z9tc-11 irlrft&quot; readability=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;3 had no consensus to move forward (we recorded objections, authors know what would get people to change their mind).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;s90z9tc-11 irlrft&quot; readability=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;Other papers got feedback, some need input from other groups, they'll be seen again by EWGI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;s90z9tc-11 irlrft&quot; readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;7 in the backlog (down from 27).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;hr class=&quot;s90z9tc-6 jgOjch&quot;/&gt;&lt;h3 class=&quot;s90z9tc-2 kErgRC&quot;&gt;Evolution Working Group (EWG) Progress&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;s90z9tc-6 jgOjch&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;At the last meeting, EWG finalized the feature set for C++20. At Kona, we focused on finalizing those features:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;s90z9tc-12 drWKKm&quot; readability=&quot;4.0314341846758&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;s90z9tc-11 irlrft&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;Contracts: We worked on refining the feature. The only change this meeting was renaming &lt;code class=&quot;s90z9tc-7 cMUrmP&quot;&gt;expects&lt;/code&gt;/&lt;code class=&quot;s90z9tc-7 cMUrmP&quot;&gt;ensures&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code class=&quot;s90z9tc-7 cMUrmP&quot;&gt;pre&lt;/code&gt;/&lt;code class=&quot;s90z9tc-7 cMUrmP&quot;&gt;post&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;s90z9tc-11 irlrft&quot; readability=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;Modules: Through the heroic efforts of some committee members, we fixed internal linkage escaping modules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;s90z9tc-11 irlrft&quot; readability=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;Coroutines: We looked at all of the various coroutines proposals, and held an educational evening session. EWG decided once again to move forward with the TS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;s90z9tc-11 irlrft&quot; readability=&quot;0.57936507936508&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;s90z9tc-7 cMUrmP&quot;&gt;operator &amp;lt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;: We looked at &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://wg21.link/p1186r1&quot;&gt;a proposal for making adoption of &lt;code class=&quot;s90z9tc-7 cMUrmP&quot;&gt;operator &amp;lt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; easier&lt;/a&gt;, and sent it to CWG with minor modifications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;We also fixed some &lt;code class=&quot;s90z9tc-7 cMUrmP&quot;&gt;char8_t&lt;/code&gt; breakage, and sent &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://wg21.link/P1152R1&quot;&gt;the proposal for deprecating some uses of &lt;code class=&quot;s90z9tc-7 cMUrmP&quot;&gt;volatile&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to CWG for inclusion in C++20 (with minor changes).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;s90z9tc-2 kErgRC&quot;&gt;Language Wording Group (CWG) Progress&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;s90z9tc-6 jgOjch&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;CWG focused on completing the specification for C++20 language features and responding to the National Body comments for the Reflection TS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;We spent a lot of the week working on &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://wg21.link/P1103&quot;&gt;the merged modules paper&lt;/a&gt; so that it would be ready for a vote this week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;s90z9tc-6 jgOjch&quot;/&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;s90z9tc-6 jgOjch&quot;/&gt;&lt;h3 class=&quot;s90z9tc-2 kErgRC&quot;&gt;Library Evolution Working Group Incubator (LEWGI) Progress&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;s90z9tc-6 jgOjch&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;This week, LEWGI primarily focused on post C++20 work:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;s90z9tc-12 drWKKm&quot; readability=&quot;20.703082747431&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;s90z9tc-11 irlrft&quot; readability=&quot;7.1189427312775&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;The Numerics TS (new number types, etc): &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://wg21.link/P4038&quot;&gt;P4038&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://wg21.link/P1438&quot;&gt;P1438&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://wg21.link/P0828&quot;&gt;P0828&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://wg21.link/P0037&quot;&gt;P0037&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://wg21.link/&quot;&gt;P0554&lt;/a&gt;, . We really like the basic design of the new composable arithmetic types, although we want to make sure we focus on the most important ones for the TS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;s90z9tc-11 irlrft&quot; readability=&quot;0.49049429657795&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;Linear Algebra. We had an evening session where we discussed &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://wg21.link/P1417&quot;&gt;the history of C++ linear algebra libraries and requirements for a standard linear algebra library&lt;/a&gt;. We also spent some time providing early library design review to &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://wg21.link/P1385&quot;&gt;one concrete linear algebra proposal&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;s90z9tc-11 irlrft&quot; readability=&quot;4.8768472906404&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://wg21.link/P1386&quot;&gt;Audio&lt;/a&gt;. As with linear algebra, there was an evening session on audio to discuss the history, motivation, and use cases, and we also spent some time providing early library design feedback to the authors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;s90z9tc-11 irlrft&quot; readability=&quot;1.8071428571429&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://wg21.link/P0829&quot;&gt;Freestanding Reorganization&lt;/a&gt;. This large paper proposes bringing more parts of the standard library into freestanding. We discussed how this should be done; in particular, how do we deal with standard library types that can only be partially supported in freestanding environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;s90z9tc-11 irlrft&quot; readability=&quot;3.8610038610039&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://wg21.link/P0959&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;s90z9tc-7 cMUrmP&quot;&gt;std::uuid&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. This is the second time that LEWGI has seen this paper. Last time, we decided we definitely wanted to pursue it, so now we're focusing on refining the design. At this meeting, we discussed possible security concerns relating to older UUID variants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;s90z9tc-11 irlrft&quot; readability=&quot;2.8552631578947&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://wg21.link/P0447&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;s90z9tc-7 cMUrmP&quot;&gt;std::colony&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. We took another look at this paper, which proposes a new container useful for managing the lifetime of a collection of objects. We still haven't committed to pursuing it, but we're still interested in learning more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;s90z9tc-11 irlrft&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;The Concurrency TS v2: &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://wg21.link/P0260&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;s90z9tc-7 cMUrmP&quot;&gt;std::buffer_queue&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://wg21.link/P0261&quot;&gt;Distributed Counters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;s90z9tc-11 irlrft&quot; readability=&quot;0.65454545454545&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;Text/Strings: &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://wg21.link/P1433&quot;&gt;Compile Time Regular Expressions&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://wg21.link/P1228&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;s90z9tc-7 cMUrmP&quot;&gt;std::concat&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://wg21.link/P1479&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;s90z9tc-7 cMUrmP&quot;&gt;std::ostringstream&lt;/code&gt; Wrapper&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://wg21.link/P1402&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;s90z9tc-7 cMUrmP&quot;&gt;std::cstring_view&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;s90z9tc-11 irlrft&quot; readability=&quot;0.52631578947368&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;Ranges Enhancements and Fixes: &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://wg21.link/P1456&quot;&gt;Making &lt;em class=&quot;s90z9tc-15 kRPwUl&quot;&gt;View&lt;/em&gt; only require &lt;em class=&quot;s90z9tc-15 kRPwUl&quot;&gt;Moveable&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://wg21.link/P1474&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;s90z9tc-7 cMUrmP&quot;&gt;std::to_address&lt;/code&gt; for &lt;em class=&quot;s90z9tc-15 kRPwUl&quot;&gt;ContiguousIterator&lt;/em&gt;s&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://wg21.link/P1419&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;s90z9tc-7 cMUrmP&quot;&gt;std::ranges::static_extent&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;s90z9tc-11 irlrft&quot; readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;Networking TS Enhancements and Fixes: &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://wg21.link/P1100&quot;&gt;P1100&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://wg21.link/P1145&quot;&gt;P1145&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://wg21.link/P1133&quot;&gt;P1133&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://wg21.link/P1322&quot;&gt;P1322&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://wg21.link/P1442&quot;&gt;P1442&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3 class=&quot;s90z9tc-2 kErgRC&quot;&gt;Library Evolution Working Group (LEWG) Progress&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;s90z9tc-6 jgOjch&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;At this meeting, LEWG completed the design of the C++20 standard library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;LEWG spent a lot of time this week looking at papers that address the deployment of &lt;code class=&quot;s90z9tc-7 cMUrmP&quot;&gt;operator&amp;lt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; into the standard library: &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://wg21.link/P0891&quot;&gt;P0891&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://wg21.link/P0790&quot;&gt;P0790&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://wg21.link/P1189&quot;&gt;P1189&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;LEWG also discussed the &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://wg21.link/P1453&quot;&gt;options for modularizing the standard library in C++20&lt;/a&gt;. We decided that for C++20, the best option is to make it possible for traditional &lt;code class=&quot;s90z9tc-7 cMUrmP&quot;&gt;#include&lt;/code&gt;s to be transparently treated as module imports, and to make each standard library header importable. E.g. in C++20, you can &lt;code class=&quot;s90z9tc-7 cMUrmP&quot;&gt;import &amp;lt;vector&amp;gt;;&lt;/code&gt; - and of course you can still &lt;code class=&quot;s90z9tc-7 cMUrmP&quot;&gt;#include &amp;lt;vector&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;. In the future, we plan to reorganize the standard library and expose new standard library modules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;Also, we revisited adding sized counts to the standard library, and decided to add a free &lt;code class=&quot;s90z9tc-7 cMUrmP&quot;&gt;ssize&lt;/code&gt; function to get the size of a container or span as a signed type. &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://wg21.link/P1227&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;s90z9tc-7 cMUrmP&quot;&gt;std::span&lt;/code&gt; now matches the containers in that &lt;code class=&quot;s90z9tc-7 cMUrmP&quot;&gt;size&lt;/code&gt; returns an unsigned value&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;Finally, LEWG continued looking at &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://wg21.link/P0443&quot;&gt;executors&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://wg21.link/P1393&quot;&gt;properties&lt;/a&gt;. We decided that we need more time to refine properties, so both features are being retargeted for C++23, instead of C++20.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;s90z9tc-2 kErgRC&quot;&gt;Library Wording Group (LWG) Progress&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;s90z9tc-6 jgOjch&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;LWG continued working on the specification for the C++20 standard library. There's still a lot of work left to do at the next meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;At this meeting, LWG continued working on &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://wg21.link/P1135&quot;&gt;the C++20 synchronization library&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://wg21.link/P0429&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;s90z9tc-7 cMUrmP&quot;&gt;std::flatmap&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://wg21.link/P0645&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;s90z9tc-7 cMUrmP&quot;&gt;std::format&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. These should make it into C++20, but they won't be ready until Cologne.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;We also spent a lot of time working on a series of papers (&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://wg21.link/P1458&quot;&gt;P1458&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://wg21.link/P1459&quot;&gt;P1459&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://wg21.link/P1462&quot;&gt;P1462&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://wg21.link/P1463&quot;&gt;P1463&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://wg21.link/P1464&quot;&gt;P1464&lt;/a&gt;) that applies &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://wg21.link/P0788&quot;&gt;the new guidance on specifying type requirements, preconditions, and postconditions in the standard library&lt;/a&gt;. This addresses some of the technical debt we've accumulated over the years and cleans up the specification of the standard library a lot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;s90z9tc-6 jgOjch&quot;/&gt;&lt;h3 class=&quot;s90z9tc-2 kErgRC&quot;&gt;Concurrency and Parallelism Study Group (SG1) Progress&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;s90z9tc-6 jgOjch&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;SG1 met for just four days this week; we had an unusually small number of work items.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;We spent time talking about &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://wg21.link/P0876&quot;&gt;the fibers proposal&lt;/a&gt; and some related proposals (&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://wg21.link/P1364&quot;&gt;P1364&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://wg21.link/P0866&quot;&gt;P0866&lt;/a&gt;). We identified some new issues and implementability concerns; we'll have to do more work at future meetings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;We continued discussing the Concurrency TS v1, which is starting to take shape; its primary content will be &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://wg21.link/P0940&quot;&gt;concurrent data structures and building blocks for data structures&lt;/a&gt;. We discussed &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://wg21.link/P0652&quot;&gt;the proposed concurrent hashmap&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://wg21.link/p1470&quot;&gt;some concerns about it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;We approved the wording for &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://wg21.link/P1152R1&quot;&gt;Deprecating &lt;code class=&quot;s90z9tc-7 cMUrmP&quot;&gt;volatile&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (as did EWG), discussed &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://wg21.link/P1382&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;s90z9tc-7 cMUrmP&quot;&gt;volatile_load&amp;lt;T&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;s90z9tc-7 cMUrmP&quot;&gt;volatile_store&amp;lt;T&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; as follow-up, and &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://wg21.link/P1202&quot;&gt;asymmetric fences&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;We adjourned during LEWG discussions of &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://wg21.link/P0443&quot;&gt;executors&lt;/a&gt; and had some executors discussions of our own, notably &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://wg21.link/p1367&quot;&gt;whether execution agents have thread local storage&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://wg21.link/P1341&quot;&gt;the future of asynchronous interfaces in the C++ standard library&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;s90z9tc-6 jgOjch&quot;/&gt;&lt;h3 class=&quot;s90z9tc-2 kErgRC&quot;&gt;Compile Time Programming and Reflection Study Group (SG7) Progress&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;s90z9tc-6 jgOjch&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;We discussed two reflection paper (&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://wg21.link/P1447&quot;&gt;P1447&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://wg21.link/P0953&quot;&gt;P0953&lt;/a&gt;) and compared their approaches, main differences was the use of multiple types of the reflection object based on &lt;code class=&quot;s90z9tc-7 cMUrmP&quot;&gt;reflexpr&lt;/code&gt; expression and style (free or member functions) of the API. We also pushed forward &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://wg21.link/P1278&quot;&gt;modern &lt;code class=&quot;s90z9tc-7 cMUrmP&quot;&gt;offsetof&lt;/code&gt; replacement&lt;/a&gt; to LEWG.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;Also, the Reflection TS, which came out of SG7, was published at this meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;s90z9tc-6 jgOjch&quot;/&gt;&lt;h3 class=&quot;s90z9tc-2 kErgRC&quot;&gt;Undefined Behavior Study Group (SG12)/Vulnerabilities Working Group (WG23) Progress&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;s90z9tc-6 jgOjch&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;SG12 and WG23 once again met to continue work on documenting security vulnerabilities that the C++ language is susceptible to. Additionally, we started the preliminary work for a new deliverable; an updated revision of the MISRA guidelines that covers C++11, 14, 17 and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;We also discussed &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://wg21.link/P1434&quot;&gt;pointer provenance&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://wg21.link/P1407&quot;&gt;signed integer overflow&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;s90z9tc-6 jgOjch&quot;/&gt;&lt;h3 class=&quot;s90z9tc-2 kErgRC&quot;&gt;I/O Study Group (SG13) Progress&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;s90z9tc-6 jgOjch&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;The study group met for a half-day and discussed &lt;code class=&quot;s90z9tc-7 cMUrmP&quot;&gt;std::audio&lt;/code&gt;. The main discussion centered around the &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://wg21.link/p1386r0&quot;&gt;proposed audio API&lt;/a&gt;. We discussed what the API should look like, which types and containers would be used, and what use cases we’re trying to help. Our intent is to ship an Audio TS. We also discussed &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://wg21.link/P1501R0&quot;&gt;feedback on &lt;code class=&quot;s90z9tc-7 cMUrmP&quot;&gt;std::audio&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which will be available in the post-meeting mailing. The study group also briefly discussed higher-level audio interfaces, for example a facility to play a file to the default output device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;There was no discussion of 2D Graphics: the authors’ focus is currently on the linear algebra subset of that proposal. Linear algebra is being handled by other groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;s90z9tc-6 jgOjch&quot;/&gt;&lt;h3 class=&quot;s90z9tc-2 kErgRC&quot;&gt;Tooling Study Group (SG15) Progress&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;s90z9tc-6 jgOjch&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;First, there's been a change in leadership for SG15: Titus Winters, the original chair, is stepping down. Bryce Adelstein Lelbach will be taking over as the new SG15 chair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;SG15's focus for the near-term future is on modules interactions with the C++ ecosystem (tools, build systems, etc). We had two telecons before Kona and an evening session at Kona to discuss these interactions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;We've decided the best way to proceed is to create &lt;strong class=&quot;s90z9tc-14 juBaow&quot;&gt;a C++ Ecosystem Technical Report&lt;/strong&gt; which explores and describes the best practices and state of the art for modules tooling interactions. A Technical Report is a type of ISO document more similar to an essay or study than a normative specification. For example, take a look at the prior &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;http://www.open-std.org/jtc1/sc22/wg21/docs/TR18015.pdf&quot;&gt;C++ Performance Technical Report&lt;/a&gt;. Note that we used to use a different type of Technical Report (e.g. &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/C%2B%2B_Technical_Report_1&quot;&gt;TR1&lt;/a&gt;) for what we now call Technical Specifications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;s90z9tc-6 jgOjch&quot;/&gt;&lt;h3 class=&quot;s90z9tc-2 kErgRC&quot;&gt;Text Study Group (SG16) Progress&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;s90z9tc-6 jgOjch&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;Two proposals that originated from SG16 were voted into C++20 this week:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;This may come as a surprise to many, but the C++ standard did not previously guarantee that &lt;code class=&quot;s90z9tc-7 cMUrmP&quot;&gt;u&quot;&quot;&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;s90z9tc-7 cMUrmP&quot;&gt;U&quot;&quot;&lt;/code&gt; literals were encoded as UTF-16 and UTF-32 respectively despite the fact that is what every implementation already did. We can now rely on this guarantee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;We discussed the three papers listed below in session.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;s90z9tc-12 drWKKm&quot; readability=&quot;4.1685267857143&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;s90z9tc-11 irlrft&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://wg21.link/P1433&quot;&gt;Compile Time Regular Expressions&lt;/a&gt;: We provided guidance to the author regarding how to align the proposed regular expression support with requirements of &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://www.unicode.org/reports/tr18&quot;&gt;Unicode Technical Standard #18&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;s90z9tc-11 irlrft&quot; readability=&quot;2.702875399361&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://wg21.link/P1208&quot;&gt;Source-Code Information Capture&lt;/a&gt;: We provided guidance regarding the treatment of file names. On some platforms, it is not possible to associate any particular character encoding with file names. We encouraged treating file names as an implementation defined sequence of bytes for the purposes of source locations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;s90z9tc-11 irlrft&quot; readability=&quot;3.4357682619647&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://wg21.link/P1439&quot;&gt;Charset Transcoding, Transformation, and Transliteration&lt;/a&gt;: We gained valuable insight into requirements for interfaces providing transcoding and transliteration services based on long term experience working with legacy and private character encodings. The discussion made it clear that such interfaces must allow extensions if only to allow custom handling for use of the Unicode private use area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;s90z9tc-6 jgOjch&quot;/&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;s90z9tc-6 jgOjch&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;We've scheduled three additional meetings between now and the next full committee meeting to work on specific parts of C++20.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;s90z9tc-15 kRPwUl&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;s90z9tc-14 juBaow&quot;&gt;NOTE: This is a plan not a promise. Treat it as speculative and tentative. See&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://wg21.link/P1000&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;s90z9tc-15 kRPwUl&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;s90z9tc-14 juBaow&quot;&gt;P1000&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em class=&quot;s90z9tc-15 kRPwUl&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;s90z9tc-14 juBaow&quot;&gt;for the latest plan.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;s90z9tc-12 drWKKm&quot; readability=&quot;3.5&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;s90z9tc-11 irlrft&quot; readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;IS = International Standard. The C++ programming language. C++11, C++14, C++17, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;s90z9tc-11 irlrft&quot; readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;TS = Technical Specification. &quot;Feature branches&quot; available on some but not all implementations. Coroutines TS v1, Modules TS v1, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;s90z9tc-11 irlrft&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;CD = Committee Draft. A draft of an IS/TS that is sent out to national standards bodies for review and feedback (&quot;beta testing&quot;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;table class=&quot;s90z9tc-19 iDFCDm&quot;&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;s90z9tc-20 eCOxQD&quot;&gt;&lt;th class=&quot;s90z9tc-25 cmsMXn&quot;&gt;Meeting&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class=&quot;s90z9tc-25 cmsMXn&quot;&gt;Location&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class=&quot;s90z9tc-25 cmsMXn&quot;&gt;Objective&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody readability=&quot;19.5&quot;&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;s90z9tc-20 eCOxQD&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;2017 Summer Meeting&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;Toronto&lt;/del&gt; 🇨🇦&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;First meeting of C++20.&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;s90z9tc-20 eCOxQD&quot; readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;2017 Fall Meeting&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;Albuquerque&lt;/del&gt; 🇺🇸&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;Design major C++20 features.&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;s90z9tc-20 eCOxQD&quot; readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;2018 Spring Meeting&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;Jacksonville&lt;/del&gt; 🇺🇸&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;Design major C++20 features.&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;s90z9tc-20 eCOxQD&quot; readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;2018 Summer Meeting&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;Rapperswil&lt;/del&gt; 🇨🇭&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;Design major C++20 features.&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;s90z9tc-20 eCOxQD&quot; readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;2018 Summer LWG Meeting&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;Chicago&lt;/del&gt; 🇺🇸&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;Work on wording for C++20 features.&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;s90z9tc-20 eCOxQD&quot; readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;2018 Fall EWG Modules Meeting&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;Seattle&lt;/del&gt; 🇺🇸&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;Design modules for C++20.&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;s90z9tc-20 eCOxQD&quot; readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;2018 Fall LEWG/SG1 Executors Meeting&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;Seattle&lt;/del&gt; 🇺🇸&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;Design executors for C++20.&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;s90z9tc-20 eCOxQD&quot; readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;2018 Winter Meeting&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;San Diego&lt;/del&gt; 🇺🇸&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;Major language feature freeze.&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;s90z9tc-20 eCOxQD&quot; readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;s90z9tc-14 juBaow&quot;&gt;2019 Spring Meeting&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;s90z9tc-14 juBaow&quot;&gt;Kona&lt;/strong&gt; 🏄‍♂️ 🌊 🇺🇸&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;s90z9tc-14 juBaow&quot;&gt;Feature freeze. C++20 design is feature-complete.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;s90z9tc-20 eCOxQD&quot; readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;2019 Summer Meeting&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;Cologne 🇩🇪&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;Complete CD wording. Start CD balloting (&quot;beta testing&quot;).&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;s90z9tc-20 eCOxQD&quot; readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;2019 Fall Meeting&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;Belfast 🇬🇧&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;CD ballot comment resolution (&quot;bug fixes&quot;).&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;s90z9tc-20 eCOxQD&quot; readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;2020 Spring Meeting&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;Prague 🇨🇿&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;CD ballot comment resolution (&quot;bug fixes&quot;), C++20 completed.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;s90z9tc-20 eCOxQD&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;2020 Summer Meeting&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;Bulgaria 🇧🇬&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;First meeting of C++23.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;s90z9tc-20 eCOxQD&quot; readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;2020 Fall Meeting&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;s90z9tc-15 kRPwUl&quot;&gt;New York (Tentative) 🇺🇸&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;Design major C++23 features.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;s90z9tc-20 eCOxQD&quot; readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;2021 Winter Meeting&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;Kona 🏄‍♂️ 🌊 🇺🇸&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;Design major C++23 features.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;s90z9tc-20 eCOxQD&quot; readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;2021 Summer Meeting&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;🗺️&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;Design major C++23 features.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;s90z9tc-6 jgOjch&quot;/&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;s90z9tc-6 jgOjch&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;s90z9tc-15 kRPwUl&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;s90z9tc-14 juBaow&quot;&gt;NOTE: This is a plan not a promise. Treat it as speculative and tentative.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;s90z9tc-12 drWKKm&quot; readability=&quot;3.5&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;s90z9tc-11 irlrft&quot; readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;IS = International Standard. The C++ programming language. C++11, C++14, C++17, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;s90z9tc-11 irlrft&quot; readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;TS = Technical Specification. &quot;Feature branches&quot; available on some but not all implementations. Coroutines TS v1, Modules TS v1, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;s90z9tc-11 irlrft&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;CD = Committee Draft. A draft of an IS/TS that is sent out to national standards bodies for review and feedback (&quot;beta testing&quot;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;s90z9tc-14 juBaow&quot;&gt;Changes since last meeting are in bold.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class=&quot;s90z9tc-19 iDFCDm&quot;&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;s90z9tc-20 eCOxQD&quot;&gt;&lt;th class=&quot;s90z9tc-25 cmsMXn&quot;&gt;Feature&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class=&quot;s90z9tc-25 cmsMXn&quot;&gt;Status&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class=&quot;s90z9tc-25 cmsMXn&quot;&gt;Depends On&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class=&quot;s90z9tc-25 cmsMXn&quot;&gt;Current Target (Conservative Estimate)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class=&quot;s90z9tc-25 cmsMXn&quot;&gt;Current Target (Optimistic Estimate)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody readability=&quot;5.9831578947368&quot;&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;s90z9tc-20 eCOxQD&quot; readability=&quot;1.7611940298507&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://en.cppreference.com/w/cpp/language/constraints&quot;&gt;Concepts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;Concepts TS v1 published and merged into C++20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;C++20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;C++20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;s90z9tc-20 eCOxQD&quot; readability=&quot;1.8333333333333&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://en.cppreference.com/w/cpp/experimental/ranges&quot;&gt;Ranges&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;Ranges TS v1 published and merged into C++20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;Concepts&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;C++20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;C++20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;s90z9tc-20 eCOxQD&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://wg21.link/P0542&quot;&gt;Contracts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;Merged into C++20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;C++20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;C++20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;s90z9tc-20 eCOxQD&quot; readability=&quot;1.7307692307692&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://wg21.link/P1103&quot;&gt;Modules&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;Merged design approved for C++20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;C++20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;C++20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;s90z9tc-20 eCOxQD&quot; readability=&quot;1.7183098591549&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://wg21.link/N4723&quot;&gt;Coroutines&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;s90z9tc-14 juBaow&quot;&gt;Coroutines TS v1 published and merged into C++20&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;s90z9tc-14 juBaow&quot;&gt;C++20&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;C++20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;s90z9tc-20 eCOxQD&quot; readability=&quot;1.6949152542373&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://wg21.link/P0443&quot;&gt;Executors&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;s90z9tc-14 juBaow&quot;&gt;Proposed v1 design approved for C++23&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;s90z9tc-14 juBaow&quot;&gt;C++26&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;s90z9tc-14 juBaow&quot;&gt;C++23&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;s90z9tc-20 eCOxQD&quot; readability=&quot;1.6610169491525&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://wg21.link/N4711&quot;&gt;Networking&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;Networking TS v1 published&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;Executors&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;C++26&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;C++23&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;s90z9tc-20 eCOxQD&quot; readability=&quot;1.5918367346939&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://wg21.link/P0194&quot;&gt;Reflection&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;s90z9tc-14 juBaow&quot;&gt;Reflection TS v1 published&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;s90z9tc-14 juBaow&quot;&gt;C++26&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;s90z9tc-21 jruhvq&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;s90z9tc-14 juBaow&quot;&gt;C++23&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/cpp/comments/9vwvbz/2018_san_diego_iso_c_committee_trip_report_ranges/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;s90z9tc-14 juBaow&quot;&gt;Last Meeting's Reddit Trip Report.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;s90z9tc-14 juBaow&quot;&gt;If you have any questions, ask them in this thread!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/u/blelbach&quot;&gt;/u/blelbach&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/u/bigcheesegs&quot;&gt;/u/bigcheesegs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/u/nliber&quot;&gt;/u/nliber&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/u/chandlerc1024&quot;&gt;/u/chandlerc1024&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/u/louis_dionne&quot;&gt;/u/louis_dionne&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/u/je4d&quot;&gt;/u/je4d&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/u/hanickadot&quot;&gt;/u/hanickadot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/u/tahonermann&quot;&gt;/u/tahonermann&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;s90z9tc-27 fvqGYz&quot; href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/u/jfbastien&quot;&gt;/u/jfbastien&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s90z9tc-10 fHRkcP&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;s90z9tc-15 kRPwUl&quot;&gt;and others&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 21:54:49 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ingve</dc:creator>
<og:title>r/cpp - 2019-02 Kona ISO C++ Committee Trip Report (C++20 design is complete; Modules in C++20; Coroutines in C++20; Reflection TS v1 published; work begins on a C++ Ecosystem Technical Report)</og:title>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.reddit.com/r/cpp/comments/au0c4x/201902_kona_iso_c_committee_trip_report_c20/</og:url>
<og:description>357 votes and 292 comments so far on Reddit</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.reddit.com/r/cpp/comments/au0c4x/201902_kona_iso_c_committee_trip_report_c20/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Reinforcement Learning and Optimal Control</title>
<link>http://web.mit.edu/dimitrib/www/RLbook.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://web.mit.edu/dimitrib/www/RLbook.html</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;meta http-equiv=&quot;Content-Type&quot; content=&quot;text/html; charset=UTF-8&quot; /&gt;&lt;title&gt;&lt;/title&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot; readability=&quot;215.5162562754&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://counter.mit.edu/tally&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;by Dimitri P. Bertsekas&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Athena Scientific, 2019&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://web.mit.edu/dimitrib/www/RLCOVER.jpg&quot; width=&quot;190&quot; height=&quot;280&quot; alt=&quot;Cover_RLBOOK_small.jpg&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; border=&quot;2&quot; hspace=&quot;10&quot; vspace=&quot;10&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a draft of a book that is scheduled to be finalized sometime within 2019, and to be published by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.athenasc.com&quot;&gt;Athena Scientific&lt;/a&gt;. It represents &quot;work in progress,&quot; and it will be periodically updated. It more than likely contains errors (hopefully not serious ones). Furthermore, its references to the literature are incomplete. Your comments and suggestions to the author at dimitrib@mit.edu are welcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of the book is to consider large and challenging multistage decision problems, which can be solved in principle by dynamic programming and optimal control, but their exact solution is computationally intractable. We discuss solution methods that rely on approximations to produce suboptimal policies with adequate performance. These methods are collectively referred to as reinforcement learning, and also by alternative names such as approximate dynamic programming, and neuro-dynamic programming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our subject has benefited enormously from the interplay of ideas from optimal control and from artificial intelligence. One of the aims of this monograph is to explore the common boundary between these two fields and to form a bridge that is accessible by workers with background in either field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mathematical style of the book is somewhat different from the author's dynamic programming books, and the neuro-dynamic programming monograph, written jointly with John Tsitsiklis. We rely more on intuitive explanations and less on proof-based insights. Still we provide a rigorous short account of the theory of finite and infinite horizon dynamic programming, and some basic approximation methods, in an appendix. For this we require a modest mathematical background: calculus, elementary probability, and a minimal use of matrix-vector algebra.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The methods of this book have been successful in practice, and often spectacularly so, as evidenced by recent amazing accomplishments in the games of chess and Go. However, across a wide range of problems, their performance properties may be less than solid. This is a reflection of the state of the art in the field: there are no methods that are guaranteed to work for all or even most problems, but there are enough methods to try on a given challenging problem with a reasonable chance that one or more of them will be successful in the end. Accordingly, we have aimed to present a broad range of methods that are based on sound principles, and to provide intuition into their properties, even when these properties do not include a solid performance guarantee. Hopefully, with enough exploration with some of these methods and their variations, the reader will be able to address adequately his/her own problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;h2&gt;BOOK PREFACE, CONTENTS, AND CHAPTERS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click here for &lt;a href=&quot;http://web.mit.edu/dimitrib/www/RL_Frontmatter.pdf&quot;&gt;preface and table of contents.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drafts of book chapters (periodically updated, check for latest versions):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://web.mit.edu/dimitrib/www/RL_MONOGRAPH1.pdf&quot;&gt;Chapter 1: Exact Dynamic Programming&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://web.mit.edu/dimitrib/www/RL_MONOGRAPH2.pdf&quot;&gt;Chapter 2: Approximation in Value Space&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://web.mit.edu/dimitrib/www/RL_MONOGRAPH3.pdf&quot;&gt;Chapter 3: Parametric Approximation&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://web.mit.edu/dimitrib/www/RL_MONOGRAPH4.pdf&quot;&gt;Chapter 4: Infinite Horizon Reinforcement Learning&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://web.mit.edu/dimitrib/www/RL_MONOGRAPH5.pdf&quot;&gt;Chapter 5: Aggregation&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://web.mit.edu/dimitrib/www/RL_Index_Refs.pdf&quot;&gt;References&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click here for a &lt;a href=&quot;http://web.mit.edu/dimitrib/www/Slides_RL_and_Optimal_Control.pdf&quot;&gt;slide overview presentation&lt;/a&gt; from Conference on Decision and Control, Dec. 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;h2&gt;REINFORCEMENT LEARNING COURSE AT ASU: SLIDES AND VIDEO LECTURES&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lecture slides for a course in Reinforcement Learning and Optimal Control (January 8-February 21, 2019), at Arizona State University:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://web.mit.edu/dimitrib/www/Slides_Lecture1_RLOC.pdf&quot;&gt;Slides-Lecture 1&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://web.mit.edu/dimitrib/www/Slides_Lecture2_RLOC.pdf&quot;&gt;Slides-Lecture 2&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://web.mit.edu/dimitrib/www/Slides_Lecture3_RLOC.pdf&quot;&gt;Slides-Lecture 3&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://web.mit.edu/dimitrib/www/Slides_Lecture4_RLOC.pdf&quot;&gt;Slides-Lecture 4&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://web.mit.edu/dimitrib/www/Slides_Lecture5_RLOC.pdf&quot;&gt;Slides-Lecture 5&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://web.mit.edu/dimitrib/www/Slides_Lecture6_RLOC.pdf&quot;&gt;Slides-Lecture 6&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://web.mit.edu/dimitrib/www/Slides_Lecture7_RLOC.pdf&quot;&gt;Slides-Lecture 7&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://web.mit.edu/dimitrib/www/Slides_Lecture8_RLOC.pdf&quot;&gt;Slides-Lecture 8&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://web.mit.edu/dimitrib/www/Slides_Lecture9_RLOC.pdf&quot;&gt;Slides-Lecture 9&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://web.mit.edu/dimitrib/www/Slides_Lecture10_RLOC.pdf&quot;&gt;Slides-Lecture 10&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://web.mit.edu/dimitrib/www/Slides_Lecture11_RLOC.pdf&quot;&gt;Slides-Lecture 11&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://web.mit.edu/dimitrib/www/Slides_Lecture12_RLOC.pdf&quot;&gt;Slides-Lecture 12&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://web.mit.edu/dimitrib/www/Slides_Lecture13_RLOC.pdf&quot;&gt;Slides-Lecture 13&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Videos of lectures from Reinforcement Learning and Optimal Control course at Arizona State University: (Clisk around the screen to see JUST THE VIDEO, or JUST THE SLIDES, or BOTH SIMULTANEOUSLY).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mslgoee.asu.edu/Mediasite/Play/2d63c9507ef1456397ada6716e8523591d&quot;&gt;Video-Lecture 1&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://mslgoee.asu.edu/Mediasite/Play/74cb238e344b4c59872b037d12fd55071d&quot;&gt;Video-Lecture 2&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://mslgoee.asu.edu/Mediasite/Play/64e916f66f904aaf88928ea1db7ed3771d?catalog=7cf46910-2a82-46a8-acdd-754be6ef903e&quot;&gt;Video-Lecture 3&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;a href=&quot;http://mslgoee.asu.edu/Mediasite/Play/13abccaf5116433a9b15dbcbe2ad5d4c1d?catalog=7cf46910-2a82-46a8-acdd-754be6ef903e&quot;&gt;Video-Lecture 4&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://mslgoee.asu.edu/Mediasite/Play/6de16968e3594ef99c69dc6b8831c7d01d?catalog=7cf46910-2a82-46a8-acdd-754be6ef903e&quot;&gt;Video-Lecture 5&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://mslgoee.asu.edu/Mediasite/Play/550d5023d8e547aeb180d3de85156c921d?catalog=7cf46910-2a82-46a8-acdd-754be6ef903e&quot;&gt;Video-Lecture 6&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://mslgoee.asu.edu/Mediasite/Play/ca9bfa4b270648b4bbf7acfdb5b859ce1d&quot;&gt;Video-Lecture 7&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://mslgoee.asu.edu/Mediasite/Play/c213da231ef34a1a960b3aef2eb421b41d?catalog=7cf46910-2a82-46a8-acdd-754be6ef903e&quot;&gt;Video-Lecture 8&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://mslgoee.asu.edu/Mediasite/Play/31661dda1bad463bb0f3b9b9a0188ad91d&quot;&gt;Video-Lecture 9&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://mslgoee.asu.edu/Mediasite/Play/819a954034b745538508df54452f246a1d&quot;&gt;Video-Lecture 10&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://mslgoee.asu.edu/Mediasite/Play/0d4179ce0b784618bd298d9aaeb51d901d&quot;&gt;Video-Lecture 11&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://mslgoee.asu.edu/Mediasite/Play/a26b5e041c854e11aeca3642cd5c89311d&quot;&gt;Video-Lecture 12&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://mslgoee.asu.edu/Mediasite/Play/a91c810a28d240b4a06fa79c505bee021d&quot;&gt;Video-Lecture 13&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lecture 13 is an &lt;a href=&quot;http://web.mit.edu/dimitrib/www/Slides_Lecture13_RLOC.pdf&quot;&gt;overview of the entire course&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Dimitri P. Bertsekas&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The fourth edition (February 2017) contains a substantial amount of new material, particularly on approximate DP in Chapter 6. This chapter was thoroughly reorganized and rewritten, to bring it in line, both with the contents of Vol. II, whose latest edition appeared in 2012, and with recent developments, which have propelled approximate DP to the forefront of attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the highlights of the revision of Chapter 6 are an increased emphasis on one-step and multistep lookahead methods, parametric approximation architectures, neural networks, rollout, and Monte Carlo tree search. Among other applications, these methods have been instrumental in the recent spectacular success of computer Go programs. The material on approximate DP also provides an introduction and some perspective for the more analytically oriented treatment of Vol. II.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click here for direct ordering from the publisher and &lt;a href=&quot;http://athenasc.com/dpbook.html&quot;&gt;preface, table of contents, supplementary educational material, lecture slides, videos, etc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dynamic Programming and Optimal Control, Vol. I, ISBN-13: 978-1-886529-43-4, 576 pp., hardcover, 2017&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Dimitri P. Bertsekas&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The fourth edition of Vol. II of the two-volume DP textbook was published in June 2012. This is a major revision of Vol. II and contains a substantial amount of new material, as well as a reorganization of old material. The length has increased by more than 60% from the third edition, and most of the old material has been restructured and/or revised. Volume II now numbers more than 700 pages and is larger in size than Vol. I. It can arguably be viewed as a new book!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Approximate DP has become the central focal point of this volume, and occupies more than half of the book (the last two chapters, and large parts of Chapters 1-3). Thus one may also view this new edition as a followup of the author's 1996 book &quot;Neuro-Dynamic Programming&quot; (coauthored with John Tsitsiklis). A lot of new material, the outgrowth of research conducted in the six years since the previous edition, has been included.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A new printing of the fourth edition (January 2018) contains some updated material, particularly on undiscounted problems in Chapter 4, and approximate DP in Chapter 6. References were also made to the contents of the 2017 edition of Vol. I, and to high profile developments in deep reinforcement learning, which have brought approximate DP to the forefront of attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dynamic Programming and Optimal Control, Vol. II: Approximate Dynamic Programming, ISBN-13: 978-1-886529-44-1, 712 pp., hardcover, 2012&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;h2&gt;CHAPTER UPDATE - NEW MATERIAL&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click here for an &lt;a href=&quot;http://web.mit.edu/dimitrib/www/DP2_Chapter%204_UPDATED.pdf&quot;&gt;updated version of Chapter 4&lt;/a&gt;, which incorporates recent research on a variety of undiscounted problem topics, including&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Deterministic optimal control and adaptive DP (Sections 4.2 and 4.3).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Stochastic shortest path problems under weak conditions and their relation to positive cost problems (Sections 4.1.4 and 4.4).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Affine monotonic and multiplicative cost models (Section 4.5).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;h2&gt;PREFACE, SLIDES, AND OTHER INFORMATION&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click here for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.athenasc.com/dpbook.html&quot;&gt;preface and detailed information.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click here &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Dynamic-Programming-Optimal-Control-Edition/dp/1886529442/ref=sr_1_16?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1341296960&amp;amp;sr=8-16&amp;amp;keywords=bertsekas+dynamic+programming&quot;&gt;to order at Amazon.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lectures on Exact and Approximate Finite Horizon DP: Videos from a 4-lecture, 4-hour short course at the University of Cyprus on finite horizon DP, Nicosia, 2017. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLhJFJvQl2LfravyApezJ8eDvJfBe_FzLi&quot;&gt;Videos from Youtube.&lt;/a&gt; (Lecture Slides: &lt;a href=&quot;http://web.mit.edu/dimitrib/www/ADP_Cyprus_2017_ONE.pdf&quot;&gt;Lecture 1&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://web.mit.edu/dimitrib/www/ADP_Cyprus_2017_TWO.pdf&quot;&gt;Lecture 2&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://web.mit.edu/dimitrib/www/ADP_Cyprus_2017_THREE.pdf&quot;&gt;Lecture 3&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://web.mit.edu/dimitrib/www/ADP_Cyprus_2017_FOUR.pdf&quot;&gt;Lecture 4&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Videos from a 6-lecture, 12-hour short course at Tsinghua Univ., Beijing, China, 2014. &lt;a href=&quot;http://adpthu2014.weebly.com/videos.html&quot;&gt;From the Tsinghua course site,&lt;/a&gt; and from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLiCLbsFQNFAxOmVeqPhI5er1LGf2-L9I4&quot;&gt;Youtube.&lt;/a&gt; Click here to download &lt;a href=&quot;http://web.mit.edu/dimitrib/www/ADP_Slides_Tsinghua_Complete.pdf&quot;&gt;Approximate Dynamic Programming Lecture slides,&lt;/a&gt; for this 12-hour video course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click here to download &lt;a href=&quot;http://web.mit.edu/dimitrib/www/ADP_Short_Course_Complete.pdf&quot;&gt;lecture slides&lt;/a&gt; for a 7-lecture short course on Approximate Dynamic Programming, Caradache, France, 2012.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click here to download &lt;a href=&quot;http://web.mit.edu/dimitrib/www/DP_Slides_2015.pdf&quot;&gt;lecture slides&lt;/a&gt; for the MIT course &quot;Dynamic Programming and Stochastic Control (6.231), Dec. 2015. The last six lectures cover a lot of the approximate dynamic programming material.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click here to download &lt;a href=&quot;http://web.mit.edu/dimitrib/www/publ.html&quot;&gt;research papers and other material&lt;/a&gt; on Dynamic Programming and Approximate Dynamic Programming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;address&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.mit.edu:8001/cgi/counter/web.mit.edu/dimitrib/dpchapter&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/address&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 19:24:59 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>iron0013</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://web.mit.edu/dimitrib/www/RLbook.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Google Maps: Bird Mode</title>
<link>https://twitter.com/btaylor/status/1099370126678253569</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://twitter.com/btaylor/status/1099370126678253569</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The rule was: the review had to end on time. When the clock ticked zero, the buzzer would buzz, and like an NBA game, the meeting was over and decisions final.

So here we are, throwing out names like “Airplane View,” “Superman,” “I Feel Picture-y,” and this clock is ticking down&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 19:22:05 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>tosh</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://mobile.twitter.com/btaylor/status/1099370126678253569</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>A Famous Photo of Chernobyl’s Most Dangerous Radioactive Material (2016)</title>
<link>https://www.atlasobscura.com/articles/the-famous-photo-of-chernobyls-most-dangerous-radioactive-material-was-a-selfie</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.atlasobscura.com/articles/the-famous-photo-of-chernobyls-most-dangerous-radioactive-material-was-a-selfie</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;article-caption-pre-rd&quot;&gt;Artur Korneyev, Deputy Director of Shelter Object, viewing the “elephants foot” lava flow at Chernobyl, 1996. (Photo: US Department of Energy)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;item-body-text-graf&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;section-start-text&quot;&gt;At first glance, it’s hard&lt;/span&gt; to know what’s happening in this picture. A giant mushroom seems to have sprouted in a factory floor, where ghostly men in hardhats seem to be working.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;item-body-text-graf&quot;&gt;But there’s something undeniably eerie about the scene, for good reason. You’re looking at the largest agglomeration of one of the most toxic substances ever created: corium.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;item-body-text-graf&quot;&gt;In the days and weeks after the Chernobyl nuclear disaster in late April 1986, simply being in the same room as this particular pile of radioactive material—known as the Elephant’s Foot—would have killed you within a couple of minutes. Even a decade later, when this image was taken, the radiation probably caused the film to develop strangely, creating the photo’s grainy quality. The man in this photo, Artur Korneyev, has likely visited this area more than anyone else, and in doing so has been exposed to more radiation than almost anyone in history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;item-body-text-graf&quot;&gt;Remarkably, he’s probably still alive. The story of how the United States got a hold of this singular photo of a human in the presence of this incredibly toxic material is itself fraught with mystery—almost as much as why someone would take what is essentially a selfie with a hunk of molten radiated lava.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;item-body-text-graf&quot;&gt;This picture first came to America in the late 1990s, after the newly independent Ukrainian government took over the plant and set up the Chornobyl Center for Nuclear Safety, Radioactive Waste and Radioecology (spelling often gets changed as words go from Russian to English). Soon after, the center invited other governments to collaborate on nuclear safety projects. The U.S. Department of Energy tapped the Pacific Northwest National Laboratories (PNNL)—a bustling science center up in Richland, Washington—to help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;item-body-text-graf&quot;&gt;At the time, Tim Ledbetter was a relatively new hire in PNNL’s IT department, and he was tasked with creating a digital photo library that the DOE’s International Nuclear Safety Project could use to show its work to the American public (or, at least, to the tiny sliver of the population that was online back then). He had project members take photos while they were in Ukraine, hired a freelance photographer to grab some other shots, and solicited images from Ukrainian colleagues at the Chornobyl Center. Intermixed with &lt;a href=&quot;http://insp.pnnl.gov/-library-uk_ch_1-1.htm&quot;&gt;hundreds of images of awkward bureaucratic handshakes and people in lab coats&lt;/a&gt;, though, are a dozen or so shots from the ruins inside Unit 4, where 10 years before, on April 26, 1986, a reactor had exploded during a test of the plant turbine-generator system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;item-body-text-graf&quot;&gt;As radioactive plumes rose high above the plant, poisoning the area, the rods liquefied below, melting through the reactor vessel to form a substance called corium, perhaps the most toxic stuff on Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;article-image lazy&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.atlasobscura.com/assets/blank-11b9c95a68e295dddd0ea924647536578ce285b2c8469a223c01df1ff3166af1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;auto&quot; data-kind=&quot;article-image&quot; id=&quot;article-image-23642&quot; data-src=&quot;//assets.atlasobscura.com/article_images/23642/image.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;article-caption-pre-rd&quot;&gt;Corium flowing like lava through the reactor. The valve was made for steam to move through. (Photo: &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chernobyl_disaster#/media/File:Chernobyl_lava_flow.jpg&quot;&gt;PNNL library&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;item-body-text-graf&quot;&gt;Corium has been created outside of the lab at least five times, according to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ne.anl.gov/eda/farmer_bio.html&quot;&gt;Mitchell Farmer&lt;/a&gt;, a senior nuclear engineer at Argonne National Laboratory, another Department of Energy center outside of Chicago. Corium formed once at the Three Mile Island reactor in Pennsylvania in 1979, once in Chernobyl, and three separate times during the Fukushima Daiichi meltdown in Japan in 2011. Farmer creates modified versions of corium in the lab in order to better understand how to mitigate accidents in the future. Research on the substance has found, for example, that dumping water on it after it forms actually does stop some fission products from decaying and producing more dangerous isotopes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;item-body-text-graf&quot;&gt;Of the five corium creations, only Cherobyl’s has escaped its containment. With no water to cool the mass, the radioactive sludge moved through the unit &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oecd-nea.org/rp/chernobyl/c01.html&quot;&gt;over the course a week&lt;/a&gt; following the meltdown, taking on molten concrete and sand to go along with the uranium (fuel) and zirconium (cladding) molecules. This poisonous lava flowed downhill, eventually burning through the floor of the building. When nuclear inspectors finally accessed the area several months after the initial explosion, they found that &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tesec-int.org/chernobyl/Radioactive%20waste%20in%20the%20Sarcophagus.htm&quot;&gt;11 tons of it&lt;/a&gt; had settled into a three meter wide grey mass at the corner of a steam distribution corridor below. This, they dubbed the Elephant’s Foot. Over the years, the Elephant’s Foot cooled and cracked. Even today, though, it’s still estimated to be slightly above the ambient temperature as the radioactive material decomposes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;item-body-text-graf&quot;&gt;Ledbetter’s not able to remember exactly where he got these images. He compiled the library almost 20 years ago, and the website on which they were hosted is in rough shape; only thumbnails of the images are left. (Ledbetter, who still works at PNNL, was surprised to learn that any of the site was still publicly accessible.) But he’s sure he didn’t hire someone to take photos of the Elephant’s Foot, so they likely were sent in by a Ukrainian colleague.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;item-body-text-graf&quot;&gt;In 2013, Kyle Hill stumbled across the image, which had been shared several times on the internet in the ensuing years, while writing &lt;a href=&quot;http://nautil.us/blog/chernobyls-hot-mess-the-elephants-foot-is-still-lethal&quot;&gt;a piece about the Elephant’s Foot for &lt;em&gt;Nautilus&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; magazine, and tracked it back to the old PNNL site. Following his lead, I went back there to look for more details. After a little digging through the site’s CSS coding, I was able to locate &lt;a href=&quot;http://insp.pnnl.gov/-library-uk_ch_6.htm&quot;&gt;a long-lost caption for the image&lt;/a&gt;: “Artur Korneev, Deputy Director of Shelter Object, viewing the ‘elephants foot’ lava flow, Chornobyl NPP. Photographer: Unknown. Fall 1996.” Ledbetter confirmed the caption matched the photo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;item-body-text-graf&quot;&gt;Korneev turns out to be an alternate spelling for Korneyev. Artur Korneyev is a dark-humored Kazakhstani nuclear inspector who has been working to educate people about—and protect people from—the Elephant’s Foot since it was first created by the explosion at the Chernobyl nuclear plant in 1986. The last time a reporter spoke to him, as far as I can tell, was in 2014, when &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2014/04/27/science/chernobyl-capping-a-catastrophe.html?_r=0&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt; science reporter Henry Fountain interviewed him in Slavutich&lt;/a&gt;, Ukraine, a city built especially to house the evacuated personnel from Chernobyl.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;article-image lazy&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.atlasobscura.com/assets/blank-11b9c95a68e295dddd0ea924647536578ce285b2c8469a223c01df1ff3166af1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;auto&quot; data-kind=&quot;article-image&quot; id=&quot;article-image-23644&quot; data-src=&quot;//assets.atlasobscura.com/article_images/23644/image.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;article-caption-pre-rd&quot;&gt;A zoomed image of Korneyev&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;item-body-text-graf&quot;&gt;I wasn’t able to locate Korneyev for an interview, but it’s possible to put together clues embedded in the photos to explain the image. I looked through all the other captions of photos similar photos of the destroyed core, and they were all taken by Korneyev, so it’s likely this photo was an old-school timed selfie. The shutter speed was probably a little slower than for the other photos in order for him to get into position, which explains why he seems to be moving and why the glow from his flashlight looks like a lightning flash. The graininess of the photo, though, is likely due to the radiation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;item-body-text-graf&quot;&gt;For Korneyev, this particular trip was only one of hundreds of dangerous missions he’s taken to the core since he first arrived on site in the days following the initial explosion. His initial job was to locate the fuel deposits and help determine their radiation levels. (The Elephant’s Foot initially gave off more than 10,000 roentgens an hour, which would kill a person three feet from it in less than two minutes.) Soon after that, he began leading cleanup efforts, sometimes even kicking pieces of solid fuel out of the way. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.slate.com/articles/health_and_science/explainer/2013/04/chernobyl_death_toll_how_many_cancer_cases_are_caused_by_low_level_radiation.html&quot;&gt;More than 30 workers died from Acute Radiation Syndrome&lt;/a&gt; during the explosion and ensuring cleanup. Despite the incredible amount of exposure, Korneyev kept returning inside the hastily constructed concrete sarcophagus, often with journalists in tow to document the dangers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;item-body-text-graf&quot;&gt;In 2001, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.themoscowtimes.com/arts_n_ideas/article/tmt/367277.html&quot;&gt;he brought a reporter from the &lt;em&gt;Associated Press&lt;/em&gt; back to the core&lt;/a&gt;, where the radiation still measured 800 roentgens an hour. In 2009, Marcel Theroux, the celebrated novelist (and son of writer Paul Theroux and cousin of actor Justin Theroux) &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.travelandleisure.com/articles/alive-in-the-dead-zone&quot;&gt;wrote an article for &lt;em&gt;Travel + Leisure&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; about his trip to the sarcophagus and the mad, maskless guide who mocked Theroux’s anxiety as “purely psychological.” While Theroux refers to him as Viktor Korneyev, it’s likely the man is Artur, as he made the same dark joke he would a few years later in a &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt; article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;item-body-text-graf&quot;&gt;His current status is murky. When the &lt;em&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt; caught up to Korneyev a year and a half ago, he was helping to plan construction of a $1.5 billion arch that, when finished in 2017, will cap the decaying sarcophagus and prevent airborne isotopes from escaping. In his mid 60s, he was sickly, with cataracts, and had been barred from re-entering the sarcophagus after years of irradiation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;item-body-text-graf item-body-last&quot;&gt;Korneyev’s sense of humor remained intact, though. He seemed to have no regrets about his life’s work. “Soviet radiation,” he joked, “is the best radiation in the world.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 15:29:42 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>lelf</dc:creator>
<og:title>The Famous Photo of Chernobyl's Most Dangerous Radioactive Material Was a Selfie</og:title>
<og:url>http://www.atlasobscura.com/articles/the-famous-photo-of-chernobyls-most-dangerous-radioactive-material-was-a-selfie</og:url>
<og:image>https://assets.atlasobscura.com/media/W1siZiIsInVwbG9hZHMvYXNzZXRzL2E5MDQ4ZDE2ZmU3YzUwYjZlM18xOTMxXzE1ZDE4NWVhYTdjOTU0ZTc3ZjUzNDNkOTQxZTI1ZmJkLmpwZyJdLFsicCIsImNvbnZlcnQiLCIiXSxbInAiLCJjb252ZXJ0IiwiLXF1YWxpdHkgODEgLWF1dG8tb3JpZW50Il0sWyJwIiwidGh1bWIiLCI2MDB4PiJdXQ</og:image>
<og:description>At first glance, it’s hard to know what’s happening in this picture. A giant mushroom seems to have sprouted in a factory floor, where ghostly men in...</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.atlasobscura.com/articles/the-famous-photo-of-chernobyls-most-dangerous-radioactive-material-was-a-selfie</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Cleave.js – Format input text content when you are typing</title>
<link>https://nosir.github.io/cleave.js/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://nosir.github.io/cleave.js/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/nosir/cleave.js&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://nosir.github.io/cleave.js/images/right-graphite@2x.png&quot; alt=&quot;Fork me on GitHub&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;header readability=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;title-bar&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cleave.js&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Format your &lt;span class=&quot;input-txt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;span class=&quot;green&quot;&gt;input&lt;/span&gt;/&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; content when you are typing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/header&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;demos&quot;&gt;
&lt;section&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Credit card number formatting&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;demo&quot; readability=&quot;7.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;input-title&quot;&gt;Enter credit card number&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;cards clearfix&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;-2&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;col-right&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Express: starts with &lt;span class=&quot;link-number&quot;&gt;34/37&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;34 &lt;span class=&quot;dots&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;col-right&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VISA: starts with &lt;span class=&quot;link-number&quot;&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4 &lt;span class=&quot;dots&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;-2&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;col-right&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diners Club: starts with &lt;span class=&quot;link-number&quot;&gt;300-305/309...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;300 &lt;span class=&quot;dots&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;-2&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;col-right&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MasterCard: starts with &lt;span class=&quot;link-number&quot;&gt;51-55/22-27&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;51 &lt;span class=&quot;dots&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;-2&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;col-right&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JCB: starts with 35/2131/1800&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;35 &lt;span class=&quot;dots&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;-2&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;col-right&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discover: starts with 6011|65|644-649&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6011 &lt;span class=&quot;dots&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;code&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-javascript&quot;&gt;var cleave = new Cleave('.input-element', {
    creditCard: true,
    onCreditCardTypeChanged: function (type) {
        // update UI ...
    }
});&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Phone number formatting&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;demo&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;input-title&quot;&gt;Enter phone number&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;code code-phone&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-javascript&quot;&gt;var cleave = new Cleave('.input-element', {
    phone: true,
    phoneRegionCode: '{country}'
});&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Date formatting&lt;/h3&gt;


&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Time formatting&lt;/h3&gt;


&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Numeral formatting&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;demo&quot; readability=&quot;7.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;input-title&quot;&gt;Enter numeral&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;numeral-selector selector&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p/&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;select-cover&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Style: thousand&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;arrow&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;input placeholder=&quot;Enter numeral&quot; class=&quot;input-numeral&quot; type=&quot;text&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;code code-numeral&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-javascript&quot;&gt;var cleave = new Cleave('.input-element', {
    numeral: true,
    numeralThousandsGroupStyle: 'thousand'
});&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Custom options&lt;/h3&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;demo&quot; readability=&quot;14.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;input-title&quot;&gt;Delimiter: ['.', '.', '-']&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;code&quot; readability=&quot;16&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-javascript&quot;&gt;var cleave = new Cleave('.input-element', {
    delimiters: ['.', '.', '-'],
    blocks: [3, 3, 3, 2],
    uppercase: true
});&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section&gt;&lt;h3&gt;ReactJS component&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;demo&quot; readability=&quot;8.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;code code-phone&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-javascript&quot;&gt;import React from 'react';
import ReactDOM from 'react-dom';
import Cleave from 'cleave.js/react';

class MyComponent extends React.Component {
    onChange(event) {
        // formatted pretty value
        console.log(event.target.value);

        // raw value
        console.log(event.target.rawValue);
    }

    render() {
        return (
        &amp;lt;Cleave placeholder=&quot;Enter your credit card number&quot;
                options={{creditCard: true}}
                onChange={this.onChange.bind(this)} /&amp;gt;
        );
    }
}
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;btn-try-in&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;Try demo in the playground

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section class=&quot;section-playground&quot;&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Playground&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;see-more&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See more on Github&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 15:15:33 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>octosphere</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-au</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://nosir.github.io/cleave.js/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Toxic ‘Forever Chemicals’ in Drinking Water Leave Military Families Reeling</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/02/22/us/military-water-toxic-chemicals.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2019/02/22/us/military-water-toxic-chemicals.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;FOUNTAIN, Colo. — When Army Staff Sgt. Samuel Fortune returned from Iraq, his body battered by war, he assumed he’d be safe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Then the people around him began to get sick. His neighbors, all living near five military bases, complained of tumors, thyroid problems and debilitating fatigue. Soon, the Colorado health department &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.colorado.gov/pacific/sites/default/files/PFC%20BWCancer_Final.pdf&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; an unusually high number of kidney cancers in the region. Then Mr. Fortune’s wife fell ill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The military, it turned out, had been leaching toxic chemicals into the water for decades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Mr. Fortune felt “stabbed in the back,” he said. “We give our lives and our bodies for our country, and our government does not live up to their end of the deal.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;That was 2016. Since then, the Defense Department has admitted that it allowed a firefighting foam to slip into at least 55 drinking water systems at military bases around the globe, sometimes for generations. This exposed tens of thousands of Americans, possibly many more, to &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.atsdr.cdc.gov/pfas/health-effects.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;per-and&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.atsdr.cdc.gov/pfas/health-effects.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;polyfluoroalkyl&lt;/a&gt; substances, a group of man-made chemicals known as PFAS that have been linked to cancers, immune suppression and other serious health problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;[For more stories about the experiences and costs of war,&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/newsletters/at-war?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;sign up for the weekly At War newsletter&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;.]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Though the presence of the chemicals has been known for years, &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/02/14/climate/epa-chemical-plan-pfas.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;an announcement&lt;/a&gt; last week from the Environmental Protection Agency for the first time promised regulatory action, a significant acknowledgment of the startling scope of the problem that drew outrage from veterans and others living in contaminated communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Acting administrator Andrew Wheeler said that the agency would begin the process of potentially limiting the presence of two of the compounds in drinking water, calling this a “pivotal moment in the history of the agency.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The admission drew some praise, but many said that it was not enough and that millions of people would keep ingesting the substances while a regulatory process plods along. “It should have been called an inaction plan,” said Judith Enck, a former E.P.A. regional administrator appointed by President Barack Obama.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-wrapper&quot; class=&quot;css-79elbk ehw59r11&quot;&gt;

&lt;div data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-children&quot; class=&quot;css-1a48zt4 ehw59r111&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1xdhyk6 erfvjey0&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1tej78p0&quot;&gt;Image&lt;/span&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;css-1m50asq&quot; src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/02/13/us/00water-02alt/merlin_109770922_9717bba1-0425-4ff3-9189-83c02bca43f1-articleLarge.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;auto=webp&amp;amp;disable=upscale&quot; srcset=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/02/13/us/00water-02alt/merlin_109770922_9717bba1-0425-4ff3-9189-83c02bca43f1-articleLarge.jpg?quality=90&amp;amp;auto=webp 600w,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/02/13/us/00water-02alt/merlin_109770922_9717bba1-0425-4ff3-9189-83c02bca43f1-jumbo.jpg?quality=90&amp;amp;auto=webp 1024w,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/02/13/us/00water-02alt/merlin_109770922_9717bba1-0425-4ff3-9189-83c02bca43f1-superJumbo.jpg?quality=90&amp;amp;auto=webp 2048w&quot; sizes=&quot;((min-width: 600px) and (max-width: 1004px)) 84vw, (min-width: 1005px) 60vw, 100vw&quot; itemprop=&quot;url&quot; itemid=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/02/13/us/00water-02alt/merlin_109770922_9717bba1-0425-4ff3-9189-83c02bca43f1-articleLarge.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;auto=webp&amp;amp;disable=upscale&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;css-8i9d0s e13ogyst0&quot;&gt;Volunteers distributed bottled water to residents of Security, Colo., in 2016.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot; class=&quot;css-vuqh7u e1z0qqy90&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1tej78p0&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Matthew Staver for The New York Times&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;While the military has used the chemicals extensively, it is far from the only entity to do so, and in recent years, companies like &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2016/01/10/magazine/the-lawyer-who-became-duponts-worst-nightmare.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;DuPont&lt;/a&gt; have come under fire for leaching PFAS into water systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;All told, 10 million people could be drinking water laced with high levels of PFAS, according to Patrick Breysse, a top official at the federal Centers for Disease Control. Mr. Breysse has &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://news.bloombergenvironment.com/environment-and-energy/cdc-sounds-alarm-on-chemical-contamination-in-drinking-water&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;called&lt;/a&gt; the presence of the chemicals “one of the most seminal public health challenges” of the coming decades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The residents of Fountain, a mountain-flanked suburb of Colorado Springs, were told of the contamination by local officials who had been required by the E.P.A. to test the water for the substances, a step toward possible regulation. Soon dozens of communities from New York to Washington State discovered their drinking water was also polluted with PFAS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Many people began demanding that state and military officials test their blood for the chemicals, hoping to learn the extent of their presence in their bodies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The military has started an expensive cleanup effort that has involved shifting entire municipalities to new water sources and assessing toxic plumes that continue to spread for miles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Maureen Sullivan, the military’s deputy assistant secretary for environment, said the government had moved “aggressively” to tackle the problem, assessing cleanup duties and looking for alternatives to the firefighting foam, a version of which the military &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://theintercept.com/2018/02/10/firefighting-foam-afff-pfos-pfoa-epa/&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;still uses&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“I’m proud of what the Department of Defense has done in the past two-plus years,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;But frustration persists. The military never alerted all of the people who drank polluted water, meaning some are still in the dark. When asked how many people were affected by contamination, Ms. Sullivan said she “couldn’t hazard a guess.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-13nfagi&quot;&gt;
&lt;section id=&quot;colorado-map&quot; data-id=&quot;100000006374645&quot; class=&quot;interactive-embedded interactive-size-scoop custom-graphic-container css-jpvew7 e13l8dds1&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;interactive-graphic custom-graphic css-17ih8de e13l8dds0&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-0223-nat-web-COLORADOmapCLR-box&quot; class=&quot;ai2html ai2html-box-v5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-0223-nat-web-COLORADOmapCLR-300&quot; class=&quot;g-artboard&quot; data-aspect-ratio=&quot;1&quot; data-min-width=&quot;300&quot;&gt;&lt;img id=&quot;g-0223-nat-web-COLORADOmapCLR-300-img&quot; class=&quot;g-aiImg g-aiAbs&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/newsgraphics/2019/02/22/colorado-map/8ad63528f154a14305f366ddf9b2180003d8a5db/0223-nat-web-COLORADOmapCLR-300.jpg&quot; src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhCgAKAIAAAB8fHwAAACH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAAKAAoAAAIIhI+py+0PYysAOw==&quot;/&gt;




&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai0-6&quot; class=&quot;g-LABELS g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle1&quot;&gt;Colorado Springs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div id=&quot;g-ai0-9&quot; class=&quot;g-LABELS g-aiAbs g-aiPointText&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;g-pstyle0&quot;&gt;New Mexico&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;footer class=&quot;css-irejme interactive-footer custom-footer&quot;&gt;&lt;p data-testid=&quot;credit&quot; class=&quot;css-1ct2c9h interactive-credit custom-credit&quot;&gt;By The New York Times&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/footer&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“We’re tracking water sources,” she said, “not people.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Local and state governments have had to carve millions from their budgets to deal with the problem, much of which may never be paid back. In places like Oscoda, Mich., where the lake now froths with toxic foam, residents are &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.mlive.com/news/2019/01/air-force-refuses-to-follow-michigan-pfas-law.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;fighting with defense officials&lt;/a&gt; over the extent to which the military must clean up the mess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“When I was in the Air Force, they preached all the time: ‘Do the right thing. Integrity first. Service before self. Excellence in all we do’,” said Aaron Weed, a 22-year veteran who is now Oscoda’s town supervisor. “This is not the Air Force that I was a part of,” he continued. “The side of the Air Force that I am seeing is just disgraceful.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Blood testing has emerged as a sticking point. Specifically, a growing movement of veterans and others, united in advocacy groups with names like Fountain Valley Clean Water Coalition and Need Our Water, are asking the military test their blood for the chemicals, hoping to bring results to their doctors or use them in lawsuits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Their requests have been denied, and the military says that too little is known about the substances to make the results useful. Instead, it will pay for the C.D.C. to start yearslong population-based health studies in &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.cdc.gov/media/releases/2019/p0221-cdc-atsdr-pfas-exposure.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;some communities&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“They don’t want to know,” said Cindi Ashbeck, 56, a veteran who worked out of Wurtsmith Air Force Base in Michigan. “It’s not being addressed, because you open that can of worms, and you’ve got an Agent Orange thing on your hands.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;PFAS are a broad class of chemicals developed in the 1940s. Because they repel grease and water, they have been used across industries for decades, often to prevent stains. They are placed in a dizzying array of products: food packaging, nonstick pans, clothing, furniture. They are also used to extinguish fires where petroleum-based explosions pose a danger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;But the chemicals move quickly through the earth and into water, &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/these-toxic-chemicals-are-everywhere-and-they-wont-ever-go-away/2018/01/02/82e7e48a-e4ee-11e7-a65d-1ac0fd7f097e_story.html?utm_term=.7debdb271ca1&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;where they persist indefinitely.&lt;/a&gt; Some scientists have deemed them “forever chemicals,” and over the last two decades, a growing body of research has shown that the compounds meant to help us are likely hurting us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-wrapper&quot; class=&quot;css-79elbk ehw59r11&quot;&gt;

&lt;div data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-children&quot; class=&quot;css-1a48zt4 ehw59r111&quot;&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;css-8i9d0s e13ogyst0&quot;&gt;“We give our lives and our bodies for our country, and our government does not live up to their end of the deal,” said Samuel Fortune, who served two tours in Iraq.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The most comprehensive &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;http://www.c8sciencepanel.org/&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;data&lt;/a&gt;, based on a study of 69,000 people living near in a West Virginia DuPont plant, say exposure is associated with kidney cancer, testicular cancer, thyroid disease, high cholesterol and ulcerative colitis, among other problems, while animal studies &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.atsdr.cdc.gov/pfc/docs/pfas_clinician_fact_sheet_508.pdf&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;show delays&lt;/a&gt; in development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Mr. Fortune grew up in Sheridan, Wyo., where joining the Army was the way to avoid the coal mine or a job at Wal-Mart, he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;He enlisted in 1998, serving two tours in Iraq as a mechanic. On his final visit, while he was waiting on the airfield for his ride out of the country, enemy mortar threw him against a wall meant to fortify the area, damaging his back and tearing all the tendons in his shoulders. He had to be rebuilt, with metal. “Five rods, two plates, nine screws, 10 nails, 20 staples,” he said. “I make an X-ray glow.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The Army then stationed Mr. Fortune in Colorado Springs, home to five military bases, placing him, his wife, Bianca, and their children, Bryan and Sophia, in the center of a contamination zone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;He learned about the contamination in 2016. The military said it had come from the Peterson Air Force Base nearby. His family had been drinking the water for a decade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Soon, Ms. Fortune was in and out of the hospital, and Mr. Fortune became increasingly concerned that the cause was the chemicals. His wife told doctors of a debilitating pain in her right abdomen, intense joint pain and exhaustion. Her blood cell counts rose and fell like yo-yos. Some doctors thought it was Lyme disease; others weren’t so sure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Like many around the country, Mr. Fortune has joined one of several lawsuits against the companies that made the firefighting foam, including 3M and Tyco Fire Products. Others, &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.recordonline.com/news/20180807/newburgh-sues-feds-state-manufacturers-over-toxic-water&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;including&lt;/a&gt; the City of Newburgh, N.Y., are &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theintell.com/news/20181002/court-sets-precedent-rules-navy-can-be-sued-for-pfas-claims&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;suing&lt;/a&gt; the military directly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-wrapper&quot; class=&quot;css-79elbk ehw59r11&quot;&gt;

&lt;div data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-children&quot; class=&quot;css-1a48zt4 ehw59r111&quot;&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;css-8i9d0s e13ogyst0&quot;&gt;Steve Patterson, whose family members learned they had been drinking contaminated water for decades, has lost several of his relatives to cancer in recent years.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot; class=&quot;css-vuqh7u e1z0qqy90&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1tej78p0&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Ryan David Brown for The New York Times&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;But the lawyer in the Colorado case, David McDivitt, said he thought that would be too difficult because “it’s tough to sue the federal government.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;For years, there were signs that the chemicals in the military’s firefighting foam were dangerous. Defense Department studies dating to the 1970s indicated that the substances were harmful to laboratory animals, according to an &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://gazette.com/health/toxic-legacy-air-force-studies-dating-back-decades-show-danger/article_024f688b-9f1e-5395-9819-dc97cf71bf9d.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;investigation&lt;/a&gt; by The Colorado Springs Gazette, and the Army Corps of Engineers told Fort Carson to stop using the foam in 1991, calling it “harmful to the environment.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;In 2000, under pressure from the E.P.A., 3M &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://archive.epa.gov/epapages/newsroom_archive/newsreleases/33aa946e6cb11f35852568e1005246b4.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;phased out&lt;/a&gt; production of some of the compounds, announcing that they could “could potentially pose a risk to human health.” Five years later, the E.P.A. declared that another compound was “likely to be carcinogenic to humans.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;But the military has said it continued to use firefighting foams containing the compounds because companies have continued to produce them and the E.P.A. doesn’t regulate them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Industry officials have said they are following E.P.A. rules, while the E.P.A. has said it is still exploring regulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“You know the Shaggy song, ‘It wasn’t me’?’” said Mr. McDivitt. “It’s like that.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;In Fountain, the Defense Department has installed short-term water filters and is building treatment plants meant to fix the problem in the long-term. This has won the praise of some local officials. “We’re pleased with where we’re at,” said Curtis Mitchell of the Fountain water district.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Not everyone agrees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;After news broke of the contamination in Fountain and nearby communities, the Colorado health department said that while the area had a higher-than-normal rate of several cancers, that might be explained by high rates of obesity and smoking in the region.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Steve Patterson, 62, whose family had been drinking fouled water for decades, is skeptical of that explanation. A dozen of his relatives have died of cancer, some genetically related to him, some not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Mr. Fortune recently began asking the military to test his wife’s blood for the substances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;When officials declined, Mr. Fortune persisted, he said, and medical staff called him aggressive. “I’m not aggressive, I’m angry,” he said. “If you’re being poisoned, you want to know what it is, what it’s doing to you, and what you can do to stop it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 13:42:10 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>longdefeat</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/02/22/us/military-water-toxic-chemicals.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Toxic ‘Forever Chemicals’ in Drinking Water Leave Military Families Reeling</og:title>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/02/23/us/23water-1-print/00water-001-facebookJumbo.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>The pollution, often from foam used in firefighting, is part of a mounting concern over the presence of toxic substances that could affect at least 10 million Americans.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/02/22/us/military-water-toxic-chemicals.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>We’re Reading Fahrenheit 451 Wrong (2018)</title>
<link>https://thefrailestthing.com/2018/06/15/were-reading-fahrenheit-451-wrong/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://thefrailestthing.com/2018/06/15/were-reading-fahrenheit-451-wrong/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I was reminded of Ray Bradbury’s &lt;em&gt;Fahrenheit 451&lt;/em&gt; a day or two ago while &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2018/06/apples-airpods-are-an-omen/554537/&quot;&gt;reading Ian Bogost&lt;/a&gt; on Apple’s Airpods. Bogost examined Airpods’ potential long term social consequences. “Human focus, already ambiguously cleft between world and screen,” he suggests, “will become split again, even when maintaining eye contact.” A little further on, he writes, “Everyone will exist in an ambiguous state between public engagement with a room or space and private retreat into devices or media.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a good piece, you should read the whole thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It reminded me of Bradbury on two counts. First, and most obviously, Bradbury’s novel imaginatively predicted Airpods before earphones were invented. In the novel they are called Seashells, and they are just one of the ways that characters in the story sever their connection with the world beyond their heads, to borrow &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thenewatlantis.com/publications/attention-deficit&quot;&gt;Matt Crawford’s formulation&lt;/a&gt;. Second, Bogost’s fears echo Bradbury’s. &lt;em&gt;Fahrenheit 451&lt;/em&gt; isn’t really about censorship, after all, and it’s unfortunate that the novel has been reduced to that theme in the popular imagination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bradbury makes clear that the firemen who famously start fires to burn books are doing so only long after people stopped reading books of their own accord as other forms of media came to dominate their experience. Actually, to be more precise, they did not stop reading altogether. They stopped reading certain kinds of books: the ones that made demands of the reader, intellectual, emotional, moral demands that might upset their fragile sense of well-being.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fahrenheit 451&lt;/em&gt;, in other words, is more Huxley than Orwell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fundamentally, I would argue it is, like Huxley’s &lt;em&gt;Brave New World,&lt;/em&gt; about happiness. “Are you happy?” a young girl named Clarisse asks Montag, the protagonist. It is the question that triggers all the subsequent action in the novel. It is the question that awakens Montag to the truth of his situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At one remove from the question of happiness, is the matter of alienation from reality effected by media technologies. In 1953, when barely half of American households owned a television set, and primitive sets at that, Bradbury foresaw a future of complete immersion in four wall-sized screens through which people would socialize interactively with characters from popular programs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speed also severed people from meaningful contact with the world and became an impediment to thought. Literal speed—billboards where as long as football fields in order to be seen by drivers zooming by and walking was deemed a public nuisance—and the speed of information. An old professor, who knew better but did not have the courage to fight the changes he witnessed, explained the problem to Montag:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Speed up the film, Montag, quick. Click? Pic? Look, Eye, Now, Flick, Here, There, Swift, Pace, Up, Down, In, Out, Why, How, Who, What, Where, Eh? Uh! Bang! Smack! Wallop, Bing, Bong, Boom! Digest-digests, digest-digest-digests. Politics? One column, two sentences, a headline! Then, in mid-air, all vanishes! Whirl man’s mind around about so fast under the pumping hands of publishers, exploiters, broadcasters, that the centrifuge flings off all unnecessary, time-wasting thought!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Social media was still more than fifty years away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This same professor, Faber, later went on to lecture Montag about what was needed. Three things, he claimed. First, quality information, from books or elsewhere. Second, leisure, but not just “off-hours,” which Montag was quick to say he had plenty of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Off-hours, yes. But time to think? If you’re not driving a hundred miles an hour, at a clip where you can’t think of anything else but the danger, then you’re playing some game or sitting in some room where you can’t argue with the fourwall televisor. Why? The televisor is ‘real.’ It is immediate, it has dimension. It tells you what to think and blasts it in. It must be, right. It seems so right. It rushes you on so quickly to its own conclusions your mind hasn’t time to protest, ‘What nonsense!'”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third needful thing? A society that granted “the right to carry out actions based on what we learn from the inter-action of the first two.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not a bad prescription, if you ask me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earlier in the novel, as Montag travelled by subway to meet Faber for the first, he clung to a copy of the Bible that he had stowed away. He knows he will have to surrender it, so he attempts to memorize as much as he can. But he discovers that his mind is a sieve. He recalled that when he was a child an older relative would play a joke on him by offering a dime if he could fill a sieve with sand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As he travelled to meet Faber, “he remembered the terrible logic of that sieve.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, he thought to himself, “if you read fast and read all, maybe some of the sand will stay in the sieve. But he read and the words fell through, and he thought, in a few hours, there will be Beatty, and here will be me handing this over, so no phrase must escape me, each line must be memorized.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But his material environment undermined his efforts. As in &lt;a href=&quot;https://thefrailestthing.com/2010/08/20/the-cost-of-distraction-what-kurt-vonnegut-knew/&quot;&gt;Kurt Vonnegut’s short story, &lt;em&gt;Harrison Bergeron&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, distraction undid the work of the mind. In this case, Montag’s focus and concentration battled and lost against the tools of marketing. An ad for Denham’s Dentrifice blared over a loud speaker as he tried to commit what he read to memory. The brief memorable scene portrays a scenario that should feel all-too familiar to us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He clenched the book in his fists. Trumpets blared.&lt;br/&gt;“Denham’s Dentrifice.”&lt;br/&gt;Shut up, thought Montag. Consider the lilies of the field.&lt;br/&gt;“Denham’s Dentifrice.”&lt;br/&gt;They toil not-&lt;br/&gt;“Denham’s–”&lt;br/&gt;Consider the lilies of the field, shut up, shut up.&lt;br/&gt;“Dentifrice !&lt;br/&gt;“He tore the book open and flicked the pages and felt them as if he were blind, he picked at the shape of the individual letters, not blinking.&lt;br/&gt;“Denham’s. Spelled : D-E-N”&lt;br/&gt;They toil not, neither do they . . .&lt;br/&gt;A fierce whisper of hot sand through empty sieve.&lt;br/&gt;“Denham’s does it!”&lt;br/&gt;Consider the lilies, the lilies, the lilies…&lt;br/&gt;“Denham’s dental detergent.”&lt;br/&gt;“Shut up, shut up, shut up!” It was a plea, a cry so terrible that Montag found himself on his feet, the shocked inhabitants of the loud car staring, moving back from this man with the insane, gorged face, the gibbering, dry mouth, the flapping book in his fist. The people who had been sitting a moment before, tapping their feet to the rhythm of Denham’s Dentifrice, Denham’s Dandy Dental Detergent, Denham’s Dentifrice Dentifrice Dentifrice, one two, one two three, one two, one two three. The people whose mouths had been faintly twitching the words Dentifrice Dentifrice Dentifrice. The train radio vomited upon Montag, in retaliation, a great ton-load of music made of tin, copper, silver, chromium, and brass. The people were pounded into submission; they did not run, there was no place to run; the great air-train fell down its shaft in the earth.&lt;br/&gt;“Lilies of the field.” “Denham’s.”&lt;br/&gt;“Lilies, I said!”&lt;br/&gt;The people stared.&lt;br/&gt;“Call the guard.”&lt;br/&gt;“The man’s off–”&lt;br/&gt;“Knoll View!”&lt;br/&gt;The train hissed to its stop.&lt;br/&gt;“Knoll View!&lt;br/&gt;“Denham’s.” A whisper.&lt;br/&gt;Montag’s mouth barely moved. “Lilies…”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attention is a resource, and, like all precious resources, it must be cultivated with care and defended. It is, after all, that by which we get our grip on the world and how we remain open to world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;jp-post-flair&quot; class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-like-enabled sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;robots-nocontent sd-block sd-social sd-social-icon sd-sharing&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Share this:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 13:30:30 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>longdefeat</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>We’re Reading Fahrenheit 451 Wrong</og:title>
<og:url>https://thefrailestthing.com/2018/06/15/were-reading-fahrenheit-451-wrong/</og:url>
<og:description>I was reminded of Ray Bradbury’s Fahrenheit 451 a day or two ago while reading Ian Bogost on Apple’s Airpods. Bogost examined Airpods’ potential long term social consequences. &amp;#8…</og:description>
<og:image>https://thefrailestthing.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/alexander-leydenfrost-march-of-science-3wifc.jpg?w=200</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://thefrailestthing.com/2018/06/15/were-reading-fahrenheit-451-wrong/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Halley: Lightweight Game Engine Written in C++14</title>
<link>https://github.com/amzeratul/halley</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/amzeratul/halley</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;Box-body p-6&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;markdown-body entry-content&quot; itemprop=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/b7885bca4e4e478897b0529e681488edaad9f165/687474703a2f2f6869676865726f7264657266756e2e636f6d2f73747566662f68616c6c65792f68616c6c65795f736361726c65742e706e67&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/b7885bca4e4e478897b0529e681488edaad9f165/687474703a2f2f6869676865726f7264657266756e2e636f6d2f73747566662f68616c6c65792f68616c6c65795f736361726c65742e706e67&quot; alt=&quot;Halley Logo&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;http://higherorderfun.com/stuff/halley/halley_scarlet.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/C%2B%2B14&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/07b8d12dede8b2ecdd9f07c2d56b88c6287736d3/68747470733a2f2f696d672e736869656c64732e696f2f62616467652f6c6963656e73652d417061636865253230322e302d627269676874677265656e2e737667&quot; alt=&quot;License&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/license-Apache%202.0-brightgreen.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://isocpp.org/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/283e28cf877244df8e14fe6121b0b74d88b6f387/68747470733a2f2f696d672e736869656c64732e696f2f62616467652f6c616e67756167652d432b2b2d626c75652e737667&quot; alt=&quot;Language&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/language-C++-blue.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/C%2B%2B14&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/14eafa365535119df0dc48953fd71c5647cc6b90/68747470733a2f2f696d672e736869656c64732e696f2f62616467652f632532422532422d31342d626c75652e737667&quot; alt=&quot;Standard&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/c%2B%2B-14-blue.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lightweight game engine written in C++14. It has been used to ship Wargroove, a turn-based strategy game, on Windows, Mac (experimental), Nintendo Switch and Xbox One (soon PS4!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Halley Game Engine is licensed under the Apache 2.0 license.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make sure to check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/amzeratul/halley-template&quot;&gt;Halley-template&lt;/a&gt; repository for a blank sample.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Design guidelines &amp;amp; objectives&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Modern graphics pipelines, with first-class shader support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Written in modern C++&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&quot;True&quot; entity system based, with components that store data and systems that operate on families of components&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tuned for high performance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Code-first: no reliance on editor to generate anything&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easy to use: games should be easy to implement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easy to maintain: games should be easy to keep working on long-term, after it has grown to a large project size&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cross-platform: support as many platforms as possible&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No legacy: don't bother supporting legacy systems, such as Windows XP or older Android/iOS devices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rich tools: where possible, provide tools to assist in development and debugging&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fast iteration time: hot-reloading wherever possible&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support scripting in other languages, such as Lua&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Modules&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Halley is divided in a several sub-projects:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;engine&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;core&lt;/strong&gt;: Core features of the engine, including looper, API management, resouces, and graphics engine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;audio&lt;/strong&gt;: Audio engine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;entity&lt;/strong&gt;: Framework for dealing with entities, components, and systems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;utils&lt;/strong&gt;: Utilities library&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;net&lt;/strong&gt;: Networking library&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ui&lt;/strong&gt;: UI library&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;plugins&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;asio&lt;/strong&gt;: Network/Asio implementation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dx11&lt;/strong&gt;: Video/DX11 implementation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;opengl&lt;/strong&gt;: Video/OpenGL implementation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sdl&lt;/strong&gt;: System/SDL, Input/SDL and AudioOut/SDL implementations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;winrt&lt;/strong&gt;: System/WinRT, Input/WinRT, Platform/WinRT and AudioOut/XAudio2 implementations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tools&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;editor&lt;/strong&gt;: Editor UI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cmd&lt;/strong&gt;: Command-line interface to tools&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;runner&lt;/strong&gt;: Provides an entry point for execution and dynamic reloading. Highly experimental.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tools&lt;/strong&gt;: Editor tools to generate files and assets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tests&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;entity&lt;/strong&gt;: Stress test of entity system&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;network&lt;/strong&gt;: Stress test of network system&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;samples&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;(The samples project was taken down due to being too outdated, sorry about that!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Platforms&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following platforms are supported:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Windows&lt;/strong&gt;: Tested on Windows 10 Professional 64-bit (Should work on as low as XP 32-bit)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mac OS X&lt;/strong&gt;: Tested on Mac OS X 10.9.6&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Linux&lt;/strong&gt;: Tested on Ubuntu 16.04&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Tools required&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;CMake 3.10+&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;C++14 capable compiler:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Visual C++ 15.3 (Visual Studio 2017)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clang 3.5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GCC 5.0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Library dependencies&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Engine:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Boost 1.66.0 (header only)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OpenGL [optional]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SDL 2.0.2 (2.0.7 recommended) [optional]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Windows 10 SDK [optional]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Also required if building Tools:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Boost 1.66.0 libraries: filesystem, system&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Freetype 2.6.3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;yaml-cpp 0.5.3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Set up&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Ensure that all dependencies above are set up correctly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build with CMake
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Typical: &quot;cmake -DCMAKE_INCLUDE_PATH=path/to/headers -DCMAKE_LIBRARY_PATH=path/to/libs -DBOOST_ROOT=path/to/boost ..&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Engine only: &quot;cmake -DBUILD_HALLEY_TOOLS=0 -DBUILD_HALLEY_TESTS=0 [...]&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run &quot;halley-editor tests/entity&quot; (or whichever other project you want to test)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Launch that project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Documentation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The full documentation is available on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/amzeratul/halley/wiki&quot;&gt;Wiki&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 12:51:26 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ingve</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars0.githubusercontent.com/u/4175191?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>amzeratul/halley</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/amzeratul/halley</og:url>
<og:description>A lightweight game engine written in modern C++. Contribute to amzeratul/halley development by creating an account on GitHub.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/amzeratul/halley</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>