<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Jeff Hawkins Is Finally Ready to Explain His Brain Research</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/10/14/technology/jeff-hawkins-brain-research.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2018/10/14/technology/jeff-hawkins-brain-research.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div readability=&quot;44&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot; readability=&quot;33&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;REDWOOD CITY, Calif. — In the global race to build artificial intelligence, it was a missed opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Jeff Hawkins, a Silicon Valley veteran who spent the last decade exploring the mysteries of the human brain, arranged a meeting with DeepMind, the world’s leading A.I. lab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Scientists at DeepMind, which is owned by Google’s parent company, Alphabet, want to build machines that can do anything the brain can do. Mr. Hawkins runs a little company with one goal: figure out how the brain works and then reverse engineer it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The meeting, set for April at DeepMind’s offices in London, never happened. DeepMind employs hundreds of A.I. researchers along with a team of seasoned neuroscientists. But when Mr. Hawkins chatted with Demis Hassabis, one of the founders of DeepMind, before his visit, they agreed that almost no one at the London lab would understand his work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;46.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot; readability=&quot;38&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Mr. Hawkins says that before the world can build artificial intelligence, it must explain human intelligence so it can create machines that genuinely work like the brain. “You do not have to emulate the entire brain,” he said. “But you do have to understand how the brain works and emulate the important parts.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;At his company, called Numenta, that is what he hopes to do. Mr. Hawkins, 61, began his career as an engineer, created two classic mobile computer companies, Palm and Handspring, and taught himself neuroscience along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Now, after more than a decade of quiet work at Numenta, he thinks he and a handful of researchers working with him are well on their way to cracking the problem.On Monday, at a conference in the Netherlands, he is expected to unveil their latest research, which he says explains the inner workings of cortical columns, a basic building block of brain function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;How a larger community of researchers react to Mr. Hawkins’s work is hard to predict: Will they decide his research is worth exploring? Or will they write him off as too unorthodox in his methods and much too sure of himself?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;33&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Mr. Hawkins has been following his own, all-encompassing idea for how the brain works. It is a step beyond the projects of most neuroscientists, like understanding the brain of a fruit fly or exploring the particulars of human sight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;48.443099273608&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot; readability=&quot;45.648305084746&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;His theory starts with cortical columns. Cortical columns are a crucial part of the neocortex, the part of the brain that handles sight, hearing, language and reason. Neuroscientists don’t agree on how the neocortex works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Mr. Hawkins says cortical columns handle every task in the same way, a sort of computer algorithm that is repeated over and over again. It is a logical approach to the brain for a man who spent decades building new kinds of computing devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;All he has to do is figure out the algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;A number of neuroscientists like the idea, and some are pursuing similar ideas. They also praise Mr. Hawkins for his willingness to think so broadly. Being a maverick is not easily done in academia and the world of traditional research. But it’s a little easier when you can fund your own work, as Mr. Hawkins has.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Still, some wonder if his self-funded operation, isolated from the rigors of academic interaction, is a quixotic adventure. They have been researching the brain one little piece at a time for a good reason: Piecing how it all works together is a monumental, hard-to-fathom task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“It is clear we need a better understanding of intelligence,” said Tomaso Poggio, a neuroscientist at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology who introduced Mr. Hawkins and Mr. Hassabis. “But Jeff is doing this the hard way.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;If Mr. Hawkins’s work should pan out, it could help A.I. researchers leapfrog over what exists today. In recent years, the likes of Google, Apple and Amazon have &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/01/04/technology/self-driving-cars-aurora.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;built cars that drive on their own&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2018/08/17/technology/alexa-siri-conversation.html?mtrref=www.google.com&amp;amp;gwh=EF99C1E8F87EBDDB798F2CC40927DC9E&amp;amp;gwt=pay&amp;amp;module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;gadgets that answer questions from across the room&lt;/a&gt; and smartphone apps that &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2016/12/14/magazine/the-great-ai-awakening.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;instantly translate languages&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;52.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot; readability=&quot;50&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“The brain is by far the most complex piece of highly excitable matter in the known universe by any measure,” said Christof Koch, the chief scientist and president of the Allen Institute for Brain Science. “We don’t even understand the brain of a worm.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;css-rcspn7 eqpy7av0&quot; id=&quot;link-2f9ca0a3&quot;&gt;A call to explain the brain&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;In 1979, with an article in Scientific American, Francis Crick, a Nobel Prize winner for his DNA research, called for an all-encompassing theory of the brain, something that could explain this “profoundly mysterious” organ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Mr. Hawkins graduated from Cornell in 1979 with a degree in electrical engineering. Over the next several years, he worked at Intel, the computer chip giant, and Grid Systems, an early laptop company. But after reading that magazine article, he decided the brain would be his life’s work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;He proposed a neuroscience lab inside Intel. After the idea was rejected, he enrolled at the University of California, Berkeley. His doctoral thesis proposal was rejected, too. He was, suffice to say, an outlier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;In 1992, Mr. Hawkins founded Palm Computing. A decade and a half before the iPhone, he had created a hand-held computer for the masses. When he hired the company’s chief executive, Donna Dubinsky, he warned that whenever possible, he would drop his work with Palm and return to neuroscience. “That was always there, simmering in the background,” Ms. Dubinsky said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;37.259124087591&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot; readability=&quot;24.536496350365&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;U.S. Robotics acquired Palm in 1996 for $44 million. About two years later, Mr. Hawkins and Ms. Dubinksy left to start Handspring. &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2004/02/23/business/palm-s-marriage-of-convenience-to-handspring-shows-promise.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Palm, which bec&lt;/a&gt;a&lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2004/02/23/business/palm-s-marriage-of-convenience-to-handspring-shows-promise.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;me an independent company again in 2000, acquired Handspring&lt;/a&gt; for $192 million in stock in 2003.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Around the time of the second sale, Mr. Hawkins built his own neuroscience lab. But it was short-lived. He could not get a lab full of academics focused on his neocortical theory. So, along with Ms. Dubinsky and an A.I. researcher named Dileep George, he founded Numenta.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The company spent years trying to build and sell software, but eventually, after Mr. George left, it settled into a single project. Funded mostly by Mr. Hawkins — he won’t say how much he has spent on it — the company’s sole purpose has been explaining the neocortex and then reverse engineering it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;37&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot; readability=&quot;19&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;css-rcspn7 eqpy7av0&quot; id=&quot;link-5792ac55&quot;&gt;A coffee cup of clarity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Inside Numenta, Mr. Hawkins sits in a small office. Five other neuroscientists, mostly self-taught, work in a single room outside his door.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Mr. Hawkins said a moment of clarity came about two and a half years ago, while he was sitting in his office, staring at a coffee cup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;He touched the cup and dragged his finger across the rim. Then he leapt to his feet and ran through the door.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;51&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot; readability=&quot;47&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;He ran headlong into his wife, who had stopped by for lunch, and stumbled toward his closest collaborator, Subutai Ahmad, the vice president of research&lt;strong class=&quot;css-8qgvsz euv7paa0&quot;&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; “The cortex knows the location of everything,” Mr. Hawkins said. Mr. Ahmad had no idea what he was talking about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;As Mr. Hawkins looked at that cup, he decided that cortical columns did not just capture sensations. They captured the location of those sensations. They captured the world in three dimensions rather than two. Everything was seen in relation to what was around it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;If cortical columns handle sight and touch in this way, Mr. Hawkins thought, they handle hearing, language and even math in similar ways. He’s been working on proving that ever since.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“When the brain builds a model of the world, everything has a location relative to everything else,” Mr. Hawkins said. “That is how it understands everything.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The source of tension between Mr. Hawkins and other brain and A.I. researchers is not that they necessarily think he is wrong. It’s that they simply don’t know because what he has been trying to do has been so different. And so wildly ambitious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;For the science to advance, what Mr. Hawkins has been working on can’t stay in a silo. His ideas could benefit from extensive experimentation with other neuroscientists, said Nelson Spruston, a senior director at the Janelia Research Campus, a research lab in Virginia that focuses on neuroscience. “A continuous cycle of testing and revising biologically inspired models of neural computation is the key to developing insightful theories of the brain,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Translation: Mr. Hawkins will have to open his work to rigorous scrutiny and find a way to interact with researchers who most likely have never looked at the brain the way he does.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2018 19:30:29 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>tysone</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/10/14/technology/jeff-hawkins-brain-research.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Jeff Hawkins Is Finally Ready to Explain His Brain Research</og:title>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/10/15/business/15HAWKINS01/15HAWKINS01-facebookJumbo.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>He created the mobile computing companies Palm and Handspring. But for decades his passion has been studying how the human brain works.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/10/14/technology/jeff-hawkins-brain-research.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Google+ project and exec team</title>
<link>https://threader.app/thread/1049523067506966529</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://threader.app/thread/1049523067506966529</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;thread-head&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;pic-user d-inline&quot;&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/@morganknutson&quot;&gt;&lt;img id=&quot;post-img-user&quot; class=&quot;users-thread&quot; src=&quot;https://pbs.twimg.com/profile_images/1035062189353185282/GFHibt_J.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot; id=&quot;thread-post-start&quot;&gt;Now that Google+ has been shuttered, I should air my dirty laundry on how awful the project and exec team was.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'm still pissed about the bait and switch they pulled by telling me I'd be working on Chrome, then putting me on this god forsaken piece of shit on day one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;This will be a super slow burn that goes back many years. I’ll continue to add to over the next couple of days. I’ll preface it with a bunch of backstory and explain what I had left behind, which made me more unhappy about the culture I had come into.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;I spent most of my early career working for two radical sister non-profit orgs. I was the only designer working on&lt;br/&gt;anywhere from 4-5 different products at the same time. All centered around activism and used by millions of people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;It’s how I cut my teeth. Learned to be the designer that I am today. Most importantly, the people I worked for are imho some of the greatest people on the planet. Highly intelligent, empathetic, caring, and true role models for a young me. I adore them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;You might not know who they are, but if you’re reading this then you have definitely seen their work. Maybe OpenCongress, or Miro, or maybe Amara which is Vimeo’s partner transcription service. Definitely Fight for the Future, our internet defenders, which was shortly after me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;I married the love of my life in 2008, started a family, and at some point realized that I simply needed to make a better living. No matter how prolific, non-profits usually can’t provide the type of income that you need for a growing family with huge ambitions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;So as I gained visibility – via @&lt;a class=&quot;tweet-url username&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/dribbble&quot; data-screen-name=&quot;dribbble&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;dribbble&lt;/a&gt; – I started to field recruiters and consider new opportunities. Mostly little startups. I interviewed at one (Rockmelt) and they passed on me (hi, @&lt;a class=&quot;tweet-url username&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/iamxande&quot; data-screen-name=&quot;iamxande&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;iamxande&lt;/a&gt; 🤗).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;Got an email from Kickstarter (hi, @&lt;a class=&quot;tweet-url username&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/amotion&quot; data-screen-name=&quot;amotion&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;amotion&lt;/a&gt; 🤗). Schlepped to New York and wasted days of time to be passed on by their founders. Then they unfollowed me on twitter. At least I ate some deli. 😂&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;Then Google reached out. I remember that ”holy shit” moment. “Me!? Are they kidding?? The schmuck who tested out of high school and dropped out of college??” They told me I’d interview to work on Chrome. I was over the moon. I remember Manda tearing up. God I love her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;They gave me a little bit of time for a design exercise. You can see it here in all it’s dated glory: &lt;a href=&quot;http://morganallanknutson.com/google/&quot; title=&quot;http://morganallanknutson.com/google/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;tco-ellipsis&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;http://&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;js-display-url&quot;&gt;morganallanknutson.com/google/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;tco-ellipsis&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Click and hold for the overlay. More schlepping from LA and an interview at their silly college-like campus. I was a nervous wreck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;The process felt very haphazard. At one point a front-end dev with a bow-tie grilled me on CSS and asked some super dumb questions. My advocate (a sweetheart named Peter) seemed to be rushing people through, quelling their fears. I still appreciate his belief in me to this day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;I felt like I had done ok. The last two interviews that I failed at were real shots to the heart. I took this one incredibly seriously. I wanted this job so badly. I wanted to prove I was worthy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;Weeks went by and I heard nothing. I accepted the inevitable and started responding to other recruiters. It was ok. I wasn’t joining the big leagues. I could play triple-A ball for longer. As long as I got up to SF where the opportunities were.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;I took a gig with a failing news startup (lol) called Ongo (hi, @&lt;a class=&quot;tweet-url username&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/bethdean&quot; data-screen-name=&quot;bethdean&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;bethdean&lt;/a&gt; 🤗). They got me up here. I guess it was a bit of a Hail Mary for them. In a couple of months I knocked out more work than they could have built in a year with their eng team. Then…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;Google got back in touch almost 3-4 months after the interview (who does this??).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I got the job.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To be continued…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;Day one was so weird. It’s exactly what I’d imagined a freshmen orientation at a prestigious college would be like. I dropped out of art school, so this was foreign to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;I was with a big group of “nooglers” (so lame). We were led into a large room that looked like it was set up for a time-share pitch. I found my seat. Sat down and read the paper that was in front of me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;There was some kind of codename for the team I'd landed on that I don't recall.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was told it meant I’d be working on Google+.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fuck. “Whatever”, I thought, “I’ll just do my best and move to Chrome or something cooler after a while” Heh, so naive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;I later found out that one of the interviewers who I had liked the most - let’s call him Chuck - was the design manager on Plus and that he had fought to bring me into his team. Bittersweet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;Chuck was a sweet guy. A bit of an OG at Google. Super chill, super kind, and really funny. Seemingly non-political. My kind of manager. We’ll talk about him more later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;At some point I was given a badge and shown around the building I’d be working in. This was the first indication for me that something was awry.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Aside: The building design could only be described as kitsch. Goofy colored furniture. A slide. Crap...everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;Google+ was situated in THE main building. 1900. A floor away from Larry’s office (CEO). If you were one of the 12,000+ people at google in MV who didn’t work on Plus, then you didn’t have access to these floors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;The CEO didn’t just have an office. The entire floor was his. We all had access to it and were encouraged to use it sparingly. A “war room” here and there.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We had access to “his” cafe too. A super fancy vegan cafe called “cloud” that wouldn’t be sustainable in the real world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;Why this exclusivity? What made this project so special? Why was it held so closely to Google’s chest? I’d find out later that the SVP of Plus used his clout to swing all of this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;His name was Vic Gundotra.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;He was relatively charismatic. I remember him frequently flirting with the women on the team. Gave me a compounded horrible impression of him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;My desk was directly next to Vic’s glass-walled office. He would walk by my desk dozens of times during the day. He could see my screen from his desk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;During the 8 months I was there, culminating in me leading the redesign of his product, Vic didn’t say a word to me. No hello. No goodbye, or thanks for staying late. No handshake. No eye contact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;Vic’s product vision was fear-based. “Google built the knowledge graph, and Facebook swooped in and built the social graph. If we don’t own the social graph then we can’t claim to have indexed ALL the world’s data.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;It made sense at the time. That was a valuable dataset that Google would never be able to leverage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;Vic was powerful at Google. He had buy-in from the top and he wielded that stick aggressively. He made Plus as pervasive as he could. Each product org had a mandate to integrate its social features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;If your team, say on Gmail or Android, was to integrate Google+’s features then your team would be awarded a 1.5-3x multiplier on top of your yearly bonus. Your bonus was already something like 15% of your salary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;You read that correctly. A fuck ton of money to ruin the product you were building with bloated garbage that no one wanted 😂 No one really liked this. People drank the kool-aid though, but mostly because it was green and made of paper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;This made Plus the center of the Google universe and made Vic feel invincible, I presume. Once, I had to hold back laughter after he announced his “brilliant” idea to redesign the product from the ground up...every 6 months. lol&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;Vic left the company in 2014. Maybe because of this type of thing? Hard to say.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To be continued...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/kelly-ellis-claims-she-was-sexually-harassed-at-google-2015-3&quot; title=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/kelly-ellis-claims-she-was-sexually-harassed-at-google-2015-3&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;tco-ellipsis&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;https://www.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;js-display-url&quot;&gt;businessinsider.com/kelly-ellis-cl&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;aims-she-was-sexually-harassed-at-google-2015-3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;tco-ellipsis&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;…&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;Google, like many companies, has different tracks and levels for different disciplines. They of course asked me how much I made in my previous role. I made substantially below market rate, but *amazing* for non-profits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;They low-balled me. My offer was $115k a year with $100k in stock vesting over 4 years. It was way more than I’d ever made, but still below market rate. I accepted with no negotiating. My title was UI Designer Level II. Also low.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;Aside: Never do this. Always negotiate. Never tell a prospective employer how much you currently make. Tell them what you want. Their goal is to save money and yours is to make it. Your best interest is not theirs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;On my second day, I found out that I was sitting next to another designer and I was so stoked!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I had been solo &amp;amp; remote for 3+ years with the non-profits since I had left my second job, a little agency in LA.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;(still reminisce about the old days, @&lt;a class=&quot;tweet-url username&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/WesOHaire&quot; data-screen-name=&quot;WesOHaire&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;WesOHaire&lt;/a&gt;?🤗)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;I introduced myself.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This was their first job out of an Ivy League. They were one level below me. They were working on a tiny sliver of a sidebar tucked away on an internal page of Plus. Games, or something. “Inconsequential” is a good description.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;My first thought was “wtf? how is this a job? they pay you for this??”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was kind, of course, and let them know if they needed any help to just let me know.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now my second indication that Google wasn’t what I expected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;Thought this was the pros.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Never would’ve imagined that I was joining a team of 50+ designers where a bunch of them had never designed before.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And I was “evaluated” at *about* their level? These weren’t interns, these were designers in their very first roles ever...at Google.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;I was first placed on the Google Photos team which had been swallowed up by Plus. It had some seriously good front-end devs (and good people). It was a small team within a very large team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;My first project was to redesign the photos lightbox. I introduced some new and basic patterns, and drew all the iconography in the given aesthetic. Made some prototypes. Eng started building. Non-controversial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;This was a matter of weeks. But...now what? I didn’t have anything else lined up in the sprint.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My desk mate was still cranking away on their little area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;Well, I didn’t know the rest of the team at all, so I figured I’d go around meeting folks and offer to help with anything they needed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’d grab a seat and draw some ui, or and icon, or rattle off thoughts. Whatever they needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;I got to know a few people, but most importantly I got to know what they were working on, and it wasn’t pretty.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Everything being produced felt disjointed or siloed. Not part of the whole. The M.O. was build and copy as much shit as possible. “Win the race.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;There was a distinct lack of a grand vision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;None of it had been made with the consideration of all the products in the Google ecosystem. Just a bunch of “UX designers” not caring about the actual customer experience. Just focusing on their silos because that's how you complete tasks and play the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;It’s now November and I’m tasked with designing the opt-in UI, and parts of the functional UI for facial recognition in photos. That was about a week worth of work.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;FB copied some of my visuals on this, but whatevs our whole platform was a ripoff of theirs. 😆😅&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;I went back to knocking things out for other people.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Designed some community branding, did a sweater design for SWSX, drew some visuals for people. The entire time I was also noodling about the disparate stuff I was seeing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;I think it was around this time that Chuck, my manager who wouldn’t micro-manage but pumped you up and encouraged you to shoot for the moon (I truly liked him), got replaced by a guy that he was managing. An awfully bad designer with a love for bureaucracy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;Let’s call him Greg because his real name is just as vanilla.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He was a smarmy, politically motivated little fella who had no intentions of ever leaving Google. He told me that. I didn’t like him from the moment I met him and the feeling was mutual.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;He was now my manager.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I knew it wouldn't go well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;Half the team was out of office beginning early to mid-Dec.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I took the standard vacation time towards the end of the month, except I didn’t really vacation, I worked through all of it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I had a vision.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To be continued...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;The common thread between 99.8% of the people that I interacted with at Google is that they were ethical, highly intelligent, and hard working.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I had a lot of admiration and respect for many of them and wish more of them had stayed in touch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;The design organization was massive and spanning almost every product, of course. (Some products didn’t have designers) It felt like design had many rival factions split by not just certain product orgs, but between skill and schools of thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;There was the “creative team” which was a service team that would create icons or other assets based on the outdated style guides. You’d have to submit a form and wait for them. They were a bit surly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;Then there was a team that was iterating on Kennedy, the name for the new Google UI style. It was if they were on a mountain, secluded. This is the style that Gmail and Calendar has had for years, now replaced with some Frankenstein version of Material.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;The craziest thing about this team is that one of the most pivotal players was a...contractor. I was blown away when I found this out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;Anyhow, it wasn’t super clear what other teams were doing. It wasn’t clear who I should have been collaborating with to achieve my loftier goals of affecting all of the UI patterns at Google. Nothing was ever clear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;Which is weird because Google seemed to be very transparent. I mean, you could pop open a web page and see every detail about every employee, from their level to their desk location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;Back at home, during my break, I was cranking away. Playing with my baby girl in between trying to rationalize everything going on in the project. Real Time Communications (RTC) was hugely important to the team. Hangouts came from Plus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;Greg was managing that team originally. Part of why he was respected. Hangouts was the only good thing about this shitty product. It was sort of at odds with the current RTC paradigms. Chat Moles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;Moles were the name for the little chat boxes that pop up from bottom of gmail, enabling you to chat with someone. They’re an effective UI paradigm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;None of this stuff was tightly integrated. More of a layer on top of everything. I wanted to change that. This was Plus when I joined. Lots of sections. Lots of junk. Bad navigation. Left-aligned content. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;I wanted to make RTC a first-class citizen. I designed a responsive layout that would give you list of friends on the right, and if your screen was large enough, you’d also get all of your message threads. Almost identical UI to messages on OSX (slightly before it existed).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;That top gray bar was called the Sandbar. Just kind of slotted in there. I integrated it with a new navigation on the left side with a rounded edge. Drew a new set of icons that fit with an overall polished aesthetic. I put a lot of attention into crafting their various states.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;The whole vision was to integrate google’s other apps into this sidebar navigation. Obviously it’s a bit of a technical challenge, but this would have been a viable UI framework to work towards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;No separate websites for each product e.g. gmail, calendar, plus, just one place to go with everything seamlessly integrated. I also put a new coat of paint on literally everything. Polished it up nicely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;It’s now January of 2012. I’m back in the office. I have a little something up my sleeve. I show it around to various folks and people seem to like it. Awesome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;Even Greg reluctantly liked it. Someone (maybe him) told me I needed to talk to another guy to get buy-in on my chat plans. He was the exec that was responsible for it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I found him and was able to give him a quick elevator pitch on what I was going for with RTC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;He said “Haha, there’s no way we’re doing that. I/O is coming up and we’ve just spent the last 4 months building a Chrome extension that does something similar. If Plus has this, then we’re going to get laughed off the stage.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;I was like, “...what? But shouldn’t these all work together in a sort of ‘your conversations are available wherever you are?’ kind if way?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“No, we’re not doing that.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;I was floored. Did he say chrome extension? Did he even understand what I had explained and showed him? Was he a huge fucking idiot? Sigh. Whatever, I pushed forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;Sitting behind me was the most badass group of people on the team. The User Experience Engineering (UXE) team. They made things come to life. Wielded front-end code like no other. I showed them my work and they were legitimately stoked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;This team was lead by the imitable Andy Hertzfeld. A god damned saint. Honestly, working with Andy was the highlight of my short tenure. He seemed genuinely sad the day I told him I was leaving. I was too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;Anyhow, one guy on the team offered to build a prototype. His name was Chris, and without him this would have never gotten off the ground. He was incredible. Kind and generous, and he put in his all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;We collaborated for a couple of weeks and when he was done, you could replace your hash (unique identifier for your account) in the URL and use the prototype with your data. It was superb.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;Greg used it to pitch the redesign to Vic. Made me feel shut out and like a disposable employee due to the fact that I wasn’t involved. What was said in that meeting? Was it pitched right? Was the whole vision conveyed? So much anxiety.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;It didn’t matter. Vic bought in.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The whole team would rally around my work.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To be...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Just kidding I’ll keep going. 😂&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;Everything at google has to have code name in order to be taken seriously. I had huge ambitions for this work and the paradigms it introduced. I wanted it to be the North Star. Arrogant right? 😆&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;I told a handful of people I wanted to call it North Star while trying to gauge their reaction. The consensus was pretty much “yeah, I guess.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Greg tells me a couple days later “Vic wants to call it North Star. He thinks it will be foundational.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;🤦‍♂️ OK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;I quickly designed a logo for the project. It was essentially a compass rose. I printed a huge version and stuck it on the designated war room. I’d put my flag in the ground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;The team huddled together and started phasing the project. Areas of the product were divvied up, people took ownership, everyone worked in tandem. I was the go-to for any questions and direction. I was responsible for finishing the visuals that I had started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;One of the other designers on the team - we’ll call him Jim - had worked on Plus from its inception. He was one of the better visual designers on the team. He had done most of the icon work on the project. He was understandably proud and a bit protective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;He’s a timid and generally kind person (running theme). But also not sure of himself. Not confident in his work. Also understandable considering it wasn’t the best. Often times he seemed anxiety stricken.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;I made him a bit uneasy whenever I was around him. I could tell, and I did my damndest to be sweet to him to try to make him feel comfortable. I wanted him to like me. I want everyone to like me. It’s a problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;Aside: I was tasked earlier with redesigning the +1 button. I absolutely hated the Plus logo. It was compositionally unbalanced, and the rationale was ridiculous. “The + hangs off the edge to signify that there’s more that’s unseen.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;Aside: Nah man, it just looks like an amateur made it. I fixed the composition. Centered the “+” on the “g”. Jim and another designer fought me hard on it. I relented. I made the dumbass button with their bad logo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;Aside: They shipped my version of the logo after I left. It looked way better. They didn’t care about what was better. They just wanted THEIR work to be used, or to be able to take credit for it. I hate that weak ass shit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;Anyhow, my wholesale redesign of all of Jim’s work was obviously making him feel bad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;One day, he came up to me totally flustered in one of the micro-kitchens. He said “People aren’t liking these icons.” I said, “Oh, ok, let me know who and I’ll collect their feedback and we can make them better.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;Jim: “Just lots of people.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Me: ??? “I’m going to need to know who, or at least what the feedback is...”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jim: “They’re just not working and a lot of people are saying that.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Me: “Dude, what? How am I supposed to work with this?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jim: “I don’t know I...”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;I interrupted. I had a feeling it was actually just him and another gal that considered herself a master visual designer. They were both frustrated that I had come in and basically taken over. I got it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;Me: “OK, no worries man. Would it make you feel better if I put something together that explains my decision making and then you and whomever else can punch holes in it, and give me direct feedback?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jim: “Yeah, ok, sounds good. I’ll put something on the calendar.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;9am the next morning. A dick move.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;I went home and got to work.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the early evening I got a call from my dad. My grandmother’s health took a turn for the worst. They weren’t sure she’d make it past the evening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;I couldn’t grieve. I needed to make this happen. These two designers were beloved by Greg. I had to win them over or they’d screw everything up for me. Everything I’d worked for could come crashing down due to their pettiness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;I forged ahead. At about 9 or 10 I checked Twitter. It just so happened that there was a party going on. A bunch of people from Facebook and Path were there. Competitors to Plus, obviously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;So was Jim. Jim tweeted about having so much fun with all these Path and Facebook people.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was working my ass off, stifling the grief of my dying grandmother, all because of his passive aggressive scheduling. And he was out with our competitors??&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Angry is an understatement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;She passed away at about 11:30pm. Fuck, man 😞 I lost it. I couldn’t hold it back anymore. She was gone. I wasn’t able to tell her I loved her one last time. I’d never see her again.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I finished working through tears. I got it done and fell asleep at about 4am.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;When I woke up the next morning I had an email from Jim. “Hey Morgan, I’m really sorry, I’m dealing with a headache and won’t be able to make it in. Can we reschedule for tomorrow?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;MOTHERFUCKER ARE YOU KIDDING ME!? ARE YOU FUCKING KIDDING ME!?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;I took some deep breaths. I contemplated how I should react. I wanted to physically fight him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“No worries Jim, let’s do it tomorrow.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I had to do something about this. This was totally unacceptable to me. I forwarded the email to Greg, like the idiot that I am.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;“Greg, I had to work most of the night because of Jim, and he canceled our meeting because he was partying with our competitors. In my book, this is totally unacceptable. What am I supposed to do?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;No response. On my commute in, I got a notification of a meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;Title: Morgan&lt;br/&gt;Time: 5pm&lt;br/&gt;Location: Greg’s Desk&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;What? Am I being fired? There’s never a time when a room is not booked for a meeting. This felt like I was in trouble over something. Like a grade-schooler.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;5pm rolled around and I schlepped to Greg’s desk. He gave me his usual smug smile and his manufactured calmness and pointed to an empty room near him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;Greg: “So what happened?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I told him. He patronized me with his stupid fucking nods and his shit-eating grin.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Greg: “So I know that you have big ambitions here. I know you think might want to manage this team.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I never said that shit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;Greg: “Well, it’s not going to go as you planned. In fact, I think I’m going to make Jim your manager after we launch.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Me: “Uhhhh, ok? But why aren’t you addressing what I told you? You’re making me feel like I don’t belong here.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Greg: “I’m not sure you do.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;Me: “Soooo, are you firing me?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He laughed and said, “No, but you can go home now.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What. The. Fuck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;Google was completely and utterly ruined for me after this moment. I became very depressed. I didn’t want go in to the office. It was clear that I was not welcome.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To be continued...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can follow &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/morganknutson&quot;&gt;Morgan&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;____&lt;br/&gt;Tip: mention &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/threader_app&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;@threader_app&lt;/a&gt; on a Twitter thread with the keyword “compile” to get a link to it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Enjoy Threader? &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?text=Hi%20%40jack%2C%20I%20read%20Twitter%20threads%20on%20%40threader_app&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Tell @jack&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;download-url&quot;&gt;Download &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/threader/id1317519091?mt=8&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Threader&lt;/a&gt; on iOS.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2018 13:05:46 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>seapunk</dc:creator>
<og:title>A thread written by @morganknutson</og:title>
<og:image>https://threader.app/img/ogthreader.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>Now that Google+ has been shuttered, I should air my dirty laundry on how awful the project and exec team was. I'm still pissed about the bait and switch they pulled by telling me I'd be working on Chrome, then putting me on this god forsaken piece of shit on day one.</og:description>
<og:url>https://threader.app/thread/1049523067506966529</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://threader.app/thread/1049523067506966529</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Research: The Average Age of a Successful Startup Founder Is 45</title>
<link>https://hbr.org/2018/07/research-the-average-age-of-a-successful-startup-founder-is-45</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://hbr.org/2018/07/research-the-average-age-of-a-successful-startup-founder-is-45</guid>
<description>&lt;div readability=&quot;41&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;text-gray-light mbn mt-large2&quot;&gt;Executive Summary&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s widely believed that the most successful entrepreneurs are young. Bill Gates, Steve Jobs, and Mark Zuckerberg were in their early twenties when they launched what would become world-changing companies. Do these famous cases reflect a generalizable pattern? In fact, the average age of entrepreneurs at the time they founded their companies is 42. But what about the most successful startups? Is it possible that companies started by younger entrepreneurs are particularly successful? Research shows that among the top 0.1% of startups based on growth in their first five years, the founders started their companies, on average, when they were 45 years old.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;137.89938217123&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;mbn pbn&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-207052&quot; src=&quot;https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2018/07/jul18-11-498927582-Patricia-de-Melo-Moreira-bloomberg.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/resources/images/article_assets/2018/07/jul18-11-498927582-Patricia-de-Melo-Moreira-bloomberg-300x169.jpg 300w, /resources/images/article_assets/2018/07/jul18-11-498927582-Patricia-de-Melo-Moreira-bloomberg-1024x576.jpg 1024w, /resources/images/article_assets/2018/07/jul18-11-498927582-Patricia-de-Melo-Moreira-bloomberg-500x281.jpg 500w, /resources/images/article_assets/2018/07/jul18-11-498927582-Patricia-de-Melo-Moreira-bloomberg-383x215.jpg 383w, /resources/images/article_assets/2018/07/jul18-11-498927582-Patricia-de-Melo-Moreira-bloomberg-383x215.jpg 383w, /resources/images/article_assets/2018/07/jul18-11-498927582-Patricia-de-Melo-Moreira-bloomberg-500x281.jpg 500w, /resources/images/article_assets/2018/07/jul18-11-498927582-Patricia-de-Melo-Moreira-bloomberg-700x394.jpg 700w, /resources/images/article_assets/2018/07/jul18-11-498927582-Patricia-de-Melo-Moreira-bloomberg-850x478.jpg 850w, /resources/images/article_assets/2018/07/jul18-11-498927582-Patricia-de-Melo-Moreira-bloomberg-1200x675.jpg 1200w, /resources/images/article_assets/2018/07/jul18-11-498927582-Patricia-de-Melo-Moreira-bloomberg.jpg 1200w&quot; alt=&quot;jul18-11-498927582--Patricia de Melo Moreira-bloomberg&quot; width=&quot;1200&quot; height=&quot;675&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 48em) 55.7291667vw, 97.3924381vw&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Patricia de Melo Moreira/bloomberg/Getty Images&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s widely believed that the most successful entrepreneurs are young. Bill Gates, Steve Jobs, and Mark Zuckerberg were in their early twenties when they launched what would become world-changing companies. Do these famous cases reflect a generalizable pattern? VC and media accounts seem to suggest so. When we analyzed founders who have won TechCrunch awards over the last decade, &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/events/8th-annual-crunchies-awards/winners/&quot;&gt;the average age at the time of founding was just 31&lt;/a&gt;. For the people selected by Inc. magazine as the founders of the fastest-growing startups in 2015, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.inc.com/inc5000/list/&quot;&gt;the average age at founding was only 29&lt;/a&gt;. Consistent with these findings, Paul Graham, a cofounder of Y Combinator, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2013/05/05/magazine/y-combinator-silicon-valleys-start-up-machine.html&quot;&gt;once quipped&lt;/a&gt; that “the cutoff in investors’ heads is 32… After 32, they start to be a little skeptical.” But is this view correct?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Debunking the Myth of the Young Entrepreneur&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our team analyzed the age of all business founders in the U.S. in recent years by leveraging confidential administrative data sets from the U.S. Census Bureau. We found that the average age of entrepreneurs at the time they founded their companies is 42. But the vast majority of these new businesses are likely small businesses with no intentions to grow large (for example, dry cleaners and restaurants). To focus on businesses that are closer in spirit to the prototypical high-tech startup, we used a variety of indicators: whether the firm was granted a patent, received VC investment, or operated in an industry that employs a high fraction of STEM workers. We also focused on the location of the firm, in particular whether it was in an entrepreneurial hub such as Silicon Valley. In general, these finer-grained analyses do not modify the main conclusion: The average age of high-tech founders falls in the early forties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These averages, however, hide a large amount of variation across industries. In software startups, the average age is 40, and younger founders aren’t uncommon. However, young people are less common in other industries such as oil and gas or biotechnology, where the average age is closer to 47. The preeminent place of young founders in the popular imagination may therefore reflect disproportionate exposure to a handful of consumer-facing IT industries, such as social media, rather than equally consequential pursuits in heavy industry or business-to-business sectors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;max-width-320&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignleft size-full mtl mbl pvm has-border-top has-border-bottom wp-image-206848&quot; src=&quot;https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2018/07/W180621_AZOULAY_THEAGE-1.png&quot; srcset=&quot;/resources/images/article_assets/2018/07/W180621_AZOULAY_THEAGE-1-183x300.png 183w, /resources/images/article_assets/2018/07/W180621_AZOULAY_THEAGE-1-625x1024.png 625w, /resources/images/article_assets/2018/07/W180621_AZOULAY_THEAGE-1-383x627.png 383w, /resources/images/article_assets/2018/07/W180621_AZOULAY_THEAGE-1-500x819.png 500w, /resources/images/article_assets/2018/07/W180621_AZOULAY_THEAGE-1.png 641w&quot; alt=&quot;W180621_AZOULAY_THEAGE (1)&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 48em) 55.7291667vw, 97.3924381vw&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what about the most successful startups? Is it possible that companies started by younger entrepreneurs are particularly successful? Among the top 0.1% of startups based on growth in their first five years, we find that the founders started their companies, on average, when they were 45 years old. These highest-performing firms were identified based on employment growth. The age finding is similar using firms with the fastest sales growth instead, and founder age is similarly high for those startups that successfully exit through an IPO or acquisition. In other words, when you look at most successful firms, the average founder age goes up, not down. Overall, the empirical evidence shows that successful entrepreneurs tend to be middle-aged, not young.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In part, the dominance of middle-aged founders in starting the highest-growth companies reflects the propensity of middle-aged people to start ventures. Middle-aged people take many more bites at the apple. However, when you look at success rates conditional on actually starting a company, the evidence against youthful entrepreneurial success becomes even sharper. Among those who have started a firm, older entrepreneurs have a substantially higher success rate. Our evidence points to entrepreneurial performance rising sharply with age before cresting in the late fifties. If you were faced with two entrepreneurs and knew nothing about them besides their age, you would do better, on average, betting on the older one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;max-width-320&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignleft size-full mtl mbl pvm has-border-top has-border-bottom wp-image-206849&quot; src=&quot;https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2018/07/W180621_AZOULAY_OLDERENTREPRENEURS-1.png&quot; srcset=&quot;/resources/images/article_assets/2018/07/W180621_AZOULAY_OLDERENTREPRENEURS-1-179x300.png 179w, /resources/images/article_assets/2018/07/W180621_AZOULAY_OLDERENTREPRENEURS-1-610x1024.png 610w, /resources/images/article_assets/2018/07/W180621_AZOULAY_OLDERENTREPRENEURS-1-383x643.png 383w, /resources/images/article_assets/2018/07/W180621_AZOULAY_OLDERENTREPRENEURS-1-500x839.png 500w, /resources/images/article_assets/2018/07/W180621_AZOULAY_OLDERENTREPRENEURS-1.png 641w&quot; alt=&quot;W180621_AZOULAY_OLDERENTREPRENEURS (1)&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 48em) 55.7291667vw, 97.3924381vw&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why might this be? Although there are many other factors that may explain the age advantage in entrepreneurship, we found that work experience plays a critical role. Relative to founders with no relevant experience, those with at least three years of prior work experience in the same narrow industry as their startup were 85% more likely to launch a highly successful startup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But What About Steve Jobs?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although we have looked at extraordinarily successful firms — the top 0.1% by growth as well as the rare outcome of successful acquisition or IPO — one might still wonder if even more extreme outlier firms are started by the very young. Interestingly, however, when you study notable outliers such as Bill Gates, Steve Jobs, Jeff Bezos, or Sergey Brin and Larry Page, the growth rates of their businesses in terms of market capitalization peaked when these founders were middle-aged. Steve Jobs and Apple introduced the company’s most profitable innovation, the iPhone, when Jobs was 52. Jeff Bezos and Amazon have moved far beyond selling books online, and Amazon’s future market cap growth rate was highest when Bezos was 45. These prominent founders may not have peaked when very young. Extremely talented entrepreneurs may have unusual acumen — allowing them to succeed when they are very young — yet still see greater success as they age. Thus there is no fundamental tension between the existence of great young entrepreneurs and a general tendency for founders to reach their peak entrepreneurial potential later in life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why Do VC Investors Tend to Bet on Young Founders?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In light of this evidence, why do some VCs persist in betting on young founders? We cannot definitively answer this question with the data at our disposal, but we believe that two mechanisms could be at play. First, many VCs may operate under a mistaken belief that youth is the elixir of successful entrepreneurship — in other words, VCs are simply wrong. Though it is tempting to see age bias as the leading explanation for the divergence between our findings and investor behavior, there is a more benign possibility: VCs are not simply looking to identify the firms with the highest growth potential. Rather, they may seek investments that will yield the highest returns, and it is possible that young founders are more financially constrained than more experienced ones, leading them to cede upside to investors at a lower price. In other words, younger entrepreneurs may be a better “deal” for investors than more experienced founders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next step for researchers is to explore what exactly explains the advantage of middle-aged founders. For example, is it due to greater access to financial resources, deeper social networks, or certain forms of experience? In the meantime, it appears that advancing age is a powerful feature, not a bug, for starting the most successful firms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2018 11:27:55 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>BerislavLopac</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:image>https://hbr.org/resources/images/article_assets/2018/07/jul18-11-498927582-Patricia-de-Melo-Moreira-bloomberg.jpg</og:image>
<og:url>https://hbr.org/2018/07/research-the-average-age-of-a-successful-startup-founder-is-45</og:url>
<og:description>The most successful entrepreneurs aren’t 20-somethings.</og:description>
<og:title>Research: The Average Age of a Successful Startup Founder Is 45</og:title>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://hbr.org/2018/07/research-the-average-age-of-a-successful-startup-founder-is-45</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Dear Spotify, please let me unlink my Facebook account</title>
<link>https://eduardogarcia.xyz/blog/dear-spotify</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://eduardogarcia.xyz/blog/dear-spotify</guid>
<description>&lt;nav&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://eduardogarcia.xyz/&quot;&gt;← Home&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/nav&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;subtitle&quot;&gt;Please let me unlink my Facebook account&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;last-updated&quot;&gt;Last updated: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/thewarpaint/eduardogarcia.xyz/commit/3fcc466ebd052b6676b8d4f6efa3d5d5997c84bf&quot;&gt;October 14, 2018 &lt;code&gt;(3fcc466)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was 2014. I was young and reckless. When I saw the big blue button that read &quot;Sign up with Facebook&quot; I just couldn't resist. Now, four years later, I want out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the light of the recent &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vox.com/2018/10/13/17973190/facebook-data-breach-29-million-users&quot;&gt;Facebook data breach&lt;/a&gt; I have decided I no longer want to use my Facebook identity to log in to your service. I am aware that the official recommendation is to &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.spotify.com/us/article/i-want-to-use-spotify-without-facebook/&quot;&gt;cancel your current account, create a new one and manually move your playlists or contact support to do it for you,&lt;/a&gt; but I believe it would be better if you offered a straightforward way to do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a &lt;a href=&quot;https://community.spotify.com/t5/forums/searchpage/tab/message?q=unlink%20facebook&amp;amp;collapse_discussion=true&quot;&gt;quick search on your Community site&lt;/a&gt; reveals, I am far from the only person who would like to fix this. I can assure you all of us will be very grateful if this is implemented soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sincerely,&lt;br/&gt;a Spotify user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=18212383&quot;&gt;Follow the discussion on Hacker News&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2018 11:18:42 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>thewarpaint</dc:creator>
<og:title>Dear Spotify</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>http://eduardogarcia.xyz/blog/dear-spotify.html</og:url>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://eduardogarcia.xyz/blog/dear-spotify</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Disguised user location data collection on Huawei phone?</title>
<link>https://threader.app/thread/1051204370543648770</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://threader.app/thread/1051204370543648770</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;thread-head&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;pic-user d-inline&quot;&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/@fs0c131y&quot;&gt;&lt;img id=&quot;post-img-user&quot; class=&quot;users-thread&quot; src=&quot;https://pbs.twimg.com/profile_images/991657715192750081/tQymlTdJ.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;info-user d-inline-block&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;info-name&quot;&gt;Elliot Alderson&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;info-user-handle-c&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/fs0c131y&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;@fs0c131y&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;info-user-bio&quot;&gt;French security researcher. Worst nightmare of Oneplus, Wiko, UIDAI, Kimbho and others. Not completely schizophrenic. Not related to USANetwork. DMs open.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;info-user-date&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/fs0c131y/status/1051204370543648770&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Oct. 13, 2018&lt;/a&gt; 2 min read&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot; id=&quot;thread-post-start&quot;&gt;THREAD: I'm looking at a Huawei P20 from China, let see what can I found&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;The 1st app I reversed is an app called Decision&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;Look at the name of the files contains in the assets folder:&lt;br/&gt;- airport_china.txt&lt;br/&gt;- city_china.txt&lt;br/&gt;- cityinfo.db&lt;br/&gt;- parkinglot_china.txt&lt;br/&gt;- railwayinfo.db&lt;br/&gt;- trainInfo.db&lt;br/&gt;- trainstation.db&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Interesting, no? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;For example, the trainstation database contains:&lt;br/&gt;- address&lt;br/&gt;- name&lt;br/&gt;- latitude&lt;br/&gt;- longitude&lt;br/&gt;- city &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;In the manifest of this application, there is a GeoReceiver &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;This receiver is receiving an UUID and will lookup an known fence id &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;I'm a stupid security researcher. For the moment, the keywords are: train, airport, city, geo fence... Do you see where we are going?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;In the data folder, there is a file called CalcMain. Here some of the methods of this class:&lt;br/&gt;- callGetBusTime&lt;br/&gt;- callGetTaxiTime&lt;br/&gt;- isTrafficBusy&lt;br/&gt;- callGetHomeCity&lt;br/&gt;- callHasHotelTicket&lt;br/&gt;- callGetAirportMultiPoi&lt;br/&gt;- callHasGroupBuyingTicket&lt;br/&gt;- ... &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;Nice data types haha &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;To be clear, this app is composed of 3 background services and 2 services. There is NO UI in this app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;Please be nice &quot;DO NOT KILL ME &amp;gt;_&amp;lt;&quot; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;This is the kind of function that I love to find &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;This app doesn't seems to send the data BUT they communicate with another service called HiActionService which is coming from an Huawei app called HiAction &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;The previous screenshot is from the class called ActionCommonUtil. We can easily that Decision is sending all his events to this service through the methods in this class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;I will study the app HiAction another time but what you have to know is that this app is sending the data to hicloud[.]com, &quot;the Huawei Cloud&quot; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;In order to be more discreet, the OEM dispatch the responsibilities to multiple apps. In this case:&lt;br/&gt;1. An app or the modified Android is getting your location regularly. It will trigger a GEO_ALARM_TRIGGERED to the Decision app&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;2. Decision app is getting this location and check with his internal databases. If there is a match, it will generate an event&lt;br/&gt;3. Decision will send this event to HiAction&lt;br/&gt;4. HiAction will upload the data to the Huawei cloud&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;Ugly, no?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;Ofc, this is the big picture, I need more time to get all the details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;I started this thread 2 hours ago. Decision app was the first app I checked. I still have a lot of Huawei apps to check&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;Ofc, I will continue this thread later 😏&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;If it was not clear enough: DO NOT buy @&lt;a class=&quot;tweet-url username&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Huawei&quot; data-screen-name=&quot;Huawei&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Huawei&lt;/a&gt; phones. NEVER.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;thread-part&quot;&gt;Wow my English is really broken when I’m tired&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can follow &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/fs0c131y&quot;&gt;Elliot Alderson&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;____&lt;br/&gt;Tip: mention &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/threader_app&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;@threader_app&lt;/a&gt; on a Twitter thread with the keyword “compile” to get a link to it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Enjoy Threader? &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?text=Hi%20%40jack%2C%20I%20read%20Twitter%20threads%20on%20%40threader_app&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Tell @jack&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;download-url&quot;&gt;Download &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/threader/id1317519091?mt=8&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Threader&lt;/a&gt; on iOS.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2018 11:02:47 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>seapunk</dc:creator>
<og:title>A thread written by @fs0c131y</og:title>
<og:image>https://threader.app/img/ogthreader.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>THREAD: I'm looking at a Huawei P20 from China, let see what can I found</og:description>
<og:url>https://threader.app/thread/1051204370543648770</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://threader.app/thread/1051204370543648770</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>New York Times app autoplays video ads on articles even with paid subscription</title>
<link>https://twitter.com/james_k_nelson/status/1051404721473241088</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://twitter.com/james_k_nelson/status/1051404721473241088</guid>
<description>Ironically, I googled how to disable autoplay videos on their app, and the first result was a piece *by* &lt;a href=&quot;https://mobile.twitter.com/nytimes&quot; class=&quot;twitter-atreply dir-ltr&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot; data-mentioned-user-id=&quot;807095&quot; data-screenname=&quot;nytimes&quot;&gt;@nytimes&lt;/a&gt; that details how to block autoplay videos on *other* sites.

And then?

That same article started playing a video ad, and I got even more evil stares!</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2018 09:32:16 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jamesknelson</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://mobile.twitter.com/james_k_nelson/status/1051404721473241088</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Belgian Air Force F-16 destroyed by fire during maintenance</title>
<link>https://www.aviation24.be/military-aircraft/belgian-air-component/air-force-f-16-destroyed-maintenance-collateral-damage-second/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.aviation24.be/military-aircraft/belgian-air-component/air-force-f-16-destroyed-maintenance-collateral-damage-second/</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;td-post-sharing-top&quot;&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;td_social_sharing_article_top&quot; class=&quot;td-post-sharing td-ps-bg td-ps-notext td-ps-rounded td-post-sharing-style3&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;td-post-sharing-visible&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Facebook&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Twitter&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Google+&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Pinterest&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;WhatsApp&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Viber&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;td-post-content&quot; readability=&quot;52.779947916667&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/F-16-Van-Bouwel.jpg&quot; data-rel=&quot;lightbox-image-0&quot; data-rl_title=&quot;&quot; data-rl_caption=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-28174&quot; src=&quot;https://wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/F-16-Van-Bouwel.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;768&quot; srcset=&quot;//wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/F-16-Van-Bouwel.jpg 1024w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/F-16-Van-Bouwel-300x225.jpg 300w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/F-16-Van-Bouwel-768x576.jpg 768w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/F-16-Van-Bouwel-30x23.jpg 30w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/F-16-Van-Bouwel-585x439.jpg 585w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;© David Van Bouwel
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On 11 October around 14:10 (UTC +2), a Belgian Air Force F16 caught fire during maintenance works at Florennes Air Base. The fire completely destroyed that aircraft. The Belgian Air Force said a second F-16 received collateral damage.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On 12 October, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aviation24.be&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; received more information on the incident: a technician was working on an F-16 when he accidentally activated the six-barrels 20mm Vulcan M61A-1 cannon of that F-16. The cannon was loaded and some bullets hit another F-16AM (FA-128). That aircraft had just been refuelled and was – together with another F-16 – being prepared for a (training) mission. Due to the bullets, the F-16AM exploded and damaged the other F-16.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two technicians were injured after the blast, the Belgian Aviation Safety Directorate opened an investigation into the accident. The Belgian Air Force had 60 active F-16 aircraft remaining, including 48 on duty for NATO.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/F-16-Florennes-3.jpg&quot; data-rel=&quot;lightbox-image-1&quot; data-rl_title=&quot;&quot; data-rl_caption=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-49035&quot; src=&quot;https://wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/F-16-Florennes-3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; srcset=&quot;//wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/F-16-Florennes-3.jpg 720w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/F-16-Florennes-3-300x200.jpg 300w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/F-16-Florennes-3-696x464.jpg 696w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/F-16-Florennes-3-630x420.jpg 630w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 720px) 100vw, 720px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;© Scramble.nl &lt;a href=&quot;https://wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/F-16-Florennes-2.png&quot; data-rel=&quot;lightbox-image-2&quot; data-rl_title=&quot;&quot; data-rl_caption=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-49034&quot; src=&quot;https://wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/F-16-Florennes-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; srcset=&quot;//wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/F-16-Florennes-2.png 720w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/F-16-Florennes-2-225x300.png 225w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/F-16-Florennes-2-696x928.png 696w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/F-16-Florennes-2-315x420.png 315w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 720px) 100vw, 720px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;© Scramble.nl &lt;a href=&quot;https://wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/F-16-Florennes.png&quot; data-rel=&quot;lightbox-image-3&quot; data-rl_title=&quot;&quot; data-rl_caption=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-49033&quot; src=&quot;https://wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/F-16-Florennes.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;753&quot; height=&quot;659&quot; srcset=&quot;//wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/F-16-Florennes.png 753w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/F-16-Florennes-300x263.png 300w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/F-16-Florennes-696x609.png 696w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/F-16-Florennes-480x420.png 480w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 753px) 100vw, 753px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;© Scramble.nl
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot; readability=&quot;9.8401360544218&quot;&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot; lang=&quot;fr&quot;&gt;NEWS &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/BelgiumDefence?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@BelgiumDefence&lt;/a&gt; – Le 11 octobre 2018 vers 14 h10, un incendie s’est déclaré au cours de travaux de maintenance sur un F-16 sur la Base de Florennes. L’avion a brûlé. Un deuxième avion a subi des dommages collatéraux.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Belgian Air Force🇧🇪 (@BeAirForce) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/BeAirForce/status/1050394683007008768?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;October 11, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot; readability=&quot;7.9227799227799&quot;&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot; lang=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;NEWS &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/BelgiumDefence?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@BelgiumDefence&lt;/a&gt; – Op 11 oktober 2018 omstreeks 14u10 vatte één F16 vuur tijdens onderhoudswerken. Het vliegtuig brandde daarbij uit. Een tweede vliegtuig liep hierbij collaterale schade op.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Belgian Air Force🇧🇪 (@BeAirForce) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/BeAirForce/status/1050394035297366018?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;October 11, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;jp-relatedposts-headline&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Related&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;footer&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;td-post-sharing-bottom&quot;&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;td_social_sharing_article_bottom&quot; class=&quot;td-post-sharing td-ps-bg td-ps-notext td-ps-rounded td-post-sharing-style3&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;td-post-sharing-visible&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Facebook&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Twitter&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Google+&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Pinterest&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;WhatsApp&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Viber&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;td-block-row td-post-next-prev&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;td-block-span6 td-post-prev-post&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;td-post-next-prev-content&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Previous article&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aviation24.be/airports/brussels/work-to-rule-police-action-long-waiting-times-immigration/&quot;&gt;Work-to-rule police action at Brussels Airport results in long waiting times at immigration&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;td-block-span6 td-post-next-post&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;td-post-next-prev-content&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Next article&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aviation24.be/manufacturers/lockheed-martin/us-and-israel-grounds-entire-f-35-stealth-fighter-jet-fleet/&quot;&gt;US, UK and Israel ground entire F-35 stealth fighter jet fleet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author-box-wrap&quot; readability=&quot;6.6346153846154&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aviation24.be/author/admin/&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/283b6f077ff07987420d09a2f35e11db?s=96&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&quot; srcset=&quot;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/283b6f077ff07987420d09a2f35e11db?s=192&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&quot; class=&quot;avatar avatar-96 photo&quot; height=&quot;96&quot; width=&quot;96&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;desc&quot; readability=&quot;8.8461538461538&quot;&gt;


&lt;p&gt; Online alias luchtzak - in aviation since 1996 from cleaning to flight attendant - living in Hofstade, Belgium - two rugrats - created this site in 2001 - from www.luchtzak.be to www.aviation24.be in 2017 - traveler - KV Mechelen - 70.3 Ironman finisher - Ironman ambition&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/footer&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2018 06:21:26 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jsiepkes</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://www.aviation24.be/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/F-16-Florennes-3.jpg</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Belgian Air Force F-16 destroyed by fire during maintenance - Collateral damage on second F-16 - Aviation24.be</og:title>
<og:description>On 11 October around 14:10 (UTC +2), a Belgian Air Force F16 caught fire during maintenance works at Florennes Air Base. The fire completely destroyed that aircraft. The Belgian Air Force said a second F-16 received collateral damage. On 12 October, Aviation24.be received more information on the incident: a technician was working on an F-16 …</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.aviation24.be/military-aircraft/belgian-air-component/air-force-f-16-destroyed-maintenance-collateral-damage-second/</og:url>
<dc:language>en-GB</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.aviation24.be/military-aircraft/belgian-air-component/air-force-f-16-destroyed-maintenance-collateral-damage-second/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Show HN: Comprehensive Tutorials in Deep Learning Using TensorFlow</title>
<link>https://github.com/open-source-for-science/TensorFlow-Course</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/open-source-for-science/TensorFlow-Course</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;Box-header px-2 clearfix&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;Box-title pr-3&quot;&gt;README.rst&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Box-body p-6&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;markdown-body entry-content&quot; itemprop=&quot;text&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/open-source-for-science/TensorFlow-Course/pulls&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/contributions-welcome-brightgreen.svg?style=flat&quot; src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/926d8ca67df15de5bd1abac234c0603d94f66c00/68747470733a2f2f696d672e736869656c64732e696f2f62616467652f636f6e747269627574696f6e732d77656c636f6d652d627269676874677265656e2e7376673f7374796c653d666c6174&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/contributions-welcome-brightgreen.svg?style=flat&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ellerbrock/open-source-badge/&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;https://badges.frapsoft.com/os/v2/open-source.svg?v=102&quot; src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/2091d99fb3b1ea0dcacb2ce564d5a3fc099c9ee7/68747470733a2f2f6261646765732e66726170736f66742e636f6d2f6f732f76322f6f70656e2d736f757263652e7376673f763d313032&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://badges.frapsoft.com/os/v2/open-source.svg?v=102&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This repository aims to provide simple and ready-to-use tutorials for TensorFlow. Each tutorial includes &lt;code&gt;source code&lt;/code&gt; and most of them are associated with a &lt;code&gt;documentation&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/open-source-for-science/TensorFlow-Course/blob/master/_img/mainpage/TensorFlow_World.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;_img/mainpage/TensorFlow_World.gif&quot; src=&quot;https://github.com/open-source-for-science/TensorFlow-Course/raw/master/_img/mainpage/TensorFlow_World.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h2&gt;


&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/open-source-for-science/TensorFlow-Course#id1&quot;&gt;Motivation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are different motivations for this open source project. TensorFlow (as we write this document) is one of / the best deep learning frameworks available. The question that should be asked is why has this repository been created when there are so many other tutorials about TensorFlow available on the web?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/open-source-for-science/TensorFlow-Course#id2&quot;&gt;Why use TensorFlow?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deep Learning is in very high interest these days - there's a crucial need for rapid and optimized implementations of the algorithms and architectures. TensorFlow is designed to facilitate this goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The strong advantage of TensorFlow is it flexibility in designing highly modular models which can also be a disadvantage for beginners since a lot of the pieces must be considered together when creating the model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This issue has been facilitated as well by developing high-level APIs such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://keras.io/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Keras&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tensorflow/models/blob/master/inception/inception/slim/README.md//&quot;&gt;Slim&lt;/a&gt; which abstract a lot of the pieces used in designing machine learning algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The interesting thing about TensorFlow is that &lt;strong&gt;it can be found anywhere these days&lt;/strong&gt;. Lots of the researchers and developers are using it and &lt;em&gt;its community is growing at the speed of light&lt;/em&gt;! So many issues can be dealt with easily since they're usually the same issues that a lot of other people run into considering the large number of people involved in the TensorFlow community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/open-source-for-science/TensorFlow-Course#id3&quot;&gt;What's the point of this repository?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Developing open source projects for the sake of just developing something is not the reason behind this effort&lt;/strong&gt;. Considering the large number of tutorials that are being added to this large community, this repository has been created to break the jump-in and jump-out process that usually happens to most of the open source projects, &lt;strong&gt;but why and how&lt;/strong&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First of all, what's the point of putting effort into something that most of the people won't stop by and take a look? What's the point of creating something that does not help anyone in the developers and researchers community? Why spend time for something that can easily be forgotten? But &lt;strong&gt;how we try to do it?&lt;/strong&gt; Even up to this very moment there are countless tutorials on TensorFlow whether on the model design or TensorFlow workflow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of them are too complicated or suffer from a lack of documentation. There are only a few available tutorials which are concise and well-structured and provide enough insight for their specific implemented models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of this project is to help the community with structured tutorials and simple and optimized code implementations to provide better insight about how to use TensorFlow &lt;em&gt;quick and effectively&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is worth noting that, &lt;strong&gt;the main goal of this project is to provide well-documented tutorials and less-complicated code&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/open-source-for-science/TensorFlow-Course#id4&quot;&gt;TensorFlow Installation and Setup the Environment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/open-source-for-science/TensorFlow-Course/blob/master/docs/tutorials/installation&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;alternate text&quot; src=&quot;https://github.com/open-source-for-science/TensorFlow-Course/raw/master/_img/mainpage/installation-logo.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to install TensorFlow please refer to the following link:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_3JFEPk4qQY&amp;amp;t=2s&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;_img/mainpage/installation.gif&quot; src=&quot;https://github.com/open-source-for-science/TensorFlow-Course/raw/master/_img/mainpage/installation.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The virtual environment installation is recommended in order to prevent package conflict and having the capacity to customize the working environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/open-source-for-science/TensorFlow-Course#id5&quot;&gt;TensorFlow Tutorials&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tutorials in this repository are partitioned into relevant categories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/open-source-for-science/TensorFlow-Course#id6&quot;&gt;Warm-up&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/open-source-for-science/TensorFlow-Course/blob/master/_img/mainpage/welcome.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;alternate text&quot; src=&quot;https://github.com/open-source-for-science/TensorFlow-Course/raw/master/_img/mainpage/welcome.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/open-source-for-science/TensorFlow-Course#id7&quot;&gt;Basics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/open-source-for-science/TensorFlow-Course/blob/master/_img/mainpage/basics.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;alternate text&quot; src=&quot;https://github.com/open-source-for-science/TensorFlow-Course/raw/master/_img/mainpage/basics.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/open-source-for-science/TensorFlow-Course#id8&quot;&gt;Basic Machine Learning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/open-source-for-science/TensorFlow-Course/blob/master/_img/mainpage/basicmodels.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;alternate text&quot; src=&quot;https://github.com/open-source-for-science/TensorFlow-Course/raw/master/_img/mainpage/basicmodels.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/open-source-for-science/TensorFlow-Course#id9&quot;&gt;Neural Networks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/open-source-for-science/TensorFlow-Course/blob/master/_img/mainpage/CNNs.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;alternate text&quot; src=&quot;https://github.com/open-source-for-science/TensorFlow-Course/raw/master/_img/mainpage/CNNs.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/open-source-for-science/TensorFlow-Course#id10&quot;&gt;Some Useful Tutorials&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/open-source-for-science/TensorFlow-Course#id11&quot;&gt;Contributing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When contributing to this repository, please first discuss the change you wish to make via issue, email, or any other method with the owners of this repository before making a change. &lt;em&gt;For typos, please do not create a pull request. Instead, declare them in issues or email the repository owner&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please note we have a code of conduct, please follow it in all your interactions with the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/open-source-for-science/TensorFlow-Course#id12&quot;&gt;Pull Request Process&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please consider the following criterions in order to help us in a better way:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The pull request is mainly expected to be a code script suggestion or improvement.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A pull request related to non-code-script sections is expected to make a significant difference in the documentation. Otherwise, it is expected to be announced in the issues section.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ensure any install or build dependencies are removed before the end of the layer when doing a build and creating a pull request.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add comments with details of changes to the interface, this includes new environment variables, exposed ports, useful file locations and container parameters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You may merge the Pull Request in once you have the sign-off of at least one other developer, or if you do not have permission to do that, you may request the owner to merge it for you if you believe all checks are passed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/open-source-for-science/TensorFlow-Course#id13&quot;&gt;Final Note&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are looking forward to your kind feedback. Please help us to improve this open source project and make our work better. For contribution, please create a pull request and we will investigate it promptly. Once again, we appreciate your kind feedback and elaborate code inspections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/open-source-for-science/TensorFlow-Course#id14&quot;&gt;Acknowledgement&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have taken huge efforts in this project for hopefully being a small part of TensorFlow world. However, it would not have been plausible without the kind support and help of my friend and colleague &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/vonclites/&quot;&gt;Domenick Poster&lt;/a&gt; for his valuable advices. He helped me for having a better understanding of TensorFlow and my special appreciation goes to him. I would also like to thanks &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hadikazemi.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Hadi Kazemi&lt;/a&gt; for his contribution to this code for developing &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/open-source-for-science/TensorFlow-Course/blob/master/docs/tutorials/3-neural_network/autoencoder&quot;&gt;Undercomplete Autoencoders Tutorial&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2018 03:48:21 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>irsina</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars2.githubusercontent.com/u/43791934?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>open-source-for-science/TensorFlow-Course</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/open-source-for-science/TensorFlow-Course</og:url>
<og:description>Simple and ready-to-use tutorials for TensorFlow . Contribute to open-source-for-science/TensorFlow-Course development by creating an account on GitHub.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/open-source-for-science/TensorFlow-Course</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>CSS Layout cookbook</title>
<link>https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/CSS/Layout_cookbook</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/CSS/Layout_cookbook</guid>
<description>&lt;article id=&quot;wikiArticle&quot; readability=&quot;32.209762532982&quot;&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;The CSS layout cookbook aims to bring together recipes for common layout patterns, things you might need to implement in your own sites. In addition to providing code you can use as a starting point in your projects, these recipes highlight the different ways layout specifications can be used, and the choices you can make as a developer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;note&quot; readability=&quot;7.7938144329897&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: If you are new to CSS layout then you might first like to take a look at our &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Learn/CSS/CSS_layout&quot;&gt;CSS layout learning module&lt;/a&gt;, as this will give you the basic grounding you need to make use of the recipes here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;The_Recipes&quot;&gt;The Recipes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;Contribute_a_Recipe&quot;&gt;Contribute a Recipe&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with all of MDN we would love you to contribute a recipe in the same format as the ones shown above. &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/user:chrisdavidmills/Layout_Cookbook_Home/Contribute_a_recipe&quot;&gt;See this page&lt;/a&gt; for a template and guidelines for writing your own example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wiki-block contributors&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;offscreen&quot;&gt;Document Tags and Contributors&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 13 Oct 2018 20:40:37 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>filipoi</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:image>https://developer.mozilla.org/static/img/opengraph-logo.72382e605ce3.png</og:image>
<og:title>CSS Layout cookbook</og:title>
<og:url>https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/CSS/Layout_cookbook</og:url>
<og:description>The CSS layout cookbook aims to bring together recipes for common layout patterns, things you might need to implement in your own sites. In addition to providing code you can use as a starting point in your projects, these recipes highlight the different ways layout specifications can be used, and the choices you can make as a developer.</og:description>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/CSS/Layout_cookbook</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ten years ago today, I had the idea for an app I thought was interesting</title>
<link>https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1050990035892199424.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1050990035892199424.html</guid>
<description>At Bump that year, we’d sent an email to the entire company to dress up like a coworker for Halloween.&lt;p&gt;Then we sent a 2nd email to all except Andy saying to dress up like him: socks, sandals, tech co t-shirt, and ziplock bag wallet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lesson: Don’t take yourself too seriously. &lt;span class=&quot;entity-image&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pbs.twimg.com/media/DpXd_rTUwAACLA0.jpg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://threadreaderapp.com/images/1px.png&quot; data-src=&quot;https://pbs.twimg.com/media/DpXd_rTUwAACLA0.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 13 Oct 2018 20:28:42 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>necrodome</dc:creator>
<og:title>Thread by @dflieb: &quot;10 years ago today, I had the idea for an app I thought was interesting. I called it Bump, and sent this email to Andy Huibers. Here’s a thr […]&quot;</og:title>
<og:image>https://threadreaderapp.com/images/screenshots/thread/1050990035892199424.jpg</og:image>
<og:url>https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1050990035892199424.html</og:url>
<og:description>Thread by @dflieb: &quot;10 years ago today, I had the idea for an app I thought was interesting. I called it Bump, and sent this email to Andy Hure’s a thread with some memories and lessons learned in the last 10 years. First lesson: Persistence matters. […]&quot;</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1050990035892199424.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>