<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>How Lisp Became God&amp;#039;s Own Programming Language</title>
<link>https://twobithistory.org/2018/10/14/lisp.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://twobithistory.org/2018/10/14/lisp.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;When programmers discuss the relative merits of different programming languages, they often talk about them in prosaic terms as if they were so many tools in a tool belt—one might be more appropriate for systems programming, another might be more appropriate for gluing together other programs to accomplish some ad hoc task. This is as it should be. Languages have different strengths and claiming that a language is better than other languages without reference to a specific use case only invites an unproductive and vitriolic debate. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But there is one language that seems to inspire a peculiar universal reverence: Lisp. Keyboard crusaders that would otherwise pounce on anyone daring to suggest that some language is better than any other will concede that Lisp is on another level. Lisp transcends the utilitarian criteria used to judge other languages, because the median programmer has never used Lisp to build anything practical and probably never will, yet the reverence for Lisp runs so deep that Lisp is often ascribed mystical properties. Everyone’s favorite webcomic, &lt;em&gt;xkcd&lt;/em&gt;, has depicted Lisp this way at least twice: In &lt;a href=&quot;https://xkcd.com/224/&quot;&gt;one comic&lt;/a&gt;, a character reaches some sort of Lisp enlightenment, which appears to allow him to comprehend the fundamental structure of the universe. In &lt;a href=&quot;https://xkcd.com/297/&quot;&gt;another comic&lt;/a&gt;, a robed, senescent programmer hands a stack of parentheses to his padawan, saying that the parentheses are “elegant weapons for a more civilized age,” suggesting that Lisp has all the occult power of the Force.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another great example is Bob Kanefsky’s parody of a song called “God Lives on Terra.” His parody, written in the mid-1990s and called “Eternal Flame”, describes how God must have created the world using Lisp. The following is an excerpt, but the full set of lyrics can be found in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/fun/jokes/eternal-flame.en.html&quot;&gt;GNU Humor Collection&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For God wrote in Lisp code&lt;br/&gt;When he filled the leaves with green.&lt;br/&gt;The fractal flowers and recursive roots:&lt;br/&gt;The most lovely hack I’ve seen.&lt;br/&gt;And when I ponder snowflakes,&lt;br/&gt;never finding two the same,&lt;br/&gt;I know God likes a language&lt;br/&gt;with its own four-letter name.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can only speak for myself, I suppose, but I think this “Lisp Is Arcane Magic” cultural meme is the most bizarre and fascinating thing ever. Lisp was concocted in the ivory tower as a tool for artificial intelligence research, so it was always going to be unfamiliar and maybe even a bit mysterious to the programming laity. But programmers now &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/ProgrammerHumor/comments/5c14o6/xkcd_lisp/d9szjnc/&quot;&gt;urge each other to “try Lisp before you die”&lt;/a&gt; as if it were some kind of mind-expanding psychedelic. They do this even though Lisp is now the second-oldest programming language in widespread use, younger only than Fortran, and even then by just one year.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;/&gt; Imagine if your job were to promote some new programming language on behalf of the organization or team that created it. Wouldn’t it be great if you could convince everyone that your new language had divine powers? But how would you even do that? How does a programming language come to be known as a font of hidden knowledge?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How did Lisp get to be this way?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://twobithistory.org/images/byte_lisp.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Byte Magazine Cover, August, 1979.&quot;/&gt;&lt;em&gt;The cover of Byte Magazine, August, 1979.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;theory-a-the-axiomatic-language&quot;&gt;Theory A: The Axiomatic Language&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John McCarthy, Lisp’s creator, did not originally intend for Lisp to be an elegant distillation of the principles of computation. But, after one or two fortunate insights and a series of refinements, that’s what Lisp became. Paul Graham—we will talk about him some more later—has written that, with Lisp, McCarthy “did for programming something like what Euclid did for geometry.”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;/&gt; People might see a deeper meaning in Lisp because McCarthy built Lisp out of parts so fundamental that it is hard to say whether he invented it or discovered it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;McCarthy began thinking about creating a language during the 1956 Darthmouth Summer Research Project on Artificial Intelligence. The Summer Research Project was in effect an ongoing, multi-week academic conference, the very first in the field of artificial intelligence. McCarthy, then an assistant professor of Mathematics at Dartmouth, had actually coined the term “artificial intelligence” when he proposed the event.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:3&quot;/&gt; About ten or so people attended the conference for its entire duration.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:4&quot;/&gt; Among them were Allen Newell and Herbert Simon, two researchers affiliated with the RAND Corporation and Carnegie Mellon that had just designed a language called IPL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Newell and Simon had been trying to build a system capable of generating proofs in propositional calculus. They realized that it would be hard to do this while working at the level of the computer’s native instruction set, so they decided to create a language—or, as they called it, a “pseudo-code”—that would help them more naturally express the workings of their “Logic Theory Machine.”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:5&quot;/&gt; Their language, called IPL for “Information Processing Language”, was more of a high-level assembly dialect then a programming language in the sense we mean today. Newell and Simon, perhaps referring to Fortran, noted that other “pseudo-codes” then in development were “preoccupied” with representing equations in standard mathematical notation.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:6&quot;/&gt; Their language focused instead on representing sentences in propositional calculus as lists of symbolic expressions. Programs in IPL would basically leverage a series of assembly-language macros to manipulate and evaluate expressions within one or more of these lists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;McCarthy thought that having algebraic expressions in a language, Fortran-style, would be useful. So he didn’t like IPL very much.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:7&quot;/&gt; But he thought that symbolic lists were a good way to model problems in artificial intelligence, particularly problems involving deduction. This was the germ of McCarthy’s desire to create an algebraic list processing language, a language that would resemble Fortran but also be able to process symbolic lists like IPL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, Lisp today does not resemble Fortran. Over the next few years, McCarthy’s ideas about what an ideal list processing language should look like evolved. His ideas began to change in 1957, when he started writing routines for a chess-playing program in Fortran. The prolonged exposure to Fortran convinced McCarthy that there were several infelicities in its design, chief among them the awkward &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;IF&lt;/code&gt; statement.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:8&quot;/&gt; McCarthy invented an alternative, the “true” conditional expression, which returns sub-expression A if the supplied test succeeds and sub-expression B if the supplied test fails and which &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; only evaluates the sub-expression that actually gets returned. During the summer of 1958, when McCarthy worked to design a program that could perform differentiation, he realized that his “true” conditional expression made writing recursive functions easier and more natural.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:9&quot;/&gt; The differentiation problem also prompted McCarthy to devise the &lt;em&gt;maplist&lt;/em&gt; function, which takes another function as an argument and applies it to all the elements in a list.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:10&quot;/&gt; This was useful for differentiating sums of arbitrarily many terms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None of these things could be expressed in Fortran, so, in the fall of 1958, McCarthy set some students to work implementing Lisp. Since McCarthy was now an assistant professor at MIT, these were all MIT students. As McCarthy and his students translated his ideas into running code, they made changes that further simplified the language. The biggest change involved Lisp’s syntax. McCarthy had originally intended for the language to include something called “M-expressions,” which would be a layer of syntactic sugar that made Lisp’s syntax resemble Fortran’s. Though M-expressions could be translated to S-expressions—the basic lists enclosed by parentheses that Lisp is known for— S-expressions were really a low-level representation meant for the machine. The only problem was that McCarthy had been denoting M-expressions using square brackets, and the IBM 026 keypunch that McCarthy’s team used at MIT did not have any square bracket keys on its keyboard.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:11&quot;/&gt; So the Lisp team stuck with S-expressions, using them to represent not just lists of data but function applications too. McCarthy and his students also made a few other simplifications, including a switch to prefix notation and a memory model change that meant the language only had one real type.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:12&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1960, McCarthy published his famous paper on Lisp called “Recursive Functions of Symbolic Expressions and Their Computation by Machine.” By that time, the language had been pared down to such a degree that McCarthy realized he had the makings of “an elegant mathematical system” and not just another programming language.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:13&quot;/&gt; He later wrote that the many simplifications that had been made to Lisp turned it “into a way of describing computable functions much neater than the Turing machines or the general recursive definitions used in recursive function theory.”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:14&quot;/&gt; In his paper, he therefore presented Lisp both as a working programming language and as a formalism for studying the behavior of recursive functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;McCarthy explained Lisp to his readers by building it up out of only a very small collection of rules. Paul Graham later retraced McCarthy’s steps, using more readable language, in his essay &lt;a href=&quot;http://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/myl/llog/jmc.pdf&quot;&gt;“The Roots of Lisp”&lt;/a&gt;. Graham is able to explain Lisp using only seven primitive operators, two different notations for functions, and a half-dozen higher-level functions defined in terms of the primitive operators. That Lisp can be specified by such a small sequence of basic rules no doubt contributes to its mystique. Graham has called McCarthy’s paper an attempt to “axiomatize computation.”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:15&quot;/&gt; I think that is a great way to think about Lisp’s appeal. Whereas other languages have clearly artificial constructs denoted by reserved words like &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;while&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;typedef&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;public static void&lt;/code&gt;, Lisp’s design almost seems entailed by the very logic of computing. This quality and Lisp’s original connection to a field as esoteric as “recursive function theory” should make it no surprise that Lisp has so much prestige today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;theory-b-machine-of-the-future&quot;&gt;Theory B: Machine of the Future&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two decades after its creation, Lisp had become, according to the famous &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jargon_File&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hacker’s Dictionary&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the “mother tongue” of artificial intelligence research. Early on, Lisp spread quickly, probably because its regular syntax made implementing it on new machines relatively straightforward. Later, researchers would keep using it because of how well it handled symbolic expressions, important in an era when so much of artificial intelligence was symbolic. Lisp was used in seminal artificial intelligence projects like the &lt;a href=&quot;https://hci.stanford.edu/winograd/shrdlu/&quot;&gt;SHRDLU natural language program&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Macsyma&quot;&gt;Macsyma algebra system&lt;/a&gt;, and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ACL2&quot;&gt;ACL2 logic system&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the mid-1970s, though, artificial intelligence researchers were running out of computer power. The PDP-10, in particular—everyone’s favorite machine for artificial intelligence work—had an 18-bit address space that increasingly was insufficient for Lisp AI programs.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:16&quot;/&gt; Many AI programs were also supposed to be interactive, and making a demanding interactive program perform well on a time-sharing system was challenging. The solution, originally proposed by Peter Deutsch at MIT, was to engineer a computer specifically designed to run Lisp programs. These Lisp machines, as I described in &lt;a href=&quot;https://twobithistory.org/2018/09/30/chaosnet.html&quot;&gt;my last post on Chaosnet&lt;/a&gt;, would give each user a dedicated processor optimized for Lisp. They would also eventually come with development environments written entirely in Lisp for hardcore Lisp programmers. Lisp machines, devised in an awkward moment at the tail of the minicomputer era but before the full flowering of the microcomputer revolution, were high-performance personal computers for the programming elite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a while, it seemed as if Lisp machines would be the wave of the future. Several companies sprang into existence and raced to commercialize the technology. The most successful of these companies was called Symbolics, founded by veterans of the MIT AI Lab. Throughout the 1980s, Symbolics produced a line of computers known as the 3600 series, which were popular in the AI field and in industries requiring high-powered computing. The 3600 series computers featured large screens, bit-mapped graphics, a mouse interface, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/gV5obrYaogU?t=201&quot;&gt;powerful graphics and animation software&lt;/a&gt;. These were impressive machines that enabled impressive programs. For example, Bob Culley, who worked in robotics research and contacted me via Twitter, was able to implement and visualize a path-finding algorithm on a Symbolics 3650 in 1985. He explained to me that bit-mapped graphics and object-oriented programming (available on Lisp machines via &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flavors_(programming_language)&quot;&gt;the Flavors extension&lt;/a&gt;) were very new in the 1980s. Symbolics was the cutting edge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://twobithistory.org/images/symbolics.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bob Culley's path-finding program.&quot;/&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bob Culley’s path-finding program.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result, Symbolics machines were outrageously expensive. The Symbolics 3600 cost $110,000 in 1983.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:16:1&quot;/&gt; So most people could only marvel at the power of Lisp machines and the wizardry of their Lisp-writing operators from afar. But marvel they did. &lt;em&gt;Byte Magazine&lt;/em&gt; featured Lisp and Lisp machines several times from 1979 through to the end of the 1980s. In the August, 1979 issue, a special on Lisp, the magazine’s editor raved about the new machines being developed at MIT with “gobs of memory” and “an advanced operating system.”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:17&quot;/&gt; He thought they sounded so promising that they would make the two prior years—which saw the launch of the Apple II, the Commodore PET, and the TRS-80—look boring by comparison. A half decade later, in 1985, a &lt;em&gt;Byte Magazine&lt;/em&gt; contributor described writing Lisp programs for the “sophisticated, superpowerful Symbolics 3670” and urged his audience to learn Lisp, claiming it was both “the language of choice for most people working in AI” and soon to be a general-purpose programming language as well.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:18&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I asked Paul McJones, who has done lots of Lisp &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.softwarepreservation.org/projects/LISP/&quot;&gt;preservation work&lt;/a&gt; for the Computer History Museum in Mountain View, about when people first began talking about Lisp as if it were a gift from higher-dimensional beings. He said that the inherent properties of the language no doubt had a lot to do with it, but he also said that the close association between Lisp and the powerful artificial intelligence applications of the 1960s and 1970s probably contributed too. When Lisp machines became available for purchase in the 1980s, a few more people outside of places like MIT and Stanford were exposed to Lisp’s power and the legend grew. Today, Lisp machines and Symbolics are little remembered, but they helped keep the mystique of Lisp alive through to the late 1980s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;theory-c-learn-to-program&quot;&gt;Theory C: Learn to Program&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1985, MIT professors Harold Abelson and Gerald Sussman, along with Sussman’s wife, Julie Sussman, published a textbook called &lt;em&gt;Structure and Interpretation of Computer Programs&lt;/em&gt;. The textbook introduced readers to programming using the language Scheme, a dialect of Lisp. It was used to teach MIT’s introductory programming class for two decades. My hunch is that SICP (as the title is commonly abbreviated) about doubled Lisp’s “mystique factor.” SICP took Lisp and showed how it could be used to illustrate deep, almost philosophical concepts in the art of computer programming. Those concepts were general enough that any language could have been used, but SICP’s authors chose Lisp. As a result, Lisp’s reputation was augmented by the notoriety of this bizarre and brilliant book, which has intrigued generations of programmers (and also become &lt;a href=&quot;https://knowyourmeme.com/forums/meme-research/topics/47038-structure-and-interpretation-of-computer-programs-hugeass-image-dump-for-evidence&quot;&gt;a very strange meme&lt;/a&gt;). Lisp had always been “McCarthy’s elegant formalism”; now it was also “that language that teaches you the hidden secrets of programming.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s worth dwelling for a while on how weird SICP really is, because I think the book’s weirdness and Lisp’s weirdness get conflated today. The weirdness starts with the book’s cover. It depicts a wizard or alchemist approaching a table, prepared to perform some sort of sorcery. In one hand he holds a set of calipers or a compass, in the other he holds a globe inscribed with the words “eval” and “apply.” A woman opposite him gestures at the table; in the background, the Greek letter lambda floats in mid-air, radiating light.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://twobithistory.org/images/sicp.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The cover art for SICP.&quot;/&gt;&lt;em&gt;The cover art for SICP.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honestly, what is going on here? Why does the table have animal feet? Why is the woman gesturing at the table? What is the significance of the inkwell? Are we supposed to conclude that the wizard has unlocked the hidden mysteries of the universe, and that those mysterious consist of the “eval/apply” loop and the Lambda Calculus? It would seem so. This image alone must have done an enormous amount to shape how people talk about Lisp today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the text of the book itself is often just as weird. SICP is unlike most other computer science textbooks that you have ever read. Its authors explain in the foreword to the book that the book is not merely about how to program in Lisp—it is instead about “three foci of phenomena: the human mind, collections of computer programs, and the computer.”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:19&quot;/&gt; Later, they elaborate, describing their conviction that programming shouldn’t be considered a discipline of computer science but instead should be considered a new notation for “procedural epistemology.”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:20&quot;/&gt; Programs are a new way of structuring thought that only incidentally get fed into computers. The first chapter of the book gives a brief tour of Lisp, but most of the book after that point is about much more abstract concepts. There is a discussion of different programming paradigms, a discussion of the nature of “time” and “identity” in object-oriented systems, and at one point a discussion of how synchronization problems may arise because of fundamental constraints on communication that play a role akin to the fixed speed of light in the theory of relativity.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:21&quot;/&gt; It’s heady stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All this isn’t to say that the book is bad. It’s a wonderful book. It discusses important programming concepts at a higher level than anything else I have read, concepts that I had long wondered about but didn’t quite have the language to describe. It’s impressive that an introductory programming textbook can move so quickly to describing the fundamental shortfalls of object-oriented programming and the benefits of functional languages that minimize mutable state. It’s mind-blowing that this then turns into a discussion of how a stream paradigm, perhaps something like today’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://rxjs-dev.firebaseapp.com/&quot;&gt;RxJS&lt;/a&gt;, can give you the best of both worlds. SICP distills the essence of high-level program design in a way reminiscent of McCarthy’s original Lisp paper. The first thing you want to do after reading it is get your programmer friends to read it; if they look it up, see the cover, but then don’t read it, all they take away is that some mysterious, fundamental “eval/apply” thing gives magicians special powers over tables with animal feet. I would be deeply impressed in their shoes too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But maybe SICP’s most important contribution was to elevate Lisp from curious oddity to pedagogical must-have. Well before SICP, people told each other to learn Lisp as a way of getting better at programming. The 1979 Lisp issue of &lt;em&gt;Byte Magazine&lt;/em&gt; is testament to that fact. The same editor that raved about MIT’s new Lisp machines also explained that the language was worth learning because it “represents a different point of view from which to analyze problems.”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:22&quot;/&gt; But SICP presented Lisp as more than just a foil for other languages; SICP used Lisp as an &lt;em&gt;introductory&lt;/em&gt; language, implicitly making the argument that Lisp is the best language in which to grasp the fundamentals of computer programming. When programmers today tell each other to try Lisp before they die, they arguably do so in large part because of SICP. After all, the language &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brainfuck&quot;&gt;Brainfuck&lt;/a&gt; presumably offers “a different point of view from which to analyze problems.” But people learn Lisp instead because they know that, for twenty years or so, the Lisp point of view was thought to be so useful that MIT taught Lisp to undergraduates before anything else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;lisp-comes-back&quot;&gt;Lisp Comes Back&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same year that SICP was released, Bjarne Stroustrup published the first edition of &lt;em&gt;The C++ Programming Language&lt;/em&gt;, which brought object-oriented programming to the masses. A few years later, the market for Lisp machines collapsed and the AI winter began. For the next decade and change, C++ and then Java would be the languages of the future and Lisp would be left out in the cold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is of course impossible to pinpoint when people started getting excited about Lisp again. But that may have happened after Paul Graham, Y-Combinator co-founder and Hacker News creator, published a series of influential essays pushing Lisp as the best language for startups. In his essay &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.paulgraham.com/avg.html&quot;&gt;“Beating the Averages,”&lt;/a&gt; for example, Graham argued that Lisp macros simply made Lisp more powerful than other languages. He claimed that using Lisp at his own startup, Viaweb, helped him develop features faster than his competitors were able to. &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20061004035628/http://wiki.alu.org/Chris-Perkins&quot;&gt;Some programmers at least&lt;/a&gt; were persuaded. But the vast majority of programmers did not switch to Lisp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What happened instead is that more and more Lisp-y features have been incorporated into everyone’s favorite programming languages. Python got list comprehensions. C# got Linq. Ruby got… well, Ruby &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.randomhacks.net/2005/12/03/why-ruby-is-an-acceptable-lisp/&quot;&gt;is a Lisp&lt;/a&gt;. As Graham noted even back in 2001, “the default language, embodied in a succession of popular languages, has gradually evolved toward Lisp.”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:23&quot;/&gt; Though other languages are gradually becoming like Lisp, Lisp itself somehow manages to retain its special reputation as that mysterious language that few people understand but everybody should learn. In 1980, on the occasion of Lisp’s 20th anniversary, McCarthy wrote that Lisp had survived as long as it had because it occupied “some kind of approximate local optimum in the space of programming languages.”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:24&quot;/&gt; That understates Lisp’s real influence. Lisp hasn’t survived for over half a century because programmers have begrudgingly conceded that it is the best tool for the job decade after decade; in fact, it has survived even though most programmers do not use it at all. Thanks to its origins and use in artificial intelligence research and perhaps also the legacy of SICP, Lisp continues to fascinate people. Until we can imagine God creating the world with some newer language, Lisp isn’t going anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you enjoyed this post, more like it come out every two weeks! Follow &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/TwoBitHistory&quot;&gt;@TwoBitHistory&lt;/a&gt; on Twitter or subscribe to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://twobithistory.org/feed.xml&quot;&gt;RSS feed&lt;/a&gt; to make sure you know when a new post is out.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Previously on TwoBitHistory…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot; readability=&quot;5.1949685534591&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;This week's post: A look at Chaosnet, the network that gave us the &quot;CH&quot; DNS class.&lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/dC7xqPYzi5&quot;&gt;https://t.co/dC7xqPYzi5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
— TwoBitHistory (@TwoBitHistory) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/TwoBitHistory/status/1046437600658169856?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;September 30, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 02:20:36 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>chwolfe</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://twobithistory.org/images/logo.png</og:image>
<og:url>https://twobithistory.org/2018/10/14/lisp.html</og:url>
<og:title>How Lisp Became God's Own Programming Language</og:title>
<og:description>A look at the fascinating history behind the one programming language with magical powers.</og:description>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://twobithistory.org/2018/10/14/lisp.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Paul Allen has died</title>
<link>https://www.cnbc.com/2018/10/15/microsoft-co-founder-paul-allen-dies-of-cancer-at-age-65.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.cnbc.com/2018/10/15/microsoft-co-founder-paul-allen-dies-of-cancer-at-age-65.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;group&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;inline_quotes&quot; data-gdsid=&quot;25619&quot; data-inline-quote-symbol=&quot;MSFT&quot; href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/quotes/?symbol=MSFT&quot;&gt;Microsoft&lt;/a&gt; Co-Founder Paul Allen died from complications of non-Hodgkin's lymphoma on Monday afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Allen's Vulcan Inc. announced that he died in Seattle at 65 years old.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;embed-container twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;inline_asset&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/VulcanInc/status/1051957360455892992&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;@VulcanInc: It is with deep sadness that we announce the death of @PaulGAllen, our founder and noted technologist, philanthropist, community builder, conservationist, musician and supporter of the arts. All of us who worked with Paul feel an inexpressible loss today.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Allen's sister, Jody, said he was &quot;a remarkable individual on every level.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;While most knew Paul Allen as a technologist and philanthropist, for us he was a much-loved brother and uncle, and an exceptional friend. Paul's family and friends were blessed to experience his wit, warmth, his generosity and deep concern,&quot; she said in a statement. &quot;For all the demands on his schedule, there was always time for family and friends. At this time of loss and grief for us – and so many others – we are profoundly grateful for the care and concern he demonstrated every day.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Allen ranked among the world's wealthiest individuals. As of Monday afternoon, he ranked 44th on &lt;a class=&quot;inline_asset&quot; href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/billionaires/#29058880251c&quot;&gt;Forbes' 2018 list of billionaires&lt;/a&gt; with an estimated net worth of more than $20 billion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through Vulcan, Allen's network of philanthropic efforts and organizations, the Microsoft co-founder supported research in artificial intelligence and new frontier technologies. The group also invested in Seattle's cultural institutions and the revitalization of parts of the city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Allen owned two professional sports teams, the NFL Seattle Seahawks and NBA Portland Trailblazers. He was also an electric guitarist who occasionally jammed with celebrity musicians including Bono and Mick Jagger, and a huge music fan. He funded and designed the Experience Music Project in Seattle, devoted to the history of rock music and dedicated to his musical hero Jimi Hendrix. (It has since been re-christened the &lt;a class=&quot;inline_asset&quot; href=&quot;https://www.mopop.org/&quot;&gt;Museum of Pop Culture&lt;/a&gt;.) The building was designed by architect Frank Gehry to resemble a melted electric guitar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vulcan CEO Bill Hilf said, &quot;All of us who had the honor of working with Paul feel inexpressible loss today.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;He possessed a remarkable intellect and a passion to solve some of the world's most difficult problems, with the conviction that creative thinking and new approaches could make profound and lasting impact,&quot; Hilf said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earlier this month, Allen revealed that he had started treatment for non-Hodgkin's lymphoma, the same type of cancer he was treated for in 2009. In 1983, Allen left the company he founded with Bill Gates when he was first diagnosed with Hodgkin's disease, which he defeated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bill Gates, who co-founded Microsoft with Allen, said that &quot;personal computing would not have existed without him&quot;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;I am heartbroken by the passing of one of my oldest and dearest friends, Paul Allen. From our early days together at Lakeside School, through our partnership in the creation of Microsoft, to some of our joint philanthropic projects over the years, Paul was a true partner and dear friend. Personal computing would not have existed without him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Paul wasn't content with starting one company. He channeled his intellect and compassion into a second act focused on improving people's lives and strengthening communities in Seattle and around the world. He was fond of saying, &quot;If it has the potential to do good, then we should do it.&quot; That's the kind of person he was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul loved life and those around him, and we all cherished him in return. He deserved much more time, but his contributions to the world of technology and philanthropy will live on for generations to come. I will miss him tremendously.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Current Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella said Allen made &lt;a class=&quot;inline_asset&quot; href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:6457724980540121088/&quot;&gt;&quot;indispensible&quot; contributions to Microsoft&lt;/a&gt; and the technology industry. Nadella also said he learned a lot from Allen and will continue to be inspired by him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;As co-founder of Microsoft, in his own quiet and persistent way, he created magical products, experiences and institutions, and in doing so, he changed the world,&quot; Nadella said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Former Microsoft CEO Steve Ballmer called Allen a &quot;truly wonderful, bright and inspiring person.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;embed-container twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;inline_asset&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/steven_ballmer/status/1051962323227856897?s=12&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;@steven_ballmer: Paul was a truly wonderful, bright and inspiring person—and a great friend. I will miss him&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steven Sinofsky, former president of Microsoft's Windows division, said Allen &quot;did so much to shape lives with computing and his later work in science, community, and research.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;embed-container twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;inline_asset&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/stevesi/status/1051959374233489408&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;@stevesi: Microsoft co-founder Paul Allen dies Paul was an original and a dear person who did so much to shape lives with computing and his later work in science, community, and research. I am so deeply saddened by his passing. He will be missed. RIP Paul.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seahawks Coach Pete Carroll said he was deeply saddened by Allen's death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;embed-container twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;inline_asset&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/petecarroll/status/1051965960830181376?s=21&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;@PeteCarroll: Deeply saddened by the passing of @PaulGAllen. I'll miss him greatly. His gracious leadership and tremendous inspiration will never be forgotten. The world is a better place because of Paul's passion, commitment, and selflessness. His legacy will live on forever.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NFL Commissioner Roger Goodell said Allen was &quot;the driving force behind keeping the NFL in the Pacific Northwest.&quot; Goodell said he valued Allen's advice on a wide range of subjects and sent his condolences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;His passion for the game, combined with his quiet determination, led to a model organization on and off the field. He worked tirelessly alongside our medical advisers to identify new ways to make the game safer and protect our players from unnecessary risk&quot; Goodell said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Trail Blazers tweeted, &quot;We miss you. We thank you. We love you.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;embed-container twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;inline_asset&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/trailblazers/status/1051962568292458496&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;@trailblazers: We miss you. We thank you. We love you.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Allen's death was met with an outpouring of condolences from tech leaders. Google CEO Sundar Pichai said with Allen's death, the world has &quot;lost a great technology pioneer today.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;embed-container twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;inline_asset&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/sundarpichai/status/1051969167618801664?s=21&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;@sundarpichai: We lost a great technology pioneer today - thank you Paul Allen for your immense contributions to the world through your work and your philanthropy. Thoughts are with his family and the entire Microsoft community.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple CEO Tim Cook called him a &quot;pioneer&quot; and a &quot;force for good.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;embed-container twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;inline_asset&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/tim_cook/status/1051976402126270464?s=12&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;@timcook Our industry has lost a pioneer and our world has lost a force for good. We send our deepest condolences to Paul's friends, the Allen family and everyone at Microsoft.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Salesforce CEO Marc Benioff said he was saddened by Allen's passing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;embed-container twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;inline_asset&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Benioff/status/1051971422296264704&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;@Benioff: Saddened by the passing of Paul Allen a great leader in tech and a man of all seasons who fully enjoyed his life and wealth yet also gave back to the world at scale. I was especially impressed with how he took care of the Oceans. May the one who brings peace bring peace to all.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazon CEO Jeff Bezos praised his &quot;relentless&quot; push forward in technology:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;embed-container twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;inline_asset&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/JeffBezos/status/1051983010722013184&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;@JeffBezos: Very sad to hear of Paul Allen's passing. His passion for invention and pushing forward inspired so many. He was relentless to the end. My heart goes out to Paul's family and friends.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— CNBC's Matt Rosoff, Ryan Ruggiero and Reuters contributed to this report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;group&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clarification: This story has been updated to reflect that Microsoft Co-Founder Paul Allen left the company after being diagnosed with Hodgkin's disease. A previous version mischaracterized the timeline of his departure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 22:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>coloneltcb</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.cnbc.com/2018/10/15/microsoft-co-founder-paul-allen-dies-of-cancer-at-age-65.html</og:url>
<og:image>https://fm.cnbc.com/applications/cnbc.com/resources/img/editorial/2018/10/15/105508389-1539640789034gettyimages-526380830.1910x1000.jpeg</og:image>
<og:title>Microsoft co-founder Paul Allen dies of cancer at age 65</og:title>
<og:description>Earlier this month, Allen revealed that he had started treatment for non-Hodgkin's lymphoma, the same type of cancer he was treated for in 2009.</og:description>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.cnbc.com/2018/10/15/microsoft-co-founder-paul-allen-dies-of-cancer-at-age-65.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Twilio to Acquire Sendgrid</title>
<link>https://www.twilio.com/press/releases/release_twilio_acquires_sendgrid</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.twilio.com/press/releases/release_twilio_acquires_sendgrid</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Accelerates Twilio’s Mission to Fuel the Future of Communications&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Brings Together the Two Leading Communication Platforms for Developers&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Combination to Create One, Best-in-Class Cloud Communications Platform for Companies to Communicate with Customers Across Every Channel&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Twilio &amp;amp; SendGrid Together Serve Millions of Developers, Have 100,000+ Customers, and Have a Greater than $700 Million Annualized Revenue Run Rate*&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twilio (NYSE:TWLO) and SendGrid today announced that they have entered into a definitive agreement for Twilio to acquire SendGrid in an all-stock transaction valued at approximately $2 billion. At the exchange ratio of 0.485 shares of Twilio Class A common stock per share of SendGrid common stock, this price equates to approximately $36.92 per share based on today’s closing prices. The transaction is expected to close in the first half of 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adding the leading email API platform to the leading cloud communications platform can drive tremendous value to the combined customer bases. The resulting company would offer developers a single, best-in-class platform to manage all of their important communication channels -- voice, messaging, video, and now email as well. Together, the companies currently drive more than half a trillion customer interactions annualized*, and growing rapidly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Increasingly, our customers are asking us to solve all of their strategic communications challenges - regardless of channel. Email is a vital communications channel for companies around the world, and so it was important to us to include this capability in our platform,&quot; said Jeff Lawson, Twilio's co-founder and chief executive officer. &quot;The two companies share the same vision, the same model, and the same values. We believe this is a once-in-a-lifetime opportunity to bring together the two leading developer-focused communications platforms to create the unquestioned platform of choice for all companies looking to transform their customer engagement.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This is a tremendous day for all SendGrid customers, employees and shareholders,” said Sameer Dholakia, SendGrid’s chief executive officer. “Our two companies have always shared a common goal - to create powerful communications experiences for businesses by enabling developers to easily embed communications into the software they are building. Our mission is to help our customers deliver communications that drive engagement and growth, and this combination will allow us to accelerate that mission for our customers.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Details Regarding the Proposed SendGrid Acquisition&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The boards of directors of Twilio and SendGrid have each approved the transaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under the terms of the transaction, Twilio Merger Subsidiary, Inc., a Delaware corporation and a wholly-owned subsidiary of Twilio, will be merged with and into SendGrid, with SendGrid surviving as a wholly-owned subsidiary of Twilio. At closing, each outstanding share of SendGrid common stock will be converted into the right to receive 0.485 shares of Twilio Class A common stock, which represents a per share price for SendGrid common stock of $36.92 based on the closing price of Twilio Class A common stock on October 15, 2018. The exchange ratio represents a 14% premium over the average exchange ratio for the ten calendar days ending, October 15, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The transaction is expected to close in the first half of 2019, subject to the satisfaction of customary closing conditions, including shareholder approvals by each of SendGrid’s and Twilio’s respective stockholders and the expiration of the applicable waiting period under the Hart-Scott-Rodino Antitrust Improvements Act. Certain stockholders of SendGrid owning approximately 6% of the outstanding SendGrid shares have entered into voting agreements and certain stockholders of Twilio who control approximately 33% of total Twilio voting power have entered into voting agreements, or proxies, pursuant to which they have agreed, among other things, and subject to the terms and conditions of the agreements, to vote in favor of the SendGrid acquisition and the issuance of Twilio shares in connection with the SendGrid acquisition, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goldman Sachs &amp;amp; Co. LLC is serving as exclusive financial advisor to Twilio and Goodwin Procter LLP is acting as legal counsel to Twilio. Morgan Stanley &amp;amp; Co. LLC. is serving as exclusive financial advisor to SendGrid and Cooley LLP and Skadden, Arps, Slate, Meagher &amp;amp; Flom LLP are acting as legal counsel to SendGrid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q3 2018 Results and Guidance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Both companies will report their respective financial results for the three months ended September 30, 2018 on November 6, 2018. However, both Twilio and SendGrid are announcing that they have exceeded the guidance provided on Aug. 6th and July 31st, respectively, for their third fiscal quarters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guidance for the combined company will be provided after the proposed transaction has closed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conference Call Information&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Twilio will host a conference call today, October 15, 2018, to discuss the SendGrid acquisition, at 2:30 p.m. Pacific Time, 5:30 p.m. Eastern Time. A live webcast of the conference call, as well as a replay of the call, will be available at &lt;a href=&quot;https://investors.Twilio.com&quot;&gt;https://investors.Twilio.com&lt;/a&gt;. The conference call can also be accessed by dialing (844) 453-4207, or +1 (647) 253-8638 (outside the U.S. and Canada). The conference ID is 6976357. Following the completion of the call through 11:59 p.m. Eastern Time on Oct. 22, 2018, a replay will be available by dialing (800) 585-8367 or +1 (416) 621-4642 (outside the U.S. and Canada) and entering passcode 6976357. Twilio has used, and intends to continue to use, its investor relations website as a means of disclosing material non-public information and for complying with its disclosure obligations under Regulation FD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About SendGrid&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;SendGrid is a leading digital communications platform enabling businesses to engage with their customers via email reliably, effectively and at scale. A leader in email deliverability, SendGrid has processed over 45 billion emails each month for internet and mobile-based customers as well as more traditional enterprises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Additional Information and Where To Find It&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;In connection with the proposed transaction between Twilio and SendGrid, Twilio will file a Registration Statement on Form S-4 and joint proxy statement/prospectus forming a part thereof. BEFORE MAKING ANY VOTING DECISION, TWILIO’S AND SENDGRID’S RESPECTIVE INVESTORS AND STOCKHOLDERS ARE URGED TO READ THE REGISTRATION STATEMENT AND JOINT PROXY STATEMENT/PROSPECTUS (INCLUDING ANY AMENDMENTS OR SUPPLEMENTS THERETO) REGARDING THE PROPOSED TRANSACTION WHEN THEY BECOME AVAILABLE BECAUSE THEY WILL CONTAIN IMPORTANT INFORMATION. Investors and security holders will be able to obtain free copies of the Registration Statement, the joint proxy statement/prospectus (when available) and other relevant documents filed or that will be filed by Twilio or SendGrid with the SEC through the website maintained by the SEC at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sec.gov&quot;&gt;http://www.sec.gov&lt;/a&gt;. They may also be obtained for free by contacting Twilio Investor Relations by email at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:ir@twilio.com&quot;&gt;ir@twilio.com&lt;/a&gt; or by phone at 415-801-3799 or by contacting SendGrid Investor Relations by email at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:ir@sendgrid.com&quot;&gt;ir@sendgrid.com&lt;/a&gt; or by phone at 720-588-4496, or on Twilio’s and SendGrid’s websites at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.investors.twilio.com&quot;&gt;www.investors.twilio.com&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.investors.sendgrid.com&quot;&gt;www.investors.sendgrid.com&lt;/a&gt;, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No Offer or Solicitation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This communication does not constitute an offer to sell or the solicitation of an offer to buy any securities nor a solicitation of any vote or approval with respect to the proposed transaction or otherwise. No offering of securities shall be made except by means of a prospectus meeting the requirements of Section 10 of the U.S. Securities Act of 1933, as amended, and otherwise in accordance with applicable law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Participants in the Solicitation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Each of Twilio and SendGrid and their respective directors and executive officers may be deemed to be participants in the solicitation of proxies from their respective shareholders in connection with the proposed transaction. Information regarding the persons who may, under the rules of the SEC, be deemed participants in the solicitation of Twilio and SendGrid shareholders in connection with the proposed transaction and a description of their direct and indirect interests, by security holdings or otherwise will be set forth in the Registration Statement and joint proxy statement/prospectus when filed with the SEC. Information regarding Twilio’s executive officers and directors is included in Twilio’s Proxy Statement for its 2018 Annual Meeting of Stockholders, filed with the SEC on April 27, 2018 and information regarding SendGrid’s executive officers and directors is included in SendGrid’s Proxy Statement for its 2018 Annual Meeting of Stockholders, filed with the SEC on April 20, 2018.&lt;br/&gt;Additional information regarding the interests of the participants in the solicitation of proxies in connection with the proposed transaction will be included in the joint proxy statement/prospectus and other relevant materials Twilio and SendGrid intend to file with the SEC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use of Forward-Looking Statements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This communication contains “forward-looking statements” within the meaning of federal securities laws. Forward-looking statements may contain words such as “believes”, “anticipates”, “estimates”, “expects”, “intends”, “aims”, “potential”, “will”, “would”, “could”, “considered”, “likely” and words and terms of similar substance used in connection with any discussion of future plans, actions or events identify forward-looking statements. All statements, other than historical facts, including statements regarding the expected timing of the closing of the proposed transaction and the expected benefits of the proposed transaction, are forward-looking statements. These statements are based on management’s current expectations, assumptions, estimates and beliefs. While Twilio believes these expectations, assumptions, estimates and beliefs are reasonable, such forward-looking statements are only predictions, and are subject to a number of risks and uncertainties that could cause actual results to differ materially from those described in the forward-looking statements.&lt;br/&gt;The following factors, among others, could cause actual results to differ materially from those described in the forward-looking statements: (i) failure of Twilio or SendGrid to obtain stockholder approval as required for the proposed transaction; (ii) failure to obtain governmental and regulatory approvals required for the closing of the proposed transaction, or delays in governmental and regulatory approvals that may delay the transaction or result in the imposition of conditions that could reduce the anticipated benefits from the proposed transaction or cause the parties to abandon the proposed transaction; successful completion of the proposed transaction; (iii) failure to satisfy the conditions to the closing of the proposed transactions; (iv) unexpected costs, liabilities or delays in connection with or with respect to the proposed transaction; (v) the effect of the announcement of the proposed transaction on the ability of SendGrid or Twilio to retain and hire key personnel and maintain relationships with customers, suppliers and others with whom SendGrid or Twilio does business, or on SendGrid’s or Twilio’s operating results and business generally; (vi) the outcome of any legal proceeding related to the proposed transaction; (vii) the challenges and costs of integrating, restructuring and achieving anticipated synergies and benefits of the proposed transaction and the risk that the anticipated benefits of the proposed transaction may not be fully realized or take longer to realize than expected; (vii) competitive pressures in the markets in which Twilio and SendGrid operate; (viii) the occurrence of any event, change or other circumstances that could give rise to the termination of the merger agreement; and (ix) other risks to the consummation of the proposed transaction, including the risk that the proposed transaction will not be consummated within the expected time period or at all. Additional factors that may affect the future results of Twilio and SendGrid are set forth in their respective filings with the SEC, including each of Twilio’s and SendGrid’s most recently filed Annual Report on Form 10-K, subsequent Quarterly Reports on Form 10-Q, Current Reports on Form 8-K and other filings with the SEC, which are available on the SEC’s website at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sec.gov&quot;&gt;www.sec.gov&lt;/a&gt;. See in particular Part II, Item 1A of Twilio’s Quarterly Report on Form 10-Q for the quarter ended June 30, 2018 under the heading “Risk Factors” and Part II, Item 1A of SendGrid’s Quarterly Report on Form 10-Q for the quarter ended June 30, 2018 under the heading “Risk Factors.” The risks and uncertainties described above and in Twilio’s most recent Quarterly Report on Form 10-Q and SendGrid’s most recent Quarterly Report on Form 10-Q are not exclusive and further information concerning Twilio and SendGrid and their respective businesses, including factors that potentially could materially affect their respective businesses, financial condition or operating results, may emerge from time to time. Readers are urged to consider these factors carefully in evaluating these forward-looking statements, and not to place undue reliance on any forward-looking statements. Readers should also carefully review the risk factors described in other documents that Twilio and SendGrid file from time to time with the SEC. The forward-looking statements in these materials speak only as of the date of these materials. Except as required by law, Twilio and SendGrid assume no obligation to update or revise these forward-looking statements for any reason, even if new information becomes available in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;* Annualized data for the quarterly period ended June 30, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Source: Twilio Inc.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 20:54:08 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>coloneltcb</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.twilio.com/press/releases/release_twilio_acquires_sendgrid</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Study shows massive insect loss</title>
<link>https://www.washingtonpost.com/science/2018/10/15/hyperalarming-study-shows-massive-insect-loss/?noredirect=on&amp;utm_term=.6e364be6ddca</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.washingtonpost.com/science/2018/10/15/hyperalarming-study-shows-massive-insect-loss/?noredirect=on&amp;utm_term=.6e364be6ddca</guid>
<description>&lt;div data-elm-loc=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;inline-content inline-photo inline-photo-normal&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/LabF-N1sgw4O8eTGYehZf3DxgYI=/480x0/arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/PYVRQXBIWREUVHWHEOM5BFUHWY.jpeg&quot; data-hi-res-src=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/nmfwK5o-CEuSYDXv5Iw9kOeiOGo=/545x0/arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/PYVRQXBIWREUVHWHEOM5BFUHWY.jpeg&quot; data-low-res-src=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/LabF-N1sgw4O8eTGYehZf3DxgYI=/480x0/arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/PYVRQXBIWREUVHWHEOM5BFUHWY.jpeg&quot; data-raw-src=&quot;https://arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/PYVRQXBIWREUVHWHEOM5BFUHWY.jpeg&quot; data-threshold=&quot;480&quot; class=&quot;unprocessed&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pb-caption&quot;&gt;The emerald anole, one of the main insect eaters in the Luquillo forest of Puerto Rico. (Brad Lister/PNAS)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;author-sig-line-wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author-sig-line&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author-byline&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author-wrapper&quot; data-authorname=&quot;Ben Guarino&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;author-hover-card&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author-headshot&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/people/ben-guarino/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/sRtAbVvTZtGoZynEk4wVZyrXrVs=/200x200/s3.amazonaws.com/arc-authors/washpost/8b9ee559-3d29-421c-9d83-e18d4c69b1b4.png&quot; class=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;author-name&quot; href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/people/ben-guarino/&quot;&gt;Ben Guarino&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author-bio&quot;&gt;Reporter covering biology, genetics, nature, paleontology and the culture of science&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;author-timestamp&quot; itemprop=&quot;datePublished&quot; content=&quot;2018-10-15T03:00-500&quot;&gt;October 15 at 3:00 PM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;2&quot;&gt;Insects around the world are in a crisis, according to a small but growing number of long-term studies showing dramatic declines in invertebrate populations. A &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/cgi/doi/10.1073/pnas.1722477115&quot;&gt;new report&lt;/a&gt; suggests that the problem is more widespread than scientists realized. Huge numbers of bugs have been lost in a pristine national forest in Puerto Rico, the study found, and the forest’s insect-eating animals have gone missing, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;3&quot;&gt;In 2014, an international team of biologists estimated that, in the past 35 years, the abundance of invertebrates such as beetles and bees had &lt;a href=&quot;http://science.sciencemag.org/content/345/6195/401.full&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;decreased by 45 percent&lt;/a&gt;. In places where long-term insect data are available, mainly in Europe, insect numbers are plummeting. A study last year showed a 76 percent &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/speaking-of-science/wp/2017/10/18/this-is-very-alarming-flying-insects-vanish-from-nature-preserves/?utm_term=.646ed11d4999&quot;&gt;decrease in flying insects&lt;/a&gt; in the past few decades in German nature preserves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;4&quot;&gt;The latest report, published Monday in the Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences, shows that this startling loss of insect abundance extends to the Americas. The study’s authors implicate climate change in the loss of tropical invertebrates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;5&quot;&gt;“This study in PNAS is a real wake-up call — a clarion call — that the phenomenon could be much, much bigger, and across many more ecosystems,” said &lt;a href=&quot;http://hydrodictyon.eeb.uconn.edu/people/dwagner/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;David Wagner&lt;/a&gt;, an expert in invertebrate conservation at the University of Connecticut who was not involved with this research. He added: “This is one of the most disturbing articles I have ever read.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div data-elm-loc=&quot;6&quot; class=&quot;inline-content inline-video&quot;&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;7&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://science.rpi.edu/biology/faculty/brad-lister&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Bradford&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://science.rpi.edu/biology/faculty/brad-lister&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Lister&lt;/a&gt;, a biologist at Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute in New York, has been studying rain forest insects in Puerto Rico since the 1970s. If Puerto Rico is the island of enchantment — “la isla del encanto” — then its rain forest is “the enchanted forest on the enchanted isle,” he said. Birds and coqui frogs trill beneath a 50-foot-tall emerald canopy. The forest, named El Yunque, is well-protected. Spanish King Alfonso XII claimed the jungle as a 19th-century royal preserve. Decades later, Theodore Roosevelt made it a national reserve, and El Yunque remains the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fs.usda.gov/main/elyunque/about-forest&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;only tropical rain forest&lt;/a&gt; in the National Forest system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;8&quot;&gt;“We went down in ’76, ’77 expressly to measure the resources: the insects and the insectivores in the rain forest, the birds, the frogs, the lizards,” Lister said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;9&quot;&gt;He came back nearly 40 years later, with his colleague Andrés García, an ecologist at the National Autonomous University of Mexico. What the scientists did not see on their return troubled them. “Boy, it was immediately obvious when we went into that forest,” Lister said. Fewer birds flitted overhead. The butterflies, once abundant, had all but vanished.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;10&quot;&gt;García and Lister once again measured the forest’s insects and other invertebrates, a group called arthropods that includes spiders and centipedes. The researchers trapped arthropods on the ground in plates covered in a sticky glue, and raised several more plates about three feet into the canopy. The researchers also swept nets over the brush hundreds of times, collecting the critters that crawled through the vegetation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;11&quot;&gt;Each technique revealed the biomass (the dry weight of all the captured invertebrates) had significantly decreased from 1976 to the present day. The sweep sample biomass decreased to a fourth or an eighth of what it had been. Between January 1977 and January 2013, the catch rate in the sticky ground traps fell 60-fold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;12&quot;&gt;“Everything is dropping,” Lister said. The most common invertebrates in the rain forest — the moths, the butterflies, the grasshoppers, the spiders and others — are all far less abundant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;13&quot;&gt;“Holy crap,” Wagner said of the 60-fold loss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;14&quot;&gt;Louisiana State University entomologist &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lsuagcenter.com/profiles/tschowalter&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Timothy Schowalter&lt;/a&gt;, who is not an author of the recent report, has studied this forest since the 1990s. The new research is consistent with his data, as well as the European biomass studies. “It takes these long-term sites, with consistent sampling across a long period of time, to document these trends,” he said. “I find their data pretty compelling.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;15&quot;&gt;The study authors also trapped anole lizards, which eat arthropods, in the rain forest. They compared these numbers with counts from the 1970s. Anole biomass dropped by more than 30 percent. Some anole species have altogether disappeared from the interior forest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;16&quot;&gt;Insect-eating frogs and birds plummeted, too. Another &lt;a href=&quot;https://luq.lter.network/data/luqmetadata173&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;research team&lt;/a&gt; used mist nets to capture birds in 1990, and again in 2005. Captures fell by about 50 percent. Garcia and Lister analyzed the data with an eye on the insectivores. The ruddy quail dove, which eats fruits and seeds, had no population change. A brilliant green bird called the &lt;a href=&quot;https://neotropical.birds.cornell.edu/Species-Account/nb/species/purtod1/overview&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Puerto Rican tody&lt;/a&gt;, which eats bugs almost exclusively, diminished by 90 percent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;17&quot;&gt;The food web appears to have been obliterated from the bottom. It’s credible that the authors link the cascade to arthropod loss, Schowalter said, because “you have all these different taxa showing the same trends — the insectivorous birds, frogs and lizards — but you don’t see those among seed-feeding birds.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;18&quot;&gt;Lister and Garcia attribute this crash to climate. In the same 40-year period as the arthropod crash, the average high temperature in the rain forest increased by 4 degrees Fahrenheit. The temperatures in the tropics stick to a narrow band. The invertebrates that live there, likewise, are adapted to these temperatures and fare poorly outside them; bugs cannot regulate their internal heat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div data-elm-loc=&quot;19&quot; class=&quot;inline-content inline-video&quot;&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;20&quot;&gt;A recent analysis of climate change and insects, published in August in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://science.sciencemag.org/content/361/6405/916&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;journal Science&lt;/a&gt;, predicts a decrease in tropical insect populations, according to an author of that study, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.uvm.edu/gund/profiles/scott-merrill&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Scott Merrill&lt;/a&gt;, who studies crop pests at the University of Vermont. In temperate regions farther from the equator, where insects can survive a wider range of temperatures, agricultural pests will devour more food as their metabolism increases, Merrill and his co-authors warned. But after a certain thermal threshold, insects will no longer lay eggs, he said, and their internal chemistry breaks down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;21&quot;&gt;The authors of a 2017 study of vanished flying insects in Germany suggested other possible culprits, including pesticides and habitat loss. Arthropods around the globe also have to contend with pathogens and invasive species.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;22&quot;&gt;“It’s bewildering, and I’m scared to death that it’s actually death by a thousand cuts,” Wagner said. “One of the scariest parts about it is that we don’t have an obvious smoking gun here.” A particular danger to these arthropods, in his view, was not temperature but droughts and lack of rainfall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;23&quot;&gt;Lister pointed out that, since 1969, pesticide use has fallen more than 80 percent in Puerto Rico. He does not know what else could be to blame. The study authors used a recent &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/03610918.2015.1122048?journalCode=lssp20&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;analytic method&lt;/a&gt;, invented by a professor of economics at Fordham University, to assess the role of heat. “It allows you to place a likelihood on variable X causing variable Y,” Lister said. “So we did that and then five out of our six populations we got the strongest possible support for heat causing those decreases in abundance of frogs and insects.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;24&quot;&gt;The authors sorted out the effects of weather like hurricanes and still saw a consistent trend, Schowalter said, which makes a convincing case for climate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;25&quot;&gt;“If anything, I think their results and caveats are understated. The gravity of their findings and ramifications for other animals, especially vertebrates, is hyperalarming,” Wagner said. But he is not convinced that climate change is the global driver of insect loss. “The decline of insects in northern Europe precedes that of climate change there,” he said. “Likewise, in New England, some tangible declines began in the 1950s.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;26&quot;&gt;No matter the cause, all of the scientists agreed that more people should pay attention to the bugpocalypse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;27&quot;&gt;“It’s a very scary thing,” Merrill said, that comes on the heels of a “gloomy, gloomy” U.N. report that estimated the world has little more than &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/energy-environment/2018/10/08/world-has-only-years-get-climate-change-under-control-un-scientists-say/?utm_term=.2bc091839d2c&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;a decade left&lt;/a&gt; to wrangle climate change under control. But “we can all step up,” he said, by using more fuel-efficient cars and turning off unused electronics. The Portland, Ore.-based Xerces Society, a nonprofit environmental group that promotes insect conservation, recommends planting a &lt;a href=&quot;https://xerces.org/pollinator-conservation/gardens/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;garden&lt;/a&gt; with native plants that flower throughout the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;28&quot;&gt;“Unfortunately, we have deaf ears in Washington,” Schowalter said. But those ears will listen at some point, he said, because our food supply will be in jeopardy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;29&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2016/02/27/science/decline-of-species-that-pollinate-poses-a-threat-to-global-food-supply-report-warns.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Thirty-five percent&lt;/a&gt; of the world’s plant crops require pollination by bees, wasps and other animals. And arthropods are more than just pollinators. They’re the planet’s wee custodians, toiling away in unnoticed or avoided corners. They chew up rotting wood and eat carrion. “And none of us want to have more carcasses around,” Schowalter said. Wild insects provide $57 billion worth of six-legged labor in the United States each year, according to a 2006 estimate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;30&quot;&gt;The loss of insects and arthropods could further rend the rain forest’s food web, Lister warned, causing plant species to go extinct without pollinators. “If the tropical forests go it will be yet another catastrophic failure of the whole Earth system,” he said, “that will feed back on human beings in an almost unimaginable way.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div data-elm-loc=&quot;31&quot; class=&quot;inline-content inline-video&quot;&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;32&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read more:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;33&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/speaking-of-science/wp/2017/10/18/this-is-very-alarming-flying-insects-vanish-from-nature-preserves/?utm_term=.48d0d82f757a&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;‘This is very alarming!’: Flying insects vanish from nature preserves&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;34&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/speaking-of-science/wp/2017/11/20/these-bizarre-flies-wear-bubbles-like-scuba-suits-to-dive-in-a-toxic-lake/?utm_term=.10ce7c718478&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Watch these bizarre flies dive underwater using bubbles like scuba suits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;35&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/speaking-of-science/wp/2017/10/25/this-bug-is-real-and-now-so-are-your-nightmares/?utm_term=.f4e9903e6208&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;This bug is real, and now so are your nightmares&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 19:29:19 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>pgrote</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.washingtonpost.com/science/2018/10/15/hyperalarming-study-shows-massive-insect-loss/</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/YBYAUUMjkiLyRRoGUQ_bAjE2JLA=/1484x0/arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/PYVRQXBIWREUVHWHEOM5BFUHWY.jpeg</og:image>
<og:title>‘Hyperalarming’ study shows massive insect loss</og:title>
<og:description>Insects are vanishing even in a pristine tropical forest, and an ecologist calls this &quot;one of the most disturbing articles I have ever read.”</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.washingtonpost.com/science/2018/10/15/hyperalarming-study-shows-massive-insect-loss/?noredirect=on</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Survey of YC female founders on sexual harassment, coercion by angels and VCs</title>
<link>https://blog.ycombinator.com/survey-of-yc-female-founders-on-sexual-harassment-and-coercion-by-angel-and-vc-investors/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.ycombinator.com/survey-of-yc-female-founders-on-sexual-harassment-and-coercion-by-angel-and-vc-investors/</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;loop-post-title single-title&quot;&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;loop-post-meta loop-post-meta-single&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;post-share-buttons&quot;/&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;post-date&quot;&gt;October 15, 2018&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot; readability=&quot;59.26614481409&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year we funded &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.projectcallisto.org/&quot;&gt;Callisto&lt;/a&gt;, a non-profit dedicated to building tech to combat sexual assault and harassment. During their time at YC, we helped Callisto send a survey to 125 of the 384 female founders who have participated in YC. They were asked if they’d ever been assaulted or coerced by an angel or VC investor in their startup career. We also created a formal process for founders in the YC community to report bad behavior by investors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, in coordination with Callisto, YC is sharing the results of this survey with the entire YC founder community and the startup community at large. Based on these results, we call upon the entire investor community to redouble its efforts to change this dynamic and abuse of power in the VC/angel investment community. YC has a &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.ycombinator.com/a-reminder-to-investors/&quot;&gt;zero-tolerance policy&lt;/a&gt; for inappropriate behavior and will ban any investor who acts inappropriately from our community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here are the results of the survey:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;88 YC female founders completed the survey&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;19 founders experienced one or more inappropriate incidents by angels or VCs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;18 experienced unwanted sexual overtures or sexual badgering&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;15 experienced sexual coercion or quid-pro-quo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4 experienced unwanted sexual contact&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When founders did report, their main reason was to protect others:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;“I wanted to make sure that other founders funded by this VC would NOT be in contact with this person, so I shared.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“I wanted other people to avoid being preyed upon by the same people.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When founders did not report, their main reason was to protect their company, or fear of retaliation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;“Did not want to endanger my company’s funding prospects”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“I was afraid of the consequences for my ability to get future funding.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“VCs would penalize women for coming forward by icing them out of social and professional situations and denying them funding opportunities, meaning the bad behavior rarely got outed.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here’s what YC is doing to combat harassment in the investor community:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;7.8396436525612&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are a YC founder who wishes to report inappropriate behavior by an investor, we have reporting system inside of Bookface (our website for YC founders). You can report at any time, even years after the incident took place. The report will remain confidential. We encourage other investors to set up similar reporting systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will also work with and support any YC founder who wants to take actions above and beyond reporting this behavior to YC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will iterate and call more attention to our reporting process in order to encourage more use of our reporting tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;5.6656346749226&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will continue to fund startups/non-profits that combat the unfair treatment of women in the workplace. In addition to funding &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.projectcallisto.org/&quot;&gt;Callisto&lt;/a&gt;, we have also funded &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tequitable.com/&quot;&gt;tEQuitable&lt;/a&gt; who is building a third-party, tech-enabled Ombuds platform for companies that addresses issues of bias, discrimination, and harassment in the workplace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here is what Callisto is doing to combat harassment in the investor community:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;3.5&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later this fall, they are launching Callisto for founders. Callisto detects serial perpetrators of sexual coercion and assault, and connects survivors to each other and their options for taking action to protect their community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Founders will be able to use Callisto to securely store the identities of perpetrators of sexual coercion and assault. These identities will be encrypted in a way that not even the Callisto team can view. If multiple founders name the same perpetrator, they will be referred to an attorney who can then decrypt the founder’s contact info and reach out to provide them with free advice on their options for coming forward, including the option to share information with other victims of the same perpetrator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;0% of female founders should be ever be harassed, coerced, or experience unwanted sexual contact by investors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Callisto chose to send the survey to the 125 founders who signed up for the YC female founder email list. They choose this group under the assumption that these founders would welcome being reached out to for the survey because they had signed up proactively to this email list. &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.ycombinator.com/survey-of-yc-female-founders-on-sexual-harassment-and-coercion-by-angel-and-vc-investors/#footnoteid1&quot;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;mc_embed_signup&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;mc_copy&quot;&gt;Sign up for weekly updates from Y Combinator.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 16:34:30 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>coloneltcb</dc:creator>
<og:title>Survey of YC female founders on sexual coercion and assault by angel and VC investors</og:title>
<og:url>https://blog.ycombinator.com/survey-of-yc-female-founders-on-sexual-harassment-and-coercion-by-angel-and-vc-investors/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>Earlier this year we funded Callisto, a non-profit dedicated to building tech to combat sexual assault and harassment. During their time at YC, we helped Callisto send a survey to YC female founders to ask if they’d ever been harassed by an angel or VC investor. We also created a formal process fo</og:description>
<og:image>https://ycombinator.wpengine.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/YC-logo-1200-1.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.ycombinator.com/survey-of-yc-female-founders-on-sexual-harassment-and-coercion-by-angel-and-vc-investors/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>How to Manage Connections Efficiently in Postgres, or Any Database</title>
<link>https://brandur.org/postgres-connections</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://brandur.org/postgres-connections</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;You start building your new project. You’ve heard good things about Postgres, so you choose it as your database. As advertised, it proves to be a satisfying tool and progress is good. You put your project into production for the first time and like you’d hoped, things go smoothly as Postgres turns out to be well-suited for production use as well.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first few months go well and traffic continues to ramp up, when suddenly a big spike of failures appears. You dig into the cause and see that your application is failing to open database connections. You find this chilling artifact littered throughout your logs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;FATAL: remaining connection slots are reserved for
non-replication superuser connections
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is one of the first major operational problems that new users are likely to encounter with Postgres, and one that might prove to be frustratingly persistent. Like the error suggests, the database is indicating that its total number of connection slots are limited, and that the limit has been reached.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ceiling is controlled by the &lt;code&gt;max_connections&lt;/code&gt; key in Postgres’ configuration, which defaults to 100. Almost every cloud Postgres provider like Google Cloud Platform or Heroku limit the number pretty carefully, with the largest databases topping out at 500 connections, and the smaller ones at much lower numbers like 20 or 25.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first sight this might seem a little counterintuitive. If the connection limit is a known problem, why not just configure a huge maximum to avoid it? As with many things in computing, the solution isn’t as simple as it might seem at first glance, and there are a number of factors that will limit the maximum number of connections that it’s practical to have; some obvious, and some not. Let’s take a closer look.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most direct constraint, but also probably the least important, is memory. Postgres is designed around a process model where a central Postmaster accepts incoming connections and forks child processes to handle them. Each of these “backend” processes starts out at around 5 MB in size, but may grow to be much larger depending on the data they’re accessing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brandur.org/assets/postgres-connections/process-model.svg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://brandur.org/assets/postgres-connections/process-model.svg&quot; class=&quot;overflowing&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
A simplified view of Postgres' forking process model.
&lt;p&gt;Since these days it’s pretty easy to procure a system where memory is abundant, the absolute memory ceiling often isn’t a main limiting factor. One that’s more subtle and more important is that the Postmaster and its backend processes use shared memory for communication, and parts of that shared space are global bottlenecks. For example, here’s the structure that tracks every ongoing process and transaction:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-c&quot;&gt;typedef struct PROC_HDR
{
    /* Array of PGPROC structures (not including dummies for prepared txns) */
    PGPROC         *allProcs;
    /* Array of PGXACT structures (not including dummies for prepared txns) */
    PGXACT         *allPgXact;

    ...
}

extern PGDLLIMPORT PROC_HDR *ProcGlobal;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Operations that might happen in any backend requires walking the entire list of processes or transactions. Adding a new process to the proc array necessitates taking an exclusive lock:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-c&quot;&gt;void
ProcArrayAdd(PGPROC *proc)
{
    ProcArrayStruct *arrayP = procArray;
    int            index;

    LWLockAcquire(ProcArrayLock, LW_EXCLUSIVE);

    ...
}
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a few such bottlenecks throughout the normal paths that Postgres uses to work, and they are of course in addition to the normal contention you’d expect to find around system resources like I/O or CPU.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cumulative effect is that within any given backend, performance is proportional to the number of all active backends in the wider system. I wrote a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/brandur/connections-test&quot;&gt;benchmark&lt;/a&gt; to demonstrate this effect: it spins up a cluster of parallel workers that each use their own connection to perform a transaction that inserts ten times, selects ten times, and deletes ten times before committing . Parallelism starts at 1, ramps up to 1000, and timing is measured for every transaction. You can see from the results that performance degrades slowly but surely as more active clients are introduced into the system:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brandur.org/assets/postgres-connections/contention@2x.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://brandur.org/assets/postgres-connections/contention.png&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/postgres-connections/contention@2x.png 2x, /assets/postgres-connections/contention.png 1x&quot; class=&quot;overflowing&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
Performance of a simple task degrading as the number of active connections in the database increases.
&lt;p&gt;So while it might be a little irking that platforms like Google Cloud and Heroku limit the total connections even on very big servers, they’re actually trying to help you. Performance in Postgres isn’t reliable when it’s scaled up to huge numbers of connections. Once you start brushing up against a big connection limit like 500, the right answer probably isn’t to increase it – it’s to re-evaluate how those connections are being used to and try to manage them more efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;connection-pool&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brandur.org/postgres-connections#connection-pool&quot;&gt;Connection pools&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A connection pool is a cache of database connections, usually local to a specific process. Its main advantage is improved performance – there’s a certain amount of overhead inherent to opening a new database connection in both the client and the server. After finishing with a connection, by checking it back into a pool instead of discarding it, the connection can be reused next time one is needed within the application. Connection pooling is built into many database adapters including Go’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://godoc.org/database/sql&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;database/sql&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Java’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Java_Database_Connectivity&quot;&gt;JDBC&lt;/a&gt;, or Active Record in Ruby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brandur.org/assets/postgres-connections/connection-pooling.svg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://brandur.org/assets/postgres-connections/connection-pooling.svg&quot; class=&quot;overflowing&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
A deployment with a number of nodes, each of which maintains a local pool of connections for their workers to use.
&lt;p&gt;Connection pools also help manage connections more efficiently. They’re configured with a maximum number of connections that the pool can hold which makes the total number of connections that you can expect a single deployed node to use deterministic. By writing application workers to only acquire a connection when they’re serving a request, those per-node pools of connections can be shared between a much larger pool of workers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A limitation of connection pools is that they’re usually only effective in languages that can be deployed within a single process. Rails implements a connection pool in Active Record, but because Ruby isn’t capable of real parallelism, it’s common to use forking servers like Unicorn or Puma. This makes those connection pools much less effective because each process needs to maintain its own .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;mvc&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brandur.org/postgres-connections#mvc&quot;&gt;Minimum viable checkouts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For any given span of work, very often it’s possible to identify a critical span in the middle where core domain logic is being run, and where a database connection needs to be held. To take an HTTP request for example, there’s usually a phase at the beginning where a worker is reading a request’s body, decoding and validating its payload, and performing other peripheral operations like rate limiting before moving on to the application’s core logic. After that logic is executed there’s a similar phase at the end where it’s serializing and sending the response, emitting metrics, performing logging, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brandur.org/assets/postgres-connections/minimum-viable-checkout.svg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://brandur.org/assets/postgres-connections/minimum-viable-checkout.svg&quot; class=&quot;overflowing&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
Workers should only hold connections as long as they're needed. There's work before and after core application logic where no connection is needed.
&lt;p&gt;Workers should only have a connection checked out of the pool while that core logic is executing. This &lt;strong&gt;minimum viable checkout&lt;/strong&gt; technique maximizes the efficient use of connections by minimizing the amount of time any given worker holds one, allowing a pool of connections to be feasibly shared amongst a much larger pool of workers. Idle workers don’t hold any connections at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;foreign-mutations&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brandur.org/postgres-connections#foreign-mutations&quot;&gt;Releasing connections around foreign mutations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve written previously about breaking units of application work into &lt;a href=&quot;https://brandur.org/idempotency-keys#atomic-phases&quot;&gt;atomic phases&lt;/a&gt; around where an application is making requests to foreign APIs. Utilization can be made even more efficient by making sure to release connections back to the pool while that slow network I/O is in flight (an application should not be in a transaction during while mutating foreign state anyway), and reacquire them afterwards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;pgbouncer&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brandur.org/postgres-connections#pgbouncer&quot;&gt;PgBouncer &amp;amp; inter-node pooling&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Connection pools and minimum viable checkouts will go a long way, but you may still reach a point where a hammer is needed. When an application is scaled out to many nodes, connection pools maximize the efficient use of connections local to any of them, but can’t do so between nodes. In most systems work should be distributed between nodes roughly equally, but because it’s normal to use randomness to do that (through something like HAProxy or other load balancer), and because work durations vary, an equal distribution of work across the whole cluster at any given isn’t likely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we have &lt;em&gt;N&lt;/em&gt; nodes and &lt;em&gt;M&lt;/em&gt; maximum connections per node, we may have a configuration where &lt;em&gt;N&lt;/em&gt; × &lt;em&gt;M&lt;/em&gt; is greater than the database’s &lt;code&gt;max_connections&lt;/code&gt; to protect against the case where a single node is handling an outsized amount of work and needs more connections. Because nodes aren’t coordinating, if the whole cluster is running close to capacity, it’s possible for a node trying to get a new connection to go over-limit and get an error back from Postgres.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this case it’s possible to install &lt;a href=&quot;https://pgbouncer.github.io/&quot;&gt;PgBouncer&lt;/a&gt; to act as a global pool by proxying all connections through it to Postgres. It functions almost exactly like a connection pool and has a few modes of operation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;4.5&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Session pooling:&lt;/strong&gt; A connection is assigned when a client opens a connection and unassigned when the client closes it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Transaction pooling:&lt;/strong&gt; Connections are assigned only for the duration of a transaction, and may be shared around them. This comes with a limitation that applications cannot use features that change the “global” state of a connection like &lt;code&gt;SET&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;LISTEN&lt;/code&gt;/&lt;code&gt;NOTIFY&lt;/code&gt;, or prepared statements .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Statement pooling:&lt;/strong&gt; Connections are assigned only around individual statements. This only works of course if an application gives up the use of transactions, at which point it’s losing a big advantage of using Postgres in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brandur.org/assets/postgres-connections/pgbouncer.svg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://brandur.org/assets/postgres-connections/pgbouncer.svg&quot; class=&quot;overflowing&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
Using PgBouncer to maintain a global connection pool to optimize connection use across all nodes.
&lt;p&gt;Transaction pooling is the best strategy for applications that are already making effective use of a node-local connection pool, and will allow such an application that’s configured with an &lt;em&gt;N&lt;/em&gt; × &lt;em&gt;M&lt;/em&gt; greater than &lt;code&gt;max_connections&lt;/code&gt; to closely approach the maximum possible theoretical utilization of available connections, and to also to avoid connection errors caused by going over-limit (although delaying requests while waiting for a connection to become available from PgBouncer is still possible).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Probably the more common use of PgBouncer is to act as a node-local connection pool for applications that can’t do a good job of implementing their own, like a Rails app deployed with Unicorn. Heroku, for example, provides and recommends the use of a standardized buildpack that deploys a per-dyno PgBouncer to accomplish this. It’s a handy tool to cover this case, but it’s advisable to use a more sophisticated technique if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a trend in frameworks for some time to try and simplify software development for their users by abstracting away the details of connection management. This might work for a time, but in the long run anyone deploying a large application on Postgres will have to understand what’s happening or they’re likely to run into trouble. It’ll usually pay to understand them earlier so that applications can be architected smartly to maximize the efficient use of a scarce resource.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developers should be aware of how many connections each node can use, how many connections a cluster can use by multiplying that number of the number of nodes, and where that total sits relative to Postgres’ &lt;code&gt;max_connections&lt;/code&gt;. It’s common to hit limits during a deploy because a graceful restart spins up new workers or nodes before shutting down old ones, so know expected connection numbers during deployments as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, although we’ve talked mostly about Postgres here, there will be practical bottlenecks like the ones described here in any database, so these techniques for managing connections should be widely portable.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;info&quot; readability=&quot;9.4862385321101&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;publishing-info-bottom&quot; readability=&quot;12.333333333333&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Article&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;How to Manage Connections Efficiently in Postgres, or Any Database&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Published&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;October 15, 2018&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;San Francisco&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find me on Twitter at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/brandur&quot;&gt;@brandur&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did I make a mistake? Please consider &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/brandur/sorg/edit/master/content/articles/postgres-connections.md&quot;&gt;sending a pull request&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 16:08:12 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>bgentry</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://brandur.org/postgres-connections</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Facebook says millions had phone numbers, search history and location stolen</title>
<link>https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2018/10/12/facebook-says-fewer-users-were-affected-by-data-breach-more-information-was-taken</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2018/10/12/facebook-says-fewer-users-were-affected-by-data-breach-more-information-was-taken</guid>
<description>&lt;div data-elm-loc=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;inline-content inline-photo inline-photo-normal&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/nfRF7tuDLe4Z0roHKvQfEDOqjqQ=/480x0/arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/FK2GC6WHHEI6RHAPF75PNVBCVI.jpg&quot; data-hi-res-src=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/XJ7C1tThe3fbVFfFKUCmROBu71I=/1484x0/arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/FK2GC6WHHEI6RHAPF75PNVBCVI.jpg&quot; data-low-res-src=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/nfRF7tuDLe4Z0roHKvQfEDOqjqQ=/480x0/arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/FK2GC6WHHEI6RHAPF75PNVBCVI.jpg&quot; data-raw-src=&quot;https://arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/FK2GC6WHHEI6RHAPF75PNVBCVI.jpg&quot; data-threshold=&quot;480&quot; class=&quot;unprocessed&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pb-caption&quot;&gt;Facebook's headquarters in Menlo Park, Calif. (Josh Edelson/AFP/Getty Images)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;author-sig-line-wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author-sig-line&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author-byline&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author-wrapper&quot; data-authorname=&quot;Brian Fung&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;author-hover-card&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author-headshot&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/people/brian-fung/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/UZzaqKFOl4D_j3OEicirT04uKHU=/200x200/s3.amazonaws.com/arc-authors/washpost/6efb8cfd-9f57-4773-8617-55c61b93c081.png&quot; class=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;author-name&quot; href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/people/brian-fung/&quot;&gt;Brian Fung&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author-bio&quot;&gt;Policy reporter focusing on telecommunications, media, cryptocurrencies and competition&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;author-timestamp&quot; itemprop=&quot;datePublished&quot; content=&quot;2018-10-12T02:46-500&quot;&gt;October 12&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;1&quot;&gt;An online attack that forced Facebook to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2018/09/28/facebook-says-million-accounts-affected-by-hackers/?utm_term=.f78888dd89b5&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;log out 90 million users last month&lt;/a&gt; directly affected 29 million people on the social network, the company said Friday, as it released new details about the scope of an incident that has regulators and law enforcement on high alert.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;2&quot;&gt;Through a series of interrelated bugs in Facebook’s programming, unnamed attackers stole the names and contact information of 15 million users, Facebook said. The contact information included a mix of phone numbers and email addresses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;3&quot;&gt;An additional 14 million users were affected more deeply, having additional details taken related to their profiles, such as their recent search history, gender, educational background, geolocation data, birth dates, and lists of people and pages they follow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;4&quot;&gt;Facebook said last month that it &lt;a href=&quot;https://newsroom.fb.com/news/2018/10/update-on-security-issue/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;detected the attack&lt;/a&gt; when it noticed an uptick in user activity. An investigation soon found that the activity was linked to the theft of security codes that, under normal circumstances, allow Facebook users to navigate away from the site while remaining logged in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;5&quot;&gt;The bugs that allowed the attack to occur gave hackers the ability to effectively take over Facebook accounts on a widespread basis, Facebook said when it disclosed the breach. The attackers began with a relatively small number of accounts that they directly controlled, exploiting flaws in the platform’s “View As” feature to gain access to other users' profiles. (The “View As” feature is designed to allow users to view their own profiles as though they are somebody else.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;6&quot;&gt;Facebook said it is cooperating with federal and other authorities on its investigation but said the FBI had advised the company not to discuss who may be behind the attack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;7&quot;&gt;What may have motivated the attackers is still unclear; despite mounting concerns about election security as U.S. officials count down to a highly contested midterm election, Facebook said there was no indication the hack was specifically related to the U.S. electoral process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;8&quot;&gt;“We don’t have a specific indication as to the intention of the hackers,” said Guy Rosen, Facebook’s vice president of product management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;9&quot;&gt;Although the hackers could have used the flaw to steal information belonging to other, third-party apps that use Facebook as a login method, Facebook said Friday that no outside apps appear to have been affected. Neither Instagram nor WhatsApp appears to have been compromised, the company added. Facebook Messenger was also unaffected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;10&quot;&gt;The 29 million affected users, along with 1 million whose security tokens were taken but did not appear to have their data stolen, will be receiving customized messages from Facebook identifying specifically which types of information on their profiles, if any, were involved in the breach. Facebook executives told reporters Friday that the company will also try to reach affected users who have since deleted their Facebook profiles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;11&quot;&gt;Facebook has also established &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/help/securitynotice?ref=sec&amp;amp;__tn__=-UK-R&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;a Web page&lt;/a&gt; that will inform users who are logged in whether their accounts were affected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;12&quot;&gt;User messages could have been exposed in one specific use case, officials said. If an affected user had been the administrator of a Facebook page, and the page had received a message from another user, that message may have been compromised, Facebook said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;13&quot;&gt;Facebook’s disclosure puts the company under even greater pressure as policymakers have taken the company to task over its approach to user privacy and data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;14&quot;&gt;“The update from Facebook today is significant now that Facebook has confirmed that the personal data of millions of users was taken by the perpetrators of the attack,&quot; said Ireland’s Data Protection Commission — the watchdog agency charged with monitoring compliance with the European Union’s new data privacy law. It said it was continuing an investigation into the breach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;15&quot;&gt;The Federal Trade Commission — which Facebook said it is cooperating with — didn’t immediately respond to a request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;16&quot;&gt;The spotlight on tech companies intensified further this week as Google said that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2018/10/08/laughing-google-bug-youre-making-big-mistake/?utm_term=.95de8f9191b1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;half a million accounts&lt;/a&gt; on its Google+ social networking service could have had information leaked as a result of a software bug. The admission prompted lawmakers to demand answers from the company and call for an FTC investigation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;17&quot;&gt;The incidents could add momentum to a congressional push for a comprehensive U.S. privacy law covering tech companies, Internet providers and others in the online ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 14:17:15 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>nopacience</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2018/10/12/facebook-says-fewer-users-were-affected-by-data-breach-more-information-was-taken/</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/XJ7C1tThe3fbVFfFKUCmROBu71I=/1484x0/arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/FK2GC6WHHEI6RHAPF75PNVBCVI.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>Facebook says millions of users had phone numbers, search history and location data stolen in recent hack</og:title>
<og:description>An online attack that forced Facebook to log out 90 million users last month directly affected 29 million people on the social network, the company said Friday as it released new details about the scope of an incident that has regulators and law enforcement on high alert.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2018/10/12/facebook-says-fewer-users-were-affected-by-data-breach-more-information-was-taken/?noredirect=on</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>M.I.T. Plans College for Artificial Intelligence, Backed by $1B</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/10/15/technology/mit-college-artificial-intelligence.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2018/10/15/technology/mit-college-artificial-intelligence.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div readability=&quot;43&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot; readability=&quot;31&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Every major university is wrestling with how to adapt to the technology wave of artificial intelligence — how to prepare students not only to harness the powerful tools of A.I., but also to thoughtfully weigh its ethical and social implications. A.I. courses, conferences and joint majors have proliferated in the last few years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;But the Massachusetts Institute of Technology is taking a particularly ambitious step, creating a new college backed by a planned investment of $1 billion. Two-thirds of the funds have already been raised, M.I.T. said, in announcing the initiative on Monday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The linchpin gift of $350 million came from Stephen A. Schwarzman, chief executive of the Blackstone Group, the big private equity firm. The college, called the M.I.T. Stephen A. Schwarzman College of Computing, will create 50 new faculty positions and many more fellowships for graduate students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;It is scheduled to begin in the fall semester next year, housed in other buildings before moving into its own new space in 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;52.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot; readability=&quot;50&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The goal of the college, said L. Rafael Reif, the president of M.I.T., is to “educate the bilinguals of the future.” He defines bilinguals as people in fields like biology, chemistry, politics, history and linguistics who are also skilled in the techniques of modern computing that can be applied to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;But, he said, “to educate bilinguals, we have to create a new structure.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Academic departments still tend to be silos, Mr. Reif explained, despite interdisciplinary programs that cross the departmental boundaries. Half the 50 faculty positions will focus on advancing computer science, and the other half will be jointly appointed by the college and by other departments across M.I.T.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Traditionally, departments hold sway in hiring and tenure decisions at universities. So, for example, a researcher who applied A.I.-based text analysis tools in a field like history might be regarded as too much a computer scientist by the humanities department and not sufficiently technical by the computer science department.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;M.I.T.’s leaders hope the new college will alter traditional academic thinking and practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“We need to rewire how we hire and promote faculty,” said Martin Schmidt, the provost of M.I.T.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Today, most dual-major programs involve taking courses in a computer science department in machine learning or data science in addition to a student’s major. The M.I.T. college is an effort to have computing baked into the curriculum rather than stapled on. It will grant degrees, though what they will be or their names have not been determined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;39&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot; readability=&quot;23&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;That appealed to Melissa Nobles, dean of M.I.T.’s School of Humanities, Arts and Social Sciences, who said she saw the new college as helping non-computer scientists bring A.I. tools to their fields — “to what they really care about.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The college, Ms. Nobles said, offers the possibility of a renewal for humanities studies at M.I.T., where students flock to computer science and engineering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“We’re excited by the possibilities,” she said. “That’s how the humanities are going to survive, not by running from the future but by embracing it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;41&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot; readability=&quot;27&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Donors, like students, are attracted more to computer science programs than to many other disciplines. But the new college at M.I.T. is designed to spread the wealth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“It’s a major fund-raising mechanism that gives M.I.T. a huge resource to apply A.I. to other fields,” said Eric Schmidt, who was the executive chairman of Alphabet, the parent company of Google, and is a visiting innovation fellow at M.I.T.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The college and its goals were shaped by a long-running conversation between Mr. Schwarzman, the principal donor, and Mr. Reif, the M.I.T. president. They first met in 2015 when Mr. Schwarzman was setting up the Schwarzman Scholars program, which awards scholarships for young people to gain a greater understanding of China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;52.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot; readability=&quot;50&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;At the time, Mr. Schwarzman was becoming increasingly fascinated by the debate over the opportunity and challenge presented by artificial intelligence. A lengthy conversation with Jack Ma, founder of the Chinese e-commerce giant Alibaba, piqued his interest, Mr. Schwarzman recalled, and he kept talking to experts and reading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“I became convinced that this technology was so powerful it was really going to remake a lot of the world as we know it,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Over the next few years, Mr. Schwarzman and Mr. Reif picked up the conversation about the trajectory of A.I. and its broad impact, when their paths crossed in places like New York and Davos, Switzerland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Over the past year, M.I.T.’s leaders and faculty were brainstorming to chart a course for the university’s future. The university had done individual initiatives in areas like the future of work and a research project on the human and machine intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;But Mr. Schwarzman urged Mr. Reif to go further, emphasizing the ethical issues raised by automated decision-making in everything from medical diagnosis to self-driving cars. He also stressed the workplace impact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“We really need to try to understand this technology, not just get hit by it,” Mr. Schwarzman said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Meanwhile, Mr. Reif was also focused on making a universitywide impact. His persistent question: “How do I make sure these tools are used by everyone in every discipline?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The new college structure was his answer. Mr. Schwarzman said he would be interested in contributing, and soon after, Mr. Reif made his pitch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;39.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot; readability=&quot;24&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“Well, that is a big number,” Mr. Schwarzman said, recalling his initial reaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;After further study, he said yes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Mr. Schwarzman said he hoped that the M.I.T. move might trigger others to invest in America’s A.I. future, not just commercially. He points to the major push the Chinese government is making, and notes the fruits of United States government-funded research in the past — technologies that helped America take the global lead in industries from the personal computer to the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xl4flh e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“I think we’ve been lagging, for whatever reason,” Mr. Schwarzman said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;30.802966101695&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-e25ngt&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-acwcvw&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;css-1vg6q84&quot;&gt;Correction:&lt;/strong&gt; 
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1yxl9xx e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;An earlier version of this article misspelled the given name of the chief executive of the Blackstone Group. He is Stephen A. Schwarzman, not Steven. The error was repeated in a picture caption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1gybuqn&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Follow Steve Lohr on Twitter: @SteveLohr&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1jhku0n&quot; readability=&quot;8.2882882882883&quot;&gt;A version of this article appears in print on , on Page B7 of the New York edition with the headline: M.I.T. Creates a College for Artificial Intelligence, Backed by $1 Billion&lt;span&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytreprints.com/&quot;&gt;Order Reprints&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/pages/todayspaper/index.html&quot;&gt;Today’s Paper&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/subscriptions/Multiproduct/lp8HYKU.html?campaignId=48JQY&quot;&gt;Subscribe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 13:26:14 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>superfx</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/10/15/technology/mit-college-artificial-intelligence.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>M.I.T. Plans College for Artificial Intelligence, Backed by $1 Billion</og:title>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/10/16/business/16mit-1/merlin_145234875_ebe023b3-3844-4a57-b2c7-590824893fe7-facebookJumbo.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>The goal, said L. Rafael Reif, the president of M.I.T., is to educate “the bilinguals of the future.” Blackstone’s Steven A. Schwarzman is contributing $350 million.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/10/15/technology/mit-college-artificial-intelligence.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Air pollution linked to “huge” reduction in intelligence</title>
<link>https://www.unenvironment.org/news-and-stories/story/air-pollution-linked-huge-reduction-intelligence</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.unenvironment.org/news-and-stories/story/air-pollution-linked-huge-reduction-intelligence</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN-IE&quot; xml:lang=&quot;EN-IE&quot;&gt;Air pollution can have a “huge” negative effect on cognitive intelligence – especially amongst older men&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span lang=&quot;EN-IE&quot; xml:lang=&quot;EN-IE&quot;&gt;– according to a study released this past August.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN-IE&quot; xml:lang=&quot;EN-IE&quot;&gt;The research is one of the first of its kind to focus on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/08/21/1809474115&quot;&gt;the links between air pollution and cognition in older people&lt;/a&gt;. It was undertaken by scientists at Peking University in Beijing, China and Yale University in the U.S. and was published in the Proceedings of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.unenvironment.org/news-and-stories/story/void(0);&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;National Academy of Sciences&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; journal. In particular, it found that long-term exposure to air pollution may impede overall cognitive performance.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN-IE&quot; xml:lang=&quot;EN-IE&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/pnas/suppl/2018/08/22/1809474115.DCSupplemental/pnas.1809474115.sapp.pdf&quot;&gt;The researchers’ sample set&lt;/a&gt; included a panel of over 25,000 people across 162 randomly chosen counties in China. The study was also based on daily readings for three atmospheric pollutants, namely sulphur dioxide (SO&lt;/span&gt;&lt;sub&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN-IE&quot; xml:lang=&quot;EN-IE&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN-IE&quot; xml:lang=&quot;EN-IE&quot;&gt;), nitrogen dioxide (NO&lt;/span&gt;&lt;sub&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN-IE&quot; xml:lang=&quot;EN-IE&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN-IE&quot; xml:lang=&quot;EN-IE&quot;&gt;) and particulate matter smaller than 10 micrometers (PM10) where the participants lived.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN-IE&quot; xml:lang=&quot;EN-IE&quot;&gt;The research found that that accumulative exposure to air pollution impedes cognitive performance in verbal and math tests. It found that as people age, the negative effect becomes particularly pronounced on verbal scores, especially for men while, “the gender gap is particularly large for the less educated.” One of the reasons why the researchers suggest that older men with less education were worst affected by chronic exposure to air pollution is because those subjects often work in outdoor, manual jobs.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN-IE&quot; xml:lang=&quot;EN-IE&quot;&gt;The scientists concluded that, “The damage on the aging brain by air pollution likely imposes substantial health and economic costs, considering that cognitive functioning is critical for the elderly for both running daily errands and making high-stake decisions&lt;/span&gt;.” &lt;span lang=&quot;EN-IE&quot; xml:lang=&quot;EN-IE&quot;&gt;Given this damaging effect of air pollution on cognition, particularly on the aging brain, “the study implies that the indirect effect on social welfare could be much larger than previously thought&lt;/span&gt;.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN-IE&quot; xml:lang=&quot;EN-IE&quot;&gt;“Polluted air can cause everyone to reduce their level of education by one year, which is huge,”&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span lang=&quot;EN-IE&quot; xml:lang=&quot;EN-IE&quot;&gt;Yale School of Public Health's Professor Xi Chen, one of the report's authors, said in an interview published in The Guardian.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN-IE&quot; xml:lang=&quot;EN-IE&quot;&gt;The study also suggests that air pollution increases the risk of degenerative diseases such as Alzheimer's and other forms of dementia.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN-IE&quot; xml:lang=&quot;EN-IE&quot;&gt;“Air pollution is a significant threat to public health and this study highlights the negative effect that such pollution may have on the ageing brain,” said Soraya Smaoun, Air Quality Coordinator at UN Environment. “A better understanding of the critical links between air pollution and health for policies and investments supporting cleaner transport and power generation, as well as energy-efficient housing and municipal waste management can reduce key sources of outdoor air pollution.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN-IE&quot; xml:lang=&quot;EN-IE&quot;&gt;According to the World Health Organization, seven million people die each year from exposure to polluted air, both indoor and outdoor. The three biggest killers which are associated to air pollution are stroke (2.2 million deaths), heart disease (2.0 million) and lung disease and cancer (1.7 million deaths).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN-GB&quot; xml:lang=&quot;EN-GB&quot;&gt;The&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span lang=&quot;EN-IE&quot; xml:lang=&quot;EN-IE&quot;&gt;World Health Organization&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN-GB&quot; xml:lang=&quot;EN-GB&quot;&gt;’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/airpollution/data/cities/en/&quot;&gt;air quality database&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;shows that that 97 per cent of cities in low- and middle-income countries with more than 100,000 inhabitants do not meet air quality guidelines presently. However, the percentage is much lower in higher income countries – 40 per cent.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN-IE&quot; xml:lang=&quot;EN-IE&quot;&gt;What is being done about air pollution?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN-GB&quot; xml:lang=&quot;EN-GB&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;A worldwide movement to address air pollution is gradually taking shape and growing.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span lang=&quot;EN-IE&quot; xml:lang=&quot;EN-IE&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://breathelife2030.org/the-issue/air-quality-in-your-city/&quot;&gt;Breathe Life&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span lang=&quot;EN-GB&quot; xml:lang=&quot;EN-GB&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;– a global campaign headed by the Climate and Clean Air Coalition, the World Health Organization and UN Environment – is supporting a range of cleaner air initiatives that cover 39 cities, regions and countries, reaching over 80 million people.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN-GB&quot; xml:lang=&quot;EN-GB&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Most major cities are still struggling to keep air pollution within acceptable levels as set out by the World Health Organization guidelines. However, by instituting policies and programmes to reduce transport and energy emissions, and by encouraging the use of clean energy, cities are leading change and improving the lives of a large number of people.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN-GB&quot; xml:lang=&quot;EN-GB&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;In 2018, the World Health Organization found that more than 57 per cent of cities in the Americas and more than 61 per cent of cities in Europe had seen a fall in both PM10 and PM2.5 particulate matter between 2010 and 2016.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN-GB&quot; xml:lang=&quot;EN-GB&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;The rise of renewable energy is also ideally positioned to make a big difference, with investment in new renewable sources outstripping fossil fuel investments every year.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN-GB&quot; xml:lang=&quot;EN-GB&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;“WHO: Breathe Life - How air pollution impacts your body”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 13:17:25 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>crunchiebones</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>http://www.unenvironment.org/news-and-stories/story/air-pollution-linked-huge-reduction-intelligence</og:url>
<og:title>Air pollution linked to “huge” reduction in intelligence</og:title>
<og:description>Air pollution can have a “huge” negative effect on cognitive intelligence – especially amongst older men – according to a study released this past August.</og:description>
<og:image>http://www.unenvironment.org/sites/default/files/styles/topics_content_promo/public/2018-10/2010-10-Air%20pollution-CHINA-USA-CLIMATE.jpg?itok=Pm7i_QvG</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.unenvironment.org/news-and-stories/story/air-pollution-linked-huge-reduction-intelligence</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Show HN: Physically Based Rendering – Online Edition</title>
<link>http://www.pbr-book.org/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.pbr-book.org/</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;landing-text&quot;&gt;Photorealistic computer graphics is ubiquitous today, with applications that include entertainment—notably, movies and video games; product design; and architecture. Over the past decade, &lt;em&gt;physically-based&lt;/em&gt; approaches to rendering have become widely used, where an accurate modeling of the physics of light scattering is at the heart of image synthesis. These approaches offer both visual realism and predictability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;landing-text&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Physically Based Rendering&lt;/em&gt; describes both the mathematical theory behind a modern photorealistic rendering system as well as its practical implementation. A method known as “literate programming” combines human-readable documentation and source code into a single reference that is specifically designed to aid comprehension. The ideas and software in this book show the reader how to design and employ a full-featured rendering system capable of creating creating stunning imagery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;landing-text&quot;&gt;The author team of Matt Pharr, Greg Humphreys, and Pat Hanrahan garnered a 2014 Academy Award for Scientific and Technical Achievement from the Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences based on the knowledge shared in the first and second editions of the book this book. The Academy called the book a “widely adopted practical roadmap for most physically based shading and lighting systems used in film production.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;landing-text&quot;&gt;Of the book, Donald Knuth wrote “This book has deservedly won an Academy Award. I believe it should also be nominated for a Pulitzer Prize.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;landing-text&quot;&gt;As of October 15, 2018, the full contents of the third edition of the book are freely available online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;landing-text&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pbr-book.org/3ed-2018/contents.html&quot;&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 13:04:23 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>wjakob</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.pbr-book.org/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>