<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Show HN: Checklist of over 100 directories to submit your startup</title>
<link>https://www.eggradients.com/startup-directory</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.eggradients.com/startup-directory</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eggradients.com/startup-directory&quot;&gt;https://www.eggradients.com/startup-directory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17591677&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17591677&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Points: 204&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 41&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 10:05:09 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>serhadiletir</dc:creator>
<og:title>+100 Startup Directories to Submit Your Startup - Submit Checklist</og:title>
<og:description>Are you looking for startup directories to submit your fabulous product?  Having an excellent product, not enough these days. You should let people know how cool the product you made. We build the ultimate list of startup directory. Enjoy.</og:description>
<og:image>https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5a9423a3f702750001758d4f/5b4b8873847c0084eba5b22d_submit-checklist-cover.jpg</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.eggradients.com/startup-directory</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>What was it like to be a software engineer at NeXT?</title>
<link>https://www.quora.com/What-was-it-like-to-be-a-software-engineer-at-NeXT-Did-workers-interact-with-Steve-Jobs/answer/Paul-King-2</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.quora.com/What-was-it-like-to-be-a-software-engineer-at-NeXT-Did-workers-interact-with-Steve-Jobs/answer/Paul-King-2</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ui_qtext_rendered_qtext&quot;&gt;Working at NeXT was the most exciting software engineering job I ever accepted.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ui_qtext_rendered_qtext&quot;&gt;NeXT was like graduate school, bringing together a high concentration of some of the brightest and most innovative technical minds. Many people had computer science (or other) research backgrounds. One thing that was unusual is that all the technical people there understood all aspects of the machine. Software people could talk about ASICs and CPU instructions, and the hardware people understood the software stack. Every aspect of what it takes to make a computer work was represented in one building: analog hardware, chip design, motherboard design, compiler design (Objective-C), loader, operating system, windowing system, application layer, and applications. Where other companies had engineering teams, NeXT would have a single individual. Many people had been managers or technical leads elsewhere and came to NeXT to be an individual contributor to help create the most innovative computer ever invented (enter reality distortion field).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ui_qtext_rendered_qtext&quot;&gt;When I joined, Steve Jobs was in a different building with the marketing folks, separated from the engineers. Supposedly the new campus had been planned that way so that Steve wouldn't tour around among the engineers, ask them what they were working on, and redirect them onto new projects when they were supposed to be working on deadlines. Because if Steve got excited and said something would be cool, engineers would stop whatever they were doing and start working on that.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ui_qtext_rendered_qtext&quot;&gt;At one point, Lotus Notes was getting traction and Steve thought it was interesting. He liked the idea of a network based application with information objects floating around. So he called a meeting with 10 software engineers around the giant board room table to brainstorm. It was exciting to be invited. The initiative got called Object Soup, and while nothing concrete emerged, it influenced the direction of parts of the software infrastructure.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ui_qtext_rendered_qtext&quot;&gt;Steve could also be ruthless with his feedback. In my first meeting with him to present what I had been working on (which was held on a Saturday morning), he looked at the demo for 5 minutes and told me I had &quot;ruined NeXTSTEP&quot; (the software platform). This was a 3 month build-up for a big demo on Monday (in 2 days) in front of the entire engineering division at Oracle (400+ people), by invitation of his close friend, CEO Larry Ellison. Steve said the work was so bad, he thought he should cancel his presentation at Oracle. &quot;Unless...&quot;, he paused with a twinkle in his eye, &quot;there is a way of making it work like the old way,&quot; referring to the smoke-and-mirrors demo he had been using on sales calls. We knew what we had to do.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ui_qtext_rendered_qtext&quot;&gt;We worked through the night to pull out all of the SQL-specific features he didn't like, and met him at the office Sunday morning. He reviewed the demo for 2 minutes and said enthusiastically, &quot;This is 10 times, no 100 times, no 1000 times better!!!&quot; The Monday demo was on, and Steve received a standing ovation from the Oracle employees.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ui_qtext_rendered_qtext&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Related&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;qlink_container&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.quora.com/What-was-it-like-to-work-at-NeXT&quot;&gt;What was it like to work at NeXT?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 05:07:18 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Nuance</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.quora.com/What-was-it-like-to-be-a-software-engineer-at-NeXT-Did-workers-interact-with-Steve-Jobs/answer/Paul-King-2</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ask HN: Got a CS degree, but I’m unable to be programmer. What can I do?</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17589482</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17589482</guid>
<description>&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.55737704918033&quot;&gt;&lt;td bgcolor=&quot;#FF6600&quot;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.998998998999&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table class=&quot;fatitem&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;5.2492492492492&quot;&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing&quot; id=&quot;17589482&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;right&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;title&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17589482&quot; class=&quot;storylink&quot;&gt;Ask HN: Got a CS degree, but I’m unable to be programmer. What can I do?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.74074074074074&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;subtext&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;score&quot; id=&quot;score_17589482&quot;&gt;257 points&lt;/span&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/user?id=Tmp1234&quot; class=&quot;hnuser&quot;&gt;Tmp1234&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;age&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17589482&quot;&gt;16 hours ago&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span id=&quot;unv_17589482&quot;/&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/hide?id=17589482&amp;amp;goto=item%3Fid%3D17589482&quot;&gt;hide&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://hn.algolia.com/?query=Ask%20HN%3A%20Got%20a%20CS%20degree%2C%20but%20I%E2%80%99m%20unable%20to%20be%20programmer.%20What%20can%20I%20do%3F&amp;amp;sort=byDate&amp;amp;dateRange=all&amp;amp;type=story&amp;amp;storyText=false&amp;amp;prefix&amp;amp;page=0&quot; class=&quot;hnpast&quot;&gt;past&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=Ask%20HN%3A%20Got%20a%20CS%20degree%2C%20but%20I%E2%80%99m%20unable%20to%20be%20programmer.%20What%20can%20I%20do%3F&quot;&gt;web&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/fave?id=17589482&amp;amp;auth=abb39731558a519577962a6f5876ccf283907097&quot;&gt;favorite&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17589482&quot;&gt;266 comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td&gt;I recently graduated and have been grinding for interview prep (leetcode and CTCI mostly), but I’m getting no where. Easy problems take me 2-5 hours. I experience PTSD like symptoms from the constant barrage of negative thoughts the difficulty and stress of doing these problems are causing me. I don’t have time to do anything else and no objectively measurable progress is being made. Even if I get a problem right, I gain little to no satisfaction at this point. I completely hate what I’ve gotten myself into. I put all my eggs in the “being a programmer” basket and it’s clearly not for me. I do have a computer science undergraduate degree which I’m hoping I can use for something. Are there any career paths I can pivot to that are less cognitively demanding than software engineering where this degree would be an asset?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td&gt;

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;yclinks&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/newsguidelines.html&quot;&gt;Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/newsfaq.html&quot;&gt;FAQ&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:hn@ycombinator.com&quot;&gt;Support&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/HackerNews/API&quot;&gt;API&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/security.html&quot;&gt;Security&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/lists&quot;&gt;Lists&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/bookmarklet.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Bookmarklet&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ycombinator.com/legal/&quot;&gt;Legal&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ycombinator.com/apply/&quot;&gt;Apply to YC&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:hn@ycombinator.com&quot;&gt;Contact&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2018 23:37:53 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Tmp1234</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17589482</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Secret Life of an Autistic Stripper</title>
<link>http://narrative.ly/secret-life-of-an-autistic-stripper/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://narrative.ly/secret-life-of-an-autistic-stripper/</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;text_173828d4e2524eb8baaf81aabc32c555&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot; data-effect=&quot;dropcaps&quot;&gt;The mouth of the tunnel is wide and dark, swallowing the light and all that breathes. Rubble is scattered along the train tracks, bordered by retaining walls covered in numerous layers of graffiti.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_00bc4b37757149ea89b8d6d42fa83aa6&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;This is where it all started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_e3b5e6194d87402b9602ac63a00ced2e&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Here by the parkway with the blasting trucks and the roaring cars, near the filigree arches of the Riverside Drive viaduct, here with the gravel crunching under my feet as I run down the railroad into this hollow mouth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_4bd95c870a39499090e0703d0b673d81&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;This is where they live, deep into the depths of the city, way underground, lying in the dirt. Sure, you know about them. Of course you know about them. They’ve always been there, resting low below the rowdy streets and the carving avenues, gulping the air from inside the earth, crawling through holes and cracks, living off the grid and off the books.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_255378998da14eddbc33e2c130c5256b&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Here in the tunnels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_1d361ec35e22464ca9fdf01c31c8f297&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;You’ve heard the rumors. Their eyes have adapted to the constant night that cloaks them from the topside world. Don’t you know they’re eating rats and human flesh? Don’t you know they want us dead? And one day they will spill outside and burn us all alive, and they will reign over our flatscreen joys and our organic delights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_b0a1ec17bd6d4d1a868432fbffa5b18b&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Of course you know about them. The lost ones, the hidden ones. The broken and the ill, the wandering, the gone. The Mole People.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_3e1c5cfe622e4f32a9f38773e3a225b8&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;“Jon,” I call, looking up. Jon has been homeless for more than fifteen years. Like many of the people interviewed for this article, he did not want to give his full name. He has been living here for a while now, in a small space between two support beams that can only be reached with a ladder. A plywood roof protects his hoarded belongings from seeping water. The place is crammed full. There is an old mattress on the floor, and cookware, blankets and electronics stacked on makeshift shelves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_07760b1cc2904e11936d0ab45ad5cb09&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;“Jon,” I repeat, and he appears, his head cautiously peaking up from his house, a relieved smile on his face when he sees me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_3160cf6edd9644a79901fdce7af10e60&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;“I thought it was the Amtrak police,” he later says while opening a beer, his legs dangling off the edge of the wall. “They been coming less, lately, but you never know. Regular police ain’t bothering me, but Amtrak, they can be nasty.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_91e23ac6d4a544948f78817565ba0c0b&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Jon says he did prison time. He is bipolar and suffers from major substance dependence. He used to be a gang member in the Bronx. He used to be a family man until he got disowned. He was a furniture salesman. The FBI is looking for him. He used to know Donald Trump. It doesn’t matter which version is true. His real story has been buried long ago under thick layers of improvised memories that grew more detailed by the years, the man slowly becoming a collage of himself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_55f10ea9c7db4293bfc6934827d00d63&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;“I’m good here,” he says. “No taxes, no rent, no nothing. There’s no hassle compared to the streets, you know what I’m saying? Here I don’t get bugged by kids. It’s a safe place. I can do what I wanna and I don’t have to take nothing from nobody.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;ImageBlock_Image alignright&quot; src=&quot;http://cz598rxdt5our6verxu01782.wpengine.netdna-cdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/fT9WHXPVSe7JVm1bK0FF_8jVxRCHi31i2UkQmsudeU9oMb40R1BMSBIhATRiQ47Q.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;225&quot;/&gt;&lt;p id=&quot;text_9f9a8175a5894c59adebca52fb2c6b52&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Today is a good day for Jon, despite the rain and the cool weather.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_77cffc9fb1984f8da2227dd2781c581d&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;“You’re the first person to visit this week,” he says. “People don’t want to speak to me when they come here. I don’t know, man. They’re scared or something. I can get why, it’s a spooky place when you don’t know it. But people, they like it when it’s scary. They like it when it’s dirty, right? It makes them feel alive. That’s why they make up these stories about cannibalism and stuff. Like alligators in the sewers.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_b4486d0a5d364fba8cc8fcf28cf8193d&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Jon offers me a sip of vodka. We drink together. He tells me to stay safe and to watch out for trains when I go back walking into the tunnel. I hear him talk to himself as I go away from the entrance and from the white sky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_0ad3332060d04f6a96805e946ff989bc&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;The smell down here is the one of brake dust and mold. I can see rats scouring for food and drinking from brown puddles in the tracks ballast. EXISTENCE IS FLAWED, a graffiti inscription reads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_5e4c71aade914b519aca5da22372a992&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;The city growls over my head — a distant growl muffled by the concrete, almost a snarl, like something cold and foul spreading over the long stretches of stained walls, like a dark and wild beast curling up around me and breathing on my neck. A dark and wild beast silently trailing me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_aa7422c9b6c2417d8d2d7eb102c11056&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;* * *&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_5110e79c5c5a4c2e9ce44eddd856414d&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot; data-effect=&quot;dropcaps&quot;&gt;Stories about underground dwellers were already flourishing when the first New York City subway line opened in 1904. The expansion of extensive sewers and steam pipes systems had brought a newfound fascination with what laid below the streets. From Jules Verne’s 1864 novel “Journey to the Center of the Earth” to George Gissing’s 1889 book “The Nether World,” literature was brimming with tales of people living in isolation or trapped under the surface, peaking in 1895 with “The Time Machine,” in which H. G. Wells described a fictional subterranean species called the “Morlocks.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_cdd9ceab4ff04488964e17206bf2750b&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;But it was only in the 1990s that the first widespread depictions of real-world tunnel residents appeared in New York. A 1990 &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/1990/06/13/nyregion/in-tunnel-mole-people-fight-to-save-home.html?pagewanted=all&quot;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; by John Tierney was the earliest to outline the phenomenon, looking at people living in an abandoned train tunnel beneath Riverside Park, along the banks of the Hudson River.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_99e8a9e1b8514d729575d0a1febf2963&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Collective imagination took over quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_d5c08fa308494322a1de28675b79afbb&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;In 1993, Jennifer Toth published her essay “&lt;a href=&quot;https://books.google.ca/books?id=H7jfvdtA0hsC&amp;amp;redir_esc=y&quot;&gt;The Mole People&lt;/a&gt;,” documenting hidden communities residing in a network of forsaken caverns, holes and shafts across Manhattan. An instant hit, it chronicled the organization of those underground societies, describing compounds of several thousands where babies were born and regular lives were lived, with elected officials, hot water and even electricity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_8c044abb3a7f4fce8f29039e1cd5ce49&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;However, the book was promptly criticized for its inconsistencies. Joseph Brennan, a New York rail buff, wrote an extensive and detailed critique in 1996, exposing many discrepancies in Toth’s reporting, such as places that couldn’t exist, exaggerated numbers and contradictory claims. According to Brennan, the whole notion of secret passages was implausible and “reminiscent of scenes in the TV series ‘Beauty and the Beast.’”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_0b5bf89e46ca42df903cba5ad3b31381&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;A 2004 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.straightdope.com/columns/read/2498/em-the-mole-people-em-revisited&quot;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; by Cecil Adams further demonstrated that many accounts were perhaps more sensationalism than truth. Adams pointed out unverifiable or incorrect facts in Toth’s work, and her skepticism peaked during her interview of Cindy Fletcher, a former tunnel dweller who challenged important points of the narration. “I’m not saying the book is not true, I just never experienced the things [she] said she saw,” Fletcher explained to Adams. I was unable to reach Toth for comment, but when Adams talked to her, the journalist said she couldn’t remember how to access certain places described in her essay — possibly not to disclose the whereabouts of trespassing squatters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_a95fc7825eeb4e0098efc8b2b1619439&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Still, while the essay might have been inflated or romanticized, it was nonetheless true that the homeless begging in the streets of New York were merely the tip of the iceberg. Photojournalists &lt;a href=&quot;http://margaretmorton.com/artist/the_tunnel.html&quot;&gt;Margaret Morton&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.andreastarreese.com/the-urban-cave-3&quot;&gt;Andrea Star Reese&lt;/a&gt; have both extensively documented communities spread in underground hideouts since Toth’s book. Dutch anthropologist Teun Voeten’s 1996 diary “Tunnel People” provided an &lt;a href=&quot;https://books.google.ca/books?id=5RWsvXPDCPYC&amp;amp;printsec=frontcover&amp;amp;source=gbs_ge_summary_r&amp;amp;cad=0#v=onepage&amp;amp;q&amp;amp;f=false&quot;&gt;incredible account&lt;/a&gt; of the months he spent with the Riverside Park Amtrak tunnel inhabitants before they were evicted and moved to Section 8 housing units. In 2000, director Marc Singer released his acclaimed documentary “&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0235327/&quot;&gt;Dark Days&lt;/a&gt;,” filming the same people followed by Voeten and Toth in their respective books.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;ImageBlock_Image alignleft&quot; src=&quot;http://cz598rxdt5our6verxu01782.wpengine.netdna-cdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/vavf7dz9Q2iXaEspnSmA_KqTLVkFOXlvIFRxf72155iK7qY3fgSqRUGcWVFZsu28.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;299&quot; height=&quot;224&quot;/&gt;&lt;p id=&quot;text_2d0cb494828542eea933d15b9ab0d330&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;“There were definitely people living in tunnels, but not a lot,” Norman Diederich, a former MTA maintenance inspector, told me. “If there are still any, they’re very discreet. This period is gone.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_e5996fa97fc640a888a0df6ac58f7432&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;“There were talks that the moles were cannibals,” Diederich continued. “That they could see in the dark. That they spoke their own language. Creepy stuff, straight out of a horror movie… Most was made-up. I personally never witnessed unusual stuff. Santa Claus, the Boogeyman, the Mole People, it’s all the same. We need to label things we don’t understand. It’s human nature.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_98136358c4b04e05aa8f8c4fb8a5ef11&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;“Just cause you can’t see don’t mean ain’t nothing there,” begins Anthony Horton’s 2008 graphic novel “&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2012/02/07/nyregion/the-fiery-end-of-a-life-lived-beneath-the-city.html?_r=2&quot;&gt;Pitch Black&lt;/a&gt;,” relating the author’s own struggles as a homeless man. Written in an abandoned crew room of the F subway line, these words were the reason I ventured into the tunnels in the first place, looking for the invisible, guided by local dwellers along the years to seek foundations of humanity in the foundations of the city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_a660d9a48e234748b43381785018936b&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;All the stories I had read about the Mole People before descending myself had two things in common.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_117ebea4ad964477bdd1c72d7527e0e5&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;They all showed simple human beings who were in no way comparable to the legends that had been told, and they all included a man named Bernard Isaac.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_89fc250b4afc4f44a3d3bda619f15eae&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;* * *&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_f14bbdf586f441e9b9917421a39dec07&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot; data-effect=&quot;dropcaps&quot;&gt;I met Bernard Isaac for the first time in 2009. “This is not a place of perdition,” he often said about the Riverside Park tunnel when we talked together during his shifts as a maintenance worker in Central Park. “This is a sanctuary. A place to find peace and take a break from the chaos.” He would then reminisce about his old life, his eyes would light up and there would be the crack of a smile, and whatever place we were in would be filled by his presence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_dd3edd5c202d486eb95c440d3763077d&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Isaac was at the very center of the Mole People legend. His BA in journalism and his studies in philosophy had somehow led him to work as a model, then as a TV crew member, then as a tour guide in the Caribbean where he began &lt;a href=&quot;https://books.google.ca/books?id=5RWsvXPDCPYC&amp;amp;printsec=frontcover#v=onepage&amp;amp;q=smuggled%20cocaine&amp;amp;f=false&quot;&gt;smuggling cocaine&lt;/a&gt; to the States. The father of two sons with two different women, he never cared much for family life, preferring to spend his smuggling profits on parties thrown at his Upper West Side penthouse. Soon he was broke, friendless and on his own. By the late 1980s, he was sleeping in the Riverside Park tunnel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_f2996498cf2545b8bba1ba7d021c6abc&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;The tunnel was known by homeless people since its inception in the 1930s, when it was used by trains to bring cattle to the city before the freight operations ended. Its population, limited at first to about three or four individuals, quickly grew at the time Isaac settled in, evolving into small tribes of vagrants who built thriving shantytowns in the newly abandoned space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_05a0f5b4fa3a40b7a592cbf6d3c3d6bd&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Few risked getting down into the tunnel. “It often scared grown men easily,” recounted Isaac in 2010 as he showed me his old hangout places. But those who did go down called it home, and it became a haven for the destitute to unwind without fear of getting arrested or &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/1993/12/04/nyregion/youths-injure-two-sleeping-homeless-men.html&quot;&gt;attacked like people on the streets often were&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_dac8b897fe1842e3ba516794d6db63cd&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;One day, three men asked Isaac for a toll as he came by the 125th Street entrance to the tunnel. He laughed at them and said “Do you know who you’re talking to? I’m the fucking lord of this tunnel!” The three men never bothered him again, and Isaac’s nickname “The Lord of the Tunnel” was born.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_15b8e68adf124cf2b2928c06ba49c3c9&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Though there never was any real leader in the shantytown, Isaac became the community’s de facto spokesman, interacting with outreach groups and journalists to explain how living there was better than dealing with shelter curfews, senseless laws and indifferent social workers. Soon interest came from all around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_e7b4f7cedd294da18da54cce5ab4fa11&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Ironically, the tunnel’s community support was in many ways more efficient than the one offered by municipal programs. In the encampment, the dwellers had a familiar place to be, watch TV, read or smoke. They had autonomy. Rules were simple but strictly enforced. Respect for privacy. No yelling. No stealing. No stupid behavior or you’d be kicked out. Some, like Isaac, were at home in the darkness, and would not have lived anywhere else. Most who lived here did not consider themselves homeless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_7c668e4ae10c4da1b836d2f1f2c79c03&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;As word spread of the tunnel, a growing number of graffiti artists came to paint the seemingly endless walls that flanked the train tracks. One of them, Chris “Freedom” Pape, had known the place for quite a while before. He became friends with Isaac and his community, teaming up with local tagger Roger Smith — known to most as just “Smith” — to paint pieces narrating their stories. “I hadpainted in the tunnel for six years before the homeless moved in, so they were curious about me,” said Pape in a 2014 interview for “&lt;a href=&quot;http://untappedcities.com/2014/05/19/catching-up-with-chris-freedom-pape-the-artist-who-gave-nycs-freedom-tunnel-its-name/&quot;&gt;Untapped Cities&lt;/a&gt;.” “I became friendly with most of them and my visits to the tunnel were much safer and even relaxing.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_7c84478b851e4dd798b7d83726eb5497&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;In a &lt;a href=&quot;http://articles.latimes.com/1990-05-13/news/mn-98_1_underground-railroad&quot;&gt;1990 Los Angeles Times article&lt;/a&gt;, Isaac explained that the small community lived as well, if not better, than the average people “up top,” as they commonly refer to the streets. “I’ve had the opportunity to get jobs,” he said. “I don’t choose to be a robot within the system… We’ve done something that one out of every 1,000 men in creation in their lifetimes will do. We dared to be ourselves.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_a8d0d08140904e8a89c3a57173a0636c&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Some residents were still eager to leave, only to come back later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_bd8cafb9ff3b454daea9d59735843c18&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;John Kovacs, one of Isaac’s neighbors in the tunnel, was once given a $50,000 offer to turn his story into a feature movie and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/1991/03/13/nyregion/after-16-years-squatter-leaves-tunnel.html&quot;&gt;left in 1991 after sixteen years in the tunnel&lt;/a&gt;. He was back less than seven months later, the $50,000 Hollywood deal gone sour and Kovacs unable to adjust to life in larger society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_9afc132b7d5242c29cf2814f42bfee11&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Another who attempted to go to the surface was Bob Kalinski, a speed addict known as the fastest cook east of the Mississippi, who could fry twenty eggs at a time when on amphetamines. A heart attack forced him to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/1994/03/28/nyregion/fleeing-the-world-underneath.html&quot;&gt;try his luck with the public housing system in 1994&lt;/a&gt;. He too returned in the following months. The sense of belonging simply was too strong. The tunnel was a better place for him to be alone in freedom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_736cd7d9230c4a7d96cd5a39dcc412a4&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;“After so many years in the streets, they kind of lose faith in humanity,” said Audrey Lombardi, a volunteer at the Holy Apostles soup kitchen in Manhattan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_c5e4dc1e2fcf4a8db3cfa2464a324ee2&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;“They can’t help it, it’s so deeply ingrained in their lives, it’s like they want to go back to the only thing they know,” she explained, noting that hurt and loneliness often became the steadiest part of a homeless person’s existence after hitting bottom and going further under.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_325f36209dae4f53ab7323b33ebc626f&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;“If I had to do it all over again?” Isaac said in &lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/66697778&quot;&gt;a video interview&lt;/a&gt;, one of his last ones, a year before his death in 2014. “Unquestionably.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_b16c276d639c4ec8b8b17d928e978738&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;* * *&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_a1d983ee36f5429b9feafa9edc8a589c&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot; data-effect=&quot;dropcaps&quot;&gt;I keep walking along the tracks. Jon must have passed out drunk, now, somewhere behind me. Every noise is threatening in the tunnel, and I find myself constantly looking over my shoulder, ready to face something too awful to name. Was that a train I heard? A cough? The metallic vibration of a dragged chain?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_28ad9bf9ee3c47e388c857ba29347a7d&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;It smells like death here. The pungent stench of rotting meat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_d9e39780f2f249b8ba49306fcf5915d7&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;“Anyone here?” I ask, stopping near an old KUMA tag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_5bdb03eac92a4e61a83f73c3a0643c7d&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;The smell of death all over now. Are those eyes glowing nearby?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_294ee4ce96fb424ea17fb907dd86526b&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;I lean against the wall and try to breathe calmly, reminding myself this place is only populated by old memories and the occasional homeless person looking for a safe place to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_5f30cbde7861411595d86a65b501610f&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;The rumbling feels closer. Something moves somewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_7dcac316a9cb46ada121b3b4e84039a7&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;I see rats scurrying by, racing into the obscurity. Then I see the charred remains of an animal in the corner of an alcove — a raccoon maybe, a big rodent with liquefied flesh, burnt fur and missing limbs. Was it eaten? By what? By whom?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_c25b9b526f724084bc4da379456de027&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;I walk away holding my breath.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_964266036ce34138a66bfb7a9f2f9e32&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;The ground is littered with discarded books and magazines. A broken crack pipe has been left on a cinder block. There is a garden chair, and overturned crates and buckets. A mangled teddy bear. Death everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_a923e6a5f93b48e798cfbd74b51e9c6c&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;“Hey man, how you doing?” says a voice behind me, making me jump with fright. “I’m sorry,” the voice immediately adds. “I didn’t mean to startle you.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_fd454940d94d4b00ad46fb29e400d6a6&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;I recognize Raúl, an undocumented Dominican immigrant of about thirty who has been living in the tunnel for a year. Raúl shaves every morning with great care. His clothes are spotless, regularly washed at a nearby laundromat. His badly decayed teeth and scrawny figure are the only hints he’s a drug addict.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_476328cbdf364fde9ac16da10558148b&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;“I didn’t hear you coming,” I say with my heart pounding like it wants out of my chest. “I came to see Bernard’s old place. Maybe talk to some people.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_f715a4d778ca4918804bad9fe934ae3c&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;“Brooklyn is there. She’s always singing out loud, it’s annoying.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_a31e0e612f624357809124dcfdf26504&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Raúl still has family out there. An ex-girlfriend and a kid. He rents an apartment from a friend when his kid comes to visit, a clean studio in a gray Washington Heights building.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;ImageBlock_Image alignright&quot; src=&quot;http://cz598rxdt5our6verxu01782.wpengine.netdna-cdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/qtwvwjd7TvmogDuk8cEY_1uA6ZfDk99Grz80z9TZ7-w90eW6AMfFkdnOxc0AMpf0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;301&quot; height=&quot;226&quot;/&gt;&lt;p id=&quot;text_21747190f095446283bdc5bae16e5902&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;“I don’t want him to think of me as a bum,” he says. “I won’t be here long enough anyway. You want coffee?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_6c6e97c31e9640f4996d987cb2f39922&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;I nod and he goes into an abandoned service room, returning with two mugs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_b930f36d5ef94f41badd91c85a193643&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;“I made a lot of bad choices in my life. I hurt a lot of people. That’s why I don’t ask for nothing, you feel me? I don’t blame anyone but myself. I collect cans, it keeps me busy. I do it all week long. It gets me $140 a week, more in summer.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_7be6470702734b23988d89d34f926e05&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;The coffee is nice and strong. It feels good in the tunnel’s cold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_7cde5da884654478b9c5856955b87c03&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Raúl uses a Fairway Market cart to bring empty soda and beer containers to various stores in the neighborhood, where he will redeem them for five cents each. The legal limit of returnable cans is 240 per person per day, so Raúl has to go to several supermarkets to earn more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_26302cab19e24d128209cfd862ae631d&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;“You can actually make a good life here when you’re broke,” he says. “I never got a problem eating what I wanted. The streets are full of opportunities if you know where to look. I deal with what I have.” He shows me a box of cupcakes he found in a garbage can, almost untouched. His dessert tonight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_a649e7917b504121b87fce60a8c8fa51&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Finding drugs has never been a problem either for Raúl, who tells me he once spent $150 on crack each day to feed his “pizzo” — his pipe — with “cheap McDonald meals in-between the smokes, and hard fucks with Puerto Rican whores because crack makes me horny as shit.” Heroin prices have gone down lately, so that means Raúl’s consumption has gone up. It’s $10 for a deck of brown heroin, making it cheaper than most other drugs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_1bc1707726e4466bbabfe3ddca05ccd6&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Raúl knows the risks. The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oasas.ny.gov/admed/fyi/herointrend.cfm&quot;&gt;worsening quality of the local drugs&lt;/a&gt; means accidents are now more frequent than ever, with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nydailynews.com/new-york/nyc-crime/heroin-making-comeback-nyc-overdoses-outnumber-homicides-article-1.2173981&quot;&gt;420 overdose-related deaths in 2013&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_4af8823a2e02408b8e1e958331d7614d&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;“It makes me feel good for a moment. As soon as I find a real job, I’ll stop, no doubt,” he says. In the buildings he helps maintain, he occasionally sells the tenants K2 — a form of synthetic marijuana that recently boomed across the city, especially in East Harlem where a homeless encampment was &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2015/09/24/nyregion/homeless-on-east-harlem-street-feel-unwanted-pressure-after-raids.html&quot;&gt;recently dismantled&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_f6e38e2bd993436b819a67bc25c7f254&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;“I do what I got to do, you know what I’m saying? I’m just a normal guy who minds his own business. This is who I am. And I never ate no fucking rats,” he jokes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_54b6f125e1fb4235a87c579684cd6dc0&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Raúl insists we share the cupcakes he found. We both eat in silence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_aa7e46f51f1b46cb8cd241a0280e3331&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;* * *&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_97d10f61f01c4a05b000b0c9ebff6463&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot; data-effect=&quot;dropcaps&quot;&gt;New York’s homeless shelters are a lucrative business. The incentives paid by the Department of Homeless Services to landlords renting out shelter units far exceed the ones given for providing tenants with permanent single room occupancy lodging. In 2014, the average stay was &lt;a href=&quot;http://n90s.org/?p=902&quot;&gt;352 days at the Freedom House&lt;/a&gt;, a homeless shelter on West 95th Street managed by private company Aguila Inc. The city paid Aguila &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.vice.com/article/how-private-companies-are-profiting-from-homelessness-in-new-york-city&quot;&gt;$3,735 per month&lt;/a&gt; for each 100-square-foot room occupied by a homeless person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_5f8e38a406b840188d6ab5f3168c9d41&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Conditions are appalling inside the Freedom House. Garbage piles up in the courtyard for rodents to feed on. Aggressive panhandling, drug dealing and violent outbursts are commonplace in the shelter’s vicinity. Sometimes a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.westsiderag.com/2013/10/10/television-tossed-from-95th-street-homeless-shelter&quot;&gt;TV is hurled out a window&lt;/a&gt;, or the police close the street after someone is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.westsiderag.com/2012/07/23/morning-bulletin-homicide-on-95th-street-train-death-on-59th&quot;&gt;stabbed in a fight&lt;/a&gt;. The NYPD &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nydailynews.com/new-york/uptown/cops-push-raids-uws-homeless-shelters-article-1.1810775&quot;&gt;regularly raids&lt;/a&gt; the place looking for people with outstanding warrants, targeting domestic abusers and failing to arrest the major dealers or car thieves roaming the area. Aguila Inc. didn’t comment on the situation when I reached out to the company, but one of their security officers, who wished to remain anonymous because he feared reprisal from his employer, told me that the lack of resources, upkeep and care were the biggest issues in the facilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_fbd4af4499fc46c2b67f49fa98a2d3ad&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;“Why would anyone want to stay [at Freedom House]?” asks Jessica, a former resident. “I can’t count the times my stuff was stolen from me. One day I was assaulted in my own room and the guards didn’t do anything!” she adds, sitting on a rug in her new spot, inside a man-made cave near the Lincoln Tunnel entrance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_38436b97abea47cd8f18c2cc51373911&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Jessica was evicted from Freedom House in late 2014, after DHS came to an agreement with community boards and nonprofit organizations to cut the shelter’s capacity in two from 400 beds to 200 — a step toward its conversion to a meaningful permanent affordable housing facility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_54a707be9cb24d54a15912c5138d08e0&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;The 23-year-old knows enough about shelters. She will never go back. She was sixteen when she got pregnant with her daughter Alyssa. She briefly lived with the baby’s father until he tired of dealing with a needy toddler, leaving never to be seen again. Jessica was then diagnosed with schizoaffective disorder and admitted to transitional housing in Brooklyn. She says that within a month, social services was badgering her to place her three-year-old in foster care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_5111685a11ac40fd971334e8c900418f&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;“The thing is, single mothers who go to shelters with their kids never keep their kids for long,” she says. “I was devastated. I called my sister and begged her to take care of Alyssa until I found a place of my own. This was the most difficult thing I’ve ever done in my life, leaving my baby. But it was the right thing to do. At least she is with family. When she grows up I will explain it all to her.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_bf084cc949da4d60b7fd7acfeb5bd3c9&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;She looks away, tears rolling down her face.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_7136ebfc8b7d49a8a5d753a3ad7c02fe&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Once her daughter was in the hands of her sister, Jessica was sent to the Freedom House where she stayed for seven months until Aguila notified her of her imminent relocation. She began sleeping in a subway tunnel after transit authorities made her leave her spot in the Herald Square station corridor on 34th Street, dragging her by her feet when she refused to stand up from her mat. “At first I was like ‘I’m never going down there.’ But then Hurricane Sandy came and I had no place to stay, and I didn’t want to go to a shelter again with all the crackheads.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_a7c3c88d230d4775a57454ef21ddbe42&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;She spent about two months living in a recess by the subway tracks of a Midtown station, protected from the elements and from harassment. She wrote a long letter to her daughter there. She never sent it. “I hope you think of me sometimes in your dreams,” the letter ends. “You are the light of my life. I miss you everyday. I love you so much.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_2abd6b89d02f4296aef9e56917a16f11&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Jessica then moved to her current place, closer to the McDonald’s restaurant where she works. The subterranean area she’s living in is part of the same railway system as the one going through the Riverside Park tunnel, and is home to a couple of other homeless people trying to avoid shelters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_9413d3da71bf4ec681b7c5602c998c6d&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;“I obviously don’t tell my colleagues I stay here. But it’s better than anywhere I’ve been before. Here I can have my dog,” Jessica says, petting a small mutt snuggled on her lap. “Plus it’s a temporary situation. I’m eligible for Section 8 housing. In less than a year I’ll be in a real apartment and I’ll have my baby with me again.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_d776d019cf214afbabff3c92175f8c73&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;On the floor of her makeshift house is a plastic box full of donated kid’s clothes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_f5e43eed50a74db1a3617793e502bc93&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Soon she will give them to her daughter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_3678ccd9e6e24be688e6682060024814&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;“I have to keep faith,” she says in the half-light.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_2f46b1243ce64903a89eb29806cc770d&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;* * *&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_1b2430e82b6840a698c21ddbd2f95046&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot; data-effect=&quot;dropcaps&quot;&gt;Trash as far as the eye can see. Clothes, glass, bike parts and Styrofoam boxes, plastic toys and rotting food carpeting the dirt ground, all frozen in the tunnel’s perpetual dusk. Brooklyn’s voice echoes in the room as she starts singing Michael Jackson’s “Billie Jean.” I accompany her with a beatbox rhythm, hands cupped around my mouth. “You good, man!” she says enthusiastically, snapping her fingers along.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_c3dac727bf3a43a4b19410e5baf28dfd&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;I catch myself wondering if Raúl can hear us from his place, cursing at us for breaking the no-noise rule of the premises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_fa10c96b8cca4922a57df091d6a35756&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Brooklyn might be the oldest resident of the Riverside Park tunnel. Now fifty-four, she has been living here since 1982, when she discovered the place by following feral cats. Like Bernard Isaac, she appeared in various films and documentaries. “I’m a celebrity, you know?” she says with a hint of pride in her voice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;ImageBlock_Image alignleft&quot; src=&quot;http://cz598rxdt5our6verxu01782.wpengine.netdna-cdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/Vb35vSEiQgO7TkcailKf_WIQuh7HUEfdFIPW7EsuaY-jay4MDpp0JyKclDHrnomM.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;299&quot; height=&quot;225&quot;/&gt;&lt;p id=&quot;text_08608659ea484f37bf7956b022a0508b&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;She has perfected her story for journalists along the years. Everything she relates is recited like a school lesson. Her stint in the Marines. The death of her parents and the loss of her family house. The kids lighting her cardboard shack on fire in the park. Her boyfriend BK and their issues. The food bowls left at her door for the forty-nine cats she feeds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_16554b6347ec440eb4ded01a1632e5dc&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;She is a tough woman who speaks her mind, and she has the unyielding attitude of someone who has trudged through life. Her bandana and dreadlocks make her look younger than she is. People in the area know her, but she doesn’t socialize much anymore. She’s been lucky enough to avoid the Amtrak police. “I’ve been here all this time because I keep to myself,” she says. “The cops let me be. I don’t pose no threat!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_80054f5430dd4de59111aa189ae265e3&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;It’s already dinnertime. Tunnel stew today, a meal made of anything available — chicken soup, microwave mixes or thrown-away vegetables cooked over a crackling wood fire. “I wish I had a big kitchen with all kinds of cutlery and equipment,” she says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_8985afa1d271459ebd953735f19a7c85&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;“I’d cook all day long, man. That would be nice.” The food smells good and draws cats inside Brooklyn’s house. “You want some?” she asks, motioning at me to sit with her. The stew is surprisingly tasty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_bee3c6281e2b4a13949e7f434091a104&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;“We’re just people,” she says after a while. “It’s hard, living here. You never get used to it. If you accept it, if you stop fighting, you’re done, okay? If you give up…you just die, you know what I’m saying?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_5cbbbddb90584a808fccbccfb61ad48d&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;After she finishes eating, Brooklyn shows me a pile of recycling bags filled with countless Poland Spring water bottles collected at a nearby bodega. “This is my savings account for when I need extra money. You gotta be creative here,” she says as she gestures to the posters and pictures pinned on her walls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_83de6acd29544e17bf76fafc3c26816b&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Brooklyn is disappointed when I tell her I have to go. She calls one of her cats as I keep walking to the south end of the tunnel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_521cdb0f49fd4b7d9aa5fafcdc6e860c&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;I soon reach Bernard Isaac’s old den, where I will spend the night, as I sometimes do when I want to taste the solitude he liked so much. The whole place feels like a grave. A cathedral for the dead and the fallen. Nothing is left from the former shacks. Even the smallest pieces of debris are gone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_a257ab31c78a4d63b4653ce7983d321c&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;I try to imagine how it was sitting here with him, watching the flames dancing in front of Pape and Smith’s reproduction of Goya’s “The Third of May.” I realize there is a certain power of being nameless and buried. A raw, burning power that some, like Isaac, will seek their whole life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_d24b2e8443a544928e6eaa519947a24c&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;“Modern society is guilty of intellectual terrorism,” &lt;a href=&quot;https://books.google.ca/books?id=5RWsvXPDCPYC&amp;amp;q=terrorism#v=snippet&amp;amp;q=terrorism&amp;amp;f=false&quot;&gt;he once said&lt;/a&gt; while talking about Nietzsche’s philosophy with graffiti artist David “Sane” Smith, the younger brother of Roger Smith. Sane immediately sprayed the quote on the wall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_e6adc4b7abd047719c2a9c022a29c4e6&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;It encompassed Isaac’s entire way of thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_6d01792cc5c542608df5b0c2b3f9c9bc&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;A train rushes by, almost silent with its unbearably bright lights, the air swelling around me as the cars dash past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_2cdae60bece44a3088aaa66fb4298057&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;I’m rolled in my blanket, quiet in my alcove. I’m not sure I exist anymore. &lt;em&gt;This place is not for anyone to be&lt;/em&gt;, I think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_684db7db7ab24d818adf3db9bea148c2&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;I wait for dreams to come. Sleeping in the tunnel is an alien experience, but the sight of rain falling down the ventilation grates and streaking the chiaroscuro light is worth it alone, definite proof that poetry can endure anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_ad72a743c32846729b2b13002edd2a4b&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;This is the final byproduct of the city. This is civilization pushed to its foremost edge, a harsh place if any, dangerous and unforgiving, but a peaceful place at the same time, welcoming in its grimness. This is a dark and wild beast inviting you to come closer because nothing will ever be all right, but she will always be at your side to keep you warm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_5df951c78aed4db8b80e26d5e0c4c683&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;* * *&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_2a437a42b7444659b87071689cd3eeec&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot; data-effect=&quot;dropcaps&quot;&gt;When Amtrak decided to reactivate the Riverside Park tunnel’s train tracks in 1991, about fifty residents were evicted from the shantytown and received vouchers for temporary housing. This first round of evictions wound up largely ineffective and the population quickly grew back to its initial size, as people from up top encampments went straight to the tunnel when they were &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/1991/06/16/nyregion/evicted-from-a-ramp-they-call-home.html&quot;&gt;swept up by police during Mayor Giuliani’s effort to clean up the streets&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_e9bb6c1c7f804f4d8e7800a10183e573&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;The Empire Line trains rushing through didn’t stop them from coming down here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_4c4b777d215149f1813013147ab437e3&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Amtrak Police Captain Doris Comb started calling for more enforcement, effectively pushing the homeless out of the active railway. Different times were looming ahead. Safer times. Sterilized. Hygienic. “We try to offer the homeless a variety of social services,” &lt;a href=&quot;https://books.google.ca/books?id=5RWsvXPDCPYC&amp;amp;pg=PA245&amp;amp;lpg=PA245&amp;amp;dq=captain+combs+amtrak&amp;amp;source=bl&amp;amp;ots=X-0ziUhMUF&amp;amp;sig=Fq__LBVQiPNxfY7Iupu0TmdWnt0&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ved=0CB0Q6AEwAGoVChMIq_2Lof21yAIVQR0eCh05ZQoM#v=onepage&amp;amp;q=captain%20combs%20amtrak&amp;amp;f=false&quot;&gt;Comb would explain in 1994&lt;/a&gt;. “The problem is that most homeless are completely isolated. They feel rejected and decline assistance.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_05e3b645115d4df996279d9c42d24798&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Bernard Isaac still held a grudge against Comb eighteen years later, for having seized the #102 universal key to the exit gates an Amtrak employee had given him. “It was clear in my head that I didn’t want to go,” he told me in 2012, sipping a tea on the Hudson River Greenway. “We were ready to brick up the entrances if needed. We knew that we would have to leave eventually, but we didn’t want to accept it just yet.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_1d9410a2c592469589193dd66b5d1f64&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;The tunnel residents weren’t quick to fill the multitude of forms requested by the Social Security Administration. Some flatly refused to cooperate and gave up all hope of being granted Section 8 apartments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_6d732887deb94849b4552a61af8cd93c&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;In 1994, U.S. Secretary of Housing Henry Cisneros visited the dwellings and, realizing the urgency of the situation, released 250 housing subsidy vouchers and a $9 million grant to help the squatters move to appropriate accommodations. Unfortunately, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/1999/06/11/nyregion/waiting-for-final-resting-place-friends-seek-proper-burial-for-former-tunnel.html?pagewanted=all&quot;&gt;Department of Housing Preservation and Development policies prevented this from happening immediately&lt;/a&gt;; the Mole People were not considered “housing-ready” even though they had already created homes from nothing, complete with furniture and decorations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_3be2dfe3cad7433f88cddd1d5261b6f0&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;It wasn’t until Mary Brosnahan, director at the Coalition for the Homeless, negotiated with Amtrak to temporarily delay the evictions, that the vouchers were distributed to the tunnel community. The dwellers eventually received permanent housing, leaving the tunnel mostly empty for the first time since the mid-1970’s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_9d8e05ff3b704b2c9d84d80ef9431f2f&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Margaret Morton would later write in a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/1995/10/07/opinion/homes-for-the-invisible.html&quot;&gt;1995&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;a&gt;New York Times&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; that this solution had been by far the most economical for the city. “It costs more than $20,000 a year to keep a person in a cot on an armory floor,” she wrote. “It costs about $12,000 to keep that person in the kind of supported housing being made available to the tunnel people.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_6f2a6b70e02e4a7e8d1db83cee8c0779&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;As the photojournalist Teun Voeten would discover in 2010, some of the former squatters later achieved normal lives again. There would even be success stories. Ralph, one of the subjects of “Dark Days,” became manager of an Upstate New York hotel and owner of a cleaning company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_8a7fe6b235e94abc818eb16e7788a77b&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Then there were the others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_2febcc9538894c95bdc729cb0b6417a8&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;One would commit suicide, sitting in front of a running train. Another was found dead in his apartment. Another succumbed to AIDS. Another simply vanished. Isaac’s friend Bob Kalinski, the speed cook, moved to a 42nd Street SRO building where he still lives at this time, in a wheelchair and with a serious heart condition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_c9c80a7325664f259972af80f06c7abc&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Bernard Isaac passed away in late 2014, closing a chapter of an old New York legend. His ashes were sprinkled across a creek in his native Florida.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_9e3c826f94e7476fb6866abe728e418e&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;The legend was gone, but homelessness was more real than ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_e4d88c5f95ee4dc4976252e0924a89cd&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;According to Coalition for the Homeless, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.coalitionforthehomeless.org/the-catastrophe-of-homelessness/facts-about-homelessness/&quot;&gt;between 58,000 and 60,000 persons slept in NYC municipal shelters every month of 2015&lt;/a&gt;, an all-time record since the Great Depression, with numbers increasing for the sixth consecutive year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_e2a878d50b0b4acdaed65a7b4ad3fc61&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;“As liberal as New Yorkers want to be known, I think there’s a class war at work in this city,” Jeanne Newman, the founder of outreach group SHARE and a dear friend of Bernard Isaac, explained during a phone conversation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_b06cbfaf9fe34dad80527b7afea91852&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Eighty percent of New York’s shelter population is currently made up of families — many working multiple jobs to make ends meet. There were 42,000 homeless children across the five boroughs in 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_a354c07cb07f43e4aa8c8ddbde0cbc56&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;“Do you know what the major cause of homelessness is in this country?” Newman asked. “It’s the lack of affordable housing. End of story. Everything else becomes a symptom. Drug issues, domestic violence issues, they’re all symptoms, as opposed to being a cause. The cause is lack of affordable housing.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_9a261945b0524d459132ded12f2ebaa3&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;The median &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.elliman.com/pdf/eab81d3a4254f9dd8f9016d9153a548529309ca5&quot;&gt;Manhattan rent jumped more than seven percent in August 2015 compared to the same period in 2014&lt;/a&gt;, while affordable housing placements fell sixty percent between 2013 and 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_8da5c11e8dcd4daba918e74aed1fc940&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;“We’re the wealthiest country in the world, why are we not fixing this problem?” Newman asked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_745faadd116f4267b1abeac53a21ce6f&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;“Amtrak Police Department now does inspections on a regular basis for signs of homeless persons and encampments,” Cliff Cole, Amtrak’s New York manager of media relations, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wsj.com/articles/SB10001424052702304432304576371570715056048&quot;&gt;told the&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;a&gt;Wall Street Journal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a&gt;in 2011&lt;/a&gt;. At the time of his declaration, only five people had been found living in the Riverside Park tunnel, but a different community was already growing on a nearby dead-end street dubbed &lt;a href=&quot;http://lens.blogs.nytimes.com/2010/07/20/showcase-190/&quot;&gt;the Batcave&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_8f101680e47c45f1bb51fe9bb92ce2c5&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Today, Chris Pape’s murals are slowly vanishing, painted over in 2009 to discourage urban explorers from visiting the tunnel. His “Buy American” masterpiece, dedicated to the tunnel’s former residents and featuring portraits of Isaac and Kalinski, doesn’t exist anymore. His Goya reproduction has been damaged by water. In a few years from now, it will be completely gone, washed away by the elements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_0543316cc3ee4075a00517e4d3f6a131&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;* * *&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_d2fceca3dbf34584a07b29a8e74232e5&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot; data-effect=&quot;dropcaps&quot;&gt;Morning light is different in the tunnel — colder maybe, and whiter, casting long straight beams onto the rails. Wind gusts make dust rise up in whirlpools. A blue jay flies past a grate. I wake up and New York slowly comes to life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_d21e5bcdca434eef893f2dbefa499dfa&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;“God will save me, and it will save you, and it will save all these people too. Soon, we will all be saved,” Carlos says later, as we watch a basketball game in Riverside Park, the overpass casting its shade over our heads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;ImageBlock_Image alignright&quot; src=&quot;http://cz598rxdt5our6verxu01782.wpengine.netdna-cdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/dLyOeSgkSbOV5uMToAov_8zpEUCYJnWJvrZaiHRE677eF8pDnyjBDcZ3oxGioDIM.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;299&quot; height=&quot;224&quot;/&gt;&lt;p id=&quot;text_200870cc96ed485fa01f301062c30e2d&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Carlos lives holed up in an old sewer pipe of about six feet high by five feet wide near the south entrance to the Riverside Park tunnel. He is one of the few original dwellers who stayed. His house is small but very practical, entirely concealed by a metal lid he takes great care of pulling on every time he gets inside. “It’s a good hideout,” he explains in a thick Spanish accent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_a577b1d9a3c54596851bbecc346c13fd&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;His electricity is tapped from an outlet further down the tunnel, allowing him to store his food in a refrigerator and have heat during winter. “Insulation is pretty good. I’m comfortable and no one can see me. I’m used to it now. It’s good for reading. I read a lot. All kinds of books. I read them and I sell them.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_9c190674c71249209916f5813122840d&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;The increased police patrols make his life less simple than it was a few years ago, but he keeps an upbeat attitude about it. “They don’t give me trouble too much. Sometimes they try to make me leave. It’s my home, I tell them. Maybe I live like a mole, but I’m not an animal.” He just wants to be left alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_52f942cd6f9345a8b9642c54998ba8fc&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Carlos shows me where a decomposing body was found by Amtrak workers in 2006, months after taggers had discovered it. Two femurs bundled in cargo pants, neatly laid into an old child stroller, with pieces of leathered skin still attached to them, and a skull standing on top of a nearby pole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_2f4795af9cb5401083ae00eb50427e0d&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;This was the tunnel’s way of saying hello.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_6f692bd24393425c9cf031e25c558000&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;We walk around together to go check on Terry, an older alcoholic man who has been staying here since his wife threw him out of their apartment in Harlem’s Lincoln Houses public housing complex. Carlos is concerned about Terry’s health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_451e89ccd327408188193d227d934f0b&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;“He’s been drinking too much,” he says. “Last week I had to call 911 on him again.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_2f49291f59224af2bb7de009e9bf7f06&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;We find the old man sleeping on a couch behind a safety wall. A copy of Steinbeck’s novel “Of Mice and Men” rests on the sofa. Inside, a sentence is underlined in blue ink. “Guys like us got nothing to look ahead to.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_b02a9eee233c4f978a3d37181a30d325&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;We stay a moment at his side before I finally leave the tunnel, emerging from the wet ground behind a grove of trees. The streets seem slower than usual. The clouds heavier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_7ef65f3b02734a3e891ced88ce82828f&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;“What does not kill me makes me stronger,” Nietzsche wrote. But hurt doesn’t make us stronger. Hurt just makes us hurt. And hurt lives in the land of the lost, and unites them in missing love and broken homes, for five cents a can, 240 cans per day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_58b4fa9d008c48e7933c6067e5c4bd15&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;The few Mole People left today survive in hurt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_eaae593d29ab417ba1d94b13d85017a1&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;They are relics of a New York that was, and witnesses of a world so estranged that nobody truly remembers it anymore. Most are too late for the topside life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_8732cf14de4242df8a58d8899cd11a58&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;How easy it would be to go away and never come back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_bbfd2711b29f497e9935d371d9a13d55&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;But this is their city. This is their home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_cd8d433d5b6a4dfdbe2f6c80b56fa007&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;These are their minds wandering and their time slipping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_712d43f1902c45fba3268c39c3eaef38&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Their hopes and their thirsts until the sun goes down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;text_f3586fc197c44fe8adb54cfb672c4d67&quot; class=&quot;TextBlock&quot; data-role=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-type=&quot;text&quot; data-align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Away — to a place made of birches and wet leaves and blue afternoons and muddy clothes, a place where dark days would be foreign — a place for them and all the unseen, warm as liquor, where hurt would be sweet and love would be real.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2018 21:42:04 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mercutio2</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Secret Life of an Autistic Stripper</og:title>
<og:description>I've always had trouble reading social cues, but in the strip club, where rules and roles are crystal clear, I finally learned to connect.</og:description>
<og:url>http://narrative.ly/secret-life-of-an-autistic-stripper/</og:url>
<og:image>http://narrative.ly/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/header_secret_life_of_a_stripper-VN-16x9.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://narrative.ly/secret-life-of-an-autistic-stripper/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>BPG Image format</title>
<link>https://bellard.org/bpg/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://bellard.org/bpg/</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;meta http-equiv=&quot;Content-Type&quot; content=&quot;text/html; charset=utf-8&quot; /&gt;&lt;title&gt;BPG Image format&lt;/title&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot; readability=&quot;38.767851807589&quot;&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;News&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BPG (Better Portable Graphics) is a new image format. Its purpose is to replace the JPEG image format when quality or file size is an issue. Its main advantages are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;High compression ratio. Files are much smaller than JPEG for similar quality.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supported by most Web browsers with a small Javascript decoder (gzipped size: 56 KB).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Based on a subset of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/High_Efficiency_Video_Coding&quot;&gt;HEVC&lt;/a&gt; open video compression standard.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supports the same chroma formats as JPEG (grayscale, YCbCr 4:2:0, 4:2:2, 4:4:4) to reduce the losses during the conversion. An alpha channel is supported. The RGB, YCgCo and CMYK color spaces are also supported.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Native support of 8 to 14 bits per channel for a higher dynamic range.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lossless compression is supported.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Various metadata (such as &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Exchangeable_image_file_format&quot;&gt;EXIF&lt;/a&gt;, ICC profile, XMP) can be included.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Animation support.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Download&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following archive contains the source code of the &lt;tt&gt;bpgenc&lt;/tt&gt;, &lt;tt&gt;bpgdec&lt;/tt&gt; and &lt;tt&gt;bpgview&lt;/tt&gt; command line utilities (for Linux) and the associated &lt;tt&gt;libbpg&lt;/tt&gt; library (read the README file in the archive). It also includes the source code of the Javascript decoder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bellard.org/bpg/libbpg-0.9.8.tar.gz&quot;&gt;libbpg-0.9.8.tar.gz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Binary distribution for Windows (64 bit only): &lt;a href=&quot;https://bellard.org/bpg/bpg-0.9.8-win64.zip&quot;&gt;bpg-0.9.8-win64.zip&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unofficial &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mirrorer/libbpg&quot;&gt;Github mirror&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Mac users, the BPG utilities are available in the &lt;tt&gt;libbpg&lt;/tt&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://brew.sh/&quot;&gt;Homebrew&lt;/a&gt; formula.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Performance&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Mozilla did a &lt;a href=&quot;http://people.mozilla.org/~josh/lossy_compressed_image_study_july_2014/&quot;&gt;study of various lossy compressed image formats&lt;/a&gt;. HEVC (hence BPG) was a clear winner by a wide margin. BPG files are actually a little smaller than raw HEVC files because the BPG header is smaller than the corresponding HEVC header.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BPG natively supports 8 to 14 bits per channel when most other formats use 8 bits (including most of the JPEG implementations and &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WebP&quot;&gt;WEBP&lt;/a&gt;). It gives a higher dynamic range (which is important for cameras and new displays) and a slightly better compression ratio (because there are less rounding errors in the decoder).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BPG uses high quality decimation (10 tap Lanczos filter) and interpolation (7 tap Lanczos filter) to handle the chroma samples in 4:2:2 and 4:2:0 formats.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BPG can be supported in hardware with standard HEVC decoders and encoders (it uses a subset of the Main 4:4:4 16 Still Picture Profile, Level 8.5).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Demo&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Technical information&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The specification of the BPG file format is available &lt;a href=&quot;https://bellard.org/bpg/bpg_spec.txt&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Licensing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The BPG decoding library uses a modified version of FFmpeg released under the LGPL version 2.1 as HEVC decoder. The BPG decoding library excluding the FFmpeg code is released under the BSD license.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The BPG encoder as a whole is released under the GPL version 2 license. The BPG encoder sources excluding x265 are released under the BSD license. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.videolan.org/developers/x265.html&quot;&gt;x265&lt;/a&gt; library is released under the GPL version 2 license. The optional &lt;a href=&quot;https://hevc.hhi.fraunhofer.de/&quot;&gt;JCTVC HEVC reference encoder&lt;/a&gt; is released under the BSD license.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some of the HEVC algorithms may be protected by patents in some countries (read the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ffmpeg.org/legal.html&quot;&gt;FFmpeg Patent Mini-FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for more information). Most devices already include or will include hardware HEVC support, so we suggest to use it if patents are an issue.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fabrice Bellard - &lt;a href=&quot;http://bellard.org&quot;&gt;http://bellard.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2018 17:02:12 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jhabdas</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://bellard.org/bpg/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why Intel will never let owners control the ME</title>
<link>https://www.devever.net/~hl/intelme</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.devever.net/~hl/intelme</guid>
<description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;background&quot;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Intel Management Engine is an auxillary microprocessor embedded into modern Intel x86 CPUs or chipsets.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.devever.net/~hl/intelme#fn1&quot; id=&quot;fn1b&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; It runs an Intel-signed proprietary binary blob. Due to code signing restrictions enforced by the hardware, it cannot be modified or replaced by the user. (AMD x86 CPUs have a similar auxillary microprocessor, but they call it the Platform Security Processor. It's locked down in exactly the same way; the AMD situation cannot be considered to be any better.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ME firmware includes functionality relating to the system boot process, but also things like DRM functionality. It also supports remote management functionality (including an HTTP server, even) targeted at enterprise IT; this functionality allows IT departments to manage client machines remotely. It can access system memory without restriction. It can access the network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;can-the-me-be-disabled-or-removed-&quot;&gt;Can the ME be disabled or removed?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This firmware cannot be removed. In response to the legitimate concern about the nature and capabilities of the ME, some laptop vendors have started advertising laptops with the ME “disabled” or “removed”. This is an exaggeration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although it's true on some older Intel platforms the system could boot without the ME, on modern platforms the ME/PSP cannot be disabled entirely because it is literally integral to the boot process in a modern system. A modern, high-performance multi-core chip is a complex beast and generally requires initialisation before the “normal” cores, the ones on which your chosen OS runs, start executing their first instruction. The x86 reset vector is a lie; a great deal happens before the BIOS starts running.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two solutions available today to reduce the threat level posed by the ME firmware: the “High Assurance Program” bit, and &lt;code&gt;me_cleaner&lt;/code&gt;. The HAP bit is a configuration flag offered by Intel apparently at the request of the US government, and appears to disable most of the ME's functionality, leaving only the functionality critical to system operation running. &lt;code&gt;me_cleaner&lt;/code&gt; removes optional modules from ME firmware images (this modification is possible because the modules are signed individually, so you can choose which modules to include), leaving only the ones critical to boot. Both of these provide a worthwhile and substantial reduction in attack surface. But this is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; a total disablement or removal of the ME, and it's inaccurate to refer to it as such.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-intel-musn-t-allow-you-to-control-it&quot;&gt;Why Intel &lt;em&gt;musn't&lt;/em&gt; allow you to control it&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intel/AMD will never allow machine owners to control the code executing on the ME/PSP because they have decided to build a business on preventing you from doing so. In particular, it's likely that they're actually contractually obligated not to let you control these processors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason is that Intel literally decided to collude with Hollywood to integrate DRM into their CPUs; they conspired with media companies to lock you out of certain parts of your machine. After all, this is the company that created HDCP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This DRM functionality is implemented on the ME/PSP. Its ability to implement DRM depends on you not having control over it, and not having control over the code that runs on it. Allowing you to control the code running on the ME would directly compromise an initiative which Intel has been advancing for over a decade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-did-amd-do-the-same-thing-&quot;&gt;Why did AMD do the same thing?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though it makes it no less forgivable, AMD had no choice in the matter, because Intel defines the market. As far as I'm aware, Ultra-HD Blu-rays depend on this Intel DRM functionality; essentially, neither your OS nor the applications running on it ever see decrypted content, it's decrypted on the ME, which doesn't trust the OS to be secure (against you), and passed securely to your GPU. (I'm to understand GPUs have similar accommodations.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As soon as Intel decided to do this, it was inevitable that AMD would also have to; if they were to decide to not follow Intel on this, they would be going to market with CPUs that can't be used to watch Ultra-HD Blu-rays (this would be a positive to me, but that's not how consumers work), and you can bet Intel would exploit this fact at every opportunity for a marketing advantage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other words, AMD's choices here are between doing the right thing and committing market suicide, and following Intel and being able to compete. For this reason the design of the PSP matches that of the ME from every perspective as regards owner control; the responsibility for the present state of affairs lies ultimately with Intel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;could-intel-or-amd-make-a-version-of-their-cpus-without-drm-and-let-owners-control-that-&quot;&gt;Could Intel or AMD make a version of their CPUs without DRM and let owners control that?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the logical next question: what stops Intel/AMD from providing variants of their CPUs which lack the DRM functionality, and for which providing control over the ME does not threaten theose schemes?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, it transpires that there may be contractual obstacles to this. According to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.phoronix.com/forums/forum/hardware/processors-memory/1032782-13-way-ibm-power9-talos-ii-vs-intel-xeon-vs-amd-linux-benchmarks-on-debian?p=1033245#post1033245&quot;&gt;posts by an AMD employee on the Phoronix forums (see linked post and all following posts by the same user),&lt;/a&gt; AMD is contractually obligated not to reveal details about the internals of their GPUs, because those GPUs implement DRM and security by obscurity and the tiresomeness of reverse engineering is apparently part of what Hollywood's counting on. In other words, AMD may be contractually precluded from revealing the internals of a DRM-free GPU (to enable open source firmware to be developed, for example), because that DRM-free GPU would be so closely related, in terms of internal architecture, to a DRM-implementing GPU that it would provide useful information to people trying to break that DRM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the above concerns AMD GPUs, it's not hard to imagine a similar dynamic in play for the ME/PSP. If Intel/AMD released CPUs with an owner-controllable ME/PSP, open source firmware would be likely to follow, and an understanding of the internals would be developed. By the above logic, Hollywood would perceive this as being helpful to people trying to break DRM on the sibling models which implement it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's basically stated that because of the above contractual obligations, it would be necessary for a DRM-free but owner-controllable design to differ significantly in its internals from a DRM'd design simply for the sake of being different, so that it doesn't reveal information about the DRM'd design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, for AMD to make CPUs or GPUs which are DRM-free but owner controllable would be likely to require substantial engineering R&amp;amp;D, for no other reason but than to satisfy these gratutitous contractual requirements. Intel/AMD are unlikely to do this unless they perceive sufficient market demand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The x86 platform is a dead end from an owner-control perspective. See also the excellent paper &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.invisiblethings.org/papers/2015/x86_harmful.pdf&quot;&gt;x86 considered harmful&lt;/a&gt; for a whole laundry list of security issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;fn1&quot; readability=&quot;8.828025477707&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1. The ME was originally on the chipset; it's thought that it's now moved to the CPU die itself, but I'm not 100% certain of this. Accounts seem to vary. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.devever.net/~hl/intelme#fn1b&quot;&gt;⏎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2018 16:48:53 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>hlandau</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>application/xhtml+xml</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.devever.net/~hl/intelme</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Intel patches new ME vulnerabilities</title>
<link>http://blog.ptsecurity.com/2018/07/intel-patches-new-me-vulnerabilities.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://blog.ptsecurity.com/2018/07/intel-patches-new-me-vulnerabilities.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-3zYKlTwm7iU/W073gA7hQsI/AAAAAAAAG_4/GX9JpmnPvIA88IKcqD89Cu553rSxOwBAgCLcBGAs/s1600/5d2a85fc04ad45edaafac045c794f031%2B%25284%2529.png&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;600&quot; data-original-width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; src=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-3zYKlTwm7iU/W073gA7hQsI/AAAAAAAAG_4/GX9JpmnPvIA88IKcqD89Cu553rSxOwBAgCLcBGAs/s640/5d2a85fc04ad45edaafac045c794f031%2B%25284%2529.png&quot; width=&quot;640&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;In early July, Intel issued security advisories &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.intel.com/content/www/us/en/security-center/advisory/intel-sa-00112.html&quot;&gt;SA-00112&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.intel.com/content/www/us/en/security-center/advisory/intel-sa-00118.html&quot;&gt;SA-00118&lt;/a&gt; regarding fixes for vulnerabilities in Intel Management Engine. Both advisories describe vulnerabilities with which an attacker could execute arbitrary code on the Minute IA PCH microcontroller.&lt;p&gt;The vulnerabilities are similar to ones previously discovered by Positive Technologies security experts last November (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.intel.com/content/www/us/en/security-center/advisory/intel-sa-00086.html&quot;&gt;SA-00086&lt;/a&gt;). But that was not the end of the story, as Intel has now released fixes for additional vulnerabilities in ME.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;What happened?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;CVE-2018-3627, the vulnerability at issue in advisory SA-00118, is described as a logic bug (not a buffer overflow) that may allow execution of arbitrary code. Ease of exploitation makes this vulnerability more dangerous than the one in SA-00086, which was locally exploitable only in case of OEM configuration errors; instead, an attacker simply needs local access.&lt;p&gt;Things are even worse with CVE-2018-3628, which is described in advisory SA-00112. This vulnerability enables full-blown remote code execution in the AMT process of the Management Engine. Moreover, all signs indicate that—unlike CVE-2017-5712 in advisory SA-00086—attackers do not need an AMT administrator account.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Intel characterizes the vulnerability as &quot;Buffer overflow in HTTP handler&quot; allowing remote code execution without authorization. This is the very scenario that used to be the stuff of nightmares for Intel users—and now has come to pass. This vulnerability is similar to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.intel.com/content/www/us/en/security-center/advisory/intel-sa-00075.html&quot;&gt;CVE-2017-5689&lt;/a&gt;, which was found in May 2017 by Embedi, but with even worse consequences.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;What now?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;Perhaps the only consolation is that for CVE-2018-3628, Intel says that exploitation is possible only from the same subnet.&lt;p&gt;Positive Technologies plans to study these vulnerabilities more closely in future research. Notably, Intel indicates the same &quot;resolved&quot; firmware versions for the vulnerabilities as for SA-00086. In other words, it is possible that these latest vulnerabilities were found during security review of Intel ME code at the same time as SA-00086, but Intel delayed publication in order to head off the alarm and disruption that could have followed from packing such a large number of critical vulnerabilities in SA-00086.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;More on Intel ME security:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2018 13:09:43 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>nh2</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://blog.ptsecurity.com/2018/07/intel-patches-new-me-vulnerabilities.html</og:url>
<og:title>Intel patches new ME vulnerabilities</og:title>
<og:description>In early July, Intel issued security advisories SA-00112 and SA-00118 regarding fixes for vulnerabilities in Intel Management Engine. ...</og:description>
<og:image>https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-3zYKlTwm7iU/W073gA7hQsI/AAAAAAAAG_4/GX9JpmnPvIA88IKcqD89Cu553rSxOwBAgCLcBGAs/w1200-h630-p-k-no-nu/5d2a85fc04ad45edaafac045c794f031%2B%25284%2529.png</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://blog.ptsecurity.com/2018/07/intel-patches-new-me-vulnerabilities.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Getting Started with Quantum Computing in Python</title>
<link>http://dataespresso.com/en/2018/07/22/Tutorial-Generating-random-numbers-with-a-quantum-computer-Python</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://dataespresso.com/en/2018/07/22/Tutorial-Generating-random-numbers-with-a-quantum-computer-Python</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Quantum computers might sound a bit exotic and far into the future, but in reality, they are now accessible in the cloud or through emulators for everyone to write quantum code. In this tutorial, we’ll go through how you can program a simple quantum computer to generate random numbers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This example can be done on any emulator or quantum computer. For this blog post, the free and open source Python library &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ProjectQ-Framework/ProjectQ&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;ProjectQ&lt;/a&gt; is used.&lt;br/&gt;ProjectQ can emulate a quantum computer on any CPU, or connect to &lt;a href=&quot;https://projectq.readthedocs.io/en/latest/projectq.setups.html?highlight=ibm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;IBMs quantum computer as a backend&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br/&gt;To get started, just install ProjectQ through pip or &lt;a href=&quot;http://projectq.readthedocs.io/en/latest/tutorials.html#getting-started&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;follow their installation guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;gutter&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;code&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;pip install projectq&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;h5 id=&quot;Programming-a-quantum-computer&quot;&gt;Programming a quantum computer&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Programming a quantum program is a bit different from what we are used to when creating classical programs, we have to dive down in the levels of computer abstractions and use logic gates to manipulate data, along the same mindset Alan Turing used when creating his famous Turing Machine, which describes a classical machine doing classical computations on classical bits.&lt;br/&gt;A Quantum Turing machine describes a computer that can perform quantum computations on a Qubit, where quantum computations refers to applying quantum logic gates such as Pauli-X, CNOT etc to Qubits.&lt;br/&gt;This means that any program possible to write on a classical computer is possible to run on a quantum computer, and vice versa, but this &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1501.00011&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;doesn’t mean any program will be more effective on a quantum computer&lt;/a&gt;, in fact, a range of programs will run slower on a quantum computer and a quantum computer will have to work in parallel with a classical computer to handle computations where the classical computer falls short, computations such as matrix multiplication or finding prime factors to break &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shor%27s_algorithm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;cryptography&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;Creating-a-random-generator-with-quantum-gates&quot;&gt;Creating a random generator with quantum gates&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creating a (pseudo) random number is one of the first things taught in computer science courses. Usually, it involves importing a pre-made library called something along the lines of ‘Random’ and then just call the appropriate function.&lt;br/&gt;In quantum computing we’re not yet at this level of abstraction, but to create a random number is almost as easy by using quantum logic gates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quantum gates are similar to the logic gates we know from classical computing. Eg AND, OR, NAND, XOR etc&lt;br/&gt;For those not familiar with the concept, logic gates are a set of input and output used to manipulate an input through boolean functions.&lt;br/&gt;For example, if we feed the OR gate two numbers where one or both is one, the output will be True, if we feed the input two zeros the output will be false.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;A&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;B&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Q&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;The table above shows the truth table of an OR gate, where A and B are inputs and Q is the output. Imagine that a door only opens when a lamp is lit and will stay closed when both lamps are turned off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Logic gates can be used to compute any operation, and in quantum computing, we can use the logic gate called Hadamard to create a random number (1 or 0).&lt;br/&gt;The Hadamard gate takes one input, and maps the output with a equal probability of being 1 or 0, i.e. create a superposition where the input can be either 1 or 0 at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The basis state |0⟩ is mapped to:&lt;br/&gt;$$\frac{|0\rangle + |1\rangle}{\sqrt{2}}$$&lt;br/&gt;The basis state |1⟩ is mapped to:&lt;br/&gt;$$\frac{|0\rangle - |1\rangle}{\sqrt{2}}$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Hadamard gate is represented by the Hadamard matrix which shows that the rows are &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hadamard_matrix&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;mutually orthogonal&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br/&gt;$$&lt;br/&gt;H = \frac{1}{\sqrt{2}} \begin{bmatrix}1 &amp;amp; 1 \\ 1 &amp;amp; -1\end{bmatrix}&lt;br/&gt;$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quantum_logic_gate&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Read more about the Hadamard matrix and other Quantum Logic gates on Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Essentially, the Hadamard gate flips a coin and while the coin is in the air, it’s in a superposition in the sense that the coin can be both head and tail until it falls back down and we glance down at it - the human way of measuring the state of the coin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our quantum random generator outlined in a few simple steps together with the coin analogy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Create a new Qubit
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fishing a coin out of our pocket&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Applying a Hadamard gate to the Qubit to put it into a superposition of equal probability of being 0 and 1.
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Tossing our coin in the air, it can now be either heads or tail.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Measuring the Qubit
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The coin has finally landed and settled, its time to look at it to see if its head or tail.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;Start by importing projectQ along with the Hadamard gate and the measuring function. We’re using projectQ in this tutorial, but the same approach can be followed in other libraries and systems as well, the code syntax will be a bit different, but the theory will be the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;gutter&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;code&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;keyword&quot;&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; projectq.ops &lt;span class=&quot;keyword&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; H, Measure&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;keyword&quot;&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; projectq &lt;span class=&quot;keyword&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; MainEngine&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;Initialise the backend, we’re using the emulator, but you can also use eg IBMs quantum computer.&lt;br/&gt;Then Create a new Qubit to apply computations on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;gutter&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;code&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;quantum_engine = MainEngine()&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;qubit = quantum_engine.allocate_qubit()&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;We now have a Qubit that initialised and ready to be turned into superposition. Remeber the coin analogy here, where we picked up a coin and now is ready to throw it in the air.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re then applying the Hadamard gate to the Qubit, this refers to the step where we toss the coin up in the air.&lt;br/&gt;The syntax to do this will vary between each library and tool but in ProjectQ it’s simply done in the following way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;gutter&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;code&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;H | qubit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;One interesting thing to pay attention to here is that we’re applying the gate directly to the Qubit and not creating a copy. This is because unlike classical bits, Qubits cannot be copied due to fundamental laws of physics.&lt;br/&gt;However, its possible to &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quantum_teleportation&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;teleport a quantum state&lt;/a&gt; from one location to another, but this is something for the next tutorial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the Qubit in a superposition, we can now measure it, this refers to the step where the coin has landed and settled on the table and its time to have a look whether its head or tail.&lt;br/&gt;In projectQ the measuring is done with the following command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;gutter&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;code&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;Measure | qubit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;The measured qubit can now be printed and will return either 0 or 1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;gutter&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;code&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;print(int(qubit))&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tidying this all up in a complete Python code along with a for loop that demonstrates the randomness of our coin toss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;gutter&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;6&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;7&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;9&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;11&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;12&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;13&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;14&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;15&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;16&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;17&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;18&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;19&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;20&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;21&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;22&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;23&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;24&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;25&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;26&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;27&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;28&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;code&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;keyword&quot;&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; projectq.ops &lt;span class=&quot;keyword&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt;  H, Measure&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;keyword&quot;&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; projectq &lt;span class=&quot;keyword&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; MainEngine&lt;/span&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;string&quot;&gt;&quot;&quot;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;string&quot;&gt;This Function creates a new qubit,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;string&quot;&gt;applies a Hadamard gate to put it in superposition,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;string&quot;&gt;and then measures the qubit to get a random&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;string&quot;&gt;1 or 0. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;string&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;string&quot;&gt;&quot;&quot;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;function&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;keyword&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;get_random_number&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;params&quot;&gt;(quantum_engine)&lt;/span&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;    qubit = quantum_engine.allocate_qubit()&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;    H | qubit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;    Measure | qubit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;    random_number = int(qubit)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;keyword&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; random_number&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;comment&quot;&gt;# This list is used to store our random numbers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;random_numbers_list = []&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;comment&quot;&gt;# initialises a new quantum backend&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;quantum_engine = MainEngine()&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;comment&quot;&gt;# for loop to generate 10 random numbers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;keyword&quot;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; i &lt;span class=&quot;keyword&quot;&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; range(&lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;):&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;comment&quot;&gt;# calling the random number function and append the return to the list&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;    random_numbers_list.append(get_random_number(quantum_engine))&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;comment&quot;&gt;# Flushes the quantum engine from memory&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;quantum_engine.flush()&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;print(&lt;span class=&quot;string&quot;&gt;'Random numbers'&lt;/span&gt;, random_numbers_list)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some outputs from the random generator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;gutter&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;6&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;7&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;9&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;code&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;Run 1: Random numbers [1, 1, 1, 1, 1, 0, 0, 1, 0, 0]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;Run 2: Random numbers [0, 0, 1, 0, 0, 0, 1, 0, 0, 1]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;Run 3: Random numbers [0, 1, 1, 0, 1, 0, 1, 0, 1, 1]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;Run 4: Random numbers [1, 0, 1, 1, 0, 0, 1, 1, 0, 0]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;Run 5: Random numbers [1, 1, 1, 1, 1, 1, 0, 1, 1, 0]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;This was a simple introduction to creating a random generator with quantum gates in Python. Feel free to post any comments, concerns or questions in the comment field below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read more about the author &lt;a href=&quot;http://dataespresso.com/Christopher-Ottesen/index.html&quot;&gt;Christopher Ottesen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2018 13:02:42 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>chriotte</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Tutorial: Getting started with Quantum Computing (Python)</og:title>
<og:url>http://dataespresso.com/en/2018/07/22/Tutorial-Generating-random-numbers-with-a-quantum-computer-Python/index.html</og:url>
<og:description>Quantum computers might sound a bit exotic and far into the future, but in reality, they are now accessible in the cloud or through emulators for everyone to write quantum code. In this tutorial, we’l</og:description>
<og:image>http://dataespresso.com/images/quantum_computer_programming_tutorial_christopher_ottesen.png</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://dataespresso.com/en/2018/07/22/Tutorial-Generating-random-numbers-with-a-quantum-computer-Python/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ask HN: How do you organize/track your personal goals?</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17586375</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17586375</guid>
<description>&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17587255&quot; readability=&quot;15.661764705882&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;7.8308823529412&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;15.661764705882&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;17.619485294118&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17587271&quot; readability=&quot;0.81578947368421&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17590488&quot; readability=&quot;3.7731481481481&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17591973&quot; readability=&quot;1.2075471698113&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17587075&quot; readability=&quot;17.773869346734&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;8.8869346733668&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;17.773869346734&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;14.811557788945&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17593448&quot; readability=&quot;2.4388489208633&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.2194244604317&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.4388489208633&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17586742&quot; readability=&quot;7.6834532374101&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.841726618705&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7.6834532374101&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17586920&quot; readability=&quot;2.3490566037736&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17588242&quot; readability=&quot;4.1525423728814&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.0762711864407&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.1525423728814&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17590148&quot; readability=&quot;2.0631067961165&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17589279&quot; readability=&quot;1.505376344086&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17589959&quot; readability=&quot;3.2602739726027&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.6301369863014&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.2602739726027&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17586753&quot; readability=&quot;4.5525291828794&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.2762645914397&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.5525291828794&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17588436&quot; readability=&quot;2.5&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.25&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.5&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17587350&quot; readability=&quot;5.2162740899358&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.6081370449679&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.2162740899358&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;5.6509635974304&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17589694&quot; readability=&quot;4.6373456790123&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.3186728395062&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.6373456790123&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;5.1010802469136&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17592308&quot; readability=&quot;4.6657381615599&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.3328690807799&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.6657381615599&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17587438&quot; readability=&quot;8.531453362256&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.265726681128&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;8.531453362256&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;9.0054229934924&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17587487&quot; readability=&quot;8.8455008488964&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.4227504244482&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;8.8455008488964&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;7.518675721562&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17587495&quot; readability=&quot;2.5166666666667&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.2583333333333&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.5166666666667&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17587523&quot; readability=&quot;4.4311926605505&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17587575&quot; readability=&quot;1.84&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17587955&quot; readability=&quot;2.2268041237113&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17587689&quot; readability=&quot;2.2707182320442&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17586602&quot; readability=&quot;18.5396729255&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;9.2698364627498&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;18.5396729255&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;15.124470018171&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17587319&quot; readability=&quot;7.4152823920266&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.7076411960133&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7.4152823920266&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;4.171096345515&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17587579&quot; readability=&quot;4.6478873239437&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.3239436619718&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.6478873239437&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17587406&quot; readability=&quot;5.7571669477234&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.8785834738617&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.7571669477234&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;7.1964586846543&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17587361&quot; readability=&quot;6.8428437792329&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.4214218896165&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.8428437792329&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;8.3091674462114&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17587755&quot; readability=&quot;3.5102040816327&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.7551020408163&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.5102040816327&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17587380&quot; readability=&quot;7.7117647058824&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.8558823529412&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7.7117647058824&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;7.7117647058824&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17587338&quot; readability=&quot;0.48780487804878&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17590294&quot; readability=&quot;5.28&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.64&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.28&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;5.28&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17588219&quot; readability=&quot;3.042735042735&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17590531&quot; readability=&quot;2.1645569620253&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17587917&quot; readability=&quot;10.506293706294&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;5.2531468531469&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;10.506293706294&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;3.5020979020979&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17586678&quot; readability=&quot;7.9349005424955&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.9674502712477&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7.9349005424955&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;16.365732368897&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17586708&quot; readability=&quot;7.8452481076535&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.9226240538267&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7.8452481076535&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;11.76787216148&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17586897&quot; readability=&quot;2.6123595505618&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.3061797752809&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.6123595505618&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17586784&quot; readability=&quot;10.144306651635&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;5.0721533258174&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;10.144306651635&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;9.2220969560316&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17589622&quot; readability=&quot;20.578751857355&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;10.289375928678&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;20.578751857355&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;20.578751857355&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17586509&quot; readability=&quot;4.5388349514563&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.2694174757282&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.5388349514563&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17587004&quot; readability=&quot;5.65625&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.828125&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.65625&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;5.1848958333333&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17586632&quot; readability=&quot;5.4857142857143&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.7428571428571&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.4857142857143&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;5.0285714285714&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17592487&quot; readability=&quot;2.9642857142857&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17589703&quot; readability=&quot;4.3863636363636&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.1931818181818&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.3863636363636&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17586914&quot; readability=&quot;3.5087719298246&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.7543859649123&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.5087719298246&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17587049&quot; readability=&quot;1.1627906976744&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17586534&quot; readability=&quot;1.265306122449&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17587514&quot; readability=&quot;5.2663755458515&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.6331877729258&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.2663755458515&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17589304&quot; readability=&quot;1.0980392156863&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17587223&quot; readability=&quot;2.5454545454545&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.2727272727273&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.5454545454545&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17587983&quot; readability=&quot;2.5507246376812&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17589090&quot; readability=&quot;10.059829059829&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;5.0299145299145&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;10.059829059829&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;9.1452991452991&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17586691&quot; readability=&quot;6.692&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.346&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.692&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;6.214&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17591280&quot; readability=&quot;11.591141396934&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;5.7955706984668&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;11.591141396934&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;5.3126064735945&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17587459&quot; readability=&quot;17.51106639839&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;8.7555331991952&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;17.51106639839&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;16.051810865191&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17587784&quot; readability=&quot;7.6296296296296&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.8148148148148&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7.6296296296296&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;10.013888888889&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17587968&quot; readability=&quot;7.4545454545455&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.7272727272727&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7.4545454545455&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;6.0568181818182&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17590032&quot; readability=&quot;14.089026915114&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;7.0445134575569&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;14.089026915114&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;17.846100759144&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17587345&quot; readability=&quot;13.94451962111&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;6.9722598105548&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;13.94451962111&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;13.014884979702&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17592663&quot; readability=&quot;2.5419847328244&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.2709923664122&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.5419847328244&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17591601&quot; readability=&quot;2.0176991150442&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17586947&quot; readability=&quot;8.8516483516484&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.4258241758242&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;8.8516483516484&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;12.293956043956&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17587222&quot; readability=&quot;5.5562130177515&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.7781065088757&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.5562130177515&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17586558&quot; readability=&quot;4.4370860927152&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.2185430463576&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.4370860927152&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17587109&quot; readability=&quot;3.3931034482759&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.6965517241379&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.3931034482759&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;3.8172413793103&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17587235&quot; readability=&quot;2.3814432989691&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17587609&quot; readability=&quot;4.6165644171779&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.308282208589&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.6165644171779&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;4.1549079754601&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17588110&quot; readability=&quot;2.4295774647887&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.2147887323944&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.4295774647887&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;120&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17586593&quot; readability=&quot;8.429003021148&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.214501510574&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;8.429003021148&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17586855&quot; readability=&quot;2.5&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.25&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.5&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17586976&quot; readability=&quot;8.7003841229193&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.3501920614597&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;8.7003841229193&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;6.7669654289373&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17588252&quot; readability=&quot;7.7538461538462&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.8769230769231&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7.7538461538462&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;6.4615384615385&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17586503&quot; readability=&quot;6.7895569620253&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.3947784810127&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.7895569620253&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;5.8196202531646&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17586713&quot; readability=&quot;0.85&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17587292&quot; readability=&quot;5.7877094972067&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.8938547486034&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.7877094972067&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;5.7877094972067&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17588062&quot; readability=&quot;6.5476923076923&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.2738461538462&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.5476923076923&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17586501&quot; readability=&quot;2.523178807947&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.2615894039735&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.523178807947&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;3.364238410596&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17589045&quot; readability=&quot;3.0545454545455&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17589593&quot; readability=&quot;3.5438596491228&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.7719298245614&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.5438596491228&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17586600&quot; readability=&quot;7.6135265700483&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.8067632850242&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7.6135265700483&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;5.2342995169082&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17586838&quot; readability=&quot;2.5128205128205&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.2564102564103&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.5128205128205&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17587201&quot; readability=&quot;3.6737588652482&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.8368794326241&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.6737588652482&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17587012&quot; readability=&quot;1.0384615384615&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17587646&quot; readability=&quot;2.4871794871795&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17587868&quot; readability=&quot;4.4230769230769&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.2115384615385&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.4230769230769&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17589269&quot; readability=&quot;2.5241379310345&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.2620689655172&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.5241379310345&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;3.3655172413793&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17587033&quot; readability=&quot;3.5&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.75&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.5&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17587682&quot; readability=&quot;3.1284046692607&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17587243&quot; readability=&quot;1.1958041958042&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17589118&quot; readability=&quot;0.47457627118644&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17588848&quot; readability=&quot;3.3333333333333&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.6666666666667&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.3333333333333&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17587553&quot; readability=&quot;4.8206599713056&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.4103299856528&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.8206599713056&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;6.2668579626973&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17588691&quot; readability=&quot;9.7020725388601&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.8510362694301&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;9.7020725388601&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;8.7318652849741&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17587389&quot; readability=&quot;4.7392996108949&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17587067&quot; readability=&quot;21.812542603954&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;10.906271301977&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;21.812542603954&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;28.752897068848&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;comment&quot; readability=&quot;31.945054945055&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c00&quot;&gt;I've tried and failed to use and stick to many productivity systems over the years. It almost seems like an obsession at this point to find technological means for improving throughput.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c00&quot;&gt;I was able to take certain ideas from GTD but I've never found myself able to stick to a particular system. They all introduce too much friction and I end up discarding them in favor of just using mind, memory, and physical reminders.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c00&quot;&gt;What starts to go missing when I ramp up productivity is the meaning behind what I'm doing. It's too easy for me to announce, 'doing things this way is stupid', putting the whole thing down, and then go back to relaxing.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c00&quot;&gt;The big problems in life don't really respond to any amount of productivity improvements. You can't GTD your way to having more meaningful personal relationships. And you can't GTD your way to more deliberate practice, you just do it, day after day.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c00&quot;&gt;I'm not &lt;em&gt;quite&lt;/em&gt; at the point where I'm willing to write off productivity hacking as profoundly missing the point of life. But tracking and organization is what you do to things that need to be done that you can't bother to make enough of a priority to where they can be focused on with 100% of your attention and creative energy. And if you are focusing on things with 100% of your attention and creative energy, then tracking just gets in the way.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c00&quot;&gt;That all said, I am actually actively working on a productivity system. It's a console and text-based system where I add things just by typing `add &amp;lt;COLLECTION&amp;gt; &amp;lt;ITEM&amp;gt;` into a terminal. Triage is accomplished by using `sort &amp;lt;COLLECTION&amp;gt;` and going through item after item with one strike of a key. Using Ruby metaprogramming superpowers, I'm slowly hacking away at the friction behind creating little software tools that all interoperate with each other.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c00&quot;&gt;What triggered this was when I got the idea to move all my personal scripts off of Github and onto Dropbox. I don't need version tracking, I need syncing and durability. This seemingly little change made all the difference in my interest in recreational coding. Being able to just pop open a console in any machine that I've set up and start running commands without having to pull git repos feels amazing. I can literally stop typing, letting the text editor autosave, then get up, go home, and get on one of my personal machines and pick right back up where I left off.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c00&quot;&gt;The grand idea is to profoundly reduce the amount of friction involved in integrating software into my life. I'll be able to `add idea vacation` then `sort` it into a category, then `plan` it, the end result being a flat list of action items that I can accomplish X number of every day.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c00&quot;&gt;Is it overkill? Absolutely. But the dream of absolute perfection is the only vision compelling enough to get me to even think about productivity improvements anymore. There's no lower fruit left for me to pick that actually moves the needle on anything. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17587544&quot; readability=&quot;5.0392156862745&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.5196078431373&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.0392156862745&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;4.6192810457516&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17589944&quot; readability=&quot;6.6433962264151&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.3216981132075&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.6433962264151&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;5.2198113207547&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;17586916&quot; readability=&quot;0.78260869565217&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2018 12:19:22 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mezod</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17586375</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>A new digital divide: Young people who can’t use keyboards</title>
<link>http://www.asahi.com/ajw/articles/AJ201803290068.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.asahi.com/ajw/articles/AJ201803290068.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;“How do I double click?” “What is a cell in a spreadsheet?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mashiko Ishii often hears that her fellow lecturers at Uchida Human Resources Development Center become confused when they are asked such basic questions during training for new employees of IT companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pressing the button of a computer mouse twice and knowing the basic unit for data input in spreadsheets are some of the fundamentals of using a computer, but it is not uncommon for even would-be system engineers to ask such questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason is clear. As smartphones have become extremely convenient, a growing number of students have never laid their hands on a personal computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lecturers who work with Ishii often start training by teaching students how to use a keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We need to teach them the basics before we start classes,” Ishii says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Younger generations often become underdogs in offices if they are unable to handle the technical requirements for their jobs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yoshiaki Hashimoto, a professor of information socio-psychology at the University of Tokyo’s graduate school, is worried that “a new digital divide is being born.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to analysis by Hashimoto and the Ministry of Internal Affairs and Communications, the Internet usage rate with smartphones and mobile devices was more than 80 percent among the demographic aged 10-19 from 2012 to 2016, but the proportion of those who used personal computers plummeted from 76 percent to 56 percent over the same period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given that they can write and submit their school reports with smartphones, they are not outsiders to the world of the Internet. However, much of this does not align with the knowledge necessary to work in their future jobs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The digital divide often refers to elderly people who are unfamiliar with IT equipment, but it seems that this phenomenon is also beginning to affect Japan’s youth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The digital divide has not been resolved for the aging population. According to Hashimoto, although the Internet usage rate rose to 88 percent in 2016 among those in their 60s, the ratio of those visiting websites was only 60 percent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems that there are many elderly people who cannot gather information they need, even though they can send e-mails on cellphones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I covered a Japan-Germany symposium on digital society in Berlin in February.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lena-Sophie Mueller, of the German nonprofit Initiative D21, pointed out: “Timetables (for railways) are no longer available in paper form. More and more services are based on the Internet and without access, those on the other side of the Internet are excluded from social participation.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the digitization of society makes our lives more convenient, it shows that there are still weaknesses in our system and that the benefits do not extend to everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a good reminder to think again that we need to keep our eye on technology’s limits and to consider what we can do to fix them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2018 11:31:27 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>paralelogram</dc:creator>
<og:title>A new digital divide: Young people who can’t use keyboards：The Asahi Shimbun</og:title>
<og:url>http://www.asahi.com/ajw/articles/AJ201803290068.html</og:url>
<og:image>http://www.asahicom.jp/ajw/articles/images/AS20180329005166_comm.jpg</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>“How do I double click?” “What is a cell in a spreadsheet?”Mashiko Ishii often hears that her fellow</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.asahi.com/ajw/articles/AJ201803290068.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>