<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Learning to Build Distributed Systems</title>
<link>http://brooker.co.za/blog/2019/04/03/learning.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://brooker.co.za/blog/2019/04/03/learning.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;meta&quot;&gt;A long email reply&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A common question I get at work is &quot;how do I learn to build big distributed systems?&quot;. I've written replies to that many times. Here's my latest attempt.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learning how to design and build big distributed systems is hard. I don't mean that the theory is harder than any other field in computer science. I also don't mean that information is hard to come by. There's a wealth of information online, many distributed systems papers are very accessible, and you can't visit a computer science school without tripping over a distributed systems course. What I mean is that learning the practice of building and running big distributed systems requires big systems. Big systems are expensive, and expensive means that the stakes are high. In industry, millions of customers depend on the biggest systems. In research and academia, the risks of failure are different, but no less immediate. Still, despite the challenges, doing and making mistakes is the most effective way to learn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learn through the work of others&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the most obvious answer, but still one worth paying attention to. If you're academically minded, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.the-paper-trail.org/post/2014-08-09-distributed-systems-theory-for-the-distributed-systems-engineer/&quot;&gt;reading lists&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://jeffhuang.com/best_paper_awards.html&quot;&gt;lists of best papers&lt;/a&gt; can give you a place to start to find interesting and relevant reading material. If you need a gentler introduction, blogs like &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.acolyer.org/&quot;&gt;Adrian Colyer's Morning Paper&lt;/a&gt; summarize and explain papers, and can also be a great way to discover important papers. There are a lot of distributed systems books I love, but I haven't found an accessible introduction I particularly like yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you prefer to start with practice, many of the biggest distributed systems shops on the planet publish papers, blogs, and talks describing their work. Even Amazon, which has a reputation for being a bit secretive with our technology, has published papers like the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.allthingsdistributed.com/files/amazon-dynamo-sosp2007.pdf&quot;&gt;classic Dynamo paper&lt;/a&gt;, and a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.allthingsdistributed.com/files/p1041-verbitski.pdf&quot;&gt;recent&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://dl.acm.org/citation.cfm?id=3183713.3196937&quot;&gt;papers&lt;/a&gt; on the Aurora database, and many more. Talks can be a valuable resource too. Here's Jaso Sorenson &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yvBR71D0nAQ&quot;&gt;describing the design of DynamoDB&lt;/a&gt;, me and Holly Mesrobian &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QdzV04T_kec&quot;&gt;describing a bit of how Lambda works&lt;/a&gt;, and Colm MacCarthaigh &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=O8xLxNje30M&quot;&gt;talking about some principles for building control planes&lt;/a&gt;. There's enough material out there to keep you busy forever. The hard part is knowing when to stop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes (as I've &lt;a href=&quot;http://brooker.co.za/blog/2014/08/10/the-space-between.html&quot;&gt;written about before&lt;/a&gt;) it can be hard to close the gap between &lt;em&gt;theory&lt;/em&gt; papers and &lt;em&gt;practice&lt;/em&gt; papers. I don't have a good answer to that problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get hands-on&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learning the theory is great, but I find that building systems is the best way to cement knowledge. Implement Paxos, or Raft, or Viewstamped Replication, or whatever you find interesting. Then test it. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jepsen-io/jepsen&quot;&gt;Fault injection&lt;/a&gt; is a great approach for that. Make notes of the mistakes you make (and you will make mistakes, for sure). Docker, EC2 and Fargate make it easier than ever to build test clusters, locally or in the cloud. I like Go as a language for building implementations of things. It's well-suited to writing network services. It compiles fast, and makes executables that are easy to move around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Go broad&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learning things outside the distributed systems silo is important, too. I learned control theory as an undergrad, and while I've forgotten most of the math I find the way of thinking very useful. Statistics is useful, too. ML. Human factors. Formal methods. Sociology. Whatever. I don't think there's shame in being narrow and deep, but being broader can make it much easier to find creative solutions to problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Become an owner&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're lucky enough to be able to, find yourself a position on a team, at a company, or in a lab that owns something big. I think the Amazon pattern of having the same team build and operate systems is ideal for learning. If you can, carry a pager. Be accountable to your team and your customers that the stuff you build works. Reality cannot be fooled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the years at AWS we've developed some great mechanisms for being accountable. &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/opensource/the-wheel/&quot;&gt;The wheel&lt;/a&gt; is one great example, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://wa.aws.amazon.com/wat.concept.coe.en.html&quot;&gt;the COE process&lt;/a&gt; (similar to what the rest of the industry calls &lt;em&gt;blameless postmortems&lt;/em&gt;) is another. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/danluu/post-mortems&quot;&gt;Dan Luu's list of postmortems&lt;/a&gt; has a lot of lessons from around the industry. I've always enjoyed these processes, because they expose the weaknesses of systems, and provide a path to fixing them. Sometimes it can feel unforgiving, but the blameless part works well. Some COEs contain as many great distributed systems lessons as the best research papers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research has different mechanisms. The goal (over a longer time horizon) is the same: good ideas and systems survive, and bad ideas and systems are fall away. People build on the good ones, with more good ideas and the whole field moves forward. Being an owner is important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another tool I like for learning is the &lt;em&gt;what-if COE&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;premortem&lt;/em&gt;. These are COEs for outages that haven't happened yet, but could happen. When building a new system, think about writing your first COE before it happens. What are the weaknesses in your system? How will it break? When replacing an older system with a new one, look at some of the older one's COEs. How would your new system perform in the same circumstances?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It takes time&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This all takes time, both in the sense that you need to allocate hours of the day to it, and in the sense that you're not going to learn everything overnight. I've been doing this stuff for 15 years in one way or another, and still feel like I'm scratching the surface. Don't feel bad about others knowing things you don't. It's an opportunity, not a threat.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2019 15:02:07 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>SirOibaf</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://brooker.co.za/blog/2019/04/03/learning.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>US Senate report on Equifax breach [pdf]</title>
<link>https://www.hsgac.senate.gov/imo/media/doc/FINAL%20Equifax%20Report.pdf</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.hsgac.senate.gov/imo/media/doc/FINAL%20Equifax%20Report.pdf</guid>
<description>&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hsgac.senate.gov/imo/media/doc/FINAL%20Equifax%20Report.pdf&quot;&gt;Download PDF&lt;/a&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2019 14:54:08 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>otterley</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.hsgac.senate.gov/imo/media/doc/FINAL%20Equifax%20Report.pdf</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Mimalloc – A compact general-purpose allocator</title>
<link>https://github.com/microsoft/mimalloc</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/microsoft/mimalloc</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;Box-body&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;markdown-body entry-content p-5&quot; itemprop=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/microsoft/mimalloc/blob/master/doc/mimalloc-logo.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img align=&quot;left&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; height=&quot;100&quot; src=&quot;https://github.com/microsoft/mimalloc/raw/master/doc/mimalloc-logo.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;mimalloc (pronounced &quot;me-malloc&quot;) is a general purpose allocator with excellent &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/microsoft/mimalloc#performance&quot;&gt;performance&lt;/a&gt; characteristics. Initially developed by Daan Leijen for the run-time systems of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/koka-lang/koka&quot;&gt;Koka&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/leanprover/lean&quot;&gt;Lean&lt;/a&gt; languages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a drop-in replacement for &lt;code&gt;malloc&lt;/code&gt; and can be used in other programs without code changes, for example, on Unix you can use it as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&amp;gt; LD_PRELOAD=/usr/bin/libmimalloc.so  myprogram
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notable aspects of the design include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;small and consistent&lt;/strong&gt;: the library is less than 3500 LOC using simple and consistent data structures. This makes it very suitable to integrate and adapt in other projects. For runtime systems it provides hooks for a monotonic &lt;em&gt;heartbeat&lt;/em&gt; and deferred freeing (for bounded worst-case times with reference counting).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;free list sharding&lt;/strong&gt;: the big idea: instead of one big free list (per size class) we have many smaller lists per memory &quot;page&quot; which both reduces fragmentation and increases locality -- things that are allocated close in time get allocated close in memory. (A memory &quot;page&quot; in &lt;em&gt;mimalloc&lt;/em&gt; contains blocks of one size class and is usually 64KiB on a 64-bit system).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;eager page reset&lt;/strong&gt;: when a &quot;page&quot; becomes empty (with increased chance due to free list sharding) the memory is marked to the OS as unused (&quot;reset&quot; or &quot;purged&quot;) reducing (real) memory pressure and fragmentation, especially in long running programs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;secure&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;mimalloc&lt;/em&gt; can be build in secure mode, adding guard pages, randomized allocation, encrypted free lists, etc. to protect against various heap vulnerabilities. The performance penalty is only around 3% on average over our benchmarks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;first-class heaps&lt;/strong&gt;: efficiently create and use multiple heaps to allocate across different regions. A heap can be destroyed at once instead of deallocating each object separately.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bounded&lt;/strong&gt;: it does not suffer from &lt;em&gt;blowup&lt;/em&gt; [1], has bounded worst-case allocation times (&lt;em&gt;wcat&lt;/em&gt;), bounded space overhead (~0.2% meta-data, with at most 16.7% waste in allocation sizes), and has no internal points of contention using only atomic operations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;fast&lt;/strong&gt;: In our benchmarks (see &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/microsoft/mimalloc#performance&quot;&gt;below&lt;/a&gt;), &lt;em&gt;mimalloc&lt;/em&gt; always outperforms all other leading allocators (&lt;em&gt;jemalloc&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;tcmalloc&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Hoard&lt;/em&gt;, etc), and usually uses less memory (up to 25% more in the worst case). A nice property is that it does consistently well over a wide range of benchmarks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://microsoft.github.io/mimalloc&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt; gives a full overview of the API. You can read more on the design of &lt;em&gt;mimalloc&lt;/em&gt; in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/research/publication/mimalloc-free-list-sharding-in-action&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;technical report&lt;/a&gt; which also has detailed benchmark results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Windows&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open &lt;code&gt;ide/vs2017/mimalloc.sln&lt;/code&gt; in Visual Studio 2017 and build. The &lt;code&gt;mimalloc&lt;/code&gt; project builds a static library (in &lt;code&gt;out/msvc-x64&lt;/code&gt;), while the &lt;code&gt;mimalloc-override&lt;/code&gt; project builds a DLL for overriding malloc in the entire program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;MacOSX, Linux, BSD, etc.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We use &lt;a href=&quot;https://cmake.org&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;cmake&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; as the build system:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&amp;gt; mkdir -p out/release
&amp;gt; cd out/release
&amp;gt; cmake ../..
&amp;gt; make
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This builds the library as a shared (dynamic) library (&lt;code&gt;.so&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;.dylib&lt;/code&gt;), a static library (&lt;code&gt;.a&lt;/code&gt;), and as a single object file (&lt;code&gt;.o&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;gt; sudo make install&lt;/code&gt; (install the library and header files in &lt;code&gt;/usr/local/lib&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;/usr/local/include&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can build the debug version which does many internal checks and maintains detailed statistics as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&amp;gt; mkdir -p out/debug
&amp;gt; cd out/debug
&amp;gt; cmake -DCMAKE_BUILD_TYPE=Debug ../..
&amp;gt; make
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will name the shared library as &lt;code&gt;libmimalloc-debug.so&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, you can build a &lt;em&gt;secure&lt;/em&gt; version that uses guard pages, encrypted free lists, etc, as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&amp;gt; mkdir -p out/secure
&amp;gt; cd out/secure
&amp;gt; cmake -DSECURE=ON ../..
&amp;gt; make
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will name the shared library as &lt;code&gt;libmimalloc-secure.so&lt;/code&gt;. Use &lt;code&gt;ccmake&lt;/code&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; instead of &lt;code&gt;cmake&lt;/code&gt; to see and customize all the available build options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Install CMake: &lt;code&gt;sudo apt-get install cmake&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install CCMake: &lt;code&gt;sudo apt-get install cmake-curses-gui&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The preferred usage is including &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;mimalloc.h&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;, linking with the shared- or static library, and using the &lt;code&gt;mi_malloc&lt;/code&gt; API exclusively for allocation. For example,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;gcc -o myprogram -lmimalloc myfile.c
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;mimalloc uses only safe OS calls (&lt;code&gt;mmap&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;VirtualAlloc&lt;/code&gt;) and can co-exist with other allocators linked to the same program. If you use &lt;code&gt;cmake&lt;/code&gt;, you can simply use:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;find_package(mimalloc 1.0 REQUIRED)
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in your &lt;code&gt;CMakeLists.txt&lt;/code&gt; to find a locally installed mimalloc. Then use either:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;target_link_libraries(myapp PUBLIC mimalloc)
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;to link with the shared (dynamic) library, or:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;target_link_libraries(myapp PUBLIC mimalloc-static)
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;to link with the static library. See &lt;code&gt;test\CMakeLists.txt&lt;/code&gt; for an example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can pass environment variables to print verbose messages (&lt;code&gt;MIMALLOC_VERBOSE=1&lt;/code&gt;) and statistics (&lt;code&gt;MIMALLOC_STATS=1&lt;/code&gt;) (in the debug version):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&amp;gt; env MIMALLOC_STATS=1 ./cfrac 175451865205073170563711388363

175451865205073170563711388363 = 374456281610909315237213 * 468551

heap stats:     peak      total      freed       unit
normal   2:    16.4 kb    17.5 mb    17.5 mb      16 b   ok
normal   3:    16.3 kb    15.2 mb    15.2 mb      24 b   ok
normal   4:      64 b      4.6 kb     4.6 kb      32 b   ok
normal   5:      80 b    118.4 kb   118.4 kb      40 b   ok
normal   6:      48 b       48 b       48 b       48 b   ok
normal  17:     960 b      960 b      960 b      320 b   ok

heap stats:     peak      total      freed       unit
    normal:    33.9 kb    32.8 mb    32.8 mb       1 b   ok
      huge:       0 b        0 b        0 b        1 b   ok
     total:    33.9 kb    32.8 mb    32.8 mb       1 b   ok
malloc requested:         32.8 mb

 committed:    58.2 kb    58.2 kb    58.2 kb       1 b   ok
  reserved:     2.0 mb     2.0 mb     2.0 mb       1 b   ok
     reset:       0 b        0 b        0 b        1 b   ok
  segments:       1          1          1
-abandoned:       0
     pages:       6          6          6
-abandoned:       0
     mmaps:       3
 mmap fast:       0
 mmap slow:       1
   threads:       0
   elapsed:     2.022s
   process: user: 1.781s, system: 0.016s, faults: 756, reclaims: 0, rss: 2.7 mb
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The above model of using the &lt;code&gt;mi_&lt;/code&gt; prefixed API is not always possible though in existing programs that already use the standard malloc interface, and another option is to override the standard malloc interface completely and redirect all calls to the &lt;em&gt;mimalloc&lt;/em&gt; library instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overriding the standard &lt;code&gt;malloc&lt;/code&gt; can be done either &lt;em&gt;dynamically&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;statically&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Dynamic override&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the recommended way to override the standard malloc interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Unix, BSD, MacOSX&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On these systems we preload the mimalloc shared library so all calls to the standard &lt;code&gt;malloc&lt;/code&gt; interface are resolved to the &lt;em&gt;mimalloc&lt;/em&gt; library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;env LD_PRELOAD=/usr/lib/libmimalloc.so myprogram&lt;/code&gt; (on Linux, BSD, etc.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;env DYLD_INSERT_LIBRARIES=usr/lib/libmimalloc.dylib myprogram&lt;/code&gt; (On MacOSX)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note certain security restrictions may apply when doing this from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/43941322/dyld-insert-libraries-ignored-when-calling-application-through-bash&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;shell&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can set extra environment variables to check that mimalloc is running, like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;env MIMALLOC_VERBOSE=1 LD_PRELOAD=/usr/lib/libmimalloc.so myprogram
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;or run with the debug version to get detailed statistics:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;env MIMALLOC_STATS=1 LD_PRELOAD=/usr/lib/libmimalloc-debug.so myprogram
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Windows&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Windows you need to link your program explicitly with the mimalloc DLL, and use the C-runtime library as a DLL (the &lt;code&gt;/MD&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;/MDd&lt;/code&gt; switch). To ensure the mimalloc DLL gets loaded it is easiest to insert some call to the mimalloc API in the &lt;code&gt;main&lt;/code&gt; function, like &lt;code&gt;mi_version()&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to the way mimalloc intercepts the standard malloc at runtime, it is best to link to the mimalloc import library first on the command line so it gets loaded right after the universal C runtime DLL (&lt;code&gt;ucrtbase&lt;/code&gt;). See the &lt;code&gt;mimalloc-override-test&lt;/code&gt; project for an example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Static override&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Unix systems, you can also statically link with &lt;em&gt;mimalloc&lt;/em&gt; to override the standard malloc interface. The recommended way is to link the final program with the &lt;em&gt;mimalloc&lt;/em&gt; single object file (&lt;code&gt;mimalloc-override.o&lt;/code&gt;). We use an object file instead of a library file as linkers give preference to that over archives to resolve symbols. To ensure that the standard malloc interface resolves to the &lt;em&gt;mimalloc&lt;/em&gt; library, link it as the first object file. For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;gcc -o myprogram mimalloc-override.o  myfile1.c ...
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We tested &lt;em&gt;mimalloc&lt;/em&gt; against many other top allocators over a wide range of benchmarks, ranging from various real world programs to synthetic benchmarks that see how the allocator behaves under more extreme circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our benchmarks, &lt;em&gt;mimalloc&lt;/em&gt; always outperforms all other leading allocators (&lt;em&gt;jemalloc&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;tcmalloc&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Hoard&lt;/em&gt;, etc), and usually uses less memory (up to 25% more in the worst case). A nice property is that it does &lt;em&gt;consistently&lt;/em&gt; well over the wide range of benchmarks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Allocators are interesting as there exists no algorithm that is generally optimal -- for a given allocator one can usually construct a workload where it does not do so well. The goal is thus to find an allocation strategy that performs well over a wide range of benchmarks without suffering from underperformance in less common situations (which is what the second half of our benchmark set tests for).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We show here only the results on an AMD EPYC system (Apr 2019) -- for specific details and further benchmarks we refer to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/research/publication/mimalloc-free-list-sharding-in-action&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;technical report&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The benchmark suite is scripted and available separately as &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/daanx/mimalloc-bench&quot;&gt;mimalloc-bench&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Benchmark Results&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Testing on a big Amazon EC2 instance (&lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/ec2/instance-types/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;r5a.4xlarge&lt;/a&gt;) consisting of a 16-core AMD EPYC 7000 at 2.5GHz with 128GB ECC memory, running Ubuntu 18.04.1 with LibC 2.27 and GCC 7.3.0. The measured allocators are &lt;em&gt;mimalloc&lt;/em&gt; (mi), Google's &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/gperftools/gperftools&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;tcmalloc&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (tc) used in Chrome, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jemalloc/jemalloc&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;jemalloc&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (je) by Jason Evans used in Firefox and FreeBSD, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/microsoft/snmalloc&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;snmalloc&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (sn) by Liétar et al. [8], &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rampantpixels/rpmalloc&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;rpmalloc&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (rp) by Mattias Jansson at Rampant Pixels, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/emeryberger/Hoard&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hoard&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Emery Berger [1], the system allocator (glibc) (based on &lt;em&gt;PtMalloc2&lt;/em&gt;), and the Intel thread building blocks &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/intel/tbb&quot;&gt;allocator&lt;/a&gt; (tbb).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/microsoft/mimalloc/blob/master/doc/bench-r5a-1.svg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/microsoft/mimalloc/raw/master/doc/bench-r5a-1.svg?sanitize=true&quot; alt=&quot;bench-r5a-1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/microsoft/mimalloc/blob/master/doc/bench-r5a-2.svg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/microsoft/mimalloc/raw/master/doc/bench-r5a-2.svg?sanitize=true&quot; alt=&quot;bench-r5a-2&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Memory usage:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/microsoft/mimalloc/blob/master/doc/bench-r5a-rss-1.svg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/microsoft/mimalloc/raw/master/doc/bench-r5a-rss-1.svg?sanitize=true&quot; alt=&quot;bench-r5a-rss-1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/microsoft/mimalloc/blob/master/doc/bench-r5a-rss-2.svg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/microsoft/mimalloc/raw/master/doc/bench-r5a-rss-2.svg?sanitize=true&quot; alt=&quot;bench-r5a-rss-1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(note: the &lt;em&gt;xmalloc-testN&lt;/em&gt; memory usage should be disregarded is it allocates more the faster the program runs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first five benchmarks we can see &lt;em&gt;mimalloc&lt;/em&gt; outperforms the other allocators moderately, but we also see that all these modern allocators perform well -- the times of large performance differences in regular workloads are over :-). In &lt;em&gt;cfrac&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;espresso&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;mimalloc&lt;/em&gt; is a tad faster than &lt;em&gt;tcmalloc&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;jemalloc&lt;/em&gt;, but a solid 10% faster than all other allocators on &lt;em&gt;espresso&lt;/em&gt;. The &lt;em&gt;tbb&lt;/em&gt; allocator does not do so well here and lags more than 20% behind &lt;em&gt;mimalloc&lt;/em&gt;. The &lt;em&gt;cfrac&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;espresso&lt;/em&gt; programs do not use much memory (~1.5MB) so it does not matter too much, but still &lt;em&gt;mimalloc&lt;/em&gt; uses about half the resident memory of &lt;em&gt;tcmalloc&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;leanN&lt;/em&gt; program is most interesting as a large realistic and concurrent workload of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/leanprover/lean&quot;&gt;Lean&lt;/a&gt; theorem prover compiling its own standard library, and there is a 8% speedup over &lt;em&gt;tcmalloc&lt;/em&gt;. This is quite significant: if Lean spends 20% of its time in the allocator that means that &lt;em&gt;mimalloc&lt;/em&gt; is 1.3× faster than &lt;em&gt;tcmalloc&lt;/em&gt; here. (This is surprising as that is not measured in a pure allocation benchmark like &lt;em&gt;alloc-test&lt;/em&gt;. We conjecture that we see this outsized improvement here because &lt;em&gt;mimalloc&lt;/em&gt; has better locality in the allocation which improves performance for the &lt;em&gt;other&lt;/em&gt; computations in a program as well).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;redis&lt;/em&gt; benchmark shows more differences between the allocators where &lt;em&gt;mimalloc&lt;/em&gt; is 14% faster than &lt;em&gt;jemalloc&lt;/em&gt;. On this benchmark &lt;em&gt;tbb&lt;/em&gt; (and &lt;em&gt;Hoard&lt;/em&gt;) do not do well and are over 40% slower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;larson&lt;/em&gt; server workload allocates and frees objects between many threads. Larson and Krishnan [2] observe this behavior (which they call &lt;em&gt;bleeding&lt;/em&gt;) in actual server applications, and the benchmark simulates this. Here, &lt;em&gt;mimalloc&lt;/em&gt; is more than 2.5× faster than &lt;em&gt;tcmalloc&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;jemalloc&lt;/em&gt; due to the object migration between different threads. This is a difficult benchmark for other allocators too where &lt;em&gt;mimalloc&lt;/em&gt; is still 48% faster than the next fastest (&lt;em&gt;snmalloc&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second benchmark set tests specific aspects of the allocators and shows even more extreme differences between them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;alloc-test&lt;/em&gt;, by &lt;a href=&quot;http://ithare.com/testing-memory-allocators-ptmalloc2-tcmalloc-hoard-jemalloc-while-trying-to-simulate-real-world-loads/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;OLogN Technologies AG&lt;/a&gt;, is a very allocation intensive benchmark doing millions of allocations in various size classes. The test is scaled such that when an allocator performs almost identically on &lt;em&gt;alloc-test1&lt;/em&gt; as &lt;em&gt;alloc-testN&lt;/em&gt; it means that it scales linearly. Here, &lt;em&gt;tcmalloc&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;snmalloc&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Hoard&lt;/em&gt; seem to scale less well and do more than 10% worse on the multi-core version. Even the best allocators (&lt;em&gt;tcmalloc&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;jemalloc&lt;/em&gt;) are more than 10% slower as &lt;em&gt;mimalloc&lt;/em&gt; here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;sh6bench&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;sh8bench&lt;/em&gt; benchmarks are developed by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.microquill.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;MicroQuill&lt;/a&gt; as part of SmartHeap. In &lt;em&gt;sh6bench&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;mimalloc&lt;/em&gt; does much better than the others (more than 2× faster than &lt;em&gt;jemalloc&lt;/em&gt;). We cannot explain this well but believe it is caused in part by the &quot;reverse&quot; free-ing pattern in &lt;em&gt;sh6bench&lt;/em&gt;. Again in &lt;em&gt;sh8bench&lt;/em&gt; the &lt;em&gt;mimalloc&lt;/em&gt; allocator handles object migration between threads much better and is over 36% faster than the next best allocator, &lt;em&gt;snmalloc&lt;/em&gt;. Whereas &lt;em&gt;tcmalloc&lt;/em&gt; did well on &lt;em&gt;sh6bench&lt;/em&gt;, the addition of object migration caused it to be almost 3 times slower than before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;xmalloc-testN&lt;/em&gt; benchmark by Lever and Boreham [5] and Christian Eder, simulates an asymmetric workload where some threads only allocate, and others only free. The &lt;em&gt;snmalloc&lt;/em&gt; allocator was especially developed to handle this case well as it often occurs in concurrent message passing systems (like the [Pony] language for which &lt;em&gt;snmalloc&lt;/em&gt; was initially developed). Here we see that the &lt;em&gt;mimalloc&lt;/em&gt; technique of having non-contended sharded thread free lists pays off as it even outperforms &lt;em&gt;snmalloc&lt;/em&gt; here. Only &lt;em&gt;jemalloc&lt;/em&gt; also handles this reasonably well, while the others underperform by a large margin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;cache-scratch&lt;/em&gt; benchmark by Emery Berger [1], and introduced with the Hoard allocator to test for &lt;em&gt;passive-false&lt;/em&gt; sharing of cache lines. With a single thread they all perform the same, but when running with multiple threads the potential allocator induced false sharing of the cache lines causes large run-time differences, where &lt;em&gt;mimalloc&lt;/em&gt; is more than 18× faster than &lt;em&gt;jemalloc&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;tcmalloc&lt;/em&gt;! Crundal [6] describes in detail why the false cache line sharing occurs in the &lt;em&gt;tcmalloc&lt;/em&gt; design, and also discusses how this can be avoided with some small implementation changes. Only &lt;em&gt;snmalloc&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;tbb&lt;/em&gt; also avoid the cache line sharing like &lt;em&gt;mimalloc&lt;/em&gt;. Kukanov and Voss [7] describe in detail how the design of &lt;em&gt;tbb&lt;/em&gt; avoids the false cache line sharing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1] Emery D. Berger, Kathryn S. McKinley, Robert D. Blumofe, and Paul R. Wilson. &lt;em&gt;Hoard: A Scalable Memory Allocator for Multithreaded Applications&lt;/em&gt; the Ninth International Conference on Architectural Support for Programming Languages and Operating Systems (ASPLOS-IX). Cambridge, MA, November 2000. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cs.utexas.edu/users/mckinley/papers/asplos-2000.pdf&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[2] P. Larson and M. Krishnan. &lt;em&gt;Memory allocation for long-running server applications&lt;/em&gt;. In ISMM, Vancouver, B.C., Canada, 1998. &lt;a href=&quot;http://citeseer.ist.psu.edu/viewdoc/download;jsessionid=5F0BFB4F57832AEB6C11BF8257271088?doi=10.1.1.45.1947&amp;amp;rep=rep1&amp;amp;type=pdf&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[3] D. Grunwald, B. Zorn, and R. Henderson. &lt;em&gt;Improving the cache locality of memory allocation&lt;/em&gt;. In R. Cartwright, editor, Proceedings of the Conference on Programming Language Design and Implementation, pages 177–186, New York, NY, USA, June 1993. &lt;a href=&quot;http://citeseer.ist.psu.edu/viewdoc/download?doi=10.1.1.43.6621&amp;amp;rep=rep1&amp;amp;type=pdf&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[4] J. Barnes and P. Hut. &lt;em&gt;A hierarchical O(n*log(n)) force-calculation algorithm&lt;/em&gt;. Nature, 324:446-449, 1986.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[5] C. Lever, and D. Boreham. &lt;em&gt;Malloc() Performance in a Multithreaded Linux Environment.&lt;/em&gt; In USENIX Annual Technical Conference, Freenix Session. San Diego, CA. Jun. 2000. Available at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kuszmaul/SuperMalloc/tree/master/tests&quot;&gt;https://github.com/kuszmaul/SuperMalloc/tree/master/tests&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[6] Timothy Crundal. &lt;em&gt;Reducing Active-False Sharing in TCMalloc.&lt;/em&gt; 2016. &lt;a href=&quot;http://courses.cecs.anu.edu.au/courses/CSPROJECTS/16S1/Reports/Timothy_Crundal_Report.pdf&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://courses.cecs.anu.edu.au/courses/CSPROJECTS/16S1/Reports/Timothy_Crundal_Report.pdf&lt;/a&gt;. CS16S1 project at the Australian National University.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[7] Alexey Kukanov, and Michael J Voss. &lt;em&gt;The Foundations for Scalable Multi-Core Software in Intel Threading Building Blocks.&lt;/em&gt; Intel Technology Journal 11 (4). 2007&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[8] Paul Liétar, Theodore Butler, Sylvan Clebsch, Sophia Drossopoulou, Juliana Franco, Matthew J Parkinson, Alex Shamis, Christoph M Wintersteiger, and David Chisnall. &lt;em&gt;Snmalloc: A Message Passing Allocator.&lt;/em&gt; In Proceedings of the 2019 ACM SIGPLAN International Symposium on Memory Management, 122–135. ACM. 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project welcomes contributions and suggestions. Most contributions require you to agree to a Contributor License Agreement (CLA) declaring that you have the right to, and actually do, grant us the rights to use your contribution. For details, visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://cla.microsoft.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://cla.microsoft.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you submit a pull request, a CLA-bot will automatically determine whether you need to provide a CLA and decorate the PR appropriately (e.g., label, comment). Simply follow the instructions provided by the bot. You will only need to do this once across all repos using our CLA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2019 14:27:09 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>dmit</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars2.githubusercontent.com/u/6154722?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>microsoft/mimalloc</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/microsoft/mimalloc</og:url>
<og:description>mimalloc is a compact general purpose allocator with excellent performance. - microsoft/mimalloc</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/microsoft/mimalloc</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Report on forced organ harvesting in China</title>
<link>https://chinatribunal.com/final-judgement-report/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://chinatribunal.com/final-judgement-report/</guid>
<description>&lt;h4&gt;On the 17th June, 2019, the China Tribunal delivered its Final Judgement and Summary Report.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;China Tribunal Short Form Conclusion – download &lt;a href=&quot;https://chinatribunal.com/final-judgement-report/china-tribunal-short-form-conclusion_final/&quot; rel=&quot;attachment wp-att-2763&quot;&gt;HERE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;China Tribunal Summary Report – download &lt;a href=&quot;https://chinatribunal.com/final-judgement-report/china-tribunal-summary-judgment_final/&quot; rel=&quot;attachment wp-att-2762&quot;&gt;HERE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The full report including appendix will be released soon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SHORT FORM CONCLUSION of THE CHINA TRIBUNAL’S JUDGMENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In December 2018 The Tribunal issued an interim judgement:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The Tribunal’s members are certain – unanimously, and sure beyond reasonable doubt – that in China forced organ harvesting from prisoners of conscience has been practiced for a substantial period of time involving a very substantial number of victims.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since then, the Tribunal has contended with a pervasive culture of secrecy, silence and obfuscation by the PRC relating to much material that could have helped in the determination of whether forced organ harvesting has occurred in China. The Tribunal is neither deterred nor disabled from reaching a proper conclusion on the evidence that is available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;China’s reputation as a gross human rights abuser has not had a bearing on the Tribunal in reaching a proper conclusion. The Tribunal has adopted a process for its work that safeguards an even-handed approach to the Peoples Republic of China’s (PRC) interests. The Tribunal has requested contributions from the PRC at every stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Tribunal has considered evidence, in its many forms, and dealt with individual issues according to the evidence relating to each issue and nothing else and thereby reached a series of conclusions that are free of any influence caused by the PRC’s reputation or other potential causes of prejudice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These were as follows;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;That there were extraordinarily short waiting times (promised by PRC doctors and hospitals) for organs to be available for transplantation;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;That there was torture of Falun Gong and Uyghurs;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;That there was accumulated numerical evidence (excluding spurious PRC data) which indicated:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;the number of transplant operations performed, and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the impossibility of there being anything like sufficient ‘eligible donors’ under the recently formed PRC voluntary donor scheme for that number of transplant operations;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;That there was a massive infrastructure development of facilities and medical personnel for organ transplant operations, often started before any voluntary donor system was even planned;- That there was direct and indirect evidence of forced organ harvesting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;These individual conclusions, when combined, led to the unavoidable final conclusion that;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Forced organ harvesting has been committed for years throughout China on a significant scale and that Falun Gong practitioners have been one – and probably the main – source of organ supply. The concerted persecution and medical testing of the Uyghurs is more recent and it may be that evidence of forced organ harvesting of this group may emerge in due course. The Tribunal has had no evidence that the significant infrastructure associated with China’s transplantation industry has been dismantled and absent a satisfactory explanation as to the source of readily available organs concludes that forced organ harvesting continues till today.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Tribunal considered whether this constituted a crime of Genocide;&lt;br/&gt;The Falun Gong and the Uyghurs in the PRC each qualify as a ‘group’ for purposes of the crime of Genocide.&lt;br/&gt;For the Falun Gong, the following elements of the crime of Genocide are clearly established:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Killing members of the group;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Causing serious bodily or mental harm to members of the group. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thus, bar one element of the crime, Genocide is, on the basis of legal advice received, clearly proved to the satisfaction of the Tribunal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The remaining element required to prove the crime is the very specific intent for Genocide.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Accepting legal advice about proving this intent, the Tribunal cannot be certain that the requisite intent is proved and thus cannot be certain that Genocide itself is proved.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The Tribunal wishes to point out that specific intent does not necessarily make a crime of Genocide worse in real wickedness than an individual Crime Against Humanity proved by the same set of facts.&lt;br/&gt;The Tribunal notes that forced organ harvesting is of unmatched wickedness even compared – on a death for death basis – with the killings by mass crimes committed in the last century. There is justifiable belief in the minds of some or many – rising to probability or high probability – that Genocide has been committed.&lt;br/&gt;In line with this, and by considering the evidence and the law, there can be no doubt that &lt;strong&gt;there is a duty on those who have the power to institute investigations for, and proceedings at, international courts or at the UN to test whether Genocide has been committed.&lt;/strong&gt; They should act immediately to determine accountability for any acts contrary to the provisions of the Genocide Convention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Commission of Crimes Against Humanity against the Falun Gong and Uyghurs has been proved beyond reasonable doubt&lt;/strong&gt; by proof of one or more of the following, legally required component acts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;murder;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;extermination;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;imprisonment or other severe deprivation of physical liberty in violation of fundamental rules of international law;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;torture;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;rape or any other form of sexual violence of comparable gravity;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;persecution on racial, national, ethnic, cultural or religious grounds that are universally recognised as impermissible under international law; and&lt;br/&gt;enforced disappearance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;in the course of a widespread and systematic attack or attacks against the Falun Gong and Uyghurs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In regard to the Uyghurs the Tribunal had evidence of medical testing on a scale that could allow them, amongst other uses, to become an ‘organ bank’. The world is already watching their interests and their geographical location – although very large – may render it possible to lend them support more easily than for the Falun Gong who are dispersed throughout the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Governments and international bodies must do their duty not only in regard to the possible charge of Genocide but also in regard to Crimes against Humanity, which the Tribunal does not allow to be any less heinous. Assuming they do not do their duty, the usually powerless citizen is, in the internet age, more powerful than s/he may recognise. Criminality of this order may allow individuals from around the world to act jointly in pressurising governments so that those governments and other international bodies are unable &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; to act.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Governments and any who interact in any substantial way with the PRC including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Doctors and medical institutions;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Industry, and businesses, most specifically airlines, travel companies, financial services businesses, law firms and pharmaceutical and insurance companies together with individual tourists,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Educational establishments;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Arts establishments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;should now recognise that they are, to the extent revealed above, interacting with a criminal state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;17th June 2019&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2019 13:36:23 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Scotrix</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Final Judgement &amp; Report - China Tribunal</og:title>
<og:description>On the 17th June, 2019, the China Tribunal delivered its Final Judgement and Summary Report. China Tribunal Short Form Conclusion – download HERE China Tribunal Summary Report – download HERE The full report including appendix will be released soon.   SHORT FORM CONCLUSION of THE CHINA TRIBUNAL’S JUDGMENT In December 2018 The Tribunal issued an …</og:description>
<og:url>https://chinatribunal.com/final-judgement-report/</og:url>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://chinatribunal.com/final-judgement-report/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>An ‘extraordinarily severe’ emergency: the radioactive leak at Harborview</title>
<link>http://www.capitolhillseattle.com/2019/06/an-extraordinarily-severe-emergency-the-radioactive-leak-at-harborview/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.capitolhillseattle.com/2019/06/an-extraordinarily-severe-emergency-the-radioactive-leak-at-harborview/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.capitolhillseattle.com/2019/06/on-the-list-before-stonewall-film-ginsberg-poetry-festival-at-volunteer-park-seattle-poetry-slam/tsjernobyl-4/&quot; rel=&quot;attachment wp-att-2067247674&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;2067247674&quot; data-permalink=&quot;http://www.capitolhillseattle.com/2019/06/on-the-list-before-stonewall-film-ginsberg-poetry-festival-at-volunteer-park-seattle-poetry-slam/tsjernobyl-4/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/www.capitolhillseattle.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Tsjernobyl-4.jpg?fit=3728%2C2796&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;3728,2796&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1.8&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Margo Vansynghel&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;iPhone 8&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1560346639&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Margo Vansynghel&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;3.99&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;20&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.0005&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Leak&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/www.capitolhillseattle.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Tsjernobyl-4.jpg?fit=400%2C300&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/www.capitolhillseattle.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Tsjernobyl-4.jpg?fit=584%2C438&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-2067247674&quot; src=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/www.capitolhillseattle.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Tsjernobyl-4.jpg?resize=584%2C438&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;584&quot; height=&quot;438&quot; srcset=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/www.capitolhillseattle.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Tsjernobyl-4.jpg?resize=600%2C450 600w, https://i2.wp.com/www.capitolhillseattle.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Tsjernobyl-4.jpg?resize=200%2C150 200w, https://i2.wp.com/www.capitolhillseattle.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Tsjernobyl-4.jpg?resize=400%2C300 400w, https://i2.wp.com/www.capitolhillseattle.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Tsjernobyl-4.jpg?w=1168 1168w, https://i2.wp.com/www.capitolhillseattle.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Tsjernobyl-4.jpg?w=1752 1752w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 584px) 100vw, 584px&quot; data-recalc-dims=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;A small platform crane hoists two men up near the roof gutter of a flat, one-floor building on the &lt;strong&gt;Harborview&lt;/strong&gt; campus on First Hill. Slowly, one of the men moves a thick, round bar roughly six inches along the gutter with his right hand, stops, and then looks at the radiation survey meter in his left. Then he moves the bar another six inches. And another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If there is any radiation left from the leak of radioactive material that left 13 people exposed during the decommissioning of an irradiator device in the middle of Seattle on May 2nd, these men will find it and wipe it down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The concrete L-shaped loading dock and parking lot, wedged between the UW Medicine Harborview Medical Center Research and Training Building and a small administrative building near Terry Ave and Terrace, is already polka-dotted with white paint marks, designating areas where potential traces of Cesium-137 were found.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While being checked for radioactive residue, the R&amp;amp;T building is still on lockdown. &lt;strong&gt;State Patrol&lt;/strong&gt; troopers guard the fenced-off entrances to make sure no one can go in and out. From behind the chain-link, there is not much to see — no Chernobyl-like scenes here — except for a sidewalk-wide stripe of white paint near the loading dock doors and a white plastic box covering the ventilation system. The parking lot exudes a ghostly calm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, the night of May 2nd, crews from the &lt;strong&gt;Seattle Fire Department&lt;/strong&gt; rushed to the scene to try to make sense of a rare incident that involved more than 50 people from at least six different agencies, including the department’s HAZMAT team, the &lt;strong&gt;Washington State Department of Health&lt;/strong&gt;, the &lt;strong&gt;FBI&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;University of Washington&lt;/strong&gt;, and a clean up crew with over 40 officials from the &lt;strong&gt;US Department of Energy&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More than six weeks after the leak, little is publicly known about what happened that night — and what went wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Records obtained by CHS, reports by the &lt;strong&gt;Nuclear Regulatory Commission&lt;/strong&gt;, as well as interviews with officials from the University of Washington, Washington State Department of Health and the US Department of Energy’s National Nuclear Security Administration shed more light on the night of the leak, and the aftermath.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plan for that night, with preparations launched early this year, had been months in the making.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.patreon.com/bePatron?c=217078&quot; rel=&quot;attachment wp-att-2067229389&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignleft&quot; src=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/www.capitolhillseattle.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/VolunteerParkPride2018-8.jpg?resize=200%2C133&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; height=&quot;133&quot; data-recalc-dims=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SUBSCRIBE TO CHS: Summer brings busy days!&lt;/strong&gt; Subscribers help pay for the writers and photographers who provide CHS's daily news coverage. We need to get our numbers back up to pay the bills! Join &lt;strong&gt;TODAY&lt;/strong&gt; to become a subscriber at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.patreon.com/bePatron?c=217078&quot;&gt;$1/$5/$10 a month&lt;/a&gt; to help CHS provide community news with &lt;strong&gt;NO PAYWALL&lt;/strong&gt;. You can also sign up for &lt;a href=&quot;https://squareup.com/store/chs-capitolhillseattle-dot-com-advertising/item/chs-annual-subscription&quot;&gt;a one-time annual payment&lt;/a&gt;. Why support CHS? More &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.patreon.com/jseattle&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;An irradiator, a medical device containing radioactive material used in research on the connections between bone marrow cells and immune response in a lab at the R&amp;amp;T building, would be decommissioned and moved to a safe disposal site with the help of International Isotopes, a contractor hired by the US Department of Energy. &lt;strong&gt;International Isotopes&lt;/strong&gt;, an Idaho-based public company valued at $20.85 million, routinely performs these kinds of operations where they go into hospitals, blood banks, and research centers to help decommission medical machines with radioactive material.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This irradiator at the R&amp;amp;T building was, like many others, for years filled with research samples to be sterilized with the help of the radioactive isotope cesium-137, which kills HIV, Hepatitis and other viruses, bacteria, and pathogens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an irradiator, blood and research samples are exposed to the radiation of cesium-137, a white powder, through a briefly opening radiation-blocking window, like a camera shutter system. This all happens inside the machine. Multiple tubes of metal containers surround the cesium-137, to make sure nothing can escape. That would be incredibly dangerous. Exposure to large amounts of cesium-137 can cause burns, radiation sickness and increase the risk of cancer– and in case of very large quantities, death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because cesium-137 is so easily dispersed in air, this also makes it an “ideal” material for a dirty bomb. That’s why an FBI officer and State Patrol Troopers are usually on site during a procedure like this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that’s why the State Patrol Troopers are still there weeks later on First Hill, guarding the entrances to the building in unmarked patrol cars. The radioactive source and the irradiator are still inside the building while the investigation runs its course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.capitolhillseattle.com/2019/06/on-the-list-before-stonewall-film-ginsberg-poetry-festival-at-volunteer-park-seattle-poetry-slam/tsjernobyl-1/&quot; rel=&quot;attachment wp-att-2067247671&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;2067247671&quot; data-permalink=&quot;http://www.capitolhillseattle.com/2019/06/on-the-list-before-stonewall-film-ginsberg-poetry-festival-at-volunteer-park-seattle-poetry-slam/tsjernobyl-1/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/www.capitolhillseattle.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Tsjernobyl-1.jpg?fit=3024%2C4032&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;3024,4032&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1.8&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Margo Vansynghel&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;iPhone 8&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1560346620&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Margo Vansynghel&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;3.99&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;20&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.000952380952381&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Leak 2&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/www.capitolhillseattle.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Tsjernobyl-1.jpg?fit=400%2C533&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/www.capitolhillseattle.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Tsjernobyl-1.jpg?fit=584%2C779&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-2067247671 size-large&quot; src=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/www.capitolhillseattle.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Tsjernobyl-1.jpg?resize=584%2C779&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;584&quot; height=&quot;779&quot; srcset=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/www.capitolhillseattle.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Tsjernobyl-1.jpg?resize=600%2C800 600w, https://i2.wp.com/www.capitolhillseattle.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Tsjernobyl-1.jpg?resize=150%2C200 150w, https://i2.wp.com/www.capitolhillseattle.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Tsjernobyl-1.jpg?resize=400%2C533 400w, https://i2.wp.com/www.capitolhillseattle.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Tsjernobyl-1.jpg?resize=225%2C300 225w, https://i2.wp.com/www.capitolhillseattle.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Tsjernobyl-1.jpg?w=1168 1168w, https://i2.wp.com/www.capitolhillseattle.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Tsjernobyl-1.jpg?w=1752 1752w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 584px) 100vw, 584px&quot; data-recalc-dims=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Cesium-137 is one of the isotopes of most concern in what’s called ‘nuclear nonproliferation,'” said &lt;strong&gt;Leigh Winfrey&lt;/strong&gt;, Ph.D., Associate Professor of Nuclear Engineering at &lt;strong&gt;Pennsylvania State University&lt;/strong&gt;. “It could potentially be a target for terrorists to take and put it in regular bombs, because it’s easily dispersed [in the air], it dissolves in water. It would be really, really nasty if it was distributed with a regular bomb.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After 9/11, concerns about dirty bombs increased, so the Department of Energy’s Off-Site Source Recovery Program (OSRP), which recovers excess and unwanted radioactive sources, expanded its efforts to decommission more types of sources that contained high amounts of radioactive material, &lt;a href=&quot;https://osrp.lanl.gov/what_is_osr.shtml&quot;&gt;particularly so-called “high-risk” sources&lt;/a&gt; greater than 130 curies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Decommissioning the device at Harborview — which contained 4,000 curies of cesium-137 — was part of a fairly common phasing-out procedure for hospitals and labs across the country. But a leak like this is not. The state Department of Health called it “very rare,” as did Winfrey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This kind of material doesn’t just sort of sit around,” Winfrey said. “so we’re usually very, very cautious.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the decommissioning process on May 2nd, this meant that seven International Isotopes contractors would be, in keeping with protocol, accompanied by an FBI officer, inspectors from the Department of Health, and two radiation experts from UW.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The procedure wouldn’t take more than one night. They would start after 5 PM and perhaps get the device out by daybreak. By the morning of May 3rd, the irradiator and vial of cesium-137 would be on trucks to be shipped to safe disposal sites, and the roughly 200 researchers and employees of the R&amp;amp;T building would be able to go back to their jobs and into their labs running tests on sexually transmitted diseases, Alzheimer’s, vaccine trials and other research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But that isn’t what happened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first leg of the procedure went fine. The machine had been moved, with a crane, to the loading dock area, basically a garage (a couple of floors above the vivarium that holds live animals, mostly rodents, for research). International Isotopes contractors had set up a secure steel “chamber” wherein they would perform a crucial, most perilous part of the operation: removing the capsule with cesium-137 from the irradiator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Separating the two before transport is not out of the ordinary. Winfrey said that transporting the capsule within the irradiator would be extremely unsafe and against regulation — there are special transport casks for the radioactive capsule that can withstand accidents and even missile hits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so, the crew, wearing steel-toed boots and gloves deployed a “grinding wheel” to remove a tungsten plug that held a protective sleeve around the capsule. Tungsten is both very hard and brittle, difficult to cut and tends to shatter. That might have made the cutting work harder. At some point, the capsule with cesium-137, instead of just the tungsten plug, was cut.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Generally, once that pin is removed, the source holder is removed from the plug and the source [cesium-137 capsule] can be accessed,” said &lt;strong&gt;Leslie Velarde&lt;/strong&gt;, Public Affairs Specialist for the DOE’s National Nuclear Security Administration. “There was never an intent to cut the source itself.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quickly, an estimated 2,800 curies of cesium-137 spread into the irradiator, the “chamber,” the loading dock and a 100-feet radius around the loading dock, plus the first three floors and one stair of the R&amp;amp;T building, resulting in “widespread contamination.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The leak happened at 9.30 PM and was discovered during a regular and procedural wipe-down, meant to see if any material had been released.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A 911 call, from the on-scene Weapons of Mass Destruction (WMD) coordinator, came in about an hour later, at 10:25 PM. The message: there has been a “radiation leak from a blood irradiator,” a draft report from the Seattle Fire Department notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quickly, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/SeattleFire/status/1124241648425115649?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1124241648425115649&amp;amp;ref_url=https://www.firehouse.com/rescue/hazardous-materials/news/21079163/seattle-harborview-medical-center-radioactive-spill-exposure-firefighters&quot;&gt;Seattle Fire Department Hazardous Materials Response Team&lt;/a&gt; (HAZMAT team) speeds to the scene. When they get there, tape has already been hung to cordon off both entrances to the parking area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The UW Radiation Safety Officer, who was on site for the operation and had most likely been exposed to the radioactive material himself, tells the Fire Department seven contractors are still inside, attempting to “weld the breach shut.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apart from them, he says, six others had been in the building: janitors who had “possibly been exposed to the contamination” and had been ushered to the corner of Alder and Terry some 150 feet away, waiting to be screened for contamination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, the HAZMAT team is not getting many answers from the safety officer: Which material exactly, leaked? Was it granular? A powder? “We attempted to question” the UW Radiation Safety Officer to develop an action plan, but “were not provided pertinent information,” the draft report states.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We had no official prior knowledge of the decommissioning of the irradiator and therefore were not aware of the site action plan or any pre-planned emergency actions,” it reads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only later did the team find out it was cesium-137 “in talcum powder form,” which is highly dispersible in the air. And it was only when they asked whether the HVAC system for the building had been secured that the UW safety officer called someone, the report notes. Within minutes, it is shut down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With information streaming in slowly, the HAZMAT Team posts up on the north side of the building because of a south wind and come up with their action plan on the fly, calling in help from a decontamination team, battalion chief and three fire engines, plus a medical services officer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That night, over 30 people from the fire department are called to the scene. They also notify the FBI, the Washington National Guard’s 10th Civil Support Team, Radiological Assistance Program Region 8, the Environmental Protection Agency and Seattle Public Utilities. The &lt;strong&gt;Federal Emergency Management Agency&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Department of Homeland Security&lt;/strong&gt; are also notified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though the information about what is happening is incomplete and still coming in, the HAZMAT team — decked out in protective suits — takes the situation seriously. They judge the contamination potential “significant” based on the type of radioactive material, radiation counts, and “the lack of PPE [Personal Protective Equipment] worn by everyone exposed.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kate Lynch&lt;/strong&gt; of the Department of Health said it wasn’t unusual that the team in charge of the decommissioning were not wearing higher-level Personal Protective Equipment because usually, “it’s a pretty simple process.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At least, the Fire Department notes, no one seemed to be in urgent medical need. The patients were wiped with dry and wet hand wipes to get the “contaminant” off, and once they were cleared, “wrapped in temporary clothing” and moved to Harborview in ambulances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In total, 10 people, the International Isotope contractors, the FBI agent and two UW employees were sent to the hospital and placed in a contained area of the Harborview Medical Center Emergency Room, though in the end, only the seven contractors submitted blood and urine samples, with the highest exposures hovering near 55 millirems of radiation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those doses, Winfrey explained, were in the order of about 1 mammogram, around 10 to 12 flights across the country, or about a quarter of a CT scan. “That’s not much at all,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the people exposed at the hospital, decontamination could begin. Outdoor louvers and doors to the loading dock were covered with heavy plastic. A team from The Department of Energy surveyed the building floors, while International Isotopes employees inspected the parking lot area, marking spots with radiation levels with white paint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At 5:51 AM, everything was somewhat under control again. By 10 AM, all of the ”patients’ had been evaluated and released from the emergency department.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.capitolhillseattle.com/2019/06/on-the-list-before-stonewall-film-ginsberg-poetry-festival-at-volunteer-park-seattle-poetry-slam/tsjernobyl-11/&quot; rel=&quot;attachment wp-att-2067247681&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;2067247681&quot; data-permalink=&quot;http://www.capitolhillseattle.com/2019/06/on-the-list-before-stonewall-film-ginsberg-poetry-festival-at-volunteer-park-seattle-poetry-slam/tsjernobyl-11/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/www.capitolhillseattle.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Tsjernobyl-11.jpg?fit=3024%2C4032&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;3024,4032&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1.8&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Margo Vansynghel&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;iPhone 8&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1560346876&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Margo Vansynghel&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;3.99&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;25&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.00025&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Leak 3&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/www.capitolhillseattle.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Tsjernobyl-11.jpg?fit=400%2C533&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/www.capitolhillseattle.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Tsjernobyl-11.jpg?fit=584%2C779&quot; class=&quot;alignright size-medium wp-image-2067247681&quot; src=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/www.capitolhillseattle.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Tsjernobyl-11.jpg?resize=400%2C533&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;533&quot; srcset=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/www.capitolhillseattle.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Tsjernobyl-11.jpg?resize=400%2C533 400w, https://i0.wp.com/www.capitolhillseattle.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Tsjernobyl-11.jpg?resize=150%2C200 150w, https://i0.wp.com/www.capitolhillseattle.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Tsjernobyl-11.jpg?resize=600%2C800 600w, https://i0.wp.com/www.capitolhillseattle.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Tsjernobyl-11.jpg?resize=225%2C300 225w, https://i0.wp.com/www.capitolhillseattle.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Tsjernobyl-11.jpg?w=1168 1168w, https://i0.wp.com/www.capitolhillseattle.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Tsjernobyl-11.jpg?w=1752 1752w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 400px) 100vw, 400px&quot; data-recalc-dims=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things were far from being back to normal, however. That the HVAC system was shut off to prohibit the cesium from spreading through the building was a good thing. But as it stayed off, in the days after the leak, the building started to heat up. Which meant the freezers in the building, which keep research specimen at -80°C, had to work harder to stay cool. Some were failing. Important research samples were in danger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Hundreds of thousands of dollars worth of equipment, labor, and samples are being lost on a daily basis. This could destroy the careers of people who have been working their entire lives on research meant to save lives and improve public health and hospital outcomes,” &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kiro7.com/news/local/critical-medical-research-inside-uw-facility-at-risk-of-being-lost/948947969&quot;&gt;an anonymous source told KIRO.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UW/Harborview personnel moved the contents of some units to other freezers nearby about a week after the spill, said &lt;strong&gt;Susan Gregg&lt;/strong&gt; of the UW Medicine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“If they were showing signs of failure, the materials were moved to other freezers,” Gregg said. “We were very diligent that none of those research specimens were damaged.” No specimens were found to have any contamination, she added. The animals, mostly rodents, held in the building’s vivarium, have all been moved to another location as well. It took about two weeks for the HVAC system to be turned back on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just this Tuesday, teams went into the building to remove bio-waste, infectious disease materials left over from experiments, and materials from incubators where things were growing since the event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most R&amp;amp;T Building employees have resumed work, said UW. Some researchers, wearing booties and gloves and escorted by someone from the clean-up crew, were able to go into the building to retrieve some samples to continue their work in other UW labs across the city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ana Mari Cauce&lt;/strong&gt;, President of the University of Washington, declared the situation an “emergency of an extraordinarily severe and extended nature,” said Gregg, who called such a declaration “pretty unprecedented.” Cauce “authorized University leaders with authority over the impacted worksite to take necessary measures, including release with pay in appropriate situations.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UW also said it was too early to “speculate to the potential costs incurred.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tina Mankowski&lt;/strong&gt; of UW Medicine said that up to now, no-one had asked for a compensation of any kind and that the UW’s HR department is in touch with the union representative of the seven janitors (also UW employees) working in another part of the building that night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UW said a notification went out to all employees of the building ahead of the planned decommissioning event on May 2nd, including the supervisors of the janitors. Asked if the janitors were supposed to be in the building that evening, Mankowski said, “I believe so.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, the decontamination — meaning measuring radiation levels with handheld detectors as well as vacuuming, sweeping and wiping up of the residual materials — continues, while both the irradiator and radioactive material remain in the building in a shielding cask.&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.capitolhillseattle.com/2019/06/on-the-list-before-stonewall-film-ginsberg-poetry-festival-at-volunteer-park-seattle-poetry-slam/tsjernobyl-6/&quot; rel=&quot;attachment wp-att-2067247676&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;2067247676&quot; data-permalink=&quot;http://www.capitolhillseattle.com/2019/06/on-the-list-before-stonewall-film-ginsberg-poetry-festival-at-volunteer-park-seattle-poetry-slam/tsjernobyl-6/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://i1.wp.com/www.capitolhillseattle.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Tsjernobyl-6.jpg?fit=3024%2C4032&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;3024,4032&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1.8&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Margo Vansynghel&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;iPhone 8&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1560346656&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Margo Vansynghel&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;3.99&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;20&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.000666666666667&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Leak 4&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://i1.wp.com/www.capitolhillseattle.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Tsjernobyl-6.jpg?fit=400%2C533&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://i1.wp.com/www.capitolhillseattle.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Tsjernobyl-6.jpg?fit=584%2C779&quot; class=&quot;alignright size-medium wp-image-2067247676&quot; src=&quot;https://i1.wp.com/www.capitolhillseattle.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Tsjernobyl-6.jpg?resize=400%2C533&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;533&quot; srcset=&quot;https://i1.wp.com/www.capitolhillseattle.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Tsjernobyl-6.jpg?resize=400%2C533 400w, https://i1.wp.com/www.capitolhillseattle.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Tsjernobyl-6.jpg?resize=150%2C200 150w, https://i1.wp.com/www.capitolhillseattle.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Tsjernobyl-6.jpg?resize=600%2C800 600w, https://i1.wp.com/www.capitolhillseattle.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Tsjernobyl-6.jpg?resize=225%2C300 225w, https://i1.wp.com/www.capitolhillseattle.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Tsjernobyl-6.jpg?w=1168 1168w, https://i1.wp.com/www.capitolhillseattle.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Tsjernobyl-6.jpg?w=1752 1752w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 400px) 100vw, 400px&quot; data-recalc-dims=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Questions remain as well. What precisely went wrong during the cutting process? What happened in the hour between the breach and the call to the fire department? And, as the responding fire department crew notes in the draft report: Why was the fire department not informed of the operation or pre-planned emergency plan? The Seattle Fire Code does not require it for this particular situation, said a Public Information Officer from Seattle Fire. And why did they not put up a barrier on the doors and vents beforehand?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We don’t know the reason [for] the process that they used,” said &lt;strong&gt;Kate Lynch&lt;/strong&gt; of the DOH. “That’s something that is being investigated. They’re [DOE] going to move it [the irradiator and source] to one of the national labs. They are going to recreate what happened in a controlled environment.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only then, the capsule and irradiator will be moved to their original destination by the Department of Energy contractors who are busy cleaning the building as we speak. About four dozen people from the Department of Energy have traveled to Seattle to oversee the investigation and clean-up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only when the Department of Health gives the green light, the building will reopen. That will take months, probably until after Labor Day said a UW spokesperson. “And we don’t even know how long after Labor Day.”&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2019 06:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>curtis</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>An ‘extraordinarily severe’ emergency: the radioactive leak at Harborview</og:title>
<og:url>http://www.capitolhillseattle.com/2019/06/an-extraordinarily-severe-emergency-the-radioactive-leak-at-harborview/</og:url>
<og:description>A small platform crane hoists two men up near the roof gutter of a flat, one-floor building on the Harborview campus on First Hill. Slowly, one of the men moves a thick, round bar roughly six inche…</og:description>
<og:image>http://www.capitolhillseattle.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Tsjernobyl-6-400x533.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.capitolhillseattle.com/2019/06/an-extraordinarily-severe-emergency-the-radioactive-leak-at-harborview/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>NSA Starts Contributing Low-Level Code to UEFI BIOS Alternative</title>
<link>https://www.tomshardware.com/news/nsa-contributes-low-level-stm-coreboot,39704.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.tomshardware.com/news/nsa-contributes-low-level-stm-coreboot,39704.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;imgContent imgCenter&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;imgWrapperOutter&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;imgWrapperInner&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;iZoom&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;https://img.purch.com/stm-intel/w/755/aHR0cDovL21lZGlhLmJlc3RvZm1pY3JvLmNvbS9JLzYvODQzMDU0L29yaWdpbmFsL1NUTTA0LkpQRw==&quot; big-src=&quot;https://img.purch.com/stm-intel/o/aHR0cDovL21lZGlhLmJlc3RvZm1pY3JvLmNvbS9JLzYvODQzMDU0L29yaWdpbmFsL1NUTTA0LkpQRw==&quot; alt=&quot;Credit: Intel&quot; title=&quot;Credit: Intel&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;imgCaption&quot;&gt;Credit: Intel&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;The NSA has started assigning developers to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://coreboot.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Coreboot project&lt;/a&gt;, which is an open source alternative to Windows BIOS/UEFI firmware. The NSA's Eugene Myers &lt;a href=&quot;https://review.coreboot.org/c/coreboot/+/33234&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;has begun contributing&lt;/a&gt; SMI Transfer Monitor (STM) implementation code for the x86 processor. Myers works for NSA’s Trusted Systems Research Group, which according to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nsa.gov/What-We-Do/Research/IA-Research/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;agency’s website&lt;/a&gt;, is meant to “conduct and sponsor research in the technologies and techniques which will secure America's information systems of tomorrow.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Can The NSA Be Trusted With Such Low-Level Code?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NSA has worked on security projects embraced by the public before, including Security-Enhanced Linux, a security module for Linux. More recently, the NSA released the Ghidra reverse engineering tool as open source, which has also been &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=Ghidra-Coreboot-NSA-RE&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;adopted by Coreboot developers&lt;/a&gt; so that they can more easily reverse-engineer hardware firmware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Myers &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.platformsecuritysummit.com/2018/speaker/myers/STMPE2Intelv84a.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;published a paper about STM&lt;/a&gt; last year on how NSA’s STM implementation could work. All Coreboot code, including all the STM contributions from the NSA, are open source, so anyone could verify that there is no backdoor in there -- in theory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In practice, the NSA could have also written the code in a less-than-secure way with vulnerabilities that are hard to detect without more experienced security researchers. Alternatively, the NSA could also  update this implementation years later, when there are less eyes on the STM implementation and the update would no longer make headlines. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This wouldn’t be completely out of the question for an agency like the NSA. After all, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.cryptographyengineering.com/2015/01/14/hopefully-last-post-ill-ever-write-on/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;NSA succeeded in pushing a backdoor&lt;/a&gt; through the NIST standardization process years ago. The agency was also accused by EFF co-founder John Gilmore of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mail-archive.com/cryptography@metzdowd.com/msg12325.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;sabotaging the IPsec protocol&lt;/a&gt; by making it too complex to ever be secure (something that would benefit an espionage agency).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More recently, it also tried to push two encryption algorithms through the ISO standardization process, but the reviewers overwhelmingly &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wikitribune.com/wt/news/article/67004/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;rejected the algorithms&lt;/a&gt; based on trust concerns and NSA’s failure to answer some technical questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;NSA Low-Level Code In Coreboot&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intel released the &lt;a href=&quot;https://firmware.intel.com/content/smi-transfer-monitor-stm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;STM specification&lt;/a&gt; and documentation of the SMT firmware security feature in 2015, six years after the discovery of bypasses against the company’s Trusted Execution Technology, which can be used to ensure that an operating system starts in a trusted environment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The STM is a hypervisor that launches inside the System Management Mode, which is a “ring -2” isolated environment that offers protected execution against tampering of low-level services, such as power management, security functions, calls to the Trusted Platform Module and so on. STM was initially supposed to work with an Intel TXT launch, but the latest specification allows the STM to work with Intel Virtualization Technology (VT) only. The TXT was not enough to protect these services against attacks, and STM is meant to do that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;imgContent imgCenter&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;imgWrapperOutter&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;imgWrapperInner&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;iZoom&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;https://img.purch.com/stm-overview/w/755/aHR0cDovL21lZGlhLmJlc3RvZm1pY3JvLmNvbS9JLzUvODQzMDUzL29yaWdpbmFsL3N0bS1vdmVydmlldy5qcGc=&quot; big-src=&quot;https://img.purch.com/stm-overview/o/aHR0cDovL21lZGlhLmJlc3RvZm1pY3JvLmNvbS9JLzUvODQzMDUzL29yaWdpbmFsL3N0bS1vdmVydmlldy5qcGc=&quot; alt=&quot;Credit: Intel&quot; title=&quot;Credit: Intel&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;imgCaption&quot;&gt;Credit: Intel&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2019 01:43:23 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ItsTotallyOn</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.tomshardware.com/news/nsa-contributes-low-level-stm-coreboot,39704.html</og:url>
<og:title>NSA Starts Contributing Low-Level Code to UEFI BIOS Alternative</og:title>
<og:description>NSA's Eugene Myers has started contributing low-level implementation code for a SMI Transfer Monitor for the Coreboot projected, raising potential security and privacy issues.</og:description>
<og:image>https://img.purch.com/o/aHR0cDovL21lZGlhLmJlc3RvZm1pY3JvLmNvbS9JLzYvODQzMDU0L29yaWdpbmFsL1NUTTA0LkpQRw==</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.tomshardware.com/news/nsa-contributes-low-level-stm-coreboot,39704.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>We tried to publish a replication of a Science paper in Science</title>
<link>https://slate.com/technology/2019/06/science-replication-conservatives-liberals-reacting-to-threats.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://slate.com/technology/2019/06/science-replication-conservatives-liberals-reacting-to-threats.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;lazy-container&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;image__src&quot; data-normal=&quot;https://compote.slate.com/images/7f7e3775-2aa7-46a4-ad4f-ffcc1c25d1c3.jpeg?width=780&amp;amp;height=520&amp;amp;rect=2198x1465&amp;amp;offset=2x0&quot; alt=&quot;An issue of Science magazine.&quot;/&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://compote.slate.com/images/7f7e3775-2aa7-46a4-ad4f-ffcc1c25d1c3.jpeg?width=780&amp;amp;height=520&amp;amp;rect=2198x1465&amp;amp;offset=2x0&quot; alt=&quot;An issue of Science magazine.&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An issue of Science magazine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photo illustration by Slate. Image by Science magazine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;in-article-recirc&quot; data-via=&quot;article-inline_recirc-rubric-science&quot;&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;in-article-recirc__list&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;in-article-recirc__item&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://slate.com/technology/2019/06/boaty-mcboatface-british-research-vessel-science-news.html&quot; class=&quot;in-article-recirc__link&quot;&gt;Boaty McBoatface, the British Research Vessel, Just Broke Some Significant Science News&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;in-article-recirc__item&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://slate.com/technology/2019/06/climate-change-disinformation-court-cases-michael-mann.html&quot; class=&quot;in-article-recirc__link&quot;&gt;One Place Climate Scientists Are Beating Deniers? Courts.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;in-article-recirc__item&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://slate.com/technology/2019/06/chernobyl-television-inaccuracies-explain-nuclear-power-as-narrative.html&quot; class=&quot;in-article-recirc__link&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chernobyl&lt;/em&gt;’s Inaccuracies Underscore How Easily Nuclear Catastrophe Lends Itself to Narrative&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;in-article-recirc__item&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://slate.com/technology/2019/06/bees-nest-plastic-adaptability.html&quot; class=&quot;in-article-recirc__link&quot;&gt;Bees Built a Nest Entirely Out of Plastic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;slate-paragraph&quot; data-editable=&quot;text&quot; data-uri=&quot;slate.com/_components/slate-paragraph/instances/cjx54gvpe000o62m3tnc55pse@published&quot; data-word-count=&quot;33&quot;&gt;Science is supposed to be self-correcting. Ugly facts kill beautiful theories, to paraphrase the 19&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt;-century biologist Thomas Huxley. But, as we learned recently, policies at the top scientific journals don’t make this easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;slate-paragraph&quot; data-editable=&quot;text&quot; data-uri=&quot;slate.com/_components/slate-paragraph/instances/cjx558fil000j3h5wioc2zkef@published&quot; data-word-count=&quot;62&quot;&gt;Our story starts in 2008, when a group of researchers published an &lt;a href=&quot;https://science.sciencemag.org/content/321/5896/1667&quot;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://digitalcommons.unl.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=1026&amp;amp;context=poliscifacpub&quot;&gt;here it is without a paywall&lt;/a&gt;) that found political conservatives have stronger physiological reactions to threatening images than liberals do. The article was published in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencemag.org/&quot;&gt;Science&lt;/a&gt;, which is one of the most prestigious general science journals around. It’s the kind of journal that can make a career in academia.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p class=&quot;slate-paragraph&quot; data-editable=&quot;text&quot; data-uri=&quot;slate.com/_components/slate-paragraph/instances/cjx558flz000s3h5wbugc6nny@published&quot; data-word-count=&quot;117&quot;&gt;It was a path-breaking and provocative study. For decades, political scientists and psychologists have tried to understand the psychological roots of ideological differences. The piece published in Science offered some clues as to &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; liberals and conservatives differ in their worldviews. Perhaps it has to do with how the brain is wired, the researchers suggested—specifically, perhaps it’s because conservatives’ brains are more attuned to threats than liberals’. It was an exciting finding, it helped usher in a new wave of psychophysiological work in the study of politics, and it generated extensive coverage in popular media. In 2018, 10 years after the publication of the study, the findings were featured on an episode of NPR’s &lt;em&gt;Hidden Brain&lt;/em&gt; podcast.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p class=&quot;slate-paragraph&quot; data-editable=&quot;text&quot; data-uri=&quot;slate.com/_components/slate-paragraph/instances/cjx558fjp000l3h5wefuz8fda@published&quot; data-word-count=&quot;71&quot;&gt;Fast forward to 2014. All four of us were studying the physiological basis of political attitudes, two of us in Amsterdam, the Netherlands (Bakker and Schumacher at the University of Amsterdam), and two of us in Philadelphia (Arceneaux and Gothreau at Temple University). We had raised funds to create labs with expensive equipment for measuring physiological reactions, because we were excited by the possibilities that the 2008 research opened for us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;slate-paragraph&quot; data-editable=&quot;text&quot; data-uri=&quot;slate.com/_components/slate-paragraph/instances/cjx558fjn000k3h5wzghxyz5m@published&quot; data-word-count=&quot;114&quot;&gt;The researchers behind the Science article had shown a series of images to 46 participants in Nebraska and used equipment to record how much the participants’ palms sweated in response. The images included scary stuff, like a spider on a person’s face. We conducted two “conceptual” replications (one in the Netherlands and one in the U.S.) that used different images to get at the same idea of a “threat”—for example, a gun pointing at the screen. Our intention in these first studies was to try the same thing in order to calibrate our new equipment. But both teams independently failed to find that people’s physiological reactions to these images correlated with their political attitudes.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pull-quote__text&quot; data-editable=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;We believe that it is bad policy for journals like Science to publish big, bold ideas and then leave it to subfield journals to publish replications showing that those ideas aren’t so accurate after&lt;span class=&quot;widont&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;all.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;slate-paragraph&quot; data-editable=&quot;text&quot; data-uri=&quot;slate.com/_components/slate-paragraph/instances/cjx558fm0000t3h5wxgppzcmc@published&quot; data-word-count=&quot;121&quot;&gt;Our first thought was that we were doing something wrong. So, we asked the original researchers for their images, which they generously provided to us, and we added a few more. We took the step of “pre-registering” a more direct replication of the Science study, meaning that we detailed exactly what we were going to do before we did it and made that public. The direct replication took place in Philadelphia, where we recruited 202 participants (more than four times than the original sample size of 46 used in the Science study). Again, we found no correlation between physiological reactions to threatening images (the original ones or the ones we added) and political conservatism—no matter how we looked at the data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;slate-paragraph&quot; data-editable=&quot;text&quot; data-uri=&quot;slate.com/_components/slate-paragraph/instances/cjx558flj000n3h5wf0igksem@published&quot; data-word-count=&quot;107&quot;&gt;By this point, we had become more skeptical of the rationale animating the original study. Neuroscientists can often find a loose match between physiological responses and self-reported attitudes. The question is whether this relationship is really as meaningful as we sometimes think it is. The brain is a complex organ with parallel conscious and unconscious systems that don’t always affect the other one-to-one. We still believe that there is value in exploring how physiological reactions and conscious experience shape political attitudes and behavior, but after further consideration, we have concluded that any such relationships are more complicated than we (and the researchers on the Science paper) presumed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;slate-paragraph&quot; data-editable=&quot;text&quot; data-uri=&quot;slate.com/_components/slate-paragraph/instances/cjx558fli000m3h5wk2c0lo2x@published&quot; data-word-count=&quot;69&quot;&gt;We drafted a &lt;a href=&quot;https://osf.io/7yt8u/&quot;&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt; that reported the failed replication studies along with a more nuanced discussion about the ways in which physiology might matter for politics and sent it to Science. We did not expect Science to immediately publish the paper, but because our findings cast doubt on an influential study published in its pages, we thought the editorial team would at least send it out for peer review.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;slate-paragraph&quot; data-editable=&quot;text&quot; data-uri=&quot;slate.com/_components/slate-paragraph/instances/cjx558flz000r3h5wrn9q2hw0@published&quot; data-word-count=&quot;65&quot;&gt;It did not. About a week later, we received a summary rejection with the explanation that the Science advisory board of academics and editorial team felt that since the publication of this article the field has moved on and that, while they concluded that we had offered a conclusive replication of the original study, it would be better suited for a less visible subfield journal.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p class=&quot;slate-paragraph&quot; data-editable=&quot;text&quot; data-uri=&quot;slate.com/_components/slate-paragraph/instances/cjx558flw000o3h5wkeqs2znj@published&quot; data-word-count=&quot;138&quot;&gt;We wrote back asking them to consider at least sending our work out for review. (They could still reject it if the reviewers found fatal flaws in our replications.) We argued that the original article continues to be highly influential and is often featured in popular science pieces in the lay media (for instance, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/2018/10/03/654127241/nature-nurture-and-your-politics?t=1560770467306&amp;amp;t=1561027892440&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.com/news/av/magazine-16770593/fear-factor-the-science-behind-america-s-red-blue-divide&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://lightyears.blogs.cnn.com/2012/04/07/politics-may-be-partly-genetic-now-what/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BAc8MKTjC5E&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;), where the research is translated into a claim that physiology allows one to predict liberals and conservatives with a high degree of accuracy. We believe that Science has a responsibility to set the record straight in the same way that a newspaper does when it publishes something that doesn’t stand up to scrutiny. We were rebuffed without a reason and with a vague suggestion that the journal’s policy on handling replications might change at some point in the future.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;slate-paragraph&quot; data-editable=&quot;text&quot; data-uri=&quot;slate.com/_components/slate-paragraph/instances/cjx558flx000p3h5weh2tkt84@published&quot; data-word-count=&quot;75&quot;&gt;We believe that it is bad policy for journals like Science to publish big, bold ideas and then leave it to subfield journals to publish replications showing that those ideas aren’t so accurate after all. Subfield journals are less visible, meaning the message often fails to reach the broader public. They are also less authoritative, meaning the failed replication will have less of an impact on the field if it is not published by Science.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;slate-paragraph&quot; data-editable=&quot;text&quot; data-uri=&quot;slate.com/_components/slate-paragraph/instances/cjx558fly000q3h5wc4av9lgx@published&quot; data-word-count=&quot;76&quot;&gt;Open and transparent science can only happen when journals are willing to publish results that contradict previous findings. We must resist the human tendency to see a failed replication as an indication that the original research team did something wrong or bad. We should continue to have frank discussions about what we’ve learned over the course of the replication crisis and what we could be doing about it (a conversation that is currently happening on Twitter).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;slate-paragraph slate-paragraph--tombstone&quot; data-editable=&quot;text&quot; data-uri=&quot;slate.com/_components/slate-paragraph/instances/cjx558fm5000u3h5wd0c44yzi@published&quot; data-word-count=&quot;112&quot;&gt;Science requires us to have the courage to let our beautiful theories die public deaths at the hands of ugly facts. Indeed, our replication also failed to replicate part of a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cambridge.org/core/journals/american-political-science-review/article/behavioral-immune-system-shapes-political-intuitions-why-and-how-individual-differences-in-disgust-sensitivity-underlie-opposition-to-immigration/AB22952FCB7F270E0D296378D2E330C7&quot;&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; published by one of us—&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencespo.fr/cevipof/sites/sciencespo.fr.cevipof/files/Aaroe%202017%20The%20behavioral%20immune%20system%20shapes%20political%20intuitions-1.pdf&quot;&gt;Arceneaux and colleagues&lt;/a&gt;—which found that physiological reactions to disgusting images correlated with immigration attitudes. Our takeaway is not that the original study’s researchers did anything wrong. To the contrary, members of the original author team—Kevin Smith, John Hibbing, John Alford and Matthew Hibbing—were very supportive of the entire process, a reflection of the understanding that science requires us to go where the facts lead us. If only journals like Science were willing to lead the way.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 22:26:45 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>hhs</dc:creator>
<og:title>We Tried to Publish a Replication of a Science Paper in Science. The Journal Refused.</og:title>
<og:url>https://slate.com/technology/2019/06/science-replication-conservatives-liberals-reacting-to-threats.html</og:url>
<og:description>Our research suggests that the theory that conservatives and liberals respond differently to threats isn’t actually true.</og:description>
<og:image>https://compote.slate.com/images/7f7e3775-2aa7-46a4-ad4f-ffcc1c25d1c3.jpeg?width=780&amp;height=520&amp;rect=2198x1465&amp;offset=2x0</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://slate.com/technology/2019/06/science-replication-conservatives-liberals-reacting-to-threats.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Get an Acme Klein Bottle</title>
<link>https://www.kleinbottle.com/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.kleinbottle.com/</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;verify-v1&quot; content=&quot;0UBm3rIvzcQNWW8CdnGKtz6JZRwH2Oc4auS30V07Qng=&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;description&quot; content=&quot;Acme Klein Bottle makes and sells glass Klein Bottles. Come visit!&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;AUTHOR&quot; content=&quot;CliffStoll&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;COPYRIGHT&quot; content=&quot;© 2008 Cliff Stoll&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;keywords&quot; content=&quot;klein bottles, klein bottle, klien bottles, kleinbottle, Cliff Stoll, Danny Stoll, kleinbottles, klien bottle, kline bottles, kline bottle, kleins bottle, kleins bottles, cline bottle, clinebottle, cline bottles, klein botle, bottle, bottles, glass bottle, glass bottles, topology, manifold, mobius loop, moebius loop, one sided, kleinbottle.com, math, mathematics, mathematical, math gift, mathematical gift, mathematical gifts, gift for mathematician, hats, dragon bowl, spouting bowl, klein bottle hat, topological, wool hat, kleinsche flasche, nonorientable, zero volume&quot;/&gt;&lt;title&gt;Acme Klein Bottle&lt;/title&gt;&lt;meta charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta http-equiv=&quot;PICS-Label&quot; content=&quot;(PICS-1.1 &amp;quot;http://www.rsac.org/ratingsv01.html&amp;quot; l gen true comment &amp;quot;RSACi North America Server&amp;quot; for &amp;quot;http://www.kleinbottle.com&amp;quot; on &amp;quot;2000.09.25T01:29-0800&amp;quot; r (n 0 s 0 v 0 l 0))&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;keywords&quot; content=&quot;klein bottle, topology&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;description&quot; content=&quot;Glass Klein Bottles&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta http-equiv=&quot;Expires&quot; content=&quot;10&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;google-translate-customization&quot; content=&quot;568d49b78464899f-183711809adb1c32-g3a7744b8de2e7056-13&quot;/&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body bgcolor=&quot;#FFFFFF&quot; id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot; readability=&quot;189.50005436555&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Glass Klein Bottles for sale - inquire within&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;1&quot; readability=&quot;1.5&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;&lt;td width=&quot;461&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Need a zero-volume bottle?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Searching for a one-sided surface?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Want the ultimate in non-orientability?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Get an &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;ACME&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; KLEIN BOTTLE!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td width=&quot;270&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kleinbottle.com/bigclassicalklein.htm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.kleinbottle.com/images/Klein%20Bottle.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Klein Bottle&quot; name=&quot;Klein Bottle&quot; width=&quot;270&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;bottom&quot;/&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;.&lt;span&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.kleinbottle.com/images/7-Klein-BottlesA.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Seven Klein Bottles in a Row!&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;208&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;bottom&quot; usemap=&quot;#babyclassic&quot;/&gt;&lt;map name=&quot;babyclassic&quot; id=&quot;babyclassic&quot;&gt;&lt;area shape=&quot;poly&quot; coords=&quot;125,179,144,71,107,42,37,46,9,69,2,193,117,203&quot; href=&quot;drinking_mug_klein_bottle.htm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; alt=&quot;Klein Stein&quot;/&gt;&lt;area shape=&quot;poly&quot; coords=&quot;199,47,253,115,258,177,217,199,131,199,156,46&quot; href=&quot;top_mouth_erlen_klein.htm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; alt=&quot;Top Mouth Erlenmeyer Klein Bottle&quot;/&gt;&lt;area shape=&quot;poly&quot; coords=&quot;242,70,257,112,262,158,278,192,339,193,352,143,343,56,303,33&quot; href=&quot;question_mark_klein_bottle.htm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; alt=&quot;Question Mark Klein Bottle&quot;/&gt;&lt;area shape=&quot;poly&quot; coords=&quot;353,181,398,197,448,177,436,110,479,38,438,4,390,21&quot; href=&quot;erlenklein.htm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; alt=&quot;Erlenmeyer Klein Bottle&quot;/&gt;&lt;area shape=&quot;poly&quot; coords=&quot;448,149,459,194,540,198,547,126,565,40,494,43&quot; href=&quot;bigclassicalklein.htm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; alt=&quot;Big Classical Klein Bottle&quot;/&gt;&lt;area shape=&quot;poly&quot; coords=&quot;547,198,617,202,617,142,637,86,607,61,576,74,553,122&quot; href=&quot;half_pint_klein.htm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; alt=&quot;Medium Classical Klein Bottle&quot;/&gt;&lt;area shape=&quot;poly&quot; coords=&quot;623,197,679,197,694,110,671,85,648,93,620,171&quot; href=&quot;baby_klein.htm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; alt=&quot;Baby Klein Bottle&quot;/&gt;&lt;/map&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;At last, Acme has conquered topological and engineering frontiers to manufacture genuine glass Klein Bottles. These are the finest closed, non-orientable, boundary-free manifolds sold anywhere in our three spatial dimensions.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;These elegant bottles make splendid gifts, outstanding classroom displays, and inferior mouse-traps. With its circle of singularities, an Acme Klein Bottle can be said to exist inside of itself -- especially handy during time-reversals.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A mathematician's delight, handcrafted in glass&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;... from your &lt;strong&gt;Zero Volume&lt;/strong&gt; Klein Bottle distributor&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://kleinbottle.foxycart.com/cart?cart=checkout&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;gt; &amp;gt; &amp;gt; Shopping Cart Checkout&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;Special -- I will write a custom message on your glass Klein bottle using a Sharpie pen (or, if you wish, sign my name on it). No charge for this -- just mention it at checkout.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;At last - I've made the Acme &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kleinbottle.com/wine_bottle_klein_bottle.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Wine Bottle Klein Bottle&lt;/a&gt; - it's now in stock!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;Self-siphoning &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kleinbottle.com/Tantalus.html&quot;&gt;Cup of Tantalus&lt;/a&gt; and a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kleinbottle.com/Tantalus.html#PyramidTeapot&quot;&gt;Topless Teapot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kleinbottle.com/PolyhedronPoster.html&quot; title=&quot;Poster of Polyhedrons&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Polyhedron Posters! Plenty of Polyhedra&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NEW -- IMPROVED! &lt;u&gt;EVERY&lt;/u&gt; ACME KLEIN BOTTLE NOW COMES PRE-EQUIPPED WITH A &lt;u&gt;GENUINE&lt;/u&gt; RIEMANNIAN METRIC! GUARANTEED!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;*CERTIFIED BY A REAL UNDERGRADUATE MATH MAJOR*  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;An Acme Klein Bottle is a perfect gift for a mathematician, computer scientist, or troglodyte. In Germany, it's called a Kleinsche Flasche. A Klein Bottle makes a great math gift and an ideal present for a mathematician!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kleinbottle.com/Origami%20Klein%20Bottle.htm&quot;&gt;Origami Klein Bottles? Yep!&lt;/a&gt; Also, check out my &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kleinbottle.com/sliced_klein_bottles.htm#Slicing_Machine&quot;&gt;Klein Bottle Slicing Machine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We made the&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kleinbottle.com/meter_tall_klein_bottle.html&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;world's largest glass Klein Bottle for the Kingbridge Centre&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kleinbottle.com/meter_tall_klein_bottle.html&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.kleinbottle.com/images/giantKleinbotandCliff2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cliff Stoll with giant Klein Bottle&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;535&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; align=&quot;bottom&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer to my most commonly asked questions:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;1) Yes, I am Cliff Stoll, and I make and sell Klein Bottles.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;2) Yes, I regularly send these to countries around the world.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;2a) Corrolary to FAQ#2: Please do not send email, asking if I ship to Spain, Portugal, Italy, or Poland. The answer is YES. Typical postal transit times are 10 to 15 days (over which I have no control)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;3) Yes, you can safely order from this website, and I will send your Klein bottle within 24 hours.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;4) Yes, I pack each one very securely to survive the post; I guarantee safe, speedy delivery.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;5) If you are unhappy with your Klein bottle, I will refund your money.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;6) If this is a gift, I'll print &quot;Happy Birthday&quot; (or whatever you want) on the packing slip or the outside of the package. If you wish, I'll write your message on the bottle with a Sharpie pen.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;7) No, I no longer do the hot glass work - I contract this out to professional glassblowing shops. I do everything else myself - from design to packing to writing the html on this website, with occasional help from my son Danny, my daughter Zoe, and my wife Pat.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;8) Yes, you are welcome to visit if you are traveling to Northern California (San Francisco/Oakland/Berkeley) Call first - 510 654 3958&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;9) No, I cannot engrave these glass Klein bottles. The borosilicate glass laughs at laser beams and the compound curves defy X-Y tables..&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;10) Yes, there are many math jokes on this website, but despite that, I really do sell Klein bottles&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;11) Yes, my son Danny and I designed each of these bottles ourselves. Our designs are copyright © by Cliff Stoll&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;12) My website looks old-fashioned because it loads faster this way and (mainly) I'm too lazy to rewrite it. I last updated this page on April 30, 2019 6:16 PM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;13) Yes, that's me in the [ video / book / talk / college / bowling alley ]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;-Cliff Stoll in Oakland (two blocks from Berkeley, 10 km east of San Francisco, and epsilon away from a boundary)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ARE YOU A STUDENT, AGE 12 TO 17?&lt;/strong&gt; Do you like the kind of math humor that's on this website? Then consider one of the terrific summer math camps! Several that come to mind: the Hampshire Summer Studies in Math (in Amherst, Massachusetts during July &amp;amp; August... learn why the Yellow Pig endorses 17 varieties of Acme Klein bottles -- &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hcssim.org&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;hcssim.org&lt;/a&gt;). Also, the MathILy program at Bryn Mawr (five weeks of maximum mathematical marvelousness) (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mathily.org&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;www.mathily.org&lt;/a&gt;). I've also heard great things about &lt;a href=&quot;https://epsiloncamp.org&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Epsilon Camp&lt;/a&gt; in Utah (well, one of the Epsilon camp counselors visited, and she really impressed me!) There are dozens more camps-- see a list of these camps at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ams.org/programs/students/emp-mathcamps&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;www.ams.org/programs/students/emp-mathcamps&lt;/a&gt; ... feel free to ask me for opinions or comments about these various math camps. Also -- Math Circles are springing up around the world ... find out if there's one in your neighborhood: www.mathcircles.org/Wiki_ExistingMathCirclePrograms_view&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;COMMITTED TO TRANSPARENCY!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;span&gt;International and transgalactic organizations require transparency and openness-- Acme is proud to offer FULLY TRANSPARENT Klein Bottles that are OPEN and VISIBLE. We certify that &lt;strong&gt;NOTHING IS HIDDEN INSIDE YOUR ACME KLEIN BOTTLE!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;In response to almost two requests, I've uploaded my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kleinbottle.com/imperfecto&quot; title=&quot;Imperfecto Ruler&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;IMPERFECTO RULER&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kleinbottle.com/m%26ms_in_a_klein_bottle.htm&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Our &quot;M&amp;amp;M's in a Klein Bottle Contest&quot; is closed&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;When you order from this website, your should immediately receive an automated confirmation from my system. When I actually pack your Klein bottle, I will compose a non-automated email, with the return address of kleinbottle &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kleinbottle.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection&quot; class=&quot;__cf_email__&quot; data-cfemail=&quot;c9a8a8a8bdbda8bd89a8bdbdbd&quot;&gt;[email protected]&lt;/a&gt; kleinbottle ddoatatdot com. That second email will have a tracking number in it, as well as a link to photos of the package that I'm sending to you. If you don't see that second email within a day of ordering, please check your spam/junk mail folder. And if you still don't see that email from me, please send me a note and I'll figure out what's worng.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;My email troubles: I receive huge amouts of spam. I never send out any spam. If you write to me, I may not see your email unless you include the phrase &quot;klein bottle&quot; in the subject. My replies to your may end up in your spam folder, so please include my address in your list of Permitted Senders.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;HOW TO GET EMAIL TO CLIFF: Send me email - KLEINBOTTLE aa ttt KLEINBOTTLE (ddoott] COM Important: to get through layers of my spam filters, please include the two words &quot;Klein Bottle&quot; in the subject of your email and also in the body of your text. Please use plain text without html. Email with subjects like &quot;Hello Cliff&quot;or &quot;Do you ship to Nigeria?&quot;or &quot;Good Day&quot; or &quot;HI&quot;will be delayed until I look at my spam folder.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;HOW TO RECEIVE EMAIL FROM CLIFF: Iif you purchase anything from me, or write to me, please add kleinbottle aa ttt kleinbottle (ddooott) com to your Permitted Senders&lt;/span&gt;. This is especially important if you use gmail, hotmail, yahoo, or AOL. Much of my email to these mailboxes gets blocked as spam, which annoys me greatly, especially when I spend half an hour composing an email and it winds up in the gutter.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Acme Klein Bottles by Cliff Stoll,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;(and Pat, Zoey, &amp;amp; Danny Stoll) 6270 Colby St., Oakland, California, 94618 USA phone +1 510 654 3958 We are a family business, operating from our home. You're welcome to stop by for coffee &amp;amp; chat - please call ahead if you plan to visit.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;** * * UPCOMING TRAVEL: * * **&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;When I'm home, I send out Klein bottles as I receive orders - within 24 hours, and often within the hour. When I'm away, I send out all Klein bottles when I return. Here's my travel schedule:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;* * * no upcoming travel * * *&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Acme Klein Bottles&lt;/strong&gt; - where yesterday's future is here &lt;em&gt;today&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;Seeking a topological solution to the global financial crisis? Help the world economy by purchasing an Acme Klein Bottle!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;I&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;last updated this page on April 30, 2019&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Custom Topology Manifolds.              Industrial and post-industrial consulting. &lt;span&gt;        Free Range Kleinbots&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mathematical gifts ... a Perfect Gift for a Mathematician ... Klein's Bottle in Glass ...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;DESIGNS SO EXCLUSIVE THAT THEY ARE NOT TO BE FOUND EVEN IN FAMOUS MUSEUMS!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;Now with a LIFETIME GUARANTEE - we guarantee that you will live your entire life OR YOUR MONEY BACK!.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;This page, the entire website, and the bottle designs are Copyright © 1995 to 2019 by Cliff Stoll&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kleinbottle.com/index.htm&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;TOP OF PAGE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 22:07:52 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>YeGoblynQueenne</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.kleinbottle.com/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Swedish Couple Builds Greenhouse Around Home</title>
<link>https://returntonow.net/2019/03/04/swedish-couple-builds-greenhouse-around-home-to-stay-warm-and-grow-food-all-year-long/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://returntonow.net/2019/03/04/swedish-couple-builds-greenhouse-around-home-to-stay-warm-and-grow-food-all-year-long/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-mce-type=&quot;bookmark&quot; class=&quot;mce_SELRES_start&quot;&gt;﻿&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Greenhouse keeps home in the 60’s, even when it’s freezing outside; allows family to grow Mediterranean fruit in Sweden&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot; wp-image-7969 aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;https://returntonow.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/img-300x180.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;525&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; srcset=&quot;https://returntonow.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/img-300x180.jpg 300w, https://returntonow.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/img-768x461.jpg 768w, https://returntonow.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/img-1024x614.jpg 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 525px) 100vw, 525px&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-7948&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marie Granmar and Charles Sacilotto literally live in a bubble, insulated from the cold and the harshness of the elements, while taking in the best of what nature has to offer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their house is built inside of a greenhouse, providing them free heat and free food in the winter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot; wp-image-7964 aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;https://returntonow.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/53595373_395632874348663_8005023616095748096_n-300x169.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;505&quot; height=&quot;285&quot; srcset=&quot;https://returntonow.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/53595373_395632874348663_8005023616095748096_n-300x169.png 300w, https://returntonow.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/53595373_395632874348663_8005023616095748096_n-768x432.png 768w, https://returntonow.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/53595373_395632874348663_8005023616095748096_n-1024x576.png 1024w, https://returntonow.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/53595373_395632874348663_8005023616095748096_n.png 1334w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 505px) 100vw, 505px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Stockholm, Sweden, where winter lasts 9 months out of the year, that’s a huge asset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The average temperature in Stockholm in January is below freezing. But step into Marie and Charles’ bubbled-in “backyard,” and you’ll be much warmer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot; wp-image-7961 aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;https://returntonow.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/53046681_788011761582393_2143229762066186240_n-300x169.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;498&quot; height=&quot;280&quot; srcset=&quot;https://returntonow.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/53046681_788011761582393_2143229762066186240_n-300x169.png 300w, https://returntonow.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/53046681_788011761582393_2143229762066186240_n-768x432.png 768w, https://returntonow.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/53046681_788011761582393_2143229762066186240_n-1024x576.png 1024w, https://returntonow.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/53046681_788011761582393_2143229762066186240_n.png 1334w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 498px) 100vw, 498px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“For example at the end of January it can be 28°F outside and it can be 68°F upstairs,”  says in the video below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/30ghnDOFbNQ&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-mce-type=&quot;bookmark&quot; class=&quot;mce_SELRES_start&quot;&gt;﻿&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A normal family in Stockholm switches on their heater on sometime around mid-September, and doesn’t turn it off again until mid-May or so, Marie says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The greenhouse allows them to reduce the number of months they need to heat their home from 9 to 6 months per year, and reduces the amount of energy they use doing so. Any supplemental heat they need, that is not provided by the sun, is provided by a wood-burning stove.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marie says she is more or less immune to the winter blues many of her friends experience during cold weather. Rain or snow, she can sit out on her balcony or her roof-top terrace and gaze at the stars, or any glimpses of sun she can catch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot; wp-image-7959 aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;https://returntonow.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/52966874_1199977286837309_3602706696318746624_n-300x169.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;529&quot; height=&quot;298&quot; srcset=&quot;https://returntonow.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/52966874_1199977286837309_3602706696318746624_n-300x169.jpg 300w, https://returntonow.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/52966874_1199977286837309_3602706696318746624_n-768x432.jpg 768w, https://returntonow.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/52966874_1199977286837309_3602706696318746624_n-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://returntonow.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/52966874_1199977286837309_3602706696318746624_n.jpg 1334w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 529px) 100vw, 529px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, during the warmest parts of the summer, her glass roof automatically opens up when it hits a certain temperature, to let the heat out so it doesn’t get too hot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It can get warm a few days in the summer,” she says, “but that’s not really a problem because we open the windows and we enjoy the heat. We like the sun!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The family’s favorite hangout is the rooftop deck. Since they built a glass ceiling, they no longer needed a roof, so they removed it to create a large space for sunbathing, reading, gardening or playing with their son on swings and bikes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot; wp-image-7968 aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;https://returntonow.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/53138989_392679704849352_489210523204714496_n-300x169.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;564&quot; height=&quot;318&quot; srcset=&quot;https://returntonow.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/53138989_392679704849352_489210523204714496_n-300x169.png 300w, https://returntonow.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/53138989_392679704849352_489210523204714496_n-768x432.png 768w, https://returntonow.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/53138989_392679704849352_489210523204714496_n-1024x576.png 1024w, https://returntonow.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/53138989_392679704849352_489210523204714496_n.png 1334w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 564px) 100vw, 564px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In addition to keeping their bodies warmer, the greenhouse also keeps their plants warmer&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The footprint of the greenhouse is nearly double that of the home, leaving plenty of room for a wrap-around garden. And since they’ve created a Mediterranean climate for themselves, the couple grows produce that typically isn’t grown in Sweden, like figs, grapes, tomatoes, cucumbers and herbs. Outside the glass they have cherry and apple trees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot; wp-image-7963 aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;https://returntonow.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/53439736_1043039315889189_6319268567531388928_n-300x169.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;529&quot; height=&quot;298&quot; srcset=&quot;https://returntonow.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/53439736_1043039315889189_6319268567531388928_n-300x169.png 300w, https://returntonow.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/53439736_1043039315889189_6319268567531388928_n-768x432.png 768w, https://returntonow.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/53439736_1043039315889189_6319268567531388928_n-1024x576.png 1024w, https://returntonow.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/53439736_1043039315889189_6319268567531388928_n.png 1334w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 529px) 100vw, 529px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Growing things here is not easy,” Marie says in the video. “We need all the extra energy we can get.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On top of free heat, the couple has also installed a rainwater collection system for free water, and a composting toilet system that provides free fertilizer for their plants. Also, the plants that thrive in their home return the favor by cleaning the air and providing more oxygen. &lt;img class=&quot; wp-image-7962 aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;https://returntonow.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/53226285_856889874652072_5802131900680110080_n-300x169.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;527&quot; height=&quot;297&quot; srcset=&quot;https://returntonow.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/53226285_856889874652072_5802131900680110080_n-300x169.png 300w, https://returntonow.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/53226285_856889874652072_5802131900680110080_n-768x432.png 768w, https://returntonow.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/53226285_856889874652072_5802131900680110080_n-1024x576.png 1024w, https://returntonow.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/53226285_856889874652072_5802131900680110080_n.png 1334w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 527px) 100vw, 527px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It starts with a urine-separating toilet and uses centrifuges, cisterns, ponds and garden beds to filter waste water and compost the remains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the future, the couple is working on designing a system to capture excess solar energy during the summer and store it for the winter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“If you want to be self sufficient, and not dependent on bigger systems, you can have this and live anywhere you like,” Marie said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s all a philosophy of life, to use nature, sun and water to live in a another world,” Charles said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Charles and Marie weren’t the first ones to build a house-inside-a-greenhouse. Their idea was inspired by Swedish architect &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bengtwarne.malwa.nu/index.html&quot;&gt;Bengt Warne&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; who built the first “&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bengtwarne.malwa.nu/natureH.html&quot;&gt;Naturhus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;” (Nature House) in Stockholm in 1974:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot; wp-image-7965 aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;https://returntonow.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/natGav1-273x300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;403&quot; height=&quot;443&quot; srcset=&quot;https://returntonow.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/natGav1-273x300.jpg 273w, https://returntonow.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/natGav1.jpg 480w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 403px) 100vw, 403px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot; wp-image-7966 aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;https://returntonow.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/natLanga-300x242.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;406&quot; height=&quot;327&quot; srcset=&quot;https://returntonow.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/natLanga-300x242.jpg 300w, https://returntonow.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/natLanga.jpg 480w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 406px) 100vw, 406px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot; wp-image-7967 aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;https://returntonow.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/natVaxt-300x201.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;395&quot; height=&quot;265&quot; srcset=&quot;https://returntonow.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/natVaxt-300x201.jpg 300w, https://returntonow.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/natVaxt-75x50.jpg 75w, https://returntonow.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/natVaxt.jpg 480w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 395px) 100vw, 395px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since then a handful of others have been built in Sweden and Germany.&lt;/p&gt;




</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 20:57:55 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>rmason</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Swedish Couple Builds Greenhouse Around Home to Stay Warm and Grow Food All Year Long</og:title>
<og:description>Greenhouse keeps home in the 60’s, even when it’s freezing outside; allows family to grow Mediterranean fruit in Sweden Marie Granmar and Charles Sacilotto literally live in a bubble, insulated from the cold and the harshness of the elements, while taking in the best of what nature has to offer. …</og:description>
<og:url>https://returntonow.net/2019/03/04/swedish-couple-builds-greenhouse-around-home-to-stay-warm-and-grow-food-all-year-long/</og:url>
<og:image>https://returntonow.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/img.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://returntonow.net/2019/03/04/swedish-couple-builds-greenhouse-around-home-to-stay-warm-and-grow-food-all-year-long/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Show HN: Catj – A new way to display JSON files</title>
<link>https://github.com/soheilpro/catj</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/soheilpro/catj</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;Box-body&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;markdown-body entry-content p-5&quot; itemprop=&quot;text&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Displays JSON files in a flat format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Input:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;{
  &quot;mappings&quot;: {
    &quot;templates&quot;: [
      {
        &quot;fields&quot;: {
          &quot;mapping&quot;: {
            &quot;norms&quot;: false,
            &quot;type&quot;: &quot;text&quot;,
            &quot;fields&quot;: {
              &quot;keyword&quot;: {
                &quot;ignore_above&quot;: 256,
                &quot;type&quot;: &quot;keyword&quot;
              }
            }
          }
        }
      }
    ]
  }
}
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Output:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;.mappings.templates[0].fields.mapping.norms = false
.mappings.templates[0].fields.mapping.type = &quot;text&quot;
.mappings.templates[0].fields.mapping.fields.keyword.ignore_above = 256
.mappings.templates[0].fields.mapping.fields.keyword.type = &quot;keyword&quot;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;It makes it easier to understand the structure of JSON files.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The output is valid JavaScript which can be used directly in code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It's very helpful when writing queries for tools like &lt;a href=&quot;https://stedolan.github.io/jq/manual/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;jq&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Install&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;npm install -g catj
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Usage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;catj [file]
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If no file is specified, catj reads from the standard input.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Version History&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.0&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Initial release.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Author&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Soheil Rashidi&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Copyright and License&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Copyright 2014 Soheil Rashidi&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Licensed under the The MIT License (the &quot;License&quot;); you may not use this work except in compliance with the License. You may obtain a copy of the License in the LICENSE file, or at:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.opensource.org/licenses/mit-license.php&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://www.opensource.org/licenses/mit-license.php&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software distributed under the License is distributed on an &quot;AS IS&quot; BASIS, WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied. See the License for the specific language governing permissions and limitations under the License.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 20:10:10 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>soheilpro</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars0.githubusercontent.com/u/1636009?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>soheilpro/catj</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/soheilpro/catj</og:url>
<og:description>Displays JSON files in a flat format. Contribute to soheilpro/catj development by creating an account on GitHub.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/soheilpro/catj</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>