<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Georgia election server wiped after lawsuit filed</title>
<link>http://www.mercurynews.com/2017/10/26/georgia-election-server-wiped-after-lawsuit-filed/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.mercurynews.com/2017/10/26/georgia-election-server-wiped-after-lawsuit-filed/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;By Frank Bajak | Associated Press&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A computer server crucial to a lawsuit against Georgia election officials was quietly wiped clean by its custodians just after the suit was filed, The Associated Press has learned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The server’s data was destroyed July 7 by technicians at the Center for Elections Systems at Kennesaw State University, which runs the state’s election system. The data wipe was revealed in an email sent last week from an assistant state attorney general to plaintiffs in the case that was later obtained by the AP. More emails obtained in a public records request confirmed the wipe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Interested in more coverage of the California marijuana industry? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thecannifornian.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Head to TheCannifornian.com&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://bayareane.ws/THCnewsletter&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;subscribe to The Cannifornian newsletter&lt;/a&gt; to get cannabis-related news, features and more.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;The lawsuit, filed on July 3 by a diverse group of election reform advocates, aims to force Georgia to retire its antiquated and heavily criticized election technology. The server in question, which served as a statewide staging location for key election-related data, made national headlines in June after a security expert disclosed a gaping security hole that wasn’t fixed six months after he reported it to election authorities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wiped out&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not clear who ordered the server’s data irretrievably erased.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Kennesaw election center answers to Georgia’s secretary of state, Brian Kemp, a Republican who is running for governor in 2018 and is the main defendant in the suit. A spokeswoman for the secretary of state’s office said Wednesday that “we did not have anything to do with this decision,” adding that the office also had no advance warning of the move.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The center’s director, Michael Barnes, referred questions to the university’s press office, which declined comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plaintiffs in the lawsuit, who are mostly Georgia voters, want to scrap the state’s 15-year-old vote-management system — particularly its 27,000 AccuVote touchscreen voting machines, hackable devices that don’t use paper ballots or keep hardcopy proof of voter intent. The plaintiffs were counting on an independent security review of the Kennesaw server, which held electronic poll book and other elections staging data for counties, to demonstrate the system’s unreliability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wiping the server clean “forestalls any forensic investigation at all,” said Richard DeMillo, a Georgia Tech computer scientist who has closely followed the case. “People who have nothing to hide don’t behave this way.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;State security&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The server data could have revealed whether Georgia’s most recent elections were compromised by malicious hackers. The plaintiffs contend that the results of both last November’s election and a special June 20 congressional runoff — won by Kemp’s predecessor, Karen Handel — cannot be trusted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Possible Russian interference in U.S. politics, including attempts to penetrate voting systems, has been an acute national preoccupation since the Obama administration first sounded the alarm more than a year ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kemp and his GOP allies insist Georgia’s elections system is secure. But Marilyn Marks, executive director of the Coalition for Good Governance, a plaintiff, believes the server data was erased precisely because the system isn’t secure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I don’t think you could find a voting systems expert who would think the deletion of the server data was anything less than insidious and highly suspicious,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Now you see it, now you don’t&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It could still be possible to recover relevant information from the server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The FBI is known to have made an exact data image of the server in March when it investigated the security hole. The email that disclosed the server wipe said the state attorney general’s office was “reaching out to the FBI to determine whether they still have the image.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Atlanta FBI spokesman Stephen Emmett, responding to AP questions, would not say whether that image still exists. Nor would he say whether agents examined it to determine whether the server’s files might have been altered by unauthorized users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other backups also appear to be gone. In the same email to plaintiffs’ attorneys, assistant state attorney general Cristina Correia wrote that two backup servers were also wiped clean on Aug. 9, just as the lawsuit moved to federal court.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Failing to service the server&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A 180-page collection of Kennesaw State emails, obtained Friday by the Coalition for Good Governments via an open records search, details the destruction of the data on all three servers and a partial and ultimately ineffective effort by Kennesaw State systems engineers to fix the main server’s security hole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result of the failed effort, sensitive data on Georgia’s 6.7 million voters — including social security numbers, party affiliation and birthdates — as well as passwords used by county officials to access elections management files remained exposed for months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem was first discovered by Atlanta security researcher Logan Lamb, who happened across it while doing online research in August 2016. He informed the election center’s director at the time, noting in an email that “there is a strong possibility your site is already compromised.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on his review of the emails, Lamb believes that electronic polling books could have been altered in Georgia’s biggest counties to add or drop voters or to scramble their data. Malicious hackers could have altered the templates of the memory cards used in voting machines to skew results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An attacker could even have potentially modified “ballot-building” files to corrupt the outcome, said Lamb, who works at Atlanta-based security firm Bastille Networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The bigger picture&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tale of the wayward election server is striking, but to voting experts it’s only part of a much larger problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Department of Homeland Security says 21 states had elections systems scanned or penetrated by Russia-backed hackers last year, though there is no evidence they altered voting outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But computer security experts say it’s possible Russians or other malicious actors have sown undetected booby traps in the highly decentralized U.S. voting landscape. In June, a leaked National Security Agency memo showed that 122 elections officials in various states were targeted with phishing emails crafted by Russian agents intent on stealing their passwords.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That revelation helped persuade Lamb to go public in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 21:18:05 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>wglb</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Georgia election server wiped after lawsuit filed</og:title>
<og:url>http://www.mercurynews.com/2017/10/26/georgia-election-server-wiped-after-lawsuit-filed/</og:url>
<og:description>Richard DeMillo, a Georgia Tech computer scientist who has closely followed the case, said: “People who have nothing to hide don’t behave this way.”</og:description>
<og:image>http://www.mercurynews.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/election-security-georg_2.jpg?w=1024&amp;h=576</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.mercurynews.com/2017/10/26/georgia-election-server-wiped-after-lawsuit-filed/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Monsanto Attacks Scientists After Studies Show Trouble for Its New Weedkiller</title>
<link>http://www.npr.org/sections/thesalt/2017/10/26/559733837/monsanto-and-the-weed-scientists-not-a-love-story</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.npr.org/sections/thesalt/2017/10/26/559733837/monsanto-and-the-weed-scientists-not-a-love-story</guid>
<description>&lt;div id=&quot;res560082476&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap image large&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;imagewrap&quot; data-crop-type=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2017/10/25/dicamba_not_love_story-1_custom-b2b257513177c51dd530a642dc19452d79fb33b1-s1100-c15.jpg&quot; data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2017/10/25/dicamba_not_love_story-1_custom-b2b257513177c51dd530a642dc19452d79fb33b1-s1100.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img lazyOnLoad&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;credit-caption&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-wrap&quot; readability=&quot;8.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image caption&quot; readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bob Scott, a weed scientist at the University of Arkansas, says he wishes more testing could have been done on the new dicamba formulations, but &quot;the product was not made available to us.&quot; &lt;strong class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Dan Charles/ NPR&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong class=&quot;hide-caption&quot;&gt;hide caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;strong class=&quot;toggle-caption&quot;&gt;toggle caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Dan Charles/ NPR&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;enlarge_measure&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img_wrap&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2017/10/25/dicamba_not_love_story-1_custom-b2b257513177c51dd530a642dc19452d79fb33b1-s1200.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;enlarge_html&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image_data&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Bob Scott, a weed scientist at the University of Arkansas, says he wishes more testing could have been done on the new dicamba formulations, but &quot;the product was not made available to us.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Dan Charles/ NPR&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a normal year, Kevin Bradley, a professor of weed science at the University of Missouri, would have spent his summer testing new ways to control a troublesome little plant called water hemp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This has not been a normal year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;I don't even talk about weed management anymore,&quot; &lt;a href=&quot;https://ipm.missouri.edu/IPCM/2017/8/Update-on-Dicamba-related-Injury-Investigations-and-Estimates-of-Injured-Soybean-Acreage/&quot;&gt;Bradley&lt;/a&gt; tells me, and he sounds disgusted. &quot;Nobody calls me and ask me those questions. I barely have time to even work with my graduate students. Everything is about dicamba. Every single day.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dicamba, an old weedkiller that is being used in new ways, has thrust Bradley and a half-dozen other university weed scientists into the unfamiliar role of whistleblower, confronting what they believe are misleading and scientifically unfounded claims by one of the country's biggest seed and pesticide companies: Monsanto.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;It's not comfortable. I'm like anybody else, I don't like [it when] people are unhappy with me,&quot; says &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.weeds.iastate.edu/personnel/owen.htm&quot;&gt;Mike Owen&lt;/a&gt;, a weed specialist at Iowa State University. Then he chuckles. &quot;But sometimes, like John Wayne said, a man's got to do what a man's got to do!&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id=&quot;ad-backstage-wrap&quot; aria-label=&quot;advertisement&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;aside id=&quot;ad-mobilebackfill-wrap&quot; aria-label=&quot;advertisement&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Certainly, there's not a weed scientist in any of these states who would back down, who would change their story,&quot; says &lt;a href=&quot;https://cropsciences.illinois.edu/people/profile/hager&quot;&gt;Aaron Hager&lt;/a&gt;, at the University of Illinois.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;res560093665&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap internallink insettwocolumn inset2col&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bucket img&quot;&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;featuredStackSquareImage555872494&quot; href=&quot;http://www.npr.org/sections/thesalt/2017/10/07/555872494/a-wayward-weed-killer-divides-farm-communities-harms-wildlife&quot; data-metrics=&quot;{&amp;quot;category&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Story to Story&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;action&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Click Internal Link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;label&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;http:\/\/www.npr.org\/sections\/thesalt\/2017\/10\/07\/555872494\/a-wayward-weed-killer-divides-farm-communities-harms-wildlife&amp;quot;}&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2017/10/05/promo_weed_sq-a3beaea1e7d09955a0771c7679b03f649e1f96b8-s100-c15.jpg&quot; data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2017/10/05/promo_weed_sq-a3beaea1e7d09955a0771c7679b03f649e1f96b8-s100.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img lazyOnLoad&quot; alt=&quot;A Wayward Weedkiller Divides Farm Communities, Harms Wildlife&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tensions between Monsanto and the nation's weed scientists actually began several years ago, when Monsanto first moved to make dicamba the centerpiece of a new weedkilling strategy. The company tweaked the genes in soybeans and cotton and created genetically modified varieties of those crops that can tolerate doses of dicamba. (Normally, dicamba kills those crops.) This allowed farmers to spray the weedkiller directly on their soybean or cotton plants, killing the weeds while their crops survived.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's an approach that Monsanto pioneered with crops that were genetically modified to tolerate glyphosate, or Roundup. After two decades of heavy exposure to glyphosate, however, devastating weeds like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.npr.org/sections/thesalt/2012/03/07/147656157/farmers-face-tough-choice-on-ways-to-fight-new-strains-of-weeds&quot;&gt;Palmer amaranth&lt;/a&gt;, or pigweed, developed resistance to it. So farmers are looking for new weedkilling tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dicamba, however, has a well-known defect. It's volatile; it tends to evaporate from the soil or vegetation where it has been sprayed, creating a cloud of plant-killing vapor that can spread in unpredictable directions. It happens more in hot weather, and Monsanto's new strategy inevitably would mean spraying dicamba in the heat of summer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monsanto and two other chemical companies, BASF and DuPont, announced that they had solved this problem with new &quot;low-volatility&quot; formulations of dicamba that don't evaporate as easily. Yet the companies — especially Monsanto — made it difficult for university scientists to verify those claims with independent tests before the products were released commercially.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;I wish we could have done more testing. We've been asking to do more testing for several years, but the product was not made available to us,&quot; says Bob Scott, a weed scientist at the University of Arkansas. &quot;These are proprietary products. Until they release those formulations for testing, we're not allowed to [test them].&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make matters worse, Monsanto started selling its new dicamba-tolerant soybeans in 2016, before the new low-volatility formulations of dicamba were even approved for sale. It tempted farmers to use older versions of dicamba on these crops, illegally, and some farmers couldn't resist that temptation. In Arkansas, there were widespread &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.npr.org/sections/thesalt/2016/08/01/487809643/crime-in-the-fields-how-monsanto-and-scofflaw-farmers-hurt-soybeans-in-arkansas&quot;&gt;reports&lt;/a&gt; that dicamba was damaging neighboring fields that didn't have the benefit of Monsanto's new genes. In one case, a dispute between farmers led to a fatal &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.npr.org/templates/transcript/transcript.php?storyId=531272125&quot;&gt;shooting&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;res560093656&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap internallink insettwocolumn inset2col&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bucket img&quot;&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;featuredStackSquareImage552803465&quot; href=&quot;http://www.npr.org/sections/thesalt/2017/09/22/552803465/arkansas-defies-monsanto-moves-to-ban-rogue-weedkiller&quot; data-metrics=&quot;{&amp;quot;category&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Story to Story&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;action&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Click Internal Link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;label&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;http:\/\/www.npr.org\/sections\/thesalt\/2017\/09\/22\/552803465\/arkansas-defies-monsanto-moves-to-ban-rogue-weedkiller&amp;quot;}&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2017/09/22/img_58951_sq-2dcd58b066eef0d8b9f73dc92f67164751e45884-s100-c15.jpg&quot; data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2017/09/22/img_58951_sq-2dcd58b066eef0d8b9f73dc92f67164751e45884-s100.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img lazyOnLoad&quot; alt=&quot;Arkansas Defies Monsanto, Moves To Ban Rogue Weedkiller&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That fall, at a meeting of weed scientists, Hager confronted Monsanto's representatives. According to Hager, he told the company that &quot;you knowingly released these varieties in an area of the U.S. where you knew that glyphosate resistance [in weeds] was rampant. When you did that ... you knew what was going to happen.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;I got a blank stare,&quot; Hager recalls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This past summer, the floodgates on dicamba use opened. The new formulations of dicamba were approved for use (although Arkansas only allowed farmers to use BASF's product, not Monsanto's) and farmers rushed to adopt the new technology. They planted dicamba-tolerant crops on 26 million acres.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;res560082587&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap image large&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;imagewrap&quot; data-crop-type=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2017/10/25/dicamba_not_love_story-2_custom-968664dcf88fa278f1497073c7d0e5450053c5ea-s1100-c15.jpg&quot; data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2017/10/25/dicamba_not_love_story-2_custom-968664dcf88fa278f1497073c7d0e5450053c5ea-s1100.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img lazyOnLoad&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;credit-caption&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-wrap&quot; readability=&quot;8.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image caption&quot; readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A farmer's nightmare weed, glyphosate-resistant Palmer amaranth, or pigweed, sprouts in a soybean field in Arkansas. Its evolution has farmers looking for new weedkilling strategies. &lt;strong class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Dan Charles /NPR&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong class=&quot;hide-caption&quot;&gt;hide caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;strong class=&quot;toggle-caption&quot;&gt;toggle caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Dan Charles /NPR&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;The demand for it is overwhelming. The need to control these difficult-to-manage weeds is huge,&quot; says Scott Partridge, Monsanto's vice president of global strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When spraying started, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.npr.org/sections/thesalt/2017/10/07/555872494/a-wayward-weed-killer-divides-farm-communities-harms-wildlife&quot;&gt;complaints&lt;/a&gt; rolled in. The new &quot;low volatility&quot; versions of dicamba didn't stay where they belonged. They drifted into nearby fields, damaging crops there — mostly soybeans, but also vegetables and orchards. There were reports of damage from Mississippi to Minnesota, but the problem was worst in Arkansas, Missouri and Tennessee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;By the end of May, first of June, it became impossible; the calls were coming in, three or four a day. Sometimes eight or 12 a day,&quot; says the University of Arkansas' Scott. &quot;There is no precedent for what we've seen this year.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first, the companies selling these herbicides — both Monsanto and BASF — seemed unconcerned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;All I got was denial that there was a problem,&quot; Bradley says. &quot;What I kept hearing was: It's not a big problem nationwide; we always have these kinds of mistakes or accidents with the introduction of any new technology.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So Bradley, a past president of the Weed Science Society of America, started collecting data on crop damage from across the country, mapping the epidemic. By the end of the summer, Bradley estimated that at least 3.1 million acres of crops had shown some injury from drifting dicamba.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the scale of dicamba damage increasingly clear, a fierce debate erupted over its cause.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monsanto's executives insist that the people who sprayed dicamba were just learning how to do it properly and didn't follow directions. Partridge says his company checked out more than a thousand cases of dicamba damage, &quot;and in 88 percent of those instances, the label was not followed.&quot; Farmers or pesticide applicators sprayed dicamba too close to neighboring fields, didn't clean out their equipment properly or used the wrong nozzles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Every one of those [mistakes] is fixable by education,&quot; Partridge says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;University weed scientists say that that is only part of the explanation and that the problem can't be fixed so easily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bradley, Scott and their colleagues in other states say that much of the damage they saw this year didn't appear to come from &quot;physical drift&quot; of windblown droplets of dicamba, coming directly from a sprayer. Physical drift, they say, typically produces a plume of damage that diminishes with distance from the source of the spray. Instead, they saw entire hundred-acre fields of soybeans with cupped leaves, and the damage was uniform from one end to the other. They also saw damage in orchards and fields that were far removed from any fields sprayed with dicamba.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This pattern, they say, looks more like what they had feared all along: volatilization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;res560083493&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap image medium&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;imagewrap&quot; data-crop-type=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2017/10/25/dicamba_not_love_story-3_custom-ef5121c100cbfd089d20355fa31f6dbc76d68ac9-s800-c15.jpg&quot; data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2017/10/25/dicamba_not_love_story-3_custom-ef5121c100cbfd089d20355fa31f6dbc76d68ac9-s800.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img lazyOnLoad&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;credit-caption&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-wrap&quot; readability=&quot;7.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image caption&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lyle Hadden, a soybean farmer, holds leaves and a stalk from a soybean plant in a field he planted that shows signs of being affected by dicamba. &lt;strong class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;The Washington Post/Getty Images&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong class=&quot;hide-caption&quot;&gt;hide caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;strong class=&quot;toggle-caption&quot;&gt;toggle caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;The Washington Post/Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is more, the scientists say, field experiments that they finally carried out this summer point toward evaporating dicamba as a cause.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bob Scott shows me one such experiment, a field of soybeans at a research station near Lonoke, Ark. Here, soybeans were injured by dicamba that definitely did not enter the field through mistakes in spraying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;It's important to remember, we did not spray this plot,&quot; Scott says. Instead, at a location far away from this field, he and his colleagues sprayed trays of soil with various dicamba-containing herbicides. Then they carried the trays into this field and placed them between the rows of soybeans for 48 hours. The trays and soybeans were protected underneath plastic hoops — essentially, miniature greenhouses — that were open at each end. The dicamba evaporated from the trays and injured the soybean plants nearby, curling their leaves and stunting their growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;A lot of people were very disappointed when they saw the plots,&quot; Scott says. &quot;A lot of people didn't want to see what they were seeing, and were in disbelief.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These observations have huge implications. If the new formulations of dicamba evaporate and spread, they cannot easily be controlled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;If this were any other product, I feel like it would be just pulled off the market, and we'd be done with it,&quot; Scott says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But dicamba, and the crops created to tolerate it, aren't just any products. There is big money behind them. Monsanto, seed dealers, farmers who are struggling with weed problems — they all have a stake in this technology. The university scientists who are pointing out problems with them are confronting an economic juggernaut.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monsanto — and farmers who want to use dicamba — have been fighting back. In Arkansas, where state regulators &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.npr.org/sections/thesalt/2017/09/22/552803465/arkansas-defies-monsanto-moves-to-ban-rogue-weedkiller&quot;&gt;proposed&lt;/a&gt; a ban on dicamba during the growing season next year, Monsanto recently sued the regulators, arguing that the ban was based on &quot;unsubstantiated theories regarding product volatility that are contradicted by science.&quot; The company &lt;a href=&quot;https://monsanto.com/app/uploads/2017/09/Monsantos-Petition-for-Rulemaking-to-the-Arkansas-State-Plant-B_84746_1.pdf&quot;&gt;called&lt;/a&gt; on regulators to disregard information from Jason Norsworthy, one of the University of Arkansas' weed researchers, because he had recommended that farmers use a non-dicamba alternative from a rival company. Monsanto also attacked the objectivity of Ford Baldwin, a former university weed scientist who now works as a consultant to farmers and herbicide companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;I read it as an attack on all of us, and anybody who dares to [gather] outside data,&quot; Scott says. &quot;And some of my fellow weed scientists read it that way as well.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bradley says executives from Monsanto have made repeated calls to his supervisors. &quot;What the exact nature of those calls [was], I'm not real sure,&quot; Bradley says. &quot;But I'm pretty sure it has something to do with not being happy with what I'm saying.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I contacted three academic deans at the University of Missouri, asking for details about the calls. A university spokesman said they were too busy to respond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monsanto's Partridge says, &quot;We are not attacking Dr. Bradley. We respect him, his position, opinion, and his work. We respect him, and academics in general.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bradley says criticism from people in Missouri's farming community whom he has known for years hits him even harder. &quot;To have somebody say that what [I'm] saying is bad for Missouri agriculture, that's a hard one to take,&quot; he says. &quot;There's not a lot of glory in these positions, or major financial incentive. We chose these jobs to help the farmers in our states.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monsanto's explanation for what happened this summer, and how to prevent it, seems to be carrying the day in Washington, D.C. Two weeks ago, the Environmental Protection Agency &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.npr.org/sections/thesalt/2017/10/13/557607443/with-ok-from-epa-use-of-controversial-weedkiller-is-expected-to-double&quot;&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; that it will allow continued use of dicamba next year. The EPA is imposing a few additional restrictions on who can spray it, and when. Those restrictions will have little effect, or none at all, on damage caused by volatilization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arkansas' proposal to ban use of dicamba during the growing season next summer has not yet received final approval. A public hearing on the proposal is set for Nov. 8.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kevin Bradley thinks there is one positive result from the controversy. &quot;It has made more farmers aware of what we do, and that is, unbiased research and calling it like we see it,&quot; he says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the course of recent decades, publicly funded agricultural extension services have shrunk, and farmers have turned to seed and chemical companies for advice. &quot;It's become so weighted towards — 'well, the companies did their research, and it said this, so that must be the way it is!' &quot; Bradley says. &quot;You know what? Maybe that's not the way it is.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 15:02:48 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>zymhan</dc:creator>
<og:title>Monsanto Attacks Scientists After Studies Show Trouble For Weedkiller Dicamba</og:title>
<og:url>http://www.npr.org/sections/thesalt/2017/10/26/559733837/monsanto-and-the-weed-scientists-not-a-love-story</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>Scientists are accusing the seed and pesticide giant of denying the risks of its latest weedkilling technology. Monsanto has responded by attacking some of those critics.</og:description>
<og:image>https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2017/10/25/dicamba_not_love_story-1_wide-cfb55f06dd3d8e396002315852f23ca6b0aa0ac0.jpg?s=1400</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.npr.org/sections/thesalt/2017/10/26/559733837/monsanto-and-the-weed-scientists-not-a-love-story</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>“Startup” asks internship applicant to build their app before phone screen</title>
<link>https://www.reddit.com/r/cscareerquestions/comments/78rhz7/this_startup_asked_me_to_do_a_project_for_an/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.reddit.com/r/cscareerquestions/comments/78rhz7/this_startup_asked_me_to_do_a_project_for_an/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;score&quot; title=&quot;84&quot;&gt;84&lt;/span&gt;  · &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone complete an SWE internship at McDonald's, Burger King, etc.?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;score&quot; title=&quot;849&quot;&gt;849&lt;/span&gt;  · &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This &quot;startup&quot; asked me to do a project for an unpaid internship before any kind of phone screen...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;score&quot; title=&quot;12&quot;&gt;12&lt;/span&gt;  · &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discriminatory Hiring Ad (Name and Shame)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;score&quot; title=&quot;13&quot;&gt;13&lt;/span&gt;  · &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every piece of software I've ever wanted or dreamed of already exists. How do I make personal projects that are original?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;score&quot; title=&quot;8&quot;&gt;8&lt;/span&gt;  · &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Western Governors University (WGU) Is Under Audit/Investigation What You Need To Know&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;score&quot; title=&quot;19&quot;&gt;19&lt;/span&gt;  · &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Problematic colleague: How should I cover my bases?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;score&quot; title=&quot;8&quot;&gt;8&lt;/span&gt;  · &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What can I do to become an overall better person and software engineer?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;score&quot; title=&quot;22&quot;&gt;22&lt;/span&gt;  · &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not enjoying this as much as I thought I would&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;· &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are there repercussions for claiming unemployment benefits? Stigma? (California)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;score&quot; title=&quot;9&quot;&gt;9&lt;/span&gt;  · &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SWE, Project Management, Program Management, Product Management, Engineering Management&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 12:29:33 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>erklik</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://www.redditstatic.com/icon.png</og:image>
<og:description>This was the email I received after applying (side note, this company's whole platform is centered around photo based marketing): &quot;Hi _______...</og:description>
<og:title>This &quot;startup&quot; asked me to do a project for an unpaid internship before any kind of phone screen... • r/cscareerquestions</og:title>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.reddit.com/r/cscareerquestions/comments/78rhz7/this_startup_asked_me_to_do_a_project_for_an/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Android Studio 3.0 Release Notes</title>
<link>https://developer.android.com/studio/releases/index.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://developer.android.com/studio/releases/index.html</guid>
<description>&lt;nav class=&quot;inline-toc&quot;&gt;&lt;ol class=&quot;toc&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/releases/index.html#3-0-0&quot;&gt;3.0 (October 2017)&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;toc&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/releases/index.html#android-plugin-for-gradle-3-0-0&quot;&gt;Android Plugin for Gradle 3.0.0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/releases/index.html#kotlin-support&quot;&gt;Kotlin support&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/releases/index.html#java-8-language-support&quot;&gt;Java 8 language features support&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/releases/index.html#android-profiler&quot;&gt;Android Profiler&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/releases/index.html#apk-debugger&quot;&gt;APK profiling and debugging&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/releases/index.html#device-file-explorer&quot;&gt;Device File Explorer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/releases/index.html#instant-apps&quot;&gt;Instant Apps support&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/releases/index.html#android-things-modules&quot;&gt;Android Things modules&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/releases/index.html#adaptive-icons-wizard&quot;&gt;Adaptive Icons wizard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/releases/index.html#support-for-font-resources&quot;&gt;Support for font resources&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/releases/index.html#firebase-app-indexing-assistant&quot;&gt;Firebase App Indexing Assistant&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/releases/index.html#app-links-assistant&quot;&gt;Android App Links Assistant&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/releases/index.html#url-intent-filter-validator&quot;&gt;URL intent-filter validator&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/releases/index.html#layout-editor&quot;&gt;Layout Editor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/releases/index.html#layout-inspector&quot;&gt;Layout Inspector&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/releases/index.html#apk-analyzer&quot;&gt;APK Analyzer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/releases/index.html#preview-the-new-d8-dex-compiler&quot;&gt;Preview for D8 DEX compiler&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/releases/index.html#googles_maven_repository&quot;&gt;Google's Maven repository&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/releases/index.html#other-changes&quot;&gt;Other changes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/releases/index.html#2-3-0&quot;&gt;2.3 (March 2017)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/releases/index.html#2-2-0&quot;&gt;2.2 (September 2016)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/releases/index.html#2-1-0&quot;&gt;2.1 (April 2016)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/releases/index.html#2-0-0&quot;&gt;2.0 (April 2016)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/releases/index.html#older-releases&quot;&gt;Older Releases&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/releases/index.html#Troubleshooting&quot;&gt;Troubleshooting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/nav&gt;&lt;p&gt;Android Studio is the official IDE for Android development, and includes everything you need to build Android apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get the latest version, click &lt;strong&gt;Help &amp;gt; Check for update&lt;/strong&gt; (on Mac, &lt;strong&gt;Android Studio &amp;gt; Check for updates&lt;/strong&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or you can &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/index.html&quot;&gt;download Android Studio here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;3-0-0&quot;&gt;3.0 (October 2017)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Android Studio 3.0.0 is a major release that includes a variety of new features and improvements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;youtube-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/0n9sBgds-Hs?autohide=1&amp;amp;showinfo=0&amp;amp;enablejsapi=1&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caution&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;macOS users:&lt;/strong&gt; If you are updating an older version of Android Studio, you may encounter an update error dialog that says &quot;Some conflicts were found in the installation area&quot;. Simply ignore this error and click &lt;strong&gt;Cancel&lt;/strong&gt; to resume the installation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;android-plugin-for-gradle-3-0-0&quot;&gt;Android Plugin for Gradle 3.0.0&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/releases/gradle-plugin.html&quot;&gt;Android plugin for Gradle&lt;/a&gt; includes a variety of improvements and new features, but it primarily improves build performance for projects that have a large number of modules. When using the new plugin with these large projects, you should experience the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Faster build configuration times due to new delayed dependency resolution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/build/gradle-plugin-3-0-0-migration.html#variant_aware&quot;&gt;Variant-aware dependency resolution&lt;/a&gt; for only the projects and variants you are building.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Faster incremental build times when applying simple changes to code or resources.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;aside class=&quot;note&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;span&gt;These improvements required significant changes that break some of the plugin's behaviors, DSL, and APIs. &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/build/gradle-plugin-3-0-0-migration.html&quot;&gt;Upgrading to version 3.0.0&lt;/a&gt; might require changes to your build files and Gradle plugins.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;This version also includes the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information about what's changed, see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/releases/gradle-plugin.html#3-0-0&quot;&gt;Android Plugin for Gradle Release Notes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're ready to upgrade to the new plugin, see &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/build/gradle-plugin-3-0-0-migration.html&quot;&gt;Migrate to Android Plugin for Gradle 3.0.0&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;kotlin-support&quot;&gt;Kotlin support&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As &lt;a href=&quot;https://android-developers.googleblog.com/2017/05/android-announces-support-for-kotlin.html&quot;&gt;announced at Google I/O 2017&lt;/a&gt;, the Kotlin programming language is now officially supported on Android. So with this release, Android Studio includes Kotlin language support for Android development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can incorporate Kotlin into your project by converting a Java file to Kotlin (click &lt;strong&gt;Code &amp;gt; Convert Java File to Kotlin File&lt;/strong&gt;) or by creating a new Kotlin- enabled project using the New Project wizard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get started, read how to &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/projects/add-kotlin.html&quot;&gt;add Kotlin to your project&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/images/releases/kotlin-convert_2x.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;600&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;java-8-language-support&quot;&gt;Java 8 language features support&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can now use certain Java 8 language features and consume libraries built with Java 8. &lt;strong&gt;Jack is no longer required&lt;/strong&gt;, and you should first &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/write/java8-support.html#disable_jack&quot;&gt;disable Jack&lt;/a&gt; to use the improved Java 8 support built into the default toolchain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To update your project to support the new Java 8 language toolchain, update the &lt;strong&gt;Source Compatibility&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Target Compatibility&lt;/strong&gt; to 1.8 in the &lt;strong&gt;Project Structure&lt;/strong&gt; dialog (click &lt;strong&gt;File &amp;gt; Project Structure&lt;/strong&gt;). To learn more, read how to &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/write/java8-support.html&quot;&gt;use Java 8 language features&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/images/projects/project-java-compatibility_2x.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;700&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;android-profiler&quot;&gt;Android Profiler&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new Android Profiler &lt;strong&gt;replaces the Android Monitor tool&lt;/strong&gt; and provides a new suite of tools to measure your app's CPU, memory, and network usage in realtime. You can perform sample-based method tracing to time your code execution, capture heap dumps, view memory allocations, and inspect the details of network-transmitted files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To open, click &lt;strong&gt;View &amp;gt; Tool Windows &amp;gt; Android Profiler&lt;/strong&gt; (or click &lt;strong&gt;Android Profiler&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/images/buttons/toolbar-android-profiler.png&quot; class=&quot;inline-icon&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt; in the toolbar).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The event timeline at the top of the window shows touch events, key presses, and activity changes so you have more context to understand other performance events in the timeline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;note&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;span&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/debug/am-logcat.html&quot;&gt;Logcat&lt;/a&gt; view also moved to a separate window (it was previously inside Android Monitor, which was removed).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/images/profile/android-profiler-overview_2x.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;856&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the Android Profiler's overview timeline, click on the &lt;strong&gt;CPU&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;MEMORY&lt;/strong&gt;, or &lt;strong&gt;NETWORK&lt;/strong&gt; timelines to access the corresponding profiler tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;cpu_profiler&quot;&gt;CPU Profiler&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CPU Profiler helps you analyze the CPU thread usage of your app by triggering a sample or instrumented CPU trace. Then, you can troubleshoot CPU performance issues using a variety of data views and filters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information, see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/profile/cpu-profiler.html&quot;&gt;CPU Profiler guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/images/releases/cpu-profiler_2x.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;856&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;memory_profiler&quot;&gt;Memory Profiler&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Memory Profiler helps you identify memory leaks and memory churn that can lead to stutter, freezes, and even app crashes. It shows a realtime graph of your app's memory use, lets you capture a heap dump, force garbage collections, and track memory allocations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information, see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/profile/memeory-profiler.html&quot;&gt;Memory Profiler guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/images/releases/memory-profiler_2x.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;856&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;network_profiler&quot;&gt;Network Profiler&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Network Profiler allows you to monitor the network activity of your app, inspect the payload of each of your network requests, and link back to the code that generated the network request.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information, see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/profile/network-profiler.html&quot;&gt;Network Profiler guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/images/releases/network-profiler_2x.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;856&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;apk-debugger&quot;&gt;APK profiling and debugging&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Android Studio now allows you to &lt;strong&gt;profile and debug any APK&lt;/strong&gt; without having to build it from an Android Studio project—as long as the APK is built to &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/debug/index.html#enable-debug&quot;&gt;enable debugging&lt;/a&gt; and you have access to the debug symbols and source files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get started, click &lt;strong&gt;Profile or debug APK&lt;/strong&gt; from the Android Studio Welcome screen. Or, if you already have a project open, click &lt;strong&gt;File &amp;gt; Profile or debug APK&lt;/strong&gt; from the menu bar. This displays the unpacked APK files, but it does not decompile the code. So, to properly add breakpoints and view stack traces, you need to attach Java source files and native debug symbols.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information, see &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/debug/apk-debugger.html&quot;&gt;Profile and Debug Pre-built APKs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/images/debug/apk-debugging_2x.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;856&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;device-file-explorer&quot;&gt;Device File Explorer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new Device File Explorer allows you to inspect your connected device's filesystem, and transfer files between the device and your computer. This replaces the filesystem tool available in DDMS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To open, click &lt;strong&gt;View &amp;gt; Tool Windows &amp;gt; Device File Explorer&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information, see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/debug/device-file-explorer.html&quot;&gt;Device File Explorer guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/images/debug/device-file-explorer_2x.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;570&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;instant-apps&quot;&gt;Instant Apps support&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New support for Android Instant Apps allows you to create Instant Apps in your project using &lt;strong&gt;two new module types&lt;/strong&gt;: Instant App modules and Feature modules (these require that you &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/topic/instant-apps/getting-started/setup.html#setup-sdk&quot;&gt;install the Instant Apps Development SDK&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/images/projects/instant-apps-module_2x.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;800&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Android Studio also includes a &lt;strong&gt;new modularize refactoring action&lt;/strong&gt; to help you add support for Instant Apps in an existing project. For example, if you want to refactor your project to place some classes in an Instant App feature module, select the classes in the &lt;strong&gt;Project&lt;/strong&gt; window and click &lt;strong&gt;Refactor &amp;gt; Modularize&lt;/strong&gt;. In the dialog that appears, select the module where the classes should go and click &lt;strong&gt;OK&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And when you're ready to test your Instant App, you can &lt;strong&gt;build and run your Instant App module&lt;/strong&gt; on a connected device by specifying the Instant App's URL within the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/run/rundebugconfig.html#general-tab&quot;&gt;run configuration launch options&lt;/a&gt;: Select &lt;strong&gt;Run &amp;gt; Edit Configurations&lt;/strong&gt;, select your Instant App module, and then set the URL under &lt;strong&gt;Launch Options&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information, see &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/topic/instant-apps/index.html&quot;&gt;Android Instant Apps&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;android-things-modules&quot;&gt;Android Things modules&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New Android Things templates in the New Project and New Module wizards to help you start developing for Android-powered IOT devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information, see how to &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/things/training/first-device/create-studio-project.html&quot;&gt;create an Android Things project&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;adaptive-icons-wizard&quot;&gt;Adaptive Icons wizard&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image Asset Studio now supports &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/guide/topics/graphics/vector-drawable-resources.html&quot;&gt;vector drawables&lt;/a&gt; and allows you to create &lt;strong&gt;adaptive launcher icons for Android 8.0&lt;/strong&gt; while simultaneously creating traditional icons (&quot;Legacy&quot; icons) for older devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To start, right-click on the &lt;strong&gt;res&lt;/strong&gt; folder in your project, and then click &lt;strong&gt;New &amp;gt; Image Asset&lt;/strong&gt;. In the &lt;strong&gt;Asset Studio&lt;/strong&gt; window, select &lt;strong&gt;Launcher Icons (Adaptive and Legacy)&lt;/strong&gt; as the icon type.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;note&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;span&gt;You must set &lt;code&gt;compileSdkVersion&lt;/code&gt; to 26 or higher to use adaptive launcher icons.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;For more information, read about &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/guide/practices/ui_guidelines/icon_design_adaptive.html&quot;&gt;Adaptive Icons&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/images/write/image-asset-studio_2x.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;856&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;support-for-font-resources&quot;&gt;Support for font resources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To support the new font resources in Android 8.0, Android Studio includes a &lt;strong&gt;font resources selector&lt;/strong&gt; to help bundle fonts into your app or configure your project to download the fonts on the device (when available). The layout editor can also &lt;strong&gt;preview the fonts&lt;/strong&gt; in your layout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To try downloadable fonts, ensure that your device or emulator is running Google Play Services v11.2.63 or higher. For more information, read about &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/guide/topics/ui/look-and-feel/downloadable-fonts.html&quot;&gt;Downloadable Fonts&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/images/write/font-download_2x.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;800&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;firebase-app-indexing-assistant&quot;&gt;Firebase App Indexing Assistant&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Firebase Assistant has been updated with a new tutorial to test &lt;a href=&quot;https://firebase.google.com/docs/app-indexing/&quot;&gt;App Indexing&lt;/a&gt;. To open the Assistant, select &lt;strong&gt;Tools &amp;gt; Firebase&lt;/strong&gt;. Then select &lt;strong&gt;App Indexing &amp;gt; Test App Indexing&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tutorial includes new buttons to test your public and personal content indexing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;In step 2, click &lt;strong&gt;Preview search results&lt;/strong&gt; to verify that your URLs are showing up in Google Search results.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In step 3, click &lt;strong&gt;Check for errors&lt;/strong&gt; to verify that the indexable objects in your app have been added to the personal content index.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;app-links-assistant&quot;&gt;Android App Links Assistant&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/write/app-link-indexing.html&quot;&gt;App Links Assistant&lt;/a&gt; has been updated with the following new capabilities:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Add URL tests&lt;/strong&gt; for each URL mapping to be sure your intent filters handle real-world URLs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/images/write/applinks-url-validation-callout_2x.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;756&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also define these URL tests by hand using the &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;tools:validation&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; tag described below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create a Digital Asset Links file&lt;/strong&gt; with the appropriate object entry to support &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/identity/smartlock-passwords/android/&quot;&gt;Google Smart Lock&lt;/a&gt;, and add the corresponding &lt;code&gt;asset_statements&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;meta-data&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; tag to your manifest file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/images/write/applinks-smartlock-callout_2x.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;756&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;url-intent-filter-validator&quot;&gt;URL intent-filter validator&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Android Studio now supports a special tag in the manifest file that allows you to &lt;strong&gt;test your intent filter URLs&lt;/strong&gt;. These are the same tags that the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/releases/index.html#app-links-assistant&quot;&gt;App Links Assistant can create for you&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To declare a test URL for an intent filter, add a &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;tools:validation&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; element alongside the corresponding &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;intent-filter&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; element. For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;prettyprint&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;activity ...&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;intent-filter&amp;gt;
        ...
    &amp;lt;/intent-filter&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;tools:validation testUrl=&quot;https://www.example.com/recipe/1138&quot; /&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/activity&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be sure to also include &lt;code&gt;xmlns:tools=&quot;http://schemas.android.com/tools&quot;&lt;/code&gt; in the &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;manifest&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; tag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If any one of the test URLs does not pass the intent filter definition, a lint error appears. Such an error still allows you to build debug variants, but it will break your release builds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/images/write/intent-url-validation_2x.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;530&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;layout-editor&quot;&gt;Layout Editor&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/write/layout-editor.html&quot;&gt;Layout Editor&lt;/a&gt; has been updated with a number of enhancements, including the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;New toolbar layout and icons.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated layout in the component tree.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved drag-and-drop view insertions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New error panel below the editor, showing all issues with suggestions to fix (if available).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Various UI enhancements for building with &lt;code&gt;ConstraintLayout&lt;/code&gt;, including the following:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;New support to &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/training/constraint-layout/index.html#constrain-to-a-barrier&quot;&gt;create barriers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New support to create groups: In the toolbar, select &lt;strong&gt;Guidelines &amp;gt; Add Group&lt;/strong&gt; (requires &lt;a href=&quot;https://androidstudio.googleblog.com/2017/10/constraintlayout-110-beta-2.html&quot;&gt;ConstraintLayout 1.1.0 beta 2&lt;/a&gt; or higher)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New UI to create chains: Select multiple views, and then right-click and select &lt;strong&gt;Chain&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/images/write/layout-editor-errors_2x.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;856&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;layout-inspector&quot;&gt;Layout Inspector&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/debug/layout-inspector.html&quot;&gt;Layout Inspector&lt;/a&gt; includes enhancements to make it easier to debug issues with your app layouts, including grouping properties into common categories and new search functionality in both the &lt;strong&gt;View Tree&lt;/strong&gt; and the &lt;strong&gt;Properties&lt;/strong&gt; panes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/images/debug/layout-inspector_2x.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;856&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;apk-analyzer&quot;&gt;APK Analyzer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can now use the APK Analyzer from the command line with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/command-line/apkanalyzer.html&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;apkanalyzer&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The APK Analyzer has also been updated with the following improvements:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;For APKs built with ProGuard, you can load ProGuard mapping files that add capabilities to the DEX viewer, including:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Bolded nodes to indicate that the nodes should not be removed when shrinking code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A button to show nodes that were removed during the shrinking process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A button that restores the original names of nodes in the tree view that were obfuscated by ProGuard.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The DEX Viewer now shows the estimated size impact of each package, class and method.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New filtering options at the top to show and hide fields and methods.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the tree view, nodes that are references not defined in the DEX file appear in italics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;For more information, see &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/build/apk-analyzer.html&quot;&gt;Analyze Your Build with APK Analyzer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;preview-the-new-d8-dex-compiler&quot;&gt;Preview for D8 DEX compiler&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Android Studio 3.0 includes an optional new DEX compiler called D8. It will eventually replace the DX compiler, but you can opt-in to use the new D8 compiler now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DEX compilation directly impacts your app's build time, &lt;code&gt;.dex&lt;/code&gt; file size, and runtime performance. And when comparing the new D8 compiler with the current DX compiler, D8 compiles faster and outputs smaller &lt;code&gt;.dex&lt;/code&gt; files, while having the same or better app runtime performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To try it, set the following in your project's &lt;code&gt;gradle.properties&lt;/code&gt; file:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;prettyprint&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;android.enableD8=true
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information, see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://android-developers.googleblog.com/2017/08/next-generation-dex-compiler-now-in.html&quot;&gt;blog post about the D8 compiler&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;googles_maven_repository&quot;&gt;Google's Maven repository&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Android Studio now uses Google’s Maven Repository by default instead of depending on the Android SDK Manager to get updates for Android Support Library, Google Play Services, Firebase, and other dependencies. This makes it easier to keep your libraries up to date, especially when using a continuous integration (CI) system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All new projects now include the Google Maven repository by default. To update your existing project, add &lt;code&gt;google()&lt;/code&gt; in the &lt;code&gt;repositories&lt;/code&gt; block of the top-level &lt;code&gt;build.gradle&lt;/code&gt; file:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;prettyprint&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;allprojects {
    repositories {
        google()
    }
}
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn more about &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/build/dependencies.html#google-maven&quot;&gt;Google's Maven repository here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;other-changes&quot;&gt;Other changes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Native debugging with Android Studio no longer supports 32-bit Windows. We've chosen to focus on other platforms because very few developers are using this platform. If you are using 32-bit Windows and you plan to debug native code, you should keep using &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/archive.html#android-studio-2-3-3&quot;&gt;Android Studio 2.3&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upgraded the base IDE to &lt;a href=&quot;https://confluence.jetbrains.com/display/IDEADEV/IntelliJ+IDEA+2017.1.2+Release+Notes&quot;&gt;IntelliJ 2017.1.2&lt;/a&gt;, which adds a number of new features from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jetbrains.com/idea/whatsnew/#v2016-3&quot;&gt;2016.3&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2017/02/intellij-idea-2017-1-public-preview-java-9-debugger-vcs-search-editor-and-many-more/&quot;&gt;2017.1&lt;/a&gt;, such as Java 8 language refactoring, parameter hints, semantic highlighting, draggable breakpoints, instant results in search, and much more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added many new lint checks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Also see the latest &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/releases/emulator.html&quot;&gt;Android Emulator updates&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-3-0&quot;&gt;2.3 (March 2017)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Android Studio 2.3.0 is primarily a bug fix and stability release, but it also includes a number of new features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;updates-box&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.3.3 (June 2017)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a minor update to add support for Android O (API level 26).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;updates-box&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.3.2 (April 2017)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a minor update to Android Studio 2.3 for the following changes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;AVD Manager updates to support Google Play in system images.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bug fixes for NDK builds when using R14+ of the NDK.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also see corresponding updates for &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/releases/emulator.html&quot;&gt;Android Emulator 26.0.3&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;updates-box&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.3.1 (April 2017)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a minor update to Android Studio 2.3 that fixes an issue where some physical Android devices did not work properly with &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/run/index.html#instant-run&quot;&gt;Instant Run&lt;/a&gt; (see &lt;a href=&quot;https://code.google.com/p/android/issues/detail?id=235879&quot;&gt;Issue #235879&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;New&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;youtube-wrapper attempt-right&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/VFyKclKBGf0?autohide=1&amp;amp;showinfo=0&amp;amp;enablejsapi=1&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Android Studio can now convert PNG, BMP, JPG, and static GIF files to WebP format. WebP is an image file format from Google that provides lossy compression (like JPEG) as well as transparency (like PNG) but can provide better compression than either JPEG or PNG. For more information, see &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/write/convert-webp.html&quot;&gt;Convert Images to WebP in Android Studio&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The new &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/write/app-link-indexing.html&quot;&gt;App Links Assistant&lt;/a&gt; simplifies the process of adding Android App Links to your app into a step-by-step wizard. Android App Links are HTTP URLs that bring users directly to specific content in your Android app.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Layout Editor now includes support for two new ConstraintLayout features:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Define a view size based on an aspect ratio.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create packed, spread, and weighted linear groups with constraint chains.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
For more information, see &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/training/constraint-layout/index.html&quot;&gt;Build a Responsive UI with ConstraintLayout&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Layout Editor also now lets you create a list of &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/write/layout-editor.html#edit-properties&quot;&gt;favorite attributes&lt;/a&gt; so you don't have to click &lt;strong&gt;View all attributes&lt;/strong&gt; to access the attributes you use most.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When adding a material icon using the Vector Import Dialog (&lt;strong&gt;File &amp;gt; New &amp;gt; Vector Asset&lt;/strong&gt;), you can now filter the list of available icons by category or by icon name. For more information, see &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/write/vector-asset-studio.html#materialicon&quot;&gt;Adding a material icon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/write/annotations.html#accessibility&quot;&gt;New and updated annotations&lt;/a&gt;. The new &lt;code&gt;@RestrictTo&lt;/code&gt; annotation for methods, classes, and packages lets you restrict an API. The updated &lt;code&gt;@VisibleForTesting&lt;/code&gt; annotation now has an optional &lt;code&gt;otherwise&lt;/code&gt; argument that lets you designate what the visibility of a method should be if not for the need to make it visible for testing. Lint uses the &lt;code&gt;otherwise&lt;/code&gt; option to enforce the intended visibility of the method.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/write/lint.html#snapshot&quot;&gt;lint baseline support&lt;/a&gt; allows you to use a snapshot of your project's current set of warnings as a baseline for future inspection runs so only new issues are reported. The baseline snapshot lets you start using lint to fail the build for new issues without having to go back and address all existing issues first.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New lint checks, including the following:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Obsolete &lt;code&gt;SDK_INT&lt;/code&gt; Checks: Android Studio removes obsolete code that checks for SDK versions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Object Animator Validation: Lint analyzes your code to make sure that your &lt;code&gt;ObjectAnimator&lt;/code&gt; calls reference valid methods with the right signatures and checks that those methods are annotated with &lt;code&gt;@Keep&lt;/code&gt; to prevent ProGuard from renaming or removing them during release builds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unnecessary Item Decorator Copy: Older versions of the &lt;code&gt;RecyclerView&lt;/code&gt; library did not include a divider decorator class, but one was provided as a sample in the support demos. Recent versions of the library have a divider decorator class. Lint looks for the old sample and suggests replacing it with the new one.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WifiManager Leak: Prior to Android 7.0 (API level 24), initializing the &lt;code&gt;WifiManager&lt;/code&gt; with &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/reference/android/content/Context.html#getSystemService(java.lang.Class%3CT%3E)&quot;&gt;Context.getSystemService()&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt; can cause a memory leak if the context is not the application context. Lint looks for these initializations, and if it &lt;em&gt;cannot&lt;/em&gt; determine that the context is the application context, it suggests you use &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/reference/android/content/Context.html#getApplicationContext()&quot;&gt;Context.getApplicationContext()&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt; to get the proper context for the initialization.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved Resource Prefix: The existing &lt;code&gt;resourcePrefix&lt;/code&gt; lint check had many limitations. You can now configure your project with a prefix, such as &lt;code&gt;android { resourcePrefix '&lt;var&gt;my_lib&lt;/var&gt;' }&lt;/code&gt;, and lint makes sure that all of your resources are using this prefix. You can use variations of the name for styles and themes. For example for the &lt;var&gt;my_lib&lt;/var&gt; prefix, you can have themes named &lt;code&gt;MyLibTheme&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;myLibAttr&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;my_lib_layout&lt;/code&gt;, and so on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Switch to WebP: This check identifies images in your project that can be converted to WebP format based on your project’s &lt;code&gt;minSdkVersion&lt;/code&gt; setting. An associated quickfix can automatically convert the images, or you can &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/write/convert-webp.html&quot;&gt;convert images to WebP&lt;/a&gt; manually.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unsafe WebP: If your project already includes WebP images, this check analyzes your project to ensure that your &lt;code&gt;minSdkVersion&lt;/code&gt; setting is high enough to support the included images. For more information about WebP support in Android and Android Studio, see &lt;a class=&quot;external&quot; href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/speed/webp/faq#which_web_browsers_natively_support_webp&quot;&gt;Which browsers natively support WebP?&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/write/convert-webp.html&quot;&gt;Create WebP Images Using Android Studio&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Changes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;A separate button to push changes with Instant Run: After deploying your app, you now click &lt;strong&gt;Apply Changes&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/images/buttons/toolbar-apply-changes.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;inline-icon&quot;/&gt; to quickly push incremental changes to your running app using Instant Run. The &lt;strong&gt;Run&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/images/buttons/toolbar-run.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;inline-icon&quot;/&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Debug&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/images/buttons/toolbar-debug.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;inline-icon&quot;/&gt; buttons are always available to you when you want to reliably push your changes and force an app restart.
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Instant Run is supported only when deploying your app to a target device running Android 5.0 (API level 21) or higher.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Instant Run is no longer disabled for projects that &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/projects/add-native-code.html&quot;&gt;link to external native projects&lt;/a&gt; using CMake or ndk-build. However, you can only use Instant Run to push incremental changes to your Java code, not your native code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cold swaps (which you can force for a running app by clicking &lt;strong&gt;Run&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/images/buttons/toolbar-run.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;inline-icon&quot;/&gt;) are now more reliable. Forcing a cold swap also fixes the issue where changes to notification and widget UIs were not updated on the target device.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Includes optimizations that make app startup much faster. These optimizations may affect profiling, so you should temporarily &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/run/index.html#disable-ir&quot;&gt;disable Instant Run&lt;/a&gt; whenever profiling your app.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;AVD Manager&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/images/buttons/toolbar-avd-manager.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;inline-icon&quot;/&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;SDK Manager&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/images/buttons/toolbar-sdk-manager.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;inline-icon&quot;/&gt; buttons are now included in the lean Navigation Bar as well as the full Toolbar. To use the lean Navigation Bar, click &lt;strong&gt;View&lt;/strong&gt; to open the View menu, then ensure that &lt;strong&gt;Navigation Bar&lt;/strong&gt; is selected and &lt;strong&gt;Toolbar&lt;/strong&gt; is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; selected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/images/releases/navigationbar_sdkavd_2x.png&quot; width=&quot;757&quot;/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &quot;Hybrid&quot; debugger has been renamed to &quot;Dual&quot; debugger.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/run/rundebugconfig.html&quot;&gt;Run/Debug Configurations&lt;/a&gt; dialog, under Defaults in the left pane, the following run configuration names have changed with no behavior changes:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The JUnit name has changed to Android JUnit. If you have a project that uses JUnit run configurations, those configurations are transformed to Android JUnit run configurations the first time you open the project with Android Studio. A dialog appears to inform you of the name change.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Android Tests name has changed to Android Instrumented Tests.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/debug/am-gpu-debugger.html&quot;&gt;GPU Debugger&lt;/a&gt; has been removed from Android Studio as of version 2.3. An open-source, standalone version of the tool is now available on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/google/gapid&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Run/Debug option is no longer available when you right-click a &lt;code&gt;*.gradle build&lt;/code&gt; script.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All templates now use &lt;code&gt;ConstraintLayout&lt;/code&gt; as the default layout.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Widgets palette in the Layout Editor has been redesigned.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;This release also includes a number of bug fixes. &lt;a href=&quot;https://code.google.com/p/android/issues/list?can=1&amp;amp;q=target%3D2.3+status%3DReleased&amp;amp;colspec=ID+Status+Priority+Owner+Summary+Stars+Reporter+Opened&amp;amp;cells=tiles&quot;&gt;See all bug fixes in 2.3.0.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;note&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Known issue:&lt;/strong&gt; Some device manufacturers block apps from automatically launching after being installed on the device. When deploying your app to a physical device using Android Studio 2.3, this restriction breaks the intended behavior of Instant Run and causes the following error output: &lt;code&gt;Error: Not found; no service started&lt;/code&gt;. To avoid this issue, either &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/run/emulator.html&quot;&gt;use the emulator&lt;/a&gt; or enable automatic launching for your app in your device's settings. The proceedure for doing this is different for each device, so check the instructions provided by the manufacturer. For example, some affected Asus devices need to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.asus.com/support/faq/1013752&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot;&gt;whitelist apps using the Auto-start Manager&lt;/a&gt;. To learn more about this issue, see &lt;a href=&quot;https://code.google.com/p/android/issues/detail?id=235879&quot;&gt;Issue #235879&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-2-0&quot;&gt;2.2 (September 2016)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;updates-box&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.2.3 (December 2016)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a minor update to Android Studio 2.2. It includes a bug fixes focused around gradle, the core IDE, and lint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Highlighted build changes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;ProGuard version rollback. Due to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://sourceforge.net/p/proguard/bugs/625/&quot;&gt;correctness issue&lt;/a&gt; discovered in ProGuard 5.3.1, we have rolled back to ProGuard 5.2.1. We have worked with the ProGuard team on getting a fix quickly, and we expect to roll forward to ProGuard 5.3.2 in Android Studio 2.3 Canary 3.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bug fix for &lt;code&gt;aaptOptions&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;IgnoreAssetsPattern&lt;/code&gt; not working properly (&lt;a href=&quot;http://b.android.com/224167&quot;&gt;issue 224167&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bug fix for Gradle autodownload for Constraint Layout library (&lt;a href=&quot;https://code.google.com/p/android/issues/detail?id=212128&quot;&gt;issue 212128&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bug fix for a JDK8/Kotlin compiler + dx issue (&lt;a href=&quot;http://b.android.com/227729&quot;&gt;issue 227729&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://code.google.com/p/android/issues/list?can=1&amp;amp;q=target%3D2.2.3+status%3AReleased+&amp;amp;colspec=ID+Status+Priority+Owner+Summary+Stars+Reporter+Opened&amp;amp;cells=tiles&quot;&gt;See all bug fixes in 2.2.3&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;updates-box&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.2.2 (October 2016)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a minor update to Android Studio 2.2. It includes a number of small changes and bug fixes, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;When reporting Instant Run issues through the IDE, the report now also includes logcat output for &lt;code&gt;InstantRun&lt;/code&gt; events. To help us improve Instant Run, please &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/run/index.html#submit-feedback&quot;&gt;enable extra logging and report any issues&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A number of small bug fixes for Gradle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A fix for problems with generating multiple APKs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;updates-box&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.2.1 (October 2016)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a minor update to Android Studio 2.2. It includes several bug fixes and a new feature to enable extra logging to help us troubleshoot Instant Run issues—to help us improve Instant Run, please &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/run/index.html#submit-feedback&quot;&gt;enable extra logging and report any issues&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;New&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;youtube-wrapper attempt-right&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/NbHsi3-uR8E?autohide=1&amp;amp;showinfo=0&amp;amp;enablejsapi=1&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;All new &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/write/layout-editor.html&quot;&gt;Layout Editor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; with tools custom-built to support &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/training/constraint-layout/index.html&quot;&gt;ConstraintLayout&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://tools.android.com/tech-docs/layout-inspector&quot;&gt;Layout Inspector&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; lets you examine snapshots of your layout hierarchy while your app is running on the emulator or a device.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/write/firebase.html&quot;&gt;Assistant&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; window to help you integrate Firebase services into your app.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/build/apk-analyzer.html&quot;&gt;APK Analyzer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; tool so you can inspect the contents of your packaged app.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://tools.android.com/tech-docs/test-recorder&quot;&gt;Espresso Test Recorder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; tool (currently in beta) to help you create UI tests by recording your own interactions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://tools.android.com/tech-docs/build-cache&quot;&gt;build cache&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (currently experimental) to speed up build performance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New &lt;strong&gt;C/C++ build integration with CMake and ndk-build&lt;/strong&gt;. Compile and build new or existing native code into libraries packaged into your APK, and debug using lldb. For new projects, Android Studio uses CMake by default, but also supports ndk-build for existing projects. To learn how to include native code in your Android application, read &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/projects/add-native-code.html&quot;&gt;Add C and C++ Code to Your Project&lt;/a&gt;. To learn how to debug native code with lldb, see &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/debug/index.html#debug-native&quot;&gt;Debug Native Code&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/intro/index.html#sample-code&quot;&gt;Samples Browser&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; so you can easily look up Google Android sample code from within Android Studio to jump start app development.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New &lt;strong&gt;Merged Manifest Viewer&lt;/strong&gt; to help you diagnose how your manifest file merges with your app dependencies across project build variants.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Run&lt;/strong&gt; window now contains log messages for the current running app. Note that you can configure the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/debug/am-logcat.html&quot;&gt;logcat Monitor&lt;/a&gt; display, but not the &lt;strong&gt;Run&lt;/strong&gt; window.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/run/emulator.html&quot;&gt;Android Emulator&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; features:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Added new &lt;strong&gt;Virtual&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Sensors&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Cellular&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;gt; &lt;strong&gt;Signal Strength&lt;/strong&gt; controls.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added an &lt;strong&gt;LTE&lt;/strong&gt; option to the &lt;strong&gt;Cellular&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;gt; &lt;strong&gt;Network type&lt;/strong&gt; control.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added simulated vertical swipes for scrolling through vertical menus with a mouse wheel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/run/rundebugconfig.html&quot;&gt;Run/Debug Configuration&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; features:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Debugger&lt;/strong&gt; tab of the Android App and Android Tests templates now contain several new options for debugging with LLDB.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Profiling&lt;/strong&gt; tab of the Android App and Android Tests templates now contain a &lt;strong&gt;Capture GPU Commands&lt;/strong&gt; option for enabling GPU tracing. You can display GPU traces in the GPU Debugger (a beta feature).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Android Tests template now has a &lt;strong&gt;Firebase Test Lab Device Matrix&lt;/strong&gt; option for the &lt;strong&gt;Deployment Target&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Native Application template has been deprecated. If you use this template in a project, Android Studio automatically converts it to the Android App template.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Android Application template has been renamed to Android App.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved installation, configuration, performance, and UI features in the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/debug/am-gpu-debugger.html&quot;&gt;GPU Debugger&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (currently in beta).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Android Studio now comes bundled with &lt;strong&gt;OpenJDK 8&lt;/strong&gt;. Existing projects still use the JDK specified in &lt;strong&gt;File &amp;gt; Project Structure &amp;gt; SDK Location&lt;/strong&gt;. You can switch to use the new bundled JDK by clicking &lt;strong&gt;File &amp;gt; Project Structure &amp;gt; SDK Location&lt;/strong&gt; and checking the &lt;strong&gt;Use embedded JDK&lt;/strong&gt; checkbox.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added new &lt;strong&gt;help menus and buttons&lt;/strong&gt; in the UI so you can more easily find the online documentation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Changes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Updated the IDE codebase from IntelliJ 15 to &lt;strong&gt;IntelliJ 2016.1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Instant Run now requires the platform SDK corresponding to the target device API level to be installed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Instant Run will automatically disabled if user is running the app under a work profile or as a secondary user.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed many reliability issues for &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/run/index.html#instant-run&quot;&gt;Instant Run&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; where changes were not getting deployed or the app would crash:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Some app assets were not deployed to your running app. ( &lt;a href=&quot;http://b.android.com/213454&quot;&gt;Bug: #213454&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;App crashes when user transitions between Instant Run and non Instant Run sessions where a Serializable class does not have serialVersionUID defined. (&lt;a href=&quot;http://b.android.com/209006&quot;&gt;Bug: #209006&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Style changes aren’t reflected with Instant Run. (&lt;a href=&quot;http://b.android.com/210851&quot;&gt;Bug: #210851&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Instant Run session is unreliable and causes FileNotFoundException. (&lt;a href=&quot;http://b.android.com/213083&quot;&gt;Bug: #213083&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changes to drawables not reflected until full rebuild is performed for KitKat. (&lt;a href=&quot;http://b.android.com/215360&quot;&gt;Bug: #21530&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resource changes aren’t reflected with Instant Run when custom sourceSets contain nested paths. (&lt;a href=&quot;http://b.android.com/219145&quot;&gt;Bug: #219145&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hot and warm swap don't work if changed class contains annotation with enum value. (&lt;a href=&quot;http://b.android.com/209047&quot;&gt;Bug: #209047&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changes to annotation data not reflected with Instant Run. (&lt;a href=&quot;http://b.android.com/210089&quot;&gt;Bug: #210089&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Instant Run doesn't pick up code changes if you make changes outside the IDE. (&lt;a href=&quot;http://b.android.com/213205&quot;&gt;Bug: #213205&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Instant Run session is unreliable due to mismatch security token. (&lt;a href=&quot;http://b.android.com/211989&quot;&gt;Bug: #211989&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cold swap fails for devices that doesn’t properly support run-as. (&lt;a href=&quot;http://b.android.com/210875&quot;&gt;Bug: #210875&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;App crash after instant run restart. (&lt;a href=&quot;http://b.android.com/219744&quot;&gt;Bug: #219744&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ClassNotFoundException observed when switching from Instant Run to Instant Debug. (&lt;a href=&quot;http://b.android.com/215805&quot;&gt;Bug: #215805&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved performance for &lt;strong&gt;Gradle sync&lt;/strong&gt; within the IDE, especially for large projects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved build times for both full and incremental builds with new app packaging code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved &lt;strong&gt;Jack compiler performance and features&lt;/strong&gt;, including support for annotation processors and dexing in process. To learn more, read the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/releases/gradle-plugin.html#revisions&quot;&gt;Android plugin for Gradle 2.2.0 release notes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added an updated &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/googlesamples/android-AccelerometerPlay&quot;&gt;AccelerometerPlay&lt;/a&gt; sample so you can try out the emulator &lt;strong&gt;Accelerometer&lt;/strong&gt; control. Select &lt;strong&gt;File&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;gt; &lt;strong&gt;New&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;gt; &lt;strong&gt;Import Sample&lt;/strong&gt; to import the project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed the &lt;strong&gt;Scale&lt;/strong&gt; AVD property from the AVD Manager.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Android Emulator &lt;strong&gt;-port&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;-ports&lt;/strong&gt; command-line options now report which ports and serial number the emulator instance is using, and warn if there are any issues with the values you provided.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/write/create-java-class.html&quot;&gt;Create New Class dialog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and the corresponding file templates. &lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; If you've previously customized the &lt;strong&gt;AnnotationType&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Class&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Enum&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Interface&lt;/strong&gt;, or &lt;strong&gt;Singleton&lt;/strong&gt; file templates, you need to modify your templates to comply with the new templates or you won’t be able to use the new fields in the &lt;strong&gt;Create New Class&lt;/strong&gt; dialog.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/write/vector-asset-studio.html&quot;&gt;Vector Asset Studio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; user interface and added support for Adobe Photoshop Document (PSD) files.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/write/image-asset-studio.html&quot;&gt;Image Asset Studio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; user interface.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/write/theme-editor.html&quot;&gt;Theme Editor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;'s Resource Picker.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed memory leaks and reduced overall memory usage in Android Studio.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added a &lt;strong&gt;Background&lt;/strong&gt; button in the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/intro/update.html#sdk-manager&quot;&gt;SDK Manager&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; so you can get back to work and install your packages in the background.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/intro/accessibility.html&quot;&gt;Accessibility features&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, including support for screen readers and keyboard navigation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enhanced &lt;strong&gt;Code Analysis&lt;/strong&gt; includes code quality checks for Java 8 language usage and more cross-file analysis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Several toolbar icons have changed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-1-0&quot;&gt;2.1 (April 2016)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The primary changes in this update provide support for development with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/preview/index.html&quot;&gt;Android N Preview&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;updates-box&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.1.3 (August 2016)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This update adds compatibility with Gradle 2.14.1, which includes performance improvements, new features, and an important &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gradle.org/2.14/release-notes#local-privilege-escalation-when-using-the-daemon&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot;&gt;security fix&lt;/a&gt;. For more details, see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gradle.org/2.14.1/release-notes&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot;&gt;Gradle release notes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By default, new projects in Android Studio 2.1.3 use Gradle 2.14.1. For existing projects, the IDE prompts you to upgrade to Gradle 2.14.1 and &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/releases/gradle-plugin.html#revisions&quot;&gt;Android plugin for Gradle 2.1.3&lt;/a&gt;, which is required when using Gradle 2.14.1 and higher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;updates-box&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.1.2 (June 2016)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This update includes a number of small changes and bug fixes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/run/index.html#instant-run&quot;&gt;Instant Run&lt;/a&gt; updates and bug fixes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improvements to LLDB performance and crash notifications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed a regression in the Android Studio 2.1.1 security update that caused &lt;code&gt;git rebase&lt;/code&gt; to fail.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;updates-box&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.1.1 (May 2016)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Security release update.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Android N platform adds support for &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/write/java8-support.html&quot;&gt;Java 8 language features&lt;/a&gt;, which require a new experimental compiler called Jack. The latest version of Jack is currently supported only in Android Studio 2.1. So if you want to use Java 8 language features, you need to use Android Studio 2.1 to build your app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;note&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/tools/building/building-studio.html#instant-run&quot;&gt;Instant Run&lt;/a&gt; is disabled when you enable the Jack compiler because they currently are not compatible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although Android Studio 2.1 is now stable, the Jack compiler is still experimental and you must enable it with &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/preview/j8-jack.html#configuration&quot;&gt;the &lt;code&gt;jackOptions&lt;/code&gt; property&lt;/a&gt; in your &lt;code&gt;build.gradle&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other than the changes to support the N Preview, Android Studio 2.1 includes minor bug fixes and the following enhancements:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;prettyprint notranslate&quot; translate=&quot;no&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;The Java-aware C++ debugger is now enabled by default when you're
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;using an N device or emulator and select &lt;strong&gt;Native&lt;/strong&gt; debugger mode (in the &lt;strong&gt;Debugger&lt;/strong&gt; tab for your run/debug configuration).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For other build enhancements, including incremental Java compilation and dexing-in-process,update your &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/tools/revisions/gradle-plugin.html&quot;&gt;Android plugin for Gradle&lt;/a&gt; to version 2.1.0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-0-0&quot;&gt;2.0 (April 2016)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;note&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; If you are developing for the N Developer Preview, you should use Android Studio 2.1 Preview. Android Studio 2.0 does not support all the features required to target the N Preview. To learn more, read about how to properly &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/preview/setup-sdk.html&quot;&gt;set up your developer environment&lt;/a&gt; for the N Preview.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Instant Run&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Android Studio now deploys clean builds faster than ever before. Additionally, pushing incremental code changes to the emulator or a physical device is now almost instantaneous. Review your updates without redeploying a new debug build or, in many cases, without restarting the app.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Instant Run supports pushing the following changes to a running app:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Changes to the implementation of an existing instance method or static method&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changes to an existing app resource&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changes to structural code, such as a method signature or a static field (requires a target device running API level 21 or higher).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read the documentation to learn more &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/tools/building/building-studio.html#instant-run&quot;&gt;about Instant Run&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;p class=&quot;note&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; Instant Run is supported only when you deploy the debug build variant, use &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/tools/revisions/gradle-plugin.html#revisions&quot;&gt;Android plugin for Gradle version 2.0.0&lt;/a&gt; or higher, and configure your app's module-level &lt;code&gt;build.gradle&lt;/code&gt; file for &lt;code&gt;minSdkVersion 15&lt;/code&gt; or higher. For the best performance, configure your app for &lt;code&gt;minSdkVersion 21&lt;/code&gt; or higher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New additions to Lint:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Inspection of &lt;code&gt;switch&lt;/code&gt; statements using &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/reference/android/support/annotation/IntDef.html&quot;&gt;@IntDef&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt; annotated integers to make sure all constants are handled. To quickly add any missing statements, use the intention action drop-down menu and select &lt;strong&gt;Add Missing @IntDef Constants&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flags for incorrect attempts to use string interpolation to insert version numbers in the &lt;code&gt;build.gradle&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flags for anonymous classes that extend the &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/reference/android/app/Fragment.html&quot;&gt;Fragment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt; class.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flags for native code in unsafe locations, such as the &lt;code&gt;res/&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;asset/&lt;/code&gt; folders. This flag encourages storing native code in the &lt;code&gt;libs/&lt;/code&gt; folder, which is then securely packaged into the application’s &lt;code&gt;data/app-lib/&lt;/code&gt; folder at install time. &lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;https://android-review.googlesource.com/#/c/169950/&quot;&gt;AOSP: #169950&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flags for unsafe calls to &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/reference/java/lang/Runtime.html#load(java.lang.String)&quot;&gt;Runtime.load()&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/reference/java/lang/System.html#load(java.lang.String)&quot;&gt;System.load()&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt; calls. &lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;https://android-review.googlesource.com/#/c/179980/&quot;&gt;AOSP: #179980&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find and remove any unused resources by selecting &lt;strong&gt;Refactor &amp;gt; Remove Unused Resources&lt;/strong&gt; from the menu bar. Unused resource detection now supports resources only referenced by unused resources, references in raw files such as &lt;code&gt;.html&lt;/code&gt; image references, and &lt;code&gt;tools:keep&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;tools:discard&lt;/code&gt; attributes used by the Gradle resource shrinker, while considering inactive source sets (such as resources used in other build flavors) and properly handling static field imports.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Checks that implicit API references are supported on all platforms targeted by &lt;code&gt;minSdkVersion&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flags improper usage of &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/reference/android/support/v7/widget/RecyclerView.html&quot;&gt;RecyclerView&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/reference/android/os/Parcelable.html&quot;&gt;Parcelable&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/reference/android/support/annotation/IntDef.html&quot;&gt;@IntDef&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/reference/android/support/annotation/IntRange.html&quot;&gt;@IntRange&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/reference/android/support/annotation/Size.html&quot;&gt;@Size&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt; inspections are now also checked for &lt;code&gt;int&lt;/code&gt; arrays and varargs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Additional Improvements&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Optimized for Android Emulator 2.0, which is faster than ever before, supports a wider range of virtual devices, and features a drastically improved UI. To learn more about the new emulator, read the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/releases/sdk-tools.html#notes&quot;&gt;SDK Tools release notes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improvements to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/tools/devices/managing-avds.html&quot;&gt;Android Virtual Device Manager&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;System images are now categorized under the following tabs: &lt;em&gt;Recommended&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;x86&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Other&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Under advanced settings, you can enable multi-core support and specify the number of cores the emulator can use.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Under advanced settings, you can determine how graphics are rendered on the emulator by selecting one of the following options:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hardware:&lt;/strong&gt; use you computer's graphics card for faster rendering.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Software:&lt;/strong&gt; use software-based rendering.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Auto:&lt;/strong&gt; let the emulator decide the best option. This is the default setting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved AAPT packaging times by specifying deploy target before the app is built. This allows Android Studio to efficiently package only the resources required by the specified device.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added Cloud Test Lab integration to provide on-demand app testing with the convenience and scalability of a cloud service. Learn more about how you can &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/training/testing/start/index.html#run-ctl&quot;&gt;use Cloud Test Lab with Android Studio&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added a preview of the new &lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;https://tools.android.com/tech-docs/gpu-profiler&quot;&gt;GPU Debugger&lt;/a&gt;. For graphics intensive applications, you can now visually step through your OpenGL ES code to optimize your app or game.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added Google App Indexing Test. Add support for URLs, app indexing, and search functionality to your apps to help drive more traffic to your app, discover which app content is used most, and attract new users. Test and validate URLs in your app all within Android Studio. See &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/tools/help/app-link-indexing.html&quot;&gt;Supporting URLs and App Indexing in Android Studio&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upgrades from the latest IntelliJ 15 release, including improved code analysis and performance. See &lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.jetbrains.com/idea/whatsnew&quot;&gt;What's New in IntelliJ&lt;/a&gt; for a complete description of the new features and enhancements.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;XML editor auto-complete now adds quotations marks when completing attributes. To check if this option is enabled, open the &lt;strong&gt;Setting&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;Preferences&lt;/strong&gt; dialogue, navigate to &lt;strong&gt;Editor &amp;gt; General &amp;gt; Smart Keys&lt;/strong&gt;, and check the box next to &lt;strong&gt;Add quotes for attribute value on attribute completion&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;https://b.android.com/195113&quot;&gt;Issue: 195113&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The XML editor now supports code completion for &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/topic/libraries/data-binding/index.html#layout_details&quot;&gt;data binding&lt;/a&gt; expressions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;older-releases&quot;&gt;Older Releases&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;toggle-content closed&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/releases/index.html#&quot; onclick=&quot;return toggleContent(this)&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://developer.android.com/assets/images/styles/disclosure_down.png&quot; class=&quot;toggle-content-img&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;Android Studio v1.5.1&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;(December 2015)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;toggle-content-toggleme&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fixes and enhancements:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fixed a rendering failure issue in the Layout Editor. &lt;a href=&quot;http://b.android.com/194612&quot;&gt;Issue: 194612&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added the ability to vary &lt;code&gt;description&lt;/code&gt; manifest attributes by configuration. &lt;a href=&quot;http://b.android.com/194705&quot;&gt;Issue: 194705&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved the contrast of the Android Studio Darcula appearance theme in Vector Asset Studio. &lt;a href=&quot;http://b.android.com/191819&quot;&gt;Issue: 191819&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added &lt;em&gt;Help&lt;/em&gt; button support to Vector Asset Studio.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added support for the &lt;code&gt;%&lt;/code&gt; operator for data binding. &lt;a href=&quot;http://b.android.com/194045&quot;&gt;Issue: 194045&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed a case where launching an app for debugging resulted in the debugger connecting to the wrong device. &lt;a href=&quot;http://b.android.com/195167&quot;&gt;Issue: 195167&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed a null pointer exception that could occur when attempting to run an app in certain scenarios.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;toggle-content closed&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/releases/index.html#&quot; onclick=&quot;return toggleContent(this)&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://developer.android.com/assets/images/styles/disclosure_down.png&quot; class=&quot;toggle-content-img&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;Android Studio v1.5.0&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;(November 2015)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;toggle-content-toggleme&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fixes and enhancements:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Added new Memory Monitor analysis abilities to Android Monitor. When you view an HPROF file captured from this monitor, the display is now more helpful so you can more quickly locate problems, such as memory leaks. To use this monitor, click &lt;strong&gt;Android Monitor&lt;/strong&gt; at the bottom of the main window. In Android Monitor, click the &lt;strong&gt;Memory&lt;/strong&gt; tab. While the monitor is running, click the &lt;strong&gt;Dump Java Heap&lt;/strong&gt; icon, and then click &lt;strong&gt;Captures&lt;/strong&gt; in the main window and double-click the file to view it. Click &lt;em&gt;Capture Analysis&lt;/em&gt; on the right. (The Android Device Monitor can't be running at the same time as Android Monitor.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added new deep link and app link support. The Code Editor can automatically create an intent filter for deep linking in the &lt;code&gt;AndroidManifest.xml&lt;/code&gt; file. It can also generate code to help you integrate with the &lt;a href=&quot;http://developers.google.com/app-indexing/android/publish&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot;&gt;App Indexing API&lt;/a&gt; in an activity in a Java file. A deep link testing feature helps you verify that a specified deep link can launch an app. In the &lt;strong&gt;General&lt;/strong&gt; tab of the &lt;em&gt;Run/Debug Configurations&lt;/em&gt; dialog, you can specify deep link launch options. You can also test App Indexing API calls in an activity by using the Android Monitor &lt;strong&gt;logcat&lt;/strong&gt; display. The Android &lt;code&gt;lint&lt;/code&gt; tool now has warnings for certain issues involving deep links and the App Indexing API.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added the ability to use short names when code-completing custom views in the Code Editor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added support for more &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/reference/android/graphics/drawable/VectorDrawable.html&quot;&gt;VectorDrawable&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt; elements to &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/tools/help/vector-asset-studio.html&quot;&gt;Vector Asset Studio&lt;/a&gt; for backward-compatibility. Vector Asset Studio can use these elements to convert vector drawables into PNG raster images to use with Android 4.4 (API level 20) and lower.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added new &lt;code&gt;lint&lt;/code&gt; checks for Android TV and Android Auto to give you immediate, actionable feedback in Android Studio, along with several quick fixes. For example, for Android TV, it can report and provide a quick fix for permissions, unsupported hardware, &lt;code&gt;uses-feature&lt;/code&gt; element, and missing banner issues. For Android Auto, it can validate the correct usage in the descriptor file referred from your &lt;code&gt;AndroidManifest.xml&lt;/code&gt; file, report if there isn't an intent filter for the &lt;code&gt;MediaBrowserService&lt;/code&gt; class, and identify certain voice actions issues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added new &lt;code&gt;lint&lt;/code&gt; checks for insecure broadcast receivers, &lt;code&gt;SSLCertificateSocketFactory&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;HostnameVerifier&lt;/code&gt; class uses, and &lt;code&gt;File.setReadable()&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;File.setWritable()&lt;/code&gt; calls. It also detects invalid manifest resource lookups, especially for resources that vary by configuration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed a number of stability issues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;toggle-content closed&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/releases/index.html#&quot; onclick=&quot;return toggleContent(this)&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://developer.android.com/assets/images/styles/disclosure_down.png&quot; class=&quot;toggle-content-img&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;Android Studio v1.4.1&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;(October 2015)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;toggle-content-toggleme&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fixes and enhancements:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fixed a Gradle model caching issue that could lead to excessive Gradle syncing when the IDE was restarted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed a native debugging deadlock issue.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed an issue blocking users of the Subversion 1.9 version control system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed a &lt;em&gt;Device Chooser&lt;/em&gt; dialog problem where after connecting a device that was unauthorized you could no longer select the emulator. &lt;a href=&quot;http://b.android.com/189658&quot;&gt;Issue: 189658&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed incorrect translation error reporting for locales that have a region qualifier and a translation in the region (but not in the base locale). &lt;a href=&quot;http://b.android.com/188577&quot;&gt;Issue: 188577&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed a deadlock issue in the Theme Editor related to its interaction with the Layout Editor. &lt;a href=&quot;http://b.android.com/188070&quot;&gt;Issue: 188070&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed a Theme Editor reload and edit conflict causing attributes to not properly update. &lt;a href=&quot;http://b.android.com/187726&quot;&gt;Issue: 187726&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved Theme Editor performance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed an issue where the &lt;code&gt;android:required&lt;/code&gt; attribute was ignored in the manifest. &lt;a href=&quot;http://b.android.com/187665&quot;&gt;Issue: 187665&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;toggle-content closed&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/releases/index.html#&quot; onclick=&quot;return toggleContent(this)&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://developer.android.com/assets/images/styles/disclosure_down.png&quot; class=&quot;toggle-content-img&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;Android Studio v1.4.0&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;(September 2015)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;toggle-content-toggleme&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fixes and enhancements:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Added the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/tools/help/vector-asset-studio.html&quot;&gt;Vector Asset Studio&lt;/a&gt; tool for importing vector graphics, such as material icons and SVG files. To use this tool, in the Android view of the Project window, right-click the &lt;strong&gt;res&lt;/strong&gt; folder and select &lt;strong&gt;New&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;gt; &lt;strong&gt;Vector Asset&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added new Android Monitor functions, GPU and Network. To use these monitors, click &lt;strong&gt;Android Monitor&lt;/strong&gt; at the bottom of the main window. The Android Device Monitor can't be running at the same time as Android Monitor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added an early preview of the new Theme Editor. To use this feature, select &lt;strong&gt;Tools&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;gt; &lt;strong&gt;Android&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;gt; &lt;strong&gt;Theme Editor&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated the Android templates for the Design Support Library. Templates now include support for the Material Design specification, as well as the &lt;code&gt;appcompat&lt;/code&gt; Support Library for backwards compatibility.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;toggle-content closed&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/releases/index.html#&quot; onclick=&quot;return toggleContent(this)&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://developer.android.com/assets/images/styles/disclosure_down.png&quot; class=&quot;toggle-content-img&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;Android Studio v1.3.2&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;(August 2015)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;toggle-content-toggleme&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fixes and enhancements:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Added support for Android 6.0 (API level 23), including new icons and AVD Manager support for creating devices with new screen densities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed an exception that was occurring during update checks. &lt;a href=&quot;http://b.android.com/183068&quot;&gt;Issue: 183068&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed problem where unresolved view coordinates could cause the layout editor to crash. &lt;a href=&quot;http://b.android.com/178690&quot;&gt;Issue: 178690&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed issue with invalid resource type warnings. &lt;a href=&quot;http://b.android.com/182433&quot;&gt;Issue: 182433&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed lint check that was incorrectly flagging resources as private. &lt;a href=&quot;http://b.android.com/183120&quot;&gt;Issue: 183120&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;toggle-content closed&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/releases/index.html#&quot; onclick=&quot;return toggleContent(this)&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://developer.android.com/assets/images/styles/disclosure_down.png&quot; class=&quot;toggle-content-img&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;Android Studio v1.3.1&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;(August 2015)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;toggle-content-toggleme&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fixes and enhancements:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fixed support for creating an Android Wear Android Virtual Device (AVD) on Windows.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated the &lt;em&gt;Project Wizard&lt;/em&gt; to use the entered project name.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added support to allow the Android SDK to be stored in a read-only directory.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated Android plugin for Gradle version to 1.3.0.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed issues with launching a debug session from the Android Debug Bridge (adb) Unix shell.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed the Java package renaming message to show the correct package name.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;toggle-content closed&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/releases/index.html#&quot; onclick=&quot;return toggleContent(this)&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://developer.android.com/assets/images/styles/disclosure_down.png&quot; class=&quot;toggle-content-img&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;Android Studio v1.3.0&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;(July 2015)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;toggle-content-toggleme&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fixes and enhancements:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Added options to enable &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/tools/studio/studio-features.html#dev-services&quot;&gt;developer services&lt;/a&gt;, such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/admob/&quot;&gt;AdMob&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/distribute/analyze/start.html&quot;&gt;Analytics&lt;/a&gt;, in your app from within Android Studio.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added additional &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/tools/debugging/annotations.html&quot;&gt;annotations&lt;/a&gt;, such as &lt;code&gt;@RequiresPermission&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;@CheckResults&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;@MainThread&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added the capability to generate Java heap dumps and analyze thread allocations from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/tools/studio/index.html#mem-cpu&quot;&gt;Memory Monitor&lt;/a&gt;. You can also convert Android-specific HPROF binary format files to standard HPROF format from within Android Studio.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integrated the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/tools/help/sdk-manager.html&quot;&gt;SDK Manager&lt;/a&gt; into Android Studio to simplify package and tools access and provide update notifications.
&lt;p class=&quot;note&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; The standalone SDK Manager is still available from the command line, but is recommended for use only with standalone SDK installations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added the &lt;code&gt;finger&lt;/code&gt; command in the emulator console to simulate &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/tools/studio/studio-features.html#finger-print&quot;&gt;fingerprint&lt;/a&gt; authentication.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added a &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;public&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; resource declaration to designate library resources as &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/tools/studio/studio-features.html#private-res&quot;&gt;public and private&lt;/a&gt; resources.
&lt;p class=&quot;note&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; Requires &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/tools/building/plugin-for-gradle.html&quot;&gt;Android plugin for Gradle&lt;/a&gt; version 1.3 or higher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/tools/data-binding/guide.html&quot;&gt;data binding&lt;/a&gt; support to create declarative layouts that bind your application logic to layout elements.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added support for a separate &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/tools/studio/studio-features.html#test-module&quot;&gt;test APK module&lt;/a&gt; to build test APKs in Android Studio.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/tools/devices/managing-avds.html&quot;&gt;AVD Manager&lt;/a&gt; with HAXM optimizations and improved notifications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added 64-bit ARM and MIPS emulator support for &lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;http://wiki.qemu.org/Main_Page&quot;&gt;QEMU&lt;/a&gt; 2.1.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simplified the resolution of Lint warnings by adding quick fixes, such as the automatic generation of &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/reference/android/os/Parcelable.html&quot;&gt;Parcelable&lt;/a&gt; implementation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added live template support for quick insertion of code snippets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;toggle-content closed&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/releases/index.html#&quot; onclick=&quot;return toggleContent(this)&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://developer.android.com/assets/images/styles/disclosure_down.png&quot; class=&quot;toggle-content-img&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;Android Studio v1.2.2&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;(June 2015)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;toggle-content-toggleme&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fixes and enhancements:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fixed build issues that were blocking builds from completing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;toggle-content closed&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/releases/index.html#&quot; onclick=&quot;return toggleContent(this)&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://developer.android.com/assets/images/styles/disclosure_down.png&quot; class=&quot;toggle-content-img&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;Android Studio v1.2.1&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;(May 2015)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;toggle-content-toggleme&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fixes and enhancements:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fixed minor performance and feature issues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;toggle-content closed&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/releases/index.html#&quot; onclick=&quot;return toggleContent(this)&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://developer.android.com/assets/images/styles/disclosure_down.png&quot; class=&quot;toggle-content-img&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;Android Studio v1.2.0&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;(April 2015)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;toggle-content-toggleme&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fixes and enhancements:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Updated the Android runtime window to include the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/tools/studio/index.html#mem-cpu&quot;&gt;Memory Monitor&lt;/a&gt; tool and added a tab for CPU performance monitoring.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added a &lt;em&gt;Captures&lt;/em&gt; tab in the left margin to display the captured memory and CPU performance data files, such as CPU method tracking and memory heap snapshots.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expanded &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/tools/debugging/annotations.html&quot;&gt;annotation&lt;/a&gt; support with additional metadata annotations and inferred nullability.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enhanced the Translations Editor with additional support for Best Current Practice (BCP) 47, which uses 3-letter language and region codes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integrated IntelliJ 14 and 14.1 features for improved code analysis and performance:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Enhanced debugging to show inline values for variables and referring objects, as well as perform inline evaluation of lambda and operator expressions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added code style detection for tab and indent sizes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added scratch files for code experiments and prototyping without project files.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added the simultaneous insertion of opening and closing tags in HTML and XML files.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added a built-in Java class decompiler so you can look at what’s inside a library for which the source code is not available.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.jetbrains.com/idea/whatsnew&quot;&gt;What's New in IntelliJ&lt;/a&gt; for a complete description of the new features and enhancements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added additional &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/tools/studio/index.html#project-view&quot;&gt;Project Views&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;em&gt;Scratches&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Project Files&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Problems&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Production&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Tests&lt;/em&gt; to enhance project management and access.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enhanced the &lt;strong&gt;File &amp;gt; Settings&lt;/strong&gt; menu and dialogs for improved settings access and management.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added support for high-density displays for Windows and Linux.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added support for 280 dpi resources in the &lt;code&gt;res/drawable-280dpi/&lt;/code&gt; folder.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;toggle-content closed&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/releases/index.html#&quot; onclick=&quot;return toggleContent(this)&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://developer.android.com/assets/images/styles/disclosure_down.png&quot; class=&quot;toggle-content-img&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;Android Studio v1.1.0&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;(February 2015)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;toggle-content-toggleme&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Various fixes and enhancements:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Added support for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/design/wear/index.html&quot;&gt;Android Wear&lt;/a&gt; watch template.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Modified new project and module creation to include &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/tools/projects/index.html#mipmap&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;res/mipmap&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; folders for density-specific launcher icons. These &lt;code&gt;res/mipmap&lt;/code&gt; folders replace the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/guide/topics/resources/drawable-resource.html&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;res/drawable&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; folders for launcher icons.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated launcher icons to have a &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/design/material/index.html&quot;&gt;Material Design&lt;/a&gt; look and added an &lt;code&gt;xxxhdpi&lt;/code&gt; launcher icon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added and enhanced Lint checks for region and language combinations, launcher icons, resource names, and other common code problems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added support for Best Current Practice (BCP) language tag 47.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;toggle-content closed&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/releases/index.html#&quot; onclick=&quot;return toggleContent(this)&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://developer.android.com/assets/images/styles/disclosure_down.png&quot; class=&quot;toggle-content-img&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;Android Studio v1.0.1&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;(December 2014)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;toggle-content-toggleme&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Various fixes and enhancements:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fixed AVD Manager and &lt;strong&gt;device.xml&lt;/strong&gt; file lock issue.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed the emulator log on Windows systems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed issue with creating AVDs with Android Studio and Android SDK installed on different drives on Windows systems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sets the default update channel for new downloads to &lt;strong&gt;Stable&lt;/strong&gt;. If you installed the 1.0.0 version of Android Studio and would like stable, production-ready version updates, use &lt;strong&gt;File &amp;gt; Settings &amp;gt; Updates&lt;/strong&gt; to change to the &lt;strong&gt;Stable&lt;/strong&gt; update channel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;toggle-content closed&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/releases/index.html#&quot; onclick=&quot;return toggleContent(this)&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://developer.android.com/assets/images/styles/disclosure_down.png&quot; class=&quot;toggle-content-img&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;Android Studio v1.0&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;(December 2014)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;toggle-content-toggleme&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initial release of Android Studio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;toggle-content closed&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/releases/index.html#&quot; onclick=&quot;return toggleContent(this)&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://developer.android.com/assets/images/styles/disclosure_down.png&quot; class=&quot;toggle-content-img&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;Android Studio v0.8.14&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;(October 2014)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;toggle-content-toggleme&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&quot;http://tools.android.com/recent/androidstudio0814inbetachannel&quot;&gt;tools.android.com&lt;/a&gt; for a full list of changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;toggle-content closed&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/releases/index.html#&quot; onclick=&quot;return toggleContent(this)&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://developer.android.com/assets/images/styles/disclosure_down.png&quot; class=&quot;toggle-content-img&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;Android Studio v0.8.6&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;(August 2014)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;toggle-content-toggleme&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&quot;http://tools.android.com/recent&quot;&gt;tools.android.com&lt;/a&gt; for a full list of changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;toggle-content closed&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/releases/index.html#&quot; onclick=&quot;return toggleContent(this)&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://developer.android.com/assets/images/styles/disclosure_down.png&quot; class=&quot;toggle-content-img&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;Android Studio v0.8.0&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;(June 2014)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;toggle-content-toggleme&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Added support for Android Wear projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&quot;http://tools.android.com/recent&quot;&gt;tools.android.com&lt;/a&gt; for a full list of changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;toggle-content closed&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/releases/index.html#&quot; onclick=&quot;return toggleContent(this)&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://developer.android.com/assets/images/styles/disclosure_down.png&quot; class=&quot;toggle-content-img&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;Android Studio v0.5.2&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;(May 2014)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;toggle-content closed&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/releases/index.html#&quot; onclick=&quot;return toggleContent(this)&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://developer.android.com/assets/images/styles/disclosure_down.png&quot; class=&quot;toggle-content-img&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;Android Studio v0.4.6&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;(March 2014)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;toggle-content closed&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/releases/index.html#&quot; onclick=&quot;return toggleContent(this)&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://developer.android.com/assets/images/styles/disclosure_down.png&quot; class=&quot;toggle-content-img&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;Android Studio v0.4.2&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;(Jan 2014)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;toggle-content closed&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/releases/index.html#&quot; onclick=&quot;return toggleContent(this)&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://developer.android.com/assets/images/styles/disclosure_down.png&quot; class=&quot;toggle-content-img&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;Android Studio v0.3.2&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;(Oct 2013)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;toggle-content closed&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/releases/index.html#&quot; onclick=&quot;return toggleContent(this)&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://developer.android.com/assets/images/styles/disclosure_down.png&quot; class=&quot;toggle-content-img&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;Android Studio v0.2.x&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;(July 2013)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;toggle-content-toggleme&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Merged in the latest IntelliJ codebase changes. Includes fixes for issues reported by Studio users such as tweaks to Linux font sizes and font rendering.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Android Gradle plug-in updated to 0.5.0.
&lt;p class=&quot;caution&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Caution:&lt;/strong&gt; This new version is not backwards compatible. When opening a project that uses an older version of the plug-in, Studio will show an error stating &lt;strong&gt;Gradle &amp;lt;project_name&amp;gt; project refresh failed.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The updated Gradle plug-in includes the following changes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fixed IDE model to contain the output file even if it's customized through the DSL. Also fixed the DSL to get/set the output file on the variant object so that it's not necessary to use &lt;code&gt;variant.packageApplication or variant.zipAlign&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed dependency resolution so that we resolved the combination of (default config, build types, flavor(s)) together instead of separately.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed dependency for tests of library project to properly include all the dependencies of the library itself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed case where two dependencies have the same leaf name.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed issue where Proguard rules file cannot be applied on flavors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;All Gradle plugin release notes are available are here: &lt;a href=&quot;http://tools.android.com/tech-docs/new-build-system&quot;&gt;http://tools.android.com/tech-docs/new-build-system&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gradle errors from aapt no longer point to merged output files in the build/ folder, they point back to the real source locations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Parallel Builds. It's now possible to use Gradle's parallel builds. Please be aware that parallel builds are in &quot;incubation&quot; (see &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gradle.org/docs/current/userguide/gradle_command_line.html&quot;&gt;Gradle's documentation&lt;/a&gt;.) This feature is off by default. To enable it, go to &lt;strong&gt;Preferences&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;gt; &lt;strong&gt;Compiler&lt;/strong&gt; and check the box &lt;em&gt;Compile independent modules in parallel&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Further work on the new resource repository used for layout rendering, resource folding in the editor, and more:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Basic support for .aar library dependencies (e.g. using a library without a local copy of the sources). Still not working for resource XML validation and navigation in source editors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cycle detection in resource references.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quick Documentation (F1), which can show all translations of the string under the caret, will now also show all resource overlays from the various Gradle flavors and build types, as well as libraries. They are listed in reverse resource overlay order, with strikethrough on the versions of the string that are masked.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixes to handle updating the merged resources when the set of module dependencies change.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;XML rendering fixes to properly handle character entity declarations and XML and unicode escapes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Save screenshot support for the layout preview and layout editor windows.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Template bug fixes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lint bug fixes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Various fixes for crash reports. Thank you, and keep filing crash reports!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;toggle-content closed&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/releases/index.html#&quot; onclick=&quot;return toggleContent(this)&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://developer.android.com/assets/images/styles/disclosure_down.png&quot; class=&quot;toggle-content-img&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;Android Studio v0.1.x&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;(May 2013)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;toggle-content-toggleme&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Various bug fixes, including a fix for a common Windows installation issue.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;Troubleshooting&quot;&gt;Troubleshooting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you encounter problems in Android Studio, check the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/known-issues.html&quot;&gt;Known Issues&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/troubleshoot.html&quot;&gt;Troubleshoot page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;footer class=&quot;devsite-footer-promos nocontent&quot;&gt;&lt;nav class=&quot;devsite-full-site-width&quot;/&gt;&lt;/footer&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;dac-toast-group&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;dac-toast&quot; data-toast=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;dac-toast-wrap&quot;&gt;This site uses cookies to store your preferences for site-specific language and display options. &lt;button class=&quot;dac-toast-close-btn&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dac-button dac-raised dac-primary&quot;&gt;OK&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div data-modal=&quot;newsletter&quot; data-newsletter-fb=&quot;&quot; data-swap=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;dac-modal newsletter&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;dac-modal-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;dac-modal-window&quot;&gt;
&lt;header class=&quot;dac-modal-header&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;dac-swap&quot; data-swap-container=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;dac-swap-section dac-active dac-down&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;norule dac-modal-header-title&quot; data-t=&quot;newsletter.title&quot;&gt;Get the latest Android developer news and tips that will help you find success on Google Play.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;dac-modal-header-subtitle&quot; data-t=&quot;newsletter.requiredHint&quot;&gt;* Required Fields&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section class=&quot;dac-swap-section dac-up&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;norule dac-modal-header-title&quot; data-t=&quot;newsletter.successTitle&quot;&gt;Hooray!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/header&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;dac-swap&quot; data-swap-container=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;dac-swap-section dac-active dac-left&quot;&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section class=&quot;dac-swap-section dac-right&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;dac-modal-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;newsletter-success-message&quot; data-t=&quot;newsletter.successDetails&quot;&gt;You have successfully signed up for the latest Android developer news and tips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div data-modal=&quot;langform&quot; class=&quot;dac-modal&quot; id=&quot;langform&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;dac-modal-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;dac-modal-window&quot;&gt;
&lt;header class=&quot;dac-modal-header&quot;&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;dac-swap-section dac-active dac-down&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;norule dac-modal-header-title&quot;&gt;Browse this site in ?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/header&gt;&lt;section class=&quot;dac-swap-section dac-active dac-left&quot;&gt;&lt;section class=&quot;dac-modal-content&quot;&gt;&lt;fieldset class=&quot;dac-form-fieldset&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;cols&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col-2of2 langform-leftCol&quot;&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;resetLangText&quot;&gt;You requested a page in , but your language preference for this site is .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;resetLangCta&quot;&gt;Would you like to change your language preference and browse this site in ? If you want to change your language preference later, use the language menu at the bottom of each page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/fieldset&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;footer class=&quot;dac-modal-footer&quot; id=&quot;langfooter&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/releases/index.html#&quot; class=&quot;yes&quot; onclick=&quot;return false;&quot;&gt;&lt;button class=&quot;button dac-primary dac-modal-action lang yes&quot; data-t=&quot;newsletter.resetLangButtonYes&quot; data-modal-toggle=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/releases/index.html#&quot; class=&quot;yes&quot; onclick=&quot;return false;&quot;&gt;Change Language&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/releases/index.html#&quot; class=&quot;&quot; onclick=&quot;return false;&quot;&gt;&lt;button class=&quot;button dac-primary dac-modal-action lang no&quot; data-t=&quot;newsletter.resetLangButtonNo&quot; data-modal-toggle=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/studio/releases/index.html#&quot; class=&quot;&quot; onclick=&quot;return false;&quot;&gt;Not Now &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/footer&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 10:11:44 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>satysin</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://developer.android.com/studio/releases/index.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Many junior scientists need to take a hard look at their job prospects</title>
<link>http://www.nature.com/news/many-junior-scientists-need-to-take-a-hard-look-at-their-job-prospects-1.22879</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.nature.com/news/many-junior-scientists-need-to-take-a-hard-look-at-their-job-prospects-1.22879</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;img img-middle&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-content cleared&quot; readability=&quot;34&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.nature.com/polopoly_fs/7.47285.1508840645!/image/WEB_GettyImages-590968542.jpg_gen/derivatives/landscape_630/WEB_GettyImages-590968542.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;David Williams/Corbis/Getty&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Most PhD students will have to look beyond academia for a career.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For his 2012 PhD thesis, the sociologist Chris Platts surveyed and interviewed more than 300 young footballers — aged 17 and 18 — at UK club academies who were hoping to pursue a career in the game. He told the newspaper &lt;em&gt;The Guardian&lt;/em&gt; this month that just four of them currently have gained a professional contract. That’s a drop-out rate of 99%. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For our Careers section this week, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/uidfinder/10.1038/nj7677-549a&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nature&lt;/em&gt; surveyed more than 5,700 early-career scientists&lt;/a&gt; worldwide who are working on PhDs. Three-quarters of them, they told us, think it’s likely that they will pursue an academic career when they graduate, just like Platts — now a senior lecturer in sport development and sport business management at Sheffield Hallam University, UK. How many will succeed?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Statistics say these young researchers will have a better chance of pursuing their chosen job than the young footballers. But not by much. Global figures are hard to come by, but only three or four in every hundred PhD students in the United Kingdom will land a permanent staff position at a university. It’s only a little better in the United States. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply put, most PhD students need to make plans for a life outside academic science. And more universities and PhD supervisors must make this clear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That might sound like an alarmist and negative attitude for the International Weekly Journal of Science. But it has been evident for years that international science is training many more PhD students than the academic system can support. Most of the keen and talented young scientists who responded to our survey will probably never get a foot in the door. Of those who do, a sizeable number are likely to drift from short-term contract to short-term contract until they become disillusioned and look elsewhere. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As &lt;em&gt;Nature&lt;/em&gt; has said before, it is good for PhD students and postdocs to pursue careers outside academia. Many will find similar challenges and rewards in industry. And it is surely of benefit to science and society at large that a sizeable number of well-educated and well-trained scientists spread to other sectors, and take with them healthy scepticism and respect for evidence. It is certainly better for young scientists to take a realistic view early in their career path, when they still have time to adjust their ambitions. So why do people in science still see this reality as a dirty secret?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;pullquote pullquote-left&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;pullquote-sleeve&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s not just undergraduates who benefit from a variety of possibilities.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our survey, for example, shows that one-third of respondents do not have useful conversations about careers with their PhD supervisors. And non-academic jobs are low on the agenda when future options are discussed. Almost one-third of the students disagreed or strongly disagreed with the statement that their supervisor has useful advice for non-academic careers. That’s about the same as was reported in &lt;em&gt;Nature&lt;/em&gt;’s previous PhD survey, in 2015. If you supervise a PhD student or know someone who does, then please help to shrink that number by the time the next survey goes out, in 2019. Supervisors are busy people but they are often the face of the university and the academic system for students, and so the most obvious place to seek guidance. At the very least, they should be willing to point students towards the university careers service, which should also focus more on options outside academia. It’s not just undergraduates who benefit from a variety of possibilities. Indeed, postgraduates arguably need more attention and advice because so many people — including themselves — believe that they are now on a path to a professorship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another major point worth making from the 2017 survey is about mental health. More than one-quarter of the students who responded listed mental health as an area of concern, and 45% of those said they had sought help for anxiety or depression caused by their PhD. One-third of those got useful help from their institution (which of course means that two-thirds did not). Still, just 5% said no help was available there or elsewhere, which, given the general difficulty in accessing mental-health support in many countries, suggests that young people in the education system are perhaps better served than many outside it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the outlook for junior scientists in academia is mixed, then, luckily for science, most don’t seem to let it put them off. Indeed, it’s striking to note that nearly eight in ten of the young scientists surveyed said they were satisfied with their decision to start a PhD. That reflects well on the excellent opportunities, facilities and supervision that many receive. Just like the footballers, some will succeed, and they will find a career in academic science to be as thrilling, rewarding and satisfying as they hope. But someone needs to tell the rest what happens next.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 07:58:29 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>sz4kerto</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Many junior scientists need to take a hard look at their job prospects</og:title>
<og:description>Permanent jobs in academia are scarce, and someone needs to let PhD students know.</og:description>
<og:url>http://www.nature.com/news/many-junior-scientists-need-to-take-a-hard-look-at-their-job-prospects-1.22879</og:url>
<og:image>http://www.nature.com/polopoly_fs/7.47285.1508840645!/image/WEB_GettyImages-590968542.jpg_gen/derivatives/nature_homepage/WEB_GettyImages-590968542.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.nature.com/news/many-junior-scientists-need-to-take-a-hard-look-at-their-job-prospects-1.22879</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Introducing Amazon EC2 P3 Instances</title>
<link>https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2017/10/introducing-amazon-ec2-p3-instances/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2017/10/introducing-amazon-ec2-p3-instances/</guid>
<description>&lt;div readability=&quot;33&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;P3 instances provide a powerful platform for ML and HPC by also leveraging 64 vCPUs using the custom Intel Xeon E5 processors, 488 GB of RAM, and up to 25 Gbps of aggregate network bandwidth leveraging Elastic Network Adapter technology.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;34&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;&quot; readability=&quot;13&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on NVIDIA’s latest Volta architecture, each Tesla V100 GPUs provide 125 TFLOPS of mixed-precision performance, 15.7 TFLOPS of single precision (FP32) performance and 7.8 TFLOPS of double precision (FP64) performance. This is possible because each Tesla V100 GPUs contains 5,120 CUDA Cores and 640 Tensor Cores. A 300 GB/s NVLink hyper-mesh interconnect allows GPU-to-GPU communication at high speed and low latency. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;33.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;&quot; readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For ML applications, P3 instances offer up to 14x performance improvement over P2 instances, allowing developers to train their machine learning models in hours instead of days, and bring their innovations to market faster.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;36&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;&quot; readability=&quot;17&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;P3 instances are available in three instance sizes, p3.2xlarge with 1 GPU, p3.8xlarge with 4 GPUs and p3.16xlarge with 8 GPUs. They are available in US East (N. Virginia), US West (Oregon), EU West (Ireland) and Asia Pacific (Tokyo) regions. Customers can purchase P3 instances as On-Demand Instances, Reserved Instances, Spot Instances, and Dedicated Hosts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 06:18:13 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>aseidl</dc:creator>
<og:title>Introducing Amazon EC2 P3 Instances</og:title>
<og:type>company</og:type>
<og:url>//aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2017/10/introducing-amazon-ec2-p3-instances/</og:url>
<og:image>https://a0.awsstatic.com/main/images/logos/aws_logo_smile_1200x630.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2017/10/introducing-amazon-ec2-p3-instances/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Video Games Are Destroying the People Who Make Them</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2017/10/25/opinion/work-culture-video-games-crunch.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2017/10/25/opinion/work-culture-video-games-crunch.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;403&quot; data-total-count=&quot;2491&quot; id=&quot;story-continues-3&quot;&gt;In a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.igda.org/page/dss2016&quot;&gt;2016 survey&lt;/a&gt; by the International Game Developers Association, 65 percent of developers said they’d had to crunch, with 52 percent adding that they’d done it more than twice in the previous two years. (Of those who said they did not crunch, 32 percent noted “that their job did require periods of long hours, extended work hours or extended overtime that was just not called ‘crunch.’ ”)&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;600&quot; data-total-count=&quot;3091&quot;&gt;While many jobs are demanding, the conditions in this industry are uniquely unforgiving. Most game developers in the United States do not receive extra compensation for extra hours. They may gaze with envy at their colleagues in the film industry, where unions help regulate hours and ensure overtime pay. Their income pales in comparison to what’s offered in other fields with reputations for brutal hours, like banking and law. The average American game developer earned $83,060 in 2013, according to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gamasutra.com/view/news/221533/Game_Developer_Salary_Survey_2014_The_results_are_in.php&quot;&gt;a Gamasutra survey&lt;/a&gt;, or less than half the pay of a first-year associate at a New York law firm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;214&quot; data-total-count=&quot;3305&quot;&gt;While I was reporting for a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.harpercollins.com/9780062651235/&quot;&gt;book&lt;/a&gt; on how video games are made, veteran game makers told me stories of lost family time, relationship strains and such severe burnout that they considered leaving for other industries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;228&quot; data-total-count=&quot;3533&quot;&gt;“People think that making games is easy,” said Marcin Iwinski, a co-chief executive and co-founder of CD Projekt Red, the Polish developer of a 2015 game, The Witcher 3. “It’s hard-core work. It can destroy your life.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;333&quot; data-total-count=&quot;3866&quot;&gt;Mr. Iwinski, like many other top video game creators, sees crunch as a necessary evil. He and other developers say because of the rapid evolution of video game technology, among other reasons, the time it takes to complete basic tasks can vary drastically from project to project, which makes it difficult to plan accurate schedules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;339&quot; data-total-count=&quot;4205&quot;&gt;A growing faction of game developers, however, argues that it’s possible to make good games without crunching. Tanya X. Short, a co-founder of the independent studio Kitfox Games, asked colleagues to sign an online pledge against excessive overtime. The pledge, which was &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSc2LGt1HOZN5G9dPS81qPxmY2f3TaqmBTMeVUvter50n5u_Lg/viewform?c=0&amp;amp;w=1&quot;&gt;published last year&lt;/a&gt;, has been signed by over 500 game developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;89&quot; data-total-count=&quot;4294&quot;&gt;“Crunch trades short-term gains for long-term suffering,” said Ms. Short in an email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;331&quot; data-total-count=&quot;4625&quot;&gt;To avoid long-term deleterious effects, game developers must commit to stop facilitating a culture in which crunch is the norm. The occasional long night or weekend at the office can be useful and even exhilarating, but as a constant, it is damaging. No video game is worth burnout, brain damage or overnight stays at the hospital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;388&quot; data-total-count=&quot;5013&quot;&gt;Those of us who cover the video game industry can see that the current conditions are unsustainable. Too many of the people who make games have left for more lucrative, less stressful industries. Too many who have stayed have suffered the physical and mental consequences. Game developers need to insist — to their bosses and, most important, to themselves — that health comes first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;visually-hidden skip-to-text-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/10/25/opinion/work-culture-video-games-crunch.html#whats-next&quot;&gt;Continue reading the main story&lt;/a&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 00:28:22 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>danso</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2017/10/25/opinion/work-culture-video-games-crunch.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Opinion | Video Games Are Destroying the People Who Make Them</og:title>
<og:description>The industry’s infamous “crunch” culture is taking a serious toll on workers.</og:description>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2017/10/26/opinion/26schreier/26schreier-facebookJumbo.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2017/10/25/opinion/work-culture-video-games-crunch.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>I have no side code projects to show you</title>
<link>https://www.codementor.io/ezekielbuchheit/no-i-have-no-side-code-projects-to-show-you-cz1tyhgdz</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.codementor.io/ezekielbuchheit/no-i-have-no-side-code-projects-to-show-you-cz1tyhgdz</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I know the exact moment in the interview I lost the job for a boutique app firm in downtown Austin. They wanted to see some of my code, and, of course, they understood I couldn't show them anything from my current or past companies. But that shouldn't be an issue, certainly I can demonstrate any one of my numerous side projects that I no-doubt have in progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I have no side projects. I have no presence on github. I have no open-source projects with which I whittle away my evenings. I have exactly zero pull requests for any of the latest sexy codebases all the cool coders are in on. I don't mess around with exercises in Haskel. And I loathe hackathons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And when I said I have no side projects to show, what they heard - what interviewers hear - is: I am not the best. I am not a passionate developer. I don't spend the necessary time to keep on top of my education and skills. That development is &quot;just a job.&quot; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And to some degree this is true. I am not the best. I have met some of the best, and we are fundamentally different creatures. If I may make an analogy, back in my distance running days I could consistently get in the top 5-10% of finishers, but the differences between me and the elites was the difference between me and the bottom 1%. I was a passionate runner. I ran 50+ miles a week. I pushed myself to excel. To excel within the boundaries of the time and life-balance I had set for myself. To achieve elite status would take a life sacrifice that I wasn't willing to make. It would mean running at the expense of all other experiences. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a small group of people for whom code speaks. They discovered more than a job, they discovered a calling. Code is a craft and they are artists. For every one of those folks there are thousands of amazing, solid developers that will write circles around 90% of the other CS graduates. But they aren't &quot;the best.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When companies say they want &quot;passionate developers&quot; that are coding in their free time, when companies say they want &quot;the best,&quot; I get nervous. It's a myopic approach to team building. It's a subtle way of requesting human machines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've made it a point to add to my resume and online profiles the other things about which I am passionate. The silly art project that I launched in Austin. My dog business. Running, painting, writing. It's important to me that these attributes be valued by my workplace. If they value it in me, then they value it in others, and that speaks volumes about the company culture. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The world is catching up to this reality, bit by bit. The Bay Area, Seattle, NYC - these may be the hottest, hippest areas to have your startup or giant conglomerate, but you severely limit your pool of potential candidates to a tiny puddle of people that can live in these cities. I have four children. I own an entire separate dog playcare business with my wife. I am an active member of the local art community. There is no way I could ever live in one of these other cities. And while some companies are realizing that I am not an edge case - Facebook, Google, Amazon, they all have a significant presence in Austin specifically because they've drained the talent elsewhere - too many places are still convinced that &quot;the best&quot; lives to code. That &quot;the best&quot; is attracted to your company because you have a nap room, work 80 hour weeks and have a ping pong table. That &quot;the best&quot; is happy to drink into the Earth every Friday and has absolutely no evening or weekend plans. Ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did not get the job at the boutique app firm in downtown Austin. I have no code side projects to show you. On Thursday evenings I go to a life drawing studio and spend three hours with other artists sketching a variety of poses from our model. Most evenings after I've made dinner and spent time with the wife and kids, I sit down and knock out 2,000 words on my fifth novel (and like the four abominations that preceded, it will sit in my Pile of Shame, never to be seen by another human being.) Weekends I hike. I dive deep into art. I am a passionate developer because I am a passionate person. But I have no code here to show you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 19:15:39 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>nnd</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>No, I have no side code projects to show you | Codementor</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.codementor.io/ezekielbuchheit/no-i-have-no-side-code-projects-to-show-you-cz1tyhgdz</og:url>
<og:image></og:image>
<og:description>I know the exact moment in the interview I lost the job for a boutique app firm in downtown Austin. They wanted to see some of my code, and, of</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.codementor.io/ezekielbuchheit/no-i-have-no-side-code-projects-to-show-you-cz1tyhgdz</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The fight over preserving public land takes a twist in Montana’s mountains</title>
<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2017-10-25/this-land-is-no-longer-your-land</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2017-10-25/this-land-is-no-longer-your-land</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;section-break&quot;&gt;Brad Wilson is following a forest trail and scanning the dusky spaces between the fir trees for signs of movement. The black handle of a .44 Magnum juts prominently from his pack. If he stumbles on a startled bear at close range, the retired sheriff’s deputy wants to know the gun is within quick reach, in case something stronger than pepper spray is needed. Wilson isn’t the type who likes to take chances; he’s the type who plans ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before setting foot on this path, he unfolded a huge &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fs.fed.us/&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;US Forest Service&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;U.S. Forest Service&lt;/a&gt; map and reviewed the route, Trail 267. He put a finger at the trailhead, which was next to a ranger’s station, then traced its meandering path into the Crazy Mountains, a chain in south-central Montana that’s part of the northern Rockies. Like many of the trails and roads that lead into U.S. Forest Service land, Trail 267 twists in and out of private properties. These sorts of paths have been used as access points for decades, but “No Trespassing” signs are popping up on them with increasing frequency, along with visitors’ logs in which hikers, hunters, and Forest Service workers are instructed to sign their names, tacitly acknowledging that the trail is private and that permission for its use was granted at the private landowners’ discretion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;lazy-img-319537188&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/iWzQ1Y9rO09M/v1/60x-1.jpg&quot; data-native-src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/iWzQ1Y9rO09M/v1/-1x-1.jpg&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img__image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Retired lawman Wilson says ranchers have become more obstacles than neighbors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photographer: Thomas Prior for Bloomberg Businessweek&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wilson hates the signs and the logbooks, interpreting them as underhanded attempts by a handful of ranchers to dictate who gets to enter federal property adjacent to their own. Several of the owners operate commercial hunting businesses or rental cabins; by controlling the points of ingress to public wilderness, Wilson says, they could effectively turn tens of thousands of acres of federal land into extensions of their own ranches. That would allow them to charge thousands of dollars per day for exclusive access, while turning away anyone—hikers, anglers, bikers, hunters, locals like Wilson, or even forest rangers—who didn’t strike a deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wilson, 63, is out on the trail to show me how the paths weave through private plots before reaching a destination he loves, and to show me why he loves it: The pebbled trout streams are crystalline, the elk run rampant, and painterly snowcaps break the big sky. The ranches along the way are pretty great, too, the kind of real estate that inspires—and, if acquired, perhaps even satisfies—the hunger a lot of people feel for scenic refuge. Many of the landholders are newcomers from out of state, though some old-timers remain—families that earned their deeds generations ago, the principal paid by ancestors who shivered through pitiless winters in tar-paper shacks. Wilson has been hiking and hunting the Crazies since he was a little kid, but only in the past year or so, he says, have the private ranchers seemed more like obstacles than neighbors. “They could shut down pretty much the whole interior of the Crazy Mountains, as far as I can see,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He trudges up a rooty slope and, after a blind bend, sees something straddling the trail that stops him cold. It’s a padlocked metal gate. He hiked this trail a couple of weeks before, and the fence wasn’t there. A sign on it reads, “Private Property: No Forest Service Access, No Trespassing.” It’s exactly the kind of sign he’d been bad-mouthing a few minutes earlier, but he wasn’t expecting to see one here. The locked gate feels like an escalation, a new weapon in an improvised war.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The change in Wilson’s hiking plan is frustrating, but he’s getting used to the feeling. A year ago he was just a retired county lawman working as a trustee for the &lt;a href=&quot;http://montanacowboyfame.org/index.html&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Montana Cowboy Hall of Fame &amp;amp; Western Heritage Center - Home&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;Montana Cowboy Hall of Fame&lt;/a&gt;, and he never would have guessed that, in a battle involving ranchers, he’d find himself on the side of dirt bikers and trail rats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A debate is taking place across the country over preserving land for recreational public use, but most of the attention is focused on vast swaths of historically or scientifically significant terrain that Presidents Barack Obama, Bill Clinton, and to a lesser extent George W. Bush protected under the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nps.gov/history/archeology/sites/antiquities/fullMap.htm&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;NPS Archeology Program: Antiquities Act Centennial&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;national monument designation&lt;/a&gt;—for example, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fs.fed.us/visit/bears-ears-national-monument&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Bears Ears National Monument&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;Bears Ears&lt;/a&gt; in Utah and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nps.gov/kaww/index.htm&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Katahdin Woods and Waters National Monument (U.S. National Park Service)&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;Katahdin Woods and Waters&lt;/a&gt; in Maine. These disputed trails leading into the Crazy Mountains represent another front in the escalating battle over control of federal territory, and the fighting here is just as contentious as over the monuments. Historic settlement patterns in the American West created a checkerboard pattern of landownership: Public properties are often broken-up plots, resulting in numerous access disputes. According to a &lt;a href=&quot;http://westernpriorities.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/Landlocked-Measuring-Public-Land-Access.pdf&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Landlocked: Measuring Public Land Access in the West (.pdf)&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;2013 study&lt;/a&gt; by the Center for Western Priorities, that dynamic has effectively locked the public out of about 4 million acres of land in Western states; almost half of that blocked public land, or about 2 million acres, is in Montana, according to the study. The push to end public thoroughfare is either an overdue reassertion of private property rights or an openly cynical land snatch, depending which side of the gate you’re standing on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before Wilson turns around and walks back to the trailhead, he vows that he’ll be better prepared next time. Alongside the .44 he’ll pack a pair of super-heavy-duty bolt cutters, and he swears he’ll tear that gate down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;lazy-img-319550570&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/iJs_QuEUA_Zc/v10/60x-1.png&quot; data-native-src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/iJs_QuEUA_Zc/v10/-1x-1.png&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img__image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;section-break&quot;&gt;Late last October, in the dying days of the Obama era, a U.S. district judge issued a verdict that seemed to set a precedent for paths like this one. The Texas-based owners of a Montana property called Wonder Ranch, about 100 miles southeast of the Crazy Mountains, had &lt;a href=&quot;http://billingsgazette.com/lifestyles/recreation/judge-to-tour-site-of-madison-valley-trail-dispute/article_35255ace-a09e-53f9-b16d-49ce002e9452.html&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Judge to tour site of Madison Valley trail dispute&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;sued the Forest Service&lt;/a&gt; after the government filed a statement of interest claiming an easement—a legal agreement to use a portion of someone’s land for a specific purpose—on a trail that ran across the ranch’s property before reaching the Lee Metcalf Wilderness. The Forest Service said the trail had been routinely used as an access route to the forest by the government and the public for decades, and therefore it should be considered public because of historical use. The owners’ suit argued that the government had no right to an easement. The Department of Justice countersued, producing evidence dating back more than a century showing that the public and the government consistently used the trail for packhorses and hike-ins. The Forest Service &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.leagle.com/decision/infdco20161025g69&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;WONDER RANCH, LLC v. U.S.&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;won the case&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Had the landowners been able to show that the trail had been used for at least five consecutive years only by those who’d received their permission, their claims of private control might have held. That helps explain why Alex Sienkiewicz, the forest ranger overseeing the district that includes the Crazy Mountains, every year sends an email to his staff reminding them never to ask landowners’ permission to use trails that the government already considers public. “By asking permission,” he wrote in last year’s reminder, “one undermines the public access rights and plays into their lawyers’ trap of establishing a history of permissive access.” That didn’t mean anyone could veer off the trail and slip onto the private property—that’s trespassing, no question about it—it just meant the trail itself should be considered a public throughway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;lazy-img-319550558&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/ifDTgcIAthU8/v10/60x-1.png&quot; data-native-src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/ifDTgcIAthU8/v10/-1x-1.png&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img__image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every trail leading to public land is different, and not all necessarily have a history of public use, but Sienkiewicz was echoing the government’s generally established position regarding such access points, the one argued by Justice Department attorneys in the Wonder Ranch LLC case. Obama himself outlined his administration’s overarching philosophy when he visited southern Montana during his first term to &lt;a href=&quot;http://flatheadbeacon.com/2009/09/02/white-house-photos-obama-fly-fishing-in-montana/&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;White House Photos: Obama Fly Fishing in Montana&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;try his hand at fly-fishing&lt;/a&gt;. “He said he felt really strongly that a key to getting kids to become adults that care about their natural surroundings is making sure they can get out to them in the first place,” says Dan Vermillion, a local fly-fishing outfitter and the chair of Montana’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://fwp.mt.gov/doingBusiness/insideFwp/commission/&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Montana Fish, Wildlife &amp;amp; Parks :: Fish &amp;amp; Wildlife Commission&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;Fish and Wildlife Commission&lt;/a&gt;, who waded into the Gallatin River with Obama. “Public access is one of those great equalizers that says whether you’re rich, poor, or otherwise, you still have access to public lands, and you can go out and enjoy them.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;lazy-img-319537071&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/iiNY7ApsmTto/v3/60x-1.jpg&quot; data-native-src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/iiNY7ApsmTto/v3/-1x-1.jpg&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img__image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A disputed road leading to public land, blocked by the landowning Galt family, who sell self-guided hunts on their ranch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photographer: Thomas Prior for Bloomberg Businessweek&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a while, it seemed that attitude might be one of the rare Obama positions that President Donald Trump could live with. In a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fieldandstream.com/articles/hunting/2016/01/qa-donald-trump-on-guns-hunting-and-conservation&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Q&amp;amp;A: Donald Trump on Guns, Hunting, and Conservation&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;pre-election interview&lt;/a&gt;, Trump told the magazine &lt;em&gt;Field &amp;amp; Stream&lt;/em&gt; he didn’t like the idea of transferring the land to the states, suggesting such transfers could erode public oversight of them: “I want to keep the lands great, and you don’t know what the state is going to do,” he said. “I mean, are they going to sell if they get into a little bit of trouble? And I don’t think it’s something that should be sold. We have to be great stewards of this land. This is magnificent land.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Public land advocates smelled a contradiction, since the new president was positioning himself elsewhere as a champion of private property rights. And regardless of what he said, Trump’s campaign had tapped into a very deep well of antigovernment sentiment, the sort that Nevada rancher &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2017-02-09/las-vegas-trial-starting-for-6-in-bundy-ranch-standoff&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Las Vegas Trial Starting for Six in Bundy Ranch Standoff&quot;&gt;Cliven Bundy&lt;/a&gt; appealed to when he occupied public territories and led armed standoffs against federal agents in 2014 and again in 2016. The co-chair of a state group called Veterans for Trump &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.guns.com/2016/03/07/veterans-for-trump-co-chair-arrested-with-bundy-crew/&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;‘Veterans for Trump’ co-chair arrested with Bundy crew&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;pleaded guilty&lt;/a&gt; to helping organize the ad hoc rebel militia, and Roger Stone, a longtime Trump adviser, has been one of Bundy’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hcn.org/articles/politics-why-is-roger-stone-so-interested-in-cliven-bundy&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Why is a Trump operative so interested in Cliven Bundy?&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;most vocal supporters&lt;/a&gt;. Immediately after the election, whether or not the results had anything to do with their actions, the Crazy Mountains landowners launched a collective blitz to take control of the trails leading to Forest Service property.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;section-break&quot;&gt;Rob Gregoire, an engineer from Bozeman, Mont., says he had little idea what awaited him when he marched up the Crazy Mountains on Nov. 23, 2016. He’d been granted a state tag allowing him to hunt bull elk on the eastern slopes, and before he set out for Forest Service land, he’d called Sienkiewicz, the district ranger, to double-check that the public trail marked on his map was indeed public. The ranger had explained agency policy to him, which indicated that the trail was public, but told Gregoire to use his own judgment if a landowner objected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gregoire decided to go for it. When the trail veered through a private plot called the Hailstone Ranch, he spotted a No Trespassing sign that read, “The Forest Service Has No Easement Here.” He ignored it, consulting his GPS to make sure he never strayed from the path onto the private ranch land. The landowner somehow detected that he was using the trail (“I think he had an alarm or something,” Gregoire later speculated) and called a sheriff’s deputy, who was waiting for Gregoire to return at the end of the day. The deputy charged him with criminal trespassing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shortly after that, the owners of nine ranches neighboring the Hailstone went after Sienkiewicz. Back on July 20, a volunteer at &lt;a href=&quot;http://plwa.org/&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;PLWA - Public Land / Water Access Association, Inc&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;Public Land/Water Access Association Inc.&lt;/a&gt;, a Montana nonprofit that supports open public access to federal lands and waterways, had gotten hold of, then posted on its Facebook page, Sienkiewicz’s most recent annual email reminder to his staff advising them never to sign visitor logs for trail access or ask permission. The property owners apparently assumed that Sienkiewicz had posted the item himself—proof that he was behaving as a political activist, not a public servant. The ranch owners sent a letter to U.S. Senator Steve Daines, a Republican representing Montana, saying in part, “As a direct result of this inflammatory Facebook post, we have many questions about the FS position regarding access across our private property.” Several of the ranchers who signed the letter have also been listed as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.opensecrets.org/members-of-congress/contributors?cid=N00033054&amp;amp;cycle=2018&amp;amp;recs=100&amp;amp;type=I&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Sen. Steven Daines - Montana • OpenSecrets&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;contributors&lt;/a&gt; to Daines’s political campaigns in the past five years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In May, Daines echoed the landowners’ complaints—and forwarded a screen shot of the Facebook post—in a letter to Thomas Tidwell, then the chief of the Forest Service, and to Agriculture Secretary Sonny Perdue, whose agency oversees the Forest Service. Less than two weeks later, Representative Pete Sessions (R-Texas) got involved, firing off a similar complaint to Perdue and Interior Secretary Ryan Zinke, who has a long history in Montana. An avid hunter and fisherman, he was born in Bozeman, about 40 miles from the Crazies. He was also a Montana congressman, filling the seat Daines had occupied before he moved to the Senate. (At least one of the ranchers donated to Zinke’s campaign.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;lazy-img-319544164&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/ihwwOZUGgs7s/v1/60x-1.jpg&quot; data-native-src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/ihwwOZUGgs7s/v1/-1x-1.jpg&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img__image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A road leading toward the Crazy Mountains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photographer: Thomas Prior for Bloomberg Businessweek&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.emwh.org/public%20access/Crazy%20Mountains/Texas%20Representative%20Pete%20Sessions%20Letter%20to%20Secretary%20of%20Agriculture%20Sonny%20Purdue.pdf&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Texas Representative Pete Sessions' Letter to Secretary of Agriculture Sonny Purdue&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;his letter&lt;/a&gt;, Sessions described the Forest Service’s approach to public access as part of “the war on private property owners conducted by the Obama administration.” The Wonder Ranch owners hadn’t been among the nine who signed the initial letter, but they were the link that got Sessions involved. One of the co-owners, a Texan named Chris Hudson, lives in Sessions’ district, and Sessions proposed that Hudson and Perdue meet. Sessions also recommended that the Forest Service issue a nationwide directive to prevent rangers or individual districts from declaring paths and roads public based on historic use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not known if Perdue or Zinke took direct action after receiving the complaints (Perdue’s, Zinke’s, and Sessions’ offices didn’t return calls for this story, nor did Hudson’s attorney). But the week after Sessions’ letter was sent, Sienkiewicz was removed from his job as district ranger, pending an internal review, and moved to a desk job evaluating gold mining proposals in another part of Montana. The public controversy surrounding his suspension stretched on for more than four months and brought significant local criticism to the Forest Service. “Alex was just following the Forest Service manual,” says Bernard Lea, who spent 36 years in the Forest Service in Montana before retiring and becoming a leader of the Public Land/Water Access Association. The day before Sienkiewicz was told of his transfer, Gregoire agreed to settle his trespassing charge and pay a $500 fine. The county attorney overseeing the case happened to be the husband of one of the landowners who’d signed the letter to Perdue and Daines complaining about Sienkiewicz. “With him on board,” Gregoire says, “I didn’t think I could win.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Defenders of Sienkiewicz and Gregoire—a group that included land access advocates, proprietors of recreation businesses, wildlife groups, and individuals—cast the developments as evidence of an under-the-table assault on public lands that the Trump administration appeared to endorse, if not initiate. This spring, Trump requested that Zinke’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.doi.gov/&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;U.S. Department of the Interior&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;Department of the Interior&lt;/a&gt; review national monuments, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.whitehouse.gov/the-press-office/2017/04/26/presidential-executive-order-review-designations-under-antiquities-act&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Presidential Executive Order on the Review of Designations Under the Antiquities Act&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;designated or enlarged since 1996&lt;/a&gt;, and possibly downsize them, a step he said could rectify what he considered a “massive federal land grab.” Several politicians from Utah, such as Orrin Hatch, Rob Bishop, and Jason Chaffetz, had led the downsizing push, and for years they’d been advocating turning such lands over to the states—the strategy Trump had earlier declared would result in a selloff to the highest bidder. The department eventually suggested downsizing six of the 27 monuments under review, but the ultimate fate of those lands and waters remains in limbo; the matter will go to Congress, and the conservationists have said they will fight the new boundaries in court.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;lazy-img-319537068&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/ignbJl9Ykips/v2/60x-1.jpg&quot; data-native-src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/ignbJl9Ykips/v2/-1x-1.jpg&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img__image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PERC’s Anderson says ranch owners serve nature better than government can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photographer: Thomas Prior for Bloomberg Businessweek&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;section-break&quot;&gt;“I absolutely hate the movie &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0105265/?ref_=fn_al_tt_1&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;A River Runs Through It (1992) - IMDb&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;A River Runs Through It&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;,” says &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.perc.org/staff/terry-anderson&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Terry Anderson | PERC – The Property and Environment Research Center&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;Terry Anderson&lt;/a&gt;, senior fellow and the former president and executive director of the Bozeman-based Property and Environment Research Center, commonly known as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.perc.org/&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;PERC – The Property and Environment Research Center |&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;PERC&lt;/a&gt;. “It destroyed fly-fishing in Montana.” He’s referring to the wave of tourists in fresh-off-the-rack waders inspired by Brad Pitt in the film, who’s guided through life in leaf-filtered light by fraternal love and river sport. Anderson grew up in Montana, and he remembers when the Bozeman airport terminal was smaller than a coffee shop, and you could spend all day on a hike without seeing another soul. The unofficial state motto is “The Last Best Place,” and the feeling that untrammeled natural landscapes are becoming scarce has engendered a strain of possessiveness. At a gas station near the Crazy Mountains, you’ll find T-shirts that say “Montana Sucks—Now Go Home and Tell All Your Friends” and bumper stickers that read “Montana Is Full—I Hear North Dakota Is Nice.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anderson has carved out a field for himself in something called free-market environmentalism. Along with his job at PERC, he’s a professor emeritus at Montana State University and a senior fellow at Stanford’s Hoover Institution, a libertarian-leaning think tank. In op-eds published across the country, he’s an evangelist for limited government and private property rights. He views many environmentalists with undisguised contempt, and they generally return the favor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like many nonprofits, PERC doesn’t disclose its funding sources, but &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.greenpeace.org/international/en/&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Greenpeace International Home | Greenpeace International&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;Greenpeace International&lt;/a&gt; has posted records showing that they’ve included &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/quote/XOM:US&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot;&gt;Exxon Mobil Corp.&lt;/a&gt; and the industrialists &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/billionaires/id/1654748&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Charles&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/billionaires/id/1423900&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;David Koch&lt;/a&gt;. Anderson probably wouldn’t worry too much about how that looks: He believes the private sector, in most cases, is a better steward of nature than the government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He argues that public land access obeys a dynamic prevalent in vehicular traffic planning. When highway departments construct additional lanes to a highway to ease congestion, he says, it generally has the opposite effect, merely allowing more drivers to clog the road. In a similar way, encouraging the use of multiple pathways into public lands degrades the environment. Better, he maintains, would be to let private stakeholders control access and charge fees instead of burdening taxpayers with the job; fewer people would trample the trails, and those trails would be better kept.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the right place and the right time, the notion that the Crazies are being overrun by hordes of weekenders desperate for recreation is easy to conjure. It’s best done on a sun-shot Saturday morning in summer, close to Half Moon Campground, which is near the lone uncontested public entry point on the east side of the Crazies. Here, campers and hikers gather before dispersing into the relative solitude of the vast mountain wilderness. On one such morning in August, no fewer than 33 vehicles overfilled a parking area near the trailhead. “It’s like a Walmart parking lot,” grumbled Dario Quilici, a 35-year-old who was hiking in with Gino Mussolini, his German wirehaired pointer, for some camping and fishing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quilici’s plan was seat-of-the-pants. He thought he might spend three or four days hiking to an exit point on the far side of the mountains, but he didn’t realize that the most direct trail was blocked by the gate Wilson had confronted. Other possible paths were also contested. When I told him this, he redirected his criticism away from the parking lot and toward the landowners. “I bet they have some lobbying power,” he said. “They just want to keep everything like it’s their own private reserve.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;lazy-img-319537218&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/iTU7v0x8fKXU/v2/60x-1.jpg&quot; data-native-src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/iTU7v0x8fKXU/v2/-1x-1.jpg&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img__image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The town of Wilsall, at the foot of the Crazies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photographer: Thomas Prior for Bloomberg Businessweek&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Herein lies the big challenge for the landowners and their defenders: Survey after survey has shown that the public hates the idea that someone can lock taxpayers out of public land, and that they’re suspicious of transferring control of such tracts to private enterprise. Nevertheless, Anderson and PERC deny that their position is out of step with public opinion, even casting it as pro-access. Their rationale is oblique: If the Forest Service insists the public has a right to use the trails, they say, private landowners will naturally rebel; numerous court battles will ensue, tying up the trails in years of litigation and costing the government millions of dollars. And as the cases proceed, the landowners will take steps to secure their property rights, blocking traffic on the trails until the mess is sorted out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“In the places where now there are signs,” Anderson predicts, “you’ll see a locked gate.” His comment is an informed one. He counts several of the landowners involved in the Crazy Mountains disputes as friends, including the owners of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://anchoroutfitting.com/&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Hunt South Central Montana Anchor Outfitting Montana Outfitter Elk Hunting Montana Deer Hunting Montana Mountain Goat Hunt Crazy Mountains Antelope Hunt South Central Montana&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;Rein Anchor Outfitting and Ranch&lt;/a&gt;, who operate a hunting lodge and signed the letter against Sienkiewicz. PERC’s affiliation with politically connected outfitters that stand to profit if trails are closed bolsters the sense, to Wilson and others confronting locked gates, that a void in coherent policy about public land management is being filled by cronyism that rewards wealth and connections above all else. Another co-owner of the Wonder Ranch, Frank-Paul King, a friend and former student of Anderson’s, served on PERC’s board. Hudson, the man who got Representative Sessions involved, is King’s brother-in-law, and he’s also a board member and the former president of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.biggame.org/&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Dallas Safari Club | More Than A Club. A Way Of Life!&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;Dallas Safari Club&lt;/a&gt;, a group that made national headlines in 2014 when it auctioned off a trip to Africa to hunt an endangered rhinoceros. (The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dallasnews.com/news/news/2015/05/21/texan-who-paid-350k-in-dallas-safari-club-auction-finally-bags-rhino&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Texan who paid $350K in Dallas Safari Club auction finally bags rhino | News | Dallas News&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;winning bidder&lt;/a&gt;, who paid $350,000, traveled to Namibia and shot a black rhino bull, an animal the club said had threatened the rest of the herd.) The Dallas Safari Club has &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dscf.org/grants/&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Grants – Dallas Safari Club Foundation&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;granted PERC funding&lt;/a&gt; for, among other things, a study on “private conservation in the public interest.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2016 the Dallas Safari Club hosted a fundraiser featuring the big-game hunting enthusiast Donald Trump Jr. that netted $60,000 in campaign donations to the Republican National Committee. “The candidate’s family connection to hunting and its legacy gives DSC a huge opportunity to have the right people in place as advocates for our mission,” the club’s newsletter stated. After Trump was elected, Hudson was listed as an organizer for a post-inaugural fundraiser called “Opening Day 45,” which featured Eric and Donald Trump Jr. as co-chairs. It was canceled after TMZ published an &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tmz.com/2016/12/16/donald-trump-inauguration-party/&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Donald Trump &amp;amp; Family Celebrate Hunters and Fisherman at Inauguration Bash&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;early draft of the invitation&lt;/a&gt; last December, promising personal access to President Trump, along with a multiday hunting excursion with his sons, to anyone who donated more than $500,000, sparking criticism that the sons planned to peddle access to their father.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This circle of big-game hunters is relatively small, which means links among them are numerous enough to allow critics of the Trump administration to claim political malfeasance, and they’re tangential enough that defenders can argue that they’re coincidental and easily misconstrued. One person who has hunted with Trump Jr. is Senator Daines, of the anti-Sienkiewicz letters. The two men met last fall in a camp in Montana during an elk hunt. Daines later called on Trump Jr. to return to the state to campaign on behalf of Greg Gianforte, who was running for the congressional seat Zinke gave up to lead the Interior Department. This spring, Trump Jr. explained that he had grown to trust Daines unequivocally; when the senator told the president’s son that Gianforte was “an awesome guy,” he decided to get involved. “That vouching was enough for me,” Trump Jr. said at a rally in April.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;section-break&quot;&gt;On a Thursday evening in August, a couple dozen people gathered in an old schoolhouse in Livingston, Mont., to grill Mary Erickson, the Forest Service’s supervisor of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nationalforests.org/our-forests/find-a-forest/custer-national-forest&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Custer National Forest - National Forest Foundation&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;Custer Gallatin National Forest&lt;/a&gt;, about Sienkiewicz’s reassignment. Most of the people in the crowd viewed the case with skepticism or outrage, and Erickson appeared to be choosing her words carefully to avoid pushing anyone toward the angrier end of the scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trail access issue was extremely sensitive inside the Forest Service, she explained, and potentially costly, too. The Trump administration was &lt;a href=&quot;http://mtstandard.com/news/government-and-politics/trump-budget-proposes-big-changes-in-forest-service-interior-spending/article_6916ad68-6d66-5f2a-adc0-84d8b1ef813e.html&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Trump budget proposes big changes in Forest Service, Interior spending&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;proposing&lt;/a&gt; a 73 percent cut in the Forest Service’s capital improvement and maintenance budget and an 84 percent reduction, from $77 million to $12 million, in its trail program budget. The Wonder Ranch case, she observed, had cost the government “in the millions of dollars,” and it wasn’t over yet—the landowners were appealing the decision, and it now sat with an appellate judge. “I’m not saying we’re never going to go to court, but the Forest Service is going to be careful about when we go to court and make sure we’re going to court on cases we can win,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;lazy-img-319544171&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/iBwjMY5L7304/v4/60x-1.jpg&quot; data-native-src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/iBwjMY5L7304/v4/-1x-1.jpg&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img__image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A padlock on a gate blocking access to the Porcupine Lowline Trail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photographer: Thomas Prior for Bloomberg Businessweek&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Erickson downplayed suggestions that any of the politicians involved in the Sienkiewicz case had been directly responsible for his removal, and she suggested that Sienkiewicz should have been more diplomatic when he dealt with the local landowners, to avoid the appearance of “pulling to this side or that side” regarding any questions of public access.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That notion didn’t sit well with some in the audience, particularly those who believed that if the unfolding drama showed bias toward an interest group, it was toward the private landowners. Nick Gevock, the conservation director of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://montanawildlife.org/&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Montana Wildlife Federation&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;Montana Wildlife Federation&lt;/a&gt;, told Erickson that Sienkiewicz was a public servant and he’d simply taken the side of the general public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The agency in mid-October announced it was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bozemandailychronicle.com/news/environment/livingston-forest-service-ranger-to-be-reinstated-after-internal-review/article_5e6c8657-e61a-5fb4-95bd-f08d2c510c98.html&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Livingston Forest Service ranger to be reinstated after internal review&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;giving Sienkiewicz his job back&lt;/a&gt;. But Gevock’s frustrations spoke to an unresolved question underlying all of the disputes: Who, exactly, is the Forest Service &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fs.fed.us/about-agency/what-we-believe&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;What We Believe | US Forest Service&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;supposed to serve&lt;/a&gt;? On the agency’s website, former Director Thomas Tidwell wrote that its guiding principles were clearly established by &lt;a href=&quot;http://foresthistory.org/research-explore/us-forest-service-history/people/chiefs/gifford-pinchot-1865-1946/&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;4th Chief of the Division of Forestry, 1898-1905 &amp;amp; 1st Chief of the Forest Service, 1905-1910&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;Gifford Pinchot&lt;/a&gt;, the service’s founding chief, during the Gilded Age—“a time when the nation’s resources were being exploited for the benefit of the wealthy few,” Tidwell stated. “The national forests were based on a notion that was just the opposite—that these lands belong to everyone.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The public access advocates say they’re not sure they trust the spirit of Pinchot’s original message has survived intact. The mixed signals coming from the Trump administration mean everything rests on how those sometimes conflicting messages are interpreted. Zinke has repeatedly insisted, without offering specifics, that he is pro-access, and on his first day in office he &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.courthousenews.com/zinke-expands-hunters-access-public-lands/&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Zinke Expands Hunters’ Access to Public Lands&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;pledged&lt;/a&gt; to fight against the “dramatic decreases in access to public lands across the board” that he said were plaguing America. “It worries me to think about hunting and fishing becoming activities for the landowning elite,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But this past July, while public land advocates were protesting the Interior Department’s pending move to downsize the national monuments and hikers were cursing the new No Trespassing signs in the Crazies, Zinke traveled to Denver to speak at the annual conference of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.alec.org/&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;American Legislative Exchange Council&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;American Legislative Exchange Council&lt;/a&gt;, or ALEC. The group, a conservative lobbying coalition that helps lawmakers draft legislative proposals, has energetically pushed for the potential &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.alec.org/model-policy/resolution-demanding-that-congress-convey-title-of-federal-public-lands-to-the-states/&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;RESOLUTION DEMANDING THAT CONGRESS CONVEY TITLE OF FEDERAL PUBLIC LANDS TO THE STATES&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;transfer of federal lands to the states&lt;/a&gt;. Whether Zinke’s speech clarified the government’s general, overarching philosophy on public-vs.-private control of lands that are currently federal, only members of the lobbying group can say for sure. Unlike several other speeches delivered at the conference, Zinke’s wasn’t transcribed or published, and it was closed to the general public.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;(&lt;span itemprop=&quot;description&quot;&gt;A previous version of this story ascribed a grant from the Dallas Safari Club to PERC that was for The Conservation Fund. The text has been corrected in the 28th paragraph to reflect the accurate study.&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 18:12:21 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>petethomas</dc:creator>
<og:description>The fight over preserving public land during the Trump era is taking a strange, angry twist in Montana’s Crazy Mountains.</og:description>
<og:image>https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/iMY1pGDqIKzs/v0/1200x630.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>When This Land Is No Longer Your Land</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2017-10-25/this-land-is-no-longer-your-land</og:url>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2017-10-25/this-land-is-no-longer-your-land</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Screen sharing in Slack, made interactive via Screenhero acquisition (YC W13)</title>
<link>https://slackhq.com/screen-sharing-in-slack-made-interactive-cf8816efaa01</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://slackhq.com/screen-sharing-in-slack-made-interactive-cf8816efaa01</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;section-inner sectionLayout--insetColumn&quot; readability=&quot;51.555784061697&quot;&gt;

&lt;h2 name=&quot;55b1&quot; id=&quot;55b1&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h4 graf-after--h3 graf--subtitle&quot;&gt;The next best thing to working in the same room&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*Q2v5NNgB-xfdMm9tNct0Tg@2x.png&quot; data-width=&quot;3000&quot; data-height=&quot;1676&quot; data-is-featured=&quot;true&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*Q2v5NNgB-xfdMm9tNct0Tg@2x.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*Q2v5NNgB-xfdMm9tNct0Tg@2x.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;0b3a&quot; id=&quot;0b3a&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;Working with teammates in Slack, wherever they are, started with messaging. Then came voice and video calls, followed by screen sharing. And now, screen sharing from a Slack call has gone interactive: You can invite others to write, code, design — or whatever working together means to you — all directly from your shared screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 name=&quot;fb5c&quot; id=&quot;fb5c&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h4 graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--h4-strong&quot;&gt;Invite others on the call to contribute&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;665b&quot; id=&quot;665b&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h4&quot;&gt;To begin, simply share your screen from a Slack call, and hit the “share control of your screen” button. Each participant will then receive their own cursor, along with the ability to type, edit, scroll, and click through the contents of the shared screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*rix6BFhNgGI3WM08tr7mwQ@2x.png&quot; data-width=&quot;3000&quot; data-height=&quot;1360&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*rix6BFhNgGI3WM08tr7mwQ@2x.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*rix6BFhNgGI3WM08tr7mwQ@2x.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;9e51&quot; id=&quot;9e51&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;And when not in control, viewing participants can temporarily draw over the shared screen, directing attention to particular cells in a spreadsheet, lines of a paragraph, or anything else they want to highlight. Along with the &lt;a href=&quot;http://slackhq.com/slack-calls-now-with-100-more-video-50bf365a0d98#a101&quot; data-href=&quot;http://slackhq.com/slack-calls-now-with-100-more-video-50bf365a0d98#a101&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;emoji reactions&lt;/a&gt; you can already send in Slack calls, the drawing tool can help make presentations feel like more like a two-way conversation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*yf_z8vwx7QukWkduVsD5xQ@2x.png&quot; data-width=&quot;3000&quot; data-height=&quot;1360&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*yf_z8vwx7QukWkduVsD5xQ@2x.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*yf_z8vwx7QukWkduVsD5xQ@2x.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--figure-em&quot;&gt;Viewers on the call can direct attention to specific parts of the screen&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;h4 name=&quot;44c8&quot; id=&quot;44c8&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h4 graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--h4-strong&quot;&gt;How organizations are using it&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;c248&quot; id=&quot;c248&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h4&quot;&gt;Over the past months, customers helping beta test this feature have already found plenty of ways to use it. Some organizations share control of their screen for step-by-step IT troubleshooting, while others use it for pair programming. &lt;a href=&quot;https://slack.com/customer-stories/zapier&quot; data-href=&quot;https://slack.com/customer-stories/zapier&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Zapier&lt;/a&gt;, a software company with a fully distributed workforce, relies on interactive screen sharing so that two or more individuals can work together triaging bugs and responding to customer tickets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;3df9&quot; id=&quot;3df9&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p graf--trailing&quot;&gt;As always, native calls are only one way to work face-to-face or voice-to-voice in Slack — our many &lt;a href=&quot;https://get.slack.help/hc/en-us/articles/208492868-Voice-video-screen-sharing-apps&quot; data-href=&quot;https://get.slack.help/hc/en-us/articles/208492868-Voice-video-screen-sharing-apps&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;third-party calling integrations&lt;/a&gt; such as Zoom, Blue Jeans, Google Hangouts and others allow your team to choose what works best for you to move projects forward with teammates in faraway places.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 17:22:44 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jsherwani</dc:creator>
<og:title>Screen sharing in Slack, made interactive – Several People Are Typing — The Official Slack Blog</og:title>
<og:url>https://slackhq.com/screen-sharing-in-slack-made-interactive-cf8816efaa01</og:url>
<og:image>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*Q2v5NNgB-xfdMm9tNct0Tg@2x.png</og:image>
<og:description>The next best thing to working in the same room</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://slackhq.com/screen-sharing-in-slack-made-interactive-cf8816efaa01?gi=e111a157159c</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>