<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Goldman Sachs Is Setting Up a Cryptocurrency Trading Desk</title>
<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2017-12-21/goldman-is-setting-up-a-cryptocurrency-trading-desk</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2017-12-21/goldman-is-setting-up-a-cryptocurrency-trading-desk</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;At least one of Wall Street’s biggest firms is growing more comfortable with cryptocurrencies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/quote/GS:US&quot; title=&quot;Company Overview&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;Goldman Sachs Group Inc.&lt;/a&gt; is setting up a trading desk to make markets in digital currencies such as bitcoin, according to people with knowledge of the strategy. The bank aims to get the business running by the end of June, if not earlier, two of the people said. Another said it’s still trying to work out security issues as well as how it would hold, or custody, the assets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The move positions Goldman Sachs to become the first large Wall Street firm to make markets in cryptocurrencies, whose wild price swings and surging values have captured the public’s imagination but given pause to established institutions. Already, the bank is among just a few mainstream firms clearing a new breed of bitcoin futures offered by Cboe Global Markets Inc. and CME Group Inc. Citigroup Inc. and Bank of America Corp., for example, have been taking a wait-and-see approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;aside class=&quot;inline-newsletter&quot; data-state=&quot;ready&quot;/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goldman Sachs is now assembling a team in New York, one of the people said. While the bank hasn’t made a decision where to house the desk, one possibility is that it will operate within the fixed-income, currencies and commodities unit’s systematic trading function, which conducts transactions electronically, two people said. Darren Cohen, in the firm’s principal strategic investments group, is also looking at opportunities, another person said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“In response to client interest in digital currencies, we are exploring how best to serve them,” Michael DuVally, a spokesman, said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-tout-type=&quot;story&quot;&gt;&lt;a itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2017-12-21/jpmorgan-dips-a-toe-into-analysis-of-bitcoin-futures-volatility&quot; title=&quot;Click for full story&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Read more on a rival: JPMorgan dips toe into analysis of bitcoin futures volatility&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Publicly, Chief Executive Officer &lt;a itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/billionaires/id/2378577&quot; title=&quot;Billionaire Profile&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Lloyd Blankfein&lt;/a&gt; has been circumspect. He &lt;a itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/terminal/OX9EG1AIBMDC&quot; title=&quot;Lloyd Blankfein: Still thinking about #Bitcoin. No conclusion - not endorsing/rejecting. Know that folks also were skeptical&quot; class=&quot;terminal-news-story&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;tweeted&lt;/a&gt; in October that his firm was looking at how to deal with bitcoin. In a Bloomberg Television interview last month, he &lt;a itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2017-11-30/blankfein-says-too-soon-for-bitcoin-strategy-as-volatility-jumps&quot; title=&quot;Blankfein Says Too Soon for Bitcoin Plan as Volatility Jumps (1)&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; his bank didn’t need a bitcoin strategy yet because the digital currency is still just developing and volatile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And when the bank began clearing futures earlier this month, it demanded that some clients set aside funds equal to the full value of their trade, people familiar with the policy &lt;a itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2017-12-14/goldman-said-to-seek-100-margin-on-some-bitcoin-futures-trades&quot; title=&quot;Goldman Said to Demand 100% Margin on Some Bitcoin Futures (1)&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; at the time. The conservatism deterred some customers and led them to take their business elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For more on cryptocurrencies, check out the &lt;em&gt;Decrypted&lt;/em&gt; podcast: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2017 20:46:11 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>chollida1</dc:creator>
<og:description>At least one of Wall Street’s biggest firms is growing more comfortable with cryptocurrencies.</og:description>
<og:image>https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/iGy3946fe0QE/v0/1200x700.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>Goldman Is Setting Up a Cryptocurrency Trading Desk</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2017-12-21/goldman-is-said-to-be-building-a-cryptocurrency-trading-desk</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2017-12-21/goldman-is-said-to-be-building-a-cryptocurrency-trading-desk</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Gamers Want DMCA Exemption for ‘Abandoned’ Online Games</title>
<link>https://torrentfreak.com/gamers-want-dmca-exemption-for-abandoned-online-games-171221/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://torrentfreak.com/gamers-want-dmca-exemption-for-abandoned-online-games-171221/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://torrentfreak.com/images/starwarsf.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;235&quot; height=&quot;225&quot; class=&quot;alignright size-full wp-image-148899&quot;/&gt;The U.S. Copyright Office is considering whether or not to update the DMCA’s anti-circumvention provisions, which prevent the public from tinkering with DRM-protected content and devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These provisions are renewed every three years. To allow individuals and organizations to chime in, the Office traditionally launches a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.regulations.gov/document?D=COLC-2017-0007-0070&quot;&gt;public consultation&lt;/a&gt;, before it makes any decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week a series of new responses were received and many of these focused on abandoned games. As is true for most software, games have a limited lifespan, so after a few years they are no longer supported by manufacturers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To preserve these games for future generations and nostalgic gamers, the Copyright Office previously included game preservation exemptions. This means that libraries, archives and museums can use emulators and other circumvention tools to make old classics playable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, these exemptions are limited and do not apply to games that require a connection to an online server, which includes most recent games. When the online servers are taken down, the game simply disappears forever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This should be prevented, according to The Museum of Art and Digital Entertainment (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.themade.org/&quot;&gt;the MADE&lt;/a&gt;), a nonprofit organization operating in California.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Although the Current Exemption does not cover it, preservation of online video games is now critical,” MADE writes in its comment to the Copyright Office.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Online games have become ubiquitous and are only growing in popularity. For example, an estimated fifty-three percent of gamers play multiplayer games at least once a week, and spend, on average, six hours a week playing with others online.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the previous review, &lt;a href=&quot;https://torrentfreak.com/eff-seeks-dmca-exemption-to-preserve-abandoned-games-150409/&quot;&gt;similar calls&lt;/a&gt; for an online exemption were made but, at the time, the Register of Copyrights noted that multiplayer games could still be played on local area networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Today, however, local multiplayer options are increasingly rare, and many games no longer support LAN connected multiplayer capability,” MADE counters, adding that nowadays even some single-player games require an online connection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“More troubling still to archivists, many video games rely on server connectivity to function in single-player mode and become unplayable when servers shut down.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MADE asks the Copyright Office to extend the current exemptions and include games with an online connection as well. This would allow libraries, archives, and museums to operate servers for these abandoned games and keep them alive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The nonprofit museum is not alone in its call, with digital rights group &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.publicknowledge.org/&quot;&gt;Public Knowledge&lt;/a&gt; submitting a similar comment. They also highlight the need to preserve online games. Not just for nostalgic gamers, but also for researchers and scholars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This issue is more relevant than ever before, as hundreds of online multiplayer games have been abandoned already.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It is difficult to quantify the number of multiplayer servers that have been shut down in recent years. However, Electronic Arts’ ‘Online Services Shutdown’ list is one illustrative example,” Public Knowledge writes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The list — which is littered with popular franchises such as FIFA World Cup, Nascar, and The Sims — currently stands at 319 games and servers discontinued since 2013, or just over one game per week since 2012.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, several ‘regular’ gaming fans have also made their feelings known. While their arguments are usually not as elaborate, the personal pleasure people still get out of older games can’t be overstated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I have been playing video games since the Atari 2600, for 35 years. Nowadays, game ‘museums’ — getting the opportunity to replay games from my youth, and share them with my child — are a source of joy for me,” one individual commenter wrote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I would love the opportunity to explore some of the early online / MMO games that I spent so much time on in the past!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Game on?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;—&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;sup&gt;Header image via &lt;a href=&quot;https://mmos.com/review/star-wars-galaxies&quot;&gt;MMOs.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2017 20:17:53 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>duramato</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Gamers Want DMCA Exemption for 'Abandoned' Online Games - TorrentFreak</og:title>
<og:description>Several organizations and gaming fans are asking the Copyright Office to make a DMCA circumvention exemption for abandoned online games, to preserve them for future generations. The exemption would allow museums and libraries to offer copies of abandoned online servers, so these games won't turn to dust.</og:description>
<og:url>https://torrentfreak.com/gamers-want-dmca-exemption-for-abandoned-online-games-171221/</og:url>
<og:image>https://torrentfreak.com/images/swgammo.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://torrentfreak.com/gamers-want-dmca-exemption-for-abandoned-online-games-171221/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Open-sourcing MonkeyType – Let your Python code type-hint itself</title>
<link>https://engineering.instagram.com/let-your-code-type-hint-itself-introducing-open-source-monkeytype-a855c7284881</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://engineering.instagram.com/let-your-code-type-hint-itself-introducing-open-source-monkeytype-a855c7284881</guid>
<description>&lt;p name=&quot;9513&quot; id=&quot;9513&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;Today we are excited to announce we’re open-sourcing &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Instagram/MonkeyType&quot; data-href=&quot;https://github.com/Instagram/MonkeyType&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;MonkeyType&lt;/a&gt;, our tool for automatically adding type annotations to your Python 3 code via runtime tracing of types seen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 name=&quot;9612&quot; id=&quot;9612&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Motivation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;3433&quot; id=&quot;3433&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;At Instagram we have hundreds of engineers working on well over a million lines of Python 3. Every day we have new engineers joining the team from other projects and other languages who need to ramp up quickly and get productive in our codebase. And we’re constantly shipping new code into production, every few minutes, all day long, every day. So we’re keen to make our code easier for new developers to read and understand, as well as more amenable to static analysis that shrinks the domain of possible bugs. Type annotations and static type checking fit that bill.&lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt;Writing new code with type annotations is easy enough; most of our engineers are eager to do that. But the returns on static type checking are low until we reach a critical mass of type-annotated code, especially our core frameworks and libraries. In other words: we have a &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of existing code that needs type annotations added.&lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt;Our first forays into manually adding type annotations were discouraging. It can take hours to annotate a single module, sometimes painstakingly tracing through multiple layers of function calls and objects to understand the possible types at some call site. (This is, of course, the same pain that anyone trying to maintain that function might experience; that’s why we want to add type annotations!)&lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt;So we built MonkeyType. Instead of guessing or spelunking for the right types, let your test suite or (better!) your production system tell you what the real types are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 name=&quot;8266&quot; id=&quot;8266&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Usage&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;e6d2&quot; id=&quot;e6d2&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;Sounds great! I’ve run &lt;code class=&quot;markup--code markup--p-code&quot;&gt;pip install monkeytype&lt;/code&gt;. What's next?&lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt;Before MonkeyType can tell us anything useful, we need to let it trace some function calls. The simplest way to do this is with &lt;code class=&quot;markup--code markup--p-code&quot;&gt;monkeytype run&lt;/code&gt;, which runs any Python script under MonkeyType tracing. For instance, you can easily run your test suite under MonkeyType:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre name=&quot;a336&quot; id=&quot;a336&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--pre graf-after--p&quot;&gt;
$ monkeytype run runtests.py
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;590c&quot; id=&quot;590c&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--pre&quot;&gt;(or &lt;code class=&quot;markup--code markup--p-code&quot;&gt;monkeytype run `which pytest`&lt;/code&gt;, or whatever your preferred flavor.)&lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt;While your tests are running, MonkeyType inspects the argument types and return/yield type of every function call, recording them in a database. (By default it keeps them in a local SQLite database, but like just about everything MonkeyType does, &lt;a href=&quot;http://monkeytype.readthedocs.io/en/latest/configuration.html#monkeytype.config.Config.trace_store&quot; data-href=&quot;http://monkeytype.readthedocs.io/en/latest/configuration.html#monkeytype.config.Config.trace_store&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;this is configurable&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;8cb4&quot; id=&quot;8cb4&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Of course, your test suite may not provide the best type information — sometimes tests use fakes instead of the real types, and we’ve found plenty of cases where type checking revealed that our tests were accidentally passing in different types from production. So if you don’t want to annotate based on your test suite, you can record call traces from production runtime. For this use case, MonkeyType provides &lt;a href=&quot;http://monkeytype.readthedocs.io/en/latest/tracing.html#trace-context-manager&quot; data-href=&quot;http://monkeytype.readthedocs.io/en/latest/tracing.html#trace-context-manager&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;a context manager API&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre name=&quot;9c4b&quot; id=&quot;9c4b&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--pre graf-after--p&quot;&gt;
from monkeytype import trace
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre name=&quot;157a&quot; id=&quot;157a&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--pre graf-after--pre&quot;&gt;
with trace():&lt;br/&gt;# ...
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;bc6f&quot; id=&quot;bc6f&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--pre&quot;&gt;If you need even more flexibility, you can &lt;a href=&quot;http://monkeytype.readthedocs.io/en/latest/tracing.html#calltracer&quot; data-href=&quot;http://monkeytype.readthedocs.io/en/latest/tracing.html#calltracer&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;create your own&lt;/a&gt; &lt;code class=&quot;markup--code markup--p-code&quot;&gt;CallTracer&lt;/code&gt;, install it with &lt;code class=&quot;markup--code markup--p-code&quot;&gt;sys.setprofile()&lt;/code&gt;, and remove it when you're ready.&lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt;Once you've got some call traces recorded, you can generate a stub file for any module:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre name=&quot;9db3&quot; id=&quot;9db3&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--pre graf-after--p&quot;&gt;
$ monkeytype stub some.module
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;4133&quot; id=&quot;4133&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--pre&quot;&gt;If the stub looks reasonable and you want to apply the annotations directly to your code, MonkeyType will do that too:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre name=&quot;4723&quot; id=&quot;4723&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--pre graf-after--p&quot;&gt;
$ monkeytype apply some.module
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;8134&quot; id=&quot;8134&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--pre&quot;&gt;Review the now-annotated code in &lt;code class=&quot;markup--code markup--p-code&quot;&gt;some/module.py&lt;/code&gt;, correct the annotations if needed, and commit it!&lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt;Because of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://monkeytype.readthedocs.io/en/latest/stores.html&quot; data-href=&quot;http://monkeytype.readthedocs.io/en/latest/stores.html&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;backing-store design&lt;/a&gt;, you don't have to record traces and annotate all at one go. You can collect traces into the database over a long period of time and gradually annotate more and more modules from the collected data as you're ready to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;8be6&quot; id=&quot;8be6&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;With &lt;a href=&quot;http://monkeytype.readthedocs.io/en/latest/generation.html#type-rewriters&quot; data-href=&quot;http://monkeytype.readthedocs.io/en/latest/generation.html#type-rewriters&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;configurable type rewriters&lt;/a&gt;, you can easily tweak MonkeyType’s generated type annotations for your preferred type annotation style or specific edge cases in your codebase.&lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt; For lots more details on customization options, refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://monkeytype.readthedocs.io&quot; data-href=&quot;https://monkeytype.readthedocs.io&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;the documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 name=&quot;1b38&quot; id=&quot;1b38&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Open Source&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;50d0&quot; id=&quot;50d0&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;Check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Instagram/MonkeyType&quot; data-href=&quot;https://github.com/Instagram/MonkeyType&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;the code&lt;/a&gt;, give it a spin, and let us know what you think! We’re looking forward to your bug reports and suggested improvements. If you’d like to contribute, we have a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Instagram/MonkeyType/issues?q=is%3Aissue+is%3Aopen+label%3A%22good+first+issue%22&quot; data-href=&quot;https://github.com/Instagram/MonkeyType/issues?q=is%3Aissue+is%3Aopen+label%3A%22good+first+issue%22&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;list of suggested starter tasks&lt;/a&gt; in the issue tracker.&lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt;MonkeyType does require Python 3.6+, and generates only Python 3 style type annotations (no type comments). If you aren’t quite there yet, you may want to start with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=66XoCk79kjM&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=66XoCk79kjM&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;our PyCon 2017 keynote&lt;/a&gt; on how we migrated those million lines of code to Python 3 last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 name=&quot;1140&quot; id=&quot;1140&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf-after--p&quot;&gt;How we use MonkeyType at Instagram&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;007c&quot; id=&quot;007c&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;We choose a small random sample of production web requests and turn on MonkeyType tracing via a Django middleware. Traces are stored and retrieved from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/notes/facebook-engineering/under-the-hood-data-diving-with-scuba/10150599692628920/&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/notes/facebook-engineering/under-the-hood-data-diving-with-scuba/10150599692628920/&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;SCUBA&lt;/a&gt;, Facebook’s data analysis platform, using &lt;a href=&quot;http://monkeytype.readthedocs.io/en/latest/stores.html&quot; data-href=&quot;http://monkeytype.readthedocs.io/en/latest/stores.html&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;a custom CallTraceStore&lt;/a&gt;. We run tracing constantly, so we are always adding new type traces from production. Since production code changes frequently, this keeps our traces up to date.&lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt;Whenever an engineer wants to add type annotations to a module, they just run &lt;code class=&quot;markup--code markup--p-code&quot;&gt;monkeytype stub&lt;/code&gt; and then &lt;code class=&quot;markup--code markup--p-code&quot;&gt;monkeytype apply&lt;/code&gt;, fix any type errors revealed by the new annotations, and submit a diff!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 name=&quot;6fc1&quot; id=&quot;6fc1&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Results&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;69b3&quot; id=&quot;69b3&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;With MonkeyType’s help, we’ve already annotated over a third of the functions in our codebase, and we’re already seeing type-checking catch many bugs that would have otherwise likely shipped to production. Race you to 100%!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;fff7&quot; id=&quot;fff7&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p graf--trailing&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;Carl Meyer is an engineer on Instagram’s infrastructure team.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2017 20:16:08 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ambivalence</dc:creator>
<og:title>Let your code type-hint itself: introducing open source MonkeyType</og:title>
<og:url>https://engineering.instagram.com/let-your-code-type-hint-itself-introducing-open-source-monkeytype-a855c7284881</og:url>
<og:description>Today we are excited to announce we’re open-sourcing MonkeyType, our tool for automatically adding type annotations to your Python 3 code…</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://engineering.instagram.com/let-your-code-type-hint-itself-introducing-open-source-monkeytype-a855c7284881?gi=10b8a2d0e556</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Apple Says Apps Must Now Disclose Odds for Loot Boxes</title>
<link>https://kotaku.com/apple-says-itunes-apps-must-now-disclose-odds-for-loot-1821497923</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://kotaku.com/apple-says-itunes-apps-must-now-disclose-odds-for-loot-1821497923</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;img-wrapper lazy-image&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-permalink-sub-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;js_lightbox-wrapper lightbox-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.kinja-img.com/gawker-media/image/upload/s--fbrCY5ix--/c_scale,fl_progressive,q_80,w_800/nrx5hz31v79uumuvu7yi.png&quot; class=&quot;lazyload ls-lazy-image-tag&quot; data-sizes=&quot;auto&quot; data-width=&quot;951&quot; data-chomp-id=&quot;nrx5hz31v79uumuvu7yi&quot; data-format=&quot;png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
The Simpsons Tapped Out is one of many iOS games to include loot boxes.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple announced &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/news/?id=12202017a&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; onclick=&quot;window.ga('send', 'event', 'Embedded Url', 'External link', 'https://developer.apple.com/news/?id=12202017a', {metric25:1})&quot;&gt;a sweeping revision to the guidelines for its App Store yesterday&lt;/a&gt;, which now includes a provision that loot boxes must be transparent about their odds.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Apps offering ‘loot boxes’ or other mechanisms that provide randomized virtual items for purchase must disclose the odds of receiving each type of item to customers prior to purchase,” reads the new rule, which will affect the most popular games on iOS, including &lt;em&gt;Hearthstone&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;The Simpsons Tapped Out&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Clash Royale&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Loot boxes, which have always been common in the world of iOS gaming, are virtual grab bags that can give players a host of items ranging from common to rare. Most of the time, you can buy these loot boxes not just for in-game currency but for real money, which has led some players to classify them as gambling—a label that &lt;a href=&quot;https://kotaku.com/esrb-says-it-doesnt-see-loot-boxes-as-gambling-1819363091&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; onclick=&quot;window.ga('send', 'event', 'Embedded Url', 'Internal link', 'https://kotaku.com/esrb-says-it-doesnt-see-loot-boxes-as-gambling-1819363091', {metric25:1})&quot;&gt;the Entertainment Software Rating Board doesn’t acknowledge&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This news comes after a year full of controversy over loot boxes, which many players see as manipulative, predatory methods to get them to spend more money on games. Although many mobile games have always had them, loot boxes received renewed attention this year thanks to their inclusion in console games like &lt;em&gt;Shadow of War&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Star Wars Battlefront II&lt;/em&gt;. Rage over the latter game dominated its launch to the point where its publisher, EA, announced the day before release that &lt;a href=&quot;https://kotaku.com/ea-temporarily-removes-microtransactions-from-star-wars-1820528445&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; onclick=&quot;window.ga('send', 'event', 'Embedded Url', 'Internal link', 'https://kotaku.com/ea-temporarily-removes-microtransactions-from-star-wars-1820528445', {metric25:1})&quot;&gt;it was temporarily removing all of &lt;em&gt;Battlefront II&lt;/em&gt;’s microtransactions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As rage over these practices gets louder and louder, Apple’s move is the first of what may be many steps that game publishers and distributors voluntarily take in an attempt to avoid regulation from outside bodies.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2017 17:35:27 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>kelukelugames</dc:creator>
<og:title>Apple Says Apps Must Now Disclose Odds For Loot Boxes</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:image>https://i.kinja-img.com/gawker-media/image/upload/s--i05n2NU---/c_fill,fl_progressive,g_center,h_450,q_80,w_800/nrx5hz31v79uumuvu7yi.png</og:image>
<og:url>https://kotaku.com/apple-says-itunes-apps-must-now-disclose-odds-for-loot-1821497923</og:url>
<og:description>Apple announced a sweeping revision to the guidelines for its App Store yesterday, which now includes a provision that loot boxes must be transparent about their odds.</og:description>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://kotaku.com/apple-says-itunes-apps-must-now-disclose-odds-for-loot-1821497923</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Chrome is Not the Standard</title>
<link>http://www.chriskrycho.com/2017/chrome-is-not-the-standard.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.chriskrycho.com/2017/chrome-is-not-the-standard.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Over the past few years, I’ve increasingly seen articles with headlines that run something like, “New Feature Coming To the Web”—followed by content which described how Chrome had implemented an experimental new feature. “You’ll be able to use this soon!” has been the promise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reality is a bit more complicated. Sometimes, ideas the Chrome team pioneers make their way out to the rest of the browsers and become tools we can all use. Sometimes… they get shelved because none of the other browsers decide to implement them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many times, when this latter tack happens, developers grouse about the other browser makers who are “holding the web back.” But there is a fundamental problem in this way of looking at things: &lt;em&gt;Chrome isn’t the standard.&lt;/em&gt; The fact that Chrome proposes something, and even the fact that a bunch of developers like it, does not a standard make. Nor does it impose an obligation to other browsers to prioritize it, or even to ship it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As web developers, it can be easy to become focused on interesting new features for the platform we work on. That’s no different than the excitement Android and iOS developers have when Google and Apple release new SDKs for developing on their platforms. It’s healthy to be excited about possible new features, things that might make our jobs easier or enable us to do things we couldn’t do before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; an important difference between those platforms and the web. Those platforms are the domain of a single vendor. The web is a shared platform. This is its unique benefit, and its unique cost. It uniquely allows us to write software that can actually run, and run reasonably well, &lt;em&gt;everywhere&lt;/em&gt;. But it also means that a minimum of four companies—the major browser vendors—get a say in whether a feature is a &lt;em&gt;feature&lt;/em&gt; or whether it’s just an interesting idea one of the teams had.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s get concrete about an example that’s been extremely high-profile for the last couple years—and, to be clear, one I think is a &lt;em&gt;good&lt;/em&gt; idea from Google: &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/web/progressive-web-apps/&quot; title=&quot;Google’s PWA page&quot;&gt;progressive web apps&lt;/a&gt; (hereafter &lt;abbr title=&quot;Progressive Web App&quot;&gt;PWA&lt;/abbr&gt;). They have been pitched by Google and other supporters as an unambiguous win for the user experience of complex web applications. And, as a web developer myself, I’m actually inclined to agree with that assessment! However, I have fairly regularly seen people getting angry at especially Apple for not prioritizing support for &lt;abbr title=&quot;Progressive Web App&quot;&gt;PWA&lt;/abbr&gt;s in (especially iOS) Safari—Apple is, in this view, “holding back the future of the web.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well… no. For any given idea Google pitches, Apple may or may not be sold on Google’s vision of the web, or they may even think it’s a good idea but not &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; important than other things they’re working on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this is what it &lt;em&gt;means&lt;/em&gt; to be part of the web platform. No single company gets to dominate the others in terms of setting the agenda for the web. Not Firefox, with its development and advocacy of &lt;a href=&quot;http://webassembly.org/&quot;&gt;WebAssembly&lt;/a&gt;, dear to my heart though that is. Not Microsoft and the IE/Edge team, with its proposal of the CSS grid spec in &lt;em&gt;2011&lt;/em&gt;, sad though I am that it languished for as long as it did. Not Apple, with its pitch for &lt;a href=&quot;https://webkit.org/blog/7846/concurrent-javascript-it-can-work/&quot; title=&quot;“Concurrent JavaScript: it can work!”&quot;&gt;concurrent JavaScript&lt;/a&gt;. And not—however good its developer relations team is—Chrome, with any of the many ideas it’s constantly trying out, including &lt;abbr title=&quot;Progressive Web App&quot;&gt;PWA&lt;/abbr&gt;s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s also worth recognizing how these decisions aren’t, in almost any case, unalloyed pushes for “the future of the web.” They reflect &lt;em&gt;business&lt;/em&gt; priorities, just like any other technical prioritization. Google cares about &lt;abbr title=&quot;Progressive Web App&quot;&gt;PWA&lt;/abbr&gt;s because Google makes its money from the web and wants people to spend more of their time on the web. Apple cares about things like the battery life implications and the sheer speed of its iOS JavaScript engine because it makes money from hardware and it wants people to be happy with their iPhones and iPads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does any one of those browser’s commitments map cleanly to &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; users’ (or even all &lt;em&gt;developers’&lt;/em&gt;) priorities? Of course not! This is and always has been the beauty of a competitive browser landscape. I’m a web developer who wants &lt;abbr title=&quot;Progressive Web App&quot;&gt;PWA&lt;/abbr&gt; support everywhere—so I want Apple supporting it. But I’m also a smartphone user who wants those applications to &lt;em&gt;scream&lt;/em&gt; on my device—not to crawl, like they do on Chrome on Android, which is still years behind iOS in performance. As an end user, not just a developer, it matters to me that running Safari on my laptop instead of Chrome can dramatically increase my battery life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are tradeoffs, plain and simple. Chrome ships new features fast, but they’re not always stable and they often have performance costs. Safari ships new features on a much slower cadence, but they’re usually solid and always perform incredibly well. These are both engineering and business tradeoffs, and the companies behind the browsers are making because of their own business and engineering priorities. Don’t valorize any of the browser vendors, and don’t act as if &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; of them is the standard, or a reliable predictor of the future. Instead, value what each brings to the table, but also value the interplay &lt;em&gt;at&lt;/em&gt; the table, and the ways each of these vendors pushes the others and challenges the others’ assumptions of what is most important. That’s what makes the web so great, even when it makes things move more slowly. Sometimes—often, even!—moving more slowly not in the &lt;em&gt;experimental&lt;/em&gt; phase but in the &lt;em&gt;finalizing&lt;/em&gt; phase makes for a much better outcome overall.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2017 17:14:37 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>chriskrycho</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://www.chriskrycho.com/2017/chrome-is-not-the-standard.html</og:url>
<og:title>Chrome is Not the Standard</og:title>
<og:description>No single browser vendor represents ”the future of the web.” Each ships in line with its own business priorities. And that's a good thing.</og:description>
<og:image>http://www.chriskrycho.com//assets/images/ck.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.chriskrycho.com/2017/chrome-is-not-the-standard.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Rust in 2017: what we achieved</title>
<link>https://blog.rust-lang.org/2017/12/21/rust-in-2017.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.rust-lang.org/2017/12/21/rust-in-2017.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Rust’s development in 2017 fit into a single overarching theme: &lt;strong&gt;increasing productivity, especially for newcomers to Rust&lt;/strong&gt;. From tooling to libraries to documentation to the core language, we wanted to make it easier to get things done with Rust. That desire led to &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.rust-lang.org/2017/02/06/roadmap.html&quot;&gt;a roadmap&lt;/a&gt; for the year, setting out 8 high-level objectives that would guide the work of the team.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;How’d we do? &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Really, really well&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s not room in a single post to cover everything that happened, but we’ll cover some of the highlights below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;rust-should-have-a-lower-learning-curve&quot;&gt;Rust should have a lower learning curve&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Books&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RustBridge curriculum&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://rustbridge.github.io/&quot;&gt;RustBridge workshops&lt;/a&gt; are focused on getting underrepresented people into Rust. Ashley Williams has vastly improved &lt;a href=&quot;https://rustbridge.github.io/a-very-brief-intro-to-rust/#1&quot;&gt;the workshop curriculum&lt;/a&gt; this year, and we’re planning on having a teacher training in early 2018. The curriculum is available for anyone to use, as long as events are only called RustBridge if they focus on underrepresented folks. See more about RustBridge in 2017 under the Mentorship goal!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Language improvements&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;rust-should-have-a-pleasant-edit-compile-debug-cycle&quot;&gt;Rust should have a pleasant edit-compile-debug cycle&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;cargo check&lt;/code&gt; workflow&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Cargo &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.rust-lang.org/2017/03/16/Rust-1.16.html&quot;&gt;now offers&lt;/a&gt; a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;check&lt;/code&gt; subcommand which can be used to speed up the edit-compile cycle when you’re working on getting your code to pass the compiler’s checks. This mode, in particular, skips producing executable artifacts for crates in the dependency tree, instead doing just enough work to be able to type check the current crate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Incremental recompilation&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The cornerstone of our approach to improving compilation times is incremental recompilation, allowing rebuilds to reuse significant pieces of work from prior compilations. Over the course of the year we have put a lot of work into making this happen and now we are happy to announce that incremental compilation will &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.rust-lang.org/2014/10/30/Stability.html&quot;&gt;start riding the trains&lt;/a&gt; with the next beta version of the compiler in January and become available on the stable channel with Rust 1.24 in February!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can see how incremental recompilation performs in practice on some of our key benchmarks below. Note that &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;-opt&lt;/code&gt; refers to optimized builds, “best case” refers to a recompilation with no changes, and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;println&lt;/code&gt; refers to a recompilation with a small change, like adding a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;println&lt;/code&gt; call to a function body. We expect the 50+% speedups we’re seeing now to continue to grow next year as we push incremental recompilation more deeply through the compiler.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Together with the changes in the compiler we will also update Cargo to use incremental recompilation by default for select use cases, so you can take advantage of improved compile times without the need for additional configuration. Of course you will also be able to opt into and out of the feature on a case by case basis as you see fit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.rust-lang.org/images/2017-12-Retro/incr-bench.png&quot; alt=&quot;Incremental recompilation benchmarks&quot; class=&quot;center&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;rust-should-provide-a-solid-but-basic-ide-experience&quot;&gt;Rust should provide a solid, but basic IDE experience&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Rust now has solid IDE support in IntelliJ and via the Rust Language Server (RLS). Whether you prefer a fully-featured IDE or a more lightweight editor with IDE features, you can boost your productivity by taking advantage of great Rust integration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IntelliJ&lt;/strong&gt;. Rust has official support in &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.jetbrains.com/blog/2017/08/04/official-support-for-open-source-rust-plugin-for-intellij-idea-clion-and-other-jetbrains-ides/&quot;&gt;JetBrains’ IDEs&lt;/a&gt; (IntelliJ IDEA, CLion, WebStorm, etc.), which includes:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Finding types, functions and traits across the whole project, its dependencies and the standard library.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hierarchical overview of the symbols defined in the current file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Search for all implementations of a given trait.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to definition of symbol at cursor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Navigation to the parent module.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Refactoring and code generation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RLS&lt;/strong&gt;. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang-nursery/rls&quot;&gt;RLS&lt;/a&gt; is an editor-independent source of intelligence about Rust programs. It is used to power Rust support in many editors including &lt;a href=&quot;https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=rust-lang.rust&quot;&gt;Visual Studio Code&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=DanielGriffen.Rust&quot;&gt;Visual Studio&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://atom.io/packages/ide-rust&quot;&gt;Atom&lt;/a&gt;, with more in the pipeline. It is on schedule for a 1.0 release in early 2018, but is currently &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.rust-lang.org/2017/10/12/Rust-1.21.html&quot;&gt;available in preview form&lt;/a&gt; for all channels (nightly, beta, and stable). It supports:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Code completion (using Racer)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to definition (and peek definition if the editor supports it)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find all references&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find impls for a type or trait&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Symbol search (current file and project)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reformatting using rustfmt, renaming&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apply error suggestions (e.g., to add missing imports)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Docs and types on hover&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Code generation using snippets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cargo tasks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Installation and update of the RLS (via rustup)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;rust-should-integrate-easily-into-large-build-systems&quot;&gt;Rust should integrate easily into large build systems&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alternative registries.&lt;/strong&gt; Cargo now has unstable support for &lt;a href=&quot;http://rust-lang.github.io/rfcs/2141-alternative-registries.html&quot;&gt;installing crates from registries other than crates.io&lt;/a&gt;. This will enable companies to manage and use internal crates as easily as open source crates. Work is underway developing crate servers that are more tailored for private use than the crates.io server is.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cargo as a component&lt;/strong&gt;. A lot of work this year went into gathering constraints from stakeholders who want to integrate Rust crates into a large existing build system (like &lt;a href=&quot;https://bazel.build/&quot;&gt;Bazel&lt;/a&gt;). The Cargo team has &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rfcs/pull/2136&quot;&gt;formulated a vision&lt;/a&gt; of Cargo as a suite of components that can be customized or swapped out, making it easy for an external build system to manage the work it is built to do, while still integrating with crates.io and with Cargo workflows. While we did not get as far as we hoped in terms of implementing this vision, there is ongoing work spiking out “build plan generation” to a sufficient degree that it can support the Firefox build system and &lt;a href=&quot;http://gittup.org/tup/&quot;&gt;Tup&lt;/a&gt;. This initial spike should provide a good strawman for further iteration in early 2018.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;rust-should-provide-easy-access-to-high-quality-crates&quot;&gt;Rust should provide easy access to high quality crates&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;rust-should-be-well-equipped-for-writing-robust-servers&quot;&gt;Rust should be well-equipped for writing robust servers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Futures and Tokio&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Much of the story for Rust on the server has revolved around its async I/O story. The futures crate &lt;a href=&quot;http://aturon.github.io/blog/2016/08/11/futures/&quot;&gt;was introduced&lt;/a&gt; in late 2016, and the Tokio project (which provides a networking-focused event loop for use with futures) &lt;a href=&quot;https://tokio.rs/blog/tokio-0-1/&quot;&gt;published its 0.1&lt;/a&gt; early in 2017. Since then, there’s been significant work building out the “Tokio ecosystem”, and a lot of feedback about the core primitives. Late in the year, the Tokio team proposed a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tokio-rs/tokio-rfcs/pull/3&quot;&gt;significant API revamp&lt;/a&gt; to streamline and clarify the crate’s API, and work is underway on a book dedicated to asynchronous programming in Rust. This latest round of work is expected to land very early in 2018.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Async ecosystem&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;There’s been huge growth in the ecosystem around Tokio, including support for &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tokio-rs/tokio-curl&quot;&gt;curl&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/alexcrichton/tokio-openssl&quot;&gt;openssl&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/dermesser/tokio-inotify&quot;&gt;inotify&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/alexcrichton/tokio-signal&quot;&gt;unix signals&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/dwrensha/capnproto-rust&quot;&gt;cap’n proto&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://crates.io/crates/tk-sendfile&quot;&gt;sendfile&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://crates.io/crates/tokio-postgres&quot;&gt;postgres&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://crates.io/crates/couchbase&quot;&gt;couchbase&lt;/a&gt;, and more. In addition, Rust has async server libraries for both &lt;a href=&quot;http://hyper.rs/&quot;&gt;HTTP1&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/carllerche/h2&quot;&gt;HTTP2.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Generators&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Thanks to a heroic community effort, Rust also saw &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rfcs/pull/2033&quot;&gt;experimental generator support&lt;/a&gt; land in 2017! That support provides the ingredients necessary for &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;async&lt;/code&gt;/&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;await&lt;/code&gt; notation, which is &lt;a href=&quot;https://internals.rust-lang.org/t/help-test-async-await-generators-coroutines/5835&quot;&gt;usable today&lt;/a&gt; on nightly. Further work in this area is expected to be a high priority in early 2018.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Web frameworks&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Finally, sophisticated web frameworks like &lt;a href=&quot;https://rocket.rs/&quot;&gt;Rocket&lt;/a&gt; (sync) and &lt;a href=&quot;http://gotham.rs/&quot;&gt;Gotham&lt;/a&gt; (async) have continued to evolve this year, and take advantage of Rust’s expressivity to provide a robust but productive style of programming.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;rust-should-have-10-level-crates-for-essential-tasks&quot;&gt;Rust should have 1.0-level crates for essential tasks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Libz Blitz&lt;/strong&gt;. The library team launched the &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.rust-lang.org/2017/05/05/libz-blitz.html&quot;&gt;Libz Blitz&lt;/a&gt; this year, a major effort to vet and improve a large number of foundational crates and push them toward 1.0 releases. It was a massive community effort: we performed a crowd-sourced “crate evaluation” every two weeks, fully vetting a crate against a clear set of guidelines, assessing the issue tracker, and sussing out any remaining design questions. While not all of the assessed crates have published a 1.0 yet, they are all very close to doing so. The full list includes: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang-nursery/log/issues?q=is%3Aissue+is%3Aopen+label%3A%22help+wanted%22&quot;&gt;log&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sebasmagri/env_logger/issues?q=is%3Aissue+is%3Aopen+label%3A%22help+wanted%22&quot;&gt;env_logger&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/nikomatsakis/rayon/issues?q=is%3Aissue+is%3Aopen+label%3A%22help+wanted%22&quot;&gt;rayon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/carllerche/mio/issues?utf8=%E2%9C%93&amp;amp;q=is%3Aissue%20is%3Aopen%20label%3A%22help%20wanted%22%20&quot;&gt;mio&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/servo/rust-url/issues/319&quot;&gt;url&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/seanmonstar/num_cpus/issues/55&quot;&gt;num_cpus&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/steveklabnik/semver/issues/139&quot;&gt;semver&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/hyperium/mime/labels/help%20wanted&quot;&gt;mime&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/seanmonstar/reqwest/issues?q=is%3Aissue+is%3Aopen+label%3Aeasy&quot;&gt;reqwest&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang-nursery/tempdir/issues?q=is%3Aissue+is%3Aopen+label%3A%22help+wanted%22&quot;&gt;tempdir&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-threadpool/rust-threadpool/issues/86&quot;&gt;threadpool&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/BurntSushi/byteorder/issues?utf8=%E2%9C%93&amp;amp;q=is%3Aissue%20is%3Aopen%20label%3A%22help%20wanted%22%20&quot;&gt;byteorder&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang-nursery/bitflags/issues?utf8=%E2%9C%93&amp;amp;q=is%3Aissue%20is%3Aopen%20label%3A%22help%20wanted%22%20&quot;&gt;bitflags&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/alexcrichton/cc-rs&quot;&gt;cc-rs&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/BurntSushi/walkdir/issues/47&quot;&gt;walkdir&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://crates.io/crates/same-file&quot;&gt;same-file&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://crates.io/crates/memmap&quot;&gt;memmap&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang-nursery/lazy-static.rs/issues?utf8=%E2%9C%93&amp;amp;q=is%3Aopen%20is%3Aissue%20label%3A%22help%20wanted%22%20&quot;&gt;lazy_static&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/alexcrichton/flate2-rs/issues?q=is%3Aissue+is%3Aopen+label%3A%22help+wanted%22&quot;&gt;flate2&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;API Guidelines&lt;/strong&gt;. A great by-product of the Libz Blitz is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://rust-lang-nursery.github.io/api-guidelines/&quot;&gt;API Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; book, which consolidates the official library team API guidance as informed by the standard library and the Libz Blitz process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;We ran 5 &lt;a href=&quot;https://rustbridge.github.io/&quot;&gt;RustBridge Workshops&lt;/a&gt; in 2017, in Kyiv, Ukraine; Mexico City, Mexico; Portland, OR, USA; Zurich, Switzerland; and Columbus, OH, USA! RustBridge workshops aim to get underrepresented folks started in Rust. Attendees get an introduction to syntax and concepts, work on some &lt;a href=&quot;http://exercism.io/&quot;&gt;exercism&lt;/a&gt; exercises, and build a web application that delivers emergency compliments and crab pictures. We hope to scale this program and help more folks run more workshops in 2018!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.rust-lang.org/2017/06/27/Increasing-Rusts-Reach.html&quot;&gt;Increasing Rust’s Reach program&lt;/a&gt; brought people with skills from other areas (such as teaching) and with different experiences into Rust so that we can improve in areas where the community is missing these skills and experiences. The participants have helped immensely, and many are planning to continue helping in the Rust community going forward. We’re glad they’re here! Here are some blog posts about the experience:
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Last but not least, we also launched the first Rust &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.rust-lang.org/2017/09/18/impl-future-for-rust.html&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;impl Period&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. This was an ambitious effort to simultaneously help get a lot of new people contributing to the Rust ecosystem while also getting a lot of things done. To that end, we created 40+ working groups, each with their own focus area, leaders, and chat channel. These groups identified good “entry points” for people who wanted to contribute, and helped mentor them through the changes needed. This event was a wild success and resulted in changes and contributions to all areas of Rust, ranging from the compiler internals to documentation to the ecosystem at large. To those of you who participated, a great big thank you — and please keep contributing! To those of you who didn’t get a chance, don’t worry: we hope to make this a regular tradition.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll be spinning up the 2018 roadmap process in the very near future; watch this space!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We got a staggering amount of work done this year — and the “we” here includes an equally staggering number of people. Because the work has been spread out over so many facets of the project, it’s hard to provide a single list of people who contributed. For the impl period specifically, you can see detailed contribution lists in the newsletters:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;but of course, there have been contributions of all kinds during the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this post, I’d like to specifically call out the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;leaders&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;mentors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; who have helped orchestrate our 2017 work. Leadership of this kind — where you are working to enable others — is hard work and not recognized enough. So let’s hand it to these folks!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cargo&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/carols10cents&quot;&gt;carols10cents&lt;/a&gt;, for sustained leadership and mentoring work throughout the year on crates.io.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Community&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Compiler&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/nikomatsakis/&quot;&gt;nikomatsakis&lt;/a&gt;, for an incredible amount of leadership, organization, and mentoring work, &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; for a lot of high-value hacking on NLL in particular.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/arielb1/&quot;&gt;arielb1&lt;/a&gt;, likewise for mentoring &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; hacking work, spanning both NLL and the rest of the compiler.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/michaelwoerister/&quot;&gt;michaelwoerister&lt;/a&gt;, for pushing continuously on delivering incremental recompilation, and creating opportunities for others to join in throughout the year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/eddyb&quot;&gt;eddyb&lt;/a&gt;, for continuing to act as a general compiler guru, and for tackling some truly heavy lifts around const generics this year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dev tools&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/nrc/&quot;&gt;nrc&lt;/a&gt;, for overseeing the dev tools group as a whole, and for steady work toward shipping the RLS and rustfmt, despite many thorny infrastructure problems to get there.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/matklad&quot;&gt;matklad&lt;/a&gt;, for the incredible work on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/intellij-rust/intellij-rust/blob/master/CONTRIBUTORS.txt&quot;&gt;IntelliJ Rust&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/intellij-rust/intellij-rust/blob/master/CONTRIBUTORS.txt&quot;&gt;.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/xanewok&quot;&gt;xanewok&lt;/a&gt;, for &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang-nursery/rls/graphs/contributors&quot;&gt;enormous efforts&lt;/a&gt; making the RLS a reality.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/fitzgen&quot;&gt;fitzgen&lt;/a&gt;, for happily corralling a huge contributor base around &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang-nursery/rust-bindgen&quot;&gt;bindgen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Docs&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/steveklabnik/&quot;&gt;steveklabnik&lt;/a&gt;, for launching and overseeing a hugely exciting revamp of rustdoc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/QuietMisdreavus&quot;&gt;quietmisdreavus&lt;/a&gt;, for overseeing tons of activity in the docs world, but most especially for helping the community significantly improve rustdoc this year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Infrastructure&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Mark-Simulacrum&quot;&gt;mark-simulacrum&lt;/a&gt;, for getting the &lt;a href=&quot;https://perf.rust-lang.org/&quot;&gt;perf&lt;/a&gt; website to a highly useful state, and for overhauling rustbuild to better support contribution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/aidanhs/&quot;&gt;aidanhs&lt;/a&gt;, for coordinating maintenance of crater.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Language&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/withoutboats/&quot;&gt;withoutboats&lt;/a&gt;, for keeping us focused on the programmer experience and for helping the community navigate discussion around very thorny language design issues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/cramertj/&quot;&gt;cramertj&lt;/a&gt;, for keeping us focused on &lt;em&gt;shipping&lt;/em&gt;, and in particular building consensus around some of the topics where that’s been hardest to find: impl Trait, and module system changes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/nikomatsakis/&quot;&gt;nikomatsakis&lt;/a&gt;, for making the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rfcs/pull/2094&quot;&gt;NLL RFC&lt;/a&gt; so accessible, and pioneering the idea of using a separate repo for it to allow for greater participation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Libraries&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/brson/&quot;&gt;brson&lt;/a&gt;, for envisioning and largely overseeing the Libz Blitz initiative.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kodraus&quot;&gt;kodraus&lt;/a&gt;, for gracefully taking over the Libz Blitz and seeing it to a successful conclusion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/dtolnay&quot;&gt;dtolnay&lt;/a&gt;, for taking on the API guidelines work and getting it to a coherent and polished state.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/budziq&quot;&gt;budziq&lt;/a&gt;, for a ton of work coordinating and editing contributions to the cookbook.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/dhardy&quot;&gt;dhardy&lt;/a&gt;, for leading a heroic effort to revamp the rand crate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Technical leaders are an essential ingredient for our success, and I hope in 2018 we can continue to grow our leadership pool, and get even more done — together.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2017 16:47:09 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>steveklabnik</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.rust-lang.org/2017/12/21/rust-in-2017.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Five years with Rust</title>
<link>http://words.steveklabnik.com/five-years-with-rust</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://words.steveklabnik.com/five-years-with-rust</guid>
<description>&lt;time datetime=&quot;2017-12-21&quot; class=&quot;article_time&quot;&gt;December 21, 2017&lt;/time&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today is five years since I first heard of Rust. &lt;a href=&quot;http://words.steveklabnik.com/four-years-with-rust&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;I wrote a post last year&lt;/a&gt; about it. This year, I have something slightly different in mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Five years is a long time in tech. It’s also a long time for me to be focused on one specific thing; other than the pizza job I held in high school and college, I’ve never stayed in a single job for five years. (This is true today as well; it’s not like I got a job with Rust the first day I learned of its existence.) I started with Ruby and Rails in 2008/2009, and my final commits to Rails were in August/September of 2013. So at this point, my career has basically been split in half, rather than dominated by Ruby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Five years ago tomorrow, I registered &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rustforrubyists.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://www.rustforrubyists.com/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I had lunch with someone I’m very honored to call a friend. We talked about a lot of things, but also about Rust’s past, present, and future. One thing I’ve always felt a little awkward about is that there was a crucial point back in 2011/2012 where I wasn’t sure what to do with myself. I was very frustrated by the industry, and considered doing other things instead. But, as they and I talked about, sometimes, it’s not about your interests. If what you want to do is change the world, caring a lot isn’t enough; you have to analyze what you can actually &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt;. While I think our industry is pretty broken, I at least have the ability to try and improve it, thanks to my stature. (God, even just typing that makes me feel gross.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to put my time into Rust because I believed, and still believe, that it’s an important thing. And I saw the work that needed to be done, and saw that it’s the kind of work that I could do. And so, it’s maybe not something bigger, but I resolved myself to doing the work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Five years in, I think my journey has been successful so far. I’m proud of how far Rust has come. That said, there’s a lot more work to do. I’m still committed as ever to getting that work done, and feel proud to be able to work alongside people as amazing as the Rust community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s to five more years. 🍻&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;691&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kudos&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;691&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kudos&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2017 16:46:17 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>doppp</dc:creator>
<og:title>Five years with Rust • Steve Klabnik</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>Today is five years since I first heard of Rust. I wrote a post last year about it. This year, I have something slightly different in mind. Five years is a long time in tech. It’s also a long time for me to be focused on one specific thing; other... | Steve Klabnik | &amp;ldquo;The most violent element in society is ignorance.&amp;rdquo; - Emma Goldman</og:description>
<og:image>https://d2l2xugcou6irs.cloudfront.net/svbtle_logo.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://words.steveklabnik.com/five-years-with-rust</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Start your open-source career</title>
<link>https://blog.algolia.com/start-your-open-source-career/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.algolia.com/start-your-open-source-career/</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot;&gt;This year I gave a talk about how to make open-source projects successful by ensuring everything is in place to attract all kinds of contributions: issues, documentation or code updates. After the talk, the feedback I got was “It’s nice, you showed how to make projects successful, but &lt;strong&gt;how do I even start&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;doing open-source?&lt;/strong&gt;“. This blog post is an answer to that question; it explains how and where to start contributing to projects and then how to create your own projects.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The knowledge shared here is based on our experience: at Algolia, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/algolia&quot;&gt;we have released&lt;/a&gt; and maintained multiple open-source projects that proved to be successful over time, and I have spent a good amount of time practicing and creating &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/vvo&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;open-source projects&lt;/a&gt; too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone wp-image-7230 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://blog.algolia.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/Pastebot-Dragged-Image-21-12-2017-140501-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;427&quot; srcset=&quot;https://blog.algolia.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/Pastebot-Dragged-Image-21-12-2017-140501-2.png 1100w, https://blog.algolia.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/Pastebot-Dragged-Image-21-12-2017-140501-2-320x124.png 320w, https://blog.algolia.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/Pastebot-Dragged-Image-21-12-2017-140501-2-768x298.png 768w, https://blog.algolia.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/Pastebot-Dragged-Image-21-12-2017-140501-2-720x279.png 720w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1100px) 100vw, 1100px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;A key moment for my career was six years ago at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fasterize.com/en/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Fasterize&lt;/a&gt; (a website performance accelerator). We faced an important &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Memory_leak&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;memory leak&lt;/a&gt; on our &lt;a href=&quot;https://nodejs.org/en/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Node.js&lt;/a&gt; workers. After searching everywhere except inside the actual Node.js codebase, we found nothing that could cause it. Our workaround was to restart the workers every day (this reset the memory usage to zero) and just live with it, but we knew this was not a very elegant solution and so &lt;strong&gt;I wanted to understand the problem &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;as a whole&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When my co-founder &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/stephanerios/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Stéphane&lt;/a&gt; suggested I have a look at the Node.js codebase, I almost laughed. I thought to myself: “If there’s a bug, it’s most probably our code, not the code from the developers who created a revolutionary server-side framework. But, OK, I’ll have a look”. Two days later &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/nodejs/node-v0.x-archive/pull/3181#issue-4313777&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;my two character fix&lt;/a&gt; to the http layer of Node.js was merged, and solved our own memory leak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doing this was a major confidence boost for me. Amongst the thirty other people who had contributed to the http.js file were folks I admired, like &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/isaacs/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;isaacs&lt;/a&gt; (npm creator)— making me realize that code is just… code, regardless of who wrote it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you experiencing a bug with an open-source project? Dig in and don’t stop at your local workaround. Your solution can benefit others and lead you to more open-source contributions. &lt;strong&gt;Read other people’s code&lt;/strong&gt;. You might not fix your issue right away, it might take some time to understand the code base, but you will learn new modules, new syntax and different ways to code that will make you grow as a developer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Opportunistic contributions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.algolia.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/image6.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone wp-image-7223 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://blog.algolia.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/image6.png&quot; alt=&quot;First contributions labels on the the Node.js repository&quot; width=&quot;1999&quot; height=&quot;566&quot; srcset=&quot;https://blog.algolia.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/image6.png 1999w, https://blog.algolia.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/image6-320x91.png 320w, https://blog.algolia.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/image6-768x217.png 768w, https://blog.algolia.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/image6-720x204.png 720w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1999px) 100vw, 1999px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;First contributions labels on the the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/nodejs/node/labels/good%20first%20issue&quot;&gt;Node.js repository&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I don’t have an idea” is a common complaint by developers who want to contribute to open-source but think they don’t have any good ideas or good projects to share. Well, to that I say: that’s OK. There are &lt;strong&gt;opportunistic ways to contribute to open-source&lt;/strong&gt;. Many projects have started to list good contributions for first-timers via labels or tags.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find contribution ideas by going through these websites: &lt;a href=&quot;https://opensourcefriday.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Open Source Friday&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.firsttimersonly.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;First Timers Only&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://yourfirstpr.github.io/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Your First PR&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.codetriage.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;CodeTriage&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://24pullrequests.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;24 Pull Requests&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://up-for-grabs.net/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Up For Grabs&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://contributor.ninja/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Contributor-ninja&lt;/a&gt; (the list comes from &lt;a href=&quot;https://opensource.guide/how-to-contribute/#finding-a-project-to-contribute-to&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;opensource.guide&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Build some tooling&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tooling is a nice way to publish something useful to others without having to think too much about complex problems or API design. You could publish a boilerplate for your favorite framework or platform that would gather the knowledge of many blog posts and tools into a nicely explained project, ready with live reload and publishing features. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/facebookincubator/create-react-app&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;create-react-app&lt;/a&gt; is one good example of such tooling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.algolia.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/image5-2.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-7222&quot; src=&quot;https://blog.algolia.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/image5-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot of GitHub's search for 58K boilerplate repositories &quot; width=&quot;1999&quot; height=&quot;644&quot; srcset=&quot;https://blog.algolia.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/image5-2.png 1999w, https://blog.algolia.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/image5-2-320x103.png 320w, https://blog.algolia.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/image5-2-768x247.png 768w, https://blog.algolia.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/image5-2-720x232.png 720w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1999px) 100vw, 1999px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;There are &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/search?utf8=%E2%9C%93&amp;amp;q=boilerplate&amp;amp;type=&quot;&gt;58K boilerplate&lt;/a&gt; repositories on GitHub, it’s easy and rewarding to publish one&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today you can also build pure JavaScript plugins for &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/blog/2231-building-your-first-atom-plugin&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Atom&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://code.visualstudio.com/docs/extensions/overview&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Visual Studio Code&lt;/a&gt; like we did with &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.algolia.com/atom-plugin-install-npm-module/&quot;&gt;our Atom autocomplete module import plugin&lt;/a&gt;. Is there a very good plugin for Atom or Sublime Text that does not yet exist in your favourite editor? &lt;strong&gt;Go build it&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, you could also create plugins for &lt;a href=&quot;https://webpack.js.org/contribute/writing-a-plugin/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;webpack&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/thejameskyle/babel-handbook&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;babel&lt;/a&gt; that are solving a particular use case of your JavaScript stack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The good thing is that most platforms will explain &lt;strong&gt;how to create and publish plugins&lt;/strong&gt; so you won’t have to think too much about how to do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Be the new maintainer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When browsing through projects on GitHub, you might sometimes find and use &lt;strong&gt;projects that are abandoned by their creator&lt;/strong&gt;. They are still valuable, but many issues and pull requests are sitting in the repository without any answer from the maintainer. &lt;strong&gt;What are your options?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Publish a fork under a new name&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be the new maintainer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;I recommend you do both at the same time. The former will help you move forward with your project while the latter will benefit you and the community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How to become the new maintainer, you ask? Drop an email or a tweet to the maintainer and say “Hey, I want to maintain this project, what do you think?”. This usually works well and is a great way to start your open-source career with a project that is already known and useful to others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.algolia.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/image2-2.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-7219&quot; src=&quot;https://blog.algolia.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/image2-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Example message sent to maintain an abandoned repository&quot; width=&quot;1999&quot; height=&quot;702&quot; srcset=&quot;https://blog.algolia.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/image2-2.png 1999w, https://blog.algolia.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/image2-2-320x112.png 320w, https://blog.algolia.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/image2-2-768x270.png 768w, https://blog.algolia.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/image2-2-720x253.png 720w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1999px) 100vw, 1999px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/vvoyer/status/744986995630424064&quot;&gt;Example tweet&lt;/a&gt; sent to revive an abandoned project&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best way to find your own project is to &lt;strong&gt;look at problems that today have no good solutions&lt;/strong&gt;. If you find yourself browsing the web for a particular library solving one of your problems and you don’t find it, then that’s the right time to create an open-source library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s another &lt;strong&gt;key moment&lt;/strong&gt; for my own career. At Fasterize we needed a fast and lightweight image lazy loader for our website performance accelerator —not a jQuery plugin but a standalone project that would be injected and must work on any website, on every browser. I spent hours searching the whole web for the perfect already-existing library and I failed at it. So I said: “We’re doomed. I can’t find a good project, we can’t do our startup”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To this, Stéphane replied: “Well, just create it”. Hmm.. ok then! I started by copy pasting a &lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/3228521/stand-alone-lazy-loading-images-no-framework-based&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;StackOverflow answer&lt;/a&gt; in a JavaScript file and ultimately &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/vvo/lazyload&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;built an image lazy loader&lt;/a&gt; that ended up being used on websites like &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flipkart&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Flipkart.com&lt;/a&gt; (~200M visits per month, #9 website in India). After this success, my mind was wired to open-source. I suddenly understood that open-source could be just another part of my developer career, instead of a field that only legends and &lt;a href=&quot;http://antirez.com/news/112&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;mythical 10x programmers&lt;/a&gt; fit into.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.algolia.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/image1-3.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignleft wp-image-7218 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://blog.algolia.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/image1-3.png&quot; alt=&quot;Stack Overflow screenshot &quot; width=&quot;1844&quot; height=&quot;764&quot; srcset=&quot;https://blog.algolia.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/image1-3.png 1844w, https://blog.algolia.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/image1-3-320x133.png 320w, https://blog.algolia.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/image1-3-768x318.png 768w, https://blog.algolia.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/image1-3-720x298.png 720w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1844px) 100vw, 1844px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A problem without any good solution: solve it in a reusable way!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Timing is important&lt;/strong&gt;. If you decide not to build a reusable library but rather inline some workaround code in your own application, then that’s a missed opportunity. At some point, someone will create the project you might have created. Instead, extract and publish reusable modules from your application as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Publish it, market it and share it&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be sure anyone willing to find your module will indeed find it, you must:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Create a good &lt;a href=&quot;https://opensource.guide/starting-a-project/#writing-a-readme&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;README&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a href=&quot;https://shields.io/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;badges&lt;/a&gt; and vanity metrics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a dedicated website with a nice design and online playground. Want some inspiration? Have a look at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/prettier/prettier&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Prettier&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Post your project as answers to StackOverflow and GitHub issues related to the problem you are solving&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Post your project on &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/submit&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;HackerNews&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/programming/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;reddit&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.producthunt.com/posts/new&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;ProductHunt&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://hashnode.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Hashnode&lt;/a&gt; and any other community-specific aggregation website&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Propose your new project to the newsletters about your platform&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to meetups or give talks about your project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.algolia.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/image4-2.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-7221 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://blog.algolia.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/image4-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot of Hacker News post&quot; width=&quot;1944&quot; height=&quot;862&quot; srcset=&quot;https://blog.algolia.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/image4-2.png 1944w, https://blog.algolia.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/image4-2-320x142.png 320w, https://blog.algolia.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/image4-2-768x341.png 768w, https://blog.algolia.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/image4-2-720x319.png 720w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1944px) 100vw, 1944px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Show your new project to the world&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t fear posting to many websites&lt;/strong&gt;; as long as you truly believe what you have made will be valuable, there is no such thing as too much information. In general, communities are really happy to have something to share!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Be patient and iterate&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In term of “vanity metrics” (number of stars or downloads), some projects will skyrocket on day one but then have their growth stopped very early. Others will wait one year before being ready for HN frontpage. Trust that your project will be at some point noticed by other users, and if it never does, then you have learned something: it’s probably no use to anyone but you  — and that is one more learning for your next project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I have many projects that have 0 stars&lt;/strong&gt; (like &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/vvo/mocha-browse&quot;&gt;mocha-browse&lt;/a&gt;), but I am never disappointed because I don’t have high expectations. That’s how I always think at the beginning of a project: I found a good problem, I solved it the best way I could, maybe some people will use it, maybe not. Not a big deal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Two projects for a single solution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my favourite part of doing open-source. At Algolia in 2015 we were looking at solutions to unit test and freeze the html output of our &lt;a href=&quot;https://reactjs.org/docs/jsx-in-depth.html&quot;&gt;JSX&lt;/a&gt; written React components for &lt;a href=&quot;https://community.algolia.com/instantsearch.js/&quot;&gt;InstantSearch.js&lt;/a&gt;, our React UI library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since JSX is translated to function calls, our solution at that time was to write expect(&amp;lt;Component /&amp;gt;).toDeepEqual(&amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;span/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div). That’s just comparing two function calls output.But the output of those calls are complex object trees: when run, it would show “Expected {-type: ‘span’, …}”. The input and output comparison was impossible and developers were getting mad when writing tests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To solve this problem, we created &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/algolia/expect-jsx&quot;&gt;algolia/expect-jsx&lt;/a&gt; that allowed us to have JSX string diffs in our unit tests output instead of unreadable object trees. Input and output of the test would be using the same semantics. We did not stop there. Instead of publishing one library, we extracted another one out of it and published two libraries:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By publishing two modules that are tackling one problem together, you can make the community benefit from your low-level solutions that can be reused on a lot of different projects, even in ways you never thought your module would be used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, react-element-to-jsx-string is used in a lot of other &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npmjs.com/browse/depended/react-element-to-jsx-string&quot;&gt;test expectations frameworks&lt;/a&gt; along with being used on documentation plugins like &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/storybooks/addon-jsx&quot;&gt;storybooks/addon-jsx&lt;/a&gt;.Today, to test the output of your React components, use &lt;a href=&quot;http://facebook.github.io/jest/docs/en/snapshot-testing.html#snapshot-testing-with-jest&quot;&gt;Jest and snapshots testing&lt;/a&gt;, there’s no more the need for expect-jsx in those situations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Feedback and contributions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.algolia.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/image3-2.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-7220 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://blog.algolia.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/image3-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;A fake issue screenshot&quot; width=&quot;1988&quot; height=&quot;558&quot; srcset=&quot;https://blog.algolia.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/image3-2.png 1988w, https://blog.algolia.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/image3-2-320x90.png 320w, https://blog.algolia.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/image3-2-768x216.png 768w, https://blog.algolia.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/image3-2-720x202.png 720w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1988px) 100vw, 1988px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;That’s a lot of issues. Also, it’s faked just to have a nice picture 🙂&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you start getting feedback and contributions, be prepared to be open-minded and optimistic. You will get enthusiastic feedback, but also negative comments. Remember that any interaction with a user is a contribution, even when it seems like just complaining.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For one thing, it is never easy to convey intentions/tone in written conversations. You could be interpreting “This is strange…” as: it’s awesome/it’s really bad/I don’t understand/I am happy/I am sad.  Ask for more details and try to rephrase the issue to better understand where it’s coming from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few tips to avoid genuine complaints:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;To better guide users giving feedback, provide them with an &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/blog/2111-issue-and-pull-request-templates&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;ISSUE_TEMPLATE&lt;/a&gt; that is displayed when they create a new issue.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Try to reduce the friction for new contributors to a minimum.Keep in mind that they may not yet be into testing and would gladly learn from you. Don’t hold Pull Requests for new contributors because there’s a missing semicolon;, help them feel safe. You can gently ask them to add them, and if that doesn’t work, you can also merge as-is and then write the tests and documentation yourself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide a good developer experience environment in terms of automated tests, &lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/8503559/what-is-linting&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;linting&lt;/a&gt; and formatting code or livereload examples.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;That’s it&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading, I hope you liked this article to the point where you want to help or build projects. Contributing to open-source is a great way to expand your skillset, it’s not a mandatory experience for every developer, but a good opportunity to get out of your comfort zone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am now looking forward to your first or next open-source project, tweet it to me &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/vvoyer&quot;&gt;@vvoyer&lt;/a&gt; and I’ll be happy to give you advice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you love open-source and would like to practice it in a company instead than doing it on your free time, Algolia has open positions for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.algolia.com/careers#60c7c780-1009-4030-8e44-f653fa2ebd36&quot;&gt;open-source JavaScript developers.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other resources you might like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://opensource.guide/&quot;&gt;opensource.guide&lt;/a&gt;, Learn how to launch and grow your project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://octobox.io/&quot;&gt;Octobox&lt;/a&gt;, your GitHub notifications as an email. Awesome way to avoid the “too many issues” effect by focusing on the ones that matter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://probot.github.io/&quot;&gt;Probot&lt;/a&gt;, GitHub Apps to automate and improve your workflow like closing very old issues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sindresorhus/refined-github&quot;&gt;Refined GitHub&lt;/a&gt; provides an awesome maintainer experience for GitHub UI at many levels&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://octolinker.github.io/&quot;&gt;OctoLinker&lt;/a&gt; makes browsing other people’s code on GitHub a great experience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/voiceofivana&quot;&gt;Ivana&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/tiphaine-gillet-01a3735b/&quot;&gt;Tiphaine&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/adrienjoly&quot;&gt;Adrien&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/dzello&quot;&gt;Josh&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/codeharmonics&quot;&gt;Peter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/rayrutjes&quot;&gt;Raymond&lt;/a&gt; for their help, review and contributions on this blog post.&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2017 16:38:12 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>vvoyer</dc:creator>
<og:title>Start your open-source career</og:title>
<og:url>https://blog.algolia.com/start-your-open-source-career/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>This year I gave a talk about how to make open-source projects successful by ensuring everything is in place to attract all kinds of contributions: issues, documentation or code updates. After the talk, the feedback I got was &quot;It’s nice, you showed how to make projects successful, but how do I even</og:description>
<og:image>https://blog.algolia.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/12-2017_Open-Source-projects.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.algolia.com/start-your-open-source-career/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Facebook’s Political Unit Enables Propaganda</title>
<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2017-12-21/inside-the-facebook-team-helping-regimes-that-reach-out-and-crack-down</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2017-12-21/inside-the-facebook-team-helping-regimes-that-reach-out-and-crack-down</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;section-break&quot;&gt;Under fire for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/quote/FB:US&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;Facebook Inc.&lt;/a&gt;’s role as a platform for political propaganda, co-founder Mark Zuckerberg has punched back, saying his mission is above partisanship. “We hope to give all people a voice and create a platform for all ideas,” Zuckerberg &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/zuck/posts/10104067130714241&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;wrote in September&lt;/a&gt; after President Donald Trump accused Facebook of bias.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Zuckerberg’s social network is a politically agnostic tool for its more than 2 billion users, he has said. But Facebook, it turns out, is no bystander in global politics. What he hasn’t said is that his company actively works with political parties and leaders including those who use the platform to stifle opposition—sometimes with the aid of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2017-12-07/how-rodrigo-duterte-turned-facebook-into-a-weapon-with-a-little-help-from-facebook&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;“troll armies”&lt;/a&gt; that spread misinformation and extremist ideologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The initiative is run by a little-known Facebook global government and politics team that’s neutral in that it works with nearly anyone seeking or securing power. The unit is led from Washington by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.msnbc.com/msnbc/women-bridging-tech-and-politics-the-2016-election-katie-harbath&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;Katie Harbath&lt;/a&gt;, a former Republican digital strategist who worked on former New York Mayor Rudy Giuliani’s 2008 presidential campaign. Since Facebook hired Harbath three years later, her team has traveled the globe helping political clients use the company’s powerful digital tools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;lazy-img-321843651&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/i4NdQZAdI9dA/v16/60x-1.jpg&quot; data-native-src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/i4NdQZAdI9dA/v16/-1x-1.jpg&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img__image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Katie Harbath.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photographer: Kirk Irwin/Getty Images for Glamour&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In some of the world’s biggest democracies—from India and Brazil to Germany and the U.K.—the unit’s employees have become de facto campaign workers. And once a candidate is elected, the company in some instances goes on to train government employees or provide technical assistance for live streams at official state events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;section-break&quot;&gt;Even before Facebook was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2017-11-01/social-media-companies-get-unaccustomed-grilling-on-russia-ads&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;forced to explain&lt;/a&gt; its role in U.S. election meddling—portrayed by its executives as a largely passive affair involving Russian-funded ads—the company’s direct and growing role &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/business/success/categories/government-politics&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;catering to political campaigns&lt;/a&gt; raised concerns inside the social media giant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s not Facebook’s job, in my opinion, to be so close to any election campaign,” said Elizabeth Linder, who started and ran the Facebook politics unit’s Europe, Middle East and Africa efforts until 2016. Linder had originally been excited about the company’s potential to be “extraordinarily useful for the world’s leaders—but also the global citizenry.” She said she decided to leave the company in part because she grew uncomfortable with what she saw as increased emphasis on electioneering and campaigns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the U.S., the unit &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2016-10-27/inside-the-trump-bunker-with-12-days-to-go&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;embedded employees&lt;/a&gt; in Trump’s campaign. (Hillary Clinton’s camp declined a similar offer.) In India, the company helped develop the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/narendramodi/&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;online presence&lt;/a&gt; of Prime Minister Narendra Modi, who now has more Facebook followers than any other world leader. In the Philippines, it trained the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/rodyduterte/&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;campaign&lt;/a&gt; of Rodrigo Duterte, known for encouraging extrajudicial killings, in how to most effectively use the platform. And in Germany it helped the anti-immigrant &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2017-09-29/the-german-far-right-finds-friends-through-facebook&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Alternative for Germany party (AfD)&lt;/a&gt; win its first Bundestag seats, according to campaign staff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;lazy-img-321843984&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/iVo3TbMrXFdg/v1/60x-1.jpg&quot; data-native-src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/iVo3TbMrXFdg/v1/-1x-1.jpg&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img__image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supporters of the Alternative for Germany (AfD) party dressed in blue tights attend a campaign rally ahead of European parliamentary elections on May 23, 2014, in Berlin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photographer: Sean Gallup/Getty Images&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By all accounts, Facebook has been an indispensable &lt;a href=&quot;https://fr.newsroom.fb.com/news/2017/04/facebook-lance-un-outil-pour-faciliter-lacces-aux-programmes-des-candidats-a-la-presidentielle/&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;tool of civic engagement&lt;/a&gt;, with candidates and elected officials from mayor to prime minister using the platform to communicate directly with their constituents, and with grassroots groups like Black Lives Matter relying on it to organize. The company says it offers the same tools and services to all candidates and governments regardless of political affiliation, and even to civil society groups that may have a lesser voice. Facebook says it provides advice on how best to use its tools, not strategic advice about what to say.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We’re proud to work with the thousands of elected officials around the world who use Facebook as a way to communicate directly with their constituents, interact with voters, and hear about the issues important in their community,” Harbath said in an emailed statement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She said the company is investing in artificial intelligence and other ways to better police hate speech and threats. “We take our responsibility to prevent abuse of our platform extremely seriously,” Harbath said. “We know there are ways we can do better, and are constantly working to improve.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Power and social media converge by design at Facebook. The company has long worked to crush its smaller rival, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2017-05-02/twitter-says-it-would-love-world-leaders-to-use-it-like-trump&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, in a race to be the platform of choice for the world’s so-called influencers, whether politicians, cricket stars or Kardashians. Their posts will, in theory, draw followers to Facebook more frequently, resulting in higher traffic for advertisers and better data about what attracts users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Politicians running for office can be lucrative ad buyers. For those who spend enough, Facebook offers customized services to help them build effective campaigns, the same way it would &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/quote/UNA:NA&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;Unilever NV&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/quote/KO:US&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;Coca-Cola Co.&lt;/a&gt; ahead of a product launch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Facebook declined to give the size of its politics unit, one executive said it can expand to include hundreds during the peak of an election, drawing in people from the company’s legal, information security and policy teams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;section-break&quot;&gt;At meetings with political campaigns, members of Harbath’s team sit alongside Facebook advertising sales staff who help monetize the often viral attention stirred up by elections and politics. They train politicians and leaders how to set up a campaign page and get it authenticated with a blue verification check mark, how to best use video to engage viewers and how to target ads to critical voting blocs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;lazy-img-321843735&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/iQAR8coRuoHo/v16/60x-1.jpg&quot; data-native-src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/iQAR8coRuoHo/v16/-1x-1.jpg&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img__image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rodrigo Duterte.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photographer: Mark R. Cristino/AFP/Getty Images&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once those candidates are elected, their relationship with Facebook can help extend the company’s reach into government in meaningful ways, such as being well positioned to push against regulations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the very least, the optics of directly aiding campaigns or those in power may create the impression among users that Facebook is taking sides. Its effort effectively helping the Scottish National Party to victory in 2015 is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/business/success/snp&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;recounted as a “success story”&lt;/a&gt; on Facebook’s corporate website that lists business case studies, even though those who favor staying in the U.K. might see it otherwise. In April, Vietnamese officials bragged that Facebook would build a dedicated channel to prioritize takedown requests for content that offended authorities. The company generally routes requests from governments through a separate channel, and takes the content down if it violates community standards. If it violates local law, it’ll only be unavailable in the relevant country.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“They’re too cozy with power,” said &lt;a href=&quot;https://steinhardt.nyu.edu/faculty/Mark_Crispin_Miller&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;Mark Crispin Miller&lt;/a&gt;, a media and culture professor at New York University.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That problem is exacerbated when Facebook’s engine of democracy is deployed in an undemocratic fashion. A November &lt;a href=&quot;https://freedomhouse.org/article/new-report-freedom-net-2017-manipulating-social-media-undermine-democracy&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;report by Freedom House&lt;/a&gt;, a U.S.-based nonprofit that advocates for political and human rights, found that a growing number of countries are “manipulating social media to undermine democracy.” One aspect of that involves “patriotic trolling,” or the use of government-backed harassment and propaganda meant to control the narrative, silence dissidents and consolidate power.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;section-break&quot;&gt;Internally, Facebook executives are grappling with how to distinguish between what constitutes trolling harassment and protected political speech. Zuckerberg has long maintained the company doesn’t want to play censor, but Facebook has drawn some lines—banning Greece’s Golden Dawn, the ultranationalist party, for example. The company also often removes the &lt;a href=&quot;https://newsroom.fb.com/news/2017/06/how-we-counter-terrorism/&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;most extreme content&lt;/a&gt;, from white nationalists in the U.S. and from the Islamic State, as well as content it catches violating its “community standards” on hate speech and violence. Not all such content gets caught.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In retrospect, the nexus of power and data at Facebook seems inevitable. In 2007, Facebook opened its first office in Washington. The presidential election the following year saw the rise of the world’s first “Facebook President” in Barack Obama, who with the platform’s help was able to reach millions of voters in the weeks before the election. The number of Facebook users surged around the Arab Spring uprisings in the Middle East around 2010 and 2011, demonstrating the broad power of the platform to influence democracy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;lazy-img-321844100&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/iWSQ3CmHdr1g/v1/60x-1.jpg&quot; data-native-src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/iWSQ3CmHdr1g/v1/-1x-1.jpg&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img__image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scottish National Party leader Nicola Sturgeon at a rally in Glasgow in April 2015. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photographer: Jeff J Mitchell/Getty Images&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the time Facebook named Harbath, the former Giuliani aide, to lead its global politics and government unit, elections were becoming major social-media attractions. They now rank alongside the Super Bowl and the Olympics in terms of events that draw blockbuster ad dollars and boost engagement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook began getting involved in electoral hotspots around the world. They went to Argentina in 2015, where now-President Mauricio Macri streamed campaign rallies live on Facebook and, once elected, announced his entire cabinet on the site, complete with emojis. The same year, Poland’s nationalist president, Andrzej Duda, became one of the first world leaders to livestream his inauguration on the social network. Even as Duda has overseen a crackdown on press freedom in the country, Facebook’s corporate website says the company was “integral” to his electoral success and that his page is “one of his office’s main communication channels.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook has embedded itself in some of the globe’s most controversial political movements while resisting transparency. Since 2011, it has asked the U.S. Federal Election Commission for blanket exemptions from political advertising disclosure rules that could have helped it avoid the current crisis over Russian ad spending ahead of the 2016 election, Bloomberg reported in October. After a Congressional inquiry into Russian election meddling, Facebook has pledged to be more transparent about ad buyers and said it’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2017-10-04/facebook-fought-for-years-to-avoid-political-ad-disclosure-rules&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;open to regulation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;section-break&quot;&gt;The company’s relationship with governments remains complicated. Facebook has come under fire in the European Union, including for the spread of Islamic extremism on its network. The company just issued its &lt;a href=&quot;https://transparency.facebook.com/&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;annual transparency report&lt;/a&gt; explaining that it will only provide user data to governments if that request is legally sufficient, and will push back in court if it’s not. Despite Facebook’s desire to eventually operate in China and Zuckerberg’s flirtation with the country’s leaders, it’s still unwilling to compromise as much as the government wants it to in order to enter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;lazy-img-321843682&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/i71U2.abwTlg/v16/60x-1.jpg&quot; data-native-src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/i71U2.abwTlg/v16/-1x-1.jpg&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img__image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Narendra Modi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photographer: Rob Stothard/Getty Images&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;India is arguably Facebook’s most important market, with the nation recently edging out the U.S. as the company’s biggest. The number of users there is growing twice as fast as in the U.S. And that doesn’t even count the 200 million people who use the company’s WhatsApp messaging service in India, more than anywhere else on the globe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the time of India’s 2014 elections, Facebook had for months been working with several campaigns. Modi, who belongs to the nationalist Bharatiya Janata Party, relied heavily on Facebook and WhatsApp to recruit volunteers who in turn spread his message on social media. Since his election, Modi’s Facebook followers have risen to 43 million, almost twice Trump’s count.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within weeks of Modi’s election, Zuckerberg and Chief Operating Officer Sheryl Sandberg both visited the nation as it was rolling out a critical free internet service that the government later curbed. Harbath and her team have also traveled there, offering a series of workshops and sessions that have trained more than 6,000 government officials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Modi’s social media reach grew, his followers increasingly turned to Facebook and WhatsApp to target harassment campaigns against his political rivals. India has become a hotbed for fake news, with one hoax story this year that circulated on WhatsApp leading to two separate mob beatings resulting in seven deaths. The nation has also become an increasingly dangerous place for opposition parties and reporters. In the past year, several journalists critical of the ruling party have been killed. Hindu extremists who back Modi’s party have used social media to issue death threats against Muslims or critics of the government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the night of Sept. 5, a Honda motorcycle pulled in front of the Bengaluru home of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloombergquint.com/politics/2017/09/06/dissent-journalist-gauri-lankesh-who-stood-for-free-speech-killed&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;Gauri Lankesh&lt;/a&gt;, an outspoken critic of Modi who had been targeted by patriotic trolls on Facebook and other social media. As the Indian journalist was unlocking her gate, three bullets struck her in the head and chest, killing her. No arrests have been made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://thewire.in/175643/gauri-lankesh-final-editorial-fake-news/&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;final editorial&lt;/a&gt; Lankesh had written for her newspaper was titled “In the Age of False News.” In it, she lamented how misinformation and propaganda on social media were poisoning the political environment.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;— With assistance by Benjamin Elgin&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2017 15:59:49 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ucaetano</dc:creator>
<og:description>Some of the unit’s clients stifle opposition and stoke extremism.</og:description>
<og:image>https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/ihMXZRVm.Ag0/v0/1200x630.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>The Facebook Team Helping Regimes That Fight Their Opposition</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2017-12-21/inside-the-facebook-team-helping-regimes-that-reach-out-and-crack-down</og:url>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2017-12-21/inside-the-facebook-team-helping-regimes-that-reach-out-and-crack-down</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Apple Says It Slows Older iPhones to Save Their Battery Life</title>
<link>http://text.npr.org/s.php?sId=572538593</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://text.npr.org/s.php?sId=572538593</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;meta http-equiv=&quot;Content-Type&quot; content=&quot;text/html; charset=UTF-8&quot; /&gt;&lt;title&gt;Text-Only NPR.org : Apple Says It Slows Older iPhones To Save Their Battery Life&lt;/title&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;robots&quot; content=&quot;noindex, nofollow&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;viewport&quot; content=&quot;width=device-width, initial-scale=1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot; readability=&quot;126.58561020036&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Text-Only NPR.org (go to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npr.org&quot;&gt;full version&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://text.npr.org/&quot;&gt;Home&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple Says It Slows Older iPhones To Save Their Battery Life&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By Bill Chappell&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NPR.org, December 21, 2017 · Confirming iPhone owners' suspicions that Apple purposefully slows the operation of older phones, Apple says that it does just that — and that slowing down processors makes it easier for old batteries to perform after they've begun to lose capacity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple is responding to owners of older phones who have increasingly said they notice slower performance after they upgrade their devices' software. The difference was highlighted in a recent &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/iphone/comments/7inu45/psa_iphone_slow_try_replacing_your_battery/&quot;&gt;Reddit post&lt;/a&gt; — and it was quantified in a blog post at Geekbench, the processor bench-marking company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Older phones operate more quickly if they're using older versions of Apple's iOS operating system, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.geekbench.com/blog/2017/12/iphone-performance-and-battery-age/&quot;&gt;Geekbench found&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The slowdown affects a range of Apple phones, including the iPhone 7 and iPhone 6S, models that came out in 2016 and 2015, respectively. The company says it plans to apply the same strategy to &quot;other products in the future.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smartphones' lithium-ion batteries lose their pep as they age, but processors remain hungry for quick bursts of power. So, Apple used software to throttle the demand — effectively governing the speed at which the phones can operate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The situation is prickly: More than 10 years after Apple introduced its first iPhone, the company says it's trying to deliver the &quot;best experience&quot; to customers by preventing unexpected power-related shutdowns. In addition to addressing aging batteries, the company said it tries to &quot;smooth out&quot; power demand in phones that are operating in cold conditions or that have a low battery charge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But some customers say the company's strategy of dealing with the power demand pushes them to replace their older iPhones with newer models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the Reddit post that generated intense interest in Apple's battery strategy earlier this month, a user named &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/user/TeckFire&quot;&gt;TeckFire&lt;/a&gt; reported that after noticing that different versions of the iPhone 6 series were running at vastly different speeds, they saw speeds pick up again once the battery on an iPhone 6S was replaced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That post triggered responses in which other Apple customers wondered whether the battery ploy was also to blame for their older Macbook laptops not working as well as they once had.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Explaining how Apple's approach could feed suspicions of &quot;planned obsolescence,&quot; John Poole, founder of Geekbench parent Primate Labs, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.geekbench.com/blog/2017/12/iphone-performance-and-battery-age/&quot;&gt;writes&lt;/a&gt;, &quot;users may believe that the slow down is due to [central processing unit] performance, instead of battery performance.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the battery being the reason that Apple is slowing the phones, Poole adds, &quot;This fix will also cause users to think, 'My phone is slow so I should replace it' not, 'My phone is slow so I should replace its battery.' &quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The discrepancy between processors and batteries runs deep — and it's increasingly being highlighted, as lithium-ion batteries are recognized as not having much room for improvement. As Kristin Persson, a professor of materials and engineering at University of California, Berkeley, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.marketplace.org/2017/12/07/tech/lithium-ion-batteries-are-about-good-they-can-get&quot;&gt;told Marketplace on Thursday morning&lt;/a&gt;, lithium-ion batteries are &quot;highly optimized,&quot; and researchers have been working on creating a better battery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Persson told Marketplace's Molly Wood:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;15&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;So if you compare batteries to, for example, computers, the difference is really that in batteries you have to invent new materials to make them better, whereas in semiconductors, you're inherently, most of the time, using the same materials and you're just making them smaller, which is easier.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is Apple's statement on the battery/CPU issue:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Our goal is to deliver the best experience for customers, which includes overall performance and prolonging the life of their devices. Lithium-ion batteries become less capable of supplying peak current demands when in cold conditions, have a low battery charge or as they age over time, which can result in the device unexpectedly shutting down to protect its electronic components.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Last year we released a feature for iPhone 6, iPhone 6s and iPhone SE to smooth out the instantaneous peaks only when needed to prevent the device from unexpectedly shutting down during these conditions. We've now extended that feature to iPhone 7 with iOS 11.2, and plan to add support for other products in the future.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;© NPR&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2017 15:09:46 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>lyk</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://text.npr.org/s.php?sId=572538593</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>