<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Volkswagen exec admits full self-driving cars &amp;#039;may never happen&amp;#039;</title>
<link>https://www.thedrive.com/tech/31816/key-volkswagen-exec-admits-level-5-autonomous-cars-may-never-happen</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.thedrive.com/tech/31816/key-volkswagen-exec-admits-level-5-autonomous-cars-may-never-happen</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;article-head&quot;&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;dek&quot;&gt;Full autonomy remains an impossibly difficult prize.&lt;/h2&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;hero-image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;image-fade-in&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://the-drive.imgix.net/https%3A%2F%2Fapi.thedrive.com%2Fwp-content%2Fuploads%2F2018%2F03%2Fself-driving-wtf.jpg%3Fquality%3D85?w=1440&amp;amp;auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;ixlib=js-1.4.1&amp;amp;s=38925739b1eab4de5bcc5a2f47071f5e&quot; srcset=&quot;https://the-drive.imgix.net/https%3A%2F%2Fapi.thedrive.com%2Fwp-content%2Fuploads%2F2018%2F03%2Fself-driving-wtf.jpg%3Fquality%3D85?w=1440&amp;amp;auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;ixlib=js-1.4.1&amp;amp;s=38925739b1eab4de5bcc5a2f47071f5e 1x,https://the-drive.imgix.net/https%3A%2F%2Fapi.thedrive.com%2Fwp-content%2Fuploads%2F2018%2F03%2Fself-driving-wtf.jpg%3Fquality%3D85?w=1920&amp;amp;auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;ixlib=js-1.4.1&amp;amp;s=bbcbb7dd757b6da35fd996a327516de8 1.5x&quot; onload=&quot;this.style.opacity=1&quot;/&gt;Federico Gambarini/picture-alliance/dpa/AP Images&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;has-ad-column&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;articleFragment paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thedrive.com/news/3545/study-claims-10-million-self-driving-cars-will-be-on-the-road-by-2020&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;years of sunny optimism and big promises&lt;/a&gt;, automakers are beginning to realize just how difficult it is to make a market-ready, full self-driving car. The CEO of Volkswagen's autonomous driving division &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wardsauto.com/ces/vw-exec-level-4-self-driver-may-be-good-it-gets&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;recently admitted that Level 5 autonomy&lt;/a&gt;—that's full computer control of the vehicle with zero limitations—might actually never happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A quick primer on the now-industry-standard SAE International rules on how to discuss self-driving abilities: Level 0 is no automation whatsoever. Level 1 is partial assistance with certain aspects of driving, like lane keep assist or adaptive cruise control. Level 2 is a step up to systems that can take control of the vehicle in certain situations, like Tesla's Autopilot or Cadillac's Super Cruise, while still requiring the driver to pay attention. Get past that and we enter the realm of speculation: Level 3 promises full computer control under defined conditions during a journey, Level 4 expands that to start-to-finish autonomous tech limited only by virtual safeguards like a geofence, and Level 5 is the total hands-off, go-anywhere-at-the-push-of-a-button experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sitting down with &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wardsauto.com/ces/vw-exec-level-4-self-driver-may-be-good-it-gets&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;WardsAuto&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/em&gt;at the Consumer Electronics Show in Las Vegas last week, VW Autonomy's Alex Hitzinger said Level 4 might be the realistic limit for what automakers can build. He wasn’t shy in pointing out the relative difficulty of trying for full Level 5 autonomy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This is one of the hardest problems we have. This is like we are going to Mars,” Hitzinger said in a comment. “Maybe it will never happen.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite that, he's confident in VW's ability to make a Level 4 autonomous vehicle, saying that the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thedrive.com/tech/23724/volkswagen-i-d-buzz-cargo-concept-340-mile-range-electric-work-van&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;upcoming I.D. Buzz electric van&lt;/a&gt; will be the first VW to receive the technology. That makes sense given the van's potential as a commercial vehicle; other automakers have pointed to those as a natural starting place for autonomous efforts since they generally follow fixed driving routes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was just a few short years ago when we were all swimming in golden promises from carmakers about the advances we'd see by the end of the decade. Well, 2020 is here, and the reality of the challenge—made even tougher by the critical need for infrastructure upgrades and smart policymaking from governments around the world—seems to have finally settled in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Got a tip? Send us a note: tips@thedrive.com&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;related-content related-content--rich&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;title-message&quot;&gt;MORE TO READ&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;related-article&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;What Are The Regulatory Barriers To Full Self-Driving?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;dek&quot;&gt;Elon Musk says Tesla needs regulator approval to release the &quot;Full Self-Driving&quot; functionality to the public, but does he? It's complicated.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;related-article&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;How the Language of Self-Driving Is Killing Us&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;dek&quot;&gt;We can't fix something this broken. But we can—and should—replace it.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;related-article&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;Wait, Who Even Asked for Self-Driving Cars in the First Place?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;dek&quot;&gt;Five years ago, autonomy wasn’t even a thing. Now it’s the &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; thing. Why?&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/section&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2020 17:44:40 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>stopads</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Key Volkswagen Exec Admits Full Self-Driving Cars 'May Never Happen'</og:title>
<og:description>Full autonomy remains an impossibly difficult prize.</og:description>
<og:image>https://api.thedrive.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/self-driving-wtf.jpg?quality=85</og:image>
<og:url>https://www.thedrive.com/tech/31816/key-volkswagen-exec-admits-level-5-autonomous-cars-may-never-happen</og:url>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.thedrive.com/tech/31816/key-volkswagen-exec-admits-level-5-autonomous-cars-may-never-happen</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Students defeat new &amp;#039;Barnacle&amp;#039; parking clamp, skip fines and get free internet</title>
<link>https://postmediadriving.wordpress.com/auto-news/news/students-defeat-new-barnacle-parking-boot-skip-fines-and-get-free-internet</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://postmediadriving.wordpress.com/auto-news/news/students-defeat-new-barnacle-parking-boot-skip-fines-and-get-free-internet</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;big-box-ad native-box-ad&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;gpt-bigboxmid&quot; class=&quot;pn_dfpads adslot&quot; data-ad=&quot;[[300,250],[300,252]]&quot; data-ad-loc=&quot;mid&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;University of Oklahoma students furious after finding out a new parking-fine device, nicknamed “The Barnacle,” would be implemented at their school have already got the administration to scrap it after figuring out a fix to remove the boot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Barnacle is a plastic cover that uses suction to stick to the windshield of a vehicle, and is deployed by a parking enforcement officer who’s caught a car with three outstanding parking fines on their record.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The high-tech device doesn’t immobilize the vehicle like old-school wheel “boot” clamps used to, but it does make it almost impossible to see out of the front windshield, and was seen by the university as a cheaper, more “convenient” fine collection method than towing the car away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To properly remove the Barnacle, students are supposed to pay a $185 fee via an app and then return the device to a designated drop box. Obviously, some students thought that fee was ridiculous  – just like paying for parking at a university where you’re already paying a hefty tuition fee – and devised a different way to remove the Barnacle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As it turns out, to take off the Barnacle, all you need to do is run your vehicle’s windshield defroster for 15 minutes, and then use a credit card or similar thin piece of plastic to release the suction cup around the edge. &lt;em&gt;Presto!&lt;/em&gt; You’re free from fees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other students shared other solutions – blocking its signal and deactivating it by covering it in aluminum, or fitting your windshield with a mock Barnacle of your own – but our fave low-tech workaround was shared by a user who found out his campus only had 12 wheel boots to go around and bought and illegally parked 12 scrapyard cars that could be “sacrificed” so everyone else could park however they wanted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The defroster hack was posted to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/specializedtools/comments/e541r4/new_type_of_parking_enforcement_on_my_campus/&quot;&gt;reddit&lt;/a&gt;, where it received more than 46,000 upvotes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the Barnacle is off your vehicle, you’re free to drive around as usual. At least one of these hackers took things a step further, though, exacting an ironic revenge on the device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;lead-ad&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;gpt-lead-ad&quot; class=&quot;pn_dfpads adslot&quot; data-ad=&quot;[720,185]&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because it has a GPS &lt;a href=&quot;https://driving.ca/chevrolet/tracker&quot; title=&quot;tracker&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot; class=&quot;auto-link&quot;&gt;tracker&lt;/a&gt; meant to set off a loud alarm whenever it, or the car it’s attached to, moves, the Barnacle also has a built-in SIM card. One reddit user figured out the SIM card had unlimited data, and hacked it so they could tether their own personal cell phone to its network, giving them unlimited free phone data for several months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After “receiving feedback from the community” – that is, having its new parking enforcement method thwarted – OU has decided to pause the trial use of the five devices it’d borrowed from the Barnacle’s manufacturer. The company’s CEO says improvements have been made to counter these hacks already, but we’re curious to see where this parking arms race heads next.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2020 16:01:09 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>elliekelly</dc:creator>
<og:title>Students defeat new ‘Barnacle’ parking clamp, skip fines and get free internet</og:title>
<og:url>https://driving.ca/auto-news/news/students-defeat-new-barnacle-parking-boot-skip-fines-and-get-free-internet</og:url>
<og:image>https://postmediadriving.files.wordpress.com/2020/01/t0z68k8fu9241.jpg?quality=80</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>Parking at University of Oklahoma without paying was about to get a lot more expensive before these kids defeated the school's high-tech boot with a low-effort solution</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://driving.ca/auto-news/news/students-defeat-new-barnacle-parking-boot-skip-fines-and-get-free-internet</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Clearview AI helps law enforcement match photos of people to their online images</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2020/01/18/technology/clearview-privacy-facial-recognition.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2020/01/18/technology/clearview-privacy-facial-recognition.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Until recently, Hoan Ton-That’s greatest hits included an obscure iPhone game and an app that let people put Donald Trump’s distinctive yellow hair on their own photos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Then Mr. Ton-That — an Australian techie and onetime model — did something momentous: He invented a tool that could end your ability to walk down the street anonymously, and provided it to hundreds of law enforcement agencies, ranging from local cops in Florida to the F.B.I. and the Department of Homeland Security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;His tiny company, Clearview AI, devised a groundbreaking facial recognition app. You take a picture of a person, upload it and get to see public photos of that person, along with links to where those photos appeared. The system — whose backbone is a database of more than three billion images that Clearview claims to have scraped from Facebook, YouTube, Venmo and millions of other websites — goes far beyond anything ever constructed by the United States government or Silicon Valley giants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Federal and state law enforcement officers said that while they had only limited knowledge of how Clearview works and who is behind it, they had used its app to help solve shoplifting, identity theft, credit card fraud, murder and child sexual exploitation cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-ew4tgv&quot; aria-label=&quot;companion column&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Until now, technology that readily identifies everyone based on his or her face has been taboo because of its radical erosion of privacy. Tech companies capable of &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.cnet.com/news/facebook-built-a-facial-recognition-app-for-employees/&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;releasing such a tool&lt;/a&gt; have refrained from doing so; in 2011, Google’s chairman at the time &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.telegraph.co.uk/technology/google/8522574/Google-warns-against-facial-recognition-database.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; it was the one technology the company had held back because it could be used “&lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://webcache.googleusercontent.com/search?q=cache:MwDlXjKEg2oJ:https://www.huffpost.com/entry/facial-recognition-google_n_869583+&amp;amp;cd=3&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;ct=clnk&amp;amp;gl=us&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;in a very bad way&lt;/a&gt;.” Some large cities, including San Francisco, have barred police from using facial recognition technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;But without public scrutiny, more than 600 law enforcement agencies have started using Clearview in the past year, according to the company, which declined to provide a list. The computer code underlying its app, analyzed by The New York Times, includes programming language to pair it with augmented-reality glasses; users would potentially be able to identify every person they saw. The tool could identify activists at a protest or an attractive stranger on the subway, revealing not just their names but where they lived, what they did and whom they knew.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;And it’s not just law enforcement: Clearview has also licensed the app to at least a handful of companies for security purposes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“The weaponization possibilities of this are endless,” said Eric Goldman, co-director of the High Tech Law Institute at Santa Clara University. “Imagine a rogue law enforcement officer who wants to stalk potential romantic partners, or a foreign government using this to dig up secrets about people to blackmail them or throw them in jail.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Clearview has shrouded itself in secrecy, avoiding debate about its boundary-pushing technology. When I began looking into the company in November, its website was a bare page showing a nonexistent Manhattan address as its place of business. The company’s one employee listed on LinkedIn, a sales manager named “John Good,” turned out to be Mr. Ton-That, using a fake name. For a month, people affiliated with the company would not return my emails or phone calls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-ew4tgv&quot; aria-label=&quot;companion column&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;While the company was dodging me, it was also monitoring me. At my request, a number of police officers had run my photo through the Clearview app. They soon received phone calls from company representatives asking if they were talking to the media — a sign that Clearview has the ability and, in this case, the appetite to monitor whom law enforcement is searching for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Facial recognition technology has always been controversial. It makes people nervous about Big Brother. It has a tendency to deliver false matches for certain groups, like people of color. And some facial recognition products used by the police — including Clearview’s — haven’t been vetted by independent experts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Clearview’s app carries extra risks because law enforcement agencies are uploading sensitive photos to the servers of a company whose ability to protect its data is untested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The company eventually started answering my questions, saying that its earlier silence was typical of an early-stage start-up in stealth mode. Mr. Ton-That acknowledged designing a prototype for use with augmented-reality glasses but said the company had no plans to release it. And he said my photo had rung alarm bells because the app “flags possible anomalous search behavior” in order to prevent users from conducting what it deemed “inappropriate searches.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;In addition to Mr. Ton-That, Clearview was founded by Richard Schwartz — who was an aide to Rudolph W. Giuliani when he was mayor of New York — and backed financially by Peter Thiel, a venture capitalist behind Facebook and Palantir.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Another early investor is a small firm called Kirenaga Partners. Its founder, David Scalzo, dismissed concerns about Clearview making the internet searchable by face, saying it’s a valuable crime-solving tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-ew4tgv&quot; aria-label=&quot;companion column&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“I’ve come to the conclusion that because information constantly increases, there’s never going to be privacy,” Mr. Scalzo said. “Laws have to determine what’s legal, but you can’t ban technology. Sure, that might lead to a dystopian future or something, but you can’t ban it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-ew4tgv&quot; aria-label=&quot;companion column&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-79elbk&quot; data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-wrapper&quot;&gt;

&lt;div data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-children&quot; class=&quot;css-1a48zt4 ehw59r15&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1xdhyk6 erfvjey0&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1tej78p0&quot;&gt;Image&lt;/span&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Hoan Ton-That, founder of Clearview AI, whose app matches faces to images it collects from across the internet.&quot; class=&quot;css-1m50asq&quot; src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2020/01/19/business/18clearview-01/merlin_166989150_339af8f6-72dc-4344-8bea-138e3b8ba466-articleLarge.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;auto=webp&amp;amp;disable=upscale&quot; srcset=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2020/01/19/business/18clearview-01/merlin_166989150_339af8f6-72dc-4344-8bea-138e3b8ba466-articleLarge.jpg?quality=90&amp;amp;auto=webp 600w,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2020/01/19/business/18clearview-01/merlin_166989150_339af8f6-72dc-4344-8bea-138e3b8ba466-jumbo.jpg?quality=90&amp;amp;auto=webp 1024w,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2020/01/19/business/18clearview-01/merlin_166989150_339af8f6-72dc-4344-8bea-138e3b8ba466-superJumbo.jpg?quality=90&amp;amp;auto=webp 2048w&quot; sizes=&quot;((min-width: 600px) and (max-width: 1004px)) 84vw, (min-width: 1005px) 80vw, 100vw&quot; itemprop=&quot;url&quot; itemid=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2020/01/19/business/18clearview-01/merlin_166989150_339af8f6-72dc-4344-8bea-138e3b8ba466-articleLarge.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;auto=webp&amp;amp;disable=upscale&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;css-16f3y1r e13ogyst0&quot;&gt;Hoan Ton-That, founder of Clearview AI, whose app matches faces to images it collects from across the internet.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot; class=&quot;css-cnj6d5 e1z0qqy90&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1tej78p0&quot;&gt;Credit...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Amr Alfiky for The New York Times&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;css-1320w4z eoo0vm40&quot; id=&quot;link-3c8fcb9c&quot;&gt;Addicted to A.I.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Mr. Ton-That, 31, grew up a long way from Silicon Valley. In his native Australia, he was raised on tales of his royal ancestors in Vietnam. In 2007, he dropped out of college and moved to San Francisco. The iPhone had just arrived, and his goal was to get in early on what he expected would be a vibrant market for social media apps. But his early ventures never gained real traction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;In 2009, Mr. Ton-That created a site that let people share links to videos with all the contacts in their instant messengers. Mr. Ton-That shut it down after it was branded a “&lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://bits.blogs.nytimes.com/2009/02/24/viddyho-phishing-scam-hits-gmail/&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;phishing scam&lt;/a&gt;.” In 2015, he spun up &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.148apps.com/app/1040750174/&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Trump Hair&lt;/a&gt;, which added Mr. Trump’s distinctive coif to people in a photo, and a photo-sharing program. Both fizzled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Dispirited, Mr. Ton-That moved to New York in 2016. Tall and slender, with long black hair, he considered a modeling career, he said, but after one shoot he returned to trying to figure out the next big thing in tech. He started reading academic papers on artificial intelligence, image recognition and machine learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Mr. Schwartz and Mr. Ton-That met in 2016 at a book event at the Manhattan Institute, a conservative think tank. Mr. Schwartz, now 61, had amassed an impressive Rolodex working for Mr. Giuliani in the 1990s and serving as the editorial page editor of The New York Daily News in the early 2000s. The two soon decided to go into the facial recognition business together: Mr. Ton-That would build the app, and Mr. Schwartz would use his contacts to drum up commercial interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Police departments have had access to facial recognition tools for almost &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2020/01/12/technology/facial-recognition-police.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;20 years&lt;/a&gt;, but they have historically been limited to searching government-provided images, such as mug shots and driver’s license photos. In recent years, facial recognition algorithms have improved in accuracy, and companies like Amazon offer products that can create a facial recognition program for any database of images.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Mr. Ton-That wanted to go way beyond that. He began in 2016 by recruiting a couple of engineers. One helped design a program that can automatically collect images of people’s faces from across the internet, such as employment sites, news sites, educational sites, and social networks including Facebook, YouTube, Twitter, Instagram and even Venmo. Representatives of those companies said their policies prohibit such scraping, and Twitter said it &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://developer.twitter.com/en/developer-terms/more-on-restricted-use-cases&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;explicitly banned&lt;/a&gt; use of its data for facial recognition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-ew4tgv&quot; aria-label=&quot;companion column&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Another engineer was hired to perfect a facial recognition algorithm that was derived from academic papers. The result: a system that uses what Mr. Ton-That described as a “state-of-the-art neural net” to convert all the images into mathematical formulas, or vectors, based on facial geometry — like how far apart a person’s eyes are. Clearview created a vast directory that clustered all the photos with similar vectors into “neighborhoods.” When a user uploads a photo of a face into Clearview’s system, it converts the face into a vector and then shows all the scraped photos stored in that vector’s neighborhood — along with the links to the sites from which those images came.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Mr. Schwartz paid for server costs and basic expenses, but the operation was bare bones; everyone worked from home. “I was living on credit card debt,” Mr. Ton-That said. “Plus, I was a Bitcoin believer, so I had some of those.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-ew4tgv&quot; aria-label=&quot;companion column&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-a7yk8a e73j0it0&quot;&gt;

&lt;span aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;css-16f3y1r e13ogyst0&quot;&gt;Mr. Ton-That showing the results of a search for a photo of himself.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot; class=&quot;css-cnj6d5 e1z0qqy90&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1tej78p0&quot;&gt;Credit...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Amr Alfiky for The New York Times&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;css-1320w4z eoo0vm40&quot; id=&quot;link-33e380c5&quot;&gt;Going Viral With Law Enforcement&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;By the end of 2017, the company had a formidable facial recognition tool, which it called Smartcheckr. But Mr. Schwartz and Mr. Ton-That weren’t sure whom they were going to sell it to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Maybe it could be used to vet babysitters or as an add-on feature for surveillance cameras. What about a tool for security guards in the lobbies of buildings or to help hotels greet guests by name? “We thought of every idea,” Mr. Ton-That said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;One of the odder pitches, in late 2017, was to Paul Nehlen — an anti-Semite and self-described “&lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/powerpost/wp/2017/12/27/ryans-pro-white-primary-foe-denounced-by-breitbart-after-his-anti-semitic-tweets/&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;pro-white&lt;/a&gt;” Republican running for Congress in Wisconsin — to use “unconventional databases” for “extreme opposition research,” according to a document provided to Mr. Nehlen and later posted online. Mr. Ton-That said the company never actually offered such services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The company soon changed its name to Clearview AI and began marketing to law enforcement. That was when the company got its first round of funding from outside investors: Mr. Thiel and Kirenaga Partners. Among other things, Mr. Thiel was famous for secretly financing Hulk Hogan’s lawsuit that bankrupted the popular website Gawker. Both Mr. Thiel and Mr. Ton-That had been the subject of negative articles by Gawker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-ew4tgv&quot; aria-label=&quot;companion column&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“In 2017, Peter gave a talented young founder $200,000, which two years later converted to equity in Clearview AI,” said Jeremiah Hall, Mr. Thiel’s spokesman. “That was Peter’s only contribution; he is not involved in the company.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Even after a second funding round in 2019, Clearview remains tiny, having raised $7 million from investors, according to &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://pitchbook.com/profiles/company/232177-96&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Pitchbook&lt;/a&gt;, a website that tracks investments in start-ups. The company declined to confirm the amount.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;In February, the Indiana State Police started experimenting with Clearview. They solved a case within 20 minutes of using the app. Two men had gotten into a fight in a park, and it ended when one shot the other in the stomach. A bystander recorded the crime on a phone, so the police had a still of the gunman’s face to run through Clearview’s app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;They immediately got a match: The man appeared in a video that someone had posted on social media, and his name was included in a caption on the video. “He did not have a driver’s license and hadn’t been arrested as an adult, so he wasn’t in government databases,” said Chuck Cohen, an Indiana State Police captain at the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The man was arrested and charged; Mr. Cohen said he probably wouldn’t have been identified without the ability to search social media for his face. The Indiana State Police became Clearview’s first paying customer, according to the company. (The police declined to comment beyond saying that they tested Clearview’s app.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Clearview deployed current and former Republican officials to approach police forces, offering free trials and annual licenses for as little as $2,000. Mr. Schwartz tapped his political connections to help make government officials aware of the tool, according to Mr. Ton-That. (“I’m thrilled to have the opportunity to help Hoan build Clearview into a mission-driven organization that’s helping law enforcement protect children and enhance the safety of communities across the country,” Mr. Schwartz said through a spokeswoman.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The company’s main contact for customers was Jessica Medeiros Garrison, who managed Luther Strange’s Republican campaign for Alabama attorney general. Brandon Fricke, an N.F.L. agent engaged to the Fox Nation host Tomi Lahren, &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;http://clerk.house.gov/public_disc/financial-pdfs/2019/10029687.pdf&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;said in a financial disclosure report&lt;/a&gt; during a &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://splinternews.com/what-the-frick-e-is-this-1837985411&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;congressional campaign in California&lt;/a&gt; that he was a “growth consultant” for the company. (Clearview said that it was a brief, unpaid role, and that the company had enlisted Democrats to help market its product as well.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-ew4tgv&quot; aria-label=&quot;companion column&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The company’s most effective sales technique was offering 30-day free trials to officers, who then encouraged their acquisition departments to sign up and praised the tool to officers from other police departments at conferences and online, according to the company and documents provided by police departments in response to public-record requests. Mr. Ton-That finally had his viral hit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;In July, a detective in Clifton, N.J., urged his captain in an email to buy the software because it was “able to identify a suspect in a matter of seconds.” During the department’s free trial, Clearview had identified shoplifters, an Apple Store thief and a good Samaritan who had punched out a man threatening people with a knife.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Photos “could be covertly taken with telephoto lens and input into the software, without ‘burning’ the surveillance operation,” the detective wrote in the &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.muckrock.com/foi/clifton-6861/clifton-nj-83767/&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;email&lt;/a&gt;, provided to The Times by two researchers, Beryl Lipton of MuckRock and Freddy Martinez of Open the Government. They &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.muckrock.com/news/archives/2020/jan/18/clearview-ai-facial-recogniton-records/&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;discovered Clearview&lt;/a&gt; late last year while looking into how &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.muckrock.com/project/police-surveillance-facial-recognition-use-in-your-backyard-452/&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;local police departments are using facial recognition&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;According to a Clearview sales presentation reviewed by The Times, the app helped identify a range of individuals: a person who was accused of sexually abusing a child whose face appeared in the mirror of someone’s else gym photo; the person behind a string of mailbox thefts in Atlanta; a John Doe found dead on an Alabama sidewalk; and suspects in multiple identity-fraud cases at banks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-ew4tgv&quot; aria-label=&quot;companion column&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;In Gainesville, Fla., Detective Sgt. Nick Ferrara heard about Clearview last summer when it advertised on CrimeDex, a list-serv for investigators who specialize in financial crimes. He said he had previously relied solely on a state-provided facial recognition tool, &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2020/01/12/technology/facial-recognition-police.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;FACES&lt;/a&gt;, which draws from more than 30 million Florida mug shots and Department of Motor Vehicle photos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-ew4tgv&quot; aria-label=&quot;companion column&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Sergeant Ferrara found Clearview’s app superior, he said. Its nationwide database of images is much larger, and unlike FACES, Clearview’s algorithm doesn’t require photos of people looking straight at the camera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“With Clearview, you can use photos that aren’t perfect,” Sergeant Ferrara said. “A person can be wearing a hat or glasses, or it can be a profile shot or partial view of their face.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;He uploaded his own photo to the system, and it brought up his Venmo page. He ran photos from old, dead-end cases and identified more than 30 suspects. In September, the Gainesville Police Department paid $10,000 for an annual Clearview license.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Federal law enforcement, including the F.B.I. and the Department of Homeland Security, are trying it, as are Canadian law enforcement authorities, according to the company and government officials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Despite its growing popularity, Clearview avoided public mention &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.wftv.com/news/local/florida-law-enforcement-agencies-use-facial-recognition-identify-alleged-thief/SGHPUGB5W5CX3FYVSLU7P6EV7I/&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;until the end of 2019&lt;/a&gt;, when Florida prosecutors charged a woman with grand theft after two grills and a vacuum were stolen from an Ace Hardware store in Clermont. She was identified when the police ran a still from a surveillance video through Clearview, which led them to her Facebook page. A tattoo visible in the surveillance video and Facebook photos confirmed her identity, according to an affidavit in the case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;css-1320w4z eoo0vm40&quot; id=&quot;link-58741576&quot;&gt;‘We’re All Screwed’&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Mr. Ton-That said the tool does not always work. Most of the photos in Clearview’s database are taken at eye level. Much of the material that the police upload is from surveillance cameras mounted on ceilings or high on walls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“They put surveillance cameras too high,” Mr. Ton-That lamented. “The angle is wrong for good face recognition.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-ew4tgv&quot; aria-label=&quot;companion column&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Despite that, the company said, its tool finds matches up to 75 percent of the time. But it is unclear how often the tool delivers false matches, because it has not been tested by an independent party such as the National Institute of Standards and Technology, a federal agency that &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nist.gov/programs-projects/face-recognition-vendor-test-frvt-ongoing&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;rates the performance&lt;/a&gt; of facial recognition algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“We have no data to suggest this tool is accurate,” said Clare Garvie, a researcher at Georgetown University’s Center on Privacy and Technology, who has studied the &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flawedfacedata.com/&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;government’s use of facial recognition&lt;/a&gt;. “The larger the database, the larger the risk of misidentification because of the doppelgänger effect. They’re talking about a massive database of random people they’ve found on the internet.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;But current and former law enforcement officials say the app is effective. “For us, the testing was whether it worked or not,” said Mr. Cohen, the former Indiana State Police captain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;One reason that Clearview is catching on is that its service is unique. That’s because Facebook and other social media sites prohibit people from scraping users’ images — Clearview is violating the sites’ terms of service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“A lot of people are doing it,” Mr. Ton-That shrugged. “Facebook knows.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Jay Nancarrow, a Facebook spokesman, said the company was reviewing the situation with Clearview and “will take appropriate action if we find they are violating our rules.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Mr. Thiel, the Clearview investor, sits on Facebook’s board. Mr. Nancarrow declined to comment on Mr. Thiel's personal investments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Some law enforcement officials said they didn’t realize the photos they uploaded were being sent to and stored on Clearview’s servers. Clearview tries to pre-empt concerns with &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://int.nyt.com/data/documenthelper/6690-clearview-faq/c8b081a0bcca12e7903a/optimized/full.pdf#page=1&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;an F.A.Q. document&lt;/a&gt; given to would-be clients that says its customer-support employees won’t look at the photos that the police upload.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-ew4tgv&quot; aria-label=&quot;companion column&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Clearview also hired Paul D. Clement, a United States solicitor general under President George W. Bush, to assuage concerns about the app’s legality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;In &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://int.nyt.com/data/documenthelper/6689-clearview-legal-memo/c8b081a0bcca12e7903a/optimized/full.pdf#page=1&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;an August memo&lt;/a&gt; that Clearview provided to potential customers, including the &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.muckrock.com/foi/atlanta-325/facial-recognition-atlanta-ga-76491&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Atlanta Police Department&lt;/a&gt; and the Pinellas County Sheriff’s Office in Florida, Mr. Clement said law enforcement agencies “do not violate the federal Constitution or relevant existing state biometric and privacy laws when using Clearview for its intended purpose.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Mr. Clement, now a partner at Kirkland &amp;amp; Ellis, wrote that the authorities don’t have to tell defendants that they were identified via Clearview, as long as it isn’t the sole basis for getting a warrant to arrest them. Mr. Clement did not respond to multiple requests for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The memo appeared to be effective; the Atlanta police and Pinellas County Sheriff’s Office soon started using Clearview.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Because the police upload photos of people they’re trying to identify, Clearview possesses a growing database of individuals who have attracted attention from law enforcement. The company also has the ability to manipulate the results that the police see. After the company realized I was asking officers to run my photo through the app, my face was flagged by Clearview’s systems and for a while showed no matches. When asked about this, Mr. Ton-That laughed and called it a “software bug.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“It’s creepy what they’re doing, but there will be many more of these companies. There is no monopoly on math,” said Al Gidari, a privacy professor at Stanford Law School. “Absent a very strong federal privacy law, we’re all screwed.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-ew4tgv&quot; aria-label=&quot;companion column&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Mr. Ton-That said his company used only publicly available images. If you change a privacy setting in Facebook so that search engines can’t link to your profile, your Facebook photos won’t be included in the database, he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;But if your profile has already been scraped, it is too late. The company keeps all the images it has scraped even if they are later deleted or taken down, though Mr. Ton-That said the company was working on a tool that would let people request that images be removed if they had been taken down from the website of origin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Woodrow Hartzog, a professor of law and computer science at Northeastern University in Boston, sees Clearview as the latest proof that &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/10/17/opinion/facial-recognition-ban.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;facial recognition should be banned&lt;/a&gt; in the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“We’ve relied on industry efforts to self-police and not embrace such a risky technology, but now those dams are breaking because there is so much money on the table,” Mr. Hartzog said. “I don’t see a future where we harness the benefits of face recognition technology without the crippling abuse of the surveillance that comes with it. The only way to stop it is to ban it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;css-1320w4z eoo0vm40&quot; id=&quot;link-41e29459&quot;&gt;Where Everybody Knows Your Name&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;During a recent interview at Clearview’s offices in a WeWork location in Manhattan’s Chelsea neighborhood, Mr. Ton-That demonstrated the app on himself. He took a selfie and uploaded it. The app pulled up 23 photos of him. In one, he is shirtless and lighting a cigarette while covered in what looks like blood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Mr. Ton-That then took my photo with the app. The “software bug” had been fixed, and now my photo returned numerous results, dating back a decade, including photos of myself that I had never seen before. When I used my hand to cover my nose and the bottom of my face, the app still returned seven correct matches for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Police officers and Clearview’s investors predict that its app will eventually be available to the public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-ew4tgv&quot; aria-label=&quot;companion column&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Mr. Ton-That said he was reluctant. “There’s always going to be a community of bad people who will misuse it,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Even if Clearview doesn’t make its app publicly available, a copycat company might, now that the taboo is broken. Searching someone by face could become as easy as Googling a name. Strangers would be able to listen in on sensitive conversations, take photos of the participants and know personal secrets. Someone walking down the street would be immediately identifiable — and his or her home address would be only a few clicks away. It would herald the end of public anonymity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Asked about the implications of bringing such a power into the world, Mr. Ton-That seemed taken aback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“I have to think about that,” he said. “Our belief is that this is the best use of the technology.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-jwz2nf etfikam0&quot;&gt;Jennifer Valentino-DeVries, Gabriel J.X. Dance and Aaron Krolik contributed reporting. Kitty Bennett contributed research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-ew4tgv&quot; aria-label=&quot;companion column&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2020 11:12:22 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>johanam</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2020/01/18/technology/clearview-privacy-facial-recognition.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>The Secretive Company That Might End Privacy as We Know It</og:title>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2020/01/19/business/19clearview/19clearview-facebookJumbo-v4.png</og:image>
<og:description>A little-known start-up helps law enforcement match photos of unknown people to their online images — and “might lead to a dystopian future or something,” a backer says.</og:description>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2020/01/18/technology/clearview-privacy-facial-recognition.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Smart homes will turn dumb overnight as Charter kills security service</title>
<link>https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2020/01/smart-homes-will-turn-dumb-overnight-as-charter-kills-security-service/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2020/01/smart-homes-will-turn-dumb-overnight-as-charter-kills-security-service/</guid>
<description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/charter-spectrum-vehicle-800x533.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A Charter Spectrum service vehicle.&quot;/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;caption-text&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/charter-spectrum-vehicle.jpg&quot; class=&quot;enlarge-link&quot; data-height=&quot;600&quot; data-width=&quot;900&quot;&gt;Enlarge&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;sep&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; A Charter Spectrum vehicle.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;aside id=&quot;social-left&quot; class=&quot;social-left&quot; aria-label=&quot;Read the comments or share this article&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;comment-count-before&quot;&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;91 posters participating&quot; class=&quot;comment-count icon-comment-bubble-down&quot; href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2020/01/smart-homes-will-turn-dumb-overnight-as-charter-kills-security-service/?comments=1&quot;&gt;reader comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;a title=&quot;91 posters participating&quot; class=&quot;comment-count icon-comment-bubble-down&quot; href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2020/01/smart-homes-will-turn-dumb-overnight-as-charter-kills-security-service/?comments=1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;comment-count-number&quot;&gt;133&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;visually-hidden&quot;&gt;with 91 posters participating&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;share-links&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Share this story&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;Charter is killing its home-security service and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.spectrum.net/support/home-security/home-security-equipment-faq&quot;&gt;telling customers&lt;/a&gt; that security devices they've purchased will stop working once the service is shut down on February 5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The impending shutdown and customers' anger at Charter—a cable company also known by the brand name &quot;Spectrum&quot;—has been widely reported over the past month. Over the years, some customers have spent &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ksby.com/news/national-news/spectrum-ending-home-security-leaving-customers-scrambling&quot;&gt;large sums&lt;/a&gt; on products that will no longer work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One user posting on a DSLReports forum said they spent &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dslreports.com/forum/r32599845-&quot;&gt;$1,200&lt;/a&gt; on sensors and IP cameras, which will be essentially useless in a couple of weeks. The devices won't connect to other alarm-monitoring services, and Charter will no longer offer the ability to remotely manage the system and view security video. (We're guessing a Charter alarm would still be able to make loud noises when someone breaks into a house, but that doesn't mean it'll work with an alarm-monitoring service.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Charter partnered with Amazon's Ring and Abode to give customers a free equipment bundle if they buy a year of monitoring, but those deals may not be enough to compensate customers who purchased a lot of devices from Charter over the years. Charter is not providing refunds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;No interoperability&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A big question is why there's no way for Charter customers to keep using these devices, given that they rely on the Zigbee specification that allows multi-vendor interoperability for smart-home products. Why can't Charter customers connect their security devices to a Zigbee-enabled smart-home hub or use them with another alarm-monitoring service that supports Zigbee? One user on DSLReports &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dslreports.com/forum/r32599958-Other-Spectrum-Shuttering-Home-Security-Feb-5-2020&quot;&gt;pointed out&lt;/a&gt; that years ago, Spectrum devices &quot;were firmware coded to prevent them from being seen and usable within the normal universe of Zigbee devices.&quot; But could Charter issue a software update that lets these products work with other Zigbee systems?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We haven't gotten a definitive answer, but it seems that a Zigbee hub alone isn't enough to ensure that Charter's security products work with alarm-monitoring systems offered by other vendors. We asked Charter, and a company spokesperson initially told us the following: &quot;My understanding is that other service providers who use Zigbee have their own devices/software/certification that make those devices non-transferable to someone else's home security solution. That isn't something specific to Charter.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We then contacted the &lt;a href=&quot;https://zigbeealliance.org/&quot;&gt;Zigbee Alliance&lt;/a&gt;, an industry group that develops standards and certifies products to ensure multi-vendor interoperability. The first answer a Zigbee Alliance spokesperson gave us made it sound like the Charter products should be re-usable with other vendors' Zigbee-enabled systems:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our team looked into this and the involved Zigbee devices [used by Charter] were sourced through Icontrol and were Zigbee Certified and Icontrol certified. Via a factory reset they can be joined to another hub—so a re-pair process is possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Icontrol Networks' business lines were purchased by &lt;a href=&quot;https://corporate.comcast.com/comcast-voices/comcast-closes-icontrol-acquisition&quot;&gt;Comcast&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.alarm.com/about/press/PressGeneric.aspx?cmid=432&quot;&gt;Alarm.com&lt;/a&gt; in March 2017.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So can Charter customers simply do a factory reset, join their security products to any Zigbee hub, and sign up for another security service? Not quite. Even if there is a factory-reset method available on a particular device, that doesn't mean the reset will make the device compatible with other vendors' systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;The answer varies by exact device,&quot; the Zigbee Alliance told us. &quot;Each device will have a factory reset method, but what that is varies by manufacturer.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Zigbee Alliance is trying to solve this problem with its &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20190529005298/en/Zigbee-Alliance-Announces-%E2%80%98All-Hubs-Initiative%E2%80%99-Driven&quot;&gt;All Hubs Initiative&lt;/a&gt; announced in May 2019, which aims to improve interoperability, the spokesperson told us. But it appears that effort won't help Charter customers keep their products running after February 5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Factory reset won’t help&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the Zigbee Alliance answered our questions, we asked Charter if it's possible for customers to perform a factory reset and pair their devices with non-Charter Zigbee hubs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Charter's answer included some good news for customers, but not much. What Charter calls &quot;lifestyle devices,&quot; such as thermostats and lighting devices, &quot;will work on hubs that support those devices and can be defaulted and re-paired with that hub,&quot; Charter told us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Charter security devices can't be joined to other security systems, even if they use Zigbee, the company told us. While those thermostats and lights will work with other vendors, &quot;that isn't the case with the security devices such as window and door alarms, which account for the majority of Spectrum Home Security devices,&quot; Charter said. &quot;Other home security providers have their own security/alarm devices, software and certifications and those systems wont accept a security device that they haven't tested or certified.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://support.smartthings.com/hc/en-us/articles/115005074883-ADT-Security-Hub-FAQ#devices&quot;&gt;ADT says&lt;/a&gt; that its security hub works with Zigbee lights, cameras, thermostats, door locks, and other products, but that &quot;only ADT-monitored security devices can be used for security monitoring with the ADT Security Hub.&quot; Charter's system appears to be similarly restricted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;In this case, Charter probably has hard-coded these devices to only work with its security services,&quot; Ars IT Editor Sean Gallagher told me when I asked him to help me make sense of the problem. Although certain products like light bulbs and smart locks are widely compatible across different vendors' hubs, Gallagher also noted that &quot;Zigbee is famously nonstandard as a standard.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Customers lose&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the question of why the products won't work after February 5 is hard to answer, one thing was immediately clear: Charter customers are getting a bad deal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Charter noted in a statement that it &quot;inherited&quot; the home-security business from Time Warner Cable and Bright House Networks when it bought those companies &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2016/05/charter-completes-acquisition-of-time-warner-cable-and-bright-house/&quot;&gt;in May 2016&lt;/a&gt;. Those acquisition made Charter the second biggest cable provider in the US, but Charter apparently never wanted the home-security service that came with the greatly expanded cable business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;Spectrum stopped marketing the Home Security product after that transaction in 2016 but has continued to maintain the service for the past 3+ years,&quot; Charter told us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Charter is giving customers a couple of options to soften the blow. Charter &lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.ring.com/products/charter-alarm-offer&quot;&gt;partnered with Amazon's Ring&lt;/a&gt; to offer a free security kit (with an alarm base station, alarm keypad, three contact sensors, one motion detector, and one range extender) when customers purchase one year of Ring monitoring for $340. This deal doesn't sound so great once you realize that Ring sells the &lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.ring.com/pages/protect-plans&quot;&gt;same one-year subscription for $100&lt;/a&gt; instead of $340, and separately sells a &lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.ring.com/products/alarm-security-kit?variant=56549618187&quot;&gt;5-piece equipment set for $199&lt;/a&gt; or a &lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.ring.com/products/alarm-security-kit-10-piece?variant=17900742738009&quot;&gt;10-piece equipment set for $259&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Charter also partnered with Abode on a &lt;a href=&quot;https://goabode.com/spectrum-security-upgrade-special-offer&quot;&gt;similar deal&lt;/a&gt; that includes an 8-piece kit with four sensors, a gateway, key fob, keypad, and streaming camera when customers buy one year of monitoring for $179. Abode says its standard yearly price is $200, but it's currently &lt;a href=&quot;https://goabode.com/plans&quot;&gt;on sale for $100&lt;/a&gt; even if you're not a Spectrum customer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;We are dedicated to making this a smooth transition for our Home Security customers and have partnered with Ring and Abode, two leading home security providers, to bring our customers exclusive offers and discounts on replacement security service and products,&quot; Charter said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's not clear how many Charter customers use the home-security service. The company said that the shutdown &quot;impacts a very small number of Spectrum's customers&quot; because Charter stopped marketing the service in 2016. (Charter has &lt;a href=&quot;https://ir.charter.com/news-releases/news-release-details/charter-announces-second-quarter-2019-results&quot;&gt;28.7 million total customers&lt;/a&gt; across its cable TV, broadband, and phone businesses.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Ring and Abode deals may be enough to satisfy some Charter customers. But some say these deals won't replace all the equipment they've purchased over the years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steve Rottinghouse, a longtime Spectrum security customer who was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ksby.com/news/national-news/spectrum-ending-home-security-leaving-customers-scrambling&quot;&gt;profiled&lt;/a&gt; by KSBY News in Central California this month, said he &quot;spent almost $900 for cameras, motion sensors, door sensors, window sensors, and a thermostat.&quot; But he said the deals offered through Ring and Abode would replace only &quot;a fraction of the setup he has here in his house, and [that] he will have to spend hundreds of dollars more to build a similar Ring security system,&quot; KSBY reported.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;I called [Charter] and asked if I can get a credit toward my phone bill or cable bill,&quot; Rottinghouse told the news station. &quot;And they said no.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Disclosure: The Advance/Newhouse Partnership, which owns 13 percent of Charter, is part of Advance Publications. Advance Publications owns Condé Nast, which owns Ars Technica.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2020 09:12:16 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>BerislavLopac</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2020/01/smart-homes-will-turn-dumb-overnight-as-charter-kills-security-service/</og:url>
<og:title>Smart homes will turn dumb overnight as Charter kills security service</og:title>
<og:image>https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/charter-spectrum-vehicle-760x380.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>Charter's product shutdown highlights lack of interoperability in alarm systems.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2020/01/smart-homes-will-turn-dumb-overnight-as-charter-kills-security-service/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Cartridge cannot be used until printer is enrolled in HP Instant Ink</title>
<link>https://twitter.com/ryandonsullivan/status/1218149470220632064</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://twitter.com/ryandonsullivan/status/1218149470220632064</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Related, anyone have a printer they recommend that doesn’t do this nonsense? 

If the subscription saved me from grossly overpaying for ink I’d consider it. But I still grossly overpay for ink because I’m an American and office supply extortion is part of our birthright.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2020 08:09:19 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>pionerkotik</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://mobile.twitter.com/ryandonsullivan/status/1218149470220632064</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>HTTP static server one-liners</title>
<link>https://gist.github.com/willurd/5720255</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://gist.github.com/willurd/5720255</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Each of these commands will run an ad hoc http static server in your current (or specified) directory, available at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:8000&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://localhost:8000&lt;/a&gt;. Use this power wisely.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/webdev/comments/1fs45z/list_of_ad_hoc_http_server_oneliners/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Discussion on reddit&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Python 2.x&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
$ python -m SimpleHTTPServer 8000
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Python 3.x&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
$ python -m http.server 8000
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Twisted &lt;sub&gt;&lt;sup&gt;(Python)&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
$ twistd -n web -p 8000 --path &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
$ python -c &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;from twisted.web.server import Site; from twisted.web.static import File; from twisted.internet import reactor; reactor.listenTCP(8000, Site(File(&quot;.&quot;))); reactor.run()&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depends on &lt;a href=&quot;http://twistedmatrix.com/trac/wiki/Downloads&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Twisted&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Ruby&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
$ ruby -rwebrick -e&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;WEBrick::HTTPServer.new(:Port =&amp;gt; 8000, :DocumentRoot =&amp;gt; Dir.pwd).start&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&quot;http://barkingiguana.com/2010/04/11/a-one-line-web-server-in-ruby/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Barking Iguana&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Ruby 1.9.2+&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
$ ruby -run -ehttpd &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt; -p8000
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/willurd/5720255#comment-855952&quot;&gt;nobu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;adsf &lt;sub&gt;&lt;sup&gt;(Ruby)&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
$ gem install adsf   &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt; install dependency&lt;/span&gt;
$ adsf -p 8000
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/willurd/5720255/#comment-841393&quot;&gt;twome&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;No directory listings.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Sinatra &lt;sub&gt;&lt;sup&gt;(Ruby)&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
$ gem install sinatra   &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt; install dependency&lt;/span&gt;
$ ruby -rsinatra -e&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;set :public_folder, &quot;.&quot;; set :port, 8000&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;No directory listings.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Perl&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
$ cpan HTTP::Server::Brick   &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt; install dependency&lt;/span&gt;
$ perl -MHTTP::Server::Brick -e &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;$s=HTTP::Server::Brick-&amp;gt;new(port=&amp;gt;8000); $s-&amp;gt;mount(&quot;/&quot;=&amp;gt;{path=&amp;gt;&quot;.&quot;}); $s-&amp;gt;start&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.perlmonks.org/?node_id=865239&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Anonymous Monk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Plack &lt;sub&gt;&lt;sup&gt;(Perl)&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
$ cpan Plack   &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt; install dependency&lt;/span&gt;
$ plackup -MPlack::App::Directory -e &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;Plack::App::Directory-&amp;gt;new(root=&amp;gt;&quot;.&quot;);&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; -p 8000
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&quot;http://advent.plackperl.org/2009/12/day-5-run-a-static-file-web-server-with-plack.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;miyagawa&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Mojolicious &lt;sub&gt;&lt;sup&gt;(Perl)&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
$ cpan Mojolicious::Lite   &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt; install dependency&lt;/span&gt;
$ perl -MMojolicious::Lite -MCwd -e &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;app-&amp;gt;static-&amp;gt;paths-&amp;gt;[0]=getcwd; app-&amp;gt;start&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; daemon -l http://&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;:8000
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;No directory listings.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;http-server &lt;sub&gt;&lt;sup&gt;(Node.js)&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
$ npm install -g http-server   &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt; install dependency&lt;/span&gt;
$ http-server -p 8000
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: This server does funky things with relative paths. For example, if you have a file &lt;code&gt;/tests/index.html&lt;/code&gt;, it will load &lt;code&gt;index.html&lt;/code&gt; if you go to &lt;code&gt;/test&lt;/code&gt;, but will treat relative paths as if they were coming from &lt;code&gt;/&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;node-static &lt;sub&gt;&lt;sup&gt;(Node.js)&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
$ npm install -g node-static   &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt; install dependency&lt;/span&gt;
$ static -p 8000
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;No directory listings.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;PHP &lt;sub&gt;&lt;sup&gt;(&amp;gt;= 5.4)&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
$ php -S 127.0.0.1:8000
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/webdev/comments/1fs45z/list_of_ad_hoc_http_server_oneliners/cad9ew3&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;/u/prawnsalad&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/willurd/5720255#comment-841131&quot;&gt;MattLicense&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;No directory listings.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Erlang&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot; readability=&quot;35&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
$ erl -s inets -eval &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;inets:start(httpd,[{server_name,&quot;NAME&quot;},{document_root, &quot;.&quot;},{server_root, &quot;.&quot;},{port, 8000},{mime_types,[{&quot;html&quot;,&quot;text/html&quot;},{&quot;htm&quot;,&quot;text/html&quot;},{&quot;js&quot;,&quot;text/javascript&quot;},{&quot;css&quot;,&quot;text/css&quot;},{&quot;gif&quot;,&quot;image/gif&quot;},{&quot;jpg&quot;,&quot;image/jpeg&quot;},{&quot;jpeg&quot;,&quot;image/jpeg&quot;},{&quot;png&quot;,&quot;image/png&quot;}]}]).&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/willurd/5720255/#comment-841166&quot;&gt;nivertech&lt;/a&gt; (with the addition of some basic mime types)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;No directory listings.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;busybox httpd&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
$ busybox httpd -f -p 8000
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/willurd/5720255#comment-841915&quot;&gt;lvm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;webfs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
$ webfsd -F -p 8000
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depends on &lt;a href=&quot;http://linux.bytesex.org/misc/webfs.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;webfs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;IIS Express&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
C:&lt;span class=&quot;pl-cce&quot;&gt;\&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;C:\Program Files (x86)\IIS Express\iisexpress.exe&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; /path:C:&lt;span class=&quot;pl-cce&quot;&gt;\M&lt;/span&gt;yWeb /port:8000
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depends on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.iis.net/learn/extensions/introduction-to-iis-express/iis-express-overview&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;IIS Express&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Credit: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/webdev/comments/1fs45z/list_of_ad_hoc_http_server_oneliners/cada8no&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;/u/fjantomen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;No directory listings. &lt;code&gt;/path&lt;/code&gt; must be an absolute path.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any suggestions, drop them in the comments below or on the reddit discussion. To get on this list, a solution must:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;serve static files using your current directory (or a specified directory) as the server root,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;be able to be run with a single, one line command (dependencies are fine if they're a one-time thing),&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;serve basic file types (html, css, js, images) with proper mime types,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;require no configuration (from files or otherwise) beyond the command itself (no framework-specific servers, etc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;must run, or have a mode where it can run, in the foreground (i.e. no daemons)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2020 05:44:38 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>known</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://github.githubassets.com/images/modules/gists/gist-og-image.png</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Big list of http static server one-liners</og:title>
<og:url>https://gist.github.com/willurd/5720255</og:url>
<og:description>Big list of http static server one-liners. GitHub Gist: instantly share code, notes, and snippets.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://gist.github.com/willurd/5720255</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Show HN: OneDev – A Lightweight GitLab Alternative</title>
<link>https://github.com/theonedev/onedev</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/theonedev/onedev</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;With Issue Tracking, Git Management, Pull Request, and Build Farm. Simple yet Powerful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feature highlights compared to other products in the market:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Docker First Kubernetes Native Build Farm&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trivial to set up a build farm to run massive CI builds as pods in Kubernetes. No agents or runners required. Transparent support for Linux and Windows containers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/theonedev/onedev/blob/master/features/job-executor.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/theonedev/onedev/raw/master/features/job-executor.png&quot; alt=&quot;Job Executor&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Create Build Spec in a Breeze&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No YAML files to write. No complex grammars to remember. Create build spec for your projects instantly without learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/theonedev/onedev/blob/master/features/cispec.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/theonedev/onedev/raw/master/features/cispec.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Cispec&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Flexible Build Workflow and Pipeline&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conditional build parameters. Create matrix builds by combining different parameters. Connect jobs to create pipelines. Run jobs concurrently to speed up processing. Run jobs automatically upon certain events, or manually by authorized users&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/theonedev/onedev/blob/master/features/build-workflow.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/theonedev/onedev/raw/master/features/build-workflow.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Build Workflow&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Custom Issue States and Fields&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add custom issue states and fields. Configure field dependencies. Transit issue state automatically upon certain events, or manually by authorized users&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/theonedev/onedev/blob/master/features/custom-issue.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/theonedev/onedev/raw/master/features/custom-issue.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Custom Issue&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Auto-Refreshing Issue Boards&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Define issue boards to show issues in columns based on values of specified field. Perform issue operations without leaving the board. Refresh board automatically to reflect most recent issue state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/theonedev/onedev/blob/master/features/issue-boards.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/theonedev/onedev/raw/master/features/issue-boards.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Issue Boards&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Symbol Search and Navigation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Language aware symbol search. Symbol navigation in source code and diff. Outline display and search. Works for every commit. Currently supports Java, JavaScript, C, C++, CSharp, Go, PHP, Python, CSS, SCSS, LESS and R.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/theonedev/onedev/blob/master/features/symbol-search.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/theonedev/onedev/raw/master/features/symbol-search.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Symbol Search&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Code Discussions and Comprehensions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instant and lightweight code discussions on code and diff blocks without creating pull requests. Discussions stay with the code to help code comprehension even if file is changed or renamed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/theonedev/onedev/blob/master/features/code-comments.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/theonedev/onedev/raw/master/features/code-comments.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Code Comments&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Flexible Pull Request Review Policies&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enforce pull request review with branch protections. Specify required reviewers and builds for desired file patterns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/theonedev/onedev/blob/master/features/branch-protection.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/theonedev/onedev/raw/master/features/branch-protection.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Branch Protection&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Painless Pull Request Review&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Review pull request commits as a whole or one by one. Organize code discussions in threads to show changes since last review explicitly&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/theonedev/onedev/blob/master/features/increment-review.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/theonedev/onedev/raw/master/features/increment-review.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Increment Review&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Powerful Query Language&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perform sophisticated queries against projects, commits, builds, issues, pull requests or code comments with a powerful query language. Save query for quick access. Subscribe to saved query to get notified of interesting events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/theonedev/onedev/blob/master/features/powerful-query.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/theonedev/onedev/raw/master/features/powerful-query.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Powerful Query&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Deep Integration of Code, Issue, Pull Request and Build&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Configure issues to transit to desired state upon commit, build or pull request events. See commit and pull request events in issue activities. Query fixed issues between builds. Find builds or pull requests fixing particular issues or commits&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/theonedev/onedev/blob/master/features/issue-query.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/theonedev/onedev/raw/master/features/issue-query.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Issue Query&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fine Grained Permission Control&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Define permission schemes best suiting your development workflow. For instance, you may specify who can change particular source folder, who can assign issues, who can run release builds, or who can access build log, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/theonedev/onedev/blob/master/features/role.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/theonedev/onedev/raw/master/features/role.png&quot; alt=&quot;Role&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2020 01:09:25 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>robinshen</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars0.githubusercontent.com/u/44279871?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>theonedev/onedev</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/theonedev/onedev</og:url>
<og:description>Super Easy All-In-One DevOps Platform. Contribute to theonedev/onedev development by creating an account on GitHub.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/theonedev/onedev</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>I&amp;#039;ve been working on X11 on jailbroken iOS</title>
<link>https://maxleiter.com/X11/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://maxleiter.com/X11/</guid>
<description>&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm excited to announce that X11 is coming soon to iOS. Most (see below) packages and dependencies for a fully functioning X11 desktop system have been compiled and are available on Cydia for iOS 11+. All packages have been compiled for arm64 and have been tested on iOS 12.4 and iOS 13.1. This requires a jailbroken device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This site will serve largely as documentation for building yourself. You can add the Cydia repo below for the deb packages. Please let me know if you run across any issues with the debs; it's likely I messed up including a library or something like that. &lt;em&gt;(These aren't done just yet.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;cydia://url/https://cydia.saurik.com/api/share#?source=https://maxleiter.com/cydia&quot; readability=&quot;4.7957695113056&quot;&gt;&lt;button readability=&quot;9.5915390226112&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;cydia://url/https://cydia.saurik.com/api/share#?source=https://maxleiter.com/cydia&quot;&gt;Add to Cydia&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;https://maxleiter.com/X11/pic.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;X11 on iOS&quot;/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the moment, a virtual screen is accessed via a VNC client to an Xvnc&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://maxleiter.com/X11/#1&quot; id=&quot;1src&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;instance running on the iDevice. If you're unfamiliar, Xvnc is an X server with a virtual screen that can be accessed via VNC. The best part of this is no drivers are required: it's all handled by Xvnc.

&lt;p&gt;I want to turn my iPad into a proper development environment, and a windowing system helps with that. It's a powerful machine with a Unix-like OS, so X11 seemed like a reasonable project. X11 allows running arbirtary applications like browsers and IDEs, assuming you can make them compile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;X11 on iOS via Xvnc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Working window manager (jwm)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/MaxLeiter/cydia/tree/master/debs&quot;&gt;Loads&lt;/a&gt; of other packaged libraries, tools, and applications, including meson/ninja and ocaml.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All available in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://maxleiter.com/cydia&quot;&gt;Cydia repo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix modern versions of fontconfig (&amp;gt; 2.8.0)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Proper desktop enviroments like XFCE and GNOME&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;requires GTK&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Qt support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experiment with Wayland via wayvnc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
If you're interested in using X11 now, or helping make it available sooner, feel free to &lt;a href=&quot;https://maxleiter.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#462b273e31232a2a682a232f32233406212b272f2a6825292b&quot;&gt;email me&lt;/a&gt; or find me on IRC as MaxLeiter in #X11iOS on Freenode. More information on contributing is in the works.

&lt;a href=&quot;https://maxleiter.com/X11/instructions.html&quot;&gt;On a separate page&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Getting &lt;code&gt;checking build system type... Invalid configuration `arm64-apple-darwin19.0.0': machine `arm64-apple' not recognized&lt;/code&gt;? Run &lt;code&gt;echo 'echo arm-apple-darwin' &amp;gt; config.sub&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once I finish this it should be a little easier porting libraries and apps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 23:47:59 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>MaxLeiter</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://maxleiter.com/X11/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Boltzmann Brain</title>
<link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boltzmann_brain</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boltzmann_brain</guid>
<description>&lt;a class=&quot;mw-jump-link&quot; href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boltzmann_brain#mw-head&quot;&gt;Jump to navigation&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;a class=&quot;mw-jump-link&quot; href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boltzmann_brain#p-search&quot;&gt;Jump to search&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;div id=&quot;mw-content-text&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot; class=&quot;mw-content-ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;mw-parser-output&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;thumb tright&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;thumbinner&quot; style=&quot;width:222px;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Boltzmann2.jpg&quot; class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/a/ad/Boltzmann2.jpg/220px-Boltzmann2.jpg&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; width=&quot;220&quot; height=&quot;269&quot; class=&quot;thumbimage&quot; srcset=&quot;//upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/a/ad/Boltzmann2.jpg/330px-Boltzmann2.jpg 1.5x, //upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/a/ad/Boltzmann2.jpg/440px-Boltzmann2.jpg 2x&quot; data-file-width=&quot;490&quot; data-file-height=&quot;600&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;div class=&quot;thumbcaption&quot;&gt;Ludwig Boltzmann, after whom Boltzmann brains are named&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;b&gt;Boltzmann brain&lt;/b&gt; argument suggests that it is more likely for a single brain to spontaneously and briefly form in a void (complete with a false memory of having existed in our universe) than it is for our universe to have come about in the way modern science thinks it actually did. It was first proposed as a &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reductio_ad_absurdum&quot; title=&quot;Reductio ad absurdum&quot;&gt;reductio ad absurdum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt; response to &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ludwig_Boltzmann&quot; title=&quot;Ludwig Boltzmann&quot;&gt;Ludwig Boltzmann&lt;/a&gt;'s early explanation for the low-entropy state of our universe.&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-1&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boltzmann_brain#cite_note-1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Physics&quot; title=&quot;Physics&quot;&gt;physics&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thought_experiment&quot; title=&quot;Thought experiment&quot;&gt;thought experiment&lt;/a&gt;, a Boltzmann brain is a fully formed brain, complete with memories of a full human life in our universe, that arises due to extremely rare random fluctuations out of a state of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thermodynamic_equilibrium&quot; title=&quot;Thermodynamic equilibrium&quot;&gt;thermodynamic equilibrium&lt;/a&gt;. Theoretically over a period of time on the order of hundreds of billions of years, by sheer chance atoms in a void could spontaneously come together in such a way as to assemble a functioning human brain. Like any brain in such circumstances, it would almost immediately stop functioning and begin to deteriorate.&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-2&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boltzmann_brain#cite_note-2&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The idea is ironically named after the Austrian &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Physicist&quot; title=&quot;Physicist&quot;&gt;physicist&lt;/a&gt; Ludwig Boltzmann (1844–1906), who in 1896 published a theory that tried to account for the fact that we find ourselves in a universe that is not as chaotic as the budding field of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thermodynamics&quot; title=&quot;Thermodynamics&quot;&gt;thermodynamics&lt;/a&gt; seemed to predict. He offered several explanations, one of them being that the universe, even one that is fully random (or at &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thermal_equilibrium&quot; title=&quot;Thermal equilibrium&quot;&gt;thermal equilibrium&lt;/a&gt;), would spontaneously fluctuate to a more ordered (or low-&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Entropy&quot; title=&quot;Entropy&quot;&gt;entropy&lt;/a&gt;) state. One criticism of this &quot;Boltzmann universe&quot; hypothesis is that the most common thermal fluctuations are as close to equilibrium overall as possible; thus, by any reasonable criterion, actual humans in the actual universe would be vastly less likely than &quot;Boltzmann brains&quot; existing alone in an empty universe.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Boltzmann brains gained new relevance around 2002, when some cosmologists started to become concerned that, in many existing theories about the Universe, human brains in the current Universe appear to be vastly outnumbered by Boltzmann brains in the future Universe who, by chance, have exactly the same perceptions that we do; this leads to the conclusion that statistically we ourselves are likely to be Boltzmann brains. Such a &lt;i&gt;reductio ad absurdum&lt;/i&gt; argument is sometimes used to argue against certain theories of the Universe. When applied to more recent theories about the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Multiverse&quot; title=&quot;Multiverse&quot;&gt;multiverse&lt;/a&gt;, Boltzmann brain arguments are part of the unsolved &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Measure_problem_(cosmology)&quot; title=&quot;Measure problem (cosmology)&quot;&gt;measure problem of cosmology&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;Boltzmann_universe&quot;&gt;Boltzmann universe&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1896, the mathematician &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ernst_Zermelo&quot; title=&quot;Ernst Zermelo&quot;&gt;Ernst Zermelo&lt;/a&gt; advanced a theory that the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Second_Law_of_Thermodynamics&quot; class=&quot;mw-redirect&quot; title=&quot;Second Law of Thermodynamics&quot;&gt;Second Law of Thermodynamics&lt;/a&gt; was absolute rather than statistical.&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-3&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boltzmann_brain#cite_note-3&quot;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Zermelo bolstered his theory by pointing out that the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Poincaré_recurrence_theorem&quot; title=&quot;Poincaré recurrence theorem&quot;&gt;Poincaré recurrence theorem&lt;/a&gt; shows statistical entropy in a closed system must eventually be a periodic function; therefore, the Second Law, which is always observed to increase entropy, is unlikely to be statistical. To counter Zermelo's argument, the Austrian physicist &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ludwig_Boltzmann&quot; title=&quot;Ludwig Boltzmann&quot;&gt;Ludwig Boltzmann&lt;/a&gt; advanced two theories. The first theory, now believed to be the correct one, is that the Universe started for some unknown reason in a low-entropy state. The second and alternative theory, published in 1896 but attributed in 1895 to Boltzmann's assistant &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ignaz_Schütz&quot; title=&quot;Ignaz Schütz&quot;&gt;Ignaz Schütz&lt;/a&gt;, is the &quot;Boltzmann universe&quot; scenario. In this scenario, the Universe spends the vast majority of eternity in a featureless state of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Heat_death_of_the_universe&quot; title=&quot;Heat death of the universe&quot;&gt;heat death&lt;/a&gt;; however, over enough eons, eventually a very rare thermal fluctuation will occur where atoms bounce off each other in exactly such a way that it creates substructures such as our entire observable universe. Boltzmann argues that, while most of the Universe is featureless, we do not see those regions because they are devoid of intelligent life; to Boltzmann, it is unremarkable that we view solely the interior of our Boltzmann universe, as that is the only place where intelligent life lives. (This may be the first use in modern science of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anthropic_principle&quot; title=&quot;Anthropic principle&quot;&gt;anthropic principle&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-carroll2017_4-0&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boltzmann_brain#cite_note-carroll2017-4&quot;&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-5&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boltzmann_brain#cite_note-5&quot;&gt;[5]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 1931, astronomer &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Arthur_Eddington&quot; title=&quot;Arthur Eddington&quot;&gt;Arthur Eddington&lt;/a&gt; pointed out that, because a large fluctuation is exponentially less probable than a small fluctuation, observers in Boltzmann universes will be vastly outnumbered by observers in smaller fluctuations. Physicist &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Richard_Feynman&quot; title=&quot;Richard Feynman&quot;&gt;Richard Feynman&lt;/a&gt; published a similar counterargument within his widely-read 1964 &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Feynman_Lectures_on_Physics&quot; class=&quot;mw-redirect&quot; title=&quot;Feynman Lectures on Physics&quot;&gt;Feynman Lectures on Physics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;. By 2004, physicists had pushed Eddington's observation to its logical conclusion: the most numerous observers in an eternity of thermal fluctuations would be minimal &quot;Boltzmann brains&quot; popping up in an otherwise featureless universe.&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-carroll2017_4-1&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boltzmann_brain#cite_note-carroll2017-4&quot;&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-Albrecht_&amp;amp;_Sorbo_6-0&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boltzmann_brain#cite_note-Albrecht_&amp;amp;_Sorbo-6&quot;&gt;[6]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;Creation&quot;&gt;Creation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given enough time, every possible structure is formed via random fluctuation.&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-nytimes_7-0&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boltzmann_brain#cite_note-nytimes-7&quot;&gt;[7]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Boltzmann-style thought experiments focus on structures like human brains that are presumably self-aware observers. Given any arbitrary criteria for what constitutes a Boltzmann brain (or planet, or universe), smaller structures that minimally and barely meet the criteria are vastly and exponentially more common than larger structures; a rough analogy is how the odds of a real English word showing up when you shake a box of &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scrabble&quot; title=&quot;Scrabble&quot;&gt;Scrabble&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt; letters are greater than the odds that a whole English sentence or paragraph will form.&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-nytimes_7-1&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boltzmann_brain#cite_note-nytimes-7&quot;&gt;[7]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; The average timescale required for formation of a Boltzmann brain is vastly greater than the current age of the Universe. In modern physics, Boltzmann brains can be formed either by &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quantum_fluctuation&quot; title=&quot;Quantum fluctuation&quot;&gt;quantum fluctuation&lt;/a&gt;, or by a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thermal_fluctuation&quot; class=&quot;mw-redirect&quot; title=&quot;Thermal fluctuation&quot;&gt;thermal fluctuation&lt;/a&gt; generally involving &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nucleation&quot; title=&quot;Nucleation&quot;&gt;nucleation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-carroll2017_4-2&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boltzmann_brain#cite_note-carroll2017-4&quot;&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;Via_quantum_fluctuation&quot;&gt;Via quantum fluctuation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By one calculation, a Boltzmann brain would appear as a quantum fluctuation in the vacuum after a time interval of &lt;span class=&quot;mwe-math-element&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mwe-math-mathml-inline mwe-math-mathml-a11y&quot; style=&quot;display: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;math xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML&quot; alttext=&quot;{\displaystyle 10^{10^{50}}}&quot;&gt;&lt;semantics&gt;&lt;mrow class=&quot;MJX-TeXAtom-ORD&quot;&gt;&lt;mstyle displaystyle=&quot;true&quot; scriptlevel=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;msup&gt;&lt;mn&gt;10&lt;/mn&gt;&lt;mrow class=&quot;MJX-TeXAtom-ORD&quot;&gt;&lt;msup&gt;&lt;mn&gt;10&lt;/mn&gt;&lt;mrow class=&quot;MJX-TeXAtom-ORD&quot;&gt;&lt;mn&gt;50&lt;/mn&gt;&lt;/mrow&gt;&lt;/msup&gt;&lt;/mrow&gt;&lt;/msup&gt;&lt;/mstyle&gt;&lt;/mrow&gt;&lt;annotation encoding=&quot;application/x-tex&quot;&gt;{\displaystyle 10^{10^{50}}}&lt;/annotation&gt;&lt;/semantics&gt;&lt;/math&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://wikimedia.org/api/rest_v1/media/math/render/svg/86915ec94e1a8bbad54a000d1fc05300cba3122d&quot; class=&quot;mwe-math-fallback-image-inline&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; style=&quot;vertical-align: -0.338ex; width:5.7ex; height:3.009ex;&quot; alt=&quot;10^{10^{50}}&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt; years. This fluctuation can occur even in a true &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Minkowski_space&quot; title=&quot;Minkowski space&quot;&gt;Minkowski vacuum&lt;/a&gt; (a flat spacetime vacuum lacking &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vacuum_energy&quot; title=&quot;Vacuum energy&quot;&gt;vacuum energy&lt;/a&gt;). Quantum mechanics heavily favors smaller fluctuations that &quot;borrow&quot; the least amount of energy from the vacuum. Typically, a quantum Boltzmann brain would suddenly appear from the vacuum (alongside an equivalent amount of virtual antimatter), remain only long enough to have a single coherent thought or observation, and then disappear into the vacuum as suddenly as it appeared. Such a brain is completely self-contained, and can never radiate energy out to infinity.&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-davenport_8-0&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boltzmann_brain#cite_note-davenport-8&quot;&gt;[8]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;Via_nucleation&quot;&gt;Via nucleation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Current evidence suggests that the observable Universe is not a Minkowski space, but rather a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/De_Sitter_universe&quot; title=&quot;De Sitter universe&quot;&gt;de Sitter universe&lt;/a&gt; with a positive &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cosmological_constant&quot; title=&quot;Cosmological constant&quot;&gt;cosmological constant&lt;/a&gt;. In a de Sitter vacuum (but not in a Minkowski vacuum), a Boltzmann brain can form via nucleation of non-virtual particles gradually assembled by chance from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hawking_radiation&quot; title=&quot;Hawking radiation&quot;&gt;Hawking radiation&lt;/a&gt; emitted from the de Sitter space's bounded &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cosmological_horizon&quot; title=&quot;Cosmological horizon&quot;&gt;cosmological horizon&lt;/a&gt;. One estimate for the average time required until nucleation is around &lt;span class=&quot;mwe-math-element&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mwe-math-mathml-inline mwe-math-mathml-a11y&quot; style=&quot;display: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;math xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML&quot; alttext=&quot;{\displaystyle 10^{10^{69}}}&quot;&gt;&lt;semantics&gt;&lt;mrow class=&quot;MJX-TeXAtom-ORD&quot;&gt;&lt;mstyle displaystyle=&quot;true&quot; scriptlevel=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;msup&gt;&lt;mn&gt;10&lt;/mn&gt;&lt;mrow class=&quot;MJX-TeXAtom-ORD&quot;&gt;&lt;msup&gt;&lt;mn&gt;10&lt;/mn&gt;&lt;mrow class=&quot;MJX-TeXAtom-ORD&quot;&gt;&lt;mn&gt;69&lt;/mn&gt;&lt;/mrow&gt;&lt;/msup&gt;&lt;/mrow&gt;&lt;/msup&gt;&lt;/mstyle&gt;&lt;/mrow&gt;&lt;annotation encoding=&quot;application/x-tex&quot;&gt;{\displaystyle 10^{10^{69}}}&lt;/annotation&gt;&lt;/semantics&gt;&lt;/math&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://wikimedia.org/api/rest_v1/media/math/render/svg/900b55449486036ec27f0c6137daad5aef275715&quot; class=&quot;mwe-math-fallback-image-inline&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; style=&quot;vertical-align: -0.338ex; width:5.7ex; height:3.009ex;&quot; alt=&quot;{\displaystyle 10^{10^{69}}}&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt; years.&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-davenport_8-1&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boltzmann_brain#cite_note-davenport-8&quot;&gt;[8]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; A typical nucleated Boltzmann brain will, after it finishes its activity, cool off to absolute zero and eventually completely decay, as any isolated object would in the vacuum of space. Unlike the quantum fluctuation case, the Boltzmann brain will radiate energy out to infinity. In nucleation, the most common fluctuations are as close to thermal equilibrium overall as possible given whatever arbitrary criteria are provided for labeling a fluctuation a &quot;Boltzmann brain&quot;.&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-carroll2017_4-3&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boltzmann_brain#cite_note-carroll2017-4&quot;&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Theoretically a Boltzmann brain can also form, albeit again with a tiny probability, at any time during the matter-dominated early universe.&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-bousso_9-0&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boltzmann_brain#cite_note-bousso-9&quot;&gt;[9]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;Modern_Boltzmann_brain_problems&quot;&gt;Modern Boltzmann brain problems&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many cosmologists believe that if a theory predicts that Boltzmann brains with human-like experiences vastly outnumber normal human brains, then that theory should be rejected or disfavored. Others argue that brains produced via quantum fluctuation, and maybe even brains produced via nucleation in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=De_Sitter_vacuum&amp;amp;action=edit&amp;amp;redlink=1&quot; class=&quot;new&quot; title=&quot;De Sitter vacuum (page does not exist)&quot;&gt;de Sitter vacuum&lt;/a&gt;, don't count as observers. Quantum fluctuations are easier to exclude than nucleated brains, as quantum fluctuations can more easily be targeted by straightforward criteria (such as their lack of interaction with the environment at infinity).&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-carroll2017_4-4&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boltzmann_brain#cite_note-carroll2017-4&quot;&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-davenport_8-2&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boltzmann_brain#cite_note-davenport-8&quot;&gt;[8]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some cosmologists believe that a better understanding of the degrees of freedom in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quantum_vacuum&quot; class=&quot;mw-redirect&quot; title=&quot;Quantum vacuum&quot;&gt;quantum vacuum&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Holographic_principle&quot; title=&quot;Holographic principle&quot;&gt;holographic string theory&lt;/a&gt; can solve the Boltzmann brain problem.&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-10&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boltzmann_brain#cite_note-10&quot;&gt;[10]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;In_single-Universe_scenarios&quot;&gt;In single-Universe scenarios&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a single de Sitter Universe with a cosmological constant, and starting from any finite spatial slice, the number of &quot;normal&quot; observers is finite and bounded by the heat death of the Universe. If the Universe lasts forever, the number of nucleated Boltzmann brains is, in most models, infinite; cosmologists such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alan_Guth&quot; title=&quot;Alan Guth&quot;&gt;Alan Guth&lt;/a&gt; worry that this would make it seem &quot;infinitely unlikely for us to be normal brains&quot;.&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-nytimes_7-2&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boltzmann_brain#cite_note-nytimes-7&quot;&gt;[7]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; One caveat is that if the Universe is a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/False_vacuum&quot; title=&quot;False vacuum&quot;&gt;false vacuum&lt;/a&gt; that locally decays into a Minkowski or a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Big_Crunch&quot; title=&quot;Big Crunch&quot;&gt;Big Crunch&lt;/a&gt;-bound &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anti-de_Sitter_space&quot; title=&quot;Anti-de Sitter space&quot;&gt;anti-de Sitter space&lt;/a&gt; in less than 20 billion years, then infinite Boltzmann nucleation is avoided. (If the average local false vacuum decay rate is over 20 billion years, Boltzmann brain nucleation is still infinite, as the Universe increases in size faster than local vacuum collapses destroy the portions of the Universe within the collapses' future &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Light_cones&quot; class=&quot;mw-redirect&quot; title=&quot;Light cones&quot;&gt;light cones&lt;/a&gt;). Proposed hypothetical mechanisms to destroy the universe within that timeframe range from superheavy &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gravitinos&quot; class=&quot;mw-redirect&quot; title=&quot;Gravitinos&quot;&gt;gravitinos&lt;/a&gt; to a heavier-than-observed top quark triggering &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Higgs_boson#Nature_of_the_universe,_and_its_possible_fates&quot; title=&quot;Higgs boson&quot;&gt;death by Higgs&lt;/a&gt;&quot;.&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-11&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boltzmann_brain#cite_note-11&quot;&gt;[11]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-12&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boltzmann_brain#cite_note-12&quot;&gt;[12]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-linde_13-0&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boltzmann_brain#cite_note-linde-13&quot;&gt;[13]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If no cosmological constant exists, and if the presently observed &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vacuum_energy&quot; title=&quot;Vacuum energy&quot;&gt;vacuum energy&lt;/a&gt; is from &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quintessence_(physics)&quot; title=&quot;Quintessence (physics)&quot;&gt;quintessence&lt;/a&gt; that will eventually completely dissipate, then infinite Boltzmann nucleation is also avoided.&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-14&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boltzmann_brain#cite_note-14&quot;&gt;[14]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;In_eternal_inflation&quot;&gt;In eternal inflation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div role=&quot;note&quot; class=&quot;hatnote navigation-not-searchable&quot;&gt;Further information: &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Measure_problem_(cosmology)&quot; title=&quot;Measure problem (cosmology)&quot;&gt;Measure problem (cosmology)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One class of solutions to the Boltzmann brain problem makes use of differing approaches to the measure problem in cosmology: in &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Infinity&quot; title=&quot;Infinity&quot;&gt;infinite&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Multiverse&quot; title=&quot;Multiverse&quot;&gt;multiverse&lt;/a&gt; theories, the ratio of normal observers to Boltzmann brains depends on how infinite limits are taken. Measures might be chosen to avoid appreciable fractions of Boltzmann brains.&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-DeSimoneEtAl2010_15-0&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boltzmann_brain#cite_note-DeSimoneEtAl2010-15&quot;&gt;[15]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-LindeVanchurinWinitzki2009_16-0&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boltzmann_brain#cite_note-LindeVanchurinWinitzki2009-16&quot;&gt;[16]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-LindeNoorbala2010_17-0&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boltzmann_brain#cite_note-LindeNoorbala2010-17&quot;&gt;[17]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Unlike the single-universe case, one challenge in finding a global solution in eternal inflation is that all possible string landscapes must be summed over; in some measures, having even a small fraction of universes infested with Boltzmann brains causes the measure of the multiverse as a whole to be dominated by Boltzmann brains.&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-linde_13-1&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boltzmann_brain#cite_note-linde-13&quot;&gt;[13]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-18&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boltzmann_brain#cite_note-18&quot;&gt;[18]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The measurement problem in cosmology also grapples with the ratio of normal observers to abnormally early observers. In measures such as the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Proper_time&quot; title=&quot;Proper time&quot;&gt;proper time&lt;/a&gt; measure that suffer from an extreme &quot;youngness&quot; problem, the typical observer is a &quot;Boltzmann baby&quot; formed by rare fluctuation in an extremely hot, early universe.&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-bousso_9-1&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boltzmann_brain#cite_note-bousso-9&quot;&gt;[9]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;See_also&quot;&gt;See also&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div&gt;

 
&lt;table class=&quot;multicol&quot; role=&quot;presentation&quot; style=&quot;border-collapse: collapse; padding: 0; border: 0; background:transparent; width:100%;&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left; vertical-align: top;&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anthropic_principle&quot; title=&quot;Anthropic principle&quot;&gt;Anthropic principle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brain_in_a_vat&quot; title=&quot;Brain in a vat&quot;&gt;Brain in a vat&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bekenstein_bound&quot; title=&quot;Bekenstein bound&quot;&gt;Bekenstein bound&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/China_brain&quot; title=&quot;China brain&quot;&gt;China brain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dream_argument&quot; title=&quot;Dream argument&quot;&gt;Dream argument&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Evolution_of_biological_complexity&quot; title=&quot;Evolution of biological complexity&quot;&gt;Evolution of biological complexity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left; vertical-align: top;&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Observer_(physics)&quot; title=&quot;Observer (physics)&quot;&gt;Observer (physics)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Matrioshka_brain&quot; title=&quot;Matrioshka brain&quot;&gt;Matrioshka brain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Simulated_reality&quot; title=&quot;Simulated reality&quot;&gt;Simulated reality&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Simulation_hypothesis&quot; title=&quot;Simulation hypothesis&quot;&gt;Simulation hypothesis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Swampman&quot; title=&quot;Swampman&quot;&gt;Swampman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Poincaré_recurrence_theorem&quot; title=&quot;Poincaré recurrence theorem&quot;&gt;Poincaré recurrence theorem&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left; vertical-align: top;&quot;&gt;

&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;Notes&quot;&gt;Notes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;reflist columns references-column-width&quot; style=&quot;-moz-column-width: 30em; -webkit-column-width: 30em; column-width: 30em; list-style-type: decimal;&quot;&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;references&quot;&gt;&lt;li id=&quot;cite_note-1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-cite-backlink&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boltzmann_brain#cite_ref-1&quot;&gt;^&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;reference-text&quot;&gt;&lt;cite class=&quot;citation web&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sean_M._Carroll&quot; title=&quot;Sean M. Carroll&quot;&gt;Carroll, Sean&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;http://www.preposterousuniverse.com/blog/2008/12/29/richard-feynman-on-boltzmann-brains/&quot;&gt;&quot;Richard Feynman on Boltzmann Brains&quot;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;reference-accessdate&quot;&gt;. Retrieved &lt;span class=&quot;nowrap&quot;&gt;24 June&lt;/span&gt; 2019&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;span title=&quot;ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Abook&amp;amp;rft.genre=unknown&amp;amp;rft.btitle=Richard+Feynman+on+Boltzmann+Brains&amp;amp;rft.aulast=Carroll&amp;amp;rft.aufirst=Sean&amp;amp;rft_id=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.preposterousuniverse.com%2Fblog%2F2008%2F12%2F29%2Frichard-feynman-on-boltzmann-brains%2F&amp;amp;rfr_id=info%3Asid%2Fen.wikipedia.org%3ABoltzmann+brain&quot; class=&quot;Z3988&quot;/&gt;&lt;style data-mw-deduplicate=&quot;TemplateStyles:r935243608&quot;&gt;&lt;![CDATA[.mw-parser-output cite.citation{font-style:inherit}.mw-parser-output .citation q{quotes:&quot;\&quot;&quot;&quot;\&quot;&quot;&quot;'&quot;&quot;'&quot;}.mw-parser-output .id-lock-free a,.mw-parser-output .citation .cs1-lock-free a{background:url(&quot;//upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/6/65/Lock-green.svg/9px-Lock-green.svg.png&quot;)no-repeat;background-position:right .1em center}.mw-parser-output .id-lock-limited a,.mw-parser-output .id-lock-registration a,.mw-parser-output .citation .cs1-lock-limited a,.mw-parser-output .citation .cs1-lock-registration a{background:url(&quot;//upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/d/d6/Lock-gray-alt-2.svg/9px-Lock-gray-alt-2.svg.png&quot;)no-repeat;background-position:right .1em center}.mw-parser-output .id-lock-subscription a,.mw-parser-output .citation .cs1-lock-subscription a{background:url(&quot;//upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/a/aa/Lock-red-alt-2.svg/9px-Lock-red-alt-2.svg.png&quot;)no-repeat;background-position:right .1em center}.mw-parser-output .cs1-subscription,.mw-parser-output .cs1-registration{color:#555}.mw-parser-output .cs1-subscription span,.mw-parser-output .cs1-registration span{border-bottom:1px dotted;cursor:help}.mw-parser-output .cs1-ws-icon a{background:url(&quot;//upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/4/4c/Wikisource-logo.svg/12px-Wikisource-logo.svg.png&quot;)no-repeat;background-position:right .1em center}.mw-parser-output code.cs1-code{color:inherit;background:inherit;border:inherit;padding:inherit}.mw-parser-output .cs1-hidden-error{display:none;font-size:100%}.mw-parser-output .cs1-visible-error{font-size:100%}.mw-parser-output .cs1-maint{display:none;color:#33aa33;margin-left:0.3em}.mw-parser-output .cs1-subscription,.mw-parser-output .cs1-registration,.mw-parser-output .cs1-format{font-size:95%}.mw-parser-output .cs1-kern-left,.mw-parser-output .cs1-kern-wl-left{padding-left:0.2em}.mw-parser-output .cs1-kern-right,.mw-parser-output .cs1-kern-wl-right{padding-right:0.2em}]]&gt;&lt;/style&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;cite_note-2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-cite-backlink&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boltzmann_brain#cite_ref-2&quot;&gt;^&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;reference-text&quot;&gt;&lt;cite class=&quot;citation podcast&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sean_M._Carroll&quot; title=&quot;Sean M. Carroll&quot;&gt;Sean Carroll&lt;/a&gt; (17 June 2019). &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://www.preposterousuniverse.com/podcast/2019/06/17/episode-51-anthony-aguirre-on-cosmology-zen-entropy-and-information/&quot;&gt;&quot;Sean Carroll's Mindscape&quot;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;i&gt;preposterousuniverse.com&lt;/i&gt; (Podcast). Sean Carroll.  Event occurs at 1:01.47&lt;span class=&quot;reference-accessdate&quot;&gt;. Retrieved &lt;span class=&quot;nowrap&quot;&gt;2 March&lt;/span&gt; 2019&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;span title=&quot;ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Abook&amp;amp;rft.genre=unknown&amp;amp;rft.btitle=Sean+Carroll%27s+Mindscape&amp;amp;rft.pub=Sean+Carroll&amp;amp;rft.date=2019-06-17&amp;amp;rft.au=Sean+Carroll&amp;amp;rft_id=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.preposterousuniverse.com%2Fpodcast%2F2019%2F06%2F17%2Fepisode-51-anthony-aguirre-on-cosmology-zen-entropy-and-information%2F&amp;amp;rfr_id=info%3Asid%2Fen.wikipedia.org%3ABoltzmann+brain&quot; class=&quot;Z3988&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;mw-deduplicated-inline-style&quot; href=&quot;mw-data:TemplateStyles:r935243608&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;cite_note-3&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-cite-backlink&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boltzmann_brain#cite_ref-3&quot;&gt;^&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;reference-text&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stephen_Brush&quot; class=&quot;extiw&quot; title=&quot;de:Stephen Brush&quot;&gt;Brush, S. G.&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;i&gt;Nebulous Earth: A History of Modern Planetary Physics&lt;/i&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cambridge&quot; title=&quot;Cambridge&quot;&gt;Cambridge&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cambridge_University_Press&quot; title=&quot;Cambridge University Press&quot;&gt;Cambridge University Press&lt;/a&gt;, 1996), &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://books.google.cz/books?id=vTBZyesS08kC&amp;amp;pg=PA129#v=onepage&amp;amp;q&amp;amp;f=false&quot;&gt;p. 129&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;cite_note-carroll2017-4&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-cite-backlink&quot;&gt;^ &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boltzmann_brain#cite_ref-carroll2017_4-0&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;a&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boltzmann_brain#cite_ref-carroll2017_4-1&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;b&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boltzmann_brain#cite_ref-carroll2017_4-2&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;c&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boltzmann_brain#cite_ref-carroll2017_4-3&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;d&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boltzmann_brain#cite_ref-carroll2017_4-4&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;e&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;reference-text&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sean_M._Carroll&quot; title=&quot;Sean M. Carroll&quot;&gt;Carroll, S. M.&lt;/a&gt;,  &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1702.00850&quot;&gt;&quot;Why Boltzmann brains are bad&quot;&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ithaca,_New_York&quot; title=&quot;Ithaca, New York&quot;&gt;Ithaca, New York&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ArXiv&quot; title=&quot;ArXiv&quot;&gt;arXiv&lt;/a&gt;, 2017).&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;cite_note-5&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-cite-backlink&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boltzmann_brain#cite_ref-5&quot;&gt;^&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;reference-text&quot;&gt;&lt;cite class=&quot;citation book&quot;&gt;Bostrom, Nick (2002). &quot;Introduction&quot;. &lt;i&gt;Anthropic Bias: Observation Selection Effects in Science and Philosophy&lt;/i&gt;. Psychology Press. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/International_Standard_Book_Number&quot; title=&quot;International Standard Book Number&quot;&gt;ISBN&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Special:BookSources/9780415938587&quot; title=&quot;Special:BookSources/9780415938587&quot;&gt;&lt;bdi&gt;9780415938587&lt;/bdi&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;span title=&quot;ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Abook&amp;amp;rft.genre=bookitem&amp;amp;rft.atitle=Introduction&amp;amp;rft.btitle=Anthropic+Bias%3A+Observation+Selection+Effects+in+Science+and+Philosophy&amp;amp;rft.pub=Psychology+Press&amp;amp;rft.date=2002&amp;amp;rft.isbn=9780415938587&amp;amp;rft.aulast=Bostrom&amp;amp;rft.aufirst=Nick&amp;amp;rfr_id=info%3Asid%2Fen.wikipedia.org%3ABoltzmann+brain&quot; class=&quot;Z3988&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;mw-deduplicated-inline-style&quot; href=&quot;mw-data:TemplateStyles:r935243608&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;cite_note-Albrecht_&amp;amp;_Sorbo-6&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-cite-backlink&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boltzmann_brain#cite_ref-Albrecht_&amp;amp;_Sorbo_6-0&quot;&gt;^&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;reference-text&quot;&gt;&lt;cite class=&quot;citation journal&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Andreas_Albrecht_(cosmologist)&quot; title=&quot;Andreas Albrecht (cosmologist)&quot;&gt;Albrecht, Andreas&lt;/a&gt;; Sorbo, Lorenzo (September 2004). &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/bib_query?arXiv:hep-th/0405270&quot;&gt;&quot;Can the universe afford inflation?&quot;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Physical_Review&quot; title=&quot;Physical Review&quot;&gt;Physical Review D&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;. &lt;b&gt;70&lt;/b&gt; (6): 063528. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ArXiv&quot; title=&quot;ArXiv&quot;&gt;arXiv&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;span class=&quot;cs1-lock-free&quot; title=&quot;Freely accessible&quot;&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/hep-th/0405270&quot;&gt;hep-th/0405270&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bibcode&quot; title=&quot;Bibcode&quot;&gt;Bibcode&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://ui.adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2004PhRvD..70f3528A&quot;&gt;2004PhRvD..70f3528A&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Digital_object_identifier&quot; title=&quot;Digital object identifier&quot;&gt;doi&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1103%2FPhysRevD.70.063528&quot;&gt;10.1103/PhysRevD.70.063528&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;reference-accessdate&quot;&gt;. Retrieved &lt;span class=&quot;nowrap&quot;&gt;16 December&lt;/span&gt; 2014&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;span title=&quot;ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Ajournal&amp;amp;rft.genre=article&amp;amp;rft.jtitle=Physical+Review+D&amp;amp;rft.atitle=Can+the+universe+afford+inflation%3F&amp;amp;rft.volume=70&amp;amp;rft.issue=6&amp;amp;rft.pages=063528&amp;amp;rft.date=2004-09&amp;amp;rft_id=info%3Aarxiv%2Fhep-th%2F0405270&amp;amp;rft_id=info%3Adoi%2F10.1103%2FPhysRevD.70.063528&amp;amp;rft_id=info%3Abibcode%2F2004PhRvD..70f3528A&amp;amp;rft.aulast=Albrecht&amp;amp;rft.aufirst=Andreas&amp;amp;rft.au=Sorbo%2C+Lorenzo&amp;amp;rft_id=http%3A%2F%2Fadsabs.harvard.edu%2Fcgi-bin%2Fbib_query%3FarXiv%3Ahep-th%2F0405270&amp;amp;rfr_id=info%3Asid%2Fen.wikipedia.org%3ABoltzmann+brain&quot; class=&quot;Z3988&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;mw-deduplicated-inline-style&quot; href=&quot;mw-data:TemplateStyles:r935243608&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;cite_note-nytimes-7&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-cite-backlink&quot;&gt;^ &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boltzmann_brain#cite_ref-nytimes_7-0&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;a&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boltzmann_brain#cite_ref-nytimes_7-1&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;b&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boltzmann_brain#cite_ref-nytimes_7-2&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;c&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;reference-text&quot;&gt;&lt;cite class=&quot;citation news&quot;&gt;Overbye, Dennis (2008). &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2008/01/15/science/15brain.html?pagewanted=all&quot;&gt;&quot;Big Brain Theory: Have Cosmologists Lost Theirs?&quot;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_New_York_Times&quot; title=&quot;The New York Times&quot;&gt;The New York Times&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;reference-accessdate&quot;&gt;. Retrieved &lt;span class=&quot;nowrap&quot;&gt;26 February&lt;/span&gt; 2018&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;span title=&quot;ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Ajournal&amp;amp;rft.genre=article&amp;amp;rft.jtitle=The+New+York+Times&amp;amp;rft.atitle=Big+Brain+Theory%3A+Have+Cosmologists+Lost+Theirs%3F&amp;amp;rft.date=2008&amp;amp;rft.aulast=Overbye&amp;amp;rft.aufirst=Dennis&amp;amp;rft_id=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.nytimes.com%2F2008%2F01%2F15%2Fscience%2F15brain.html%3Fpagewanted%3Dall&amp;amp;rfr_id=info%3Asid%2Fen.wikipedia.org%3ABoltzmann+brain&quot; class=&quot;Z3988&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;mw-deduplicated-inline-style&quot; href=&quot;mw-data:TemplateStyles:r935243608&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;cite_note-davenport-8&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-cite-backlink&quot;&gt;^ &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boltzmann_brain#cite_ref-davenport_8-0&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;a&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boltzmann_brain#cite_ref-davenport_8-1&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;b&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boltzmann_brain#cite_ref-davenport_8-2&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;c&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;reference-text&quot;&gt;Davenport, M., &amp;amp; Olum, K. D. (2010). Are there Boltzmann brains in the vacuum. arXiv preprint arXiv:1008.0808.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;cite_note-bousso-9&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-cite-backlink&quot;&gt;^ &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boltzmann_brain#cite_ref-bousso_9-0&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;a&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boltzmann_brain#cite_ref-bousso_9-1&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;b&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;reference-text&quot;&gt;Bousso, R., Freivogel, B., &amp;amp; Yang, I. S. (2008). Boltzmann babies in the proper time measure. &lt;i&gt;Physical Review D&lt;/i&gt;, 77(10), 103514.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;cite_note-10&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-cite-backlink&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boltzmann_brain#cite_ref-10&quot;&gt;^&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;reference-text&quot;&gt;Garriga, J., &amp;amp; Vilenkin, A. (2009). Holographic multiverse. &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Journal_of_Cosmology_and_Astroparticle_Physics&quot; title=&quot;Journal of Cosmology and Astroparticle Physics&quot;&gt;Journal of Cosmology and Astroparticle Physics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;, 2009(01), 021.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;cite_note-11&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-cite-backlink&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boltzmann_brain#cite_ref-11&quot;&gt;^&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;reference-text&quot;&gt;&lt;cite class=&quot;citation news&quot;&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg21929333-200-death-by-higgs-rids-cosmos-of-space-brain-threat/&quot;&gt;&quot;Death by Higgs rids cosmos of space brain threat&quot;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/New_Scientist&quot; title=&quot;New Scientist&quot;&gt;New Scientist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;. 15 February 2017&lt;span class=&quot;reference-accessdate&quot;&gt;. Retrieved &lt;span class=&quot;nowrap&quot;&gt;26 February&lt;/span&gt; 2018&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;span title=&quot;ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Ajournal&amp;amp;rft.genre=article&amp;amp;rft.jtitle=New+Scientist&amp;amp;rft.atitle=Death+by+Higgs+rids+cosmos+of+space+brain+threat&amp;amp;rft.date=2017-02-15&amp;amp;rft_id=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.newscientist.com%2Farticle%2Fmg21929333-200-death-by-higgs-rids-cosmos-of-space-brain-threat%2F&amp;amp;rfr_id=info%3Asid%2Fen.wikipedia.org%3ABoltzmann+brain&quot; class=&quot;Z3988&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;mw-deduplicated-inline-style&quot; href=&quot;mw-data:TemplateStyles:r935243608&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;cite_note-12&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-cite-backlink&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boltzmann_brain#cite_ref-12&quot;&gt;^&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;reference-text&quot;&gt;Boddy, K. K., &amp;amp; Carroll, S. M. (2013). Can the Higgs Boson Save Us From the Menace of the Boltzmann Brains?. arXiv preprint arXiv:1308.4686.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;cite_note-linde-13&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-cite-backlink&quot;&gt;^ &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boltzmann_brain#cite_ref-linde_13-0&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;a&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boltzmann_brain#cite_ref-linde_13-1&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;b&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;reference-text&quot;&gt;Linde, A. (2007). Sinks in the landscape, Boltzmann brains and the cosmological constant problem. &lt;i&gt;Journal of Cosmology and Astroparticle Physics&lt;/i&gt;, 2007(01), 022.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;cite_note-14&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-cite-backlink&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boltzmann_brain#cite_ref-14&quot;&gt;^&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;reference-text&quot;&gt;Carlip, S. (2007). Transient observers and variable constants or repelling the invasion of the Boltzmann’s brains. &lt;i&gt;Journal of Cosmology and Astroparticle Physics&lt;/i&gt;, 2007(06), 001.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;cite_note-DeSimoneEtAl2010-15&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-cite-backlink&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boltzmann_brain#cite_ref-DeSimoneEtAl2010_15-0&quot;&gt;^&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;reference-text&quot;&gt;&lt;cite class=&quot;citation journal&quot;&gt;Andrea De Simone; Alan H. Guth; Andrei Linde; Mahdiyar Noorbala; Michael P. Salem; Alexander Vilenkin (14 September 2010). &quot;Boltzmann brains and the scale-factor cutoff measure of the multiverse&quot;. &lt;i&gt;Physical Review D&lt;/i&gt;. &lt;b&gt;82&lt;/b&gt; (6): 063520. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ArXiv&quot; title=&quot;ArXiv&quot;&gt;arXiv&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;span class=&quot;cs1-lock-free&quot; title=&quot;Freely accessible&quot;&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/0808.3778&quot;&gt;0808.3778&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bibcode&quot; title=&quot;Bibcode&quot;&gt;Bibcode&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://ui.adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2010PhRvD..82f3520D&quot;&gt;2010PhRvD..82f3520D&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Digital_object_identifier&quot; title=&quot;Digital object identifier&quot;&gt;doi&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1103%2FPhysRevD.82.063520&quot;&gt;10.1103/PhysRevD.82.063520&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;span title=&quot;ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Ajournal&amp;amp;rft.genre=article&amp;amp;rft.jtitle=Physical+Review+D&amp;amp;rft.atitle=Boltzmann+brains+and+the+scale-factor+cutoff+measure+of+the+multiverse&amp;amp;rft.volume=82&amp;amp;rft.issue=6&amp;amp;rft.pages=063520&amp;amp;rft.date=2010-09-14&amp;amp;rft_id=info%3Aarxiv%2F0808.3778&amp;amp;rft_id=info%3Adoi%2F10.1103%2FPhysRevD.82.063520&amp;amp;rft_id=info%3Abibcode%2F2010PhRvD..82f3520D&amp;amp;rft.au=Andrea+De+Simone&amp;amp;rft.au=Alan+H.+Guth&amp;amp;rft.au=Andrei+Linde&amp;amp;rft.au=Mahdiyar+Noorbala&amp;amp;rft.au=Michael+P.+Salem&amp;amp;rft.au=Alexander+Vilenkin&amp;amp;rfr_id=info%3Asid%2Fen.wikipedia.org%3ABoltzmann+brain&quot; class=&quot;Z3988&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;mw-deduplicated-inline-style&quot; href=&quot;mw-data:TemplateStyles:r935243608&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;cite_note-LindeVanchurinWinitzki2009-16&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-cite-backlink&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boltzmann_brain#cite_ref-LindeVanchurinWinitzki2009_16-0&quot;&gt;^&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;reference-text&quot;&gt;&lt;cite class=&quot;citation journal&quot;&gt;Andrei Linde; Vitaly Vanchurin; Sergei Winitzki (15 January 2009). &quot;Stationary Measure in the Multiverse&quot;. &lt;i&gt;Journal of Cosmology and Astroparticle Physics&lt;/i&gt;. &lt;b&gt;2009&lt;/b&gt; (1): 031. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ArXiv&quot; title=&quot;ArXiv&quot;&gt;arXiv&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;span class=&quot;cs1-lock-free&quot; title=&quot;Freely accessible&quot;&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/0812.0005&quot;&gt;0812.0005&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bibcode&quot; title=&quot;Bibcode&quot;&gt;Bibcode&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://ui.adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2009JCAP...01..031L&quot;&gt;2009JCAP...01..031L&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Digital_object_identifier&quot; title=&quot;Digital object identifier&quot;&gt;doi&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1088%2F1475-7516%2F2009%2F01%2F031&quot;&gt;10.1088/1475-7516/2009/01/031&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;span title=&quot;ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Ajournal&amp;amp;rft.genre=article&amp;amp;rft.jtitle=Journal+of+Cosmology+and+Astroparticle+Physics&amp;amp;rft.atitle=Stationary+Measure+in+the+Multiverse&amp;amp;rft.volume=2009&amp;amp;rft.issue=1&amp;amp;rft.pages=031&amp;amp;rft.date=2009-01-15&amp;amp;rft_id=info%3Aarxiv%2F0812.0005&amp;amp;rft_id=info%3Adoi%2F10.1088%2F1475-7516%2F2009%2F01%2F031&amp;amp;rft_id=info%3Abibcode%2F2009JCAP...01..031L&amp;amp;rft.au=Andrei+Linde&amp;amp;rft.au=Vitaly+Vanchurin&amp;amp;rft.au=Sergei+Winitzki&amp;amp;rfr_id=info%3Asid%2Fen.wikipedia.org%3ABoltzmann+brain&quot; class=&quot;Z3988&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;mw-deduplicated-inline-style&quot; href=&quot;mw-data:TemplateStyles:r935243608&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;cite_note-LindeNoorbala2010-17&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-cite-backlink&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boltzmann_brain#cite_ref-LindeNoorbala2010_17-0&quot;&gt;^&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;reference-text&quot;&gt;&lt;cite class=&quot;citation journal&quot;&gt;Andrei Linde; Mahdiyar Noorbala (9 September 2010). &quot;Measure problem for eternal and non-eternal inflation&quot;. &lt;i&gt;Journal of Cosmology and Astroparticle Physics&lt;/i&gt;. &lt;b&gt;2010&lt;/b&gt; (9): 008. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ArXiv&quot; title=&quot;ArXiv&quot;&gt;arXiv&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;span class=&quot;cs1-lock-free&quot; title=&quot;Freely accessible&quot;&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1006.2170&quot;&gt;1006.2170&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bibcode&quot; title=&quot;Bibcode&quot;&gt;Bibcode&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://ui.adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2010JCAP...09..008L&quot;&gt;2010JCAP...09..008L&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Digital_object_identifier&quot; title=&quot;Digital object identifier&quot;&gt;doi&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1088%2F1475-7516%2F2010%2F09%2F008&quot;&gt;10.1088/1475-7516/2010/09/008&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;span title=&quot;ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Ajournal&amp;amp;rft.genre=article&amp;amp;rft.jtitle=Journal+of+Cosmology+and+Astroparticle+Physics&amp;amp;rft.atitle=Measure+problem+for+eternal+and+non-eternal+inflation&amp;amp;rft.volume=2010&amp;amp;rft.issue=9&amp;amp;rft.pages=008&amp;amp;rft.date=2010-09-09&amp;amp;rft_id=info%3Aarxiv%2F1006.2170&amp;amp;rft_id=info%3Adoi%2F10.1088%2F1475-7516%2F2010%2F09%2F008&amp;amp;rft_id=info%3Abibcode%2F2010JCAP...09..008L&amp;amp;rft.au=Andrei+Linde&amp;amp;rft.au=Mahdiyar+Noorbala&amp;amp;rfr_id=info%3Asid%2Fen.wikipedia.org%3ABoltzmann+brain&quot; class=&quot;Z3988&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;mw-deduplicated-inline-style&quot; href=&quot;mw-data:TemplateStyles:r935243608&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;cite_note-18&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-cite-backlink&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boltzmann_brain#cite_ref-18&quot;&gt;^&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;reference-text&quot;&gt;&lt;cite class=&quot;citation journal&quot;&gt;Bousso, R.; Freivogel, B. (2007). &quot;A paradox in the global description of the multiverse&quot;. &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Journal_of_High_Energy_Physics&quot; title=&quot;Journal of High Energy Physics&quot;&gt;Journal of High Energy Physics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;. &lt;b&gt;2007&lt;/b&gt; (06): 018. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Digital_object_identifier&quot; title=&quot;Digital object identifier&quot;&gt;doi&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1088%2F1126-6708%2F2007%2F06%2F018&quot;&gt;10.1088/1126-6708/2007/06/018&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;span title=&quot;ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Ajournal&amp;amp;rft.genre=article&amp;amp;rft.jtitle=Journal+of+High+Energy+Physics&amp;amp;rft.atitle=A+paradox+in+the+global+description+of+the+multiverse&amp;amp;rft.volume=2007&amp;amp;rft.issue=06&amp;amp;rft.pages=018&amp;amp;rft.date=2007&amp;amp;rft_id=info%3Adoi%2F10.1088%2F1126-6708%2F2007%2F06%2F018&amp;amp;rft.aulast=Bousso&amp;amp;rft.aufirst=R.&amp;amp;rft.au=Freivogel%2C+B.&amp;amp;rfr_id=info%3Asid%2Fen.wikipedia.org%3ABoltzmann+brain&quot; class=&quot;Z3988&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;mw-deduplicated-inline-style&quot; href=&quot;mw-data:TemplateStyles:r935243608&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;Further_reading&quot;&gt;Further reading&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;style data-mw-deduplicate=&quot;TemplateStyles:r886047268&quot;&gt;&lt;![CDATA[.mw-parser-output .refbegin{font-size:90%;margin-bottom:0.5em}.mw-parser-output .refbegin-hanging-indents&gt;ul{list-style-type:none;margin-left:0}.mw-parser-output .refbegin-hanging-indents&gt;ul&gt;li,.mw-parser-output .refbegin-hanging-indents&gt;dl&gt;dd{margin-left:0;padding-left:3.2em;text-indent:-3.2em;list-style:none}.mw-parser-output .refbegin-100{font-size:100%}]]&gt;&lt;/style&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;refbegin reflist&quot; style=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&quot;Disturbing Implications of a Cosmological Constant&quot;, Lisa Dyson, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Matthew_Kleban&quot; title=&quot;Matthew Kleban&quot;&gt;Matthew Kleban&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Leonard_Susskind&quot; title=&quot;Leonard Susskind&quot;&gt;Leonard Susskind&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Journal_of_High_Energy_Physics&quot; title=&quot;Journal of High Energy Physics&quot;&gt;Journal of High Energy Physics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt; 0210 (2002) 011 (&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/hep-th/0208013&quot;&gt;at arXiv&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&quot;Is Our Universe Likely to Decay within 20 Billion Years?&quot;, Don N. Page, (&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/hep-th/0610079&quot;&gt;at arXiv&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&quot;Sinks in the Landscape, Boltzmann Brains, and the Cosmological Constant Problem&quot;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Andrei_Linde&quot; title=&quot;Andrei Linde&quot;&gt;Andrei Linde&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Journal_of_Cosmology_and_Astroparticle_Physics&quot; title=&quot;Journal of Cosmology and Astroparticle Physics&quot;&gt;Journal of Cosmology and Astroparticle Physics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;, 0701 (2007) 022 (&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/hep-th/0611043&quot;&gt;at arXiv&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&quot;Spooks in Space&quot;, Mason Inman, &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/New_Scientist&quot; title=&quot;New Scientist&quot;&gt;New Scientist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;, Volume 195, Issue 2617, 18 August 2007, &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://www.newscientist.com/channel/fundamentals/mg19526171.100-spooks-in-space.html&quot;&gt;pp. 26-29&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&quot;Big Brain Theory: Have Cosmologists Lost Theirs?&quot;, Dennis Overbye, &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2008/01/15/science/15brain.html?pagewanted=all&quot;&gt;&lt;i/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_New_York_Times&quot; title=&quot;The New York Times&quot;&gt;The New York Times&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;, 15 January 2008&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;!-- 
NewPP limit report
Parsed by mw1266
Cached time: 20200118153722
Cache expiry: 2592000
Dynamic content: false
Complications: [vary&amp;#8208;revision&amp;#8208;sha1]
CPU time usage: 0.448 seconds
Real time usage: 1.775 seconds
Preprocessor visited node count: 989/1000000
Preprocessor generated node count: 0/1500000
Post&amp;#8208;expand include size: 23254/2097152 bytes
Template argument size: 1118/2097152 bytes
Highest expansion depth: 12/40
Expensive parser function count: 4/500
Unstrip recursion depth: 1/20
Unstrip post&amp;#8208;expand size: 39268/5000000 bytes
Number of Wikibase entities loaded: 3/400
Lua time usage: 0.227/10.000 seconds
Lua memory usage: 5.34 MB/50 MB
--&gt;
&lt;!--
Transclusion expansion time report (%,ms,calls,template)
100.00% 1665.857      1 -total
 30.91%  514.946      1 Template:Citation_needed
 27.49%  457.928      1 Template:Short_description
 26.72%  445.172      1 Template:Reflist
 26.18%  436.172      1 Template:Fix
 17.60%  293.231      2 Template:Category_handler
 12.05%  200.813      2 Template:Pagetype
 11.91%  198.469      5 Template:Cite_journal
  6.58%  109.595      1 Template:Cite_web
  5.79%   96.373      1 Template:Delink
--&gt;

&lt;!-- Saved in parser cache with key enwiki:pcache:idhash:9638200-0!canonical!math=5 and timestamp 20200118153720 and revision id 930752997
 --&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Special:CentralAutoLogin/start?type=1x1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;border: none; position: absolute;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
		
		&lt;div class=&quot;printfooter&quot;&gt;Retrieved from &quot;&lt;a dir=&quot;ltr&quot; href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Boltzmann_brain&amp;amp;oldid=930752997&quot;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Boltzmann_brain&amp;amp;oldid=930752997&lt;/a&gt;&quot;&lt;/div&gt;
		
		
		&lt;div class=&quot;visualClear&quot;/&gt;
		
	</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 21:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>6581</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/a/ad/Boltzmann2.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boltzmann_brain</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>PopSockets CEO calls out Amazon&amp;#039;s tactics before House committee</title>
<link>https://mashable.com/article/amazon-bullying-tactics-popsockets-hearing/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://mashable.com/article/amazon-bullying-tactics-popsockets-hearing/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mashable.com/category/amazon/&quot;&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; has a &quot;bullying&quot; problem.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So insisted PopSockets CEO and inventor David Barnett today while describing his company's relationship with the e-commerce and logistics giant. Barnett was addressing members of the House Subcommittee on Antitrust, Commercial, and Administrative Law and, over the course of &lt;a href=&quot;https://judiciary.house.gov/calendar/eventsingle.aspx?EventID=2386&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;the hearing&lt;/a&gt;, laid out how the Jeff Bezos-helmed corporate behemoth had pressured his smartphone accessory company in a manner best described as &lt;em&gt;incredibly shady&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Barnett was joined by executives from &lt;a href=&quot;https://mashable.com/category/sonos/&quot;&gt;Sonos&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://mashable.com/category/basecamp/&quot;&gt;Basecamp&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://mashable.com/category/tile/&quot;&gt;Tile&lt;/a&gt;, who all took turns airing a list of grievances against major tech players such as Amazon, Apple, Facebook and Google. They all recounted, in manners specific to their respective companies, how the major tech players have used their market dominance to squeeze smaller competitors in allegedly anticompetitive ways. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CEO of PopSockets, however, appeared to have a personal beef with Jeff Bezos (which he pronounced &quot;Bey-zoo&quot;). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Multiple times we discovered that Amazon itself had sourced counterfeit product and was selling it alongside our own product,&quot; he noted. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Barnett, under oath, told the gathered members of the House that Amazon initially played nice only to drop the hammer when it believed no one was watching. After agreeing to a written contract stipulating a price at which PopSockets would be sold on Amazon, the e-commerce giant would then allegedly unilaterally lower the price and demand that PopSockets make up the difference. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Pop it.&quot; class=&quot;&quot; data-fragment=&quot;m!0b74&quot; data-image=&quot;https://mondrian.mashable.com/uploads%252Fcard%252Fimage%252F1156890%252F77c0a179-8ffd-4ab0-af5e-aebfcf232303.jpg%252Foriginal.jpg?signature=9BWi_1ilgnoGu7fIyw2Gle7AwLY=&amp;amp;source=https%3A%2F%2Fblueprint-api-production.s3.amazonaws.com&quot; data-micro=&quot;1&quot; naturalwidth=&quot;950&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 300px) 280w,(max-width: 400px) 356w,(max-width: 700px) 638w,950w&quot; src=&quot;https://mondrian.mashable.com/uploads%252Fcard%252Fimage%252F1156890%252F77c0a179-8ffd-4ab0-af5e-aebfcf232303.jpg%252Ffull-fit-in__950x534.jpg?signature=kyZ1CKhmzqUghVABw3593foaAkk=&amp;amp;source=https%3A%2F%2Fblueprint-api-production.s3.amazonaws.com&quot; src_type=&quot;jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://mondrian.mashable.com/uploads%252Fcard%252Fimage%252F1156890%252F77c0a179-8ffd-4ab0-af5e-aebfcf232303.jpg%252Ffull-fit-in__280x157.jpg?signature=ChCtqge0rO9sn8FGy7Wlj5L3lVY=&amp;amp;source=https%3A%2F%2Fblueprint-api-production.s3.amazonaws.com 280w,https://mondrian.mashable.com/uploads%252Fcard%252Fimage%252F1156890%252F77c0a179-8ffd-4ab0-af5e-aebfcf232303.jpg%252Ffull-fit-in__356x205.jpg?signature=yGFg5PvoyoVKMZ0OIAY9F7ysNgk=&amp;amp;source=https%3A%2F%2Fblueprint-api-production.s3.amazonaws.com 356w,https://mondrian.mashable.com/uploads%252Fcard%252Fimage%252F1156890%252F77c0a179-8ffd-4ab0-af5e-aebfcf232303.jpg%252Ffull-fit-in__638x368.jpg?signature=4y6rG_H_rxNXKZ1PL8czAYy1E8g=&amp;amp;source=https%3A%2F%2Fblueprint-api-production.s3.amazonaws.com 638w,https://mondrian.mashable.com/uploads%252Fcard%252Fimage%252F1156890%252F77c0a179-8ffd-4ab0-af5e-aebfcf232303.jpg%252Ffull-fit-in__950x534.jpg?signature=kyZ1CKhmzqUghVABw3593foaAkk=&amp;amp;source=https%3A%2F%2Fblueprint-api-production.s3.amazonaws.com 950w&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pop it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-credit&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image: Eugene Gologursky / getty&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Colorado Congressman Ed Perlmutter asked Barnett how Amazon could &quot;ignore the contract that [PopSockets] entered into and just say, 'Sorry, that was our contract, but you got to lower your price.'&quot; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Barnett didn't mince words. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;With coercive tactics, basically,&quot; he replied. &quot;And these are tactics that are mainly executed by phone. It's one of the strangest relationships I've ever had with a retailer.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Barnett emphasized that, on paper, the contract &quot;appears to be negotiated in good faith.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, he claimed, this is followed by &quot;... frequent phone calls. And on the phone calls we get what I might call bullying with a smile. Very friendly people that we deal with who say, 'By the way, we dropped the price of X product last week. We need you to pay for it.'&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Barnett said he would push back and that's when &quot;the threats come.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SEE ALSO:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://mashable.com/article/ring-class-action-lawsuit-hacking-security/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ring hit with class action lawsuit for 'failure to take basic security precautions'&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He asserted that Amazon representatives would tell him over the phone: &quot;If we don't get it, then we're going to source product from the gray market.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other words, as with so many things Amazon, it's either play ball or get bent according to Barnett.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An Amazon spokesperson reached for comment, unsurprisingly, framed the issue differently. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;We sought to continue working with PopSockets as a vendor to ensure that we could provide competitive prices, availability, broad selection and fast delivery for those products to our customers,&quot; read the statement in part. &quot;Like any brand, however, PopSockets is free to choose which retailers it supplies and chose to stop selling directly through Amazon.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Essentially, in Amazon's view, PopSockets &lt;em&gt;chose&lt;/em&gt; to get bent. We should all be so lucky to be offered such a choice.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 20:53:53 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ilamont</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://mashable.com/article/amazon-bullying-tactics-popsockets-hearing/</og:url>
<og:title>PopSockets CEO calls out Amazon's 'bullying with a smile' tactics</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>The CEO alleged a pattern of over-the-phone threats.</og:description>
<og:image>https://mondrian.mashable.com/2020%252F01%252F17%252F43%252Fbe5ec1ae4ba540cfb19e8b767f020143.3040f.png%252F1200x630.png?signature=ovlqxdwjIPAfKyeuLnvVBUfjgcg=</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://mashable.com/article/amazon-bullying-tactics-popsockets-hearing/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>