<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>A world of free movement would be $78T richer</title>
<link>https://www.economist.com/the-world-if/2017/07/13/a-world-of-free-movement-would-be-78-trillion-richer</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.economist.com/the-world-if/2017/07/13/a-world-of-free-movement-would-be-78-trillion-richer</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;A HUNDRED-DOLLAR BILL is lying on the ground. An economist walks past it. A friend asks the economist: “Didn’t you see the money there?” The economist replies: “I thought I saw something, but I must have imagined it. If there had been $100 on the ground, someone would have picked it up.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If something seems too good to be true, it probably is not actually true. But occasionally it is. Michael Clemens, an economist at the Centre for Global Development, an anti-poverty think-tank in Washington, DC, argues that there are “trillion-dollar bills on the sidewalk”. One seemingly simple policy could make the world twice as rich as it is: open borders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;newsletter-form newsletter-form--inline&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;newsletter-form__message&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get our daily newsletter&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upgrade your inbox and get our Daily Dispatch and Editor's Picks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;latest-updates-panel__container latest-updates-panel__container--blog-post&quot;&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;latest-updates-panel__body&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;latest-updates-panel-card__wrapper&quot; readability=&quot;-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;latest-updates-panel__article-link&quot; readability=&quot;27&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;latest-updates-panel-card__title&quot;&gt;The founder of JetBlue is about to start a new airline&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;latest-updates-panel-card__wrapper&quot; readability=&quot;-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;latest-updates-panel__article-link&quot; readability=&quot;27&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;latest-updates-panel-card__title&quot;&gt;Michael Bloomberg is spending big to flip the House&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;latest-updates-panel-card__wrapper&quot; readability=&quot;-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;latest-updates-panel__article-link&quot; readability=&quot;27&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;latest-updates-panel-card__title&quot;&gt;A Supreme Court ruling heralds the end of tax-free online shopping&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;latest-updates-panel-card__wrapper&quot; readability=&quot;-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;latest-updates-panel__article-link&quot; readability=&quot;27&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;latest-updates-panel-card__title&quot;&gt;How artists depicted George Washington and the idea of the presidency&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;latest-updates-panel-card__wrapper&quot; readability=&quot;-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;latest-updates-panel__article-link&quot; readability=&quot;27&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;latest-updates-panel-card__title&quot;&gt;Do safe spaces and trigger warnings clash with liberal values?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;latest-updates-panel-card__wrapper&quot; readability=&quot;-1.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;latest-updates-panel__article-link&quot; readability=&quot;28&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;latest-updates-panel-card__title&quot;&gt;For those who fight sex-trafficking, dark rituals compound the problem&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Workers become far more productive when they move from a poor country to a rich one. Suddenly, they can join a labour market with ample capital, efficient firms and a predictable legal system. Those who used to scrape a living from the soil with a wooden hoe start driving tractors. Those who once made mud bricks by hand start working with cranes and mechanical diggers. Those who cut hair find richer clients who tip better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Labour is the world’s most valuable commodity—yet thanks to strict immigration regulation, most of it goes to waste,” argue Bryan Caplan and Vipul Naik in “A radical case for open borders”. Mexican labourers who migrate to the United States can expect to earn 150% more. Unskilled Nigerians make 1,000% more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Making Nigerians stay in Nigeria is as economically senseless as making farmers plant in Antarctica,” argue Mr Caplan and Mr Naik. And the non-economic benefits are hardly trivial, either. A Nigerian in the United States cannot be enslaved by the Islamists of Boko Haram.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The potential gains from open borders dwarf those of, say, completely free trade, let alone foreign aid. Yet the idea is everywhere treated as a fantasy. In most countries fewer than 10% of people favour it. In the era of Brexit and Donald Trump, it is a political non-starter. Nonetheless, it is worth asking what might happen if borders were, indeed, open.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To clarify, “open borders” means that people are free to move to find work. It does not mean “no borders” or “the abolition of the nation-state”. On the contrary, the reason why migration is so attractive is that some countries are well-run and others, abysmally so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Workers in rich countries earn more than those in poor countries partly because they are better educated but mostly because they live in societies that have, over many years, developed institutions that foster prosperity and peace. It is very hard to transfer Canadian institutions to Cambodia, but quite straightforward for a Cambodian family to fly to Canada. The quickest way to eliminate absolute poverty would be to allow people to leave the places where it persists. Their poverty would thus become more visible to citizens of the rich world—who would see many more Liberians and Bangladeshis waiting tables and stacking shelves—but much less severe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If borders were open, how many people would up sticks? Gallup, a pollster, estimated in 2013 that 630m people—about 13% of the world’s population—would migrate permanently if they could, and even more would move temporarily. Some 138m would settle in the United States, 42m in Britain and 29m in Saudi Arabia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gallup’s numbers could be an overestimate. People do not always do what they say they will. Leaving one’s homeland requires courage and resilience. Migrants must wave goodbye to familiar people, familiar customs and grandma’s cooking. Many people would rather not make that sacrifice, even for the prospect of large material rewards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wages are twice as high in Germany as in Greece, and under European Union rules Greeks are free to move to Germany, but only 150,000 have done so since the beginning of the economic crisis in 2010, out of a population of 11m. The weather is awful in Frankfurt, and hardly anyone speaks Greek. Even very large disparities combined with open borders do not necessarily lead to a mass exodus. Since 1986 the citizens of Micronesia have been allowed to live and work without a visa in the United States, where income per person is roughly 20 times higher. Yet two-thirds remain in Micronesia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite these caveats, it is a fair bet that open borders would lead to very large flows of people. The gap between rich and poor countries globally is much wider than the gap between the richest and less-rich countries within Europe, and most poor countries are not Pacific-island paradises. Many are violent as well as poor, or have oppressive governments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, migration is, in the jargon, “path-dependent”. It starts with a trickle: the first person to move from country A to country B typically arrives in a place where no one speaks his language or knows the right way to cook noodles. But the second migrant—who may be his brother or cousin—has someone to show him around. As word spreads on the diaspora grapevine that country B is a good place to live, more people set off from country A. When the 1,000th migrant arrives, he finds a whole neighbourhood of his compatriots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the Gallup numbers could just as well be too low. Today there are 1.4bn people in rich countries and 6bn in not-so-rich ones. It is hardly far-fetched to imagine that, over a few decades, a billion or more of those people might emigrate if there were no legal obstacle to doing so. Clearly, this would transform rich countries in unpredictable ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Voters in destination states typically do not mind a bit of immigration, but fret that truly open borders would lead to them being “swamped” by foreigners. This, they fear, would make life worse, and perhaps threaten the political system that made their country worth moving to in the first place. Mass migration, they worry, would bring more crime and terrorism, lower wages for locals, an impossible strain on welfare states, horrific overcrowding and traumatic cultural disruption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;xhead&quot;&gt;Open questions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If lots of people migrated from war-torn Syria, gangster-plagued Guatemala or chaotic Congo, would they bring mayhem with them? It is an understandable fear (and one that anti-immigrant politicians play on), but there is little besides conjecture and anecdotal evidence to support it. Granted, some immigrants commit crimes, or even headline-grabbing acts of terrorism. But in America the foreign-born are only a fifth as likely to be incarcerated as the native-born. In some European countries, such as Sweden, migrants are more likely to get into trouble than locals, but this is mostly because they are more likely to be young and male. A study of migration flows among 145 countries between 1970 and 2000 by researchers at the University of Warwick found that migration was more likely to reduce terrorism than increase it, largely because migration fosters economic growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Would large-scale immigration make locals worse off economically? So far, it has not. Immigrants are more likely than the native-born to bring new ideas and start their own businesses, many of which hire locals. Overall, migrants are less likely than the native-born to be a drain on public finances, unless local laws make it impossible for them to work, as is the case for asylum-seekers in Britain. A large influx of foreign workers may slightly depress the wages of locals with similar skills. But most immigrants have different skills. Foreign doctors and engineers ease skills shortages. Unskilled migrants care for babies or the elderly, thus freeing the native-born to do more lucrative work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;component-image blog-post__image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.static-economist.com/sites/default/files/images/print-edition/20170715_WIC005.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;component-image__img blog-post-article-image blog-post-article-image__slim&quot; srcset=&quot;/sites/default/files/imagecache/200-width/images/print-edition/20170715_WIC005.png 200w, /sites/default/files/imagecache/300-width/images/print-edition/20170715_WIC005.png 300w, /sites/default/files/imagecache/400-width/images/print-edition/20170715_WIC005.png 400w, /sites/default/files/imagecache/640-width/images/print-edition/20170715_WIC005.png 640w, /sites/default/files/imagecache/800-width/images/print-edition/20170715_WIC005.png 800w, /sites/default/files/imagecache/1000-width/images/print-edition/20170715_WIC005.png 1000w, /sites/default/files/imagecache/1200-width/images/print-edition/20170715_WIC005.png 1200w, /sites/default/files/imagecache/1280-width/images/print-edition/20170715_WIC005.png 1280w, /sites/default/files/imagecache/1600-width/images/print-edition/20170715_WIC005.png 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 600px) 640px, calc(100vw - 20px)&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Would open borders cause overcrowding? Perhaps, in popular cities like London. But most Western cities could build much higher than they do, creating more space. And mass migration would make the world as a whole less crowded, since fertility among migrants quickly plunges until it is much closer to the norm of their host country than their country of origin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Would mass immigration change the culture and politics of rich countries? Undoubtedly. Look at the way America has changed, mostly for the better, as its population soared from 5m mainly white folks in 1800 to 320m many-hued ones today. Still, that does not prove that future waves of immigration will be benign. Newcomers from illiberal lands might bring unwelcome customs, such as political corruption or intolerance for gay people. If enough of them came, they might vote for an Islamist government, or one that raises taxes on the native-born to pamper the newcomers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;xhead&quot;&gt;Eyes on the prize&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are certainly risks if borders are opened suddenly and without the right policies to help absorb the inflow. But nearly all these risks could be mitigated, and many of the most common objections overcome, with a bit of creative thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the worry is that immigrants will outvote the locals and impose an uncongenial government on them, one solution would be not to let immigrants vote—for five years, ten years or even a lifetime. This may seem harsh, but it is far kinder than not letting them in. If the worry is that future migrants might not pay their way, why not charge them more for visas, or make them pay extra taxes, or restrict their access to welfare benefits? Such levies could also be used to regulate the flow of migrants, thus avoiding big, sudden surges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This sounds horribly discriminatory, and it is. But it is better for the migrants than the status quo, in which they are excluded from rich-world labour markets unless they pay tens of thousands of dollars to people-smugglers—and even then they must work in the shadows and are subject to sudden deportation. Today, millions of migrants work in the Gulf, where they have no political rights at all. Despite this, they keep coming. No one is forcing them to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Open borders would make foreigners trillions of dollars richer,” observes Mr Caplan. A thoughtful voter, even if he does not care about the welfare of foreigners, “should not say...‘So what?’ Instead, he should say, ‘Trillions of dollars of wealth are on the table. How can my countrymen get a hefty piece of the action?’ Modern governments routinely use taxes and transfers to redistribute from young to old and rich to poor. Why not use the same policy tools to redistribute from foreign to native?” If a world of free movement would be $78trn richer, should not liberals be prepared to make big political compromises to bring it about?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2018 17:52:38 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>deegles</dc:creator>
<og:description>Yes, it would be disruptive. But the potential gains are so vast that objectors could be bribed to let it happen</og:description>
<og:image>https://cdn.static-economist.com/sites/default/files/images/2017/07/articles/main/20170715_wid004.jpg</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.economist.com/the-world-if/2017/07/13/a-world-of-free-movement-would-be-78-trillion-richer</og:url>
<og:title>A world of free movement would be $78 trillion richer</og:title>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.economist.com/the-world-if/2017/07/13/a-world-of-free-movement-would-be-78-trillion-richer</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Sleep Scientist Warns Against Walking Through Life &amp;#039;In an Underslept State&amp;#039;</title>
<link>https://www.npr.org/sections/health-shots/2017/10/16/558058812/sleep-scientist-warns-against-walking-through-life-in-an-underslept-state</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.npr.org/sections/health-shots/2017/10/16/558058812/sleep-scientist-warns-against-walking-through-life-in-an-underslept-state</guid>
<description>&lt;div id=&quot;res558128693&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap image large&quot; readability=&quot;4.6829268292683&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;imagewrap&quot; data-crop-type=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2017/10/16/sleeping2_custom-f2acd2e176cf195f1305dfcb5db011254346e819-s1100-c15.jpg&quot; data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2017/10/16/sleeping2_custom-f2acd2e176cf195f1305dfcb5db011254346e819-s1100.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img lazyOnLoad&quot; alt=&quot;Some people claim a late cup of coffee won't keep them up and that alcohol helps them sleep. But research shows both drugs mess with sleep's depth and restorative quality, says scientist and Why We Sleep author Matthew Walker.&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;credit-caption&quot;&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;MCKIBILLO/Getty Images/Imagezoo&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;enlarge_measure&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img_wrap&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2017/10/16/sleeping2_custom-f2acd2e176cf195f1305dfcb5db011254346e819-s1200.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Some people claim a late cup of coffee won't keep them up and that alcohol helps them sleep. But research shows both drugs mess with sleep's depth and restorative quality, says scientist and Why We Sleep author Matthew Walker.&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;enlarge_html&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;MCKIBILLO/Getty Images/Imagezoo&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The National Sleep Foundation recommends &lt;a href=&quot;https://sleepfoundation.org/press-release/national-sleep-foundation-recommends-new-sleep-times&quot;&gt;an average of eight hours&lt;/a&gt; of sleep per night for adults, but sleep scientist Matthew Walker says that too many people are falling short of the mark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Human beings are the only species that deliberately deprive themselves of sleep for no apparent gain,&quot; Walker says. &quot;Many people walk through their lives in an underslept state, not realizing it.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Walker is the director of the Center for Human Sleep Science at the University of California, Berkeley. He points out that lack of sleep — defined as six hours or fewer — can have serious consequences. Sleep deficiency is associated with problems in concentration, memory and the immune system, and may even shorten life span.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;res558115999&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap internallink insettwocolumn inset2col&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bucket img&quot;&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;featuredStackSquareImage555353033&quot; href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/sections/health-shots/2017/10/03/555353033/brains-link-to-immune-system-might-help-explain-alzheimers&quot; data-metrics=&quot;{&amp;quot;category&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Story to Story&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;action&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Click Internal Link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;label&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https:\/\/www.npr.org\/sections\/health-shots\/2017\/10\/03\/555353033\/brains-link-to-immune-system-might-help-explain-alzheimers&amp;quot;}&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2017/10/03/scisource_sq-f28d2737d55fa8ae394382996d308aa7ae7921e3-s100-c15.jpg&quot; data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2017/10/03/scisource_sq-f28d2737d55fa8ae394382996d308aa7ae7921e3-s100.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img lazyOnLoad&quot; alt=&quot;Brain's Link To Immune System Might Help Explain Alzheimer's&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Every disease that is killing us in developed nations has causal and significant links to a lack of sleep,&quot; he says. &quot;So that classic maxim that you may [have] heard that you can sleep when you're dead, it's actually mortally unwise advice from a very serious standpoint.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Walker discusses the importance of sleep — and offers strategies for getting the recommended eight hours — in his new book, &lt;em&gt;Why We Sleep.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interview Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On what you should do if you can't sleep&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should not actually stay in bed for very long awake, because your brain is this remarkably associative device and it quickly learns that the bed is about being awake. So you should go to another room — a room that's dim. Just read a book — no screens, no phones — and only when you're sleepy return to the bed. And that way your brain relearns the association with your bedroom being about sleep rather than wakefulness. ...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id=&quot;ad-backstage-wrap&quot; aria-label=&quot;advertisement&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another thing that people can do if you don't want to get up and go to a different room is actually try meditating. ... Being quite a stoic, hard-nosed scientist, I actually didn't really believe the data [about meditation as a sleep aid], even though the data is very strong. And I started doing it myself, particularly when I was traveling with jet lag, and I found it to be very effective. ...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;res558061532&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap internallink internallink--book&quot; previewtitle=&quot;Book Edition Information&quot; readability=&quot;4.5276073619632&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;res558061408&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap image book&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;imagewrap&quot; data-crop-type=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/books/titles/558061359/why-we-sleep-unlocking-the-power-of-sleep-and-dreams&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/bakertaylor/covers/w/why-we-sleep/9781501144318_custom-6e6a21d3ac987f36fec18f4495b2d304c69677a0-s1200-c15.jpg&quot; data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/bakertaylor/covers/w/why-we-sleep/9781501144318_custom-6e6a21d3ac987f36fec18f4495b2d304c69677a0-s1200.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img lazyOnLoad&quot; alt=&quot;Why We Sleep&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It just quiets the mind and it dampens down what we call the &quot;fight or flight&quot; branch of the nervous system, which is one of the key features of insomnia. And that can really have some efficacious benefits too. So that's another solution if people would choose not to go to a different room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On whether you can make up for a sleep deficit by sleeping longer another day&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You're trying to sleep off a debt that you've lumbered your brain and body with during the week, and wouldn't it be lovely if sleep worked like that? Sadly it doesn't. Sleep is not like the bank, so you can't accumulate a debt and then try and pay it off at a later point in time. And the reason is this: We know that if I were to deprive you of sleep for an entire night — take away eight hours — and then in the subsequent night I give you all of the sleep that you want, however much you wish to consume, you never get back all that you lost. You will sleep longer, but you will never achieve that full eight-hour repayment, as it were. So the brain has no capacity to get back that lost sleep that you've been lumbering it with during the week in terms of a debt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On letting teenagers sleep on weekends&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;res558086309&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap internallink insettwocolumn inset2col&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bucket img&quot;&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;featuredStackSquareImage429933655&quot; href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/sections/health-shots/2015/08/06/429933655/states-havent-embraced-later-school-start-times-for-teens&quot; data-metrics=&quot;{&amp;quot;category&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Story to Story&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;action&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Click Internal Link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;label&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https:\/\/www.npr.org\/sections\/health-shots\/2015\/08\/06\/429933655\/states-havent-embraced-later-school-start-times-for-teens&amp;quot;}&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2015/08/06/istock_000022330868large_sq-04c95933f6af0f8f9c4cf94313d32cd9f9bbeb7e-s100-c15.jpg&quot; data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2015/08/06/istock_000022330868large_sq-04c95933f6af0f8f9c4cf94313d32cd9f9bbeb7e-s100.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img lazyOnLoad&quot; alt=&quot;States Haven't Embraced Later School Start Times For Teens&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parents will often pull the covers off their teenager [on] weekends and say, &quot;It's daylight out! It's noon! You're wasting the day!&quot; And that's wrong for two reasons. ... It's not their fault; it's their biology that wants them to be asleep at that time. But it's more than that, because it also turns out that they are trying to sleep off a debt that we have actually saddled them with by way of this incessant model of early school start times. We have to abandon that attitude and we also have to change the educational practice as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On how the quantity and quality of sleep decreases with age&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The amount of sleep — the total amount of sleep that you get — starts to decrease the older that we get. I think one of the myths out there is that we simply need less sleep as we age, and that's not true, in fact. We need just as much sleep in our 60s, 70s [and] 80s, as we do when we're in our 40s. It's simply that the brain is not capable of generating that sleep, which it still needs, and the body still needs. So, total amount of sleep actually decreases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;res558088139&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap internallink insettwocolumn inset2col&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bucket img&quot;&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;featuredStackSquareImage460620606&quot; href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/sections/health-shots/2016/01/04/460620606/lack-of-deep-sleep-may-set-the-stage-for-alzheimers&quot; data-metrics=&quot;{&amp;quot;category&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Story to Story&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;action&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Click Internal Link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;label&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https:\/\/www.npr.org\/sections\/health-shots\/2016\/01\/04\/460620606\/lack-of-deep-sleep-may-set-the-stage-for-alzheimers&amp;quot;}&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2015/12/23/mri-alzheimers-2_sq-e8361516c7e24530ce35e3e4aac355cd37bf1310-s100-c15.jpg&quot; data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2015/12/23/mri-alzheimers-2_sq-e8361516c7e24530ce35e3e4aac355cd37bf1310-s100.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img lazyOnLoad&quot; alt=&quot;Lack Of Deep Sleep May Set The Stage For Alzheimer's&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also know that the continuity of sleep also starts to fall apart. Sleep becomes much more fragmented. There are many more awakenings throughout the night — pain, bathroom trips, etc. But we also know that it's not the quantity of sleep that changes with aging, it's also the quality of sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems to be particularly the deepest stage of sleep — something that we call non-rapid-eye-movement sleep, or non-REM sleep, the very deepest stages of non-REM sleep — those are selectively eroded by the aging process. By the time you're in your 50s, you've perhaps lost almost 40 to 50 percent of that deep sleep you were having, for example, when you were a teenager. By age 70, you may have lost almost 90 percent of that deep sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On using sleeping pills, like&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.npr.org/tags/169044285/ambien&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ambien&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;, to sleep&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately the current set or classes of sleeping pills that we have do not produce naturalistic sleep. So they are all a broad set of chemicals that we call the sedative hypnotics, and sedation is not sleep, it's very different. It doesn't give you the restorative natural benefits of sleep. ... If you look at the electrical signature of sleep that you have when you're taking those medications, it's not the same as a normal night of sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On how caffeine affects sleep&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;res558086590&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap internallink insettwocolumn inset2col&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bucket img&quot;&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;featuredStackSquareImage513060769&quot; href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/sections/health-shots/2017/02/02/513060769/not-getting-enough-sleep-camping-in-february-might-help&quot; data-metrics=&quot;{&amp;quot;category&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Story to Story&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;action&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Click Internal Link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;label&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https:\/\/www.npr.org\/sections\/health-shots\/2017\/02\/02\/513060769\/not-getting-enough-sleep-camping-in-february-might-help&amp;quot;}&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2017/02/02/camping_sq-5fd4d7d9b20cf1fca205df6a79872e96601078d6-s100-c15.jpg&quot; data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2017/02/02/camping_sq-5fd4d7d9b20cf1fca205df6a79872e96601078d6-s100.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img lazyOnLoad&quot; alt=&quot;Not Getting Enough Sleep? Camping In February Might Help&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, and most obvious for some people, is that it stops you falling asleep. Some people, however, say, &quot;I can have a cup of coffee after dinner and I fall asleep just fine, so I'm not one of those people that is sensitive to caffeine.&quot; And that's quite dangerous, because we also know that even if you can fall asleep, the depth of the sleep that you have when caffeine is swilling around within the brain is not going to be as deep anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So people may wake up the next morning, they'll feel unrefreshed. They'll start to reach for the coffeepot earlier. They'll drink more caffeine, never having realized that it was the cup of coffee last night that has left you feeling underslept, because they didn't wake up during the night, they didn't have problems falling asleep, but caffeine can still have that deleterious impact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On alcohol's effect on sleep&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alcohol ... is a sedative drug, and what you're doing there is simply knocking yourself out. You are removing consciousness quickly from the brain by way of having alcohol, but you're not putting yourself into naturalistic sleep. The other issue is that alcohol will fragment your sleep — it will litter it and punctuate it with many more awakenings throughout the night, so short ... that you tend not to remember them. So, once again, you're not quite aware of how bad your sleep was when you had alcohol in the system. The final aspect of alcohol is that it is very good at blocking your REM sleep, or your dream sleep, which is critical for aspects of mental health within the brain and emotional restitution too. So alcohol [is a] very misunderstood drug when it comes to sleep — not helpful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Heidi Saman and Thea Chaloner produced and edited the audio of this interview. Bridget Bentz and Molly Seavy-Nesper adapted it for the Web.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2018 13:43:16 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>laurex</dc:creator>
<og:title>Sleep Scientist Warns Against Walking Through Life 'In An Underslept State'</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.npr.org/sections/health-shots/2017/10/16/558058812/sleep-scientist-warns-against-walking-through-life-in-an-underslept-state</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>&quot;Human beings are the only species that deliberately deprive themselves of sleep for no apparent gain,&quot; says sleep scientist Matthew Walker. His new book is Why We Sleep.</og:description>
<og:image>https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2017/10/16/sleeping2_wide-bbb042247d9764cf91fce5708ea28219b1745f05.jpg?s=1400</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.npr.org/sections/health-shots/2017/10/16/558058812/sleep-scientist-warns-against-walking-through-life-in-an-underslept-state</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Filezilla installer is suspicious again</title>
<link>https://forum.filezilla-project.org/viewtopic.php?f=2&amp;t=48441</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://forum.filezilla-project.org/viewtopic.php?f=2&amp;t=48441</guid>
<description>I'm seeing hits on this file as well from advanced security tools in an enterprise environment. This appears to be a bit more than just a few false hits on VirusTotal. The installation of filezilla_3.29.0_win64-setup_bundled.exe file with MD5 of 9f405c266c883305537c11246bdb1d42 shows signs of malicious activity in the form of IDS/IPS bypass techniques to copy and append .dat files behind the scenes. This activity can sometimes be a false positive, but this does not appear to be a false hit.&lt;p&gt;The most suspicious part of the install we see is the spawning of an unsigned, unidentified process called tofufeti.exe which then spawns dozens of cmd.exe prompts to append these .dat files together after itself being put together by .dat file copy and appends.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;See attached screenshot for the process chain we see spawning off of filezilla_3.29.0_win64-setup_bundled.exe. Each cmd.exe process expands into another chain of cmd.exe and conhost.exe processes to perform cleanup of the temp .dat files. None of this seems necessary for a simple FileZilla installation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Can you comment on what exactly tofufeti.exe is and why this unique unsigned process is seen connecting to multiple IP's with no real content when installing the &quot;clean&quot; version of this software downloaded directly from the source?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The IP's and domains we see tofufeti.exe connecting to are:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;54.225.173.220 on tcp/80 (goquc.com)&lt;br/&gt;52.84.25.26 on tcp/80 (d39ievd5spb5kl.cloudfront.net)&lt;br/&gt;34.208.177.52 on tcp/80 (gubuh.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
Random unsigned processes reaching out to random sites with no content over port 80 is typically a sign of malware beaconing.&lt;p&gt;Running the install without choosing any of the bundled adware shows no signs of this activity and is a simple and clean install that one would expect for a lightweight tool like FileZilla. So i don't think this is FileZilla's doing exactly, more that the bundled software in this bundle download appears to be typical adware garbage, but with a serious risk of turning into something far more severe via the ability to download other malicious files in small chunks and put them together after bypassing perimeter defenses. This technique is discussed in depth here: (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.carbonblack.com/2016/09/23/security-advisory-variants-well-known-adware-families-discovered-include-sophisticated-obfuscation-techniques-previously-associated-nation-state-attacks/&quot; class=&quot;postlink&quot;&gt;https://www.carbonblack.com/2016/09/23/ ... e-attacks/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'd appreciate any comments that could shed light on what we're seeing as this does not appear to be a misunderstanding of VirusTotal scanners, but an actual advanced attack by the bundled adware in this install package, although I'd love to be proven wrong.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2018 13:32:35 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>stevekemp</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-gb</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://forum.filezilla-project.org/viewtopic.php?f=2&amp;t=48441</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Poverty reduces brainpower needed for navigating other areas of life (2013)</title>
<link>https://www.princeton.edu/news/2013/08/29/poor-concentration-poverty-reduces-brainpower-needed-navigating-other-areas-life</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.princeton.edu/news/2013/08/29/poor-concentration-poverty-reduces-brainpower-needed-navigating-other-areas-life</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Poverty and all its related concerns require so much mental energy that the poor have less remaining brainpower to devote to other areas of life, according to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencemag.org/content/341/6149/976&quot;&gt;research based at Princeton University&lt;/a&gt;. As a result, people of limited means are more likely to make mistakes and bad decisions that may be amplified by — and perpetuate — their financial woes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Published in the journal Science, the study presents a unique perspective regarding the causes of persistent poverty. The researchers suggest that being poor may keep a person from concentrating on the very avenues that would lead them out of poverty. A person's cognitive function is diminished by the constant and all-consuming effort of coping with the immediate effects of having little money, such as scrounging to pay bills and cut costs. Thusly, a person is left with fewer &quot;mental resources&quot; to focus on complicated, indirectly related matters such as education, job training and even managing their time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a series of experiments, the researchers found that pressing financial concerns had an immediate impact on the ability of low-income individuals to perform on common cognitive and logic tests. On average, a person preoccupied with money problems exhibited a drop in cognitive function similar to a 13-point dip in IQ, or the loss of an entire night's sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;view-mode-full-width media media-image&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field field--name-image field--type-image field--label-hidden field__item&quot;&gt;&lt;img srcset=&quot;/sites/default/files/styles/third_1x/public/images/2013/08/sugarcanefarmer_575.jpg?itok=HErKSiMy 575w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width:1440px) 100em, (min-width:64.063em) 60vw, 100vw&quot; src=&quot;https://www.princeton.edu/sites/default/files/styles/half_2x/public/images/2013/08/sugarcanefarmer_575.jpg?itok=ZB9dJR-C&quot; alt=&quot;Sugarcane Farmer&quot; typeof=&quot;foaf:Image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-caption&quot; readability=&quot;8.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field--name-field-media-caption field--type-text-long field--label-hidden field__item&quot; readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research based at Princeton University found that poverty and all its related concerns require so much mental energy that the poor have less remaining brainpower to devote to other areas of life. Experiments showed that the impact of financial concerns on the cognitive function of low-income individuals was similar to a 13-point dip in IQ, or the loss of an entire night's sleep. To gauge the influence of poverty in natural contexts, the researchers tested 464 sugarcane farmers in India who rely on the annual harvest for at least 60 percent of their income. Each farmer performed better on common fluid-intelligence and cognition tests post-harvest compared to pre-harvest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;&lt;p&gt;But when their concerns were benign, low-income individuals performed competently, at a similar level to people who were well off, said corresponding author Jiaying Zhao, who conducted the study as a doctoral student in the lab of co-author &lt;a href=&quot;http://psych.princeton.edu/psychology/research/shafir/index.php&quot;&gt;Eldar Shafir&lt;/a&gt;, Princeton's William Stewart Tod Professor of &lt;a href=&quot;http://psych.princeton.edu&quot;&gt;Psychology&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://wws.princeton.edu/&quot;&gt;Public Affairs&lt;/a&gt;. Zhao and Shafir worked with Anandi Mani, an associate professor of economics at the University of Warwick in Britain, and Sendhil Mullainathan, a Harvard University economics professor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;These pressures create a salient concern in the mind and draw mental resources to the problem itself. That means we are unable to focus on other things in life that need our attention,&quot; said Zhao, who is now an assistant professor of psychology at the University of British Columbia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Previous views of poverty have blamed poverty on personal failings, or an environment that is not conducive to success,&quot; she said. &quot;We're arguing that the lack of financial resources itself can lead to impaired cognitive function. The very condition of not having enough can actually be a cause of poverty.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mental tax that poverty can put on the brain is distinct from stress, Shafir explained. Stress is a person's response to various outside pressures that — according to studies of arousal and performance — can actually enhance a person's functioning, he said. In the Science study, Shafir and his colleagues instead describe an immediate rather than chronic preoccupation with limited resources that can be a detriment to unrelated yet still important tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Stress itself doesn't predict that people can't perform well — they may do better up to a point,&quot; Shafir said. &quot;A person in poverty might be at the high part of the performance curve when it comes to a specific task and, in fact, we show that they do well on the problem at hand. But they don't have leftover bandwidth to devote to other tasks. The poor are often highly effective at focusing on and dealing with pressing problems. It's the other tasks where they perform poorly.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fallout of neglecting other areas of life may loom larger for a person just scraping by, Shafir said. Late fees tacked on to a forgotten rent payment, a job lost because of poor time-management — these make a tight money situation worse. And as people get poorer, they tend to make difficult and often costly decisions that further perpetuate their hardship, Shafir said. He and Mullainathan were co-authors on a 2012 Science paper that reported a higher likelihood of poor people to engage in behaviors that reinforce the conditions of poverty, such as excessive borrowing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;They can make the same mistakes, but the outcomes of errors are more dear,&quot; Shafir said. &quot;So, if you live in poverty, you're more error prone and errors cost you more dearly — it's hard to find a way out.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first set of experiments took place in a New Jersey mall between 2010 and 2011 with roughly 400 subjects chosen at random. Their median annual income was around $70,000 and the lowest income was around $20,000. The researchers created scenarios wherein subjects had to ponder how they would solve financial problems, for example, whether they would handle a sudden car repair by paying in full, borrowing money or putting the repairs off. Participants were assigned either an &quot;easy&quot; or &quot;hard&quot; scenario in which the cost was low or high — such as $150 or $1,500 for the car repair. While participants pondered these scenarios, they performed common fluid-intelligence and cognition tests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Subjects were divided into a &quot;poor&quot; group and a &quot;rich&quot; group based on their income. The study showed that when the scenarios were easy — the financial problems not too severe — the poor and rich performed equally well on the cognitive tests. But when they thought about the hard scenarios, people at the lower end of the income scale performed significantly worse on both cognitive tests, while the rich participants were unfazed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To better gauge the influence of poverty in natural contexts, between 2010 and 2011 the researchers also tested 464 sugarcane farmers in India who rely on the annual harvest for at least 60 percent of their income. Because sugarcane harvests occur once a year, these are farmers who find themselves rich after harvest and poor before it. Each farmer was given the same tests before and after the harvest, and performed better on both tests post-harvest compared to pre-harvest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cognitive effect of poverty the researchers found relates to the more general influence of &quot;scarcity&quot; on cognition, which is the larger focus of Shafir's research group. Scarcity in this case relates to any deficit — be it in money, time, social ties or even calories — that people experience in trying to meet their needs. Scarcity consumes &quot;mental bandwidth&quot; that would otherwise go to other concerns in life, Zhao said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;These findings fit in with our story of how scarcity captures attention. It consumes your mental bandwidth,&quot; Zhao said. &quot;Just asking a poor person to think about hypothetical financial problems reduces mental bandwidth. This is an acute, immediate impact, and has implications for scarcity of resources of any kind.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;We documented similar effects among people who are not otherwise poor, but on whom we imposed scarce resources,&quot; Shafir added. &quot;It’s not about being a poor person — it's about living in poverty.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many types of scarcity are temporary and often discretionary, said Shafir, who is co-author with Mullainathan of the book, &quot;Scarcity: Why Having Too Little Means So Much,&quot; to be published in September. For instance, a person pressed for time can reschedule appointments, cancel something or even decide to take on less.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;When you're poor you can't say, 'I've had enough, I'm not going to be poor anymore.' Or, 'Forget it, I just won't give my kids dinner, or pay rent this month.' Poverty imposes a much stronger load that's not optional and in very many cases is long lasting,&quot; Shafir said. &quot;It's not a choice you're making — you're just reduced to few options. This is not something you see with many other types of scarcity.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers suggest that services for the poor should accommodate the dominance that poverty has on a person's time and thinking. Such steps would include simpler aid forms and more guidance in receiving assistance, or training and educational programs structured to be more forgiving of unexpected absences, so that a person who has stumbled can more easily try again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;You want to design a context that is more scarcity proof,&quot; said Shafir, noting that better-off people have access to regular support in their daily lives, be it a computer reminder, a personal assistant, a housecleaner or a babysitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;There's very little you can do with time to get more money, but a lot you can do with money to get more time,&quot; Shafir said. &quot;The poor, who our research suggests are bound to make more mistakes and pay more dearly for errors, inhabit contexts often not designed to help.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The paper, &quot;Poverty impedes cognitive function,&quot; was published Aug. 30 by Science. The work was supported by the National Science Foundation (award number SES-0933497), the International Finance Corporation and the IFMR Trust in India.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2018 05:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>known</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.princeton.edu/news/2013/08/29/poor-concentration-poverty-reduces-brainpower-needed-navigating-other-areas-life</og:url>
<og:title>Poor concentration: Poverty reduces brainpower needed for navigating other areas of life</og:title>
<og:description>Research based at Princeton University found that poverty and all its related concerns require so much mental energy that the poor have less remaining brainpower to devote to other areas of life.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.princeton.edu/news/2013/08/29/poor-concentration-poverty-reduces-brainpower-needed-navigating-other-areas-life</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>GitLab 11 released</title>
<link>https://about.gitlab.com/2018/06/22/gitlab-11-0-released/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://about.gitlab.com/2018/06/22/gitlab-11-0-released/</guid>
<description>&lt;div readability=&quot;192.30424496719&quot;&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;35.900893582453&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;squash-and-merge-in-gitlab-core-and-gitlabcom-free&quot;&gt; Squash and Merge in GitLab Core and GitLab.com Free&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;badge-container dark&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;top-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CORE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STARTER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREMIUM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ULTIMATE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottom-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FREE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BRONZE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SILVER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOLD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When working on a large feature, developers often push multiple commits to a work-in-progress branch, and after code review, there may be even more commits to address various code issues. Before merging that branch to master, many teams prefer to squash all the commits into a single one, ensuring a &lt;a href=&quot;https://about.gitlab.com/2018/06/07/keeping-git-commit-history-clean/&quot;&gt;clean Git history&lt;/a&gt;, making it easier for folks in the future to review previous code changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Squashing is a Git feature and a developer can do it right before merging on their local machine, but with squash and merge available directly in the GitLab web UI, you can do it with just a single click. For example, a repo maintainer merging-in the code can now do the squash without asking the code contributor to do so, saving one extra round-trip communication step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Squash and Merge, previously available in GitLab Starter, GitLab.com Bronze, and higher tiers, is now open source and available in GitLab Core and GitLab.com Free! Many users have said that all teams would benefit from this feature, and we are happy to bring it to everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.com/blackst0ne&quot;&gt;blackst0ne&lt;/a&gt; for your contribution!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Squash and Merge in GitLab Core and GitLab.com Free&quot; class=&quot;shadow&quot; src=&quot;https://about.gitlab.com/images/11_0/squash-and-merge-core.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/user/project/merge_requests/squash_and_merge.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;See the documentation on Squash and merge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;hidden-lg&quot; readability=&quot;13.651515151515&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;open-projects-in-xcode&quot;&gt; Open projects in Xcode&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;badge-container dark&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;top-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CORE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STARTER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREMIUM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ULTIMATE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottom-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FREE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BRONZE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SILVER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOLD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At WWDC earlier this month, &lt;a href=&quot;https://about.gitlab.com/2018/06/06/one-click-clone-to-xcode/&quot;&gt;Apple announced their Xcode integration with GitLab&lt;/a&gt;, which makes it easier to work with your Xcode projects hosted in GitLab.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Projects that contain a &lt;code&gt;.xcodeproj&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;.xcworkspace&lt;/code&gt; file can now be cloned in Xcode using the new Open in Xcode button in GitLab. When viewing Xcode projects in the GitLab interface, the button will be available in GitLab next to the Git URL for cloning your project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Open projects in Xcode&quot; class=&quot;shadow&quot; src=&quot;https://about.gitlab.com/images/11_0/open_in_xcode.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/user/project/repository/index.html#open-in-xcode&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;See the documentation on opening in Xcode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;21.54806312769&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;roadmap-date-ranges&quot;&gt; Roadmap date ranges&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;badge-container dark&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;top-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CORE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STARTER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREMIUM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ULTIMATE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottom-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FREE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BRONZE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SILVER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOLD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since epics can take on any start and end dates, we wanted to provide a simple way for users to quickly view the ones that are more relevant in a given time range.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this release, we are introducing Roadmap date ranges. You can now quickly click Quarters, Months, or Weeks, and immediately, the roadmap will be refreshed, enabling you see your epics from different time perspectives. Teams who are focused on shipping features in the next few weeks can use one granularity, while executive leadership folks who want a high-level overview can use the longer time-period views.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Roadmap date ranges&quot; class=&quot;shadow&quot; src=&quot;https://about.gitlab.com/images/11_0/date-ranges.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/user/group/roadmap/#timeline-duration&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;See the documentation on Roadmap date ranges&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;hidden-lg&quot; readability=&quot;21.740547588005&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;unlimited-guests-for-free-in-ultimate&quot;&gt; Unlimited Guests for free in Ultimate&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;badge-container dark&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;top-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CORE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STARTER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREMIUM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ULTIMATE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottom-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FREE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BRONZE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SILVER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOLD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to help customers get the most from their GitLab instances, Guest users no longer count against seat count for Ultimate licenses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since these users no longer consume seats (they’re effectively free to add), it gives more users in an organization the chance to join the instance and contribute to the conversation. You’re free to promote these users, but they’ll count against your license’s seat count once they’re promoted beyond Guest in any project or group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This also means that if a user logs in and is never added to a project/group, they have no role applied, therefore they are considered as ‘Guests.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/user/permissions.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;See the documentation on guest permissions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;25.2&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;issue-board-assignee-lists&quot;&gt; Issue Board assignee lists&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;badge-container dark&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;top-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CORE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STARTER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREMIUM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ULTIMATE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottom-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FREE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BRONZE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SILVER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOLD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Issue boards are a great tool for managing and tracking workflows, as your issues progress through different stages in your lifecycle, with label lists representing those stages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this release, we are introducing assignee lists to issue boards. An assignee list shows issues that are assigned to a specific user. This provides a whole new way to use issue boards: to view and manage issue assignments for your team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can now &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/user/project/issue_board.html#configurable-issue-board&quot;&gt;configure a board&lt;/a&gt; to a scope that matches that of your team, and then add assignee lists representing team members. This gives you instant visibility into what issues your team is working on, whether you are a manager who wants an overview and status of the team’s overall responsibilities, or an individual contributor who wants to sync up with another team member’s assigned issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can even add label lists and assignee lists to the same board.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Issue Board assignee lists&quot; class=&quot;shadow&quot; src=&quot;https://about.gitlab.com/images/11_0/issue-board-assignee-lists.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/user/project/issue_board.html#assignee-lists&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;See the documentation on Issue Board assignee lists&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;hidden-lg&quot; readability=&quot;22.971848225214&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;assign-ancestor-group-milestones&quot;&gt; Assign ancestor group milestones&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;badge-container dark&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;top-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CORE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STARTER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREMIUM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ULTIMATE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottom-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FREE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BRONZE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SILVER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOLD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GitLab supports subgroups, and we have now leveraged that subgrouping structure for milestones. For any issue or merge request, you can now assign it a project milestone or a group milestone inherited from &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; ancestor group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In particular, you can now have a high-level group with a set of milestones at that level. You can then use those &lt;em&gt;same&lt;/em&gt; milestones in any issues and merge requests in any subgroups deeper down, providing a powerful and flexible mechanism to organize work if you have nested groups and projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, you can filter by this milestone in group issue lists and group issue boards, so that you can pull in targeted objects from different levels in customized views.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Assign ancestor group milestones&quot; src=&quot;https://about.gitlab.com/images/11_0/assign-ancestor-group-milestones.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/user/project/milestones/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;See the documentation on Milestones&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;14.519008264463&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;issues-and-merge-requests-from-subgroups-in-api&quot;&gt; Issues and merge requests from subgroups in API&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;badge-container dark&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;top-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CORE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STARTER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREMIUM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ULTIMATE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottom-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FREE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BRONZE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SILVER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOLD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Subgroup support is also now consistent in the API when it comes to retrieving &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/api/issues.html#list-group-issues&quot;&gt;issues&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/api/merge_requests.html#list-group-merge-requests&quot;&gt;merge requests&lt;/a&gt;. That is, if you query a particular group through the API for issues and merge requests, you will get results from projects that are immediate children of that group, and also all from projects of all subgroups nesting down further. This is analogous to viewing the same objects in the web UI’s group list views, which was introduced in recent prior releases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/api/README.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;See the documentation on GitLab APIs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;hidden-lg&quot; readability=&quot;18.325581395349&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;persistent-auto-devops-deploy-tokens-for-kubernetes&quot;&gt; Persistent Auto DevOps deploy tokens for Kubernetes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;badge-container dark&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;top-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CORE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STARTER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREMIUM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ULTIMATE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottom-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FREE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BRONZE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SILVER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOLD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previously, when Auto DevOps was used for private or internal projects, the registry was not accessible by Kubernetes after the deploy job completed. This prevented the cluster from fetching the image again (for scaling, failures, etc).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With GitLab 11.0, a new deploy token is created to provide persistent access to the registry when Auto DevOps is enabled on private/internal projects. This will ensure that the cluster can perform necessary operations and reduce possible failures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/topics/autodevops/#auto-deploy&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;See the documentation on deploy tokens for Auto DevOps&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;19.016393442623&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;specify-deployment-strategy-from-auto-devops-settings&quot;&gt; Specify deployment strategy from Auto DevOps settings&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;badge-container dark&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;top-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CORE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STARTER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREMIUM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ULTIMATE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottom-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FREE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BRONZE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SILVER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOLD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While some applications may benefit from deploying every change into production immediately after it’s done, others may fare better by grouping those changes into a common environment for more thorough testing. Configuring different deployment strategies for different projects previously meant dealing with project-specific variables and then exercising them as needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting in GitLab 11.0, Auto DevOps makes specifying your deployment strategy a single-click event. When enabling Auto DevOps for a specific project, you will be able to specify whether your application gets automatically deployed to production or deployed automatically to staging and then manually to production. This single-click configuration will allow you to spend more time working on your apps and less time configuring their deployment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Specify deployment strategy from Auto DevOps settings&quot; class=&quot;shadow&quot; src=&quot;https://about.gitlab.com/images/11_0/autodevops-deploy-strategy.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/topics/autodevops/#auto-deploy&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;See the documentation on Auto DevOps deployments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;hidden-lg&quot; readability=&quot;16.227848101266&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;variables-defining-deployment-policy-for-canary-environments&quot;&gt; Variables defining deployment policy for canary environments&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;badge-container dark&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;top-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CORE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STARTER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREMIUM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ULTIMATE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottom-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FREE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BRONZE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SILVER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOLD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oftentimes we’d like to roll out changes to a subset of users or servers to evaluate its impact before deploying across an entire environment. Previously, Auto DevOps users had to make the Auto DevOps template explicit and then define the desired behavior in order to achieve canary deployments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting with GitLab 11.0, users are able to define their canary policy by making use of the &lt;code&gt;CANARY_ENABLED&lt;/code&gt; environment variable without the need to customize the Auto DevOps template, enabling faster canary policy declaration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/topics/autodevops/#deploy-policy-for-canary-environments&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;See the documentation on the deployment policy for canary environments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;23.666666666667&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;always-on-approvals&quot;&gt; Always-on approvals&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;badge-container dark&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;top-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CORE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STARTER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREMIUM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ULTIMATE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottom-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FREE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BRONZE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SILVER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOLD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Merge request approvals are a longstanding GitLab feature that allows teams to enforce code review (or any type of review) in a merge request, before unblocking it for merging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prior to this release, the feature had to be configured in the project settings. To simplify and streamline the feature, approvals are now always on for all projects in GitLab (in Starter, Bronze, or higher tiers). At the same time, however, we definitely do not want to slow down creating and merging code. So when a user creates a project, the required number of approvals is by default zero for the project (essentially, the feature is “off”). As the project grows, the user (and their team) can naturally adopt approvals by raising that required number as appropriate to their workflow needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Always-on approvals&quot; class=&quot;shadow&quot; src=&quot;https://about.gitlab.com/images/11_0/always-on-approvals.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/user/project/merge_requests/merge_request_approvals.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;See the documentation on Merge request approvals&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;hidden-lg&quot; readability=&quot;14.965573770492&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;fetch-cluster-parameters-from-gke&quot;&gt; Fetch cluster parameters from GKE&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;badge-container dark&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;top-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CORE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STARTER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREMIUM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ULTIMATE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottom-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FREE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BRONZE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SILVER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOLD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creating Kubernetes clusters in GitLab has never been easier. With GitLab 11.0, the “project” and “zones” values are automatically fetched from your Google Kubernetes Engine (GKE) account and displayed as a list for easy selection. Previously, creating a cluster using our GKE integration meant having to manually enter this data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simple cluster creation will allow you to quickly stand up clusters from GitLab and quickly deploy your apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Fetch cluster parameters from GKE&quot; class=&quot;shadow&quot; src=&quot;https://about.gitlab.com/images/11_0/fetch-gke-parameters.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/user/project/clusters/#adding-and-creating-a-new-gke-cluster-via-gitlab&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;See the documentation on Adding and creating a new GKE cluster via GitLab&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;17.144781144781&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;disable-auto-devops-jobs-with-variables&quot;&gt; Disable Auto DevOps jobs with variables&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;badge-container dark&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;top-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CORE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STARTER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREMIUM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ULTIMATE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottom-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FREE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BRONZE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SILVER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOLD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When your application doesn’t precisely fit one or more Auto DevOps stages, such as unit testing, code quality, etc., it is ideal to customize the pipeline to run only the jobs you care about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GitLab 11.0 now provides the ability to disable one or more Auto DevOps jobs through the use of environment variables. This allows you to take advantage of the power of Auto DevOps, even when your application doesn’t fit with one of its stages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/topics/autodevops/#environment-variables&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;See the documentation on Auto DevOps environment variables&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;hidden-lg&quot; readability=&quot;16.282442748092&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;lfs-files-included-when-importing-a-project&quot;&gt; LFS files included when importing a project&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;badge-container dark&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;top-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CORE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STARTER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREMIUM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ULTIMATE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottom-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FREE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BRONZE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SILVER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOLD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/workflow/lfs/manage_large_binaries_with_git_lfs.html&quot;&gt;Git LFS&lt;/a&gt; helps to version large files with Git by storing them outside the repository and lazily downloading files at checkout rather than clone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When importing a project from GitHub, Bitbucket Cloud, or using a Git URL, GitLab now imports LFS objects so that you have a complete copy of the repository including those LFS objects. Previously, LFS objects were excluded from imports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/user/project/import/index.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;See the documentation on importing projects&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;12.95154185022&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;operations-tab&quot;&gt; Operations tab&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;badge-container dark&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;top-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CORE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STARTER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREMIUM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ULTIMATE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottom-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FREE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BRONZE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SILVER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOLD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the release of GitLab 11.0 we have added an &lt;strong&gt;Operations&lt;/strong&gt; section in the navigation sidebar, making it quicker to access and easier to discover our operations features. In this release &lt;strong&gt;Environments&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Kubernetes&lt;/strong&gt; have been moved from &lt;strong&gt;CI/CD&lt;/strong&gt; to &lt;strong&gt;Operations&lt;/strong&gt;, and we will continue to add sections for features like Metrics and Logs in upcoming releases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Operations tab&quot; src=&quot;https://about.gitlab.com/images/11_0/operations_tab.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/ci/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;See the documentation on GitLab CI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;hidden-lg&quot; readability=&quot;17.052631578947&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;sast-for-net-and-scala&quot;&gt; SAST for .NET and Scala&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;badge-container dark&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;top-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CORE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STARTER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREMIUM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ULTIMATE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottom-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FREE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BRONZE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SILVER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOLD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of our effort to increase the availability of our security tools to the most common languages and frameworks, we have been continuously iterating on Static Application Security Testing (SAST).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In GitLab 11.0, we add support for two new languages, .NET and Scala. Users don’t need to change anything in their projects if they are already using Auto DevOps or the latest version of the &lt;code&gt;sast&lt;/code&gt; job definition in their &lt;code&gt;.gitlab-ci.yml&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/user/project/merge_requests/sast.html#supported-languages-and-frameworks&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;See the documentation on SAST&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;13.493449781659&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;cloud-native-gitlab-helm-chart-now-beta&quot;&gt; Cloud-native GitLab Helm chart now Beta&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;badge-container dark&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;top-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CORE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STARTER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREMIUM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ULTIMATE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottom-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FREE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BRONZE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SILVER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOLD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are excited to announce that the cloud-native GitLab &lt;a href=&quot;https://helm.sh&quot;&gt;Helm&lt;/a&gt; chart is now in beta. This chart features a more cloud-native architecture, with a container for each component of GitLab and no requirement for shared storage. These changes result in increased resilience, scalability, and performance of GitLab on Kubernetes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/install/kubernetes/gitlab_chart.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;See the documentation on GitLab Helm chart&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;hidden-lg&quot; readability=&quot;17.89349112426&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;easily-deploy-and-integrate-jupyterhub-with-gitlab&quot;&gt; Easily deploy and integrate JupyterHub with GitLab&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;badge-container dark&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;top-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CORE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STARTER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREMIUM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ULTIMATE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottom-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FREE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BRONZE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SILVER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOLD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://jupyterhub.readthedocs.io/en/stable/&quot;&gt;JupyterHub&lt;/a&gt; is a multi-user service for easily launching &lt;a href=&quot;https://jupyter-notebook.readthedocs.io/en/latest/&quot;&gt;notebooks&lt;/a&gt; across a data science team. Jupyter notebooks provide a web-based interactive programming environment commonly used for data analysis, simulation, visualization, and machine learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GitLab 11.0 can now deploy JupyterHub to an integrated Kubernetes cluster with a single click, and it is automatically configured to use GitLab for seamless authentication. Additional options like &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.com/gitlab-org/gitlab-ce/issues/47137&quot;&gt;HTTPS&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.com/gitlab-org/gitlab-ce/issues/47820&quot;&gt;group filtering&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.com/gitlab-org/gitlab-ce/issues/48236&quot;&gt;custom notebooks&lt;/a&gt; will be added in future releases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Easily deploy and integrate JupyterHub with GitLab&quot; class=&quot;shadow&quot; src=&quot;https://about.gitlab.com/images/11_0/jupyterhub.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/user/project/clusters/#installing-applications&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;See the documentation on deploying JupyterHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;19.41452991453&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;expanded-issue-weight-values&quot;&gt; Expanded Issue Weight values&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;badge-container dark&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;top-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CORE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STARTER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREMIUM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ULTIMATE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottom-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FREE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BRONZE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SILVER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOLD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Issue weights in GitLab are useful for assigning effort estimation or any other cost metric associated with working on an issue. Previously, you could only assign values 1 through 9 for an issue. But this meant that teams that wanted more granularity in their weighting were constrained.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting in this release, issue weights can take on any non-negative integer value, from 0 upward, giving you unlimited flexibility in how you use weights. Furthermore, &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/user/project/milestones/burndown_charts.html&quot;&gt;Burndown Charts&lt;/a&gt; automatically consider these new weight values, so your team can immediately make use of an expanded range.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Expanded Issue Weight values&quot; src=&quot;https://about.gitlab.com/images/11_0/expanded-issue-weight-values.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/workflow/issue_weight.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;See the documentation on Issue Weights&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;hidden-lg&quot; readability=&quot;20.243902439024&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;combined-system-note-for-successive-issue-description-updates&quot;&gt; Combined system note for successive issue description updates&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;badge-container dark&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;top-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CORE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STARTER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREMIUM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ULTIMATE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottom-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FREE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BRONZE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SILVER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOLD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GitLab allows for powerful asynchronous collaboration and communication. With the ability to document ideas and have conversations in so many places, we encourage always maintaining a single source of truth in the description area of an issue or epic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This means that descriptions are often updated, many times in succession over a few minutes, leading to multiple system notes that say that the description has been updated. With this release, we are smartly combining those system notes if they happen within a short period of time, cleaning up the visual clutter and making comments in GitLab just a little bit easier to navigate. We’ll be adding the same functionality to merge requests in the next release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Combined system note for successive issue description updates&quot; class=&quot;shadow&quot; src=&quot;https://about.gitlab.com/images/11_0/combined-system-note.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/user/project/issues/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;See the documentation on Issues&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;16.537102473498&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;view-kubernetes-pod-logs&quot;&gt; View Kubernetes pod logs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;badge-container dark&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;top-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CORE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STARTER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREMIUM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ULTIMATE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottom-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FREE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BRONZE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SILVER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOLD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A fundamental need for all developers is to be able to review logs in order to understand application behavior and troubleshoot any problems that arise. With GitLab 11.0, reviewing the logs of a troublesome pod is now just a click away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the &lt;strong&gt;Environments&lt;/strong&gt; page, the status of pods for each application is displayed using &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/user/project/deploy_boards.html&quot;&gt;Deploy Boards&lt;/a&gt;. Mousing over the pods will display the full pod name and status, and clicking on the pod will then display the logs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;View Kubernetes pod logs&quot; class=&quot;shadow&quot; src=&quot;https://about.gitlab.com/images/11_0/pod_logs.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/user/project/clusters/kubernetes_pod_logs.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;See the documentation on Pod Logs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;hidden-lg&quot; readability=&quot;18.254416961131&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;master-role-renamed-to-maintainer&quot;&gt; Master role renamed to Maintainer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;badge-container dark&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;top-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CORE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STARTER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREMIUM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ULTIMATE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottom-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FREE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BRONZE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SILVER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOLD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At GitLab, we are &lt;a href=&quot;https://about.gitlab.com/handbook/values/#diversity&quot;&gt;striving to build an inclusive culture&lt;/a&gt;. And so even within GitLab the product, we’re seeking ways to reflect that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve decided to rename the Master role to the Maintainer role. It removes the negative connotations that may be associated with the term “Master,” and at the same time, “Maintainer” is easily understood. Every small step helps, and we hope to move forward at GitLab, and together as an industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Master role renamed to Maintainer&quot; src=&quot;https://about.gitlab.com/images/11_0/master-to-maintainer.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/user/permissions.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;See the documentation on Permissions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;15.913402061856&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;label-lists-redesign&quot;&gt; Label lists redesign&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;badge-container dark&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;top-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CORE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STARTER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREMIUM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ULTIMATE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottom-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FREE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BRONZE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SILVER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOLD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Labels are a powerful mechanism in GitLab. As teams continue to create and use more labels, we want to ensure that managing them is easy. In this release, we’ve cleaned up the design of the label list pages, simplifying the interface, making it easier to consume information at a glance, and providing the UI affordances to quickly manage a particular label in further detail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Label lists redesign&quot; class=&quot;shadow&quot; src=&quot;https://about.gitlab.com/images/11_0/label-list-redesign.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/user/project/labels.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;See the documentation on Labels&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;hidden-lg&quot; readability=&quot;11.082969432314&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;consistent-naming-format-in-issues-api-scope-attribute&quot;&gt; Consistent naming format in issues API scope attribute&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;badge-container dark&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;top-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CORE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STARTER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREMIUM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ULTIMATE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottom-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FREE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BRONZE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SILVER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOLD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We made a small change in the issues API scope attribute to bring it in line with our consistent format of using snake case. The scope attribute now uses the values of &lt;code&gt;created_by_me&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;assigned_to_me&lt;/code&gt;. You should use this format starting in GitLab 11.0 instead of the previous kebab-case (hyphenated) equivalents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/api/issues.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;See the documentation on Issues API&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;15.097902097902&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;regex-support-for-variables-expressions&quot;&gt; Regex support for variables expressions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;badge-container dark&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;top-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CORE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STARTER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREMIUM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ULTIMATE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottom-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FREE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BRONZE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SILVER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOLD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In GitLab 10.7, we added support for variables expressions to &lt;code&gt;only&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;except&lt;/code&gt; keywords. This allowed to define if a job should be created if a variable existed or had a specific value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With GitLab 11.0, we are extending this syntax to allow regex. Now you can create more flexible definitions based on a fine-grained pattern matching against the value. For example, you can skip a job based on the commit message.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Regex support for variables expressions&quot; class=&quot;shadow&quot; src=&quot;https://about.gitlab.com/images/11_0/regex_variables.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/ci/variables/#variables-expressions&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;See the documentation on regex support for variables expressions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;hidden-lg&quot; readability=&quot;16.952095808383&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;get-gitlab-runner-ip-address-via-the-api&quot;&gt; Get GitLab Runner IP address via the API&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;badge-container dark&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;top-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CORE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STARTER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREMIUM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ULTIMATE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottom-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FREE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BRONZE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SILVER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOLD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In GitLab 10.6 we added the ability to see the IP address of a given GitLab Runner in the details view in the UI. This is very useful to better recognize, troubleshoot, and manage your infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With GitLab 11.0, we also expose this information in the API response so that it can be used by automated processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.com/lgreiss&quot;&gt;Lars Greiss&lt;/a&gt; for your contribution!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/api/runners.html#get-runner-s-details&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;See the documentation on GitLab Runner APIs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;7.5730337078652&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;gitlab-runner-110&quot;&gt; GitLab Runner 11.0&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;badge-container dark&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;top-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CORE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STARTER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREMIUM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ULTIMATE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottom-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FREE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BRONZE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SILVER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOLD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re also releasing GitLab Runner 11.0 today! GitLab Runner is the open source project that is used to run your CI/CD jobs and send the results back to GitLab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;key-changes-in-this-release-include&quot;&gt;Key changes in this release include:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The list of all changes can be found in GitLab Runner’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.com/gitlab-org/gitlab-runner/blob/v11.0.0/CHANGELOG.md&quot;&gt;CHANGELOG&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/runner&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;See the documentation on GitLab Runner&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;hidden-lg&quot; readability=&quot;14.771653543307&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;improved-deprecated-configuration-detection&quot;&gt; Improved deprecated configuration detection&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;badge-container dark&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;top-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CORE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STARTER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREMIUM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ULTIMATE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottom-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FREE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BRONZE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SILVER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOLD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting from GitLab 11.0, the Omnibus GitLab package will check for deprecated configuration in &lt;code&gt;gitlab.rb&lt;/code&gt;, prior to starting an upgrade. In the event deprecated configuration settings are found, the package will abort the upgrade process prior to any changes. This allows the existing version to continue to run, while an administrator updates the problematic settings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/omnibus/README.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;See the documentation on Omnibus GitLab&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;3.2242225859247&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;geo-improvements&quot;&gt; Geo improvements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;badge-container dark&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;top-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CORE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STARTER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREMIUM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ULTIMATE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottom-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FREE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BRONZE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SILVER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOLD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We continously improve our Geo feature for distributed teams. Some of the noteworthy improvements in GitLab 11.0 include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/administration/geo/replication/configuration.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;See the documentation on Geo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;hidden-lg&quot; readability=&quot;23.606557377049&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;project-specific-pipeline-id&quot;&gt; Project-specific pipeline ID&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;badge-container dark&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;top-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CORE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STARTER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREMIUM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ULTIMATE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottom-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FREE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BRONZE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SILVER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOLD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When running CI/CD jobs for your project, sometimes you need a way to differentiate one execution from another. For this scope, you need a unique identifier that changes every time a new pipeline is created. This feature was already available through the &lt;code&gt;CI_PIPELINE_ID&lt;/code&gt; environment variable, but this counter is unique for the entire GitLab instance and so it grows very fast, creating possible problems with long numbers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In GitLab 11.0 we are introducing another environment variable, &lt;code&gt;CI_PIPELINE_IID&lt;/code&gt;, that contains a reference that is specific to the project. It means that it is incremented only when another run for the same project is created, keeping the value low and allowing developers to use it as part of the release process, for example as part of the version number.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/ci/variables/#predefined-variables-environment-variables&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;See the documentation on predefined CI/CD variables&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;5.9990205680705&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;omnibus-improvements&quot;&gt; Omnibus improvements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;badge-container dark&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;top-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CORE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STARTER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREMIUM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ULTIMATE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottom-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FREE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BRONZE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SILVER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOLD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;GitLab 11.0 includes &lt;a href=&quot;https://about.mattermost.com/releases/mattermost-4-10/&quot;&gt;Mattermost 4.10&lt;/a&gt;, an &lt;a href=&quot;https://about.mattermost.com/&quot;&gt;open source Slack-alternative&lt;/a&gt; whose newest release includes Environment Variables Support in GitLab Omnibus, faster load times, ability to convert channels to private, plus much more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added a new flag, &lt;code&gt;master_on_initialization&lt;/code&gt;, to control if a database node should report it itself as master. This flag should be disabled on secondaries.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prometheus &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/omnibus/settings/prometheus.html#rules-files&quot;&gt;rules can now be configured&lt;/a&gt;, providing the ability to add your own recording or alerting rules to the embedded Prometheus server.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/administration/monitoring/prometheus/pgbouncer_exporter.html&quot;&gt;PgBouncer exporter&lt;/a&gt; has now been added, providing insight into its health and operation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;ruby&lt;/code&gt; has been updated to 2.4.4. &lt;code&gt;git&lt;/code&gt; has been updated to 2.17.1. &lt;code&gt;libpcre&lt;/code&gt; has been updated to 10.31. &lt;code&gt;PgBouncer&lt;/code&gt; has been updated to 1.8.1.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let’s Encrypt support has been added for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/omnibus/settings/ssl.html#registry&quot;&gt;Registry&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/omnibus/settings/ssl.html#mattermost&quot;&gt;Mattermost&lt;/a&gt;. When new certificates are requested, these hostnames will be added to the certificate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/omnibus/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;See the documentation on Omnibus GitLab&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;96.229723565368&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;visible-lg&quot; readability=&quot;13.651515151515&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;open-projects-in-xcode&quot;&gt; Open projects in Xcode&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;badge-container dark&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;top-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CORE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STARTER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREMIUM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ULTIMATE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottom-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FREE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BRONZE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SILVER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOLD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At WWDC earlier this month, &lt;a href=&quot;https://about.gitlab.com/2018/06/06/one-click-clone-to-xcode/&quot;&gt;Apple announced their Xcode integration with GitLab&lt;/a&gt;, which makes it easier to work with your Xcode projects hosted in GitLab.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Projects that contain a &lt;code&gt;.xcodeproj&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;.xcworkspace&lt;/code&gt; file can now be cloned in Xcode using the new Open in Xcode button in GitLab. When viewing Xcode projects in the GitLab interface, the button will be available in GitLab next to the Git URL for cloning your project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Open projects in Xcode&quot; class=&quot;shadow&quot; src=&quot;https://about.gitlab.com/images/11_0/open_in_xcode.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/user/project/repository/index.html#open-in-xcode&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;See the documentation on opening in Xcode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;visible-lg&quot; readability=&quot;21.740547588005&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;unlimited-guests-for-free-in-ultimate&quot;&gt; Unlimited Guests for free in Ultimate&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;badge-container dark&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;top-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CORE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STARTER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREMIUM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ULTIMATE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottom-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FREE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BRONZE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SILVER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOLD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to help customers get the most from their GitLab instances, Guest users no longer count against seat count for Ultimate licenses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since these users no longer consume seats (they’re effectively free to add), it gives more users in an organization the chance to join the instance and contribute to the conversation. You’re free to promote these users, but they’ll count against your license’s seat count once they’re promoted beyond Guest in any project or group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This also means that if a user logs in and is never added to a project/group, they have no role applied, therefore they are considered as ‘Guests.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/user/permissions.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;See the documentation on guest permissions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;visible-lg&quot; readability=&quot;22.971848225214&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;assign-ancestor-group-milestones&quot;&gt; Assign ancestor group milestones&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;badge-container dark&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;top-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CORE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STARTER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREMIUM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ULTIMATE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottom-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FREE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BRONZE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SILVER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOLD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GitLab supports subgroups, and we have now leveraged that subgrouping structure for milestones. For any issue or merge request, you can now assign it a project milestone or a group milestone inherited from &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; ancestor group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In particular, you can now have a high-level group with a set of milestones at that level. You can then use those &lt;em&gt;same&lt;/em&gt; milestones in any issues and merge requests in any subgroups deeper down, providing a powerful and flexible mechanism to organize work if you have nested groups and projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, you can filter by this milestone in group issue lists and group issue boards, so that you can pull in targeted objects from different levels in customized views.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Assign ancestor group milestones&quot; src=&quot;https://about.gitlab.com/images/11_0/assign-ancestor-group-milestones.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/user/project/milestones/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;See the documentation on Milestones&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;visible-lg&quot; readability=&quot;18.325581395349&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;persistent-auto-devops-deploy-tokens-for-kubernetes&quot;&gt; Persistent Auto DevOps deploy tokens for Kubernetes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;badge-container dark&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;top-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CORE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STARTER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREMIUM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ULTIMATE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottom-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FREE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BRONZE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SILVER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOLD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previously, when Auto DevOps was used for private or internal projects, the registry was not accessible by Kubernetes after the deploy job completed. This prevented the cluster from fetching the image again (for scaling, failures, etc).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With GitLab 11.0, a new deploy token is created to provide persistent access to the registry when Auto DevOps is enabled on private/internal projects. This will ensure that the cluster can perform necessary operations and reduce possible failures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/topics/autodevops/#auto-deploy&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;See the documentation on deploy tokens for Auto DevOps&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;visible-lg&quot; readability=&quot;16.227848101266&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;variables-defining-deployment-policy-for-canary-environments&quot;&gt; Variables defining deployment policy for canary environments&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;badge-container dark&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;top-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CORE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STARTER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREMIUM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ULTIMATE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottom-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FREE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BRONZE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SILVER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOLD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oftentimes we’d like to roll out changes to a subset of users or servers to evaluate its impact before deploying across an entire environment. Previously, Auto DevOps users had to make the Auto DevOps template explicit and then define the desired behavior in order to achieve canary deployments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting with GitLab 11.0, users are able to define their canary policy by making use of the &lt;code&gt;CANARY_ENABLED&lt;/code&gt; environment variable without the need to customize the Auto DevOps template, enabling faster canary policy declaration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/topics/autodevops/#deploy-policy-for-canary-environments&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;See the documentation on the deployment policy for canary environments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;visible-lg&quot; readability=&quot;14.965573770492&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;fetch-cluster-parameters-from-gke&quot;&gt; Fetch cluster parameters from GKE&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;badge-container dark&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;top-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CORE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STARTER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREMIUM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ULTIMATE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottom-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FREE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BRONZE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SILVER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOLD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creating Kubernetes clusters in GitLab has never been easier. With GitLab 11.0, the “project” and “zones” values are automatically fetched from your Google Kubernetes Engine (GKE) account and displayed as a list for easy selection. Previously, creating a cluster using our GKE integration meant having to manually enter this data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simple cluster creation will allow you to quickly stand up clusters from GitLab and quickly deploy your apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Fetch cluster parameters from GKE&quot; class=&quot;shadow&quot; src=&quot;https://about.gitlab.com/images/11_0/fetch-gke-parameters.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/user/project/clusters/#adding-and-creating-a-new-gke-cluster-via-gitlab&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;See the documentation on Adding and creating a new GKE cluster via GitLab&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;visible-lg&quot; readability=&quot;16.282442748092&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;lfs-files-included-when-importing-a-project&quot;&gt; LFS files included when importing a project&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;badge-container dark&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;top-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CORE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STARTER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREMIUM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ULTIMATE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottom-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FREE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BRONZE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SILVER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOLD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/workflow/lfs/manage_large_binaries_with_git_lfs.html&quot;&gt;Git LFS&lt;/a&gt; helps to version large files with Git by storing them outside the repository and lazily downloading files at checkout rather than clone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When importing a project from GitHub, Bitbucket Cloud, or using a Git URL, GitLab now imports LFS objects so that you have a complete copy of the repository including those LFS objects. Previously, LFS objects were excluded from imports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/user/project/import/index.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;See the documentation on importing projects&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;visible-lg&quot; readability=&quot;17.052631578947&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;sast-for-net-and-scala&quot;&gt; SAST for .NET and Scala&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;badge-container dark&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;top-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CORE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STARTER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREMIUM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ULTIMATE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottom-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FREE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BRONZE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SILVER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOLD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of our effort to increase the availability of our security tools to the most common languages and frameworks, we have been continuously iterating on Static Application Security Testing (SAST).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In GitLab 11.0, we add support for two new languages, .NET and Scala. Users don’t need to change anything in their projects if they are already using Auto DevOps or the latest version of the &lt;code&gt;sast&lt;/code&gt; job definition in their &lt;code&gt;.gitlab-ci.yml&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/user/project/merge_requests/sast.html#supported-languages-and-frameworks&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;See the documentation on SAST&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;visible-lg&quot; readability=&quot;17.89349112426&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;easily-deploy-and-integrate-jupyterhub-with-gitlab&quot;&gt; Easily deploy and integrate JupyterHub with GitLab&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;badge-container dark&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;top-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CORE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STARTER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREMIUM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ULTIMATE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottom-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FREE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BRONZE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SILVER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOLD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://jupyterhub.readthedocs.io/en/stable/&quot;&gt;JupyterHub&lt;/a&gt; is a multi-user service for easily launching &lt;a href=&quot;https://jupyter-notebook.readthedocs.io/en/latest/&quot;&gt;notebooks&lt;/a&gt; across a data science team. Jupyter notebooks provide a web-based interactive programming environment commonly used for data analysis, simulation, visualization, and machine learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GitLab 11.0 can now deploy JupyterHub to an integrated Kubernetes cluster with a single click, and it is automatically configured to use GitLab for seamless authentication. Additional options like &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.com/gitlab-org/gitlab-ce/issues/47137&quot;&gt;HTTPS&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.com/gitlab-org/gitlab-ce/issues/47820&quot;&gt;group filtering&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.com/gitlab-org/gitlab-ce/issues/48236&quot;&gt;custom notebooks&lt;/a&gt; will be added in future releases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Easily deploy and integrate JupyterHub with GitLab&quot; class=&quot;shadow&quot; src=&quot;https://about.gitlab.com/images/11_0/jupyterhub.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/user/project/clusters/#installing-applications&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;See the documentation on deploying JupyterHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;visible-lg&quot; readability=&quot;20.243902439024&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;combined-system-note-for-successive-issue-description-updates&quot;&gt; Combined system note for successive issue description updates&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;badge-container dark&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;top-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CORE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STARTER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREMIUM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ULTIMATE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottom-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FREE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BRONZE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SILVER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOLD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GitLab allows for powerful asynchronous collaboration and communication. With the ability to document ideas and have conversations in so many places, we encourage always maintaining a single source of truth in the description area of an issue or epic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This means that descriptions are often updated, many times in succession over a few minutes, leading to multiple system notes that say that the description has been updated. With this release, we are smartly combining those system notes if they happen within a short period of time, cleaning up the visual clutter and making comments in GitLab just a little bit easier to navigate. We’ll be adding the same functionality to merge requests in the next release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Combined system note for successive issue description updates&quot; class=&quot;shadow&quot; src=&quot;https://about.gitlab.com/images/11_0/combined-system-note.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/user/project/issues/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;See the documentation on Issues&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;visible-lg&quot; readability=&quot;18.254416961131&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;master-role-renamed-to-maintainer&quot;&gt; Master role renamed to Maintainer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;badge-container dark&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;top-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CORE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STARTER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREMIUM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ULTIMATE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottom-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FREE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BRONZE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SILVER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOLD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At GitLab, we are &lt;a href=&quot;https://about.gitlab.com/handbook/values/#diversity&quot;&gt;striving to build an inclusive culture&lt;/a&gt;. And so even within GitLab the product, we’re seeking ways to reflect that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve decided to rename the Master role to the Maintainer role. It removes the negative connotations that may be associated with the term “Master,” and at the same time, “Maintainer” is easily understood. Every small step helps, and we hope to move forward at GitLab, and together as an industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Master role renamed to Maintainer&quot; src=&quot;https://about.gitlab.com/images/11_0/master-to-maintainer.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/user/permissions.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;See the documentation on Permissions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;visible-lg&quot; readability=&quot;11.082969432314&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;consistent-naming-format-in-issues-api-scope-attribute&quot;&gt; Consistent naming format in issues API scope attribute&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;badge-container dark&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;top-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CORE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STARTER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREMIUM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ULTIMATE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottom-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FREE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BRONZE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SILVER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOLD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We made a small change in the issues API scope attribute to bring it in line with our consistent format of using snake case. The scope attribute now uses the values of &lt;code&gt;created_by_me&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;assigned_to_me&lt;/code&gt;. You should use this format starting in GitLab 11.0 instead of the previous kebab-case (hyphenated) equivalents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/api/issues.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;See the documentation on Issues API&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;visible-lg&quot; readability=&quot;16.952095808383&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;get-gitlab-runner-ip-address-via-the-api&quot;&gt; Get GitLab Runner IP address via the API&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;badge-container dark&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;top-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CORE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STARTER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREMIUM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ULTIMATE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottom-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FREE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BRONZE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SILVER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOLD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In GitLab 10.6 we added the ability to see the IP address of a given GitLab Runner in the details view in the UI. This is very useful to better recognize, troubleshoot, and manage your infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With GitLab 11.0, we also expose this information in the API response so that it can be used by automated processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.com/lgreiss&quot;&gt;Lars Greiss&lt;/a&gt; for your contribution!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/api/runners.html#get-runner-s-details&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;See the documentation on GitLab Runner APIs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;visible-lg&quot; readability=&quot;14.771653543307&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;improved-deprecated-configuration-detection&quot;&gt; Improved deprecated configuration detection&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;badge-container dark&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;top-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CORE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STARTER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREMIUM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ULTIMATE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottom-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FREE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BRONZE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SILVER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOLD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting from GitLab 11.0, the Omnibus GitLab package will check for deprecated configuration in &lt;code&gt;gitlab.rb&lt;/code&gt;, prior to starting an upgrade. In the event deprecated configuration settings are found, the package will abort the upgrade process prior to any changes. This allows the existing version to continue to run, while an administrator updates the problematic settings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/omnibus/README.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;See the documentation on Omnibus GitLab&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;visible-lg&quot; readability=&quot;23.606557377049&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;project-specific-pipeline-id&quot;&gt; Project-specific pipeline ID&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;badge-container dark&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;top-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CORE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STARTER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PREMIUM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ULTIMATE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottom-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FREE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BRONZE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SILVER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOLD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When running CI/CD jobs for your project, sometimes you need a way to differentiate one execution from another. For this scope, you need a unique identifier that changes every time a new pipeline is created. This feature was already available through the &lt;code&gt;CI_PIPELINE_ID&lt;/code&gt; environment variable, but this counter is unique for the entire GitLab instance and so it grows very fast, creating possible problems with long numbers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In GitLab 11.0 we are introducing another environment variable, &lt;code&gt;CI_PIPELINE_IID&lt;/code&gt;, that contains a reference that is specific to the project. It means that it is incremented only when another run for the same project is created, keeping the value low and allowing developers to use it as part of the release process, for example as part of the version number.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/ci/variables/#predefined-variables-environment-variables&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;See the documentation on predefined CI/CD variables&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2018 03:10:11 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>markdog12</dc:creator>
<og:title>GitLab 11.0 released with Auto DevOps and License Management</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://about.gitlab.com/2018/06/22/gitlab-11-0-released/</og:url>
<og:image>https://about.gitlab.com/images/tweets/gitlab-11-0-released.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://about.gitlab.com/2018/06/22/gitlab-11-0-released/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ask HN: Have you shipped anything serious with a “serverless” architecture?</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17378749</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17378749</guid>
<description>&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.55737704918033&quot;&gt;&lt;td bgcolor=&quot;#FF6600&quot;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;12.370953630796&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table class=&quot;fatitem&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;7.9527559055118&quot;&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing&quot; id=&quot;17378749&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;right&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;title&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17378749&quot; class=&quot;storylink&quot;&gt;Ask HN: Have you shipped anything serious with a “serverless” architecture?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.71428571428571&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;subtext&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;score&quot; id=&quot;score_17378749&quot;&gt;292 points&lt;/span&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/user?id=freedomben&quot; class=&quot;hnuser&quot;&gt;freedomben&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;age&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17378749&quot;&gt;23 hours ago&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span id=&quot;unv_17378749&quot;/&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/hide?id=17378749&amp;amp;goto=item%3Fid%3D17378749&quot;&gt;hide&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://hn.algolia.com/?query=Ask%20HN%3A%20Have%20you%20shipped%20anything%20serious%20with%20a%20%E2%80%9Cserverless%E2%80%9D%20architecture%3F&amp;amp;sort=byDate&amp;amp;dateRange=all&amp;amp;type=story&amp;amp;storyText=false&amp;amp;prefix&amp;amp;page=0&quot; class=&quot;hnpast&quot;&gt;past&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=Ask%20HN%3A%20Have%20you%20shipped%20anything%20serious%20with%20a%20%E2%80%9Cserverless%E2%80%9D%20architecture%3F&quot;&gt;web&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/fave?id=17378749&amp;amp;auth=bebbb888afa41ac683a6b6140d9c7a7a16048d41&quot;&gt;favorite&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17378749&quot;&gt;181 comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;21&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;17&quot;&gt;I've been watching the rise and maturing of AWS lambda and similar offerings with excitement. I've also shipped several microservices in both node and Java that are entirely serverless, making use of API gateway, lambda, dynamo db, sqs, kinesis, and others.
&lt;p&gt;For the simple case, I found the experience to be great. Deployment was simple and made use of shell scripts and the excellent AWS CLI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been hesitant to build anything serious with it tho. The primary concern has been visibility into the app. The app's operation can be quite opaque when deployed that way. Further exacerbating the issue, we've a few times lost Cloudwatch logs and other reporting due to both configuration issues and improper error handling, but these are things that would have been much easier to identify and diagnose on a real server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you shipped anything serious with a serverless architecture? Has scaling and cost been favorable? Did you run into any challenges? Would you do it again?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td&gt;

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;yclinks&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/newsguidelines.html&quot;&gt;Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/newsfaq.html&quot;&gt;FAQ&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:hn@ycombinator.com&quot;&gt;Support&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/HackerNews/API&quot;&gt;API&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/security.html&quot;&gt;Security&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/lists&quot;&gt;Lists&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/bookmarklet.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Bookmarklet&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ycombinator.com/legal/&quot;&gt;Legal&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ycombinator.com/apply/&quot;&gt;Apply to YC&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:hn@ycombinator.com&quot;&gt;Contact&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2018 00:51:37 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>freedomben</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17378749</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>A sad update about a scissors maker that went viral</title>
<link>https://kottke.org/18/06/a-sad-update-about-a-scissors-maker-that-went-viral</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://kottke.org/18/06/a-sad-update-about-a-scissors-maker-that-went-viral</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Back in 2014, &lt;a href=&quot;https://kottke.org/14/07/the-putter-togetherer&quot;&gt;a lovely short film by Shaun Bloodworth called The Putter&lt;/a&gt; went viral. The film shows Cliff Denton making scissors for Ernest Wright &amp;amp; Sons. Denton works for the company as a putter, short for putter togetherer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;widescreen embedded&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/98953952&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before the film, business at the firm was so slow that staff were only working two days a week. When the video took off online, the company received two years’ worth of orders in a single day. Two years later in June 2016, the company launched &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/scissors/ernest-wright-and-son-ltd-scissors-hand-made-in-sh&quot;&gt;a Kickstarter campaign for a throwback pair of kitchen scissors&lt;/a&gt; and ended up making four times their goal from more than 3600 backers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outwardly, this seemed to be one of those stories about how an old school company found a new audience and a second chance on the internet. But internally &lt;a href=&quot;https://theworldnews.net/gb-news/made-in-sheffield-scissor-firm-battles-back-after-boss-dies&quot;&gt;the company was struggling&lt;/a&gt;, hamstrung by a series of setbacks. Problems with design and machining the new scissors model delayed production for a year and two key employees, including putter Cliff Denton, were off the job due to illness. Shaun Bloodworth, the filmmaker, died waiting for a liver transplant. And then in February 2018, the news broke that Nick Wright, the company’s managing director, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thestar.co.uk/business/tributes-as-historic-sheffield-scissor-company-boss-dies-1-9007171&quot;&gt;had died suddenly&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under new leadership, the company vowed to carry on and fulfill all of the Kickstarter orders, but a message to Kickstarter backers yesterday revealed the company was deep in debt and would be “going into receivership”. It also revealed that Wright had taken his own life. Here’s the full message from Pam Addy, the current managing director of Ernest Wright &amp;amp; Sons. (Note: this includes a portion of a final letter written by Wright before he died.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;31&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone, this is Pam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the death of Nick Wright, who took his own life in February, myself and the rest of the Ernest Wright team have endeavored to honour all you Kickstarter backers who pledged money for the Kutrite design of kitchen scissors. Unfortunately, only now am I aware of the extent of the business debt incurred prior to my taking over as Director on March 22 2018, so it is with great sadness I announce that Ernest Wright &amp;amp; Son Ltd will be going into receivership.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have not received your goods, you will be contacted by the Insolvency Practitioner in due course. Following advice from them, if you paid by Credit Card you may wish to contact your card provider, to see whether they will refund you the money paid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nick wrote a final letter. In this letter were personal messages including one to Kickstarter people:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I tried so hard, this was no scam, I just could not make it happen. Too much pressure, not enough resource or time. I am so very genuinely sorry to you all.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What a sad situation for Wright’s family and the company. It’s tempting to want to draw conclusions between the finances, the campaign, and Wright’s death, but we don’t actually know much about the situation. But I do think this highlights the potential disconnects between mental health &amp;amp; business, publicity &amp;amp; success, and success &amp;amp; happiness. The internet can seem so intimate but ultimately it’s a thin view of an individual’s or company’s reality. (thx, dawn)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More about...&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2018 00:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>zdw</dc:creator>
<og:title>A sad update about a scissors maker that went viral</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://kottke.org/18/06/a-sad-update-about-a-scissors-maker-that-went-viral</og:url>
<og:image></og:image>
<og:description>Back in 2014, a lovely short film by Shaun Bloodworth called The Putter went viral. The film shows Cliff Denton making scissors fo</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://kottke.org/18/06/a-sad-update-about-a-scissors-maker-that-went-viral</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Keyboard Service Program for MacBook and MacBook Pro</title>
<link>https://www.apple.com/support/keyboard-service-program-for-macbook-and-macbook-pro/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.apple.com/support/keyboard-service-program-for-macbook-and-macbook-pro/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Apple has determined that a small percentage of the keyboards in certain MacBook and MacBook Pro models may exhibit one or more of the following behaviors:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;square&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;Letters or characters repeat unexpectedly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Letters or characters do not appear&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Key(s) feel &quot;sticky&quot; or do not respond in a consistent manner&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Apple or an Apple Authorized Service Provider will service eligible MacBook and MacBook Pro keyboards, free of charge. The type of service will be determined after the keyboard is examined and may involve the replacement of one or more keys or the whole keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Eligible Models&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To identify your computer's model and to see if it is eligible for this program, choose Apple () menu &amp;gt; About This Mac. Eligible models are listed below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;square&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;MacBook (Retina, 12-­inch, Early 2015)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MacBook (Retina, 12­-inch, Early 2016)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MacBook (Retina, 12-­inch, 2017)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MacBook Pro (13­-inch, 2016, Two Thunderbolt 3 Ports)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MacBook Pro (13-­inch, 2017, Two Thunderbolt 3 Ports)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MacBook Pro (13-­inch, 2016, Four Thunderbolt 3 Ports)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MacBook Pro (13-­inch, 2017, Four Thunderbolt 3 Ports)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MacBook Pro (15-­inch, 2016)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MacBook Pro (15-­inch, 2017)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Note: No other Mac notebook models are part of this program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Service Process&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please choose one of the options below for service. Your MacBook or MacBook Pro will be examined prior to any service to verify that it is eligible for this program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The type of service will be determined after the keyboard is examined and may involve the replacement of one or more keys or the whole keyboard. The service turn-around time may vary depending upon the type of service and availability of replacement parts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To prepare your unit for service, please &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.apple.com/mac-backup&quot;&gt;backup your data&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: If your MacBook or MacBook Pro has any damage which impairs the service, that issue will need to be repaired first. In some cases, there may be a cost associated with the repair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Additional Information&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This worldwide Apple program does not extend the standard warranty coverage of your MacBook or MacBook Pro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you believe your MacBook or MacBook Pro was affected by this issue, and you paid to have your keyboard repaired, you can &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/support/keyboard-service-program-for-macbook-and-macbook-pro/#cas,prkeys:PF2,cid:SC0998,sid:99980&quot;&gt;contact Apple about a refund&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The program covers eligible MacBook and MacBook Pro models for 4 years after the first retail sale of the unit.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2018 21:05:45 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>minimaxir</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.apple.com/support/keyboard-service-program-for-macbook-and-macbook-pro/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>IRC.com Bought by London Trust Media, Pledges an IRC Revival</title>
<link>https://irc.com</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://irc.com</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;What if I told you, there is a world that values you - for your thoughts, your opinions and who you are?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There is.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's a beautiful world, and for me, more importantly, it is the world that I have to thank for its consequence of keeping me alive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A score ago, I took my first steps into IRC. On cin.il.us.DAL.net, I connected to IRC and somehow found myself in a random IRC channel without any participants. Out of the blue, some random person must have typed /list and found the channel and joined out of curiosity. However it happened, this person who I will never know, spent an hour teaching me how to use IRC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a minority growing up in the middle of America, racism was a thing, and it would be a lie if I said that I never shed a tear over this. In this turbulent world, where but few genes dictate our outer appearance, and chimpanzees share 99% of the same DNA as us, somehow, we're only focused on what our &lt;strong&gt;eyes are see&lt;/strong&gt;ing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On IRC, on the other hand, I was accepted, listened to, and spoken to. IRC adopted me. IRC accepted me. And above all, IRC befriended me, without hesitation. I have met many friends on IRC.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I joined teams, from DALnet help teams to anime fansubbing groups. I was taught how to code. I learned so many different points of views.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IRC truly grew me as a person.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, I'm strong. Today, I'm confident. Today, I am social.&lt;br /&gt;Today, I am patient. Today, I am accepting. Today, I have a cause.&lt;br /&gt;This would not be the case, if yesterday, for me, was not IRC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will do unto others as I would like done to myself. IRC created me. And for this reason, I pledge to revive IRC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IRC, is a transcended level of humanity, that values you for all the other genes and experiences that make you, you - unlike the &quot;real&quot; world which is utterly focused on nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When people tell you, it's what's on the inside that counts, they are telling you to get into IRC. It's a world, that values you, for you. Putting our money where our mouths are, through London Trust Media Holdings and myself, funding, sponsorships, and other contributions have been and will continue to be provided to IRC clients like KiwiIRC and weechat, IRC networks like freenode, snoonet, DALnet, and EuropNet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, I'd like to introduce a few new projects that we are soon launching alongside notable IRC communities:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;IRC.com (A professional, friendly network for huge communities)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IRC University - Free Education for the World (Seeking top expert Ph. D professors to teach - &lt;a href=&quot;https://irc.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#2c44494040436c455e4f024f4341&quot;&gt;email us!&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IRC Gaming (We're going to have literally hundreds of thousands in cash prizes!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IRC Ventures (VC/Incubation on IRC!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IRC Foundation (Donating and supporting existing great IRC projects!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Providing IRC bouncer (always on connectivity) support to all IRC networks and keeping it open!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;In other words, IRC is here, and IRC is &lt;strong&gt;backed&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yours truly,&lt;br /&gt;Andrew Lee&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Co-founder, &lt;a href=&quot;https://londontrustmedia.com/&quot;&gt;London Trust Media Holdings&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2018 17:39:58 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>metabrew</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://irc.com/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Supreme Court Rules Police Need Warrant to Track Your Cellphone</title>
<link>https://www.npr.org/2018/06/22/605007387/supreme-court-rules-police-need-warrant-to-get-location-information-from-cell-to</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.npr.org/2018/06/22/605007387/supreme-court-rules-police-need-warrant-to-get-location-information-from-cell-to</guid>
<description>&lt;div id=&quot;res622546002&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap image large&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;imagewrap&quot; data-crop-type=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2018/06/22/ap_17326610471272_wide-066f86346e1f329dee0cedd309f13a38b92a1e8c-s1100-c15.jpg&quot; data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2018/06/22/ap_17326610471272_wide-066f86346e1f329dee0cedd309f13a38b92a1e8c-s1100.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img lazyOnLoad&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;credit-caption&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-wrap&quot; readability=&quot;6.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image caption&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The U.S. Supreme Court ruled that police need a warrant to obtain cellphone location information routinely collected by wireless providers. &lt;strong class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Carolyn Kaster/AP&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong class=&quot;hide-caption&quot;&gt;hide caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;strong class=&quot;toggle-caption&quot;&gt;toggle caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Carolyn Kaster/AP&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;enlarge_measure&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img_wrap&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2018/06/22/ap_17326610471272_wide-066f86346e1f329dee0cedd309f13a38b92a1e8c-s1200.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;enlarge_html&quot; readability=&quot;6.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image_data&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;The U.S. Supreme Court ruled that police need a warrant to obtain cellphone location information routinely collected by wireless providers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Carolyn Kaster/AP&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Updated at 5:32 p.m. ET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a landmark decision, the U.S. Supreme Court ruled Friday that police must obtain a search warrant to access an individual's cellphone location information. The 5-4 decision imposes new limits on law enforcement's ability to get at the increasing amount of data that private companies amass in the modern technological age.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cellphone providers routinely keep location information for customers to help improve service. And until now, the prevailing legal theory was that if an individual voluntarily shares his information with a third party — for instance, by signing up for cellphone service — police can get that information without a search warrant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A near-perfect tool&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;res622546977&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap internallink insettwocolumn inset2col&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bucket img&quot;&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;featuredStackSquareImage567348000&quot; href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/2017/11/29/567348000/justices-may-impose-new-limits-on-government-access-to-cellphone-data&quot; data-metrics=&quot;{&amp;quot;category&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Story to Story&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;action&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Click Internal Link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;label&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https:\/\/www.npr.org\/2017\/11\/29\/567348000\/justices-may-impose-new-limits-on-government-access-to-cellphone-data&amp;quot;}&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2017/11/29/gettyimages-881766280_sq-24171dff41a0ba50ea93e7ae463e7d53b0bd69e0-s100-c15.jpg&quot; data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2017/11/29/gettyimages-881766280_sq-24171dff41a0ba50ea93e7ae463e7d53b0bd69e0-s100.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img lazyOnLoad&quot; alt=&quot;Justices May Impose New Limits On Government Access To Cellphone Data&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Friday, the Supreme Court blew a hole in that theory. Writing for the court majority, Chief Justice John Roberts said that cellphone location information is a &quot;near perfect&quot; tool for government surveillance, analogous to an electronic monitoring ankle bracelet. The writers of the Constitution, he said, would certainly have understood that an individual has a privacy interest in the day-to-day, hour-to-hour and even minute-to-minute records of his whereabouts — a privacy interest that requires the government to get a search warrant before gaining access to that information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case before the court was brought by Timothy Carpenter, prosecuted as a ringleader in a series of armed robberies in Michigan and Ohio. Cell tower information placed him at the robbery sites, and this information became damning evidence at his trial. Carpenter appealed his conviction, contending that police unconstitutionally invaded his privacy without getting a search warrant first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id=&quot;ad-backstage-wrap&quot; aria-label=&quot;advertisement&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Supreme Court agreed on Friday, declaring that the routine court order that police obtained in Carpenter's case required only a showing that police were seeking relevant information. A search warrant requires that police meet a far higher standard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&quot;Big Brother is coming&quot;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Big Brother is coming and we need to stop it. That seems to be the big takeaway from the opinion,&quot; said Orin Kerr, Fourth Amendment scholar at the University of Southern California. &quot;It almost reflects an anxiety about technology thwarting privacy. If we don't stop the government here, what will they be able to do?&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;This is a landmark privacy case,&quot; said Jameel Jaffer, director of the Knight First Amendment Institute at Columbia University. &quot;It's also a very significant case for First Amendment freedoms — that is, for the freedoms of speech and the press and association. A government that can track your every movement without a warrant is a government that can freely monitor activist political associations, or monitor government employees' contacts with the press.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Jaffer conceded that the decision poses practical problems. &quot;It's going to be hard to apply this framework to new facts,&quot; he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Protecting privacy from progress&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chief Justice Roberts cast the decision as a narrow one. He said it does not disturb &quot;the routine use&quot; of subpoenas to obtain financial, bank and other business records, nor does it prevent police from obtaining cell location records without a warrant in emergency circumstances, such as when police are faced with a fleeing suspect, a kidnapping or threats of imminent danger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roberts also said Friday's decision does not call into question the use of security cameras and other techniques, and it &quot;does not consider other collection techniques involving foreign affairs and national security.&quot; What it does do, he said, is &quot;ensure that the progress of science does not erode the Fourth Amendment&quot; guarantee of privacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roberts, a conservative, was joined in the majority by liberal justices Ruth Bader Ginsburg, Stephen Breyer, Sonia Sotomayor and Elena Kagan. The court's four other conservative justices — Anthony Kennedy, Clarence Thomas, Samuel Alito and Neil Gorsuch — adamantly dissented, each writing separately to indicate his strong disagreement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&quot;A blizzard of litigation&quot;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kennedy's dissent noted that &quot;cell site records are created, kept, owned and controlled by cellphone service providers, who even sell this information to third parties.&quot; Therefore, he said, Carpenter cannot claim ownership or possession of the records and has no control over them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alito chimed in even more strongly. &quot;The Court's reasoning fractures two fundamental pillars of Fourth Amendment law, and in doing so, it guarantees a blizzard of litigation while threatening many legitimate and valuable investigative practices upon which law enforcement has rightfully come to rely,&quot; he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He called the majority decision &quot;mystifying&quot; and &quot;puzzling,&quot; and he noted that service providers routinely charge cellphone users a fee to inspect their own records. &quot;It would be very strange if the owner of the records were required to pay in order to inspect his own property,&quot; Alito said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thomas said that the case should turn not on whether a search occurred but on whose property was searched, and &quot;the Fourth Amendment guarantees individuals the right to be secure from searches of their persons, houses, papers and effects.&quot; Here, he said, the records don't belong to Carpenter but rather to the service provider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gorsuch put forth an entirely different argument that no other member of the court embraced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;An open box&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ed McAndrew, a former federal cybercrime prosecutor, agreed with some of the dissenters' concerns. He noted that cell location information is often gathered in the early stages of an investigation when there isn't enough information for a search warrant. The same is true in terrorism and national security investigations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;The national security context is only going to be different if we're dealing with foreign nationals,&quot; McAndrew said. &quot;If we're dealing with American citizens, the Fourth Amendment principle is going to apply.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, cellphone data are more reliable than more traditional sources of information, he said. &quot;[Data] are better witnesses than human beings ... who may be biased, may be uncooperative, may have a faulty memory.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Justice Breyer, who joined Friday's majority opinion, may have foreseen some of these problems at oral argument. &quot;This is an open box,&quot; he said. &quot;We know not where we go.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Friday's decision may limit the government's access to cellphone data, it has no impact on the ability of private companies to amass, use and sell their customers' information. That is because the Fourth Amendment only limits government conduct, not private conduct. Only Congress, in enacting legislation, can limit how private companies amass and use information.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2018 14:58:51 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>gok</dc:creator>
<og:title>In Major Privacy Win, Supreme Court Rules Police Need Warrant To Track Your Cellphone</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.npr.org/2018/06/22/605007387/supreme-court-rules-police-need-warrant-to-get-location-information-from-cell-to</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>The sharply divided justices ruled that police need a search warrant to obtain cellphone location data.</og:description>
<og:image>https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2018/06/22/ap_17326610471272_wide-066f86346e1f329dee0cedd309f13a38b92a1e8c.jpg?s=1400</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.npr.org/2018/06/22/605007387/supreme-court-rules-police-need-warrant-to-get-location-information-from-cell-to</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>