<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>AMD Ryzen 3000 announced</title>
<link>https://www.anandtech.com/show/14407/amd-ryzen-3000-announced-five-cpus-12-cores-for-499-up-to-46-ghz-pcie-40-coming-77</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.anandtech.com/show/14407/amd-ryzen-3000-announced-five-cpus-12-cores-for-499-up-to-46-ghz-pcie-40-coming-77</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Today at Computex, AMD CEO Dr. Lisa Su is announcing the raft of processors it will be launching on its new Zen 2 chiplet-based microarchitecture. Among other things, AMD is unveiling its new Ryzen 9 product tier, which it is using for its 12-core Ryzen 9 3900X processor, and which runs at 4.6 GHz boost. All of the five processors will be PCIe 4.0 enabled, and while they are being accompanied by the new X570 chipset launch, they still use the same AM4 socket, meaning some AMD 300 and 400-series motherboards can still be used. We have all the details inside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of people have been after details about AMD’s next generation Ryzen platform for several months, ever since &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.anandtech.com/show/13829/amd-ryzen-3rd-generation-zen-2-pcie-4-eight-core&quot;&gt;AMD teased the Matisse Ryzen 3000 design at CES back in January&lt;/a&gt;. Most of that information is coming out today, with Ryzen 9, Ryzen 7, and Ryzen 5 processors in the mix. All of these processors will be officially launched on July 7&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; (which is 7/7), correlating with the fact that the core chiplets of these products are built on TSMC’s 7nm process. This is technically a Sunday, but AMD doesn’t mind too much. In reality, it means users might even get them in the mail on the following Monday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before talking about features, let’s go straight into the CPU list, as that’s what most of you are here for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;85%&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody readability=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;tgrey&quot; readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;12&quot;&gt;AMD 'Matisse' Ryzen 3000 Series CPUs&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;tlblue&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;small&gt;AnandTech&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;Cores&lt;br/&gt;Threads&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Base&lt;br/&gt;Freq&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Boost&lt;br/&gt;Freq&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;L2&lt;br/&gt;Cache&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;L3&lt;br/&gt;Cache&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;PCIe&lt;br/&gt;4.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;DDR4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TDP&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Price&lt;br/&gt;(SEP)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tlgrey&quot;&gt;Ryzen 9&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;tlgrey&quot;&gt;3900X&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;12C&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;24T&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6 MB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;64 MB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;16+4+4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;105W&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$499&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tlgrey&quot;&gt;Ryzen 7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;tlgrey&quot;&gt;3800X&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8C&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;16T&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.9&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4 MB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;32 MB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;16+4+4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;105W&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$399&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tlgrey&quot;&gt;Ryzen 7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;tlgrey&quot;&gt;3700X&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8C&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;16T&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4 MB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;32 MB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;16+4+4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;65W&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$329&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tlgrey&quot;&gt;Ryzen 5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;tlgrey&quot;&gt;3600X&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6C&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;12T&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3 MB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;32 MB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;16+4+4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;95W&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$249&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tlgrey&quot;&gt;Ryzen 5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;tlgrey&quot;&gt;3600&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6C&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;12T&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3 MB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;32 MB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;16+4+4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;65W&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$199&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://images.anandtech.com/doci/14407/Ryzen9_3800X_Hand.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://images.anandtech.com/doci/14407/Ryzen9_3800X_Hand_575px.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The New Flagship: Ryzen 9 3900X&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Ryzen 3000 series will debut a new product tier for AMD: Ryzen 9. In this case, the Ryzen 9 3900X will be AMD’s first mainstream desktop 12-core processor. The processor is the only one of the group that uses two chiplets, in a 6+6 configuration. The 3900X will have a base frequency of 3.8 GHz, a turbo frequency of 4.6 GHz, and line up with 6 MB of L2 cache and 64 MB of L3 cache. This confirms that each chiplet has 32 MB of L3 cache, doubling what we saw on the first generation of the Zen microarchitecture. This CPU has a TDP of 105W, which for AMD processors is usually a good measure of all-core power consumption, and will be enabled with 24 PCIe 4.0 lanes (16 for GPU, 4 for storage, 4 for the chipset).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;85%&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody readability=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;tgrey&quot; readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;12&quot;&gt;AMD 'Matisse' Ryzen 3000 Series CPUs&lt;br/&gt;Ryzen 9&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;tlblue&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;small&gt;AnandTech&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;Cores&lt;br/&gt;Threads&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Base&lt;br/&gt;Freq&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Boost&lt;br/&gt;Freq&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;L2&lt;br/&gt;Cache&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;L3&lt;br/&gt;Cache&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;PCIe&lt;br/&gt;4.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;DDR4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TDP&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Price&lt;br/&gt;(SEP)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tlgrey&quot;&gt;Ryzen 9&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;tlgrey&quot;&gt;3900X&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;12C&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;24T&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6 MB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;64 MB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;16+4+4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;105W&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$499&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Ryzen 9 3900X will have a suggested e-tail price of $499, and it will come with a cooler (more details in the coming weeks). AMD compared this processor in its presentations to Intel’s 12-core HEDT processor, the Core i9-9920X, which has an MSRP of $1199 and doesn’t come with a cooler.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this comparison, AMD provided Cinebench R20 performance data comparing the two processors (it should be noted that we can’t confirm these results at this time). AMD states that in single thread performance, the 3900X beats the 9920X by +14%, and also wins in multi-threaded performance by 6%, all while having a lower TDP (165W vs 105W).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://images.anandtech.com/doci/14407/COMPUTEX_KEYNOTE_DRAFT_FOR_PREBRIEF.26.05.19-page-030.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://images.anandtech.com/doci/14407/COMPUTEX_KEYNOTE_DRAFT_FOR_PREBRIEF.26.05.19-page-030_575px.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Ryzen 9 3900X is the new mainstream desktop flagship, although AMD clearly has enough headroom on this design to enable a full 16 cores. Most users will expect this to come in the future, so it will be interesting to see if AMD will strategically play this card.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mainstream Madness: Ryzen 7 at 65W&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the Ryzen 7 lineup, AMD is keeping this for the 8-core versions. These CPUs only have a single chiplet inside, and no dummy chiplet. Of the two CPUs in this segment, the one that gets a big shock from us is actually the cheaper model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;85%&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody readability=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;tgrey&quot; readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;12&quot;&gt;AMD 'Matisse' Ryzen 3000 Series CPUs&lt;br/&gt;Ryzen 7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;tlblue&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;AnandTech&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;Cores&lt;br/&gt;Threads&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Base&lt;br/&gt;Freq&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Boost&lt;br/&gt;Freq&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;L2&lt;br/&gt;Cache&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;L3&lt;br/&gt;Cache&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;PCIe&lt;br/&gt;4.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;DDR4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TDP&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Price&lt;br/&gt;(SEP)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tlgrey&quot;&gt;Ryzen 7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;tlgrey&quot;&gt;3800X&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8C&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;16T&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.9&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4 MB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;32 MB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;16+4+4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;105W&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$399&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tlgrey&quot;&gt;Ryzen 7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;tlgrey&quot;&gt;3700X&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8C&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;16T&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4 MB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;32 MB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;16+4+4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;65W&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$329&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Ryzen 7 3700X is an eight core, sixteen thread CPU with a 3.6 GHz base frequency and a 4.4 GHz turbo frequency. It has 4 MB of L2 and 36 MB of L3 (half the L3 compared to Ryzen 9, because it only has one chiplet), but the amazing thing is that this chip has a TDP of just 65W. Just on paper, it looks like this processor is one of the most efficient x86 performance desktop processors ever made. This is likely the CPU configuration that AMD used in its Cinebench R20 demo back at CES, where it showed R20 equivalent multithreaded performance for 40% less system power. And the price for all this performance? Only $329. If I put my reviewer hat on and look at these specifications at a high level, the Ryzen 7 3700X promises to be the mainstream chip of choice for a substantial number of high-performance PCs this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://images.anandtech.com/doci/14407/COMPUTEX_KEYNOTE_DRAFT_FOR_PREBRIEF.26.05.19-page-024.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://images.anandtech.com/doci/14407/COMPUTEX_KEYNOTE_DRAFT_FOR_PREBRIEF.26.05.19-page-024_575px.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like with the Ryzen 9 3900X, AMD also ran a Cinebench comparsion with the 8 core Ryzen 3700X versus Intel's mainstream Core i7-9700K. Here they scored 4806, verus 3726 for the 9700K in R20's multithreaded test.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other CPU in this bracket is the Ryzen 7 3800X. This is going to be the direct upgrade from the current Ryzen 7 2700X, comes with eight cores and sixteen threads, with a base frequency of 3.9 GHz and a boost frequency of 4.5 GHz. It doesn’t seem overly impressive compared to the 3700X with its larger 105W TDP for only a few hundred MHz more on the base frequency, however as we’ve seen with the 2&lt;sup&gt;nd&lt;/sup&gt; Gen Ryzen, that extra TDP headroom usually helps with technologies like XFR that manage the boost frequencies. AMD hasn’t said anything new about how XFR or Precision Boost works in the new generation yet, we have to wait until nearer launch for that information. However the extra frequency and extra TDP will cost an extra $70: the Ryzen 7 3800X will retail for $399.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Budget Builds: Ryzen 5 with Six Cores&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not mentioned during the keynote, but discussed in the press release, AMD also gave information about its new Ryzen 5 processors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;85%&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody readability=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;tgrey&quot; readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;12&quot;&gt;AMD 'Matisse' Ryzen 3000 Series CPUs&lt;br/&gt;Ryzen 5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;tlblue&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;small&gt;AnandTech&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;Cores&lt;br/&gt;Threads&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Base&lt;br/&gt;Freq&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Boost&lt;br/&gt;Freq&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;L2&lt;br/&gt;Cache&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;L3&lt;br/&gt;Cache&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;PCIe&lt;br/&gt;4.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;DDR4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TDP&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Price&lt;br/&gt;(SEP)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tlgrey&quot;&gt;Ryzen 5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;tlgrey&quot;&gt;3600X&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6C&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;12T&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3 MB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;32 MB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;16+4+4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;95W&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$249&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tlgrey&quot;&gt;Ryzen 5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;tlgrey&quot;&gt;3600&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6C&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;12T&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3 MB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;32 MB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;16+4+4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;65W&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$199&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;These are still very competitive – users can now buy a six-core processor for under $200. The processor frequencies are consummate with the position in the stack, along with the pricing, and both CPUs will support all the same technologies (PCIe 4.0, etc) as the bigger chips. These chips still use a single chiplet, not a dual chiplet design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Performance Numbers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AMD provided some performance numbers to compare AMD to Intel CPUs. All of these tests are using Cinebench R20, which should be noted is a floating point rendering test that AMD already does well on, but there aren’t any specific optimizations here for each CPU.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://images.anandtech.com/doci/14407/COMPUTEX_KEYNOTE_DRAFT_FOR_PREBRIEF.26.05.19-page-035b.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://images.anandtech.com/doci/14407/COMPUTEX_KEYNOTE_DRAFT_FOR_PREBRIEF.26.05.19-page-035b_575px.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Direct chip to chip comparisons put AMD’s single thread performance against Intel at +1%. Though it should be noted here that something like the Ryzen 7 3800X, which boosts to 4.5 GHz, is being compared to an Intel CPU that boosts to 5.0 GHz. That would put IPC on this test firmly in the hands of AMD. Multi-threading results are a similar scenario, although the margin of difference tends to drop the more cores that AMD has access to, perhaps because more cores are fighting to get to the memory with a slightly extended memory latency compared from Intel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comparing Zen 1 to Zen 2, AMD is promoting that the Ryzen 9 3900X offers +32% better single threaded performance over the Ryzen 7 1800X. Given that we saw a 40-52% IPC increase from pre-Zen to Zen 1, another +32% on single threaded performance is a good amount to have, although that 32% does include frequency uplift. When we get the chips in, we’ll do an obvious comparison test to find the IPC difference. In multi-threaded results, AMD is promoting +100% multithreaded performance, which is helped by +50% more cores, 2x better FP throughput per core, and higher frequencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Other Features and X570 Motherboards&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aside from the 7nm chiplets, and the monumental price comparison to Intel, there are some other features to mention. AMD is promoting a +15% direct IPC increase from Zen 1 to Zen 2, due to microarchitecture improvements and cache size doubling on the L3. The CPU has 24 PCIe 4.0 lanes: sixteen for the GPU (or other PCIe cards), four for storage, and four for the chipset. The four for storage will likely be linked to the top M.2 slot. Given that some companies are advertising PCIe 4.0 SSDs here at Computex, we expect more to follow in due course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://images.anandtech.com/doci/14407/IMG_20190526_111502.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://images.anandtech.com/doci/14407/IMG_20190526_111502_575px.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new X570 chipset has 16 lanes, four for the upstream connection to the CPU, and twelve downstream for other devices. There is some discontinuity here – we heard from partners that AMD actually removed four PCIe lanes from the chipset design in order to bring the TDP of the chipset down from 15W to 11W; but the full-fat 15W version will be on the next editions of the high-end desktop (which would suggest that Threadripper isn’t dead, contrary to a lot of reporting – this is a question we will be asking Lisa Su later today). We have already seen a number of X570 motherboards ready to enter the market, and we expect around 25 new X570 models in total. It is clear that motherboard manufacturers are now getting serious on AM4 – some of these boards are likely to retail up to $600. These manufacturers are clearly expecting AMD to hit Intel hard, and have designed the motherboards to match the best that they make for Intel's CPUs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One bit of information not disclosed is memory support, however given our discussions with AMD’s partners, this is likely to be DDR4-3200 in one module per channel mode. This is a small bump over 2&lt;sup&gt;nd&lt;/sup&gt; Gen Ryzen, but still a welcome one. It will be interesting to see how the memory controller works on this design for pushing that frequency.  The memory frequency and Infinity Fabric frequency are still linked as before, so bumping up the memory frequency has additional benefits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, the release date for all these CPUs is going to be July 7&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt;. We’re waiting on AMD to disclose the sampling time frame, but our aim is to get our review up on day one. Suggestions for the review are most welcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://images.anandtech.com/doci/14407/COMPUTEX_KEYNOTE_DRAFT_FOR_PREBRIEF.26.05.19-page-037.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://images.anandtech.com/doci/14407/COMPUTEX_KEYNOTE_DRAFT_FOR_PREBRIEF.26.05.19-page-037_575px.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also have access to Dr. Lisa Su directly after the keynote today, and will write up our Q&amp;amp;A in due course. Stay tuned for that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table width=&quot;85%&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody readability=&quot;1.7391304347826&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tlgrey&quot; colspan=&quot;7&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Want to keep up to date with all of our Computex 2019 Coverage?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tlgrey&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.anandtech.com/tag/laptops&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.anandtech.com/doci/11532/acer_predator_21x_678_carousel.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Laptops&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;tlgrey&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.anandtech.com/pipeline&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.anandtech.com/doci/11508/msistoragecard_carousel.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hardware&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;tlgrey&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.anandtech.com/CPUs&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.anandtech.com/doci/11476/2017-04-10_14.19.23_678x452_carousel.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chips&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;tlgrey&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;1.0769230769231&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tlgrey&quot; colspan=&quot;7&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Follow AnandTech's &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.anandtech.com/tag/Computex-2019&quot;&gt;breaking news here&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 03:31:22 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>DuskStar</dc:creator>
<og:title>AMD Ryzen 3000 Announced: Five CPUs, 12 Cores for $499, Up to 4.6 GHz, PCIe 4.0, Coming 7/7</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.anandtech.com/show/14407/amd-ryzen-3000-announced-five-cpus-12-cores-for-499-up-to-46-ghz-pcie-40-coming-77</og:url>
<og:image>https://images.anandtech.com/doci/14407/Ryzen9_3800X_Car_678x452.jpg</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.anandtech.com/show/14407/amd-ryzen-3000-announced-five-cpus-12-cores-for-499-up-to-46-ghz-pcie-40-coming-77</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Scrum is fragile, not Agile</title>
<link>http://www.dennisweyland.net/blog/?p=43</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.dennisweyland.net/blog/?p=43</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;As the title suggests, this post is about two different aspects of Scrum. The first part deals with Scrum not being Agile and the second part is about Scrum being fragile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before going more into detail, a short disclaimer: Everything I present in this post (and in this blog in general) is my personal view and does not represent the view of my current employer, my former employers and any future employers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Scrum is not Agile&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess a typical reaction to this heading would go like “How is this possible? Scrum is not Agile? Isn’t Scrum the number one Agile software development process?”. The short answer is that Scrum claims to be an Agile process, but the sad reality is that Scrum is quite far from being Agile. I will show you why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lets have a quick look at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://agilemanifesto.org/&quot;&gt;Agile Manifesto&lt;/a&gt;. It states that it values “Individuals and interactions over processes and tools”. Lets also have a quick look at the meaning of the word agile. According to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.oxforddictionaries.com/definition/agile&quot;&gt;Oxford Dictionary&lt;/a&gt; agile means “Able to move quickly and easily”. It is not a coincidence that the term agile has been chosen to represent the high-level ideas within the Agile Manifesto. In fact, one major point behind Agile is that in many software projects it is extremely difficult to move quickly and easily. This is not the case for a completely new project, but over time many projects get into a situation where sustainable development is simply not possible anymore. To prevent this (and other issues), the Agile Manifesto and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://agilemanifesto.org/principles.html&quot;&gt;Principles behind the Agile Manifesto&lt;/a&gt; provide several high-level guidelines. These guidelines are not specific well-defined processes or tools and they allow for many different implementations. I suspect that both of these properties (high-level and allowing different implementations) were fully intended. The overall goal was not to present a silver bullet, but to help peers to avoid many of the pitfalls in software development, which the authors of the Agile Manifesto experienced first-hand and which fall into exactly these categories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now lets have a look at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scrum.org/resources/scrum-guide&quot;&gt;Scrum Guide&lt;/a&gt; (written by two of the authors of the Agile Manifesto). In contrast to the Agile Manifesto and the Agile Principles, this guide seems quite lengthy. Surprisingly, the whole guide does not mention Agile a single time. I am not sure if this was historically always the case, but if the authors of the Scrum Guide do not claim that Scrum is Agile, then we would already be done with the first part of this blog post. I assume that this is not the case, so lets move on. The Scrum Guide is about a framework which contains “roles, events, artifacts, and the rules that bind them together”. In other words, it is a very specific and well-defined process. This does not sound agile and it also does not sound Agile (remember: “Individuals and interactions over processes and tools”). &lt;strong&gt;This is quite ironic and obvious. And this is where the whole Scrum movement should have stopped.&lt;/strong&gt; But it did not and instead frustrates an increasing number of software developers all around the world. And whenever a Scrum project fails, it is not because of Scrum’s potential flaws, but because Scrum was not implemented correctly. That sounds like a nice transition into the second part of this post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Scrum is fragile&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This part is very short. I thought that the wordplay (Scrum being agile / fragile) is kind of funny and apart from that it perfectly describes one of the things that really bother me about Scrum: Whenever a Scrum project fails, it is because Scrum was not implemented correctly. And you can read about a vast amount of such projects. &lt;strong&gt;What does it mean, if a large number of intelligent software developers are not able to implement Scrum correctly? It means the whole framework is fragile.&lt;/strong&gt; And this is another major argument against using Scrum. What is a framework good for, if it is so difficult to use?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, it seems that with the help of expensive consulting and coaching, as well as training and certificates, Scrum might in fact provide value. But it is not clear if this is value for the companies developing software and the hard-working software developers or for those who offer services in and around the Scrum ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Personal View&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would like to finish this post with a bit of my personal view regarding software development, Agile and Scrum. To me it seems that one very important part of high quality software development is to maintain a simple priority queue of tasks. The weight is a combination of the value a task provides for the customer / developers and the estimated effort to implement this task. For some developers this comes naturally. For teams and companies for which this is not the case, Scrum offers a rather expensive and inefficient implementation of a priority queue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And lets be honest. Software development is a very difficult and complex work. Are we really surprised that so many projects fail? The field is still very young and we need to learn a lot. And this is crucial: We need to learn from past experiences, let it be failures or success stories. And here we collectively fail. We are not using the wrong processes or implementing the right processes in the wrong way. We are simply caught in a rat race and not able to make a short break in order to look at and learn from all the things that happened around us, maybe even before our time. It is our duty to extract the knowledge, the experiences and the wisdom from the many resources that are so easily available to us: The many many books, articles and videos about software development and, last but not least, the Agile Manifesto.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2019 22:03:53 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>pplonski86</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.dennisweyland.net/blog/?p=43</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ask HN: How do I make sure my non-technical parents are safe online?</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=20015775</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=20015775</guid>
<description>&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20016583&quot; readability=&quot;13.457364341085&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;6.7286821705426&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;13.457364341085&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20019643&quot; readability=&quot;5.4705882352941&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.7352941176471&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.4705882352941&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;3.6470588235294&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20020139&quot; readability=&quot;8.4210526315789&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.2105263157895&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;8.4210526315789&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;5.1461988304094&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20016901&quot; readability=&quot;2.2574257425743&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20018439&quot; readability=&quot;1.0819672131148&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20019151&quot; readability=&quot;11.792168674699&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;5.8960843373494&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;11.792168674699&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20020164&quot; readability=&quot;5.4696132596685&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.7348066298343&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.4696132596685&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20020190&quot; readability=&quot;8.5358744394619&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.2679372197309&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;8.5358744394619&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;6.164798206278&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20019921&quot; readability=&quot;5.4812680115274&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.7406340057637&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.4812680115274&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;4.1109510086455&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20015989&quot; readability=&quot;20.726205997392&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;10.363102998696&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;20.726205997392&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;18.752281616688&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20016527&quot; readability=&quot;5.625&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.8125&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.625&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;4.21875&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20018940&quot; readability=&quot;6.4814814814815&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.2407407407407&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.4814814814815&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;5.0925925925926&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20019839&quot; readability=&quot;1.5268817204301&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20019843&quot; readability=&quot;5.6068965517241&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.8034482758621&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.6068965517241&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20017457&quot; readability=&quot;2.6113989637306&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.3056994818653&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.6113989637306&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20016860&quot; readability=&quot;3.5227272727273&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.7613636363636&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.5227272727273&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20017032&quot; readability=&quot;5.134328358209&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.5671641791045&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.134328358209&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20016252&quot; readability=&quot;21.576397515528&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;10.788198757764&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;21.576397515528&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;17.653416149068&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20017626&quot; readability=&quot;3.4226804123711&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.7113402061856&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.4226804123711&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20017971&quot; readability=&quot;3.2520325203252&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.6260162601626&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.2520325203252&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20015917&quot; readability=&quot;9.5238095238095&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.7619047619048&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;9.5238095238095&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20019927&quot; readability=&quot;5.5285714285714&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.7642857142857&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.5285714285714&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20015994&quot; readability=&quot;3.4059405940594&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.7029702970297&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.4059405940594&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20017913&quot; readability=&quot;7.4725274725275&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.7362637362637&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7.4725274725275&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;5.1373626373626&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20019853&quot; readability=&quot;2.5975609756098&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.2987804878049&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.5975609756098&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;120&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20019870&quot; readability=&quot;10.33734939759&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;5.1686746987952&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;10.33734939759&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20018958&quot; readability=&quot;6.6644880174292&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.3322440087146&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.6644880174292&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;5.7124183006536&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20018857&quot; readability=&quot;3.5&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.75&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.5&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20019068&quot; readability=&quot;6.5196078431373&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.2598039215686&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.5196078431373&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20019142&quot; readability=&quot;10.377358490566&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;5.188679245283&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;10.377358490566&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;6.1320754716981&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20017377&quot; readability=&quot;11.664943123061&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;5.8324715615305&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;11.664943123061&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;12.150982419855&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20019294&quot; readability=&quot;3.8507462686567&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20017547&quot; readability=&quot;0.81081081081081&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20017903&quot; readability=&quot;2.1142857142857&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20018281&quot; readability=&quot;1.3589743589744&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20017651&quot; readability=&quot;10.973105134474&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;5.4865525672372&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;10.973105134474&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;8.6870415647922&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20017688&quot; readability=&quot;0.87272727272727&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20016156&quot; readability=&quot;4.8414795244386&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.4207397622193&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.8414795244386&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;5.3256274768824&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20017759&quot; readability=&quot;10.622464898596&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;5.311232449298&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;10.622464898596&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;11.105304212168&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20017006&quot; readability=&quot;10.646715328467&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;5.3233576642336&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;10.646715328467&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20018038&quot; readability=&quot;3.5512195121951&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.7756097560976&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.5512195121951&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;3.9951219512195&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20017627&quot; readability=&quot;1.4285714285714&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20017780&quot; readability=&quot;2.2747252747253&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20016924&quot; readability=&quot;6.6157517899761&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.3078758949881&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.6157517899761&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20018682&quot; readability=&quot;2.4121621621622&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.2060810810811&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.4121621621622&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20018851&quot; readability=&quot;8.7616525423729&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.3808262711864&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;8.7616525423729&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;6.3278601694915&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20019174&quot; readability=&quot;10.835726593912&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;5.4178632969558&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;10.835726593912&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;17.731188971855&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20016987&quot; readability=&quot;3.4517766497462&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.7258883248731&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.4517766497462&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20017622&quot; readability=&quot;1.4838709677419&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20019521&quot; readability=&quot;7.1815181518152&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.5907590759076&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7.1815181518152&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;120&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20020015&quot; readability=&quot;7.2805755395683&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.6402877697842&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7.2805755395683&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;160&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20015914&quot; readability=&quot;16.496158068057&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;8.2480790340285&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;16.496158068057&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;6.7925356750823&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20016281&quot; readability=&quot;6.5052356020942&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.2526178010471&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.5052356020942&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;5.1112565445026&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20018960&quot; readability=&quot;2.5423728813559&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.271186440678&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.5423728813559&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20016150&quot; readability=&quot;5.1387559808612&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.5693779904306&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.1387559808612&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20016242&quot; readability=&quot;2.4586466165414&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.2293233082707&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.4586466165414&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20016375&quot; readability=&quot;9.2836676217765&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.6418338108883&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;9.2836676217765&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;7.89111747851&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20020253&quot; readability=&quot;7.4490358126722&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.7245179063361&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7.4490358126722&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20016556&quot; readability=&quot;7.6372712146423&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.8186356073211&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7.6372712146423&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;8.4858569051581&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20017677&quot; readability=&quot;2.328&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20017526&quot; readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.5&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20016405&quot; readability=&quot;8.4134419551935&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.2067209775967&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;8.4134419551935&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;7.0112016293279&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20016571&quot; readability=&quot;4.6491228070175&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.3245614035088&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.6491228070175&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;5.5789473684211&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20016653&quot; readability=&quot;6.5963963963964&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.2981981981982&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.5963963963964&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;120&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;7.5387387387387&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20019869&quot; readability=&quot;12.657502863688&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;6.3287514318442&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;12.657502863688&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;160&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;12.657502863688&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20016604&quot; readability=&quot;11.612903225806&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;5.8064516129032&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;11.612903225806&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;6.7741935483871&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20019649&quot; readability=&quot;11.683848797251&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;5.8419243986254&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;11.683848797251&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20015943&quot; readability=&quot;3.6912751677852&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.8456375838926&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.6912751677852&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;4.6140939597315&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20015965&quot; readability=&quot;6.4954954954955&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.2477477477477&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.4954954954955&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20018318&quot; readability=&quot;6.5295698924731&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.2647849462366&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.5295698924731&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20016777&quot; readability=&quot;3.5700934579439&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.785046728972&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.5700934579439&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;3.5700934579439&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20016355&quot; readability=&quot;9.3093922651934&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.6546961325967&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;9.3093922651934&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20016522&quot; readability=&quot;2.4&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.2&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.4&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20020090&quot; readability=&quot;4.4444444444444&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.2222222222222&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.4444444444444&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;4.4444444444444&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20017831&quot; readability=&quot;12.630681818182&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;6.3153409090909&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;12.630681818182&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;13.116477272727&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20019246&quot; readability=&quot;9.6754250386399&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.8377125193199&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;9.6754250386399&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;6.7727975270479&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20016285&quot; readability=&quot;22.502254283138&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;11.251127141569&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;22.502254283138&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;13.697024346258&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20016059&quot; readability=&quot;2.4285714285714&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.2142857142857&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.4285714285714&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20018886&quot; readability=&quot;10.734482758621&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;5.3672413793103&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;10.734482758621&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;11.222413793103&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20019102&quot; readability=&quot;5.7241379310345&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.8620689655172&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.7241379310345&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;4.7701149425287&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20018384&quot; readability=&quot;14.68487394958&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;7.3424369747899&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;14.68487394958&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;14.195378151261&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20019443&quot; readability=&quot;5.8811544991511&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20017838&quot; readability=&quot;6.6694045174538&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.3347022587269&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.6694045174538&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;4.2874743326489&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20016473&quot; readability=&quot;5.7387640449438&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.8693820224719&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.7387640449438&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;5.7387640449438&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20017943&quot; readability=&quot;8.5189309576837&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.2594654788419&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;8.5189309576837&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;5.6792873051225&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20017541&quot; readability=&quot;14.638728323699&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;7.3193641618497&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;14.638728323699&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20015846&quot; readability=&quot;3.1698113207547&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20020266&quot; readability=&quot;2.4642857142857&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.2321428571429&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.4642857142857&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20015911&quot; readability=&quot;5.5873925501433&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.7936962750716&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.5873925501433&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20015947&quot; readability=&quot;2.2702702702703&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20016042&quot; readability=&quot;2.3951612903226&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20016136&quot; readability=&quot;4.4130434782609&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.2065217391304&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.4130434782609&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;120&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20016221&quot; readability=&quot;3.4444444444444&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.7222222222222&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.4444444444444&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;160&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20017718&quot; readability=&quot;7.6323851203501&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.8161925601751&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7.6323851203501&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;6.2013129102845&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20015889&quot; readability=&quot;5.125&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.5625&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.125&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;4.6979166666667&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20016390&quot; readability=&quot;5.659793814433&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.8298969072165&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.659793814433&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;5.1881443298969&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20016017&quot; readability=&quot;4.6818181818182&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.3409090909091&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.6818181818182&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20016707&quot; readability=&quot;4.4155844155844&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.2077922077922&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.4155844155844&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20015939&quot; readability=&quot;2.5217391304348&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.2608695652174&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.5217391304348&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20016034&quot; readability=&quot;7.5315315315315&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.7657657657658&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7.5315315315315&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;6.5900900900901&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20016107&quot; readability=&quot;3.4224598930481&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.7112299465241&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.4224598930481&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;120&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20016560&quot; readability=&quot;2.4135338345865&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.2067669172932&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.4135338345865&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;160&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20019576&quot; readability=&quot;1.4246575342466&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20017043&quot; readability=&quot;2.283185840708&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20017798&quot; readability=&quot;8.4565217391304&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.2282608695652&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;8.4565217391304&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;7.0471014492754&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20018046&quot; readability=&quot;3.0721649484536&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20019221&quot; readability=&quot;2.3863636363636&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20019742&quot; readability=&quot;8.5838150289017&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.2919075144509&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;8.5838150289017&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;120&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;7.1531791907514&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20019741&quot; readability=&quot;1.3225806451613&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20016328&quot; readability=&quot;5.5933806146572&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20015876&quot; readability=&quot;3.5324675324675&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.7662337662338&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.5324675324675&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20019495&quot; readability=&quot;1.7714285714286&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20015892&quot; readability=&quot;5.5&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.75&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.5&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20018270&quot; readability=&quot;7.7105263157895&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.8552631578947&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7.7105263157895&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;10.120065789474&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20017353&quot; readability=&quot;4.8460591133005&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.4230295566502&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.8460591133005&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;5.3306650246305&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20018443&quot; readability=&quot;7.55&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.775&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7.55&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;7.55&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20019536&quot; readability=&quot;3.2307692307692&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.6153846153846&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.2307692307692&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20019480&quot; readability=&quot;3.9928057553957&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20016011&quot; readability=&quot;4.136690647482&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.068345323741&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.136690647482&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20016930&quot; readability=&quot;10.565051020408&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;5.2825255102041&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;10.565051020408&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;12.485969387755&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20017722&quot; readability=&quot;8.636974789916&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.318487394958&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;8.636974789916&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;9.5966386554622&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20019409&quot; readability=&quot;4.6335697399527&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.3167848699764&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.6335697399527&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20019895&quot; readability=&quot;7.4751131221719&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.737556561086&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7.4751131221719&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;4.2047511312217&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20018427&quot; readability=&quot;9.2372881355932&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.6186440677966&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;9.2372881355932&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;5.0805084745763&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20015912&quot; readability=&quot;9.6639784946237&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.8319892473118&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;9.6639784946237&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;10.147177419355&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20017664&quot; readability=&quot;9.3562231759657&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.6781115879828&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;9.3562231759657&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;8.8884120171674&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20017756&quot; readability=&quot;5.5217391304348&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.7608695652174&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.5217391304348&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;3.6811594202899&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20017811&quot; readability=&quot;12.752694990488&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;6.3763474952441&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;12.752694990488&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;15.205136334813&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20015883&quot; readability=&quot;1.5310344827586&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20016724&quot; readability=&quot;4.7051671732523&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20016037&quot; readability=&quot;8.4270557029178&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.2135278514589&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;8.4270557029178&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20016274&quot; readability=&quot;4.5846153846154&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.2923076923077&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.5846153846154&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20016718&quot; readability=&quot;3.6571428571429&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.8285714285714&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.6571428571429&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20016416&quot; readability=&quot;5.5017301038062&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.7508650519031&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.5017301038062&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20016947&quot; readability=&quot;7.180487804878&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.590243902439&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;7.180487804878&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20015803&quot; readability=&quot;1.9421965317919&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20016174&quot; readability=&quot;2.3961038961039&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20018348&quot; readability=&quot;3.5744680851064&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.7872340425532&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.5744680851064&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20017005&quot; readability=&quot;3.4857142857143&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;1.7428571428571&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.4857142857143&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;80&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20016494&quot; readability=&quot;4.3518518518519&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.1759259259259&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.3518518518519&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20015941&quot; readability=&quot;4.3961352657005&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.1980676328502&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.3961352657005&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20017830&quot; readability=&quot;12.76026823135&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;6.3801341156748&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;12.76026823135&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;9.815590947192&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20015837&quot; readability=&quot;1.4883720930233&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20018552&quot; readability=&quot;4.3632075471698&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.1816037735849&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.3632075471698&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20015839&quot; readability=&quot;5.5960099750623&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.7980049875312&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.5960099750623&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20016801&quot; readability=&quot;4.5061728395062&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.2530864197531&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.5061728395062&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;5.4074074074074&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20016162&quot; readability=&quot;15.34634551495&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;7.6731727574751&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;15.34634551495&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;18.756644518272&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20019512&quot; readability=&quot;1.2017937219731&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20017023&quot; readability=&quot;1.1153846153846&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20017784&quot; readability=&quot;0.7843137254902&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20015830&quot; readability=&quot;11.202127659574&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;5.6010638297872&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;11.202127659574&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;5.6010638297872&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20015925&quot; readability=&quot;8.5178571428571&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;4.2589285714286&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;8.5178571428571&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;4.2589285714286&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20016989&quot; readability=&quot;5.3684210526316&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.6842105263158&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5.3684210526316&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20016770&quot; readability=&quot;1.1071428571429&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20016325&quot; readability=&quot;37.67847069884&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;18.83923534942&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;37.67847069884&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;36.686931996239&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;comment&quot; readability=&quot;47.924218503315&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;commtext c00&quot;&gt;You can't make them safe, any more than you can give them a car and make them safe on, say, a freeway. I think a better attitude is to teach them that the internet is a dangerous place, and they should 'drive' defensively.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;commtext c00&quot;&gt;Get them the simplest device possible. A cheap iPad is great. Preconfigure it to be even simpler (maybe using parental controls), and tell them not to mess with anything. Keep notes for yourself, and be prepared to restore from factory defaults every once in a while when things go weird.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;commtext c00&quot;&gt;Install as many layers of ad-blocking as possible, whether DNS blacklists, browser filters, etc. Some sites/apps won't function correctly, but rather than try to open holes, just say, 'Sorry, that doesn't work.' Trust me, your folks will just move on to something that does (maybe with your suggestions), and is likely safer.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;commtext c00&quot;&gt;Buy them a few subscriptions to reputable news sources (a good discussion itself) so they don't have an excuse that they can't pay for decent journalism and so have to pick it up from a Facebook/Youtube algorithm.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;commtext c00&quot;&gt;If you're up for it, be explicit and direct about them asking you for advice. For example, teach them how to forward an email to you -- or a screenshot or image from another camera -- so you can give them an idea of whether its safe or not.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;commtext c00&quot;&gt;If they're willing, teach them to use a password manager that creates/saves random passwords. If you can't, at least make sure their important accounts (email, bank, etc.) are adequately secured. I've (mostly) convinced my mom to write down all her passwords on pieces of paper, which are stored in an envelope in a known place in her apartment. It's not perfect, but way better than discovering every password is 'hello123'.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;commtext c00&quot;&gt;Try to teach them a little about the technology. I don't mean system architecture or code, but the basics of how online economics work (e.g., advertising vs personal data) and what algorithms are (use the analogy of meal recipes). If you discover accessible journalism that is critical of problematic technology (like privacy issues with Facebook), share it with them. I've done this a lot with older/non-tech folks and I've ever met someone who couldn't understand at least the basics.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;commtext c00&quot;&gt;Don't be afraid to tell them that you feel some technology is bad for them. You'll discover it's actually a relief for them to hear, as mostly what they're going to hear is that all technology is great, and much less about being critical about tech.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;commtext c00&quot;&gt;Finally, don't push them into any more tech than they truly need. Most non-tech people aren't that interested in exploring tech; they probably &lt;em&gt;aren't&lt;/em&gt; going to be the folks downloading apps or plugins and trying random websites just for fun. If they're comfortable walking into their bank and dealing with their accounts in person, let them continue to do that. Even if it costs a little, they're actually better off than you (or someone else) convincing them online banking is 'better.' Don't digitize their lives without a really good reason.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;commtext c00&quot;&gt;(I'm saying all of the above with the experience of being online for 40+ years, and helping other folks over that whole time. Sadly, it's gotten more difficult.)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20016234&quot; readability=&quot;4.4847328244275&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;2.2423664122137&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4.4847328244275&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;ind&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;default&quot;&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20016881&quot; readability=&quot;1.1111111111111&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing comtr&quot; id=&quot;20016258&quot; readability=&quot;1.4025974025974&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2019 16:36:23 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>nellypat</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=20015775</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Intel Announces 8 Core I9-9900KS: Every Core at 5Ghz, All the Time</title>
<link>https://www.anandtech.com/show/14402/intel-announces-5-ghz-all-core-turbo-cpu</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.anandtech.com/show/14402/intel-announces-5-ghz-all-core-turbo-cpu</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Last year, Intel showcased a CPU during its keynote a processor with all of its cores at 5 GHz. Today, that becomes a reality – Intel is set to launch a processor that promises that frequency in any scenario. The new Core i9-9900KS is an 8-core processor that will run at 5.0 GHz during single core workloads and multi-core workloads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That demo last year was on an overclockable 28-core Xeon CPU, but in reality was clocked way lower. There was even a good amount of controversy, as Intel didn’t state at the time they were using a sub-zero chiller to achieve that result. But this year we’re getting something a little more realistic. The new Core i9-9900KS uses the same silicon currently in the i9-9900K, but selectively binned in order to achieve 5.0 GHz on every core, all of the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://images.anandtech.com/doci/14402/2019-05-26%2017.46.48.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://images.anandtech.com/doci/14402/2019-05-26%2017.46.48_575px.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Technically the CPU has a base frequency of 4.0 GHz, however it will only ever go down to that amount based on a default Intel BIOS (no consumer board uses the base BIOS specifications). The new CPU will be enabled in the same motherboards as the Core i9-9900K, but with a small firmware update. The CPU also has the same integrated graphics as the Core i9-9900K.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intel did not tell us the TDP yet, but we will update this article when we know. Pricing and the launch date are also an unknown, however Intel SVP and GM Gregory Bryant is running a keynote here at Computex in a couple of days, and we expect to have the details then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;95%&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody readability=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;tgrey&quot; readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;9&quot;&gt;Intel 9th Gen Core 8-Core Desktop CPUs&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;tlblue&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;AnandTech&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Cores&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Base&lt;br/&gt;Freq&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;All-Core Turbo&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Single&lt;br/&gt;Core Turbo&lt;br/&gt;Freq&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;IGP&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;DDR4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TDP&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Price&lt;br/&gt;(1ku)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tlgrey&quot;&gt;i9-9900KS&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8 / 16&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.0 GHz&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5.0 GHz&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5.0 GHz&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;UHD 630&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2666&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tlgrey&quot;&gt;i9-9900K&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8 / 16&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.6 GHz&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.7 GHz&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5.0 GHz&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;UHD 630&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2666&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;95 W&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$488&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tlgrey&quot;&gt;i9-9900KF&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8 / 16&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.6 GHz&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.7 GHz&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5.0 GHz&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2666&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;95 W&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$488&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tlgrey&quot;&gt;i7-9700K&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8 / 8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.6 GHz&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.6 GHz&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.9 GHz&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;UHD 630&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2666&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;95 W&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$374&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tlgrey&quot;&gt;i7-9700KF&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8 / 8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.6 GHz&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.6 GHz&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.9 GHz&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2666&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;95 W&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$374&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;The main difference compared to the Core i9-9900K is currently that all-core turbo value, which is a flat 5.0 GHz, a 300 MHz increase. There's a slight chance Intel might have increased the TDP, especially given that the base frequency (which TDP is built on) has increased 10% from 3.6 GHz to 4.0 GHz.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.anandtech.com/show/13544/why-intel-processors-draw-more-power-than-expected-tdp-turbo&quot;&gt;Why Intel Processors Draw More Power Than Expected: TDP and Turbo Explained&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intel did have a demo system for us to look at, which used a standard off-the-shelf motherboard and a closed loop liquid cooler. Intel confirmed that the chip is soldered, and that this is just simply the same silicon as the 9900K but better binned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More info in a couple of days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table width=&quot;85%&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody readability=&quot;1.7391304347826&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tlgrey&quot; colspan=&quot;7&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Want to keep up to date with all of our Computex 2019 Coverage?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tlgrey&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.anandtech.com/tag/laptops&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.anandtech.com/doci/11532/acer_predator_21x_678_carousel.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Laptops&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;tlgrey&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.anandtech.com/pipeline&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.anandtech.com/doci/11508/msistoragecard_carousel.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hardware&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;tlgrey&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.anandtech.com/CPUs&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.anandtech.com/doci/11476/2017-04-10_14.19.23_678x452_carousel.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chips&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;tlgrey&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;1.0769230769231&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tlgrey&quot; colspan=&quot;7&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Follow AnandTech's &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.anandtech.com/tag/Computex-2019&quot;&gt;breaking news here&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2019 16:10:49 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Doubleguitars</dc:creator>
<og:title>Intel Announces 8 Core i9-9900KS: Every Core at 5.0 GHz, All The Time</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.anandtech.com/show/14402/intel-announces-5-ghz-all-core-turbo-cpu</og:url>
<og:image>https://images.anandtech.com/doci/14402/2019-05-26%2016.55.4633_678x452.jpg</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.anandtech.com/show/14402/intel-announces-5-ghz-all-core-turbo-cpu</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Knowledge Extraction from Unstructured Texts</title>
<link>https://blog.heuritech.com/2016/04/15/knowledge-extraction-from-unstructured-texts/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.heuritech.com/2016/04/15/knowledge-extraction-from-unstructured-texts/</guid>
<description>&lt;h2&gt;Foreword&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is an unreasonable amount of information that can be extracted from what people publicly say on the internet. At Heuritech we use this information to better understand what people want, which products they like and why. This post explains from a scientific point of view what is Knowledge extraction and details a few recent method on how to do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Highly structured databases make it easy to reason with and can be used for inference. For example in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wikidata.org/wiki/Wikidata:Main_Page&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;WikiData&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://www2007.org/papers/paper391.pdf&quot;&gt;YAGO&lt;/a&gt;, entities are isolated and linked together with relations. However, most of the human knowledge expressions take the form of unstructured texts, from which it is very hard to reason and get wisdom. Consider the example here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;4001&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://blog.heuritech.com/2016/04/15/knowledge-extraction-from-unstructured-texts/marie_curie/#main&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://heuritech.files.wordpress.com/2016/04/marie_curie.png&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;12177,3516&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;marie_curie&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://heuritech.files.wordpress.com/2016/04/marie_curie.png?w=300&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://heuritech.files.wordpress.com/2016/04/marie_curie.png?w=470&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-4001&quot; src=&quot;https://heuritech.files.wordpress.com/2016/04/marie_curie.png?w=470&quot; alt=&quot;marie_curie&quot; srcset=&quot;https://heuritech.files.wordpress.com/2016/04/marie_curie.png?w=470 470w, https://heuritech.files.wordpress.com/2016/04/marie_curie.png?w=940 940w, https://heuritech.files.wordpress.com/2016/04/marie_curie.png?w=150 150w, https://heuritech.files.wordpress.com/2016/04/marie_curie.png?w=300 300w, https://heuritech.files.wordpress.com/2016/04/marie_curie.png?w=768 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 470px) 100vw, 470px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The raw text on the left contains a lot of useful information in an unstructured way, such as birthday, nationality, activity. Extracting those information corresponds to a challenging field in Natural Language Processing, which may require sentence parsing (mapping natural language to machine interpretable representations), entity detection and multi-reference resolution to aggregate information about the same entity. Knowledge extraction is guided, for example, by the will of being able to perform &lt;em&gt;Question Answering&lt;/em&gt; tasks: in a structured knowledge base, one can make a query and then get the requested information. Another application is to perform arbitrarily complex reasoning by finding paths in a graph of extracted knowledge. In knowledge extraction, one can be interested in hypernymy where entities are included within other entities and one can also be interested in relation extraction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;The purpose of this blog post is to review methods that make possible the acquisition and extraction of structured information either from raw texts or from pre-existing Knowledge Graph. More precisely, we aim at semantically parsing a text in order to extract entities and/or relations. We define a &lt;em&gt;triplet&lt;/em&gt; in a sentence as a relation &lt;em&gt;r&lt;/em&gt; between two entities &lt;em&gt;e1&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;e2&lt;/em&gt;: (&lt;em&gt;e1, r, e2&lt;/em&gt;). A &lt;em&gt;Knowledge Graph&lt;/em&gt; (KG) denotes a collection of triplets that draw a graph: vertices are entities and edges are relations. Most of the articles presented below assume that entities are identified and disambiguated. In practice, this can be achieved with tools like &lt;a href=&quot;https://people.cs.umass.edu/~kschultz/publications/factorie-nips-2009.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;FACTORIE&lt;/a&gt; or the &lt;a href=&quot;http://nlp.stanford.edu/software/CRF-NER.shtml&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;NER parser&lt;/a&gt; from Stanford.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though at Heuritech we are more interested in knowledge extraction from raw text, we first quickly review here techniques that rely on a KG only (no extra text corpus available). The task we want to perform is to fill an incomplete KG. Before 2013, links were filled with graph theory techniques that ignored the fact that our graph is a KG.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.utc.fr/~bordesan/dokuwiki/_media/en/transe_nips13.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Translating Embeddings for Modelling Multi-relational Data&lt;/a&gt; by Bordes et al. in 2013 is a first attempt of a dedicated method for KG completion. It learns an embedding for the entities and the relations in the same low-dimensional vector space. The objective function is such that it constraints entity &lt;em&gt;e2&lt;/em&gt; to be close to &lt;em&gt;e1&lt;/em&gt; + &lt;em&gt;r&lt;/em&gt;. This is done &lt;a href=&quot;http://deeplearning4j.org/word2vec&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;3997&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://blog.heuritech.com/2016/04/15/knowledge-extraction-from-unstructured-texts/word2vec/#main&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://heuritech.files.wordpress.com/2016/04/word2vec.png&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;8470,6434&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;word2vec&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://heuritech.files.wordpress.com/2016/04/word2vec.png?w=300&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://heuritech.files.wordpress.com/2016/04/word2vec.png?w=470&quot; class=&quot;alignright wp-image-3997&quot; src=&quot;https://heuritech.files.wordpress.com/2016/04/word2vec.png?w=288&amp;amp;h=219&quot; alt=&quot;word2vec.png&quot; width=&quot;288&quot; height=&quot;219&quot; srcset=&quot;https://heuritech.files.wordpress.com/2016/04/word2vec.png?w=288&amp;amp;h=219 288w, https://heuritech.files.wordpress.com/2016/04/word2vec.png?w=576&amp;amp;h=438 576w, https://heuritech.files.wordpress.com/2016/04/word2vec.png?w=150&amp;amp;h=114 150w, https://heuritech.files.wordpress.com/2016/04/word2vec.png?w=300&amp;amp;h=228 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 288px) 100vw, 288px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;with assigning a higher score to existing triplets than to random triplets obtained with negative sampling. This above model is known as &lt;em&gt;TransE&lt;/em&gt; and this work is related with the &lt;a href=&quot;http://deeplearning4j.org/word2vec&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;wor&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;d2vec&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; work by Mikolov where relations between concepts naturally take the form of translations in the embedding space as seen in the picture here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several improvements have then been added to make way to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.fr/url?sa=t&amp;amp;rct=j&amp;amp;q=&amp;amp;esrc=s&amp;amp;source=web&amp;amp;cd=1&amp;amp;ved=0ahUKEwig146MhIfMAhVHnBoKHe8kBAcQFgghMAA&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.aaai.org%2Focs%2Findex.php%2FAAAI%2FAAAI14%2Fpaper%2Fdownload%2F8531%2F8546&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNH5SjHUAGy08evjWUaas2apAs0g9A&amp;amp;sig2=_OCX7lYt23hhDpaXjmN2jw&amp;amp;bvm=bv.119028448,d.d2s&quot;&gt;TransH&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.fr/url?sa=t&amp;amp;rct=j&amp;amp;q=&amp;amp;esrc=s&amp;amp;source=web&amp;amp;cd=1&amp;amp;ved=0ahUKEwjq7dG6g4fMAhVEqxoKHQDbBqgQFgggMAA&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.aaai.org%2Focs%2Findex.php%2FAAAI%2FAAAI15%2Fpaper%2Fdownload%2F9571%2F9523&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNGbTdExlz_-pYWXA8MO06I-9w1U0w&amp;amp;sig2=oxMJNUp-VhNcB_ctbNqwDA&amp;amp;cad=rja&quot;&gt;TransR&lt;/a&gt; models for examples. State-of-the art is held by &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/abs/1603.07704&quot;&gt;Probabilistic Reasoning via Deep Learning: Neural Association Models&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We focus here on extracting triplets (&lt;em&gt;e1, r, e2&lt;/em&gt;) from a raw text. There are several variants of this task, depending on the kind of supervision used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Triplet extraction can be done in a purely &lt;strong&gt;unsupervised way&lt;/strong&gt;. Usually the text is first parsed with several tools (such as TreeBank parser, MiniPar or OpenNLP parser) then the texts between entities (as well as the annotations from the parsers) are clustered and finally simplified. While  attractive at a first look as no supervision is needed, there are a few drawbacks. First, it requires lots of tedious work to hand-craft rules which depend on the parser used. Moreover, the clusters found contain semantically related relations but they do not give us fine-grained implications. Typically, a cluster may contain « is-capital-of » and « is-city-of » which are semantically closed relations. However, with the unsupervised approach, we will fail to discover that « is-capital-of » implies the relation « is-city-of » and not the opposite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will focus more on other kinds of supervision:  &lt;strong&gt;supervised learning&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;distant supervision&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;universal schemas&lt;/strong&gt;. We first give some definitions. &lt;em&gt;Fixed-schema&lt;/em&gt; relation extraction implies that relations to be found are in a fixed list of possible relations. On the contrary, in &lt;em&gt;open-domain&lt;/em&gt; relation extraction, relations are not constrained. In that case, there is no fixed-schema which would constrain too much the knowledge extraction, if not perfectly appropriate. However, it is much harder to generalize and to infer new relations in a graph built with open-domain relations, as there are lots of relations with various style. &lt;a href=&quot;http://nlp.stanford.edu/software/openie.html&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;OpenIE&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (Open Information Extraction) is a tool that filters and normalizes raw text between entities to obtain open-domain relations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Schema-based supervised learning&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this case, the available data is a collection of sentences where each sentence is annotated with the triplet extracted from it. This means that raw text aligned with a KG of the text. Two recent papers (both published in 2016) give cutting-edge solutions to this problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/abs/1601.00770&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;End-to-End Relation Extraction using LSTMs on Sequences and Tree Structures&lt;/a&gt; article by Miwa and Bansal shows an approach which uses two stacked networks: a &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/abs/1303.5778&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Bidirectional LSTM&lt;/a&gt; for entity detection (it creates an embedding of the entities) and a &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/abs/1503.00075&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Tree-based LSTM&lt;/a&gt; for the detection of the relation that links the entities found. The figure below from the original paper shows the architecture used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;3530&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://blog.heuritech.com/2016/04/15/knowledge-extraction-from-unstructured-texts/end2end/#main&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://heuritech.files.wordpress.com/2016/04/end2end.png&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;9747,5145&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;end2end&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://heuritech.files.wordpress.com/2016/04/end2end.png?w=300&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://heuritech.files.wordpress.com/2016/04/end2end.png?w=470&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-3530&quot; src=&quot;https://heuritech.files.wordpress.com/2016/04/end2end.png?w=470&quot; alt=&quot;end2end.png&quot; srcset=&quot;https://heuritech.files.wordpress.com/2016/04/end2end.png?w=470 470w, https://heuritech.files.wordpress.com/2016/04/end2end.png?w=940 940w, https://heuritech.files.wordpress.com/2016/04/end2end.png?w=150 150w, https://heuritech.files.wordpress.com/2016/04/end2end.png?w=300 300w, https://heuritech.files.wordpress.com/2016/04/end2end.png?w=768 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 470px) 100vw, 470px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their approach uses &lt;a href=&quot;http://nlp.stanford.edu/software/tagger.shtml&quot;&gt;POS tagging&lt;/a&gt; on the raw text which gives additional information that is fed in the bidirectional LSTM along with the original words. The strength of this method relies in being end-to-end, as the model jointly learns to detect entities and relations. The architecture is quite heavy and the authors use many tricks for training (such as &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/pdf/1506.03099v3.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;schedule sampling&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/abs/1412.1353&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;entity pre-training&lt;/a&gt;). Those tricks significantly improve the performance of the trained model. This method outperforms state-of-the art results on the relation-extraction task on ACE04 and ACE05 datasets and on relation classification on SemEval-2010 Task 8 development set. More than 80% of entities and 60% of relations can be discovered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;3559&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://blog.heuritech.com/2016/04/15/knowledge-extraction-from-unstructured-texts/bidirlstm/#main&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://heuritech.files.wordpress.com/2016/04/bidirlstm.png&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;6029,3681&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;bidirlstm&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://heuritech.files.wordpress.com/2016/04/bidirlstm.png?w=300&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://heuritech.files.wordpress.com/2016/04/bidirlstm.png?w=470&quot; class=&quot; wp-image-3559 alignright&quot; src=&quot;https://heuritech.files.wordpress.com/2016/04/bidirlstm.png?w=247&amp;amp;h=151&quot; alt=&quot;bidirlstm.png&quot; width=&quot;247&quot; height=&quot;151&quot; srcset=&quot;https://heuritech.files.wordpress.com/2016/04/bidirlstm.png?w=247&amp;amp;h=151 247w, https://heuritech.files.wordpress.com/2016/04/bidirlstm.png?w=494&amp;amp;h=302 494w, https://heuritech.files.wordpress.com/2016/04/bidirlstm.png?w=150&amp;amp;h=92 150w, https://heuritech.files.wordpress.com/2016/04/bidirlstm.png?w=300&amp;amp;h=183 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 247px) 100vw, 247px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/abs/1601.01280&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Language to Logical Form with neural attention&lt;/a&gt; by Dong and Lapata describes a sequence-to-sequence model. It takes a raw sentence as input (no need of POS tagging) and outputs desired information. In our case, the desired information is the triplet (&lt;em&gt;e1&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;r&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;e2&lt;/em&gt;) but the model of the original paper is not restricted to this particular case. The model is an encoder-decoder architecture. More precisely, LSTM units are distributed in two stacked layers and an attention mechanism is used (&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.heuritech.com/2016/01/20/attention-mechanism/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;see our other blog post for more details on attention mechanism&lt;/a&gt;). The attention mechanism makes it possible to learn a soft alignment between natural language expressions and fixed-schema relations. Rare words and numbers are handled in a post-processing step: they are masked during training with a rare-word-token or a number-token as well as a unique ID. At inference, the token+ID is replaced by the true value of word or of the number. This trick happens to be very useful to avoid having too big dictionaries. The results of the experiments reach state-of-the art results, sometimes even outperforming them. Note that the experiments are not done specifically on triplet extraction so we cannot compare this method with the model of Miwa and Bansal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supervised learning for relation extraction works well with end-to-end methods (in the case of the second article reviewed here, they do not even require POS tagging). However, this kind of learning is limited by the amount of labelled data while raw texts available on the web are virtually unlimited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Schema-based distant supervision&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Distant supervision&lt;/em&gt;, also called &lt;em&gt;weak supervision&lt;/em&gt;, is when we wish to extract relations from a text and that an initial KG is available, as a seed, for the triplet extraction task. We say that a pair of entities is &lt;em&gt;weakly-supervised&lt;/em&gt; by every relation of the KG that links the two entities of the pair. Of course, this kind of supervision is very noisy as for example the sentence « Barack Obama is 3 years older than Michelle Obama » will be weakly-labeled by the (Barack Obama, maried-to, Michelle Obama) instance of the KG (and all the other instances linking Barack Obama to his wife) but those two relations are obviously different. If we have a lot of texts and a big enough KG (with the same entities as the ones in the texts) we can learn a mapping from raw text to fixed-schema relations of the KG.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/abs/1307.7973&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Connecting Language and Knowledge Bases with Embedding Models for Relation Extraction&lt;/a&gt; by Weston, Bordes et al. (2013) is a model with distant supervision. It assumes that entities are discovered and disambiguated and the text between entities is converted in an open-domain relation using the OpenIE tool. An embedding of entities and relations is created in a same low-dimensional space. The mapping of openIE texts to most likely relations of the fixed schema is computed with a similarity measure over the embedding of the openIE text and the relations of the fixed schema. The system is trained with a ranking loss (as explained &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thespermwhale.com/jaseweston/papers/ambig-icml.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;). Given an openIE relation, the idea is to assign a higher score to a pair with one of its weak-labels than to a pair with a random relation of the KB (negative sampling). The article goes even further: once the triplets are extracted from the text, the model learns an embedding of the entities and of the relations. In that embedding, we want the relation &lt;em&gt;r&lt;/em&gt; to correspond to the translation from &lt;em&gt;e1&lt;/em&gt; to &lt;em&gt;e2&lt;/em&gt;. This embedding is created not only with the found triples but also with all the available triples from the original KG.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In all of the examples presented above, the relations found are within a initially proposed fixed-schema. However, as mentioned earlier there does not exist a fixed-schema that perfectly suits all the possible relations a text can express between two entities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Universal schemas&lt;/em&gt; build a KG by embedding both relations of a seed KG (fixed-schema relations) and open-domain relations contained in a corpus. One big advantage of universal-schema is that it does not need distant supervision. A semantic space is built for entities and relations by learning an embedding. The embedding for fixed-schema relations is the same for the open-domain relations: inference regarding the two kinds of relations is made possible and KG completion can then be improved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;3745&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://blog.heuritech.com/2016/04/15/knowledge-extraction-from-unstructured-texts/cf/#main&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://heuritech.files.wordpress.com/2016/04/cf.png&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;4368,5589&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;cf&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://heuritech.files.wordpress.com/2016/04/cf.png?w=234&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://heuritech.files.wordpress.com/2016/04/cf.png?w=470&quot; class=&quot;alignright wp-image-3745&quot; src=&quot;https://heuritech.files.wordpress.com/2016/04/cf.png?w=215&amp;amp;h=275&quot; alt=&quot;cf.png&quot; width=&quot;215&quot; height=&quot;275&quot; srcset=&quot;https://heuritech.files.wordpress.com/2016/04/cf.png?w=215&amp;amp;h=275 215w, https://heuritech.files.wordpress.com/2016/04/cf.png?w=430&amp;amp;h=550 430w, https://heuritech.files.wordpress.com/2016/04/cf.png?w=117&amp;amp;h=150 117w, https://heuritech.files.wordpress.com/2016/04/cf.png?w=234&amp;amp;h=300 234w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 215px) 100vw, 215px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first article that introduces universal schema is &lt;a href=&quot;https://people.cs.umass.edu/~lmyao/papers/univ-schema-tacl.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Relation Extraction with Matrix Factorization and Universal Schemas&lt;/a&gt; by Riedel et al. in 2013. In this article, open-domain relations are computed with the OpenIE tool. Then a binary matrix is created where rows correspond to pairs of entities and columns to the concatenation of fixed-schema relations and open-domain relations ; a 1 in the matrix means if there is a relation between the entities. We wish to predict missing values in the matrix and produce a confidence value (between 0 and 1) as shown in the picture here from the original paper. The consideration of the matrix brings the problem of relation extraction close to another field: collaborative filtering. Methods of collaborative filtering can then be used to infer new relations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several parametrizations of the embedding methods can be considered: latent feature model, neighborhood model and the entity model or even a combination of them. For training, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/pdf/1205.2618.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Bayesian Personalized Ranking (BPR)&lt;/a&gt; is used ; it is a ranking procedure that gives observed facts a better score than random facts (obtained by negative sampling).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A problem with the above approach is that each openIE text is embedded in a different vector, and so it is not possible to generalize to a new openIE text which was absent from the training set.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Universal schemas with deep learning&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cs.stanford.edu/people/danqi/papers/emnlp2015.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Representing Text for Joint Embedding of Text and Knowledge Bases&lt;/a&gt; by Toutanova et al. (2015) addresses the issue of generalizing to new open-domain relations by embedding the text between entities with a Convolutional Neural Network (ConvNet). Instead of using the openIE tool&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;3795&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://blog.heuritech.com/2016/04/15/knowledge-extraction-from-unstructured-texts/toutanova/#main&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://heuritech.files.wordpress.com/2016/04/toutanova.png&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;7341,4528&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;toutanova&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://heuritech.files.wordpress.com/2016/04/toutanova.png?w=300&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://heuritech.files.wordpress.com/2016/04/toutanova.png?w=470&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-3795&quot; src=&quot;https://heuritech.files.wordpress.com/2016/04/toutanova.png?w=668&quot; alt=&quot;toutanova.png&quot; width=&quot;334&quot; height=&quot;206&quot; srcset=&quot;https://heuritech.files.wordpress.com/2016/04/toutanova.png?w=668 668w, https://heuritech.files.wordpress.com/2016/04/toutanova.png?w=334 334w, https://heuritech.files.wordpress.com/2016/04/toutanova.png?w=150 150w, https://heuritech.files.wordpress.com/2016/04/toutanova.png?w=300 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 334px) 100vw, 334px&quot;/&gt; as in the article presented above, the ConvNet is used to parametrize the text between two entities (at word-level). Syntactic dependency parsing is used and added as extra input. On the picture here, the yellow vector is the embedding of the open-domain relation. Note that embedding similar open-domain relations also avoids the problem of &lt;em&gt;cold-start&lt;/em&gt; in collaborative filtering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/abs/1511.06396&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Multilingual Relation Extraction using Compositional Universal Schema&lt;/a&gt; by Verga et al. (2016) uses the same kind of architecture. They tried both ConvNet and LSTM recurrent neural network and it turns out that the LSTM network outperforms the ConvNet. There are two other differences between their model and the one of Toutanova. The first one is that the encoder network of the open-domain relation is used at inference time when we want to generalize to text without retraining the model. Second, Verga et al. do not use the syntactic dependency parsing information on the raw text. Verga et al. go even further since their model works with multi-lingual data. Importantly, their method performs multilingual transfer learning, providing a predictive model for a language which has no entities in the the KG, by learning identical representation for shared entities across text corpora. The figure below gives an overview of the matrix to be filled and the parametrization model. Note that different encoders (with tied weights) are used for different languages. Interestingly, joint learning of the model for English and Spanish improves the scores for the English only model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;3830&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://blog.heuritech.com/2016/04/15/knowledge-extraction-from-unstructured-texts/mutlilingual/#main&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://heuritech.files.wordpress.com/2016/04/mutlilingual.png&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;10376,4627&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;mutlilingual&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://heuritech.files.wordpress.com/2016/04/mutlilingual.png?w=300&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://heuritech.files.wordpress.com/2016/04/mutlilingual.png?w=470&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-3830&quot; src=&quot;https://heuritech.files.wordpress.com/2016/04/mutlilingual.png?w=470&quot; alt=&quot;mutlilingual&quot; srcset=&quot;https://heuritech.files.wordpress.com/2016/04/mutlilingual.png?w=470 470w, https://heuritech.files.wordpress.com/2016/04/mutlilingual.png?w=940 940w, https://heuritech.files.wordpress.com/2016/04/mutlilingual.png?w=150 150w, https://heuritech.files.wordpress.com/2016/04/mutlilingual.png?w=300 300w, https://heuritech.files.wordpress.com/2016/04/mutlilingual.png?w=768 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 470px) 100vw, 470px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article also underlines that open-domain relations obtained by filtering and normalizing raw text between entities also have an advantage for idiomatic expressions for example when the meaning of the text snippet is not a composition of the words it contains. In this case, we do not want to feed the idiomatic expression to a LSTM network but better learn a unique embedding for it. In practice, the article shows that an ensemble of both embedding parametrizations (LSTM on words and unique embedding) words very well as it takes full advantage of complementary methods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have reviewed here various techniques to infer new relations in a Knowledge Graph and to extract relations from documents. We focused on most recent techniques which rely on embedding of relations and entities, deep learning, collaborative filtering… Further work for us is to consider texts that do not always give absolute and time-invariant knowledge. For example in social media, when people express their opinion, facts can be very different from a person to another one leading to contradictions in a knowledge base. Moreover, at Heuritech we are interested in multi-modal data and so we would like to be able to extract relevant information from images and put it in the same KG as the information found in texts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eloi Zablocki &amp;amp; Team Heuritech&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;jp-post-flair&quot; class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-like-enabled sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;robots-nocontent sd-block sd-social sd-social-icon sd-sharing&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Partager :&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-block sd-like jetpack-likes-widget-wrapper jetpack-likes-widget-unloaded&quot; id=&quot;like-post-wrapper-85233566-2621-5ceb985dd0fdc&quot; data-src=&quot;//widgets.wp.com/likes/index.html?ver=20190321#blog_id=85233566&amp;amp;post_id=2621&amp;amp;origin=heuritech.wordpress.com&amp;amp;obj_id=85233566-2621-5ceb985dd0fdc&amp;amp;domain=blog.heuritech.com&quot; data-name=&quot;like-post-frame-85233566-2621-5ceb985dd0fdc&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;WordPress:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;likes-widget-placeholder post-likes-widget-placeholder&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;button&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;J'aime&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;loading&quot;&gt;chargement…&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;jp-relatedposts&quot; class=&quot;jp-relatedposts&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;jp-relatedposts-headline&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sur le même thème&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2019 14:34:28 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>homarp</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Knowledge extraction from unstructured texts</og:title>
<og:url>https://blog.heuritech.com/2016/04/15/knowledge-extraction-from-unstructured-texts/</og:url>
<og:description>Foreword There is an unreasonable amount of information that can be extracted from what people publicly say on the internet. At Heuritech we use this information to better understand what people wa…</og:description>
<og:image>https://heuritech.files.wordpress.com/2016/04/graph.png</og:image>
<dc:language>fr-FR</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.heuritech.com/2016/04/15/knowledge-extraction-from-unstructured-texts/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>‘If I disappear’: Chinese students make farewell messages amid crackdowns</title>
<link>https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/asia_pacific/if-i-disappear-chinese-students-make-farewell-messages-amid-crackdowns-over-labor-activism-/2019/05/25/6fc949c0-727d-11e9-9331-30bc5836f48e_story.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/asia_pacific/if-i-disappear-chinese-students-make-farewell-messages-amid-crackdowns-over-labor-activism-/2019/05/25/6fc949c0-727d-11e9-9331-30bc5836f48e_story.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div data-elm-loc=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;inline-content inline-video&quot;&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;1&quot; class=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dateline&quot;&gt;BEIJING —&lt;/span&gt; The video opens with the 21-year-old sociology student facing the camera. His voice quivers as he recounts his interrogation — his humiliation — for days at the hands of Beijing police.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;2&quot;&gt;The officials pressured him to quit labor activism and drop out of Peking University, he says. They slapped him until blood streamed from his nose. They jammed headphones into his ears and played hours of propaganda at full volume. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;3&quot;&gt;On the last day, he alleges, they had him bend over a table naked and spread his buttocks, joking darkly that they would teach him how to insert a listening device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;4&quot;&gt;“This all happened on campus,” Qiu Zhanxuan seethes in the video he recorded in February after he said the police released him, temporarily, after a four-day ordeal. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;5&quot;&gt;“If I disappear,” he adds, “it’ll be because of them.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;6&quot;&gt;Qiu disappeared April 29.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;7&quot;&gt;State security agents seized him that day from Beijing’s outskirts, his classmates say. Qiu’s offense? He was the leader of the Marxist student association at the elite Peking University, a communist of conscience who defied the Communist Party of China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;8&quot;&gt;Over the past eight months, China’s ruling party has gone to extraordinary lengths to shut down the small club of students at the country’s top university. Peking University’s young Marxists drew the government’s ire after they campaigned for workers’ rights and openly criticized social inequality and corruption in China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;9&quot;&gt;That alone was provocative. In recent years, China’s leaders have been highly sensitive to rumblings of labor unrest as the sputtering economy lays bare the divides between rich and poor — fissures that were formed, and mostly overlooked, during decades of white-hot growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;10&quot;&gt;But the source of the dissent carried an extra sting for the government. Peking University, after all, educates China’s best and brightest, the top 0.1 percent of the country’s high school graduates. And its rebellious young Marxists were doing something particularly embarrassing: They were standing up for disenfranchised workers against the state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;11&quot;&gt;They were, in other words, emulating the early Communist Party itself.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;12&quot;&gt;Today, at least 21 members of Peking University’s Marxist society — including its slight but steely leader Qiu — have been placed under house arrest or have vanished altogether. Scores more are regularly hauled in for interrogation and live under constant surveillance. Months of clashes, five waves of arrests and an influx of plainclothes police have, at moments, turned a world-leading university into a surreal battleground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;13&quot; class=&quot;interstitial-link&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;[&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/asia_pacific/with-wider-crackdowns-on-religion-xis-china-seeks-to-put-state-stamp-on-faith/2018/09/15/b035e704-b7f0-11e8-b79f-f6e31e555258_story.html?utm_term=.cec0d90a5f96&quot;&gt;With wider crackdowns on religion, Xi’s China seeks to put stamp on faith&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;14&quot;&gt;The story of Peking University’s Marxist club — as told by four members who remain secretly active and spoke on the condition of anonymity for their safety, their supporters, and a trove of writings and videos left by activists anticipating arrest — illustrates the anxious political atmosphere in China, where idealistic students who embrace the party’s own ideology can be suppressed just like any other political threat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;15&quot;&gt;It poses wider questions that go to the heart of modern China: What exactly does the Communist Party stand for? What gives it the right to rule?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;16&quot;&gt;Since rising to power in 2012, Chinese leader Xi Jinping has repeatedly warned his Communist Party that it needs to win back the public’s faith by alleviating poverty, rooting out corrupt officials and ramping up nationalist education and propaganda work. But often, the public just doesn’t buy it.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;17&quot;&gt;“The government stopped caring for workers long ago. It only cares about holding onto power and wealth,” a 20-something Peking University Marxist who asked to be identified as Michael said by encrypted messaging app. (Many young Chinese people use Western nicknames.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;18&quot;&gt;All over China, social friction has been rising, inflamed by decades of breakneck growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;19&quot;&gt;In the south, labor disputes are ticking up again after falling for a decade. In the north, Beijing officials provoked a national outcry last winter after they forcibly expelled communities of migrant workers from the capital. In China’s heartland, a city last year was occupied by thousands of decommissioned, jobless soldiers petitioning for compensation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;20&quot;&gt;Each challenge to authority was supported, in part, by students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;21&quot;&gt;“The government is scared because the domestic contradictions are growing,” Michael said. “Once you study Marxism, you know real socialism and China’s so-called socialism with Chinese characteristics are two different things. They sell fascism as socialism, like a street vendor passes off dog meat as lamb.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div data-elm-loc=&quot;22&quot; class=&quot;subhead&quot;&gt;Singing 'The Internationale'&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;23&quot;&gt;Sprawling behind large gates made of vermilion-painted wood and curved tiles, Peking University’s campus in northwest Beijing has been, for a century, home to China’s intellectual vanguard and future leaders, its troublemakers and its revolutionaries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;24&quot;&gt;A young Mao Zedong found Marxist-Leninism when he worked in the campus library. Peking University’s students marched in the May 4, 1919, protests against Western colonialism, a seminal moment in Chinese political activism. The same school led the occupation of Tiananmen Square, 30 years ago in 1989, before the government sent in soldiers and tanks, killing hundreds, perhaps far more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;25&quot;&gt;As China promoted dizzying free-market reforms in the 1990s, some Peking University students cut the other direction. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;26&quot;&gt;The Marxist association was formed in 2000 by students concerned about the economic dislocation and inequality already percolating around them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;27&quot;&gt;In the years that followed, the students would travel weekly to textile and electronics factories in Beijing’s outskirts. They joined assembly lines and slept and ate in dormitories to taste life at the foot of society. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;28&quot;&gt;For many, it was an ideological crucible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;29&quot;&gt;A Marxist student who asked to be identified as Lucy worked at a print factory moving books and applying labels in southeast Beijing. She spent 12-hour shifts doing repetitive motions thousands of times, until her back was sore and her legs numb. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;30&quot;&gt;She was lucky she didn’t have to provide for a family on the $300- to $450-a-month salaries like the workers beside her, she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;31&quot;&gt;“But it was precisely the experiencing and understanding of workers’ lives that put you on the path of actually practicing Marxism,” she said. “That painful suffering is the daily existence for 300 million Chinese.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;32&quot;&gt;In 2013, the group established a “workers home” on campus modeled after the social club formed in the 1920s by the Communist Party founding father and Peking University alumnus Deng Zhongxia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div data-elm-loc=&quot;33&quot; class=&quot;inline-content inline-photo inline-photo-center&quot;&gt; &lt;img class=&quot;unprocessed _3-to-2 placeholder&quot; src=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/TXJKur-cQ3m4AF9lqk_kkjfemkk=/3x2/www.washingtonpost.com/pb/resources/img/spacer.gif&quot; data-hi-res-src=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/4OTTd8wrsbSHCtZJbHSfonnWhIY=/554x0/arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/SYKKYFD4ZUI6TMPTWIZ74WAR54.jpg&quot; data-low-res-src=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/osVObcYmLlKnTUNvAb3m2Z3FZ1c=/480x0/arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/SYKKYFD4ZUI6TMPTWIZ74WAR54.jpg&quot; data-raw-src=&quot;https://arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/SYKKYFD4ZUI6TMPTWIZ74WAR54.jpg&quot; data-threshold=&quot;480&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pb-caption&quot;&gt;Qiu Zhanxuan, the former leader of the Peking University Marxist society, had a political awakening when he arrived at the university, the alma mater for Chinese Communist revolutionaries including Li Dazhao. (Obtained by The Washington Post)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;34&quot;&gt;The young Marxists would offer night classes on labor law, play chess and dance with the university’s cafeteria workers and janitors. On May Day and at year-end, students recalled, as many as 400 university workers would show up and sing “The Internationale” or early communist songs such as “The Ballad of the Anyuan Road Miners” that commemorated Mao organizing a 1922 strike.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;35&quot;&gt;Their membership swelled, too, to include humanities majors, medical students and budding scientists. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;36&quot;&gt;There was Zhan Zhenzhen, who was raised in a brick hut in Henan province by a single mother and didn’t know what staggering wealth looked like until he arrived in Beijing. There was Yue Xin, the daughter of a well-off Beijing family who brought the #MeToo movement to national attention in China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;37&quot; class=&quot;interstitial-link&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;[&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/2019/02/21/how-china-tried-stop-my-freedom-speech-canada/?utm_term=.17ad6fe9c464&quot;&gt;Opinion: How China tried to stop by freedom of speech — in Canada&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;38&quot;&gt;And there was Qiu, their leader, who arrived on a rare full scholarship in 2016 after he won the gold medal in the national Chemistry Olympiad. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;39&quot;&gt;In a written statement he would later release, Qiu described his political evolution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;40&quot;&gt;Qiu’s father, laid off by the state during China’s 1990s reforms, had managed to start a new career with his technical skills. But Qiu’s uncles, who lost their jobs, were left behind as China veered toward capitalism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;41&quot;&gt;“My father got on the last bus of ‘Reform and Opening Up,’ ” Qiu wrote, using one of the slogans from China’s turn toward a greater free market. Qiu recalled how his uncles couldn’t even afford to make $1.50 bets when the family played mah-jongg.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;42&quot;&gt;“I felt the sense of inferiority in my cousins’ eyes,” he wrote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;43&quot;&gt;Pun Ngai, a sociologist at Hong Kong University who has known the student group for years, said Qiu idolized a charismatic older member of the society named He Pengchao, who had obtained a PhD in environmental science at Peking University but left his career to start a labor nonprofit in Shenzhen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;44&quot;&gt;By his second year, Qiu joined the Marxist club and switched his major from chemistry to sociology. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;45&quot;&gt;On the WeChat social network, Qiu started posting on social issues. He turned his avatar into a picture of him clenching his fist in a Communist salute in front of a bust of Li Dazhao, the party co-founder. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;46&quot;&gt;That year, Qiu, a sophomore, became the group’s president.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;47&quot;&gt;A leftist blogger from eastern China who knows Qiu said it’s possible the government is holding some young Marxists until after the sensitive anniversary of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/asia_pacific/chinas-xi-looks-to-stoke-nationalism-as-tiananmen-anniversary-approaches/2019/04/30/41caddb0-6b3c-11e9-9d56-1c0cf2c7ac04_story.html?utm_term=.17727547c2f0&quot;&gt;Tiananmen crackdown&lt;/a&gt; on June 4, and then will release them on the condition they give up activism. But the government tried that before, he said.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;48&quot;&gt;“They would grab them, rough them up a bit, scare them, then release them,” said the blogger, who spoke on the condition of anonymity over fear of reprisals from officials. “But then the students would go right back to activism.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;49&quot;&gt;He chuckled. “It’s like they’re not scared of dying,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div data-elm-loc=&quot;50&quot; class=&quot;subhead&quot;&gt;Warning shot&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;51&quot;&gt;Last July, the students got word that workers at a welding equipment plant near Shenzhen, called Jasic Technology, were struggling to form an independent union and clashing with factory bosses and police.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div data-elm-loc=&quot;52&quot; class=&quot;inline-content inline-photo inline-photo-normal&quot;&gt; &lt;img class=&quot;unprocessed _3-to-2 placeholder&quot; src=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/TXJKur-cQ3m4AF9lqk_kkjfemkk=/3x2/www.washingtonpost.com/pb/resources/img/spacer.gif&quot; data-hi-res-src=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/Mc3rTMqZSgQIH0-oeRP4DEgbQUk=/1484x0/arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/TCPJFHD4ZUI6TMPTWIZ74WAR54.jpg&quot; data-low-res-src=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/R1hC0X3qJ4Q0gYuyX3yGiojMk1A=/480x0/arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/TCPJFHD4ZUI6TMPTWIZ74WAR54.jpg&quot; data-raw-src=&quot;https://arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/TCPJFHD4ZUI6TMPTWIZ74WAR54.jpg&quot; data-threshold=&quot;480&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pb-caption&quot;&gt;Protesters demonstrate in support of factory workers of Jasic Technology, outside Yanziling police station in Shenzhen in August 2018. (Sue-Lin Wong/Reuters)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;53&quot;&gt;About 50 students traveled south to help, not just from Peking University but also from Renmin and Tsinghua universities in Beijing and schools in southern and eastern China. Cramming into a large apartment, they churned out online essays that got hundreds of supportive responses. At night, they rallied Jasic workers in the streets with megaphones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;54&quot;&gt;Their triumph was short-lived. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;55&quot;&gt;On Aug. 24, police in riot gear raided their apartment, leading to a brief scuffle before dozens of students and workers were detained. Most were released, but four went missing, including Yue, the prominent feminist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;56&quot;&gt;In the aftermath, state media sent a warning shot to the students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;57&quot; class=&quot;interstitial-link&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;[&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2019/04/15/his-death-years-ago-today-was-spark-tiananmen-square-protests/?utm_term=.76f4d4500f8b&quot;&gt;His death 30 years ago sparked the Tiananmen protests&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;58&quot;&gt;In a report, the official Xinhua News Agency avoided mentioning the involvement of students in the Jasic protests. But Xinhua reported that Jasic workers were receiving funding from an illegal, foreign source. Such allegations in Chinese state media can portend prosecutors bringing serious subversion charges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;59&quot;&gt;When they returned to campus, the students were individually summoned to meet with police. One student, Lucy, recalled the police offering her a choice: confess that they broke the law and quit activism, and the police would drop the matter, maybe even help her secure a spot in graduate school. Don’t confess, they said, and she could be forced to drop out and arrested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;60&quot;&gt;The conversations, Lucy said, were “totally unvarnished.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;61&quot;&gt;In the weeks after that, the disappearances started to mount.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;62&quot;&gt;An officer at the Yanyuan police station near the university, where students said they were usually interrogated, declined to comment about the cases or about Qiu and his allegations of mistreatment. Peking University declined to answer faxed questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div data-elm-loc=&quot;63&quot; class=&quot;subhead&quot;&gt;'Looking at a reflection'&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;64&quot;&gt;As the Marxist students came under attack last year, they sought help from Hu Jia, a veteran dissident who sits on the opposite end of the political spectrum. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;65&quot;&gt;Hu, who has been jailed in the past for advocating Western-style democracy, loathed how the students called for a reprise of the Cultural Revolution and wrote essays larded with propaganda language. But he helped introduce them to foreign diplomats and human rights organizations, he explained, because they seemed “righteous.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;66&quot;&gt;They had the potential to be the most serious threat to the government since the Tiananmen protests, Hu said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;67&quot;&gt;“The Communist Party knows there is no greater threat than a movement that links students with the lower class,” Hu said by telephone. “They’re looking at a reflection of their early revolutionary selves.”&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;68&quot;&gt;Perhaps sensing the potential for unrest, the Communist Party in October appointed Qiu Shuiping, a former head of the Beijing branch of the Ministry of State Security — the feared foreign and domestic spy agency — to be Peking University’s new top official.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;69&quot;&gt;But the more authorities clamped down, the more the students defied them by airing what was happening on Twitter and the hosting service GitHub, services beyond the reach of Chinese censors.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;70&quot;&gt;They publicized how unidentified thugs beat up their Marxist schoolmate Zhang Shengye on campus in November before taking him away. They posted pictures of Qiu, their leader, being stuffed into a black car in broad daylight on Dec. 26 — one of several run-ins he had with state security. An uploaded video from Dec. 28 showed campus security clearing Marxists from a science building, ending with a student sprawled on the ground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;71&quot;&gt;That day, the university issued a decree that effectively disbanded the club. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div data-elm-loc=&quot;72&quot; class=&quot;inline-content inline-photo inline-photo-normal&quot;&gt; &lt;img class=&quot;unprocessed _3-to-2 placeholder&quot; src=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/TXJKur-cQ3m4AF9lqk_kkjfemkk=/3x2/www.washingtonpost.com/pb/resources/img/spacer.gif&quot; data-hi-res-src=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/z8UIfELwI40U8tjeZftB9ooU7d0=/1484x0/arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/STSAXUT4ZUI6TMPTWIZ74WAR54.jpg&quot; data-low-res-src=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/WnpJHMvRsLBN76ql_KXvDgfIsxE=/480x0/arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/STSAXUT4ZUI6TMPTWIZ74WAR54.jpg&quot; data-raw-src=&quot;https://arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/STSAXUT4ZUI6TMPTWIZ74WAR54.jpg&quot; data-threshold=&quot;480&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pb-caption&quot;&gt;A dozen students from Peking University staged a protest on Dec. 28, 2018, after the school removed the president of an on-campus Marxist group amid an ongoing crackdown on student activists. (Eva Xiao/AFP/Getty Images)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;73&quot;&gt;To irritate the plainclothes agents who followed them, some members would continue to get together anyway — to do calisthenics. Qiu kept leading “work experience” trips for a few more months. The authorities had enough on April 29, when they seized Qiu and four other students from a Beijing factory at 8:17 a.m., the club reported in an online post. Those five haven’t been seen since.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;74&quot;&gt;“I don’t support students being naive, opposing the government,” Qiu Shike, a socialist writer and Xi supporter who is influential within some elite Communist Party circles, said carefully. “But to handle them with force seems a bit low. Why not take the high road? Have an open debate with them, or talk sense into them about why they’re wrong?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;75&quot;&gt;As the number of missing students ticked up in recent months, those who still had freedom prepared “open letters” to be published in case they were seized. The remaining Marxists, coordinating in secret, recently started releasing the letters at a slow drip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;76&quot;&gt;They saved Qiu’s video and letter to release on May 4, on the anniversary of the protest that inspired their Communist revolutionary heroes a century ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;77&quot;&gt;Qiu’s letter defiantly recounted his personal life and his experiences with the police. “The deeper the persecution, the greater the blows, the more hatred one remembers in his heart,” he wrote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;78&quot;&gt;In the accompanying video, Qiu seems more vulnerable. He ponders what kind of abuse workers who challenge government authority must suffer in prison, and whether he might join them himself. But his voice hardens by the end of the three-minute recording.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;79&quot;&gt;“We’ll fight together, advance and retreat together,” Qiu says, and then raises a clenched fist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;81&quot; class=&quot;interstitial-link&quot;&gt;            &lt;strong&gt;Read more&lt;/strong&gt;         &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;82&quot; class=&quot;interstitial-link&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/asia_pacific/after-chinas-deadly-chemical-disaster-a-shattered-region-weighs-cost-of-the-rush-to-get-rich/2019/03/31/78cf3a5c-508b-11e9-bdb7-44f948cc0605_story.html?utm_term=.6339885a3bfa&quot;&gt; After chemical plant disaster, a Chinese region weighs cost of rush to ‘get rich’&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;83&quot; class=&quot;interstitial-link&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/asia_pacific/chinese-censors-go-old-school-to-clamp-down-on-twitter-a-knock-on-the-door/2019/01/04/1bd462e4-f331-11e8-9240-e8028a62c722_story.html?utm_term=.0299e302488c&quot;&gt; Chinese censors go old school against Twitter: A knock on the door&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;84&quot; class=&quot;interstitial-link&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/asia_pacific/hong-kong-court-imprisons-umbrella-movement-leaders-for-up-to-16-months/2019/04/24/ebf26586-6643-11e9-83df-04f4d124151f_story.html?utm_term=.8379fc38dbcd&quot;&gt; Hong Kong court jails ‘umbrella movement’ leaders&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;85&quot; class=&quot;interstitial-link&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.washingtonpost.com/world&quot;&gt;            Today’s coverage from Post correspondents around the world            &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-elm-loc=&quot;86&quot; class=&quot;interstitial-link&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/washingtonpostworld/&quot;&gt;            Like Washington Post World on Facebook and stay updated on foreign news         &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2019 10:34:59 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>abc-xyz</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/asia_pacific/if-i-disappear-chinese-students-make-farewell-messages-amid-crackdowns-over-labor-activism-/2019/05/25/6fc949c0-727d-11e9-9331-30bc5836f48e_story.html</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/Mc3rTMqZSgQIH0-oeRP4DEgbQUk=/1484x0/arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/TCPJFHD4ZUI6TMPTWIZ74WAR54.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>‘If I disappear’: Chinese students make farewell messages amid crackdowns over labor activism  </og:title>
<og:description>The elite Peking University has become a battleground in a rarefied ideological battle over worker conditions and rights in modern China.    </og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/asia_pacific/if-i-disappear-chinese-students-make-farewell-messages-amid-crackdowns-over-labor-activism-/2019/05/25/6fc949c0-727d-11e9-9331-30bc5836f48e_story.html?noredirect=on</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Logical fallacies in software engineering</title>
<link>https://artur-martsinkovskyi.github.io/2018/logical-fallacies-in-programming/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://artur-martsinkovskyi.github.io/2018/logical-fallacies-in-programming/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Ideas may fall short if they are fallacious and software engineering is full of ideas. Lets break some of the fallacies down to make ourselves better engineers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://artur-martsinkovskyi.github.io/assets/images/brain.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Brain&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A human brain is a complex machine that evolved over millennia. It works in the most peculiar ways possible and allows us to excel both at perception, dexterity and mind work. Some of its functions are a bit hacky. There are a lot of stereotypes and shortcuts that our mind takes in order to be more efficient and take less energy to fulfill the task. It helps most of the time although, being overwhelmingly erroneous at times, so that it leans you to the wrong decision, building an incorrect map of reality. The lenses of your perception may be flawed, the mechanism that grinds up the information you collect may be malfunctioning, your mapping can be highly incorrect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Such errors have a name. This name is ‘fallacy’. A fallacy is reasoning that is evaluated as logically incorrect and that undermines the logical validity of the argument and permits its recognition as unsound.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like other people of mind work, software engineers require a lot of thinking, analysis, and mapping of reality to fulfill their job. While doing these processes, our mind sometimes takes shorter routes to reach the destination, leading to wrong decisions or poor planning. To avoid that it is better to know your flaws.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mind processes are complex and multicontextual, so are the fallacies one may fall for on the way of thinking. Although, there are some that I consider interesting for a software engineer. Here they are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nirvana fallacy (perfect-solution fallacy) – solutions to problems are rejected because they are not perfect. This is the common problem expirienced developers have. They know how things should be, and what would be the best option for the current issue, even though it may be time-consuming and harder to graps from an outsiders perspective. Holistic solutions are beautiful and elegant, but real world deadlines and realities dictate otherwise. It is better to steer perfectionists tendentions to the project architectural uniformity, startup time, environment, log output and other ongoing metrics than attention to one particular piece of code. Even though there are people building cathedrals, most of us work on the Ford assembly line, where proper processes, isomorphy and clean workplace win the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Appeal to authority (argument from authority, argumentum ad verecundiam) – an assertion is deemed true because of the position or authority of the person asserting it. When explaining practices or opinions on some subjects of sofware development, project management, operations, e.t.c, people tend to use somebody elses saying, blogpost, conference talk or other claim as a foundation for justification of their own decision. Even though it might not always be fallacious, mostly it is better to add more contextual arguments that apply to specific solution or project rather than appealing to authority.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Historian’s fallacy – the assumption that decision makers of the past viewed events from the same perspective and had the same information as those subsequently analyzing the decision. This fallacy frequently arises when a progammer is working with legacy code. It is important to remeber that decisions of the past were not done by people who wanted to do wrong. Most likely, their poor coding standards, entangled code structure or confusing library choise had some reasonable background, related either to hardly structured development process, everchanging requirements or inadequate deadlines. However, there are obviously some really bad engineers out there also.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Misleading vividness – involves describing an occurrence in vivid detail, even if it is an exceptional occurrence, to convince someone that it is a problem; this also relies on the appeal to emotion fallacy. Some engineers may use such fallacy, exposing all the technicalities of their job to cover incompetence and justify failure in rolling out feature in time. It is better to judge on the actual context and possible outcome, not solely on the explanation of fellow engineer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Survivorship bias – a small number of successes of a given process are actively promoted while completely ignoring a large number of failures. This one is especially important for the people with business mindset that want to open a startup or enterprise. They tend to learn the success stories of prominent companies, which may be an exception, rather then a rule. Thousands of startups fail each year and only a few survive to succeed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We, engineers, tend to recheck and test artifacts of our work. Our systems have to work properly and bugs have to be eliminated at sight in order for us to be proud of our work. However, there is more to it. Our systems have defects and so do we. We need to seek for bugs in our minds, not only in our systems. If system that creates systems is not working properly, no wonder its product will be broken too. Remember: errors are not a sin, it is sin to ignore them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2019 09:38:06 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>gentleterror</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://artur-martsinkovskyi.github.io//2018/logical-fallacies-in-programming/</og:url>
<og:title> Logical fallacies in software engineering | AMBlog</og:title>
<og:image>https://artur-martsinkovskyi.github.io/</og:image>
<og:description> Programmer's delight.</og:description>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://artur-martsinkovskyi.github.io/2018/logical-fallacies-in-programming/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Bose headphones spy on listeners: lawsuit (2017)</title>
<link>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-bose-lawsuit-idUSKBN17L2BT</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.reuters.com/article/us-bose-lawsuit-idUSKBN17L2BT</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;(Reuters) - Bose Corp spies on its wireless headphone customers by using an app that tracks the music, podcasts and other audio they listen to, and violates their privacy rights by selling the information without permission, a lawsuit charged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;PrimaryAsset_container&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Image_container&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;LazyImage_container LazyImage_dark&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s4.reutersmedia.net/resources/r/?m=02&amp;amp;d=20170419&amp;amp;t=2&amp;amp;i=1181264387&amp;amp;r=LYNXMPED3I1C8&amp;amp;w=20&quot; aria-label=&quot;Bose wireless headphones are pictured in Encinitas, California, United States in this April 19, 2017 photo illustration. REUTERS/Mike Blake&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Bose wireless headphones are pictured in Encinitas, California, United States in this April 19, 2017 photo illustration. REUTERS/Mike Blake&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The complaint filed on Tuesday by Kyle Zak in federal court in Chicago seeks an injunction to stop Bose’s “wholesale disregard” for the privacy of customers who download its free Bose Connect app from Apple Inc or Google Play stores to their smartphones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MORE FROM REUTERS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reuters.com/investigates/special-report/usa-lead-la/&quot;&gt;Reuters investigates: Lead poisons children in L.A., both rich and poor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reuters.com/article/us-verizon-results-idUSKBN17M1BM&quot;&gt;Verizon experiences subscribers' exodus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reuters.com/article/us-venezuela-politics-idUSKBN17M1OO&quot;&gt;Civil unrest rocks Venezuela&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“People should be uncomfortable with it,” Christopher Dore, a lawyer representing Zak, said in an interview. “People put headphones on their head because they think it’s private, but they can be giving out information they don’t want to share.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bose did not respond on Wednesday to requests for comment on the proposed class action case. The Framingham, Massachusetts-based company has said annual sales top $3.5 billion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zak’s lawsuit was the latest to accuse companies of trying to boost profit by quietly amassing customer information, and then selling it or using it to solicit more business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After paying $350 for his QuietComfort 35 headphones, Zak said he took Bose’s suggestion to “get the most out of your headphones” by downloading its app, and providing his name, email address and headphone serial number in the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the Illinois resident said he was surprised to learn that Bose sent “all available media information” from his smartphone to third parties such as Segment.io, whose website promises to collect customer data and “send it anywhere.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Audio choices offer “an incredible amount of insight” into customers’ personalities, behavior, politics and religious views, citing as an example that a person who listens to Muslim prayers might “very likely” be a Muslim, the complaint said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Defendants’ conduct demonstrates a wholesale disregard for consumer privacy rights,” the complaint said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zak is seeking millions of dollars of damages for buyers of headphones and speakers, including QuietComfort 35, QuietControl 30, SoundLink Around-Ear Wireless Headphones II, SoundLink Color II, SoundSport Wireless and SoundSport Pulse Wireless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He also wants a halt to the data collection, which he said violates the federal Wiretap Act and Illinois laws against eavesdropping and consumer fraud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Slideshow_container Slideshow_small Slideshow_standard&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Slideshow_preview-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;LazyImage_container LazyImage_dark&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.reutersmedia.net/resources/r/?m=02&amp;amp;d=20170419&amp;amp;t=2&amp;amp;i=1181264386&amp;amp;r=LYNXMPED3I1C6&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

Slideshow &lt;span class=&quot;Slideshow_count&quot;&gt;(3 Images)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dore, a partner at Edelson PC, said customers do not see the Bose app’s user service and privacy agreements when signing up, and the privacy agreement says nothing about data collection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edelson specializes in suing technology companies over alleged privacy violations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case is Zak v Bose Corp, U.S. District Court, Northern District of Illinois, No. 17-02928.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Attribution_container&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Attribution_attribution&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Attribution_content&quot;&gt;Reporting by Jonathan Stempel in New York; Editing by David Gregorio&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;StandardArticleBody_trustBadgeContainer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;StandardArticleBody_trustBadgeTitle&quot;&gt;Our Standards:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;trustBadgeUrl&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thomsonreuters.com/en/about-us/trust-principles.html&quot;&gt;The Thomson Reuters Trust Principles.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2019 07:34:50 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>88840-8855</dc:creator>
<og:title>Bose headphones spy on listeners: lawsuit</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-bose-lawsuit-idUSKBN17L2BT</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>Bose Corp spies on its wireless headphone customers by using an app that tracks ...</og:description>
<og:image>https://s4.reutersmedia.net/resources/r/?m=02&amp;d=20170419&amp;t=2&amp;i=1181264387&amp;w=1200&amp;r=LYNXMPED3I1C8</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-bose-lawsuit-idUSKBN17L2BT</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Show HN: nextdns.io – A Combination of Cloudflare DNS and Pi-Hole</title>
<link>https://www.nextdns.io/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nextdns.io/</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nextdns.io/&quot;&gt;https://www.nextdns.io/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=20012687&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=20012687&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 324&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 134&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2019 02:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>nextdns</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nextdns.io/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Unexpected Surge in Global Methane Levels</title>
<link>https://climatenexus.org/climate-change-news/methane-surge/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://climatenexus.org/climate-change-news/methane-surge/</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;vc_row wpb_row vc_row-fluid&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wpb_column vc_column_container vc_col-sm-12&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;vc_column-inner&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wpb_wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wpb_text_column wpb_content_element&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wpb_wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An unexpected surge in global atmospheric methane is threatening to erase the anticipated gains of the Paris Climate Agreement.  This past April NOAA posted preliminary data documenting an historic leap in the global level of atmospheric methane in 2018,&lt;a href=&quot;https://climatenexus.org/climate-change-news/methane-surge/#_edn1&quot; name=&quot;_ednref1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt; underscoring a recent wave of science and data reporting that previously stable global methane levels have unexpectedly surged in recent years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The scientific community recently responded to the surge into two high profile publications by calling for a reduction in methane emissions from the natural gas system, framing it as the most practical response to the global increase.&lt;a href=&quot;https://climatenexus.org/climate-change-news/methane-surge/#_edn2&quot; name=&quot;_ednref2&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year global methane reached a new historic high, marking the second highest year-over-year jump recorded over the last 20 years.  More importantly, the jump in 2018 extended an unanticipated multi-year resurgence of growth in global methane levels that has generated enormous concern in the science community. Scientists report that the new and unexpected methane math threatens to eliminate the anticipated gains of the Paris Climate Agreement, an agreement built upon models that assumed stable methane.&lt;a href=&quot;https://climatenexus.org/climate-change-news/methane-surge/#_edn3&quot; name=&quot;_ednref3&quot;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-5257 aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;https://climatenexus.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/ch4_trend_all_gl.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; srcset=&quot;https://climatenexus.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/ch4_trend_all_gl.png 800w, https://climatenexus.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/ch4_trend_all_gl-768x576.png 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The “why” behind this resurgence is hotly debated and not well understood.   That said, most experts in the field suspect that all traditional sources (natural and anthropogenic) are contributing at least in small part to the surge, and that the biggest contributor might be wetlands responding to climate change (though there is some dissent on this point).&lt;a href=&quot;https://climatenexus.org/climate-change-news/methane-surge/#_edn4&quot; name=&quot;_ednref4&quot;&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, the answer to the question about which emissions source is &lt;u&gt;driving&lt;/u&gt; the methane surge is very different from the answer to the question about which emission source is best targeted in order to &lt;u&gt;address&lt;/u&gt; the surge.  It is extremely challenging to control how wetlands respond to climate change (assuming that is the driver).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, there is wide agreement among experts that, regardless of the drivers behind the surge, reducing emissions from fossil-fuel production and distribution, primarily through ending leaks and venting, is one of the few options available to control global methane levels and that this option is the most practical one. In addition, scientists report that there are narrow opportunities to address agricultural emissions, e.g. changes in the diet of livestock can reduce the production of methane without affecting production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Globally anthropogenic methane emissions account for roughly 48% of total methane emissions, and in turn fossil-fuel methane emissions account for roughly 34% of total anthropogenic emissions.&lt;a href=&quot;https://climatenexus.org/climate-change-news/methane-surge/#_edn5&quot; name=&quot;_ednref5&quot;&gt;[5]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the United States, the natural gas and petroleum system is the largest source of methane emissions.&lt;a href=&quot;https://climatenexus.org/climate-change-news/methane-surge/#_edn6&quot; name=&quot;_ednref6&quot;&gt;[6]&lt;/a&gt; The most recent analysis suggests that U.S. methane emissions from oil and gas activity have increased over the last 10 years at 3.4% per year,&lt;a href=&quot;https://climatenexus.org/climate-change-news/methane-surge/#_edn7&quot; name=&quot;_ednref7&quot;&gt;[7]&lt;/a&gt; about 40% over the decade.&lt;a href=&quot;https://climatenexus.org/climate-change-news/methane-surge/#_edn8&quot; name=&quot;_ednref8&quot;&gt;[8]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Background&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methane is a short-lived but super-potent greenhouse gas and is the second most important contributor to anthropogenic global warming after CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;, accounting for one-quarter of the anthropogenic radiative imbalance (the human forcing of warming) since the pre-industrial era.&lt;a href=&quot;https://climatenexus.org/climate-change-news/methane-surge/#_edn9&quot; name=&quot;_ednref9&quot;&gt;[9]&lt;/a&gt; Prior to the industrial era global methane levels were low and relatively stable for the last 800,000 years, ranging from 300–800 ppb.  With the advent of agriculture and then fossil fuel operations, methane levels skyrocketed to more than 1,800 ppb.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting in 1990s, the growth in global methane levels began to slow down, and global methane became relatively stable over the period of 2000-2006.  A resurgence of global methane was not anticipated and came as a surprise.&lt;a href=&quot;https://climatenexus.org/climate-change-news/methane-surge/#_edn10&quot; name=&quot;_ednref10&quot;&gt;[10]&lt;/a&gt; Crucially, methane levels were considered stable in the pathway models prepared for the Paris Climate Agreement.&lt;a href=&quot;https://climatenexus.org/climate-change-news/methane-surge/#_edn11&quot; name=&quot;_ednref11&quot;&gt;[11]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, global methane levels resumed rapid growth starting in 2007.  Growth accelerated further starting in 2014 and extending through 2017.&lt;a href=&quot;https://climatenexus.org/climate-change-news/methane-surge/#_edn12&quot; name=&quot;_ednref12&quot;&gt;[12]&lt;/a&gt; This exceptional growth continued in 2018.&lt;a href=&quot;https://climatenexus.org/climate-change-news/methane-surge/#_edn13&quot; name=&quot;_ednref13&quot;&gt;[13]&lt;/a&gt; NOAA recently announced that the rate of methane increase accelerated over the past five years, jumping 50 percent over the growth rate observed 2007-2013.&lt;a href=&quot;https://climatenexus.org/climate-change-news/methane-surge/#_edn14&quot; name=&quot;_ednref14&quot;&gt;[14]&lt;/a&gt; The sustained growth of the last five years was last observed in the 1980s when the Soviet Union’s gas industry was developing very rapidly.&lt;a href=&quot;https://climatenexus.org/climate-change-news/methane-surge/#_edn15&quot; name=&quot;_ednref15&quot;&gt;[15]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first the durability of this emerging trend was questioned and years of rapid growth were seen as anomalies.&lt;a href=&quot;https://climatenexus.org/climate-change-news/methane-surge/#_edn16&quot; name=&quot;_ednref16&quot;&gt;[16]&lt;/a&gt; However, the period of resumed growth in global methane levels now stands at 12 years (2007-2018) compared to the 7-year period of stable methane levels (2000-2006).  And preliminary data from 2018 indicates that the trend of extraordinarily high growth now stands at 5 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this light the era of stable global methane levels is increasingly seen as the anomaly, and growth in global methane seen as the resumption of a long-standing pattern.&lt;a href=&quot;https://climatenexus.org/climate-change-news/methane-surge/#_edn17&quot; name=&quot;_ednref17&quot;&gt;[17]&lt;/a&gt; This emerging consensus was highlighted in two recent high-profile papers published in 2019 representing the consensus views of a large array of experts in the field.&lt;a href=&quot;https://climatenexus.org/climate-change-news/methane-surge/#_edn18&quot; name=&quot;_ednref18&quot;&gt;[18]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The threat posed by this resumption in methane growth is significant.  A group of 23 scientists recently reported &lt;em&gt;“Thus even if anthropogenic CO2 emissions are successfully constrained to a RCP2.6-like pathway, the unexpected and sustained current rise in methane may so greatly overwhelm all progress from the other reduction efforts that the Paris Agreement will fail.”&lt;a href=&quot;https://climatenexus.org/climate-change-news/methane-surge/#_edn19&quot; name=&quot;_ednref19&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[19]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the resumption of growth in global methane is now well documented, the drivers are less well understood and hotly debated.  Present global environmental monitoring networks only provide sparse information about methane concentrations, making it challenging and complex to distinguish between the myriad individual sources of methane from the fossil fuel industries, and dispersed sources like wetlands and agriculture. Gaps in monitoring also make it impossible to rule out a decrease in the efficacy of natural mechanisms that sweep methane from the atmosphere (aka “sinks”).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Potential drivers in the category of increased emissions include emissions from intensive agricultural practices, emissions from oil and gas operations, and increased emissions from wetlands responding to global warming.  [&lt;em&gt;This last potential driver is particularly worrisome as it implies the engagement of a global warming feedback loop&lt;/em&gt;.]   A number of studies have assigned and evaluated the role of each of these drivers, with different studies assigning greater weight to different drivers; all are generally considered to play at least a minor role.&lt;a href=&quot;https://climatenexus.org/climate-change-news/methane-surge/#_edn20&quot; name=&quot;_ednref20&quot;&gt;[20]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the size of the role of fossil-fuel production and distribution in driving the recent growth of global methane is hotly debated, it is well documented that fossil-fuel production is one of the major drivers in sustaining industrial era methane levels.&lt;a href=&quot;https://climatenexus.org/climate-change-news/methane-surge/#_edn21&quot; name=&quot;_ednref21&quot;&gt;[21]&lt;/a&gt; As a result, reducing fossil-fuel methane emissions would have a significant impact in addressing the methane surge. The lifetime of methane is relatively short (∼11 years), and the elevated global methane levels of the industrial era only occur as a result of large anthropogenic emissions. Finally, fossil-fuel production and distribution is certainly one of the major sources of anthropogenic emissions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fossil-fuel methane emissions are also the most easily addressed source of emissions. The International Energy Agency &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.iea.org/newsroom/news/2017/october/commentary-the-environmental-case-for-natural-gas.html&quot;&gt;estimates&lt;/a&gt; industry can reduce its worldwide emissions by 75 percent—and that up to two-thirds of those reductions (40-50% of total emissions) can be realized at zero net cost.&lt;a href=&quot;https://climatenexus.org/climate-change-news/methane-surge/#_edn22&quot; name=&quot;_ednref22&quot;&gt;[22]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, there are particular opportunities to address emissions from agriculture.&lt;a href=&quot;https://climatenexus.org/climate-change-news/methane-surge/#_edn23&quot; name=&quot;_ednref23&quot;&gt;[23]&lt;/a&gt; Turner et al., 2019,  note that changes in the diet of livestock could reduce the production of methane in dairy cattle without reducing milk production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this context the 23 authors of Nisbet et al wrote: &lt;em&gt;“&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;We may not be able to influence the factors driving the new rise in methane, especially if it is a climate change feedback, but by monitoring, quantifying and reducing the very large anthropogenic inputs, especially from the gas, coal and cattle industries, and perhaps by direct removal, we may be able to cut the total methane burden to be compliant with the Paris goals.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;u&gt;Citations&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dean et al. (2018): Methane Feedbacks to the Global Climate System in a Warmer World. &lt;em&gt;Reviews of Geophysics&lt;/em&gt;. January 2018. &lt;u&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1002/2017RG000559&quot;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1002/2017RG000559&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Howarth (2019): Is Shale Gas a Major Driver of Recent Increase in Global Atmospheric Methane?, &lt;em&gt;Biogeosciences Discuss&lt;/em&gt;., &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.5194/bg-2019-131&quot;&gt;https://doi.org/10.5194/bg-2019-131&lt;/a&gt;, in review, 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jacobson et al. (2018): Chapter 8: Observations of atmospheric carbon dioxide and methane. In &lt;em&gt;Second State of the Carbon Cycle Report (SOCCR2): A Sustained Assessment Report&lt;/em&gt; [Cavallaro, N., G. Shrestha, R. Birdsey, M. A. Mayes, R. G. Najjar, S. C. Reed, P. Romero-Lankao, and Z. Zhu (eds.)]. U.S. Global Change Research Program, Washington, DC, USA, pp. 337-364, &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.7930/SOCCR2.2018.Ch8&quot;&gt;https://doi.org/10.7930/SOCCR2.2018.Ch8&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lan et al. (2019): Long‐Term Measurements Show Little Evidence for Large Increases in Total U.S. Methane Emissions Over the Past Decade. &lt;em&gt;Geophysical Research Letters&lt;/em&gt;. April 2019. &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1029/2018GL081731&quot;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1029/2018GL081731&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lyon and Schwietzke (2019) Does new NOAA study really show that methane emissions have been overestimated? No. &lt;em&gt;Energy Exchange&lt;/em&gt;. EDF. May 2019&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maasakkers et al. (2019): Global distribution of methane emissions, emission trends, and OH concentrations and trends inferred from an inversion of GOSAT satellite data for 2010–2015. &lt;em&gt;Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics&lt;/em&gt;. January&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NOAA AGGI 2019. Rising Emissions Drive Greenhouse Gas Index Increase. &lt;em&gt;NOAA Research News&lt;/em&gt;. 21 May 2019 &lt;a href=&quot;https://research.noaa.gov/article/ArtMID/587/ArticleID/2455/RISING-EMISSIONS-DRIVE-GREENHOUSE-GAS-INDEX-INCREASE&quot;&gt;https://research.noaa.gov/article/ArtMID/587/ArticleID/2455/RISING-EMISSIONS-DRIVE-GREENHOUSE-GAS-INDEX-INCREASE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nisbet et al. (2019): Very Strong Atmospheric Methane Growth in the 4 Years 2014–2017: Implications for the Paris Agreement. &lt;em&gt;Global Biogeochemical Cycles&lt;/em&gt;. March 2019. &lt;u&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1029/2018GB006009&quot;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1029/2018GB006009&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shindell et al. (2017): The social cost of methane: theory and applications. &lt;em&gt;Faraday Discussions.&lt;/em&gt; January 2017 DOI: &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1039/c7fd00009j&quot;&gt;10.1039/c7fd00009j&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turner, Frankenberg, and Kort (2019): Interpreting contemporary trends in atmospheric methane. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences&lt;/em&gt;. 19 February 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Underwood (2019): Rising Methane Emissions Could Derail the Paris Agreement. &lt;em&gt;EOS&lt;/em&gt;. 19 April 2019. &lt;a href=&quot;https://eos.org/research-spotlights/rising-methane-emissions-could-derail-the-paris-agreement&quot;&gt;https://eos.org/research-spotlights/rising-methane-emissions-could-derail-the-paris-agreement&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Worden et al. (2017): Reduced biomass burning emissions reconcile conflicting estimates of the post-2006 atmospheric methane budget. &lt;em&gt;Nature Communications&lt;/em&gt;. December 2017. &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-017-02246-0&quot;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-017-02246-0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://climatenexus.org/climate-change-news/methane-surge/#_ednref1&quot; name=&quot;_edn1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt; NOAA Earth System Research Laboratory Global Monitoring Division.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;https://esrl.noaa.gov/gmd/ccgg/trends_ch4/&quot;&gt;https://esrl.noaa.gov/gmd/ccgg/trends_ch4/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://climatenexus.org/climate-change-news/methane-surge/#_ednref2&quot; name=&quot;_edn2&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt; Nisbet et al., 2019. Turner, Frankenberg, and Kort, 2019.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://climatenexus.org/climate-change-news/methane-surge/#_ednref3&quot; name=&quot;_edn3&quot;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt; Nisbet et al., 2019; Underwood, 2019.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://climatenexus.org/climate-change-news/methane-surge/#_ednref4&quot; name=&quot;_edn4&quot;&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt; Jacobson et al., 2018. Nisbet et al, 2019. Turner, Frankenberg, and Kort, 2019.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://climatenexus.org/climate-change-news/methane-surge/#_ednref5&quot; name=&quot;_edn5&quot;&gt;[5]&lt;/a&gt; Dean et al., 2018.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://climatenexus.org/climate-change-news/methane-surge/#_ednref6&quot; name=&quot;_edn6&quot;&gt;[6]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epa.gov/ghgemissions/overview-greenhouse-gases&quot;&gt;https://www.epa.gov/ghgemissions/overview-greenhouse-gases&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://climatenexus.org/climate-change-news/methane-surge/#_ednref7&quot; name=&quot;_edn7&quot;&gt;[7]&lt;/a&gt; Lan et al. 2019.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://climatenexus.org/climate-change-news/methane-surge/#_ednref8&quot; name=&quot;_edn8&quot;&gt;[8]&lt;/a&gt; Lyon and Schwietzke (2019)&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://climatenexus.org/climate-change-news/methane-surge/#_ednref9&quot; name=&quot;_edn9&quot;&gt;[9]&lt;/a&gt; Turner, Frankenberg, and Kort, 2019.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://climatenexus.org/climate-change-news/methane-surge/#_ednref10&quot; name=&quot;_edn10&quot;&gt;[10]&lt;/a&gt; Nisbet et al., 2019. Turner, Frankenberg, and Kort, 2019. Underwood, 2019.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://climatenexus.org/climate-change-news/methane-surge/#_ednref11&quot; name=&quot;_edn11&quot;&gt;[11]&lt;/a&gt; Nisbet et al., 2019&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://climatenexus.org/climate-change-news/methane-surge/#_ednref12&quot; name=&quot;_edn12&quot;&gt;[12]&lt;/a&gt; Nisbet et al., 2019. Turner, Frankenberg, and Kort, 2019. Underwood, 2019.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://climatenexus.org/climate-change-news/methane-surge/#_ednref13&quot; name=&quot;_edn13&quot;&gt;[13]&lt;/a&gt; NOAA Earth System Research Laboratory Global Monitoring Division.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;https://esrl.noaa.gov/gmd/ccgg/trends_ch4/&quot;&gt;https://esrl.noaa.gov/gmd/ccgg/trends_ch4/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://climatenexus.org/climate-change-news/methane-surge/#_ednref14&quot; name=&quot;_edn14&quot;&gt;[14]&lt;/a&gt; NOAA AGGI, 2019&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://climatenexus.org/climate-change-news/methane-surge/#_ednref15&quot; name=&quot;_edn15&quot;&gt;[15]&lt;/a&gt; Nisbet et al, 2019&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://climatenexus.org/climate-change-news/methane-surge/#_ednref16&quot; name=&quot;_edn16&quot;&gt;[16]&lt;/a&gt; Turner, Frankenberg, and Kort, 2019&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://climatenexus.org/climate-change-news/methane-surge/#_ednref17&quot; name=&quot;_edn17&quot;&gt;[17]&lt;/a&gt; Turner et al., 2019&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://climatenexus.org/climate-change-news/methane-surge/#_ednref18&quot; name=&quot;_edn18&quot;&gt;[18]&lt;/a&gt; Nisbet et al., 2019. Turner, Frankenberg, and Kort, 2019. Underwood, 2019.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://climatenexus.org/climate-change-news/methane-surge/#_ednref19&quot; name=&quot;_edn19&quot;&gt;[19]&lt;/a&gt; Nisbet et al., 2019&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://climatenexus.org/climate-change-news/methane-surge/#_ednref20&quot; name=&quot;_edn20&quot;&gt;[20]&lt;/a&gt; Nisbet et al., 2019. Turner, Frankenberg, and Kort, 2019. Massakkers et al., 2019.  Worden et al., 2017.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; Howarth et al., 2019. Jacobson et al., 2018.  Lan et al., 2019.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://climatenexus.org/climate-change-news/methane-surge/#_ednref21&quot; name=&quot;_edn21&quot;&gt;[21]&lt;/a&gt; Dean et al., 2018. Nisbet et al., 2019.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://climatenexus.org/climate-change-news/methane-surge/#_ednref22&quot; name=&quot;_edn22&quot;&gt;[22]&lt;/a&gt; International Energy Agency, 2017. &lt;em&gt;World Energy Outlook 2017&lt;/em&gt;. IEA Publications, Paris.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.iea.org/newsroom/news/2017/october/commentary-the-environmental-case-for-natural-gas.html&quot;&gt;https://www.iea.org/newsroom/news/2017/october/commentary-the-environmental-case-for-natural-gas.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://climatenexus.org/climate-change-news/methane-surge/#_ednref23&quot; name=&quot;_edn23&quot;&gt;[23]&lt;/a&gt; Shindell et al., 2017&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2019 01:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>umadon</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Unexpected Surge in Global Methane Levels</og:title>
<og:url>https://climatenexus.org/climate-change-news/methane-surge</og:url>
<og:image>https://climatenexus.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/moor-1624585_1920.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>Follow</og:description>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://climatenexus.org/climate-change-news/methane-surge/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>