<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Red Hat Satellite to standardize on PostgreSQL backend</title>
<link>https://www.redhat.com/en/blog/red-hat-satellite-standardize-postgresql-backend</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.redhat.com/en/blog/red-hat-satellite-standardize-postgresql-backend</guid>
<description>&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;docs-internal-guid-3e35afea-7fff-5fc7-b753-89584050f97b&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.redhat.com/en/resources/introducing-red-hat-satellite-6&quot;&gt;Red Hat Satellite&lt;/a&gt; is a complex offering and we wanted to spend some time talking about the underlying databases that make Satellite work as well as some upcoming changes to this underlying database structure that you should be aware of.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;What databases does Satellite use today?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Red Hat Satellite uses two databases today - MongoDB and PostgreSQL. This is a result of multiple upstream products that use different databases.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;What changes are coming to this database structure?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;We are going to consolidate and use a single database, PostgreSQL. We began investigating a move to a single database upstream in Pulp as early as 2016. The development team decided that a relational database with rollback and transactions was necessary for the features needed in Pulp (and ultimately, Satellite).  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Why drop MongoDB Community Edition from Red Hat Satellite?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;The reasons for this direction are that we feel that PostgreSQL is a better solution for the types of data and usage that Satellite requires. Also, unifying on a single database backend simplifies the overall architecture of Satellite and can make supportability, backup, and disaster recovery easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;What does this mean for currently supported versions of Red Hat Satellite that include MongoDB Community Edition?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;The embedded version of MongoDB will continue to be supported in the Satellite versions that it has already been released in. MongoDB is embedded in currently supported versions of Satellite  6 and was first introduced in Satellite 6.0 (i.e. &lt;a href=&quot;https://access.redhat.com/support/policy/updates/satellite&quot;&gt;Red Hat Satellite Product Lifecycle&lt;/a&gt;). If a patch is needed, rather than moving to a new version of MongoDB, the Satellite team will create a patch for the issue.  Thus, the Satellite team will be patching MongoDB as needed until it is phased out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Satellite will not use newer versions of MongoDB that are licensed under SSPL.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;What is the expected impact on Satellite performance or features?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;We do not anticipate any significant performance impact with the removal of MongoDB. Also, we’ve worked hard to seek to avoid any feature impact with the removal of MongoDB, and expect that users of Satellite should continue to enjoy the features in Satellite they’ve come to depend on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;When will MongoDB Community Edition be dropped as an embedded database within Red Hat Satellite?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;This database change is a still to come, but the product team wanted to go ahead and communicate this intent to our users so they were not caught by surprise as this is a change to the underlying databases of Satellite.  No specific timing or release is being communicated at this time. At this point we’re simply hoping to raise awareness of the change that is coming to help users of Satellite prepare for the removal of MongoDB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Stay tuned to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.redhat.com/en/blog/channel/red-hat-satellite&quot;&gt;Satellite Blog&lt;/a&gt; for the specific release/date that this will take effect.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 01:19:36 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>pplonski86</dc:creator>
<og:description>Red Hat Satellite is a complex offering and we wanted to spend some time talking about the underlying databases that make Satellite work as well as some upcoming changes to this underlying database structure that you should be aware of.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.redhat.com/en/blog/red-hat-satellite-standardize-postgresql-backend</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.redhat.com/profiles/rh/themes/redhatdotcom/img/red-hat-social-share.png</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.redhat.com/en/blog/red-hat-satellite-standardize-postgresql-backend</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>FCC threatens carriers with &amp;#039;regulatory intervention&amp;#039; over robocalls</title>
<link>https://thehill.com/policy/technology/429867-fcc-threatens-carriers-with-regulatory-intervention-on-robocalls</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://thehill.com/policy/technology/429867-fcc-threatens-carriers-with-regulatory-intervention-on-robocalls</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Ajit Pai, the chairman of the Federal Communications Commission (FCC), warned phone service providers that if they don't crack down on fraudulent caller IDs from robocallers his agency will step in with regulation.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Pai sent letters to major wireless carriers in November demanding that they adopt industry-wide frameworks to crack down on the practice of &quot;spoofing,&quot; where robocallers mask a call's origin with a fraudulent number on their caller ID. On Wednesday, the FCC chair followed up with another demand that they implement caller authentication systems this year and a threat over the repercussions if they don't comply.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&quot;American consumers are sick and tired of unwanted robocalls, this consumer among them,&quot; Pai said in a statement on Wednesday. &quot;If it appears major carriers won’t meet the deadline to get this done this year, the FCC will have to consider regulatory intervention.&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;dfp-ad-mosad_1-wrapper&quot; class=&quot;dfp-tag-wrapper wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;ADVERTISEMENT&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span&gt;Some of the companies had responded to Pai's November letters saying that the work could continue past the end of the year.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The protocols being urged on the phone industry would allow carriers to work in tandem to validate caller ID signatures before they reach the call recipient.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&quot;Caller ID authentication will be a significant step towards ending the scourge of spoofed robocalls,&quot; Pai said in his statement. &quot;It’s time for carriers to implement robust caller ID authentication.&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2019 20:50:32 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jmsflknr</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>FCC threatens carriers with 'regulatory intervention' over robocalls</og:title>
<og:url>https://thehill.com/policy/technology/429867-fcc-threatens-carriers-with-regulatory-intervention-on-robocalls</og:url>
<og:description>Ajit Pai, the chairman of the Federal Communications Commission (FCC), warned phone service providers that if they don't crack down on fraudulent caller IDs from robocallers his agency will step in with regulation.</og:description>
<og:image>https://thehill.com/sites/default/files/mobilephone_istock_092718.jpg</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://thehill.com/policy/technology/429867-fcc-threatens-carriers-with-regulatory-intervention-on-robocalls</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The text of Article 13 and the EU Copyright Directive has been finalised</title>
<link>https://juliareda.eu/2019/02/eu-copyright-final-text/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://juliareda.eu/2019/02/eu-copyright-final-text/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Moments ago, negotiators from the European Parliament and the Council concluded the &lt;abbr class=&quot;c2c-text-hover&quot; title=&quot;Informal meetings attended by representatives of the European Parliament, the Council and the Commission&quot;&gt;trilogue&lt;/abbr&gt; negotiations with a &lt;strong&gt;final text&lt;/strong&gt; for the new EU Copyright Directive.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For two years we’ve debated different drafts and versions of the controversial Articles 11 and 13. Now, there is no more ambiguity: This law will fundamentally change the internet as we know it – if it is adopted in the upcoming final vote. &lt;strong&gt;But we can still prevent that!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read on for details about the text, how we got here and what to do now:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-11046 size-large&quot; src=&quot;https://juliareda.eu/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/copyright-keyhole-eu-final-1024x581.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;581&quot; srcset=&quot;https://juliareda.eu/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/copyright-keyhole-eu-final-1024x581.jpg 1024w, https://juliareda.eu/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/copyright-keyhole-eu-final-300x170.jpg 300w, https://juliareda.eu/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/copyright-keyhole-eu-final-768x436.jpg 768w, https://juliareda.eu/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/copyright-keyhole-eu-final-600x340.jpg 600w, https://juliareda.eu/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/copyright-keyhole-eu-final.jpg 1276w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Closed-door trilogue negotiations have concluded.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What’s in the EU Copyright Directive&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hot off the press, take a look at the final wording of &lt;a href=&quot;https://juliareda.eu/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Art_11_unofficial.pdf&quot;&gt;Article 11&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://juliareda.eu/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Art_13_unofficial.pdf&quot;&gt;Article 13&lt;/a&gt;. Here’s my summary:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignright wp-image-6799&quot; src=&quot;https://juliareda.eu/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/copyright-icon-uploadmonitoring.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;170&quot; height=&quot;170&quot; srcset=&quot;https://juliareda.eu/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/copyright-icon-uploadmonitoring.png 230w, https://juliareda.eu/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/copyright-icon-uploadmonitoring-150x150.png 150w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 170px) 100vw, 170px&quot;/&gt;Article 13: Upload filters&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parliament negotiator Axel Voss accepted the &lt;a href=&quot;https://juliareda.eu/2019/02/article-13-worse/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;deal between France and Germany I laid out in a recent blog post&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Commercial sites and apps where users can post material must make “best efforts” to preemptively &lt;strong&gt;buy licences for anything that users may possibly upload&lt;/strong&gt; – that is: all copyrighted content in the world. An impossible feat.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In addition, all but very few sites (those both tiny and very new) will need to do everything in their power to prevent anything from ever going online that may be an unauthorised copy of a work that a rightsholder has registered with the platform. They will have no choice but to deploy &lt;strong&gt;upload filters&lt;/strong&gt;, which are by their nature both expensive and &lt;a href=&quot;https://juliareda.eu/2017/09/when-filters-fail/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;error-prone&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Should a court ever find their licensing or filtering efforts not fierce enough, sites are &lt;strong&gt;directly liable for infringements&lt;/strong&gt; as if they had committed them themselves. This massive threat will lead platforms to over-comply with these rules to stay on the safe side, further worsening the impact on our freedom of speech.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignright wp-image-6798&quot; src=&quot;https://juliareda.eu/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/copyright-icon-extracopyright.png&quot; alt=&quot;Article 11&quot; width=&quot;170&quot; height=&quot;170&quot; srcset=&quot;https://juliareda.eu/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/copyright-icon-extracopyright.png 230w, https://juliareda.eu/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/copyright-icon-extracopyright-150x150.png 150w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 170px) 100vw, 170px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Article 11: The “link tax”&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final version of this &lt;a href=&quot;https://juliareda.eu/eu-copyright-reform/extra-copyright-for-news-sites/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;extra copyright for news sites&lt;/a&gt; closely resembles the &lt;a href=&quot;https://juliareda.eu/2018/01/copyright-bulgarian-presidency/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;version that already failed in Germany&lt;/a&gt; – only this time not limited to search engines and news aggregators, meaning it will do damage to a lot more websites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reproducing more than “single words or very short extracts” of news stories will require a licence.&lt;/strong&gt; That will likely cover many of the snippets commonly shown alongside links today in order to give you an idea of what they lead to. We will have to wait and see how courts interpret what “very short” means in practice – until then, hyperlinking (with snippets) will be mired in legal uncertainty.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No exceptions&lt;/strong&gt; are made even for services run by individuals, small companies or non-profits, which probably includes any monetised blogs or websites.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Other provisions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project to allow Europeans to conduct &lt;strong&gt;Text and Data Mining&lt;/strong&gt;, crucial for modern research and the development of artificial intelligence, has been obstructed with too many caveats and requirements. Rightholders can opt out of having their works datamined by anyone except research organisations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Authors’ rights:&lt;/strong&gt; The Parliament’s proposal that authors should have a right to proportionate remuneration has been severely watered down: Total buy-out contracts will continue to be the norm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Minor improvements for access to &lt;strong&gt;cultural heritage&lt;/strong&gt;: Libraries will be able to publish out-of-commerce works online and museums will no longer be able to claim copyright on photographs of centuries-old paintings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;* * *&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How we got here&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-5787 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://juliareda.eu/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/oettinger-copyright.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;540&quot; srcset=&quot;https://juliareda.eu/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/oettinger-copyright.jpg 960w, https://juliareda.eu/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/oettinger-copyright-300x169.jpg 300w, https://juliareda.eu/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/oettinger-copyright-768x432.jpg 768w, https://juliareda.eu/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/oettinger-copyright-600x338.jpg 600w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Former digital Commissioner Oettinger proposed the law&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The history of this law is a shameful one. &lt;a href=&quot;https://juliareda.eu/2016/08/copyright-reform-another-acta/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;From the very beginning&lt;/a&gt;, the purpose of Articles 11 and 13 was never to solve clearly-defined issues in copyright law with well-assessed measures, but to &lt;strong&gt;serve powerful special interests&lt;/strong&gt;, with hardly any concern for the collateral damage caused.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;strong&gt;relentless pursuit of this goal&lt;/strong&gt;, concerns by &lt;a href=&quot;https://juliareda.eu/2017/04/experts-slam-eu-copyright-plans/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;independent academics&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.liberties.eu/en/news/delete-article-thirteen-open-letter/13194&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;fundamental rights defenders&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://mediapublishers.eu/our-views/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;independent publishers&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://juliareda.eu/2017/04/copyright-reform-kills-eu-startups/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;startups&lt;/a&gt; and many others were ignored. At times, &lt;a href=&quot;https://juliareda.eu/2017/12/extra-news-copyright-confusion/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;confusion was spread about crystal-clear contrary evidence&lt;/a&gt;. Parliament negotiator Axel Voss defamed the unprecedented &lt;a href=&quot;http://change.org/p/european-parliament-stop-the-censorship-machinery-save-the-internet&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;protest of millions of internet users&lt;/a&gt; as “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jwj-hDvJWM8&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;built on lies&lt;/a&gt;”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In his conservative &lt;abbr class=&quot;c2c-text-hover&quot; title=&quot;European People’s Party (Conservatives)&quot;&gt;EPP&lt;/abbr&gt; group, the driving force behind this law, &lt;strong&gt;dissenters were marginalised&lt;/strong&gt;. The work of their initially-appointed representative &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.euractiv.com/section/digital/news/new-lead-mep-could-shift-talks-on-contentious-copyright-bill/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;was thrown out&lt;/a&gt; after the conclusions she reached were too sensible. Mr Voss then voted so blindly in favour of any and all restrictive measures that he was &lt;a href=&quot;https://qz.com/1389385/article-11-and-article-13-axel-voss-is-surprised-by-eu-copyright-law/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;caught by surprise&lt;/a&gt; by some of the nonsense he had gotten approved. His party, the German CDU/CSU, nonchalantly violated the coalition agreement they had signed (which rejected upload filters), paying no mind to their own &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/DoroBaer/status/1095330255236063235&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;minister for digital issues&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It took efforts equally herculean and sisyphean &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=r8pi6e5GLaQ&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;across party lines&lt;/a&gt; to prevent the text from turning out even worse than it now is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end, a &lt;strong&gt;closed-door horse trade between France and Germany&lt;/strong&gt; was enough to outweigh the objections… so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What’s important to note, though: &lt;strong&gt;It’s not “the EU” in general that is to blame&lt;/strong&gt; – but those who put special interests above fundamental rights who currently hold considerable power. You can change that at the polls! The anti-EU far right is trying to seize this opportunity to promote their narrow-minded nationalist agenda – when in fact without the persistent support of the far-right &lt;em&gt;&lt;abbr class=&quot;c2c-text-hover&quot; title=&quot;Europe of Nations and Freedom (Extreme Right)&quot;&gt;ENF&lt;/abbr&gt; Group&lt;/em&gt; (dominated by the &lt;em&gt;Rassemblement/Front National&lt;/em&gt;) the law &lt;a href=&quot;https://juliareda.eu/2018/06/not-giving-up/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;could have been stopped&lt;/a&gt; in the crucial Legal Affairs Committee and in general would not be as extreme as it is today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;* * *&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;We can still stop this law&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;pull right&quot; readability=&quot;4.3604651162791&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our best chance to stop the EU copyright law: The upcoming Parliament vote.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;tweetthis&quot; href=&quot;https://juliareda.eu/2019/02/eu-copyright-final-text/#&quot; data-tweet=&quot;We have one more chance to #SaveYourInternet and stop #Article13: The upcoming vote in @Europarl_EN. Get informed!&quot; onclick=&quot;javascript:return tweet(this);&quot;&gt;Tweet this!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Parliament and Council negotiators who agreed on the final text now return to their institutions seeking approval of the result. &lt;strong&gt;If it passes both votes unchanged, it becomes EU law&lt;/strong&gt;, which member states are forced to implement into national law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In both bodies, there is resistance.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Parliament’s process starts with the approval by the Legal Affairs Committee – which is likely to be given on Monday, February 18.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, at a date to be announced, the &lt;strong&gt;EU member state governments will vote in the Council.&lt;/strong&gt; The law can be stopped here either by 13 member state governments or by any number of governments who together represent 35% of the EU population (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.consilium.europa.eu/en/council-eu/voting-system/voting-calculator/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;calculator&lt;/a&gt;). Last time, 8 countries representing 27% of the population were opposed. Either a large country like Germany or several small ones would need to change their minds: This is the less likely way to stop it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;Our best bet: The &lt;strong&gt;final vote in the plenary of the European Parliament&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, when all 751 MEPs, directly elected to represent the people, have a vote. This will take place either between March 25 and 28, on April 4 or between April 15 and 18. We’ve already &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.technollama.co.uk/what-can-the-copyright-directive-vote-tell-us-about-the-state-of-digital-rights&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;demonstrated last July&lt;/a&gt; that a majority against a bad copyright proposal &lt;strong&gt;is achievable&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plenary can vote to &lt;strong&gt;kill the bill – or to make changes&lt;/strong&gt;, like removing Articles 11 and 13. In the latter case, it’s up to the Council to decide whether to accept these changes (the Directive then becomes law without these articles) or to shelve the project until after the EU elections in May, which will reshuffle all the cards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;This is where you come in&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final Parliament vote will happen &lt;strong&gt;mere weeks before the EU elections&lt;/strong&gt;. Most MEPs – and certainly all parties – are going to be seeking reelection. Articles 11 and 13 will be defeated if enough voters make these issues relevant to the campaigns. (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.european-elections.eu&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Here’s how to vote in the EU elections&lt;/a&gt; – change the language to one of your country’s official ones for specific information)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is up to you to make clear to your representatives: &lt;strong&gt;Their vote on whether to break the internet with Articles 11 and 13 will make or break your vote in the EU elections.&lt;/strong&gt; Be insistent – but please always stay polite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Together, we can still stop this law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p prefix=&quot;dct: http://purl.org/dc/terms/ cc: http://creativecommons.org/ns#&quot; class=&quot;cc-block&quot;&gt;To the extent possible under law, the creator has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;mashsb-container mashsb-main&quot;&gt;


&lt;/aside&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2019 19:44:37 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>TimWolla</dc:creator>
<og:title>Breaking: The text of Article 13 and the EU Copyright Directive has just been finalised</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://juliareda.eu/2019/02/eu-copyright-final-text/</og:url>
<og:description></og:description>
<dc:language>en-GB</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://juliareda.eu/2019/02/eu-copyright-final-text/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Nasa’s Mars Rover Opportunity Concludes a 15-Year Mission</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/02/13/science/mars-opportunity-rover-dead.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2019/02/13/science/mars-opportunity-rover-dead.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Opportunity, the longest-lived roving robot ever sent to another planet, explored the red plains of Mars for more than 14 years, snapping photos and revealing astonishing glimpses into its distant past. But on Wednesday, NASA announced that the rover is dead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“It is therefore that I am standing here with a sense of deep appreciation and gratitude that I declare the Opportunity mission as complete,” Thomas Zurbuchen, NASA’s associate administrator for science, said at a news conference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The golf cart-size rover was designed to last only three months, but proved itself to be an unexpected endurance athlete. It traveled more than the distance of a marathon when less than half a mile would have counted as success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;As it moved across the surface, Opportunity provided an up-close view of Mars that scientists had never seen: fine layers of rock that preserved ripples of flowing water, a prerequisite for life, from several billion years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;It also changed the paradigm for how to explore a planet. Instead of a lander studying a single spot a rover let scientists head to the most promising places.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The steady stream of photographs and data from Opportunity — and from its twin, Spirit, which persisted until 2010 — brought Mars closer to people on Earth. Because the rovers operated for so much longer than expected, NASA has now had a continuous robotic presence on Mars for most of the century.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;css-8i9d0s e13ogyst0&quot;&gt;NASA’s Opportunity rover, which provided detailed views of Mars, is dead. It was the longest-lived robot on another planet’s surface.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-cch8ym&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1dv1kvn&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot; class=&quot;emkp2hg2 css-1nwzsjy e1z0qqy90&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1tej78p0&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;NASA/JPL&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;That streak seems likely to not end soon. A &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/01/31/science/mars-curiosity-rover-mount-sharp.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;larger, more capable rover, Curiosity,&lt;/a&gt; arrived in 2012, and &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/11/19/science/nasa-mars-2020-rover.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;NASA is planning to launch another in 2020&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“Rovers and their observations resonate with people,” said Raymond E. Arvidson, a professor of planetary geology at Washington University in St. Louis, and the deputy principal investigator for the mission. “It’s as if you were walking on the surface. It has that kind of perspective, and it’s not a particularly alien landscape.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;On Tuesday night, NASA made one last call to Opportunity, which was silenced last summer by a giant dust storm. There was no reply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“It was an incredibly somber moment,” said Tanya Harrison, a member of the mission’s science team who was present in Pasadena, Calif., at the Jet Propulsion Laboratory during the final attempt to reach the rover. “Just waiting for the inevitable, basically.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The rover has been quiet since June. During the dust storm, Opportunity’s solar panels could not generate enough power to keep the spacecraft awake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;NASA had hoped that once the skies cleared, the rover would revive and continue its work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-93lbfk&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1nbz89a e6u6ph30&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/02/13/science/opportunity-rover-mars-map-1550082012212/opportunity-rover-mars-map-1550082012212-articleLarge.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1rha1bf&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;css-zd32qr e6u6ph31&quot;&gt;NASA’s Opportunity Rover Dies on Mars&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1uuihdo&quot;&gt;Fifteen years and 28 miles on the red planet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;time class=&quot;css-1j5weju e16638kd0&quot; datetime=&quot;2019-02-13&quot;&gt;Feb. 13, 2019&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Last fall, the space agency announced it would spend just a month trying to reconnect with Opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“There were some that were willing to give up quite quickly, but there was a huge backlash,” Dr. Harrison said. “We didn’t feel like the rover was being given a fair chance.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;NASA relented, but as time passed, the odds grew that the mission was finally over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Perhaps the solar panels became encrusted in a thick layer of dust, or some crucial electronic component broke down in the extremes of Martian weather. Unless astronauts on Mars one day can take a look at Opportunity, what dealt the lethal blow will likely remain a mystery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;css-8qgvsz ebyp5n10&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;[&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2019/science/astronomy-space-calendar.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;Sign up to get reminders for space and astronomy events on your calendar&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;css-8qgvsz ebyp5n10&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;.]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;css-1505tg eoo0vm40&quot; id=&quot;link-234e6880&quot;&gt;Twin rovers on the red planet&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Opportunity landed on Mars on Jan. 24, 2004, three weeks after its twin, Spirit, which set down on the opposite side of the planet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;NASA was looking to rebound from two embarrassing failures in 1999. A mix-up between English and metric units caused the Mars Climate Orbiter to be ripped apart in the atmosphere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Three months later, the Mars Polar Lander vanished during its landing. An investigation found that the spacecraft likely had shut off its engines too early and plummeted to its destruction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Steven W. Squyres, a Cornell astronomer who serves as the mission’s principal investigator, had been selected to oversee the scientific instruments for an Opportunity-like rover that was to launch in 2001. Because of NASA budget limits, the rover was changed to a stationary lander.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;After the 1999 failures, the Mars lander mission that was to launch in 2001 was canceled. The question became what to do in 2003, the next time that Earth and Mars would be close enough to send another spacecraft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;One option was to put Dr. Squyres’s instruments back on a rover, a scaled-up version of the successful Pathfinder mission in 1997.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Daniel S. Goldin, the NASA administrator, was initially skeptical, but agreed. Then he asked: Why not two rovers? A pair would provide redundancy, and allow exploration of two different regions of Mars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The rovers received the green light from NASA in the middle of 2000. Then came the rush to develop and build the rovers in time to launch in 2003, while also avoiding the corner-cutting mistakes that had doomed the 1999 spacecraft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“It was a miracle we got to Florida,” Dr. Squyres said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-wrapper&quot; class=&quot;css-79elbk ehw59r11&quot;&gt;

&lt;div data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-children&quot; class=&quot;css-1a48zt4 ehw59r111&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1xdhyk6 erfvjey0&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1tej78p0&quot;&gt;Image&lt;/span&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;css-1m50asq&quot; src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/02/13/science/13MARS3/merlin_150586221_ca75e2bf-bc12-4c38-b8ca-72f2b2a56933-articleLarge.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;auto=webp&amp;amp;disable=upscale&quot; srcset=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/02/13/science/13MARS3/merlin_150586221_ca75e2bf-bc12-4c38-b8ca-72f2b2a56933-articleLarge.jpg?quality=90&amp;amp;auto=webp 600w,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/02/13/science/13MARS3/merlin_150586221_ca75e2bf-bc12-4c38-b8ca-72f2b2a56933-jumbo.jpg?quality=90&amp;amp;auto=webp 1024w,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/02/13/science/13MARS3/merlin_150586221_ca75e2bf-bc12-4c38-b8ca-72f2b2a56933-superJumbo.jpg?quality=90&amp;amp;auto=webp 2048w&quot; sizes=&quot;((min-width: 600px) and (max-width: 1004px)) 84vw, (min-width: 1005px) 60vw, 100vw&quot; itemprop=&quot;url&quot; itemid=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/02/13/science/13MARS3/merlin_150586221_ca75e2bf-bc12-4c38-b8ca-72f2b2a56933-articleLarge.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;auto=webp&amp;amp;disable=upscale&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;css-8i9d0s e13ogyst0&quot;&gt;A self-portrait taken by Opportunity in March 2014, showing that wind had blown off much of the dust that had covered its solar panels.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot; class=&quot;css-vuqh7u e1z0qqy90&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1tej78p0&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;NASA/JPL-Caltech/Cornell Univ./Arizona State Univ.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;css-1505tg eoo0vm40&quot; id=&quot;link-63dbb33f&quot;&gt;Waters of Mars&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Three days before Opportunity’s landing, the entire mission appeared to be in jeopardy. Although it landed successfully a couple of weeks earlier, Spirit suddenly stopped talking. Engineers scrambled to figure out what had gone wrong and whether Opportunity was susceptible to the same flaw.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“There was a period of time when everyone was concerned that we were at risk,” said Peter C. Theisinger, who was then project manager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The engineers figured out the problem and started nursing Spirit back to health. Opportunity then landed perfectly and hit a scientific jackpot immediately, ending up in a small crater with exposed bedrock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The bedrock was made of finely layered sedimentary rocks that formed in water several billion years ago, but these waters were highly salty and acidic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“In reality, we were mostly talking about sulfuric acid on Mars,” recalled Dr. Squyres. “Habitable, yes, but it was no evolutionary paradise.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Over the years, Opportunity explored a series of larger and larger craters. At the rim of the biggest, the 14-mile-wide Endeavour Crater, the rover discovered bedrock that was older than the crater, lifted upward but not broken apart by the impact that had formed the cavity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The rock contained clays, which would have formed in waters that were pH-neutral or slightly alkaline. “This was water you could drink,” Dr. Squyres said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;That environment might have been habitable for microbes, had any been on Mars long ago. However, the rover was not carrying instruments to search for molecules that might have hinted at ancient life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Still, the evidence offered a picture of early Mars: a once-habitable environment that became harsh, as volcanic eruptions turned the waters acidic and the entire planet dried out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;css-1505tg eoo0vm40&quot; id=&quot;link-2500c2e4&quot;&gt;5,111 days on Mars&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;At the beginning, the mission was a dash, with the scientists trying to squeeze out as much data as they could before Spirit and Opportunity died.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The designers of the vehicles expected that dust settling from the Martian air would pile up on the solar panels, and eventually the rovers would fail from lack of power. Unexpectedly, gusts of Martian winds repeatedly acted as cleaning events, wiping the dust away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The rovers made it through the winters by parking with their solar panels pointed northward, toward the sun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Part of that success was timely new technologies — in particular, the long-lasting lithium ion batteries similar to those now used in cellphones, laptops and electric cars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“These rovers actually have the finest batteries in the solar system,” said John L. Callas, the project manager for the mission. “We’d all love if our cellphone batteries lasted this long.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The engineers also figured out workarounds to problems like a stuck heater switch that sapped energy from the rover as well as later bouts of amnesia where the rover would forget what it was doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Each year, investigators bet whether one or two rovers, or none, would make it through the year. Richard Cook, one of the top managers for the rovers, was not among the optimists. “I bet and lost $20 every year for the first five years, and then I stopped betting,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;In 2009, Spirit slipped into a sand trap and could not pull itself out. It stopped communicating in March 2010.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Opportunity continued trundling across the Martian landscape. Instead of just 90 Martian days, Opportunity lasted 5,111, counting the days until its last transmission. (A Martian day is about 40 minutes longer than an Earth day.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;NASA’s Curiosity rover, which landed in 2012, continues to explore another part of Mars, a crater that was once filled with water. &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/11/19/science/nasa-mars-2020-rover.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;In addition to NASA&lt;/a&gt;, China and a joint European-Russian collaboration are also planning to send rovers to Mars in 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;A generation of planetary scientists grew up with Opportunity. In 2004, Abigail A. Fraeman was a junior in high school who was selected by the Planetary Society to go to Pasadena and take part in the rover mission. She was with the scientists on the night of Opportunity’s landing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“It was the coolest night ever,” Dr. Fraeman said, and it inspired her to choose this as her career. She has been the deputy project scientist for Opportunity since 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Dr. Harrison was college student when the mission started and that she knew she wanted to work on a rover like Opportunity. “I never knew I would get to work on Opportunity 15 years later,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;She said that at the end of the night on Tuesday Dr. Callas phoned operators of a radio dish in Australia, part of the network that NASA uses to communicate with its interplanetary voyagers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;He thanked them for 15 years of work with Spirit and Opportunity, and said he was now signing off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“There had been a lot of talking and laughing and whatnot between crying and hugging,” Dr. Harrison said. “As soon as that moment happened, it just went silent.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1aspctq epkadsg3&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1ukm2ij epkadsg0&quot;&gt;More news from Mars&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-15g2oxy epkadsg2&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1o4azrb e16ij5yr6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-i9gxme e16ij5yr4&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1u39xnq e16ij5yr2&quot;&gt;Hear the Sounds of Wind on Mars, Recorded by NASA’s InSight Lander&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;time class=&quot;css-1yil5bp e16638kd0&quot; datetime=&quot;2018-12-07&quot;&gt;Dec. 7, 2018&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-rxyfbr e16ij5yr0&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/12/08/science/08MARTIANWINDS/08MARTIANWINDS-threeByTwoSmallAt2X.jpg&quot; class=&quot;css-32rbo2 e16ij5yr1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1o4azrb e16ij5yr6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-i9gxme e16ij5yr4&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1u39xnq e16ij5yr2&quot;&gt;NASA’s InSight Mission Has Touched Down on Mars to Study the Red Planet’s Deep Secrets&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;time class=&quot;css-1yil5bp e16638kd0&quot; datetime=&quot;2018-11-26&quot;&gt;Nov. 26, 2018&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-rxyfbr e16ij5yr0&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/11/27/science/27MARSLANDING2/27MARSLANDING2-threeByTwoSmallAt2X.jpg&quot; class=&quot;css-32rbo2 e16ij5yr1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1o4azrb e16ij5yr6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-i9gxme e16ij5yr4&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1u39xnq e16ij5yr2&quot;&gt;NASA Mars 2020 Rover Gets a Landing Site: A Crater That Contained a Lake&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;time class=&quot;css-1yil5bp e16638kd0&quot; datetime=&quot;2018-11-19&quot;&gt;Nov. 19, 2018&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-rxyfbr e16ij5yr0&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/11/21/science/21MARS-print/21MARS-print-threeByTwoSmallAt2X-v2.jpg&quot; class=&quot;css-32rbo2 e16ij5yr1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1o4azrb e16ij5yr6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-i9gxme e16ij5yr4&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1u39xnq e16ij5yr2&quot;&gt;A Large Body of Water on Mars Is Detected, Raising the Potential for Alien Life&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;time class=&quot;css-1yil5bp e16638kd0&quot; datetime=&quot;2018-07-25&quot;&gt;July 25, 2018&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-rxyfbr e16ij5yr0&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/07/26/science/26TB-MARS-promo/26TB-MARS-promo-threeByTwoSmallAt2X.jpg&quot; class=&quot;css-32rbo2 e16ij5yr1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2019 19:16:54 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jimktrains2</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/02/13/science/mars-opportunity-rover-dead.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>NASA’s Mars Rover Opportunity Concludes a 15-Year Mission</og:title>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/02/13/science/13MARS1/merlin_150586047_d7908312-f378-44cd-b7a5-cbdff40406a6-facebookJumbo.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>Silent since a giant dust storm last summer, the rover was the longest-lasting robot on another planet ever.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/02/13/science/mars-opportunity-rover-dead.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Amazon in Its Prime: Doubles Profits, Pays $0 in Federal Income Taxes</title>
<link>https://itep.org/amazon-in-its-prime-doubles-profits-pays-0-in-federal-income-taxes/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://itep.org/amazon-in-its-prime-doubles-profits-pays-0-in-federal-income-taxes/</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;row visible-xs&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col-xs-6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;small&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;February 13, 2019&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br class=&quot;visible-xs visible-sm&quot;/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;hidden-xs&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;small&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;February 13, 2019&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazon, the ubiquitous purveyor of two-day delivery of just about everything, nearly doubled its profits to $11.2 billion in 2018 from $5.6 billion the previous year and, once again, didn’t pay a single cent of federal income taxes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company’s newest corporate filing reveals that, far from paying the statutory 21 percent income tax rate on its U.S. income in 2018, Amazon reported a federal income tax rebate of $129 million. For those who don’t have a pocket calculator handy, that works out to a tax rate of negative 1 percent. The fine print of Amazon’s income tax disclosure shows that this achievement is partly due to various unspecified “tax credits” as well as a tax break for executive stock options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This isn’t the first year that the cyber-retailing giant has avoided federal taxes. &lt;a href=&quot;https://itep.org/amazon-inc-paid-zero-in-federal-taxes-in-2017-gets-789-million-windfall-from-new-tax-law/&quot;&gt;Last year, the company paid no federal corporate income taxes&lt;/a&gt; on $5.6 billion in U.S. income.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ITEP has examined the tax-paying habits of corporations for nearly 40 years and has long advocated for closing loopholes and special breaks that allow many profitable corporations to pay zero or single-digit effective tax rates. When Congress in 2017 enacted the Tax Cuts and Jobs Act and substantially cut the statutory corporate tax rate from 35 percent to 21 percent, proponents claimed the rate cut would incentivize better corporate citizenship. However, the tax law failed to broaden the tax base or close a slew of tax loopholes that allow profitable companies to routinely avoid paying federal and state income taxes on almost half of their profits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, the Trump Administration and its congressional allies included lavish new giveaways such as immediate expensing of capital investments. Multiple analysts scored the tax law as a huge revenue loser, giving away far more to big corporations in rate cuts than it takes in loophole-closers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazon is no stranger to tax controversies. Last year the company, in a staggering act of hubris, engaged in a year-long aggressive push for huge new relocation subsidies for its “HQ2” headquarters. A year later, Amazon appears to have won its two-front battle against fair taxes by continuing to altogether avoid federal taxes and obtaining lucrative packages of local tax breaks for not one but two new HQ2 locations, in New York and Virginia as well breaks for an operations center in Nashville, Tenn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To the credit of local activists, Amazon has had its feet held to the fire for its efforts to pillage local tax bases. Last week Amazon’s leadership &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/local/virginia-politics/facing-opposition-amazon-reconsiders-ny-headquarters-site-two-officials-say/2019/02/08/451ffc52-2a19-11e9-b011-d8500644dc98_story.html?noredirect=on&amp;amp;utm_term=.3a23a2ceab3a&quot;&gt;ran a gauntlet of public opposition in New York&lt;/a&gt; over the scope of the tax giveaways the company has been promised. But allies in Congress have, so far,  shown little interest in answering the tough questions about why their new corporate tax law can’t lay a glove on one of the most valuable and profitable corporations in the world.  And while the president himself has criticized Amazon for its tax avoidance in the past, the administration has so far displayed no awareness that its own tax package appears to have made the company’s corporate tax avoidance even more rampant than before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s too soon to know whether this new revelation, following hard on the heels of Netflix’s similar announcement last week, means that the floodgates have opened for a wave of Fortune 500 corporate tax avoidance: we’ll have a better sense of that a month from now, when most big multinationals will have released their financial reports for 2018, the first full year of the new Trump corporate tax law. But these initial findings appear to confirm the view that last year’s tax law was a gigantic missed opportunity for true corporate tax reform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2019 19:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>djoldman</dc:creator>
<og:title>Amazon in Its Prime: Doubles Profits, Pays $0 in Federal Income Taxes</og:title>
<og:description>Amazon, the ubiquitous purveyor of two-day delivery of just about everything, nearly doubled its profits to $11.2 billion in 2018 from $5.6 billion the previous year and, once again, didn’t pay a single cent of federal income taxes.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://itep.org/amazon-in-its-prime-doubles-profits-pays-0-in-federal-income-taxes/</og:url>
<og:image>https://itep.org/wp-content/uploads/021319-Amazon-Corporate-Taxes-Feature-Image-1024x551.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://itep.org/amazon-in-its-prime-doubles-profits-pays-0-in-federal-income-taxes/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why can’t a bot tick the &amp;#039;I&amp;#039;m not a robot&amp;#039; box?</title>
<link>https://www.quora.com/Why-can-t-a-bot-tick-the-Im-not-a-robot-box/answer/Oliver-Emberton?share=1</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.quora.com/Why-can-t-a-bot-tick-the-Im-not-a-robot-box/answer/Oliver-Emberton?share=1</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ui_qtext_rendered_qtext&quot;&gt;How complicated can one little checkbox be? I mean it’s just OH MY GOD YOU CAN’T EVEN IMAGINE.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_outer&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ui_qtext_rendered_qtext&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;landscape ui_qtext_image zoomable_in zoomable_in_feed&quot; src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-ec6d5954e3e3b426338edd7f5344a13b&quot; master_src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-6ca9bec4f35efbfb1b495f24a40a9299&quot; master_w=&quot;648&quot; master_h=&quot;200&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ui_qtext_rendered_qtext&quot;&gt;For starters, Google invented &lt;em&gt;an entire virtual machine&lt;/em&gt; – essentially a simulated computer inside a computer – just to run that checkbox.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ui_qtext_rendered_qtext&quot;&gt;That virtual machine uses their own language, which they encrypt twice.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ui_qtext_rendered_qtext&quot;&gt;This is no simple encryption. Normally when you password protect something, you might use a key to decode it. Google’s invented language is decoded with a key that is &lt;em&gt;changed by the process of reading the language&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;the language also changes as it is read&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ui_qtext_rendered_qtext&quot;&gt;Google combines (hashes) that key with the web address you’re visiting, so you can’t use a CAPTCHA from one website to bypass another. It further combines that with “fingerprints” from your browser, catching microscopic variations in your computer that a bot would struggle to replicate (like CSS rules).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ui_qtext_rendered_qtext&quot;&gt;All this is just to make it hard for you to understand what Google is even doing. You need to write tools just to analyse it. (&lt;span class=&quot;qlink_container&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/neuroradiology/InsideReCaptcha&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; onclick=&quot;return Q.openUrl(this, 122551644);&quot; class=&quot;external_link&quot; data-qt-tooltip=&quot;github.com&quot;&gt;Fortunately people did just that&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr&quot;&gt;It turns out they record and analyse:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Your computer’s timezone and time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your IP address and rough location&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your screen size and resolution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What browser you’re using&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What plugins you’re using&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How long the page took to display&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How many key presses, mouse clicks, and tap/scrolls were made&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr&quot;&gt;And … some other stuff we don’t quite understand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr&quot;&gt;We do know they &lt;span class=&quot;qlink_container&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://hovav.net/ucsd/dist/canvas.pdf&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; onclick=&quot;return Q.openUrl(this, 122551644);&quot; class=&quot;external_link&quot; data-qt-tooltip=&quot;hovav.net&quot;&gt;ask your browser to draw an invisible image&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; and send it to Google for verification. The image contains things like a nonsense font, which – depending on your computer – will fall back to a system font, and be drawn very differently. They add to this a 3D image with a special texture, drawn in such a way that the result varies between computers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_outer&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ui_qtext_image_wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;landscape ui_qtext_image zoomable_in zoomable_in_feed&quot; src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-d9b51c219e74ab45e616d04cb21cd27f&quot; master_src=&quot;https://qph.fs.quoracdn.net/main-qimg-24fc8bf58247de053ecc6720b2b3affb&quot; master_w=&quot;2446&quot; master_h=&quot;1020&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;qlink_container&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://hovav.net/ucsd/dist/canvas.pdf&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; onclick=&quot;return Q.openUrl(this, 122551644);&quot; class=&quot;external_link&quot; data-qt-tooltip=&quot;hovav.net&quot;&gt;https://hovav.net/ucsd/dist/canv...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr&quot;&gt;Finally they combine all of this data with their knowledge of the person using the computer. Almost everyone on the Internet uses &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; owned by Google – search, mail, ads, maps – and as you know Google Tracks All Of Your Things. When you click that checkbox, Google reviews your browser history to see if it looks convincingly human.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr&quot;&gt;This is easy for them, because they’re constantly observing the behaviour of &lt;em&gt;billions&lt;/em&gt; of real people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr&quot;&gt;How exactly they check all this information is impossible to know, but they’re almost certainly using machine learning (AI) on their private servers, which is impossible for an outsider to replicate. I wouldn’t be surprised if they also built an &lt;span class=&quot;qlink_container&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Adversarial_machine_learning&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; onclick=&quot;return Q.openUrl(this, 122551644);&quot; class=&quot;external_link&quot; data-qt-tooltip=&quot;wikipedia.org&quot;&gt;adversarial AI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; to try to beat their own AI, and have both learn from each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr&quot;&gt;So why is all this hard for a bot to beat? Because now you’ve got a ridiculous amount of messy human behaviours to simulate, and they’re almost unknowable, and they keep changing, and you can’t tell when. Your bot might have to sign up for a Google service and use it convincingly on a single computer, which should look different from the computers of other bots, in ways you don’t understand. It might need convincing delays and stumbles between key presses, scrolling and mouse movements. This is all incredibly difficult to crack and teach a computer, and complexity comes at a financial cost for the spammer. They might break it for a while, but if it costs them (say) $1 per successful attempt, it’s usually not worth them bothering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr&quot;&gt;Still, &lt;span class=&quot;qlink_container&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.blackhat.com/docs/asia-16/materials/asia-16-Sivakorn-Im-Not-a-Human-Breaking-the-Google-reCAPTCHA-wp.pdf&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; onclick=&quot;return Q.openUrl(this, 122551644);&quot; class=&quot;external_link&quot; data-qt-tooltip=&quot;blackhat.com&quot;&gt;people do break Google’s protection&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. CAPTCHAs are an ongoing arms race that neither side will ever win. The AI technology which makes Google’s approach so hard to fool is the same technology that is adapted to fool it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr&quot;&gt;Just wait until that AI is convincing enough to fool you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr&quot;&gt;Sweet dreams, human.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr&quot;&gt;—&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para u-ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Everything here is my best understanding of reCAPTCHA 2, which has certainly got smarter since, and Google is on v3 now. I don’t have a clue how that works, but it probably involves 11-dimensional hypercubes in a virtual multiverse).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2019 18:58:34 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>grzm</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.quora.com/Why-can-t-a-bot-tick-the-Im-not-a-robot-box/answer/Oliver-Emberton?share=1</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Earnest Capital is live</title>
<link>https://earnestcapital.com/is-earnest-capital-live-yet/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://earnestcapital.com/is-earnest-capital-live-yet/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Yep. We’re not much for big splashy launches but we have quietly gone live and are making investment decisions on a rolling basis. We expect to announce the first few very soon. Please &lt;a href=&quot;https://earnestcapital.com/apply/&quot;&gt;apply here&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://earnestcapital.com/contact/&quot;&gt;say hi&lt;/a&gt; and start the conversation before you’re ready to apply. Check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://earnestcapital.com/faq/&quot;&gt;our FAQ with answers&lt;/a&gt; to common questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re new to Earnest, we provide funding and mentorship for bootstrappers, indie hackers, and makers. We invest via a &lt;a href=&quot;https://earnestcapital.com/shared-earnings-agreement/&quot;&gt;Shared Earnings Agreement&lt;/a&gt;, a new investing model we &lt;a href=&quot;https://earnestcapital.com/funding-for-bootstrappers-2-what-we-learned/&quot;&gt;developed transparently&lt;/a&gt; with the community that aligns us with founders who want to build profitable, sustainable, calm companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We invest in businesses of all kinds, though we are particularly interested in SaaS, e-commerce, and scalable online education. We also occasionally put out Request for Startups briefs outlining topics we’re particularly interested in like &lt;a href=&quot;https://earnestcapital.com/request-for-startups-1-remote/&quot;&gt;Remote Tools for Remote Teams&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-coblocks-gif wp-block-image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media3.giphy.com/media/zaezT79s3Ng7C/giphy.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2019 16:09:46 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>tylertringas</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Is Earnest Capital Live Yet? | Earnest Capital</og:title>
<og:description>Yep.</og:description>
<og:url>https://earnestcapital.com/is-earnest-capital-live-yet/</og:url>
<og:image>https://media3.giphy.com/media/zaezT79s3Ng7C/giphy.gif</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://earnestcapital.com/is-earnest-capital-live-yet/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Tech Behind SpaceX’s New Engine</title>
<link>https://hackaday.com/2019/02/13/the-impossible-tech-behind-spacexs-new-engine/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://hackaday.com/2019/02/13/the-impossible-tech-behind-spacexs-new-engine/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Followers of the Church of Elon will no doubt already be aware of SpaceX’s latest technical triumph: the test firing of the first full-scale Raptor engine. Of course, it was hardly a secret. As he often does, Elon has been “leaking” behind the scenes information, pictures, and even video of the event on his Twitter account. Combined with the relative transparency of SpaceX to begin with, this gives us an exceptionally clear look at how literal rocket science is performed at the Hawthorne, California based company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/02/raptor_tweet-1.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;344900&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://hackaday.com/2019/02/13/the-impossible-tech-behind-spacexs-new-engine/raptor_tweet/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/02/raptor_tweet-1.png?w=420&amp;amp;h=475&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;518,586&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;raptor_tweet&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/02/raptor_tweet-1.png?w=420&amp;amp;h=475?w=354&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/02/raptor_tweet-1.png?w=420&amp;amp;h=475?w=518&quot; class=&quot;alignright wp-image-344900&quot; src=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/02/raptor_tweet-1.png?w=420&amp;amp;h=475&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;420&quot; height=&quot;475&quot; srcset=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/02/raptor_tweet-1.png?w=420&amp;amp;h=475 420w, https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/02/raptor_tweet-1.png?w=221&amp;amp;h=250 221w, https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/02/raptor_tweet-1.png?w=354&amp;amp;h=400 354w, https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/02/raptor_tweet-1.png 518w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 420px) 100vw, 420px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;This openness has been a key part of SpaceX’s popularity on the Internet (that, and the big rockets), but its been especially illuminating in regards to the Raptor. The technology behind this next generation engine, known as “full-flow staged combustion” has for decades been considered all but impossible by the traditional aerospace players. Despite extensive research into the technology by the Soviet Union and the United States, no engine utilizing this complex combustion system has even been flown. Yet, just six years after Elon announced SpaceX was designing the Raptor, they’ve completed their first flight-ready engine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The full-flow staged combustion engine is often considered the “Holy Grail” of rocketry, as it promises to extract the most possible energy from its liquid propellants. In a field where every ounce is important, being able to squeeze even a few percent more thrust out of the vehicle is worth fighting for. Especially if, like SpaceX, you’re planning on putting these new full-flow engines into the world’s largest operational booster rocket &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; spacecraft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what makes full-flow staged combustion more efficient, and why has it been so difficult to build an engine that utilizes it? To understand that, we’ll need to first take a closer look at more traditional rocket engines, and the design paradigms which have defined them since the very beginning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The Open Cycle Engine: Wasteful by Design&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of the best known rockets to have ever flown have used engines based on what is known as the gas-generator cycle, including the Saturn V, the Soyuz, the Delta IV, and even the Falcon 9. In fact, outside of the Space Shuttle, you could probably argue that nearly every milestone in the history of spaceflight was made with a gas-generator cycle engine. &lt;a href=&quot;https://hackaday.com/2017/11/03/books-you-should-read-v-2-by-walter-dornberger/&quot;&gt;It’s a technology that dates back to the V-2 rocket&lt;/a&gt;, and is one of the key breakthroughs that made liquid-fueled rockets possible. But despite its incredible success, the technology is not without its faults.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/02/raptor_plume.jpg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;344786&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://hackaday.com/2019/02/13/the-impossible-tech-behind-spacexs-new-engine/raptor_plume/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/02/raptor_plume.jpg?w=800&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;308,507&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;raptor_plume&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/02/raptor_plume.jpg?w=800?w=243&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/02/raptor_plume.jpg?w=800?w=308&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-344786&quot; src=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/02/raptor_plume.jpg?w=800&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/02/raptor_plume.jpg 308w, https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/02/raptor_plume.jpg?w=152 152w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 308px) 100vw, 308px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Merlin engine with black preburner exhaust
&lt;p&gt;Put simply, the gas-generator produces the gasses that spin a turbine, which in turn drives the propellant pumps. In some engines, the gas-generator operates on a different principle than the engine itself and has its own separate fuel supply. For example, the turbine of the V-2 rocket was spun with steam created by &lt;a href=&quot;https://hackaday.com/2019/02/05/operation-backfire-witness-to-the-rocket-age/&quot;&gt;the chemical reaction between hydrogen peroxide and warm sodium permanganate&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The downside of this method is that the secondary fuel system for the gas generator adds additional weight and complexity, the last thing you want on a rocket engine. The more modern approach, used in engines such as the Falcon 9’s Merlin, is to power the turbine by burning a relatively small amount of the same fuel and oxidizer as the primary engine. In this case, the gas generator is usually referred to as a preburner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But if the preburner was given the same fuel and oxidizer as the engine itself, and at the same ratio, it would essentially just be a smaller rocket. The exhaust would be far too hot to run through a turbine. To get around this, the preburner is run on a fuel-rich mixture which leads to incomplete combustion and lower exhaust temperature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The defining characteristic of what’s known as an open cycle engine is that the exhaust from the preburner gets dumped overboard as a waste product. In some rockets this unburned fuel can be seen as a black streak alongside of the otherwise bright exhaust plume. It’s never been a secret that there were performance gains to be had by closing the cycle, that is, capturing the preburner exhaust and feeding it into the engine’s combustion chamber. But the sooty exhaust produced from the unburned kerosene is unsuitable for recirculating through the engine. It ended up being easier to simply build larger rockets than try to capture this lost fuel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Finding the Right Mix&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the 1950’s, Soviet scientists came up with something of a compromise. Instead of using a fuel-rich mixture in the preburner which produced an exhaust that couldn’t be safely recirculated into the engine, they experimented with running the preburner oxygen-rich. Unfortunately this idea solved one problem while creating another, as there was no metal that could survive the incredibly hot oxygen-rich gas produced by the preburner. In fact, American scientists had deemed it impossible, and believed claims that their Soviet counterparts were working on the concept to be Cold War propaganda.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually the Soviets mastered the metallurgy required to build the turbine and developed several engines that operated on the oxygen-rich preburner concept. The exhaust was piped into the engine’s combustion chamber and recovered at least some of the propellants which would otherwise have been dumped overboard. &lt;a href=&quot;https://hackaday.com/2016/02/03/russian-rocket-technology-comes-in-from-the-cold/&quot;&gt;The modern day Russian RD-180 engine, currently in use by the American Atlas V&lt;/a&gt;, is a continuation of this technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American engineers went in the opposite direction. They believed that a fuel-rich mixture in the preburner was possible and could be done with existing metal alloys, so long as hydrogen was used as the fuel instead of kerosene. This ultimately lead to the development of the Space Shuttle Main Engine, which to date remains the most efficient liquid fuel rocket engine ever flown. While the Space Shuttle has long since retired, a variation of the engine itself will go on to power the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nasa.gov/exploration/systems/sls/overview.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Space Launch System&lt;/a&gt;. It will be the most powerful rocket NASA has ever built and is slated to begin missions in 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Closing the Cycle&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Either approach, whether it recaptures the oxidizer or fuel rich preburner exhaust, is clearly an improvement over dumping everything overboard. But neither is an ideal solution as there’s still potentially combustible products being wasted. Essentially the Soviet Union and the United States had both solved different halves of the same problem; to truly close the cycle, the fuel-rich and oxidizer-rich preburner designs would need to be utilized simultaneously in the same engine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;345171&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://hackaday.com/2019/02/13/the-impossible-tech-behind-spacexs-new-engine/raptor_fullflow-themed/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/02/raptor_fullflow-themed.jpg?w=400&amp;amp;h=487&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;495,603&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;raptor_fullflow-themed&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/02/raptor_fullflow-themed.jpg?w=400&amp;amp;h=487?w=328&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/02/raptor_fullflow-themed.jpg?w=400&amp;amp;h=487?w=495&quot; class=&quot;alignright wp-image-345171&quot; src=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/02/raptor_fullflow-themed.jpg?w=400&amp;amp;h=487&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;487&quot; srcset=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/02/raptor_fullflow-themed.jpg?w=400&amp;amp;h=487 400w, https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/02/raptor_fullflow-themed.jpg?w=205&amp;amp;h=250 205w, https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/02/raptor_fullflow-themed.jpg?w=328&amp;amp;h=400 328w, https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/02/raptor_fullflow-themed.jpg 495w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 400px) 100vw, 400px&quot;/&gt;The logical end result is the full-flow staged combustion engine. Such an engine has two independent pumps for oxidizer and fuel, spun by two turbines powered by their own dedicated preburners. But unlike the gas-generator cycle which burns just a small amount of fuel and oxidizer in the preburner, in a full-flow staged combustion engine, all of the fuel and oxidizer is run through their respective preburners. In other words, the fuel is burned twice: once at a lower efficiency in the preburners to produce energy for spinning the turbines, and again at maximum efficiency in the combustion chamber to produce thrust. While an exceptionally difficult engine to design and test, it completely eliminates the waste of the gas-generator cycle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But increased fuel efficiency isn’t the only advantage to this design. For example, the seals separating the turbine and the pump are less critical, as there’s no concern of contaminating the pumped liquid; ultimately they’re going to the same place. In addition, the fact that the fuel and oxidizer enter the combustion chamber as gasses further improves engine efficiency over conventional designs which spray them in as liquids.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The individual turbines on a full-flow staged combustion engine also tend to run cooler and at lower pressure than the single turbine used in a conventional rocket engine. This puts less stress on the turbine impellers, and should allow them to run for longer before they need to be inspected and replaced. Given SpaceX’s focus on reusability, this is likely seen just as important as the increased fuel efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Wait is Almost Over&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/02/raptor_starship.jpg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;345007&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://hackaday.com/2019/02/13/the-impossible-tech-behind-spacexs-new-engine/raptor_starship/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/02/raptor_starship.jpg&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;677,901&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;raptor_starship&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/02/raptor_starship.jpg?w=301&amp;amp;h=400&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/02/raptor_starship.jpg?w=470&quot; class=&quot;size-medium wp-image-345007&quot; src=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/02/raptor_starship.jpg?w=301&amp;amp;h=400&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;301&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; srcset=&quot;https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/02/raptor_starship.jpg?w=301&amp;amp;h=400 301w, https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/02/raptor_starship.jpg?w=602&amp;amp;h=800 602w, https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/02/raptor_starship.jpg?w=188&amp;amp;h=250 188w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 301px) 100vw, 301px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;SpaceX Starship Prototype
&lt;p&gt;While it will be the first one to fly, the SpaceX Raptor isn’t actually the first full-flow staged combustion engine to be built. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/RD-270&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The RD-270 was completed in 1967&lt;/a&gt; by the Soviet Union as part of their program to reach the Moon, and performed several static test burns. But after the United States landed on the Moon in 1969, effectively winning the Space Race, the engine (and the rocket it was meant to power) was canceled. Less complex, and ultimately cheaper, engines were used for the remainder of the Soviet space program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the 1990’s, the United States Government expressed an interest in the development of a domestic full-flow staged combustion engine. While there was promising turbine and preburner development by contractors Rocketdyne and Aerojet, neither the Air Force nor NASA chose to provide the funding that would have been required to complete the entire engine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So when will Raptor finally become the first full-flow staged combustion engine to leave Earth? If you believe Twitter, very soon. Elon Musk claims a prototype of the Raptor-powered Starship will be making low-altitude “hops” around their test facility located near Brownsville, Texas within the next couple of months. Of course a lot can happen between now and then, so it’s entirely possible that date may slip. But even still, it seems like 2019 will finally be the year that the “Holy Grail” of rocket engines finally takes to the air. Here’s hoping its been worth the wait.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2019 15:55:41 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>_JamesA_</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>The “Impossible” Tech Behind SpaceX’s New Engine</og:title>
<og:url>https://hackaday.com/2019/02/13/the-impossible-tech-behind-spacexs-new-engine/</og:url>
<og:description>Followers of the Church of Elon will no doubt already be aware of SpaceX’s latest technical triumph: the test firing of the first full-scale Raptor engine. Of course, it was hardly a secret. …</og:description>
<og:image>https://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2019/02/raptor_feat.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://hackaday.com/2019/02/13/the-impossible-tech-behind-spacexs-new-engine/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Whitespace killed an enterprise app</title>
<link>https://uxdesign.cc/how-white-space-killed-an-enterprise-app-and-why-data-density-matters-b3afad6a5f2a</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://uxdesign.cc/how-white-space-killed-an-enterprise-app-and-why-data-density-matters-b3afad6a5f2a</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;uiScale uiScale-ui--regular uiScale-caption--regular u-flexCenter u-marginVertical24 u-fontSize15 js-postMetaLockup&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;u-flex0&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;link u-baseColor--link avatar&quot; href=&quot;https://uxdesign.cc/@christielenneville?source=post_header_lockup&quot; data-action=&quot;show-user-card&quot; data-action-source=&quot;post_header_lockup&quot; data-action-value=&quot;12900b00be30&quot; data-action-type=&quot;hover&quot; data-user-id=&quot;12900b00be30&quot; data-collection-slug=&quot;user-experience-design-1&quot; dir=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/fit/c/100/100/1*UA6a4h5yZJ0lzD9UfX45Cw.png&quot; class=&quot;avatar-image u-size50x50&quot; alt=&quot;Go to the profile of Christie Lenneville&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;d40e&quot; id=&quot;d40e&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h4&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;Spacious. Minimalist. Clean.&lt;/em&gt; Bountiful white space has become the de facto design aesthetic in consumer apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;5446&quot; id=&quot;5446&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;And I’m not here to hate on the trend. Used effectively, white space is attractive and can greatly improve the usability of a simple interface. Long live bountiful white space!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;6228&quot; id=&quot;6228&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;But what about complex interfaces?&lt;/strong&gt; Enterprise software designers know the ones I mean: technology-enabling control panels, data-intensive logistics systems, and number-heavy accounting systems. The tools our business users rely on to get their jobs done every day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 name=&quot;e6f0&quot; id=&quot;e6f0&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Let me tell you a sad story.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;7277&quot; id=&quot;7277&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;The protagonist is a well-intentioned UX Designer at a large high-tech company who was given a new project: Redesign an internal control panel that was ugly, hard to learn, and stuffed full of content on every screen (so much data). Everyone agreed it needed modernization—it looked like it was from the early 2000s, after all!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;41e8&quot; id=&quot;41e8&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;So this designer set out to solve the problem, taking cues from modern consumer apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;ac29&quot; id=&quot;ac29&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;The new design simplified every screen. It broke apart huge pages into smaller, more focused ones. It used progressive disclosure to hide presumably insignificant information. And since today’s users don’t mind scrolling (ahem), the design incorporated white space in all of the usual places—around headers, content blocks, and in table rows. The breathing room was glorious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;34b2&quot; id=&quot;34b2&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;It lasted one month before the company was forced to retire it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;ae4e&quot; id=&quot;ae4e&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Users absolutely hated the new system. Sure, the old system was ugly, but it had everything they needed, right at their fingertips! Their jobs were incredibly fast paced—they worked in a tech support call center and were rated on productivity metrics. They didn’t have time to click or scroll to find information while the clock was &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;literally&lt;/em&gt; ticking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;e438&quot; id=&quot;e438&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;In their eyes, this new system wasn’t an upgrade, it was a boondoggle. It wasn’t just a little frustrating—&lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;it made them mad.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 name=&quot;261f&quot; id=&quot;261f&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf-after--p&quot;&gt;What’s the lesson here?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;3b7a&quot; id=&quot;3b7a&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;A large business by its nature has massive-scale data and usually thousands of users who directly interact with it—searching, manipulating, reporting, and more. They need to move through that data quickly, without a lot of digging around in the interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;86ff&quot; id=&quot;86ff&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Think of it this way: Just like you wouldn’t appreciate a dictionary with only 10 words per page (so many pages to flip through!), enterprise users don’t want systems that make them work to find the things they’re looking for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;cdd4&quot; id=&quot;cdd4&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;But that doesn’t mean your interface has to be ugly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;8651&quot; id=&quot;8651&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Well-designed data density can present massive amounts of information on every screen, while still maintaining a clear and scannable content hierarchy. Done right, users can quickly and accurately access the data they need, without impacting their ability to read text or interact with the application as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;b6be&quot; id=&quot;b6be&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Following are some recommendations on how to increase data density without decreasing the modern aesthetic of your application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 name=&quot;d7c3&quot; id=&quot;d7c3&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf-after--p&quot;&gt;First, try reducing data volume&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;149e&quot; id=&quot;149e&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;Before you start shrinking your font sizes to cram more data on every screen, see if all of that data is even necessary. Ask yourself:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;postList&quot;&gt;&lt;li name=&quot;5159&quot; id=&quot;5159&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--li-strong&quot;&gt;Can I eliminate redundant data?&lt;/strong&gt; So many systems accidentally display the same data multiple times with slight variations. (Massive tables are the first place to start looking for duplicative information.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;a0a9&quot; id=&quot;a0a9&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--li-strong&quot;&gt;Are there things my users really don’t need to see right now?&lt;/strong&gt; If you don’t know, ask! Are they really using everything that’s available to them?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;72f4&quot; id=&quot;72f4&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--li-strong&quot;&gt;Can I do a better job of grouping related information?&lt;/strong&gt; Not every discrete data element always needs its own table cell, even if that’s how it’s stored in the back-end system. See where you might reduce visual complexity by combining elements — for example, by putting a customer’s first and last name in the same field.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*McrScCVQL_FA0DwEJWjKlg.png&quot; data-width=&quot;1650&quot; data-height=&quot;130&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*McrScCVQL_FA0DwEJWjKlg.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*McrScCVQL_FA0DwEJWjKlg.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Harder to scan
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*r7D9zgr6bP6hBbKiYJbNZw.png&quot; data-width=&quot;1640&quot; data-height=&quot;114&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*r7D9zgr6bP6hBbKiYJbNZw.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*r7D9zgr6bP6hBbKiYJbNZw.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Easier to scan
&lt;h3 name=&quot;f069&quot; id=&quot;f069&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;Use good typographic standards&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;6002&quot; id=&quot;6002&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf--startsWithDoubleQuote graf-after--h3&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--blockquote-em&quot;&gt;“Spacing is essential for rapid reading of long, fundamentally meaningless strings, such as serial numbers, and it is helpful even for shorter strings such as phone numbers and dates.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;0760&quot; id=&quot;0760&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--blockquote&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--blockquote-em&quot;&gt;– Robert Bringhurst, The Elements of Typographic Style&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;7744&quot; id=&quot;7744&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--blockquote&quot;&gt;Appropriate typography is essential in an enterprise application. Font weights, kerning, and spacing all affect how quickly and easily your users can scan information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;postList&quot;&gt;&lt;li name=&quot;93b8&quot; id=&quot;93b8&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--li-strong&quot;&gt;Consider using monospaced numbers&lt;/strong&gt; when comparing digits between rows matters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;f2dd&quot; id=&quot;f2dd&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--li-strong&quot;&gt;Consider decimal-alignment of currency&lt;/strong&gt; when dollars and cents are important.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;4f59&quot; id=&quot;4f59&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--li-strong&quot;&gt;Keep line heights narrow&lt;/strong&gt;, but be careful to use enough white space to separate objects cleanly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3 name=&quot;d228&quot; id=&quot;d228&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf-after--li&quot;&gt;Use color deliberately.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;cc91&quot; id=&quot;cc91&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;Reduce the color of less-important content wherever possible. Using a conservative palette in your design makes the color you &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; use more impactful and open to interactive or visual meaning—like in error messages (usually red) or link text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*N1Jy6UJ9Qa40omXvGDC5Dg.png&quot; data-width=&quot;1908&quot; data-height=&quot;416&quot; data-is-featured=&quot;true&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*N1Jy6UJ9Qa40omXvGDC5Dg.png&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*N1Jy6UJ9Qa40omXvGDC5Dg.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;909f&quot; id=&quot;909f&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--figure&quot;&gt;In the above example, note the prominence of the single red highlight in the gray-themed table, thanks to the lack of other color. Each row suffers slightly in its horizontal scannability, but at the gain of increased table-wide scannability. Consider what is more important for your application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 name=&quot;62f5&quot; id=&quot;62f5&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Use less “furniture”&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;1610&quot; id=&quot;1610&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;In discussing making more readable tables, Robert Bringhurst notes,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;b1ac&quot; id=&quot;b1ac&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf--startsWithDoubleQuote graf-after--p&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--blockquote-em&quot;&gt;“There should be a minimum amount of furniture (rules, boxes, dots, and other guide rails for traveling through the typographic space) and a maximum amount of information.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote name=&quot;76c5&quot; id=&quot;76c5&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--blockquote graf-after--blockquote&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--blockquote-em&quot;&gt;– Robert Bringhurst, The Elements of Typographic Style&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;5fc2&quot; id=&quot;5fc2&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--blockquote&quot;&gt;When increasing the density of your application, think about which elements on your page are ultimately aesthetic and not valuable to the internal logic and visual structure of the page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 name=&quot;047d&quot; id=&quot;047d&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Let users export data, instead&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;1ca5&quot; id=&quot;1ca5&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;Sometimes you just can’t be dense enough. When dealing with large data sets, long lists, complex tables, or page after page of results, sometimes the best solution is to enable users to take that data to another tool where they can interact with it differently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;142c&quot; id=&quot;142c&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Consider adding affordances for your users to export the data they’re looking at (or a superset of it! what if your export could include &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; data than you can fit on the screen?) via XML, XLS, JSON, or CSV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 name=&quot;bd0b&quot; id=&quot;bd0b&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Don’t forget about touch&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;5c8e&quot; id=&quot;5c8e&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;Unless you can safely rule out touch-based interaction, don’t forget about minimum sizes for touch targets. For example, Material has good &lt;a href=&quot;https://material.io/design/usability/accessibility.html#layout-typography&quot; data-href=&quot;https://material.io/design/usability/accessibility.html#layout-typography&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;guidelines for the layout of touch targets&lt;/a&gt; on their accessibility page that you should definitely check out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 name=&quot;83ec&quot; id=&quot;83ec&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Look at Material’s Updates&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;0c61&quot; id=&quot;0c61&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;In recent updates to Material, Google included &lt;a href=&quot;https://material.io/design/layout/density.html#usage&quot; data-href=&quot;https://material.io/design/layout/density.html#usage&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;new standards that increase data density&lt;/a&gt;, making it significantly more usable for enterprise applications. They have well-considered, specific recommendations that come with a ton of wonderful examples of how density can affect your layout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 name=&quot;0804&quot; id=&quot;0804&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Function over form, always&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;493f&quot; id=&quot;493f&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;Enterprise designers can take a lot of great cues from consumer design, but functionality must always be our primary concern. That’s because our users don’t have a choice, they &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;have&lt;/em&gt; to use the tools we design—if they don’t think a system is usable, they can’t decide to just go download a different one. So we owe it to them to put their daily productivity first—always.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2019 15:08:33 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>kirkbackus</dc:creator>
<og:title>How white space killed an enterprise app (and why data density matters)</og:title>
<og:url>https://uxdesign.cc/how-white-space-killed-an-enterprise-app-and-why-data-density-matters-b3afad6a5f2a</og:url>
<og:image>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*N1Jy6UJ9Qa40omXvGDC5Dg.png</og:image>
<og:description>Co-Written by Patrick Deuley.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://uxdesign.cc/how-white-space-killed-an-enterprise-app-and-why-data-density-matters-b3afad6a5f2a?gi=fb6c100e8958</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>How hard is it to have a conversation on Twitter? So hard even the CEO can’t</title>
<link>https://www.recode.net/2019/2/12/18222558/kara-swisher-jack-dorsey-twitter-interview-conversation-karajack-livetweet</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.recode.net/2019/2/12/18222558/kara-swisher-jack-dorsey-twitter-interview-conversation-karajack-livetweet</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;BzJz91&quot;&gt;Twitter wants to be the place for the most important public conversations online. It still has some serious work to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;fEP6xP&quot;&gt;Twitter CEO Jack Dorsey and &lt;strong&gt;Recode&lt;/strong&gt; co-founder Kara Swisher &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.recode.net/2019/2/12/18221057/kara-swisher-jack-dorsey-twitter-live-interview-karajack&quot;&gt;agreed to conduct an interview Tuesday on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, and it had all the makings of a great read: The CEO of one of the most influential and controversial tech platforms in the world taking questions from one of the industry’s most ferocious reporters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;SiRrqh&quot;&gt;The only problem? No one could follow along.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;SrPzt4&quot;&gt;Despite the public interview and a dedicated hashtag (#karajack) for the event, it didn’t take long before the dozens of tweets between the two started to get confusing. They were listed out of order, other users started chiming in, and there was no way to properly follow the conversation thread.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;ZFXtZE&quot;&gt;Swisher’s questions about Twitter’s complex abuse policies and Dorsey’s subsequent responses were floating around my timeline along with the regular tech news and opinions I always look at. If you wanted to find a permanent thread of the chat, you had to visit one of either Kara or Jack’s pages and continually refresh. It made for a difficult and confusing experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;wKjbsu&quot;&gt;Dorsey even admitted so himself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;13aWmm&quot;&gt;“I am going to start a NEW thread to make it easy for people to follow (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/waltmossberg&quot;&gt;@waltmossberg&lt;/a&gt; just texted me that it is a “chaotic hellpit”),” &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/karaswisher/status/1095455420020375552&quot;&gt;Swisher tweeted&lt;/a&gt;, referencing &lt;strong&gt;Recode’s&lt;/strong&gt; other co-founder, the now-retired Walt Mossberg.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;0NZcEN&quot;&gt;“Ok. Definitely not easy to follow the conversation,” Dorsey replied. “Exactly why we are doing this. Fixing stuff like this will help I believe.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;NUFVZQ&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.recode.net/2019/2/12/18222178/kara-swisher-jack-dorsey-interview-twitter-transcript-karajack&quot;&gt;(&lt;strong&gt;Recode&lt;/strong&gt; chronologically compiled the full interview in two Twitter Moments. Check it out here.)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;U9wtPU&quot;&gt;That wasn’t the only problem. Swisher pressed Dorsey on what the service’s greatest problems are, how Twitter plans to take responsibility for them, and the ways that Twitter is trying to better police its service. “Please give me three concrete things you have done to fix this,” she tweeted multiple times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;3GZthv&quot;&gt;If you could find that whole exchange, you ran into another problem: Twitter’s 280 characters just don’t leave enough room for a nuanced conversation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;OCu471&quot;&gt;To that last tweet, for example, Dorsey replied with a list of four items, including things like “We have evolved our polices,” and, “We have prioritized proactive enforcement to remove burden from victims.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;whTbHZ&quot;&gt;Swisher’s responses: “WHICH?” and “HOW?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;oBt18R&quot; readability=&quot;5.9166666666667&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; readability=&quot;5.9166666666667&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;1. WHICH?&lt;br/&gt;2. HOW?&lt;br/&gt;3. OK, MUTE BUT THAT WAS A WHILE AGO&lt;br/&gt;4. WHAT MORE?&lt;br/&gt;I think people are dying for specifics. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/karajack?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#karajack&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
— Kara Swisher (@karaswisher) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/karaswisher/status/1095452756331106307?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;February 12, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;3uhqir&quot;&gt;There simply wasn’t enough room to have the kind of nuanced conversation the subject requires. It was symbolic of Twitter’s broader problem: It’s almost impossible to have a smart, healthy argument on Twitter because no one has the space needed to share their thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;rdmn5L&quot;&gt;The consensus that this interview was too hard to follow — and it was a wildly popular opinion — overshadowed what could have been a great conversation. Kudos to Dorsey for taking the time to field tough questions — though many of his answers weren’t very satisfying. He even &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jack/status/1095442976497496064&quot;&gt;left his comms team at the office&lt;/a&gt;, apparently!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;98op8z&quot; readability=&quot;6.4013157894737&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; readability=&quot;6.4013157894737&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Your &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/KaraJack?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#KaraJack&lt;/a&gt; tl;dr:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jack: We need to stop X.&lt;br/&gt;Kara: What specifically are you doing to stop X?&lt;br/&gt;Jack: We haven’t done enough to stop X. We’re thinking hard about how to do that.&lt;br/&gt;Kara: Have you done *anything* to stop X?&lt;br/&gt;Jack: We haven’t done enough.&lt;/p&gt;
— Felix Salmon (@felixsalmon) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/felixsalmon/status/1095451405723357184?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;February 12, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;2GqQBF&quot;&gt;Tuesday’s event was a chance for Twitter to show off what makes its service so incredible — that you can watch two industry titans share ideas back and forth in real time, in public. Maybe Twitter should build some kind of live chat feature for these high-profile interviews? Maybe Twitter is &lt;em&gt;already building&lt;/em&gt; some kind of live chat feature for these high profile interviews?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;LxJO9O&quot;&gt;“This thread was hard. But we got to learn a ton to fix it,” Dorsey tweeted after the interview wrapped up. “Need to make this feel a lot more cohesive and easier to follow. Was extremely challenging. Thank you for trying it with me. Know it wasn’t easy. Will consider different formats!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;2AaOQO&quot;&gt;We know that Twitter is trying to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.recode.net/2019/1/15/18183325/twitter-product-beta-healthy-conversation-effort-sara-haider&quot;&gt;improve its conversations feature&lt;/a&gt;. Maybe when it does, we’ll get round No. 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id=&quot;bNrjF6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;c-newsletter_signup_box&quot; id=&quot;newsletter-signup-short-form&quot; data-newsletter-slug=&quot;recode_daily&quot; readability=&quot;8.4857142857143&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;c-newsletter_signup_box__main&quot; readability=&quot;33&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c-newsletter_signup_box__icon&quot;/&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;c-newsletter_signup_box__title&quot;&gt;Recode Daily&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-newsletter_signup_box__blurb&quot;&gt;Sign up for our Recode Daily newsletter to get the top tech and business news stories delivered to your inbox.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;c-newsletter_signup_box__disclaimer&quot; readability=&quot;8.6&quot;&gt;By signing up, you agree to our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.voxmedia.com/pages/privacy-policy&quot;&gt;Privacy Policy&lt;/a&gt; and European users agree to the data transfer policy.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2019 12:20:16 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>longdefeat</dc:creator>
<og:description>Kara Swisher’s live-tweeted interview with Jack Dorsey highlighted some of Twitter’s product issues.</og:description>
<og:image>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Bi7bD7OI06Wo4kGMb4hiM9L8xqI=/0x290:2666x1686/fit-in/1200x630/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/7090603/20160912-jack-dorsey-twitter.0.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>How hard is it to have a conversation on Twitter? So hard even the CEO can’t do it.</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.recode.net/2019/2/12/18222558/kara-swisher-jack-dorsey-twitter-interview-conversation-karajack-livetweet</og:url>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.recode.net/2019/2/12/18222558/kara-swisher-jack-dorsey-twitter-interview-conversation-karajack-livetweet</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>