<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Airbnb to Acquire HotelTonight</title>
<link>https://press.airbnb.com/airbnb-signs-agreement-to-acquire-hoteltonight/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://press.airbnb.com/airbnb-signs-agreement-to-acquire-hoteltonight/</guid>
<description>&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Continues to Build End-to-End Travel Platform&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Delivering on Commitment to Bring Magical Travel to Everyone&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Airbnb’s mission is to create a world where anyone can belong anywhere. To advance our mission, we are reimagining travel by building an end-to-end travel platform that combines where you stay, what you do, and how you get there, all in one place. Today, we are building on this work by signing an agreement to acquire HotelTonight. HotelTonight is a hotel-booking service focused on making last-minute trips easy and fun, offering guests seamless, on-demand booking for boutique and independent hotels.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;A big part of building an end-to-end travel platform is serving every guest, whether they plan their trip a year or a day in advance.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Working with the incredible team at HotelTonight, we will offer guests an unparalleled last-minute travel experience that provides unique, memorable hospitality on every trip, on any schedule, at any time.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brian Chesky, Airbnb Co-Founder, CEO and Head of Community&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Airbnb has built an unrivaled global community of hosts and guests—we can connect travelers to more than 6 million places to stay and tens of thousands of incredible experiences around the world. Airbnb “is now the most searched-for accommodations brand” according to&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hotelnewsnow.com/Articles/291386/Glamping-as-an-asset-class-Google-misspelling&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;one Google executive&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, and guests are using Airbnb for every kind of trip, including business and last-minute travel. Today, more than 400,000 companies are using Airbnb to help manage their travel, and same-day bookings are now growing 2x year over year. Welcoming more boutique hotels to our platform will help us deliver on our commitment to make Airbnb for everyone, providing guests the authentic, local experience they have come to expect on every trip.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;We started HotelTonight because we knew people wanted a better way to book an amazing hotel room on-demand, and we are excited to join forces with Airbnb to bring this service to guests around the world.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Together, HotelTonight and Airbnb can give guests more choices and the world’s best boutique and independent hotels a genuine partner to connect them with those guests.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sam Shank, Co-founder &amp;amp; CEO of HotelTonight&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The acquisition of HotelTonight:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Accelerates our work to build an end-to-end travel platform that serves everyone.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;We are making it easier for people who use Airbnb to find last-minute places to stay when Home hosts are often already booked. The availability of boutique hotels—in addition to private rooms and entire homes that are instantly bookable—helps ensure authentic, high-quality stays are available on-demand, especially at the last minute.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;HotelTonight&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;team has developed deep relationships with boutique hotels and expertise in seamless, last-minute booking.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;HotelTonight&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;is rooted in the same kinds of hospitality properties we have welcomed to the Airbnb community, and these boutique and independent hotels contribute the majority of&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;HotelTonight&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;’s business.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Meets enormous demand from—and for—boutique hotels.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Over the past few years, we’ve seen an increasing number of hoteliers take inspiration from our Home hosts, making their boutique hotels more unique with custom touches. Last year,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://press.airbnb.com/airbnb-unveils-roadmap-to-bring-magical-travel-to-everyone/&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;we announced our intent&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;to&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.airbnb.com/b/hotels&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;make it easier for these boutique hotels to list on our platform&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;. We’ve had an overwhelming response from hoteliers&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;with strong ties to their local communities who want to offer truly personal hospitality&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;: in 2018, we more than doubled the number of rooms available on Airbnb in properties that hosts categorized as boutique hotels, bed and breakfasts, and other hospitality venues like hostels and resorts.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;We’ve also seen Airbnb guests respond enthusiastically to this increased supply, booking three times as many nights with boutique hotels in 2018 compared with 2017.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Together with HotelTonight, we can offer places to stay for every type of traveler on all kinds of trips and make it easier for small businesses and hoteliers who take pride in providing authentic, unique experiences to tap into Airbnb’s truly global network of hosts and guests.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Supports Home hosts.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;As we have welcomed boutique hotels to Airbnb, we’ve been delighted to see the positive impact for our Home hosts. The acquisition of&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;HotelTonight&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;will accelerate that positive benefit. Boutique hotels are helping to bring new guests to Airbnb and making our community larger and stronger. Once these new guests come to Airbnb, they’re returning to book with our Home hosts: in fact, nearly 90 percent of guests who first used Airbnb to book a hotel room and returned to our platform for a second trip then booked a home.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re excited to continue our work to grow our community and make Airbnb for everyone. The HotelTonight app and website will continue to operate as they do today. Once the acquisition is complete, Sam Shank will report to Greg Greeley, Airbnb’s President of Homes, and lead our boutique hotel category.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 18:43:04 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>c_t_montgomery</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Airbnb Signs Agreement to Acquire HotelTonight</og:title>
<og:description>To advance our mission, we are reimagining travel by building an end-to-end travel platform. Today, we are building on this work by signing an agreement to acquire HotelTonight.</og:description>
<og:url>https://press.airbnb.com/airbnb-signs-agreement-to-acquire-hoteltonight/</og:url>
<og:image>https://press.airbnb.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2019/03/PJMPHOTO18Q335-Society-Hotel-03568.jpg?fit=2000%2C1334</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://press.airbnb.com/airbnb-signs-agreement-to-acquire-hoteltonight/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Notepad++ drops code signing for its releases</title>
<link>https://notepad-plus-plus.org/news/notepad-7.6.4-released.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://notepad-plus-plus.org/news/notepad-7.6.4-released.html</guid>
<description>&lt;ol id=&quot;breadcrumbs&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;first&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://notepad-plus-plus.org/&quot; title=&quot;Home&quot;&gt;Home&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;news/&quot; title=&quot;News&quot;&gt;News&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;news/notepad-7.6.4-released.html&quot; title=&quot;Notepad++ 7.6.4 released&quot; class=&quot;active&quot;&gt;Notepad++ 7.6.4 released&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;06 Mar 2019 14:33:00&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you install Notepad++ version 7.6.4, You might notice there's no more blue-trusted UAC popup. Here's the explanation for the reason that we remove code signing from Notepad++ :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 years ago DigiCert donated a 3 years code signing certificate to the project, and every good thing has its end, the certificate has been expired since the beginning of this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was trying to purchase another certificate with reasonable price. However I cannot use &quot;Notepad++&quot; as CN to sign because Notepad++ doesn’t exist as company or organization. I wasted hours and hours for getting one suitable certificate instead of working on essential thing - Notepad++ project. I realize that code signing certificate is just an overpriced masturbating toy of FOSS authors - Notepad++ has done without certificate for more than 10 years, I don’t see why I should add the dependency now (and be an accomplice of this overpricing industry). I decide to do without it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It doesn’t mean there’s no more security in Notepad++, but it will be less flexible for sure:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;SHA256 hash of Installer and other packages will be provided for every release as usual. Too bad for ugly yellow-orange UAC popup while installation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Notepad++ will check the SHA256 of all the components (SciLexer.dll, GUP.exe and nppPluginList.dll) used by the program.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Markdown is supposed to work in v7.6.3, but the needed file isn't deployed correctly by the installer. The bug is fixed in this version. Additionally Markdown is available in every package from this release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;European Commission's Free and Open Source Software Auditing Bug Bounty program is still in progress, few vulnerable issues and some crash bugs are identified and fixed in this release thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hackerone.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;HackerOne&lt;/a&gt; team's help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Download 7.6.4 here:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/download/v7.6.4.html&quot;&gt;&lt;img title=&quot;Notepad++ Download&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/downloadLogo.png&quot; alt=&quot;Notepad++ Download&quot; width=&quot;268&quot; height=&quot;56&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;https://notepad-plus-plus.org/download/v7.6.4.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Auto-updater will be triggered in few days if there's no critical issue found.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you find any regression or critical bug, please report here:&lt;a href=&quot;https://notepad-plus-plus.org/community/topic/17239/notepad-v7-6-4-released&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;https://notepad-plus-plus.org/community/topic/17239/notepad-v7-6-4-released&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 16:27:03 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>pmh</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-AU</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://notepad-plus-plus.org/news/notepad-7.6.4-released.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>PureOS is convergent</title>
<link>https://puri.sm/posts/converging-on-convergence-pureos-is-convergent-welcome-to-the-future/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://puri.sm/posts/converging-on-convergence-pureos-is-convergent-welcome-to-the-future/</guid>
<description>&lt;h2&gt;Many Devices, One OS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two big mobile OS vendors have been dreaming of convergence between laptop OS and mobile OS for a long time; dreaming of being able to make the same application code execute, and operate, both on mobile phones and laptops – adapting the applications to screen size and input devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Purism is beating the duopoly to that dream, with PureOS: we are now announcing that Purism’s PureOS is convergent, and has laid the foundation for all future applications to run on both the Librem 5 phone and Librem laptops, from the same PureOS release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-62779&quot; src=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/web-on-devices-1024x576.png&quot; alt=&quot;Purism has one convergent operating system, PureOS. Google has two separate ones, ChromeOS and Android; Apple has two separate ones too, macOS and iOS.&quot; srcset=&quot;https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/web-on-devices-1024x576.png 1024w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/web-on-devices-300x169.png 300w, https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/web-on-devices-768x432.png 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Purism has one convergent operating system, PureOS. Google has two separate ones, ChromeOS and Android; Apple has two separate ones too, macOS and iOS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What Is Convergence?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’ve ever had an app on your phone that you wanted on your laptop, you’ve wanted convergence. Convergence is a term used to describe the similar functioning of an app across different platforms. Many companies are eager to have their software be convergent, because it brings a consistent look and feel, as well as the exact same functionality for apps that run on your phone and your computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Convergence can be really handy, since it allows you to use the apps you’re already familiar with, as well as the data that you’ve already synced. Convergence also brings plenty of of benefits to developers, such as writing your app once, testing it once and running it everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since this is the ideal dream, why don’t we have convergence already? Why can’t a person run the exact same app on a phone and laptop today? It turns out that this is really hard to do unless you have complete control of software source code and access to hardware itself. Even then, there is a catch; you need to compile software for both the phone’s CPU and the laptop CPU which are usually different architectures. This is a complex process that often reveals assumptions made in software development but it shows that to build a truly convergent device you need to design for convergence from the beginning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reaching convergence is one more checked item on the list that Purism’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://puri.sm/posts/purism-origin-story/&quot;&gt;founder envisioned&lt;/a&gt; when he created the company, specifically to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“…manufacture a mobile phone from the schematics on up that would run that same ethical operating system.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How We Got There&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The right path to get us here was starting with the “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.debian.org/&quot;&gt;universal operating system&lt;/a&gt;” as the foundation of PureOS, Purism’s operating system. Running on so many different CPU architectures is a huge benefit, because very often laptops need a power-hungry and fast CPU, while a phone needs a power-aware, battery-saving CPU. These CPUs are, consequently, designed differently for their different uses, and you often have to “port” or cross-compile software for it to work well on both CPUs. By basing PureOS on a solid, foundational operating system – one that has been solving this performance and run-everywhere problem for years – means there is a large set of packaged software that “just works” on many different types of CPUs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;5.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Purism’s PureOS showcasing adaptive convergent design in a Web Browser — notice as the window subtly resizes the buttons in the application’s header shift to the footer, for a mobile friendly interface.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The above example is already built into the &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.gnome.org/GNOME/epiphany/blob/master/NEWS#L74&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;master branch&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.gnome.org/Apps/Web/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;GNOME Web&lt;/a&gt; as a class-based modification to the existing code, allowing it to easily adjust and adapt to the screen size and inputs of both mobile and desktop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Adaptive Design&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Multiple architectures are not enough to reach convergence however – as most people know by now, there are many important parts in getting true convergence. A good example of the problem in website design space: if you’ve ever gone to a website on your phone that had tiny text which scrolled off your phone screen, you know that a regular web page, designed for a desktop computer, isn’t always suitable for your smaller screen phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Web designers now have toolboxes to design web pages, which they adjust for mobile or desktop in order to get easier readability and use. A similar, but far more complex practice, is required for software apps and defined by Purism as “adaptive design”. Purism is hard at work on creating adaptive &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnome.org/&quot;&gt;GNOME&lt;/a&gt; apps – and the community is joining this effort as well – apps that look great, and work great, both on a phone and on a laptop. Combining the work of the free software ecosystem with Purism’s contributions means we can target convergence for all our Librem hardware line: both the 13″ and 15″ laptops and the 5″ phone. This means we can get the most out of the ecosystem for the community: convergent apps will be easier to maintain, and therefore easier to secure. They will also be easier to build, enabling a vibrant community to build cool stuff that is free software and protects your privacy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;13&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Purism’s PureOS showcasing adaptive convergent development in Discussions (Fractal) – a matrix chat program. As the window resizes, the column width dynamically changes to preserve a legible line width, until the sidebar and message view don’t fit at the same time. At this point the leaflet folds, only the message view is visible, and a back button is added to the header-bar, to allow navigation to the room list.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Building Convergence Features into Existing Apps&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developers can tap into convergence through the tools we actively use, contribute to, and develop directly in the ecosystem. We’ve created libhandy, a mobile and adaptive presentation library for GTK+ and GNOME, which is under active development. Packaged in PureOS and Debian already, you can also use it in flatpaks, simply by including it in your flatpak maniphest in Builder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Purism’s PureOS showcasing adaptive convergent development in Password Safe, an encrypted password storing application.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are excited to provide convergence well before any of the other mobile OS vendors. Let’s see how long it takes for them to catch-up. Thank you for your continued support!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 14:09:44 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>iBelieve</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Converging on Convergence PureOS is Convergent, Welcome to the Future – Purism</og:title>
<og:description>Many Devices, One OS The two big mobile OS vendors have been dreaming of convergence between laptop OS and mobile OS for a long time; dreaming of being able to make the same application code execute, and operate, both on mobile phones and laptops – adapting the applications to screen size and input devices. Purism …</og:description>
<og:url>https://puri.sm/posts/converging-on-convergence-pureos-is-convergent-welcome-to-the-future/</og:url>
<og:image>https://puri.sm/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/aerial-photography-aerial-shot-aerial-view-1629803.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://puri.sm/posts/converging-on-convergence-pureos-is-convergent-welcome-to-the-future/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The rise of wgpu</title>
<link>https://gfx-rs.github.io/2019/03/06/wgpu.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://gfx-rs.github.io/2019/03/06/wgpu.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/gfx-rs/gfx&quot;&gt;gfx-rs&lt;/a&gt; is a Rust project aiming to make graphics programming more accessible and portable, focusing on exposing a universal Vulkan-like API targeting all platforms. Over the past 2 years we’ve put a lot of effort into making gfx-rs API compatible with Vulkan and wrapping it in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/gfx-rs/portability&quot;&gt;Vulkan Portability bindings&lt;/a&gt;. We optimized the Metal backend, nailed down hundreds of issues revealed by &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/KhronosGroup/VK-GL-CTS&quot;&gt;Vulkan Conformance Test Suite&lt;/a&gt;, contributed our expertize to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/KhronosGroup/Vulkan-Portability&quot;&gt;standardization process&lt;/a&gt;. What didn’t go entirely smoothly was the integration into Rust ecosystem: building libraries and applications on top of gfx’s hardware abstraction layer (hal) proved to be extremely challenging due to the low-levelness and unsafety of the API. There is a serious demand for an API that has the capabilities of Vulkan but is easier to work with.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The main community driving &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;gfx-hal&lt;/code&gt; adoption today is the Amethyst game engine, and they produced a nice helper library called &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/omni-viral/rendy&quot;&gt;Rendy&lt;/a&gt;. As they call it, a “collection of crates to build your own renderer”. The concept is reminiscent of LLVM (“build your own compiler”) and overall fits nicely into the Amethyst philosophy. The project has recently &lt;a href=&quot;https://community.amethyst-engine.org/t/rendy-is-released/459&quot;&gt;been released&lt;/a&gt;, and is worth checking out despite being experimental. Amethyst hasn’t fully switched to gfx-hal yet, Rendy is version 0.1.1, and gfx’s mileage may vary per backend. We’re having a lot of fun with it already, but that’s not all.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;webgpu&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;WebGPU&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w3.org/community/gpu/&quot;&gt;WebGPU&lt;/a&gt; is a new graphics/compute API developed by the browser vendors (and Intel) within W3C:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The goal is to design a new Web API that exposes these modern technologies in a performant, powerful and safe manner.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Don’t be confused by the “Web” part here - both us (gfx-rs team) and Google are trying to make it feasible to run on native platforms as well. Typically, the Web as a platform has different priorities from native: a lot of focus is placed on the security and portability (in a wider and stronger sense). Coincidentally, these are qualities we are currently missing in the gfx-rs ecosystem: security means safety (in the Rust sense), and portability means that people can use it and run everywhere, without worrying about thousands of potential configurations at run-time, or diverging behavior between platforms due to timing differences or loosely defined behavior.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;With these goals in mind, we’d like to announce our new project: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/gfx-rs/wgpu&quot;&gt;wgpu-rs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;wgpu-rs&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;wgpu-rs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;wgpu-rs is aiming to be a safe, portable API which reduces the complexity of working with low-level graphics APIs. It has a layered implementation:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;The &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;wgpu-native&lt;/code&gt; layer which exposes a C API. &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;wgpu-native&lt;/code&gt; is implemented on top of gfx-hal which allows it to work with the same platforms that gfx-hal already supports. The idea is that &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;wgpu-native&lt;/code&gt; will have a compatible C API with Google’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://dawn.googlesource.com/dawn&quot;&gt;Dawn&lt;/a&gt; implementation so they can be used interchangeably for applications compiled in other languages.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;The &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;wgpu-rs&lt;/code&gt; layer which is an idiomatic safe Rust API. It uses &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;wgpu-native&lt;/code&gt; internally on native targets. It will use Web APIs (from WASM host bindings) directly when targeting the Web in the future.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Let’s dive into the mentioned qualities of the API:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;simple&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Simple&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Writing straight Vulkan code for an application can easily challenge a user’s sanity. It’s a great API, it’s well documented, but still very complex, and it’s made with a focus on engines as opposed to direct users. You have to think about the memory allocations, pipeline stages, resource states and lifetimes, all the time. Just rendering a textured rectangle out there without triggering any validation warnings is an achievement.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;WebGPU automates some of the aspects of low-level graphics APIs which have high complexity but low return on investment. It still has the core pieces of the next-gen APIs, such as command buffers, render passes, pipeline states and layouts. Because the complexity is reduced, users will be able to direct more focus towards writing efficiently application code.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;safe&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Safe&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;WebGPU is designed from the ground up to have all the validation built-in. In our case, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;wgpu-native&lt;/code&gt; is responsible for sanitizing the inputs, capturing invalid usages, and reporting back to the user. This means that our &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;wgpu-rs&lt;/code&gt; wrapper can be entirely safe in the Rust sense. We don’t even rely on Rust syntax and features for safety, since it’s handled at the lower level, so we can have as much type-safety as we want to feel comfortable, or as little as needed to be flexible.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;portable&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Portable&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The code runs on a variety of platforms from a single source: Vulkan, Metal, D3D12/D3D11, and eventually the Web (when the browsers gain support for the API, which is also in our scope of work). And it’s expected to behave exactly the same, independent of the exposed hardware queues, image format capabilities, or memory types.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;picking-up-the-flag&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Picking up the flag&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;In a way, WebGPU is trying to accomplish all the goals we set for ourselves originally at the start of gfx-rs project. And that’s why we are so enthusiastic about it: it’s more modern, it’s more safe, it’s more portable, and there is a working group behind it with strong momentum which will eventually become widespread. Today we are releasing &lt;a href=&quot;https://crates.io/crates/wgpu/0.2.0&quot;&gt;wgpu-0.2&lt;/a&gt; for the community to try out. It’s still largely incomplete (e.g. no validation or error reporting yet), but it reached a point of being usable:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://gfx-rs.github.io/img/wgpu-shadow.png&quot; alt=&quot;WGPU shadow&quot;/&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://gfx-rs.github.io/img/wgpu-asteroid-giger.png&quot; alt=&quot;WGPU asteroid&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;wgpu-rs&lt;/code&gt; is a heavy work in progress, has only been developed since September last year, and as such some assembly is still required. However, those who don’t mind some tinkering, will find a promising library with a bright future and a compelling compatibility proposition already. We are looking forward to see what the community is able to accomplish with it, and I myself (@kvark) have a number of projects using gfx pre-ll that have been waiting for this moment to upgrade. With &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;wgpu-rs&lt;/code&gt; we can finally deprecate the old gfx and have a solid recommendation for people getting started with graphics in Rust.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 10:44:26 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jobstijl</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://gfx-rs.github.io/2019/03/06/wgpu.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>ARM processors like A12X are nearing performance parity with desktop processors</title>
<link>https://reveried.com/article/arm-processors-nearing-performance-parity-with-x86</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://reveried.com/article/arm-processors-nearing-performance-parity-with-x86</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Anandtech released their review of the iPhone XS a few months ago and despite a vague commitment to Android, my curiosity got the better of me: I read the whole thing. Most of the review didn't surprise, it had a typically great screen, battery life was solid and GPU performance had improved significantly. But several pages of it were dedicated to analysing and testing the micro-architecture of Apple’s new A12 chip, and these sections stood out in a big way. Reading the final sentence, I was somewhat shocked:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Of course there’s compiler considerations and various frequency concerns to take into account, but still we’re now talking about very small margins until Apple’s mobile SoCs outperform the fastest desktop CPUs in terms of ST [single thread] performance.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surely that’s not possible, I figured. Desktop processors were just faster. They always have been. Surely my enormous gaming setup, with an i7 4790k processor, 5 fans and far too much desk space could not be bested in peak CPU performance by a smartphone. Bullshit. So I ignored it and moved on - nothing to see here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The 2018 iPad Pro.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few months after this dismissal the iPad Pro 2018 was announced, and an interesting headline immediately hit the press: &lt;em&gt;“Apple's A12X reaches desktop CPU performance in benchmarks”&lt;/em&gt;. I saw posts with titles to this effect in various places - on tech websites, reddit, forums, in discussion threads, comment sections and more - and noticed a common reaction: many saw that the benchmark in question was Geekbench or something similar, and they rejected the central claim outright. The popular consensus was very clear: if you were to truly compare the performance in an objective fashion, a high-end Intel core i7, or even an i3, would obliterate the A12X.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wasn’t satisfied with this reaction for a bunch of reasons, even though it was precisely the reflexive rejection I employed after reading the iPhone XS review. Firstly, it struck me as odd that Anandtech, arguably the most thorough technology reviewers in tech journalism, would make such a bold claim about the A12 if it could be easily disproved. Secondly, as I looked through many iPad Pro reviews, I was consistently shocked at just how well it performed, not just in terms of fluidity, but &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QiPRnPXOvjc&quot;&gt;workload tasks&lt;/a&gt;. This was completely against what I understood to be true: that modern x86 architectures were inherently and far better than ARM-based chips, that ARM chips only had an efficiency advantage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But after a fair amount of research and deliberation, I came to a very different conclusion. There’s nuance in every corner, but after working through common arguments and misconceptions, such as that the RISC (ARM) instruction set architecture is inherently inferior to CISC (x86), that the benchmarks spruiking excellent ARM performance are inaccurate, that the performance gap is explained by different operating systems, and more, I’ve found that the central claim of these articles largely holds true: ARM processors, particularly those produced by Apple, have caught up to high-end x86 processors in most perspectives of performance. This article is the result of a deep-dive into the topic, intended somewhat to end the myth that ARM processors are behind in terms of performance. Be ready for a good, long read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;RISC v CISC&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first response I saw many employ against ARM parity was that x86 chips are based on the CISC Instruction Set Architecture (ISA) and are therefore inherently superior to mobile chips based on the RISC ISA. This argument centres around a postulation that complex desktop programs perform worse on ARM chips because they are RISC-based. Many discussions and upvotes seemed to end on this point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cs.stanford.edu/people/eroberts/courses/soco/projects/risc/risccisc/&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;CISC&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is an ISA which executes complex commands in as few lines as possible so to minimise reliance on cache and memory, while &lt;a href=&quot;https://cs.stanford.edu/people/eroberts/courses/soco/projects/risc/risccisc/&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;RISC&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; organises commands into multiple simple instructions that can be each executed in a single CPU cycle. Here’s a &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@csoham358/a-beginners-guide-to-risc-and-cisc-architectures-fc9af424db3b&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;fantastic article&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; breaking down covering the differences between the two. While they have different advantages, CISC was first prioritised not necessarily because it was inherently better, but because memory was expensive at the time and because RISC processors required a bit of software wizardry to get right (Stanford UNI). Once Windows cemented support for CISC, specifically x86, processors only, the industry and investment interest focused on CISC, and faster and faster x86 processors were demanded. A notable exception existed in PowerPC and the Mac, but soon enough Apple joined the CISC bandwagon in their Intel transition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, ARM Holdings (keeping in mind that ARM stands for Advanced RISC Machine) started to develop chips for mobile devices where efficiency, not raw performance, was the initial focus. Alongside a competitive environment between Intel and AMD and a lack of demand for RISC chips in desktop systems, this created a vague industry momentum - RISC for mobile and CISC for desktop. At some point in time, this momentum turned into a popular assumption that the &lt;em&gt;reason&lt;/em&gt; the performance gap existed was the difference in ISA. Accordingly, RISC was meant to be inferior and naturally relegated to slow but efficient chips, while high-end Intel and AMD chips would forever reign supreme on the performance front. But this is a myth, and it hasn't borne out - in so many ways the lines of RISC and CISC have blurred, borrowing design ideas over decades of manufacturing. RISC stands for Reduced Instruction Set Chip, and yet most modern RISC processors have large, complex instruction sets that rival their &lt;strong&gt;C&lt;/strong&gt;omplex &lt;strong&gt;I&lt;/strong&gt;nstruction &lt;strong&gt;S&lt;/strong&gt;et (&lt;strong&gt;C&lt;/strong&gt;hip) counterparts. Today, micro-architecture, which is how an ISA is actually implemented, is far more important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://research.cs.wisc.edu/vertical/papers/2013/hpca13-isa-power-struggles.pdf&quot;&gt;A study by the University of Wisconsin backs this up,&lt;/a&gt; stating that the performance difference between RISC and CISC is not due to their ISA, but the micro-architecture differences between products in the market, &lt;strong&gt;suggesting that either ISA has the potential to perform as well as one another.&lt;/strong&gt; In any case, 5 years ago x86 CISC chips had the developmental and micro-architectural advantage, so the ISA argument was hard to disprove.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But some combination of the portable device boom, demand for fast and efficient server processors and a general trend towards more efficient devices created a firestorm of investment and R&amp;amp;D that saw ARM processors begin to improve radically. In the last decade Intel and AMD CPUs have made small overall performance improvements year on year, while ARM chips have made sizable leaps each generation. Granted, 10 years ago commercial ARM chips were absolutely obliterated by any half-decent desktop Intel or AMD processor, so these leaps were absolutely necessary for any chance at actually competing, but the changes have been so quick that the old truths about ARM inferiority haven’t had time to leave the computing vernacular.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All this said, the original claim about against RISC still has an element of truth to it - Windows doesn’t fully support ARM or RISC based processors. When these chips have been used on Windows devices, such as in the case of the HP Envy X2, a 32-bit x86 emulator is employed to run x86 programs, and they perform terribly. To be clear, this doesn't indicate that ARM chips are slower, just that they aren’t natively supported by desktop OSes like Windows and MacOS. The key takeaway is that there’s no ISA battle anymore, the performance debate between RISC and CISC is moot, and gains are to be found in microarchitecture, not instruction set architecture. Improvements to cache implementation, instruction set width, chip size, branch prediction, and other architectural improvements are where the biggest IPC gains exist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Benchmarks are imperfect, therefore useless.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next issue I want to address are fallacies I've seen permeate discussions around ARM performance: that a benchmark is not at all useful because it is flawed or not objective in some way. I understand the reaction to a degree (I once wrote an article criticising camera benchmarks that reduce complex data into single scalar numbers), but I also believe that it’s possible to understand the shortcomings of a benchmark, not to approach it objectively, and to properly consider what it might indicate, rather than dismissing it out of hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Differences in Operating System&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's a popular but somewhat misguided belief that cross-platform benchmarks are not at all relevant because different operating systems like iOS and Windows skew the results too significantly. You've seen it before: &lt;em&gt;&quot;Yeah, it performs that well on iOS, but on a Windows machine an i5 would destroy it&quot;.&lt;/em&gt; On the surface this doesn't sound like a bad argument, since it's true in many instances, especially those benchmarks that use high-level OS APIs. Metal for example is a highly optimised low-level graphics API for iOS/MacOS only, so comparing its performance on an iPhone against OpenCL performance on a Windows machine would produce highly misleading results. But unless there's a bug or performance issue with the kernel or firmware with a tested device, the kind of compute tasks most cross-platform CPU benchmarks test are designed so that they’re not particularly bound to the platforms on which they run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To explain with a hypothetical: let’s say, using a native program, I ask an iPad Pro 2018 to calculate ten million digits of pi (a rudimentary way to measure one very particular facet of performance) and it takes 60 seconds, compared to a Windows desktop machine 90 seconds. In this scenario one of either two things are roughly true: the hardware in the iPad Pro is genuinely 33% faster at completing this task, or there's an inefficiency, bug or poor optimisation somewhere in the setup of that Windows device that is limiting its true performance in this task. It's the first scenario that is most often true. Again, this doesn’t mean the takeaway is that the iPad is 33% faster, but it does typically indicate some advantage in that particular facet of performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are examples, however, where the difference between OSes are much more significant: browser tests and JS performance. In so many of these cases, the A12X excels. NotebookCheck’s review of the iPad Pro shows it performing 16% - 50% better than the brand new Surface Pro i7 model in browser benchmarks. If we compare to a desktop processor by cross-referencing the data with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.anandtech.com/show/11859/the-anandtech-coffee-lake-review-8700k-and-8400-initial-numbers/9&quot;&gt;Anandtech’s review of the i7-8700k&lt;/a&gt;, we can see that the iPad Pro either wins or is on par in all tested browser benchmarks, only falling behind by a decent margin in WebXPRT 15 (keeping in mind the desktop setup is using a GTX 1080).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’d be completely correct if you're thinking that there’s a decent room for error in these kinds of tests - they run on different browsers and operating systems after all, and one setup could be significantly more optimised than the other, but optimisation isn’t some magic bullet pulling performance out of thin-air - &lt;strong&gt;optimisation is something that is done to make the most out of the available hardware.&lt;/strong&gt; It's fair to criticise a performance benchmark when the device or software in question is clearly not correctly optimised or compiled, but it's somewhat silly to ignore a benchmark because a device is &lt;em&gt;too&lt;/em&gt; well optimised, as so often happens in response to positive ARM benchmarks. The fact that the browser performance of a device using the A12X is trading blows with a high-end desktop processor is impressive from whichever angle you look at it. Even in the worst case scenario - on the negative end of the high margin of error that browser benchmarks have - these tests indicate clearly that an ARM-powered chip is within punching distance of high-end x86 chips in browser performance, and that’s all that needs to be true to support the central claim.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Benchmarks don't represent actual workloads.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond the cross platform point, there's a tendency for some to disregard benchmarks that show ARM as competitive because they believe that either they don't accurately represent CPU workloads, that the compute tasks they test aren't relevant to actual performance, or because they don't actually indicate end-user experience. These are also sometimes true – after all, the final score in a benchmark like Geekbench is estimated and derived from various compute tasks and the usefulness, weighting and relevance of those tests are all subjective. Linus Torvalds famously ripped into Geekbench 3 for its ridiculous testing of crypto tasks, but this and various other issues were addressed in Geekbench 4, so the benchmark today isn't actually a bad indicator of generalised peak performance. It does not necessarily indicate sustained performance, but it does give a &lt;strong&gt;roughly,&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;kinda&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;accurate&lt;/strong&gt; standardised way to compare peak potential. Once again, there can be an appreciable margin of error in these benchmarks, but it's not so significant to render them useless, able to be totally dismissed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other words: while anyone using Geekbench as a be-all-and-end-all measure of performance is, put plainly, using it wrong, the score still has relevance. Geekbench is a thermometer that’s a little broken - sure, it might be off by a few fahrenheit most of the time, but if the temperature is reporting double what it was yesterday, you can bet it's gonna feel almost double as hot.  In my opinion, those who completely, utterly dismiss Geekbench as evidence are engaging in logic just as reductive as those who interpret it with objective authority - the truth lies somewhere in the middle, as it often does. All this said, I would not want to rest my ARM performance case on Geekbench alone, so let’s explore deeper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SPEC2006 it is.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the sake of seeking more objective and thorough data, let’s look at an industry standard benchmark, SPEC2006, an encompassing tool that according to the excellent writers at Anandtech, &lt;em&gt;“is much better [than Geekbench] as a representative benchmark that fully exhibits more details of a given microarchitecture”.&lt;/em&gt; SPEC2006 measures genuine real world tasks - compression, image recognition, compiling, spam filtering, game/chess AI, pathfinding and XML processing. The numbers aren’t arbitrary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've picked the i7 6700k to compare the A12X with in this scenario. It’s the most recent and fastest i7 in the official SPEC2006 database, so in honesty, it's the only option. But since SPEC2006 is a single-core benchmark, core count changes in recent generations aren’t that relevant, and Intel haven’t improved IPC in a few generations, the results will still be quite relevant compared to using the 8700k. The iPad Pro results have been pulled from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.anandtech.com/show/13661/the-2018-apple-ipad-pro-11-inch-review/4&quot;&gt;Anandtech’s review of the iPad Pro&lt;/a&gt;. The i7 results have been pulled directly from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.spec.org/cpu2006/results/res2015q4/cpu2006-20151019-37700.pdf&quot;&gt;SPEC2006 website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compared to the top-of-the-line consumer desktop CPU from a few years ago, the A12X performs 20% worse on average in the various SPECint2006 benchmarks, a figure which almost sounds like I’ve produced evidence that doesn’t support my argument. But it achieves this result while being clocked 40% lower, while using a fraction of the power, and with absolutely zero active cooling. No one pound heatsink and fan or case fans – the processor sits inside a 5.9mm slate of silicon, metal and glass. It doesn’t matter how you slice or stretch the numbers – they are wildly impressive. The A12X is definitely winning on the IPC front, and absolutely obliterating on the performance per watt front. If you normalise for clock speed, the A12X would have performed &lt;strong&gt;significantly&lt;/strong&gt; better than the i7 overall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first I found some of these numbers hard to believe, but they're hard to argue with. The A12X has reached parity on Geekbench scores, it’s approaching parity on a host of assorted system benchmarks, it’s approaching parity on SPEC2006, it’s at parity in just about every browser benchmark, and every indication shows that it has better IPC and better performance per watt than current high-end Intel and AMD processors. Even if Anandtech are over-exaggerating, if all these benchmarks are ARM-favoured and every supporting figure has a huge margin of error, the results are still absolutely remarkable. We’re talking about processors that are designed to live in your pocket with no cooling, not one designed to go toe-to-toe with desktops, but they're doing it anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Aha! What about sustained performance?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s completely true that any decent Intel or AMD processor would defeat the A12X in intensive real-world tasks that last longer than a few minutes, like rendering a video or running a PC game (in theory), but this isn't really a rebuttal to the theme of this article, for one significant reason. Before I explain, let me clarify: the purpose of this article is not to suggest that one could take the A12X from an iPad Pro, put it in a desktop as-is and use it without any issues today, but rather to end the myth that ARM chips are behind performance-wise. With this in mind, the reason that the lack of sustained performance is not really an issue is simply because ARM processors have an absolutely enormous disadvantage that has nothing to do with microarchitecture or ISA: in practically every consumer device they are used in, they have no active cooling solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ARM chips on the market already run cooler and more efficiently than modern x86 chips, so a cooling unit as good as any generic desktop fan would not only solve the issue of sustained performance and throttling, but also likely increase the headroom for boost clocks, assuming assorted 7nm nodes are mainly limited by heat to reach higher clock speeds. With an IPC lead already, this change would allow good ARM chips like the A12X to properly compare in almost all performance scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fact that they're performing so well despite an enormous disadvantage is impressive in itself, but if Apple were to custom create an ARM chip designed to be used in a high-end desktop or laptop system with active cooling, they would likely produce the fastest consumer chip on the market. Apple modify each generation of their chip architecture and optimise it for each device category – the A12X for the iPad Pro being an enhanced tablet version of the A12 for the iPhone XS – any ARM CPU that Apple might stick in a laptop would be accordingly modified and enhanced – more Big cores, some tweaks that cater to desktop use-cases, higher base and boost clocks etc. To say we haven't seen the full potential of ARM yet would be an understatement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So how did this shift happen?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a broad sense, ARM chips have caught up because of a significant demand in the market for fast, efficient chips in portable devices, and now servers. Because of this, ARM reference designs got better and better, and Apple began to double down in a big way. While Apple aren't the only company developing extremely fast chips, with the upcoming Qualcomm Snapdragon 8CX expected to perform rather well, their custom fabrications are particularly... insane? The A12X has more execution ports than any other consumer processor Anandtech have seen (in a desktop, laptop, phone, tablet or otherwise):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;15&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Monsoon (A11) and Vortex (A12) are extremely wide machines – with 6 integer execution pipelines among which two are complex units, two load/store units, two branch ports, and three FP/vector pipelines this gives an estimated 13 execution ports, far wider than ARM's upcoming Cortex A76 and also wider than Samsung’s M3. In fact, assuming we're not looking at an atypical shared port situation, Apple’s microarchitecture seems to far surpass anything else in terms of width, including desktop CPUs.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This brings us back to the earlier point in the RISC v CISC discussion: performance is coming down to micro-architecture, not RISC or CISC, not ARM or x86. With this in mind, ARM's desirability is only likely to further improve from here. Due in part to a stagnant desktop CPU industry, with Intel not facing significant competition from AMD up until just recently, x86 development has been, plainly put, dull. Performance and feature improvements have been minor besides core count increases. The opposite has been true in the mobile and tablet industry, and there's no sign of any slowing down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if Intel manages to drastically improve IPC and efficiency in the shift to 7nm, they would be still be counting on ARM not making further strides ahead given the sheer levels of research, development and demand being funnelled from the smartphone, server, tablet, and soon laptop industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;If all this is true, why is x86 still king?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why has nothing changed? Why is x86 relegated to desktop, and why aren’t people talking about this shift?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One answer to these questions is simple: only in the last 3 years has ARM started to become truly competitive, and &lt;strong&gt;it takes far longer than 5 years to trigger widespread adoption given just how entrenched Windows and x86 software is&lt;/strong&gt;. While integrated mobile and tablet chips are currently excellent, to create an similar desktop chip with modular parts, a lot of work still has to be done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other answer is more complex: things &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; changing, behind the scenes. There’s already evidence of Apple’s shift to ARM - though it generated very little press coverage or discussion, the &lt;strong&gt;latest Macbook Pros are using Apple’s proprietary ARM-based T2 chip, built on their A11 iPhone chip, to handle H.265 video decoding&lt;/strong&gt;. I imagine that each generation of Macbook processors will offload more and more tasks to the ARM co-processor, until eventually, some generation completes the transition, and the co-processor becomes the processor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this is great news for all of us consumers: &lt;strong&gt;What better way to light a fire under the desktop and tablet CPU industry than the threat of the most lucrative hardware company in the world shifting to a competing architecture.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One day soon, we might be able to buy Macbooks with near complete vertical integration from Apple, and despite the possibility of disruption and compatibility issues, I imagine these devices might have some pretty great advantages: industry leading performance and great battery life. For now, let's wait to see what the A13X looks like - if the last few years indicate anything, we're in for a chip that could foreshadow the biggest change in the dynamic of the processor industry in a long, long time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;This was my first new article in years, so please let me know what you thought!&lt;/h6&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 04:42:03 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>kristianp</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://reveried.com/article/arm-processors-nearing-performance-parity-with-x86</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Tesla – Introducing V3 Supercharging</title>
<link>https://www.tesla.com/blog/introducing-v3-supercharging</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.tesla.com/blog/introducing-v3-supercharging</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Tesla has more than 12,000 Superchargers across North America, Europe, and Asia and our network continues to grow daily: more than 99% of the U.S. population is covered by the network, and we anticipate similar coverage in Europe by the end of 2019. Recently, we passed 90% population coverage in China and are growing that number quickly. However, in order to drive continued electric vehicle adoption and further accelerate the world’s transition to sustainable energy, charging needs to be even faster, and the number of vehicles able to charge at a location in a day needs to be significantly higher. Today, we’re unveiling V3 Supercharging, the next step in the growth of Tesla’s Supercharger network. V3, which is born from our experience building the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tesla.com/blog/tesla-powerpack-enable-large-scale-sustainable-energy-south-australia&quot;&gt;world’s largest grid-connected batteries&lt;/a&gt;, enables our vehicles to charge faster than any other electric vehicle on the market today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Faster Charging, No More Power Sharing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;V3 is a completely new architecture for Supercharging. A new 1MW power cabinet with a similar design to our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tesla.com/powerpack&quot;&gt;utility-scale products&lt;/a&gt; supports peak rates of up to 250kW per car. At this rate, a Model 3 Long Range operating at peak efficiency can recover up to 75 miles of charge in 5 minutes and charge at rates of up to 1,000 miles per hour. Combined with other improvements we’re announcing today, V3 Supercharging will ultimately cut the amount of time customers spend charging by an average of 50%, as modeled on our fleet data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/321899093&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supercharger stations with V3’s new power electronics are designed to enable any owner to charge at the full power their battery can take – no more splitting power with a vehicle in the stall next to you. With these significant technical improvements, we anticipate the typical charging time at a V3 Supercharger will drop to around 15 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On-Route Battery Warmup&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;New Supercharging infrastructure isn’t the only way we are improving our customers’ charging experience. Beginning this week, Tesla is rolling out a new feature called On-Route Battery Warmup. Now, whenever you navigate to a Supercharger station, your vehicle will intelligently heat the battery to ensure you arrive at the optimal temperature to charge, reducing average charge times for owners by 25%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This combination of higher peak power with V3, dedicated vehicle power allocation across Supercharger sites, and On-Route Battery Warmup enables customers to charge in half the time and Tesla to serve more than twice the number of customers per hour. Additionally, we are also unlocking 145kW charge rates for our 12,000+ V2 Superchargers over the coming weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.tesla.com/sites/default/files/images/blogs/average-time-charging.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;With Model 3 now shipping globally in high volumes and Model Y on the way, V3 Supercharging enables us to deliver the fastest production charging experience at an unprecedented scale compared to other electric vehicle manufacturers. By increasing the number of vehicles we’re able to charge at each Supercharger in a day, the investment we’re making in our network will go significantly further with every V3 station deployed. Paired with other savings, these efficiencies will translate to an increased pace of investment for Superchargers moving forward, with a continued focus on getting to 100% ownership coverage across all regions we operate. With thousands of new Superchargers coming online in 2019, the launch of V3, and other changes we’re making to improve throughput, the Supercharger network will be able to serve more than 2x more vehicles per day at the end of 2019 compared with today – easily keeping pace with our 2019 fleet growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beginning today, we’re opening the first public beta site in the Bay Area, which will incrementally be made available to owners in Tesla’s Early Access Program. We’re launching V3 Supercharging for Model 3, our highest volume vehicle, and we’ll continue to expand access as we review and assess the results of millions of charging events. We will increase Model S and X charging speeds via software updates in the coming months. V3 Supercharging will roll out to the wider fleet in an over the air firmware update to all owners in Q2 as more V3 Superchargers come online. Our first non-beta V3 Supercharger site will break ground next month, with North American sites ramping in Q2 and Q3 before coming to Europe and Asia-Pacific in Q4.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 04:06:04 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>arturogarrido</dc:creator>
<og:title>Introducing V3 Supercharging</og:title>
<og:description>Tesla has more than 12,000 Superchargers across North America, Europe, and Asia and our network continues to grow daily: more than 99% of the U.S. population is covered by the network, and we anticipate similar coverage in Europe by the end of 2019. Recently, we passed 90% population coverage in China and are growing that number quickly. However, in order to drive continued electric vehicle adoption and further accelerate the world’s transition to sustainable energy, charging needs to be even faster, and the number of vehicles able to charge at a location in a day needs to be significantly higher. Today, we’re unveiling V3 Supercharging, the next step in the growth of Tesla’s Supercharger network. V3, which is born from our experience building the</og:description>
<og:image>https://www.tesla.com/sites/default/files/blog_images/tesla_announcement_social.jpg</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.tesla.com/blog/introducing-v3-supercharging</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Spritestack – 3D pixelart editor based on sprite stacking technique</title>
<link>https://spritestack.io/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://spritestack.io/</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://spritestack.io/&quot;&gt;https://spritestack.io/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19325331&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19325331&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 206&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 33&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 03:31:30 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>keyle</dc:creator>
<og:description>3D pixelart editor based on sprite stacking technique.</og:description>
<og:image>https://spritestack.io/thumb.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://spritestack.io/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Leaked Documents Show the U.S. Tracking Journalists Through a Secret Database</title>
<link>https://www.nbcsandiego.com/investigations/Source-Leaked-Documents-Show-the-US-Government-Tracking-Journalists-and-Advocates-Through-a-Secret-Database-506783231.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nbcsandiego.com/investigations/Source-Leaked-Documents-Show-the-US-Government-Tracking-Journalists-and-Advocates-Through-a-Secret-Database-506783231.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;This story has been updated with a new statement from Customs and Border Protection and a response from the ACLU.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;2&quot;&gt;Documents obtained by NBC 7 Investigates show the U.S. government created a secret database of activists, journalists, and social media influencers tied to the migrant caravan and in some cases, placed alerts on their passports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;3&quot;&gt;At the end of 2018, roughly 5,000 immigrants from Central America made their way north through Mexico to the United States southern border. The story made international headlines. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;4&quot;&gt;As the migrant caravan reached the San Ysidro Port of Entry in south San Diego County, so did journalists, attorneys, and advocates who were there to work and witness the events unfolding. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;5&quot;&gt;But in the months that followed, journalists who covered the caravan, as well as those who offered assistance to caravan members, said they felt they had become targets of intense inspections and scrutiny by border officials. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;6&quot;&gt;One photojournalist said she was pulled into secondary inspections three times and asked questions about who she saw and photographed in Tijuana shelters. Another photojournalist said she spent 13 hours detained by Mexican authorities when she tried to cross the border into Mexico City. Eventually, she was denied entry into Mexico and sent back to the U.S. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;7&quot;&gt;These American photojournalists and attorneys said they suspected the U.S. government was monitoring them closely but until now, they couldn’t prove it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;8&quot;&gt;Now, documents leaked to NBC 7 Investigates show their fears weren’t baseless. In fact, their own government had listed their names in a secret database of targets, where agents collected information on them. Some had alerts placed on their passports, keeping at least two photojournalists and an attorney from entering Mexico to work. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;9&quot;&gt;The documents were provided to NBC 7 by a Homeland Security source on the condition of anonymity, given the sensitive nature of what they were divulging. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;10&quot;&gt;The source said the documents or screenshots show a SharePoint application that was used by agents from Customs and Border Protection (CBP) Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE), the U.S. Border Patrol, Homeland Security Investigations and some agents from the San Diego sector of the Federal Bureau of Investigations (FBI).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;11&quot;&gt;The intelligence gathering efforts were done under the umbrella of “Operation Secure Line,” the operation designated to monitor the migrant caravan, according to the source. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;12&quot;&gt;The documents list people who officials think should be targeted for screening at the border. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;13&quot;&gt;The individuals listed include ten journalists, seven of whom are U.S. citizens, a U.S. attorney, and 48 people from the U.S. and other countries, labeled as organizers, instigators or their roles “unknown.” The target list includes advocates from organizations like Border Angels and Pueblo Sin Fronteras. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;14&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To view the documents, &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nbcsandiego.com/multimedia/PHOTOS-Leaked-Documents-to-NBC-7-Investigates-506782041.html&quot;&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt; or the link below.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph galVidEmbed-c&quot; data-pnum=&quot;15&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;embeddedWrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;embedded vertical gallery c&quot; data-cid=&quot;506782041&quot; data-permloc=&quot;//www.nbcsandiego.com/multimedia/PHOTOS-Leaked-Documents-to-NBC-7-Investigates-506782041.html&quot; data-title=&quot;PHOTOS: Leaked Documents Show Government Tracking Journalists, Immigration Advocates&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;galleryMask&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;PHOTOS: Leaked Documents Show Government Tracking Journalists, Immigration Advocates&quot; src=&quot;https://media.nbcsandiego.com/images/620*349/Cover+Sheet.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nbcsandiego.com/multimedia/PHOTOS-Leaked-Documents-to-NBC-7-Investigates-506782041.html&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot; smallTitle&quot;&gt;PHOTOS: Leaked Documents Show Government Tracking Journalists, Immigration Advocates&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;16&quot;&gt;NBC 7 Investigates is blurring the names and photos of individuals who haven’t given us permission to publish their information. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;17&quot;&gt;The documents are titled “San Diego Sector Foreign Operations Branch: Migrant Caravan FY-2019, Suspected Organizers, Coordinators, Instigators and Media” and are dated January 9, 2019. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;18&quot;&gt;Emblazoned on it are the American and Mexican flags, with a banner that reads: &quot;ILU-OASSIS-OMEGA.&quot; An official at the Department of Homeland Security said the seal indicates that the documents are a product of the International Liaison Unit (ILU), which coordinates intelligence between Mexico and the United States. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embedded cm photo c&quot; data-cid=&quot;506783551&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;galleryMask&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;620&quot; src=&quot;https://media.nbcsandiego.com/images/620*607/Logo+on+Cover+Page_ILU-OASISS-OMEGA_San+Diego+Sector.JPG&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;noExt&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;embeddedMediaCaption nested&quot;&gt;This seal is emblazoned in the leaked documents to NBC 7 Investigates.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;20&quot;&gt;For each person, the documents show their photo, often from their passport but in some cases from their social media accounts, along with their personal information. That information includes the person’s date of birth, their “country of commencement,” and their alleged role tied to the migrant caravan. The information also includes whether officials placed an alert on the person’s passport. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;21&quot;&gt;Some individuals have a colored “X” over their photo, indicating whether they were arrested, interviewed, or had their visa or SENTRI pass revoked by officials. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;22&quot;&gt;In addition to flagging the individuals for secondary screenings, the Homeland Security source told NBC 7 that the agents also created dossiers on each person listed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;23&quot;&gt;“We are a criminal investigation agency, we’re not an intelligence agency,” the Homeland Security source told NBC 7 Investigates. “We can’t create dossiers on people and they’re creating dossiers. This is an abuse of the Border Search Authority.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;24&quot;&gt;One dossier, shared with NBC 7, was on Nicole Ramos, the Refugee Director and attorney for &lt;a href=&quot;https://alotrolado.org/&quot;&gt;Al Otro Lado&lt;/a&gt;, a law center for migrants and refugees in Tijuana, Mexico. The dossier included personal details on Ramos, including specific details about the car she drives, her mother’s name, and her work and travel history. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;25&quot;&gt;After sharing the documents with Ramos, she said Al Otro Lado is seeking more information on why she and other attorneys at the law center have been targeted by border officials. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;26&quot;&gt;“The document appears to prove what we have assumed for some time, which is that we are on a law enforcement list designed to retaliate against human rights defenders who work with asylum seekers and who are critical of CBP practices that violate the rights of asylum seekers,” Ramos told NBC 7 by email. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;27&quot;&gt;In addition to the dossier on Ramos, a list of other dossier files created was shared with NBC 7. Two of the dossier files were labeled with the names of journalists but no further details were available. Those journalists were also listed as targets for secondary screenings. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;28&quot;&gt;Customs and Border Protection has the authority to pull anyone into secondary screenings, but the documents show the agency is increasingly targeting journalists, attorneys, and immigration advocates. Former counterterrorism officials say the agency should not be targeting individuals based on their profession. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;29&quot;&gt;NBC 7 Investigates sent the information to all border and law enforcement agencies the source listed, asking whether the information was valid and if these tactics were legal. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;30&quot;&gt;A Customs and Border Protection spokesperson did not answer NBC 7’s list of questions or confirm the validity of the documents shared. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;31&quot;&gt;By email, the spokesperson said, “Criminal events, such as the breach of the border wall in San Diego, involving assaults on law enforcement and a risk to public safety, are routinely monitored and investigated by authorities.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;32&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;To read CBP’s full statement, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/5759650-CBP-Full-Statement.html&quot;&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;33&quot;&gt;“It is protocol following these incidents to collect evidence that might be needed for future legal actions and to determine if the event was orchestrated,” the statement read. “CBP and our law enforcement partners evaluate these incidents, follow all leads garnered from information collected, conduct interviews and investigations, in preparation for, and often to prevent future incidents that could cause further harm to the public, our agents, and our economy.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;34&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE - 4:20 p.m.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Minutes after our story published and five days after a Customs and Border Protection spokesperson gave us the agency's statement above, CBP told our colleagues at NBC News that the names in the database are all people who were present during violence that broke out at the border in November. The agency also said journalists are being tracked so that the agency can learn more about what started that violence. CBP never clarified that point directly to NBC 7 Investigates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;35&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE - 8:20 p.m.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;36&quot;&gt;Staff attorney Esha Bhandari with the ACLU’s Speech, Privacy, and Technology Project, called the government's targeting of journalists and migrants &quot;outrageous.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;37&quot;&gt;“This is an outrageous violation of the First Amendment. The government cannot use the pretext of the border to target activists critical of its policies, lawyers providing legal representation, or journalists simply doing their jobs. We are exploring all options in response,” Bhandari said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;38&quot;&gt;Senior staff attorney Mitra Ebadolahi with the ACLU of San Diego’s Border Litigation Project called NBC 7's report the latest example of abuse of power by the CBP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;39&quot;&gt;“For years, the U.S. government has used the pretext of ‘border security' to trample on Americans’ constitutional rights. This most recent example is just the latest in a steady stream of CBP abuse of authority, and once again underscores the dire need for meaningful agency oversight and accountability,&quot; Ebadolahi said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;40&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journalists Targeted for Border Inspections&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;41&quot;&gt;NBC 7 Investigates spoke with seven of the journalists listed on the database as targets for secondary screenings, including &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.arianadrehsler.com/&quot;&gt;freelance photojournalist Ariana Drehsler&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;42&quot;&gt;“I'm interested in covering social and political issues,” Drehsler said, adding that she covered the migrant caravan in Tijuana for Buzzfeed News and United Press International. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;43&quot;&gt;“I think there's a lot of misconceptions, maybe from both sides, about who are these people that are trying to seek asylum,” Drehsler said. “So I think as a photojournalist, it is my responsibility to cover that to the best of my abilities.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;44&quot;&gt;Drehsler estimated she had crossed the border from San Ysidro dozens of times covering the caravan. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embedded cm photo c&quot; data-cid=&quot;506777861&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;galleryMask&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;620&quot; src=&quot;https://media.nbcsandiego.com/images/620*349/I-Team+secret+database+1.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;noExt&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;embeddedMediaCaption nested&quot;&gt;Las Playas de Tijuana on December 9, 2018. At night the beach is lit up with lights from the U.S. side to help US Customs and Border Patrol find people trying to cross illegally. Photo by Ariana Drehsler/UPI&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;Photo credit: UPI&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
 
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;46&quot;&gt;“I was very transparent about what I was doing,” Drehsler said. “Sometimes you would see me carrying a camera and if I was asked by an agent what was I doing, I would tell them I was photographing the [migrant] shelters.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;47&quot;&gt;But on December 30, 2018, when Drehsler was crossing back into the United States, she was pulled into secondary inspection and questioned by border agents. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;48&quot;&gt;“Two people in plainclothes came down and took me to another room,” Drehsler said. “They questioned me in a small room, asking me questions about the shelter, what was I seeing there, who was I working for.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;49&quot;&gt;“They said that I was on the ground and they’re not, which I thought was really interesting.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;50&quot;&gt;After about an hour, Drehsler said she was allowed to leave but agents warned her that an alert had been placed on her passport and that she would be pulled into a secondary screening again if she crossed the border. The agents told her to plan accordingly, given the screenings could last an hour or more. When she asked why this alert was placed on her passport, agents told her they had no idea. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;51&quot;&gt;Drehsler said she was pulled into secondary screenings two more times while crossing the border. Each time she said she was questioned by the same agents in plainclothes. The second time was on Jan. 2, 2019, and the third time was on Jan. 4, 2019. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;52&quot;&gt;On the third occasion, Drehsler said she was told to leave her gear, including her camera and cell phone, on a table outside of the interview room. When she returned, she said it didn’t appear to her that the gear had been looked through. Agents asked Drehsler if she could show them the photos she had taken but she said she declined. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;53&quot;&gt;Some of the questions agents asked Drehsler on the third screening struck her as odd. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;54&quot;&gt;“They asked about the new caravan and if word had gotten out about how difficult it is to seek asylum in the U.S.,” Drehsler said. “Then before I left, the female agent asked if I rented or owned my home.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;55&quot;&gt;Drehsler told NBC 7 the personal details listed for her in the leaked screenshots are accurate. She confirmed the photo officials used came from her passport. The screenshots include a green “X” over Drehsler’s photograph, indicating she had been interviewed by agents. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;56&quot;&gt;Sharing the documents with Drehsler, she told NBC 7 she was “blown away.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;57&quot;&gt;“I have so many questions; I have more questions than answers,” she said. “Personally, I don't understand what [agents] are hoping to find.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;58&quot;&gt;Other journalists and attorneys have previously told news outlets like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/2019/02/15/695164916/journalists-lawyers-volunteers-face-increased-scrutiny-by-border-agents&quot;&gt;NPR&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://theintercept.com/2019/02/08/us-mexico-border-journalists-harassment/&quot;&gt;The Intercept&lt;/a&gt; that they too faced the same kind of increased scrutiny surrounding their work involving the migrant caravan. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;59&quot;&gt;Evidence of increased scrutiny of journalists at the border was detailed &lt;a href=&quot;https://cpj.org/reports/2018/10/nothing-to-declare-us-border-search-phone-press-freedom-cbp.php&quot;&gt;in an October 2018 report&lt;/a&gt; prepared by the Committee to Protect Journalists (CPJ.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;60&quot;&gt;The report identified 37 journalists who said they found the secondary screenings by border officials “invasive,” and said 20 cases involved border agents “conducting warrantless searches of [the journalists’] electronic devices.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;61&quot;&gt;The journalists featured in the leaked documents said they were separated from their electronic devices and gear but had no evidence that agents had gone through their items. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;62&quot;&gt;Kitra Cahana is another freelance photojournalist and U.S. citizen listed as a target in the documents. By phone from Honduras, Cahana told NBC 7 she also faced increased scrutiny and was eventually denied entry into Mexico for no apparent reason. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embedded cm photo c&quot; data-cid=&quot;506777941&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;galleryMask&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;620&quot; src=&quot;https://media.nbcsandiego.com/images/620*413/i-team+secret+database+2.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;noExt&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;embeddedMediaCaption nested&quot;&gt;Kitra Cahana is an award-winning freelance documentary photographer, videographer, a photo/video artist.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;Photo credit: Kitra Cahana&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
 
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;64&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://kitracahana.com/home/&quot;&gt;Cahana's work&lt;/a&gt; has been featured in National Geographic magazine, The New York Times and the CBC out of Canada. One night in late December, she said Mexican authorities photographed her passport while she and other journalists were working near the border. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;65&quot;&gt;Then, on Jan. 17, 2019, while traveling from Canada to Mexico City, Cahana said she had a connecting flight in Detroit, Michigan. Cahana said in Montreal, her passport was flagged while going through U.S. Customs pre-clearance. Cahana said she was pulled into a secondary screening where border agents asked her a list of questions about her work. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;66&quot;&gt;“They were interested in whether I had an assignment when I was going down to cover the caravan,” Cahana said. “And they wanted to know how I was funding my work.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;67&quot;&gt;Cahana said she was asked to explain how freelance photojournalism works, which she found strange. Afterward, her passport was flagged again in Detroit but eventually, she was allowed to board her flight and fly to Mexico City. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;68&quot;&gt;But when she arrived in Mexico, her passport was flagged again. Cahana said she brought this to a Mexican official and was taken into a back room with another group of detained individuals. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;69&quot;&gt;There, Cahana said her phone was taken away and she couldn’t leave the room. When she needed to use the restroom, an agent escorted her. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;70&quot;&gt;“I wasn't allowed to be in communication with anyone, I wasn’t allowed to contact my embassy,” Cahana said. “It was very confusing because my Spanish is quite limited and no one there really spoke English.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;71&quot;&gt;Cahana said the whole ordeal lasted 13 hours and in the end, she was denied entry into Mexico. She had to wait until a plane arrived that could take her back to Detroit, where her flight originated. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;72&quot;&gt;Since then, Cahana said she tried one more time to cross the border into Mexico. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;73&quot;&gt;“I was trying to cross into Mexico through Guatemala to continue my work covering the caravan and then I was denied again,” Cahana said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;74&quot;&gt;NBC 7 Investigates confirmed another journalist was denied entry into Mexico after covering the caravan in January. That journalist is also listed in the SharePoint files leaked to NBC 7. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;75&quot;&gt;In the documents shared with NBC 7, Cahana confirmed her personal details were accurate and that the photo used is from her passport. Cahana said she’s been in contact with the Committee to Protect Journalists and the ACLU as far as the alert placed on her passport, preventing her access to Mexico. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;76&quot;&gt;Cahana said the increased scrutiny by border officials could have a chilling effect on freelance journalists covering the border. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;77&quot;&gt;“In the current state of journalism, it's really freelancers who are bringing so much news to the public,” Cahana said. “And the uncertainty of having an alert placed on your passport and not knowing where and when that's going to prevent you from doing your work is really problematic.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;78&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Correction: A previous version of this story stated three photojournalists were denied entry into Mexico. After speaking with those involved, it was clarified that only two photojournalists were denied entry into Mexico. The article above has been updated to reflect this.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;79&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Want to know if you're on the target list? Have you faced increased scrutiny while covering a story at the border? NBC 7 Investigates wants to hear from you. Contact us at cbptargetlist@nbcuni.com.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 class=&quot;copyright&quot;/&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 03:23:30 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jseliger</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>The documents detail an intelligence-gathering effort by the United States and Mexican authorities, targeting more than 50 people including journalists, an attorney, and immigration advocates.</og:description>
<og:title>Leaked Documents Show the Government Tracking Journalists</og:title>
<og:url>http://www.nbcsandiego.com/investigations/Source-Leaked-Documents-Show-the-US-Government-Tracking-Journalists-and-Advocates-Through-a-Secret-Database-506783231.html</og:url>
<og:image>https://media.nbcsandiego.com/images/1200*675/Document+31.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nbcsandiego.com/investigations/Source-Leaked-Documents-Show-the-US-Government-Tracking-Journalists-and-Advocates-Through-a-Secret-Database-506783231.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ecosia – the search engine that plants trees</title>
<link>https://www.ecosia.org/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.ecosia.org/</guid>
<description>&lt;!----&gt; &lt;!----&gt; &lt;section class=&quot;search-section section&quot; data-v-01f8a2d8=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;header class=&quot;index-header&quot; data-v-13a29fdd=&quot;&quot; data-v-01f8a2d8=&quot;&quot;&gt; &lt;!----&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;main-nav&quot; data-v-6e49bbd3=&quot;&quot; data-v-13a29fdd=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;button type=&quot;button&quot; role=&quot;button&quot; aria-label=&quot;Toggle menu&quot; class=&quot;icon-button&quot; data-v-59f80d1e=&quot;&quot; data-v-6e49bbd3=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;svg xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot; width=&quot;21&quot; height=&quot;15&quot; data-v-59f80d1e=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;path d=&quot;M0 0h21v3H0zm0 6h21v3H0zm0 6h21v3H0z&quot; fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; data-v-59f80d1e=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;panel panel-right&quot; data-v-dffe1320=&quot;&quot; data-v-6e49bbd3=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;panel-header&quot; data-v-dffe1320=&quot;&quot; data-v-6e49bbd3=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;button type=&quot;button&quot; role=&quot;button&quot; aria-label=&quot;Close&quot; class=&quot;icon-button&quot; data-v-59f80d1e=&quot;&quot; data-v-6e49bbd3=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;svg xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot; width=&quot;14&quot; height=&quot;14&quot; data-v-59f80d1e=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;path d=&quot;M8.664 7l4.991 4.992a1.177 1.177 0 1 1-1.663 1.663L7 8.664l-4.992 4.991a1.177 1.177 0 1 1-1.663-1.663L5.336 7 .345 2.008A1.177 1.177 0 0 1 2.008.345L7 5.336 11.992.345a1.177 1.177 0 0 1 1.663 1.663L8.664 7z&quot; data-v-59f80d1e=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;nav role=&quot;menu&quot; class=&quot;menu&quot; data-v-d2fd5ea8=&quot;&quot; data-v-6e49bbd3=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;group&quot; data-v-d2fd5ea8=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;div role=&quot;menuitem&quot; class=&quot;item&quot; data-v-d2fd5ea8=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://info.ecosia.org/what&quot; data-track-id=&quot;menu&quot; class=&quot;link&quot; data-v-d2fd5ea8=&quot;&quot;&gt;
        How Ecosia works
      &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div role=&quot;menuitem&quot; class=&quot;item&quot; data-v-d2fd5ea8=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://info.ecosia.org/about&quot; data-track-id=&quot;menu&quot; class=&quot;link&quot; data-v-d2fd5ea8=&quot;&quot;&gt;
        About us
      &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div role=&quot;menuitem&quot; class=&quot;item&quot; data-v-d2fd5ea8=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://info.ecosia.org/mobile&quot; data-track-id=&quot;menu&quot; class=&quot;link&quot; data-v-d2fd5ea8=&quot;&quot;&gt;
        Mobile app
      &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div role=&quot;menuitem&quot; class=&quot;item&quot; data-v-d2fd5ea8=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://info.ecosia.org/privacy&quot; data-track-id=&quot;menu&quot; class=&quot;link&quot; data-v-d2fd5ea8=&quot;&quot;&gt;
        Privacy
      &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;group&quot; data-v-d2fd5ea8=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;div role=&quot;menuitem&quot; class=&quot;item&quot; data-v-d2fd5ea8=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ecosia.teemill.com&quot; data-track-id=&quot;menu&quot; class=&quot;link&quot; data-v-d2fd5ea8=&quot;&quot;&gt;
        Shop
      &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div role=&quot;menuitem&quot; class=&quot;item&quot; data-v-d2fd5ea8=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.ecosia.org&quot; data-track-id=&quot;menu&quot; class=&quot;link&quot; data-v-d2fd5ea8=&quot;&quot;&gt;
        Blog
      &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div role=&quot;menuitem&quot; class=&quot;item&quot; data-v-d2fd5ea8=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ecosia.zendesk.com/hc&quot; data-track-id=&quot;menu&quot; class=&quot;link&quot; data-v-d2fd5ea8=&quot;&quot;&gt;
        FAQ
      &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;group&quot; data-v-d2fd5ea8=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;div role=&quot;menuitem&quot; class=&quot;item&quot; data-v-d2fd5ea8=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ecosia.org/settings&quot; data-track-id=&quot;menu&quot; class=&quot;link&quot; data-v-d2fd5ea8=&quot;&quot;&gt;
        Settings
      &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/nav&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/header&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;content&quot; data-v-01f8a2d8=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;logos-container&quot; data-v-01f8a2d8=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;More about Ecosia&quot; href=&quot;https://info.ecosia.org/what&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; class=&quot;logo-wrapper&quot; data-v-01f8a2d8=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;svg xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot; viewbox=&quot;0 0 149 107&quot; data-v-01f8a2d8=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;g fill=&quot;none&quot; fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; data-v-01f8a2d8=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill=&quot;#36ACB8&quot; d=&quot;M102.659 78.692c-3.593-2.399-5.389-1.159-5.389-1.159a7.591 7.591 0 0 0 2.77 5.1 9.399 9.399 0 0 0 6.293 2.028 7.88 7.88 0 0 0-3.674-5.969zM48.873 92.6a10.72 10.72 0 0 0-1.425 8.02s2.92.822 6.594-3.976a11.056 11.056 0 0 0 2.167-9.515 12.667 12.667 0 0 0-7.324 5.505l-.012-.034zm-11.31-10.94a7.591 7.591 0 0 0-2.77 5.099s1.796 1.158 5.388-1.16a7.88 7.88 0 0 0 3.674-5.921 9.028 9.028 0 0 0-6.281 2.016l-.012-.035zm33.26 9.584a10.117 10.117 0 0 0-3.291 7.046c-.129 3.03.89 5.997 2.85 8.31a10.43 10.43 0 0 0 3.478-8.611c-.255-5.807-3.037-6.71-3.037-6.71v-.035zm19.551-.07a7.545 7.545 0 0 0 .974 5.69 9.167 9.167 0 0 0 5.32 3.894 7.834 7.834 0 0 0-1.577-6.745c-2.688-3.407-4.717-2.804-4.717-2.804v-.035zm12.285-66.29a7.88 7.88 0 0 0 3.72-5.946 9.028 9.028 0 0 0-6.293 2.028 7.591 7.591 0 0 0-2.77 5.1s1.75 1.24 5.343-1.148v-.035zM39.59 29.6a7.88 7.88 0 0 0-3.674-5.922c-3.592-2.399-5.389-1.159-5.389-1.159a7.591 7.591 0 0 0 2.77 5.1 8.947 8.947 0 0 0 6.293 2.016V29.6zm11.914-12.98a7.834 7.834 0 0 0-1.576-6.745c-2.62-3.476-4.717-2.85-4.717-2.85a7.545 7.545 0 0 0 .974 5.69 8.993 8.993 0 0 0 5.319 3.905zm40.562-4.195a10.743 10.743 0 0 0 2.168-9.364 12.748 12.748 0 0 0-7.336 5.389 10.28 10.28 0 0 0-1.345 7.938s2.874.812 6.548-3.986l-.035.023zM70.116 8.23A9.677 9.677 0 0 0 66.895.29a11.265 11.265 0 0 0-2.62 7.637 9.271 9.271 0 0 0 3.072 6.444s2.584-.846 2.804-6.166l-.035.024z&quot; data-v-01f8a2d8=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;path fill=&quot;#4B4A4B&quot; d=&quot;M8.508 79.515L.268 45.13l14.753-3.477 1.275 5.238L6.71 49.21l2.249 9.364 6.953-1.645 1.275 5.238-6.953 1.646 2.248 9.364 9.584-2.318 1.275 5.238zm25.462-5.018a8.112 8.112 0 0 1-6.294-1.425 8.402 8.402 0 0 1-3.476-5.47l-3.222-19.03a8.112 8.112 0 0 1 1.425-6.293 8.298 8.298 0 0 1 5.47-3.477 8.31 8.31 0 0 1 9.666 6.896l.672 3.975-5.47.904-.672-4.114a2.978 2.978 0 0 0-1.275-2.028 2.805 2.805 0 0 0-2.318-.522 2.689 2.689 0 0 0-1.947 1.275 3.094 3.094 0 0 0-.521 2.318l3.372 19.18a2.828 2.828 0 0 0 1.159 1.947 2.99 2.99 0 0 0 2.248.521 3.164 3.164 0 0 0 2.028-1.158 2.7 2.7 0 0 0 .522-2.249l-.811-4.81 5.47-.903.823 4.867a8.112 8.112 0 0 1-1.426 6.293 8.576 8.576 0 0 1-5.424 3.303zm84.346-8.761a9.445 9.445 0 0 1-2.85 5.922 7.382 7.382 0 0 1-3.976 1.947 8.112 8.112 0 0 1-3.002-.07 8.298 8.298 0 0 1-4.867-2.318 8.68 8.68 0 0 1-2.167-3.824 12.632 12.632 0 0 1-.371-5.1l5.1.371a7.406 7.406 0 0 0 .973 4.636 2.84 2.84 0 0 0 2.028 1.345 3.28 3.28 0 0 0 3.001-1.275 3.917 3.917 0 0 0 .904-2.249 6.513 6.513 0 0 0-1.344-4.635c-.904-1.16-2.248-2.851-3.975-5.17a20.119 20.119 0 0 1-3.002-5.098 11.59 11.59 0 0 1-.452-5.1 8.692 8.692 0 0 1 4.346-6.745 8.205 8.205 0 0 1 5.1-.753 9.11 9.11 0 0 1 4.635 2.028 7.081 7.081 0 0 1 2.098 3.14 9.677 9.677 0 0 1 .521 4.196l-5.168.15a5.795 5.795 0 0 0-.754-3.476 2.55 2.55 0 0 0-1.947-1.159 2.318 2.318 0 0 0-2.399.974 4.636 4.636 0 0 0-.973 2.468 7.915 7.915 0 0 0 1.344 5.169 28.3 28.3 0 0 0 2.028 2.62c.76.798 1.46 1.65 2.098 2.549.992 1.304 1.8 2.74 2.399 4.265.232.58.407 1.181.521 1.796.19 1.121.24 2.262.151 3.396zm6.294 10.418l-5.24-1.043 7.117-34.605 5.238 1.043zm11.16-5.771l-3.292 7.568-5.389-1.345 14.603-32.658 7.116 1.796-3.025 35.649-5.39-1.426.824-8.112-5.447-1.472zm7.486-17.824l-5.389 12.956 3.825.974 1.564-13.93z&quot; data-v-01f8a2d8=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;path fill=&quot;#FF7950&quot; d=&quot;M43.47 52.213c0 15.32 12.42 27.739 27.741 27.739 15.32 0 27.74-12.42 27.74-27.739 0-15.32-12.42-27.74-27.74-27.74-15.32 0-27.74 12.42-27.74 27.74zm5.054 9.401a24.501 24.501 0 0 1 31.979-32.07A24.504 24.504 0 0 1 95.647 52.19 24.461 24.461 0 0 1 71.21 76.694h-.07a24.504 24.504 0 0 1-22.617-15.08z&quot; data-v-01f8a2d8=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;path fill=&quot;#36ACB8&quot; d=&quot;M50.88 52.214c0 11.23 9.104 20.335 20.334 20.335 11.232 0 20.336-9.105 20.336-20.335S82.446 31.88 71.214 31.88c-11.23 0-20.334 9.104-20.334 20.334z&quot; data-v-01f8a2d8=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;path fill=&quot;#D3DA31&quot; d=&quot;M54.026 41.327c.272-.052.537-.065.735-.138.412-.23.796-.505 1.145-.822.296-.133.534-.046.752.041.276.109.523.219.82-.11.531-.592-.22-1.797-.22-2.55.013-.156.057-.309.123-.453a20.48 20.48 0 0 0-3.355 4.032zm-2.956 8.022a20.1 20.1 0 0 0-.13 1.197 20.596 20.596 0 0 0-.074 1.71 20.255 20.255 0 0 0 2.418 9.58c.213-.206.434-.356.646-.58.301-.52.67-1.042.97-1.575a15.402 15.402 0 0 0 1.793-1.275c.149-.452.37-.973.52-1.425.148-.45 1.039-1.043.9-1.876-.335-1.181-1.837-1.333-2.659-2.156-.369-.521-.75-1.159-1.154-1.645a6.95 6.95 0 0 0-3.212-2.097c-.007.047-.011.095-.017.142zm22.104-11.646a5.236 5.236 0 0 0-2.543 1.575c-.52.823.15 1.344-.82 1.796a6.429 6.429 0 0 1-1.491-.973c-.421.03-.805.25-1.041.602-.068.903.602 1.042.602 1.946-.37.522-1.273.603-1.492 1.16-.22.555 0 1.423-.45 1.945a50.143 50.143 0 0 0-1.941 1.877 4.225 4.225 0 0 0 .299 5.098c.508.51 1.16.493 1.85.474.531-.014 1.085-.028 1.617.198.903.372 1.041 2.097 1.271 2.92.451 1.343-.368 1.947-.368 3.22 0 1.276.45 4.947 2.242 4.867 2.022-.07 2.463-2.097 3.583-3.476a5.503 5.503 0 0 0 1.272-1.345c0-.67.07-1.424.07-2.095.45-1.159 1.871-1.577 2.61-2.468.741-.893.07-1.495.452-2.168a.07.07 0 0 0 .07-.069c.6-.37 1.155-.673 1.87-1.042.284-.364.585-.712.903-1.044l.671-.219c2.31 1.158 1.49 3.59 3.133 4.866.149-.07.218-.15.368-.22.125-.335.198-.688.221-1.044a2.311 2.311 0 0 1 2.462-1.576 6.374 6.374 0 0 1 1.57 2.55c.151.904-.45 1.425-.45 2.166.07.64.31 1.247.68 1.77.002 0 .002 0 .002-.002a20.284 20.284 0 0 0 1.161-6.779v-.008c0-.334-.008-.666-.025-.995l-.01-.156a20.274 20.274 0 0 0-5.644-12.936 8.652 8.652 0 0 0-1.354.07c-2.1.351-4.219.575-6.345.672-1.761 0-2.777-1.248-4.294-1.248-.225 0-.46.027-.711.091zm.405 9.406c-.52-.069-1.156-.069-1.642-.15-.068 0-2.692-2.097-2.762-2.248a.89.89 0 0 1 .52-.52 7.23 7.23 0 0 1 1.873 1.158l1.04.22c.37.3.751.521 1.156.823a5.36 5.36 0 0 0 1.42.3c0 .07.07.152.07.22v.372a2.47 2.47 0 0 0-.52.197 2.06 2.06 0 0 1-1.155-.372z&quot; data-v-01f8a2d8=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;path fill=&quot;#D3DA31&quot; d=&quot;M77.128 60.33a2.5 2.5 0 0 0-1.27 2.028c.11.226.293.409.518.521.822-.302 1.723-1.645 1.156-2.468a.673.673 0 0 0-.404-.08zM60.507 34.911c.165.17.29.376.37.6a2.626 2.626 0 0 0-.452 1.646c.054.316.244.593.52.753a5.296 5.296 0 0 0 2.242-.753c.751-.15 1.573-.22 2.312-.37.74-.152 2.438-1.518 1.838-2.56-.37-.151-1.047-.385-1.156-.372a8.303 8.303 0 0 1-3.27-.218c-.833.373-1.636.797-2.404 1.274z&quot; data-v-01f8a2d8=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;form action=&quot;https://www.ecosia.org/search&quot; class=&quot;search-form&quot; data-v-1c7a8786=&quot;&quot; data-v-01f8a2d8=&quot;&quot;&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;buttons-wrapper&quot; data-v-1c7a8786=&quot;&quot;&gt; &lt;button type=&quot;submit&quot; role=&quot;button&quot; aria-label=&quot;Submit&quot; class=&quot;icon-button button button-submit&quot; data-v-59f80d1e=&quot;&quot; data-v-1c7a8786=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;svg xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot; width=&quot;27&quot; height=&quot;27&quot; viewbox=&quot;0 0 27.23 27.58&quot; class=&quot;button-search-icon&quot; data-v-59f80d1e=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill=&quot;none&quot; stroke=&quot;#000&quot; stroke-miterlimit=&quot;10&quot; stroke-width=&quot;4&quot; d=&quot;M16.84 17.19l8.97 8.98&quot; data-v-59f80d1e=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;path d=&quot;M10.84 3a7.84 7.84 0 1 1-7.8 7.87 7.85 7.85 0 0 1 7.84-7.84m0-3a10.84 10.84 0 1 0 10.8 10.84A10.84 10.84 0 0 0 10.84.03z&quot; data-v-59f80d1e=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;!----&gt;&lt;/form&gt;  &lt;div class=&quot;learn-more&quot; data-v-01f8a2d8=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://info.ecosia.org/what&quot; data-v-01f8a2d8=&quot;&quot;&gt;
        Learn more
      &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;  &lt;!----&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;/section&gt;&lt;!----&gt;&lt;footer class=&quot;index-footer sticky&quot; data-v-432af6b6=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;content&quot; data-v-432af6b6=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ecosia.zendesk.com/hc&quot; data-track-id=&quot;footer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; class=&quot;link&quot; data-v-432af6b6=&quot;&quot;&gt;
      FAQ
    &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://info.ecosia.org/about#contact&quot; data-track-id=&quot;footer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; class=&quot;link&quot; data-v-432af6b6=&quot;&quot;&gt;
      Feedback
    &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ecosia.dropmark.com&quot; data-track-id=&quot;footer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; class=&quot;link&quot; data-v-432af6b6=&quot;&quot;&gt;
      Press
    &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://info.ecosia.org/privacy&quot; data-track-id=&quot;footer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; class=&quot;link&quot; data-v-432af6b6=&quot;&quot;&gt;
      Privacy
    &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/footer&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 01:19:44 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>kawera</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.ecosia.org/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Viewing Matrices and Probability as Graphs</title>
<link>https://www.math3ma.com/blog/matrices-probability-graphs</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.math3ma.com/blog/matrices-probability-graphs</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Today I'd like to share an idea. It's a very simple idea. It's not fancy and it's certainly not new. In fact, I'm sure many of you have thought about it already. But if you haven't—and even if you have!—I hope you'll take a few minutes to enjoy it with me. Here's the idea:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5b1d427ae0c922e912eda447/5c7ed4bcea0c9faeafe61466_pic1.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So simple! But we can get a lot of mileage out of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To start, I'll be a little more precise: every matrix corresponds to a &lt;strong&gt;weighted bipartite graph&lt;/strong&gt;. By &quot;graph&quot; I mean a collection of vertices (dots) and edges; by &quot;bipartite&quot; I mean that the dots come in two different types/colors; by &quot;weighted&quot; I mean each edge is labeled with a number.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The graph above corresponds to a $3\times 2$ matrix $M$. You'll notice I've drawn three ${\color{Green}\text{green}}$ dots—one for each row of $M$—and two ${\color{RubineRed}\text{pink}}$ dots—one for each column of $M$. I've also drawn an edge between a green dot and a pink dot if the corresponding entry in $M$ is non-zero. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5b1d427ae0c922e912eda447/5c7ed363dad0a55aa8223aea_pic2.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, there's an edge between the &lt;em&gt;second &lt;/em&gt;green dot and the &lt;em&gt;first&lt;/em&gt; pink dot because $M_{21}=4$, the entry in the second row, first column of $M$, is not zero. Moreover, I've labeled that edge &lt;em&gt;by&lt;/em&gt; that non-zero number. On the other hand, there is &lt;em&gt;no&lt;/em&gt; edge between the &lt;em&gt;first&lt;/em&gt; green dot and the &lt;em&gt;second&lt;/em&gt; pink dot because $M_{12}$, the entry in the first row, second column of the matrix, is zero.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Allow me to describe the general set-up a little more explicitly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any matrix $M$ is an array of $n\times m$ numbers. That's old news, of course. But such an array can &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; be viewed as a &lt;em&gt;function&lt;/em&gt; $M\colon X\times Y\to\mathbb{R}$ where ${\color{Green}X}=\{x_1,\ldots,x_n\}$ is a set of $n$ elements and ${\color{RubineRed}Y}=\{y_1,\ldots,y_m\}$ is a set of $m$ elements. Indeed, if I want to describe the matrix $M$ to you, then I need to tell you what each of its $ij$th entries are. In other words, for each pair of indices $(i,j)$, I need to give you a real number $M_{ij}$. But that's precisely what a function does! A function $M\colon X\times Y\to\mathbb{R}$ associates for every pair $(x_i,y_j)$ (if you like, just drop the letters and think of this as $(i,j)$) a real number $M(x_i,y_j)$. So simply write $M_{ij}$ for $M(x_i,x_j)$. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Et voila&lt;/em&gt;. A matrix is a function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5b1d427ae0c922e912eda447/5c7eda5fdd9637358da070a1_pic3.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As suggested, let's further think of $X$'s elements as being ${\color{Green}\text{green}}$ and $Y$'s elements as being ${\color{RubineRed}\text{pink}}$. Then a matrix $M$ corresponds to a weighted bipartite graph in the following way: the vertices of the graph have two different colors provided by ${\color{Green}X}$ and ${\color{RubineRed} Y}$, and there is an edge between every $x_i$ and $y_j$ which is labeled by the number $M_{ij}$. But if this number is zero, then simply omit that edge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Et voila&lt;/em&gt;. Every matrix corresponds to a graph.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nice things happen when we visualize matrices in this way. For instance...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Matrix multiplication corresponds to traveling along paths.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given two matrices (graphs) $M\colon {\color{Green}X}\times {\color{RubineRed}Y}\to\mathbb{R}$ and $N\colon {\color{RubineRed}Y}\times {\color{ProcessBlue}Z}\to\mathbb{R}$, we can multiply them by sticking their graphs together and traveling along paths: the $ij$th entry of $MN$, i.e. the value of the edge connecting $x_i$ to $z_j$, is obtained by multiplying the edges along each path from $x_i$ to $z_j$ and adding them together. For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5b1d427ae0c922e912eda447/5c7de09a2121fc6c13ed3bd5_pic5.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Symmetric matrices correspond to&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;symmetric&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;graphs.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A matrix is symmetric if it is equal to its transpose. That symmetry is always seen by reflecting across the diagonal of the matrix. But you can also see the symmetry in the graph. In particular, the graph makes it visually intuitive why $MM^\top$ and $M^\top M$ are always symmetric, for any $M$!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5b1d427ae0c922e912eda447/5c7de93767a92632915ea248_pic7.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Matrices with all nonzero entries correspond to complete bipartite graphs.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If none of the entries of a matrix is zero, then there are no missing edges in its corresponding graph. That means every vertex in $X$ is connected to every vertex in $Y$. Such bipartite graphs are called &lt;em&gt;complete&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5b1d427ae0c922e912eda447/5c7f19b7e1982c061e5cde75_pic6.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Block matrices correspond to disconnected graphs.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More specifically, the block matrix obtained from a &lt;em&gt;direct sum&lt;/em&gt; corresponds to a disconnected graph. The direct sum of two matrices is obtained by stacking them together into one larger array. (Not unlike the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.math3ma.com/blog/the-tensor-product-demystified&quot; data-rt-link-type=&quot;external&quot;&gt;direct sum of vectors&lt;/a&gt;.) The result is a big block matrix with zero-blocks. The graph of &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; matrix is obtained by stacking the graphs of the original matrices together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5b1d427ae0c922e912eda447/5c7def8d2121fc1ccded3c8d_pic8.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We could say more about matrices and graphs, but I'd like to steer the conversation in a slightly different direction. As it turns out, &lt;em&gt;probability&lt;/em&gt; fits in very nicely with our matrix-graph discussion. It does so by way of another nice little fact: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5b1d427ae0c922e912eda447/5c7f1d6999814e814ecf3ffb_pic16.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‍&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5b1d427ae0c922e912eda447/5c7e817f21677c23c06972ed_pic9.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The graphs of such probability distributions allow us to read off some nice things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Joint Probability&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By construction, the edges of the graph capture the joint probabilities: the probability of $(x_i,y_j)$ is the label on the edge connecting them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5b1d427ae0c922e912eda447/5c7e9602721c5f04dfcaa87c_pic10.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marginal Probability&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marginal probabilities are obtained by summing along the rows/columns of the matrix (equivalently, of the chart above). For example, the probability of $x_1$ is $p(x_1)=p(x_1,y_1)+p(x_1,y_2)=\frac{1}{8}+0$, which is the sum of the first row. Likewise, the probability of $y_2$ is $p(y_2)=p(x_1,y_2)+p(x_2,y_2)+p(x_3,y_2)=0+\frac{1}{8}+\frac{1}{4}$, which is the sum of the second column.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the graph, the marginal probability of $x_i$ is the sum of all edges that have $x_i$ as a vertex. Similarly, the marginal probability of $y_j$ is the sum of all edges that have $y_j$ as a vertex.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5b1d427ae0c922e912eda447/5c7e8b0c00a6e71b01573c8e_pic11.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conditional Probability&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conditional probabilities are obtained by dividing a joint probability by a marginal probability. For example, the probability of $x_3$ given $y_2$ is $p(x_3\vert y_2)=\frac{p(x_3,y_2)}{p(y_2)}$. In the graph, this is seen by dividing the edge joining $x_3$ and $y_2$ by the sum of all edges incident to $y_2$. Likewise, the conditional probability of some $y_i$ given $x_j$ is the value of the edge joining the two, divided by the sum of all edges incident to $x_j$.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5b1d427ae0c922e912eda447/5c7e931055a760636df11f08_pic12.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pretty simple, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's nothing sophisticated here, but sometimes it's nice to see old ideas in new ways!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5b1d427ae0c922e912eda447/5b527d2844acede360b8e7ae_hline.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Relations as Matrices&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll close this post with an addendum—another simple fact that I think is really delightful, namely: matrix arithmetic makes sense over commutative rings. Not just fields like $\mathbb{R}$ or $\mathbb{C}$. In fact, it gets better. You don't even need &lt;em&gt;negatives&lt;/em&gt; to multiply matrices: &lt;strong&gt;matrix arithmetic makes sense over commutative&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;semi-rings&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/strong&gt; (A semi-ring is a ring without additive inverses.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think this is so delightful because the set with two elements $\mathbb{Z}_2=\{0,1\}$ forms a semi-ring with the following addition and multiplication operations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5b1d427ae0c922e912eda447/5c7e98fc7a5823f3952c36ba_pic13.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is this so great? &lt;em&gt;Because&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;a matrix $M\colon X\times Y\to\mathbb{Z}_2$ is the same thing as a&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;relation.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; A relation is just the name for a subset $R$ of a Cartesian product $X\times Y$. In other words, every $\mathbb{Z}_2$-valued matrix defines a relation, and every relation defines a $\mathbb{Z}_2$-valued matrix: $M_{ij}= 1$ if and only if the pair $(x_i,y_j)$ is an element of the subset $R$, and $M_{ij}= 0$ otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5b1d427ae0c922e912eda447/5c7e9b5496bdb31119f4af75_pic14.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The graphs of matrices valued in $\mathbb{Z}_2$ are exactly like the graphs discussed above, except now the weight of any edge is either 0 or 1. If the weight is 0 then, as before, we simply won't draw that edge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(By the way, you can now ask, &quot;Since every relation corresponds to a matrix in $\mathbb{Z}_2$, what do matrices corresponding to &lt;em&gt;equivalence&lt;/em&gt; relations look like?&quot; But I digress....)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By changing the underlying (semi)ring from $\mathbb{R}$ to $\mathbb{Z}_2$, we've changed the way we interpret the weights. For instance, in the probabilistic scenario above, we could've asked, &quot;What's the probability of getting from $x_1$ to $y_1$?&quot; The answer is provided by the weight on the corresponding edge, in that case: 12.5%. Alternatively, when the matrix is valued in $\mathbb{Z}_2$, the question changes to: &quot;Is it &lt;em&gt;possible&lt;/em&gt; to get from $x_1$ to $y_1$?&quot; The answer is Yes if the edge is labeled by 1, and it's No if the edge is labeled by 0. (This nice idea has been explained in various places, &lt;a href=&quot;https://groups.google.com/forum/#!msg/sci.physics.research/VJNPMCfreao/TMKt9tFYNwEJ&quot; data-rt-link-type=&quot;external&quot;&gt;like here&lt;/a&gt; for instance.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What's great is that composition of relations is exactly matrix multiplication using the $\mathbb{Z}_2$ arithmetic above. In other words, given any two relations $R\subset X\times Y$ and $S\subset Y\times Z$, there is a new relation $SR\subset X\times Z$ consisting of all pairs $(x,z)$ such that there exists at least one $y\in Y$ with $(x,y)\in R$ and $(y,z)\in S$. This new relation is exactly that specified by the product of the matrices representing $R$ and $S$.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5b1d427ae0c922e912eda447/5c7ea327ddf3b8e7f7560ee3_pic15.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This little fact about matrices/relations is definitely at the top of my list of favorite-math-facts.* One reason is because the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.math3ma.com/blog/what-is-category-theory-anyway&quot; data-rt-link-type=&quot;external&quot;&gt;category&lt;/a&gt; of finite sets and relations is &lt;em&gt;a lot&lt;/em&gt; like the category of finite vector spaces and linear maps. Actually, it's more like the category of &lt;em&gt;finite-dimensional Hilbert spaces&lt;/em&gt;. And that means that a lot of seemingly disparate ideas all of the sudden become closely related. The connections can be made more precise, and it's a story that's often shared in the category theory community. Hopefully I'll get around to sharing it here on the blog, too. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5b1d427ae0c922e912eda447/5b527d2844acede360b8e7ae_hline.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*Relations are often under-appreciated, I think. In high school, I learned that &lt;em&gt;functions&lt;/em&gt; are of utmost importance. &quot;Assignments must only have &lt;em&gt;one&lt;/em&gt; output for each input,&quot; they said. No one ever mentioned anything about multiple outputs. Whenever such an anomaly &lt;em&gt;did&lt;/em&gt; crop up, it was usually presented as abnormal and off-limits. But relations deserve much better treatment! One reason is because relations are to sets what linear maps are to vector spaces. There's a lot of juice in linear algebra, so there's a lot of juice in relations too. In short, &lt;em&gt;relations are very much top-notch citizens.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2019 21:39:07 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>_Microft</dc:creator>
<og:title>Viewing Matrices &amp; Probability as Graphs</og:title>
<og:image>https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5b1d427ae0c922e912eda447/5c7f3c3431f4f3b39654f071_webflowbanner.jpg</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.math3ma.com/blog/matrices-probability-graphs</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>