<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Post-Mortem and Security Advisory: Data Exposure After travis-ci.com Outage</title>
<link>https://blog.travis-ci.com/2018-04-03-incident-post-mortem</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.travis-ci.com/2018-04-03-incident-post-mortem</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday, 13 March 2018, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.traviscistatus.com/incidents/z2b3lz2kwcfp&quot;&gt;travis-ci.com was non-operational&lt;/a&gt; for around 5.5 hours starting at 12:14 UTC. There was a backlog of builds for another 3.5 hours after the system returned to an operational state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post outlines what happened, and explains what exactly it means for you as a travis-ci.com customer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-happened&quot;&gt;What happened&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday, 13 March 2018 at 12:04 UTC a database query was accidentally run against our production database which truncated all tables. The query was blocked for around 10 minutes and finally executed at 12:14 UTC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we responded to alerts immediately following this, our API remained operational for roughly 30 minutes, connected to an almost empty database.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whenever anyone signed in to travis-ci.com during this time, they saw blank user profiles. Since their old user records had been wiped from the database, our system created new records for them, with primary keys generated from the existing sequence (PostgreSQL does not reset id sequences on truncate).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We eventually took the step of taking all applications in our system offline, and the database was restored to its original state some hours later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When our system was finally back online, those who had logged in during the 30 minutes between database truncation and our applications going offline found themselves logged in as the wrong users. Their login credentials – in the form of a signed token in localStorage – corresponded to user records created after system restore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As brand new customers are not the only accounts to require new user records, because we sync users from GitHub on a regular basis, this meant that both new and existing users at travis-ci.com were affected by this issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To address this situation, all affected tokens were revoked by 14:22 UTC on Wednesday, 14 March.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also became aware that once the database was restored, we didn’t restart our cron scheduler, causing errors with triggering scheduled cron jobs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;regarding-security&quot;&gt;Regarding Security&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the outage we have analysed our application logs for customer accounts that may have been impacted by the token mismatch. We have contacted all customers who were technically affected. A subset of these had no repositories which had run builds on travis-ci.com, and there was no evidence that any customer data was exposed. Another subset had build logs for repositories that were potentially exposed, but our access logs suggested no users accessed build logs during the period of exposure. Another subset were potentially exposed, with our access logs suggesting at least one user was logged in with access to data during the period of exposure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have advised affected customers that if they already encrypt all secrets (passwords, API tokens, sensitive environment variables etc.) using our available encryption features, they are safe from exposure. We have also advised them it would be wise to rotate any credentials stored on travis-ci.com, even if encrypted, and check repositories on travis-ci.com to make sure build logs do not contain other forms of sensitive information, as a precautionary measure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please check your emails for a Security Advisory from us - the subject line should start with “Travis CI Security Advisory:”. We have contacted GitHub repository admin users. If you haven’t received such an email, then your account has not been impacted. Please do contact &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:support@travis-ci.com?subject=Security%20Advisory%20Question&quot;&gt;support@travis-ci.com&lt;/a&gt; with any questions or concerns– we’ll be happy to assist with whatever questions you might have about this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-we-learned&quot;&gt;What We Learned&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have held an internal incident retrospective to learn more about how the data failure occurred, what can be improved on our side to protect against such a failure, and how to better restore and protect data if a similar incident should ever occur.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;12.371712636305&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;3.8954248366013&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It took us a day to uncover the root cause of the original database truncation. Using our API logs, and with information from our upstream provider about the IP address the query originated from, we were able to identify a truncate query run during tests using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/DatabaseCleaner/database_cleaner&quot;&gt;Database Cleaner&lt;/a&gt; gem. The shell the tests ran in unknowingly had a DATABASE_URL environment variable set as our production database. It was an old terminal window in a tmux session that had been used for inspecting production data many days before. The developer returned to this window and executed the test suite with the DATABASE_URL still set.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This raised the question of &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt;, when needing to debug or inspect production data, we connected our development environment to a production database with write access. The answer to this was that our tooling and processes made it difficult to connect to the read-only follower, which is why connecting to the primary database was a common shortcut.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We realised that while seeking to understand the problem, then quickly applying steps to rectify the situation, we inadvertantly left user-facing applications running. This was an error that resulted in the creation of replicated user ids.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We omitted turning certain alerts back on - which meant that we were unaware the cron scheduler was not operational.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were reminded that our most experienced developers can make inadvertent errors resulting in significant outages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a positive note, we were able to recover our entire travis-ci.com production database with only ~15 minutes of data loss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steps we have taken to avoid accidental database table truncation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Revoked the truncate permission on our databases, effectively making it impossible for tables to be truncated.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Patched our internal spec_helpers to check for the DATABASE_URL environment variable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/travis-ci/prompt_warn_env&quot;&gt;shell prompt warning&lt;/a&gt; to our developer tooling to make the shell prompt warn when a DATABASE_URL is set.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Submitted a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/DatabaseCleaner/database_cleaner/pull/521&quot;&gt;Pull Request&lt;/a&gt; to the Database Cleaner gem to safeguard against accidentally using a remote DATABASE_URL.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Steps we have taken to avoid compounding issues:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Created an alias for the follower database, to make it easier to find and connect to when testing is required against production data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automated database failover and maintenance to reduce the time and number of manual steps needed to recover from this type of situation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;In addition to the measures mentioned above, we are planning a number of short and long term improvements that are aimed at making our system more resilient and preventing similar outages from happening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here at Travis CI we take security very seriously. The data failure we experienced was unprecedented in both scope and size. Unfortunately, when responding we missed some steps which would have reduced the problems that occurred.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are incredibly sorry for any inconvenience caused to your business and your developers. We truly value the trust our customers place in us, and look forward to putting the lessons learned to good use in continuing to improve our service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please don’t hesitate to contact &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:support@travis-ci.com&quot;&gt;support@travis-ci.com&lt;/a&gt; with any further questions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2018 03:12:29 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>xtreak29</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.travis-ci.com/2018-04-03-incident-post-mortem</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Credit Card Signatures Are About to Become Extinct in the U.S</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/04/08/business/credit-card-signatures.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2018/04/08/business/credit-card-signatures.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div readability=&quot;46.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1o5hko7 emamhsk2&quot; readability=&quot;38&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xyeyil e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;For nearly a decade, Doug Taylor, a sales manager who travels often for work, has signed credit card receipts with a doodle of a dog wagging its tail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xyeyil e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;No cashier has ever rejected his “signature” as invalid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xyeyil e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“It gets a laugh, most of the time,” said Mr. Taylor, 44, who lives in Mobile, Ala. “Or they just glance at it and don’t really notice.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xyeyil e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Credit card networks are finally ready to concede what has been obvious to shoppers and merchants for years: Signatures are not a useful way to prove someone’s identity. Later this month, four of the largest networks — American Express, Discover, Mastercard and Visa — will stop requiring them to complete card transactions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xyeyil e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The signature, a centuries-old way of verifying identity, is rapidly going extinct. Personal checks are anachronisms. Pen-and-ink letters are scarce. When credit card signatures disappear, handwritten authentications will be relegated to a few special circumstances: sealing a giant transaction like a house purchase, or getting a celebrity to autograph a piece of memorabilia — and even that is being supplanted by the cellphone selfie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-1m7r71o emamhsk1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;39.80834914611&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1o5hko7 emamhsk2&quot; readability=&quot;27.486717267552&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xyeyil e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Card signatures won’t vanish overnight. The change is optional, leaving retailers to decide whether they want to stop collecting signatures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xyeyil e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Target plans to eliminate them this month. Walmart considers signatures “worthless” and has already stopped recording them on most transactions, according to Randy Hargrove, a company spokesman. It will soon get rid of them completely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xyeyil e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Mastercard said it has been wanting to make the change for years, but held off until cards embedded with computer chips became common.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xyeyil e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Card companies, which cover the costs of fraudulent credit card spending, started adding the microchips more than a decade ago &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2015/09/29/business/as-online-data-theft-escalates-banks-look-to-retailers-to-bear-the-losses.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;css-1dccl0s eo5o5yb0&quot;&gt;to reduce fraud-related losses&lt;/a&gt;. The chips create unique codes for each transaction, making the cards much harder to copy. The chips have long been popular in Europe and Asia but only took off in the United States three years ago, when the card networks &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2015/09/24/business/smallbusiness/coming-soon-to-checkouts-microchip-card-payment-systems.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;css-1dccl0s eo5o5yb0&quot;&gt;began punishing merchants&lt;/a&gt; that still relied on the old card-swipe technology. At that point, signatures became largely irrelevant in resolving fraud claims.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-1m7r71o emamhsk1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;32.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1o5hko7 emamhsk2&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xyeyil e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“The signature has really outrun its useful life,” said Linda Kirkpatrick, Mastercard’s head of business development in the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-1m7r71o emamhsk1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;50.91796875&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1o5hko7 emamhsk2&quot; readability=&quot;48.493303571429&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xyeyil e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;It took nearly a century for technology to overtake the hand-scrawled name. The charge card dates back to the 1920s, when stores started issuing &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thedepartmentstoremuseum.org/2010/11/charge-cards.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;css-1dccl0s eo5o5yb0&quot;&gt;embossed metal plates&lt;/a&gt; with paper signature strips that allowed customers to add purchases to their ledger and settle the bill later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xyeyil e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Thirty years later, banks and merchant networks introduced cards that worked at a variety of retailers. By the late 1950s, a shopper &lt;a href=&quot;https://timesmachine.nytimes.com/timesmachine/1958/08/10/91402082.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;css-1dccl0s eo5o5yb0&quot;&gt;could leave home without any cash&lt;/a&gt; and buy groceries, gas and dinner, secured only by a signature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xyeyil e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Investigators scrutinized signed credit slips to determine whether cardholders were present when transactions were made. Signatures were required on all purchases; merchants that failed to collect them generally had to absorb the losses if transactions were disputed. Retailers could also be held liable if they failed to notice that the signature on a receipt did not match the one on the back of the customer’s card.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xyeyil e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Then online shopping took off, forcing card issuers to come up with new ways to detect and adjudicate fraud. As their forensic systems improved, signatures became a relic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xyeyil e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Card networks began inching toward getting rid of signatures years ago. Most stopped requiring signatures on transactions below a certain threshold, typically $25 or $50, as far back as 2010.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xyeyil e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;But old habits die hard, and the jumble of rules about which transactions required signatures and which did not — every issuer has its own policies — discouraged many merchants, especially smaller ones, from scrapping signatures altogether.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xyeyil e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;This time, though, the card networks are sending a consistent message: Signatures are obsolete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xyeyil e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“I think they’re done,” said Mark Horwedel, the chief executive of the Merchant Advisory Group, a trade group that represents large American retailers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-1m7r71o emamhsk1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;32.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1o5hko7 emamhsk2&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xyeyil e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Mr. Horwedel said he expected that three-quarters of his group’s members will have stopped asking customers to sign their names on credit card receipts by the end of the year. Speeding up checkout lines is a powerful incentive, he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-1m7r71o emamhsk1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;50.594848484848&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1o5hko7 emamhsk2&quot; readability=&quot;47.156363636364&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xyeyil e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Smaller retailers will probably lag behind. ShopKeep and Square, two popular small business payment systems, said they do not plan to immediately update their systems to allow retailers to skip signatures on all transactions. (Both currently allow merchants to disable them on transactions below $25.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xyeyil e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“We’ll play it a little bit by ear,” said Michael DeSimone, ShopKeep’s chief executive. “Right now, I don’t think there’s a high level of awareness about this. Let’s get the changes in place and see how they work operationally, and then we’ll adapt.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xyeyil e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The new rules will vary at each card network. American Express is dropping its signature requirement globally, on all of its cards. Mastercard is ending the requirement only in the United States and Canada. Discover’s change applies in those countries plus Mexico and the Caribbean. Visa is making signatures optional in all of North America, but only for retailers with payment systems that read chip cards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xyeyil e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Some merchants are hesitant to mess with a process that customers have built into their muscle memory. Mikiah Westbrooks, the owner of &lt;a href=&quot;https://brixdetroit.com/&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;css-1dccl0s eo5o5yb0&quot;&gt;Brix&lt;/a&gt;, a wine bar in Detroit, said she worried that skipping signatures will affect her workers’ tips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xyeyil e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;She has also occasionally found signatures useful when fighting fraud claims. A customer who challenged a bill last summer backed off when she produced a signed receipt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xyeyil e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“They were lying, and I had proof,” Ms. Westbrooks said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xyeyil e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;But others are ready to cast them aside. At &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.socoffee.co/&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;css-1dccl0s eo5o5yb0&quot;&gt;Snowy Owl Coffee Roasters&lt;/a&gt; in Brewster, Mass., pausing for signatures noticeably slows things down at rush hour, said Shayna Ferullo, the shop’s owner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-1m7r71o emamhsk1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;41.28728923476&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1o5hko7 emamhsk2&quot; readability=&quot;29.143968871595&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xyeyil e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“Any extra second is valuable,” she said. “And everyone knows the signature is a joke. No one really signs any more; it’s all scribbles and squiggles. Some people do smiley faces.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xyeyil e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Mark Malkoff, a New York comedian, and his friend Greg Benson &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?annotation_id=annotation_2314913579&amp;amp;feature=iv&amp;amp;list=UUptCb6Cyb31j-iS0tkfLyLA++&amp;amp;src_vid=AzzmQEseKCA&amp;amp;v=tdSrZLo5R4E&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;css-1dccl0s eo5o5yb0&quot;&gt;posted a YouTube video&lt;/a&gt; that vividly illustrated just how widely ignored card signatures are. They went on a spree through a dozen Los Angeles stores, signing obviously fake names on all of their receipts: Justin Bieber, Jessica Alba, Vin Diesel, Oprah. On one bill, they went with “Mr. Fake Name.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xyeyil e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;None were rejected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1xyeyil e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“Fifteen years, a decade ago, they would look at your signature, they would ask for I.D. if it seemed off,” Mr. Malkoff said. “Now, no one cares. It’s the most useless, pointless thing.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-1m7r71o emamhsk1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;26.039215686275&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;PrintInformation-printInformation--2_6hD PrintInformation-news--3j8HX&quot; readability=&quot;7.3235294117647&quot;&gt;A version of this article appears in print on , on Page B1 of the New York edition with the headline: No More Hasty Scrawls: The End of Credit Card Signatures&lt;span&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytreprints.com/&quot;&gt;Order Reprints&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/pages/todayspaper/index.html&quot;&gt;Today’s Paper&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/subscriptions/Multiproduct/lp8HYKU.html?campaignId=48JQY&quot;&gt;Subscribe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2018 00:16:30 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>semiquaver</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/04/08/business/credit-card-signatures.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Credit Card Signatures Are About to Become Extinct in the U.S.</og:title>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/icons/t_logo_291_black.png</og:image>
<og:description>The major credit card networks are ending a requirement that people sign for most card transactions — the latest blow to the signature.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/04/08/business/credit-card-signatures.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>How to keep your ISP’s nose out of your browser history with encrypted DNS</title>
<link>https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2018/04/how-to-keep-your-isps-nose-out-of-your-browser-history-with-encrypted-dns/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2018/04/how-to-keep-your-isps-nose-out-of-your-browser-history-with-encrypted-dns/</guid>
<description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/dns-crypty-980x461.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;caption-text&quot;&gt;Encrypting DNS traffic between your device and a &quot;privacy-focused&quot; provider can keep someone from spying on where your browser is pointed or using DNS attacks to send you somewhere else.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;aside id=&quot;social-left&quot;&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;98 posters participating, including story author.&quot; class=&quot;comment-count icon-comment-bubble-down&quot; href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2018/04/how-to-keep-your-isps-nose-out-of-your-browser-history-with-encrypted-dns/?comments=1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;comment-count-before&quot;&gt;reader comments&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;comment-count-number&quot;&gt;166&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;share-links&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Share this story&lt;/span&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2017/12/goodbye-net-neutrality-ajit-pais-fcc-votes-to-allow-blocking-and-throttling/&quot;&gt;death of network neutrality&lt;/a&gt; and the loosening of regulations on how Internet providers handle customers' network traffic have raised many concerns over privacy. Internet providers (and others watching traffic as it passes over the Internet) have long had a tool that allows them to monitor individuals' Internet habits with ease: their Domain Name System (DNS) servers. And if they haven't been cashing in on that data already (or using it to change how you see the Internet), they likely soon will.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DNS services are the phone books of the Internet, providing the actual Internet Protocol (IP) network address associated with websites' and other Internet services' host and domain names. They turn arstechnica.com into 50.31.169.131, for example. Your Internet provider offers up DNS as part of your service, but your provider could also log your DNS traffic—in essence, recording your entire browsing history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;pullbox sidebar story-sidebar right&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Open&quot; DNS services provide a way of bypassing ISPs' services for reasons of privacy and security—and in some places, evading content filtering, surveillance, and censorship. And on April 1 (not a joke), Cloudflare launched its own new, free high-performance authoritative DNS service designed to enhance users' privacy on the Internet. This new offering also promised a way to hide DNS traffic completely from view—encryption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Named for its Internet Protocol address, &lt;a href=&quot;https://1.1.1.1/&quot;&gt;1.1.1.1&lt;/a&gt; is the result of a partnership with the research group of APNIC, the Asia-Pacific Internet registry. While it's also available as an &quot;open&quot; conventional DNS resolver (and a very fast one at that), Cloudflare is supporting two encrypted DNS protocols.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While executed with some unique Cloudflare flare, 1.1.1.1 isn't the first encrypted DNS service by any means—&lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2017/11/new-quad9-dns-service-blocks-malicious-domains-for-everyone/&quot;&gt;Quad9&lt;/a&gt;, Cisco's OpenDNS, Google's 8.8.8.8 service, and a host of smaller providers support various schemes to encrypt DNS requests entirely. But encryption doesn't necessarily mean that your traffic is invisible; some encrypted DNS services log your requests for various purposes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cloudflare has promised not to log individuals' DNS traffic and has hired an outside firm to audit that promise. APNIC wants to use traffic data to point to the IP address, which has the unfortunate legacy of being a dumping ground for &quot;garbage&quot; Internet traffic, &lt;a href=&quot;https://labs.apnic.net/?p=1127&quot;&gt;for research purposes&lt;/a&gt;, according to APNIC's Geoff Huston. But APNIC won't have access to the encrypted DNS traffic in this case, either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;pullbox sidebar story-sidebar right&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;For users, taking advantage of encrypted DNS services from Cloudflare or any other privacy-focused DNS services is not as easy as changing a number in network settings. No operating system currently directly supports any of the encrypted DNS services without the addition of some less-than-consumer-friendly software. And not all of the services are created equal in terms of software support and performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But with consumer data as product all over the news as of late, I set out to see just how to get Cloudflare's encrypted DNS service working. And overcome by my inner lab-rat, I ended up testing and dissecting clients for multiple DNS providers using three of the established protocols for DNS encryption: DNSCrypt, DNS over TLS, and DNS over HTTPS. All of them can work, but let me warn you: while it's getting easier, choosing the encrypted DNS route is not something you'd necessarily be able to walk Mom or Dad through over the phone today. (Unless, of course, your parents happen to be seasoned Linux command-line users.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/dns-recursion-4f4d72d-intro-640x481.png&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;481&quot; alt=&quot;How DNS works.&quot;/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;caption-text&quot;&gt;How DNS works.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-credit&quot;&gt;Sean Gallagher&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why are we doing this, again?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are plenty of reasons to want to make DNS traffic more secure. While Web traffic and other communications may be protected by cryptographic protocols such as Transport Layer Security (TLS), almost all DNS traffic is transmitted unencrypted. That means that your ISP (or anyone else between you and the rest of the Internet) can log the sites you visit even when you use another DNS service and use that data for a number of purposes, including filtering access to content and collecting data for advertising purposes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/dns-udp.jpg&quot; width=&quot;525&quot; height=&quot;374&quot; alt=&quot;What a typical DNS conversation between a device and a DNS resolver looks like. &quot;/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;caption-text&quot;&gt;What a typical DNS conversation between a device and a DNS resolver looks like.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;We have a 'last mile' problem in DNS,&quot; said Cricket Liu, Chief DNS Architect at the network security company Infoblox. &quot;Most of the security mechanisms we have dealt with server-to-server issues. But we have this problem where we have stub resolvers on various operating systems and don't really have any way to secure them.&quot; That's particularly a problem, Liu said, in countries that have a more hostile relationship with the Internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just using a non-logging DNS service helps to some degree. But it doesn't prevent someone from filtering those requests based on content or capturing the addresses within them with packet capture or deep packet-inspection gear. And in addition to simple, passive eavesdropping attacks, there's also the threat of more active attacks against your DNS traffic—efforts by an ISP or a government on the wire to &quot;spoof&quot; the identity of a DNS server, routing traffic to their own server to log or block traffic. Something similar (albeit apparently not maliciously) appears to be happening with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dslreports.com/forum/r31901379-AT-T-gateway-5268ac-maybe-others-misrouting-1-1-1-0-24&quot;&gt;AT&amp;amp;T's (accidental) misrouting of traffic to Cloudflare's 1.1.1.1 address,&lt;/a&gt; based on the observations of forum posters on DSLReports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most obvious way to dodge monitoring is by using a &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2016/06/aiming-for-anonymity-ars-assesses-the-state-of-vpns-in-2016/&quot;&gt;virtual private network&lt;/a&gt;. But while &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2017/05/how-to-build-your-own-vpn-if-youre-rightfully-wary-of-commercial-options/&quot;&gt;VPNs&lt;/a&gt; conceal the contents of your Internet traffic, connecting to a VPN might require a DNS request first. And once you've launched a VPN session, DNS requests may occasionally get routed outside of your VPN connection by Web browsers or other software, creating &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dnsleaktest.com/what-is-a-dns-leak.html&quot;&gt;DNS leaks&lt;/a&gt;&quot; that expose which sites you're visiting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;pullbox sidebar story-sidebar right&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;That's where encrypted DNS protocols come in—the DNSCrypt protocol (supported by Cisco OpenDNS, among others), &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rfc-editor.org/info/rfc7858&quot;&gt;DNS resolution over TLS&lt;/a&gt; (supported by Cloudflare, Google, Quad9, and OpenDNS), and &lt;a href=&quot;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/draft-ietf-doh-dns-over-https/?include_text=1&quot;&gt;DNS resolution over HTTPS&lt;/a&gt; (currently supported by Cloudflare, &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/speed/public-dns/docs/dns-over-https&quot;&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt;, and the adult-content-blocking service CleanBrowsing). Encrypted traffic both ensures that traffic can't be sniffed or modified and that requests can't be read by someone masquerading as the DNS service—eliminating middle-man attacks and spying. Using a DNS proxy for one of these services (either directly on your device or on a &quot;server&quot; inside your local network) will help prevent VPN DNS leaks, since the proxy will always be the fastest-responding DNS server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That privacy does not come packaged for mass consumption, however. None of these protocols is currently supported natively by any DNS resolver pre-packaged with an operating system. All of them require the installation (and probably compilation) of a client application that acts as a local DNS &quot;server,&quot; relaying requests made by browsers and other applications upstream to the secure DNS provider of your choice. And while two out of three of the technologies are proposed standards, no option we tested is necessarily in its final form.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So if you choose to dive into encrypted DNS, you will probably want to use a Raspberry Pi or some other dedicated piece of hardware to run it as a DNS server for your home network. That's because you'll find that configuring one of these clients is more than enough hackery. Why repeat the process multiple times when you can just query your local network's dynamic host configuration protocol (DHCP) settings to point everything at one successful installation as a DNS server? I asked myself this question repeatedly as I watched clients crash on Windows and fall asleep on MacOS during testing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2018 18:31:03 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>azizuysal</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2018/04/how-to-keep-your-isps-nose-out-of-your-browser-history-with-encrypted-dns/</og:url>
<og:title>How to keep your ISP’s nose out of your browser history with encrypted DNS</og:title>
<og:image>https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/dns-crypty-760x380.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>Using Cloudflare’s 1.1.1.1, other DNS services still require some command-line know-how.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2018/04/how-to-keep-your-isps-nose-out-of-your-browser-history-with-encrypted-dns/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>In 2004, Zuckerberg Broke Into a Facebook User&amp;#039;s Private Email Account (2010)</title>
<link>http://www.businessinsider.com/how-mark-zuckerberg-hacked-into-the-harvard-crimson-2010-3/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.businessinsider.com/how-mark-zuckerberg-hacked-into-the-harvard-crimson-2010-3/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is the story of how, in 2004, Mark Zuckerberg hacked into the email accounts of two Harvard Crimson reporters using data obtained from TheFacebook.com's logs. The details are drawn from a broader investigation of the origins of Facebook, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.businessinsider.com/how-facebook-was-founded-2010-3&quot;&gt;sourcing of which is described here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.businessinsider.com/facebook&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; CEO and cofounder &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.businessinsider.com/mark-zuckerberg&quot;&gt;Mark Zuckerberg&lt;/a&gt; now runs a site that 400 million people visit each month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But back in May 2004, he was a 19-year-old finishing up his sophomore year at Harvard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was also the acclaimed founder and creator of an increasingly popular Web site called TheFacebook.com, which had launched in February 2004.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we've reported in detail in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.businessinsider.com/how-facebook-was-founded-2010-3&quot;&gt;a separate story&lt;/a&gt;, the launch of TheFacebook.com was not without controversy. Just six days after the site launched, three Harvard seniors, Cameron Winklevoss, Tyler Winklevoss, and Divya Narendra, accused Mark of intentionally misleading them into believing he would help them build a social network called HarvardConnection.com, while he was instead using their ideas to build a competing product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After Mark launched TheFacebook.com, Cameron, Tyler and Divya hired a series of developers to build HarvardConnection -- the site Mark Zuckerberg had told them he would build but did not. By mid-May, the trio had a site ready for launch. By then the site's name had changed from HarvardConnection to ConnectU.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometime during the 14 days leading up to May 28 -- the editors at Harvard's student newspaper, the &lt;em&gt;Crimson&lt;/em&gt;, received an email in the their &quot;tips&quot; inbox from Cameron Winklevoss, one of the founders of ConnectU.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This email presented the argument Cameron Winklevoss, Tyler Winklevoss, and Divvya Narenda had already brought to Harvard's Administration Board and to Mark Zuckerberg -- that TheFacebook.com was the product of Mark Zuckerberg's fraud against the ConnectU team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the Winklevoss brothers were best known at Harvard for being exceptional rowers, the story was assigned to &lt;em&gt;Crimson&lt;/em&gt; sports writer Tim McGinn. After a phone call, Tim hosted Tyler, Cameron, and Divya in his office at the &lt;em&gt;Crimson&lt;/em&gt;. The four of them went over emails between Cameron and Mark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the ConnectU team left, the &lt;em&gt;Crimson&lt;/em&gt; invited Mark into its offices to defend himself. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Mark arrived at the Crimson, he asked Tim and Elisabeth Theodore, an editor helping with the story, to sign a non-disclosure agreement so that he could show them the work he'd done on HarvardConnection. Per &lt;em&gt;Crimson&lt;/em&gt; policy, Tim and Elisabeth refused to sign the NDA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;KonaFilter image-container float_left image&quot; data-post-image=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://static2.businessinsider.com/image/4b8d5b1d7f8b9a8043ab0400-307-230/harvard-crimson-building.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;harvard crimson building&quot; width=&quot;307&quot; height=&quot;230&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;source-only source&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/thewastedsmile/2756341321/&quot;&gt;thewastedsmile&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mark lingered around the office, evidently hoping they would change their mind. Finally, Mark agreed to forgo the NDA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a &lt;em&gt;Crimson&lt;/em&gt; computer, Mark brought up what he described as the work he did on HarvardConnection.  He gave Tim and Elisabeth a guided tour of the site. Mark's goal seemed to have been to show Tim and Elizabeth, the &lt;em&gt;Crimson&lt;/em&gt; reporter and editor, that, other than the ways in which social networks are all the same, there were no features or designs in the work he did on HarvardConnection.com that ended up in theFacebook.com.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mark's demonstration was successful: After he left, the &lt;em&gt;Crimson&lt;/em&gt; decided not to run a story.  Tim emailed Tyler, Cameron, and Divya to tell them that the story would not run. He contacted Mark to say the the same thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But then, perhaps a day or so later, the Winklevoss brothers reached out to Tim McGinn again, this time to tell him that another Harvard rower -- one named John Thomson -- had told them that Mark had stolen something for TheFacebook from him, too. They told Tim that John's claim was that Mark Zuckerberg stole from him the idea for a TheFacebook feature called &quot;Visualize Your Buddy.&quot; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a new accusation at hand, the &lt;em&gt;Crimson&lt;/em&gt; decided to re-open its investigation.  Tim McGinn called Mark and told him about about John's claim and gave him a chance to deny it. Mark denied the claim and got very upset -- apparently because he felt he had been promised there would be no story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the rest of that night and into the next morning, Tim and his editor Elisabeth Theodore attempted to follow-up with John Thomson. After they finally reached him, John told them that he made the whole Mark Zuckerberg anecdote up in order to impress the Winklevoss brothers, who were important members of the rowing team. [As an aside, kudos to the journalism at the &lt;em&gt;Crimson&lt;/em&gt;!]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tim and Elisabeth decided to drop John's claims from the story. But, this time, they decided to go ahead and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thecrimson.com/article/2004/5/28/online-facebooks-duel-over-tangled-web/&quot;&gt;publish a story on ConnectU's claims against Facebook&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mark Zuckerberg was not content to wait until the morning to find out if the Crimson would include John's accusations in its story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, he decided to access the email accounts of Crimson editors and review their emails.  How did he do this?  Here's how Mark described his hack to a friend:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mark used his site, TheFacebook.com, to look up members of the site who identified themselves as members of the &lt;em&gt;Crimson&lt;/em&gt;.  Then he examined a log of failed logins to see if any of the Crimson members had ever entered an incorrect password into TheFacebook.com.  If the cases in which they had entered failed logins, Mark tried to use them to access the Crimson members' Harvard email accounts.  He successfully accessed two of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other words, Mark appears to have used private login data from TheFacebook to hack into the separate email accounts of some TheFacebook users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In one account he accessed, Mark saw an email from &lt;em&gt;Crimson&lt;/em&gt; writer Tim McGinn to Cameron, Tyler, and Divya. Another email Mark read was this one, from &lt;em&gt;Crimson&lt;/em&gt; managing editor Elisabeth Theodore to Tim McGinn:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From: Elisabeth Susan Theodore&lt;br/&gt;To: Timothy John McGinn&lt;br/&gt;Subject: Re: Follow-up&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;OK, he did seem very sleazy. And I thought that some of his answers to the questions were not very direct or open. I also thought that his reactiont o the website was very very weird. But, even if it's true so what? It's an [redacted] thing ot od but it's not illegal, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We reached out to Tim McGinn and Elisabeth Theodore for comment.  Both declined to comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we reviewed the details of this story with Facebook, the company had this comment:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;We’re not going to debate the disgruntled litigants and anonymous sources who seek to rewrite Facebook’s early history or embarrass Mark Zuckerberg with dated allegations. The unquestioned fact is that since leaving Harvard for Silicon Valley nearly six years ago, Mark has led Facebook's growth from a college website to a global service playing an important role in the lives of over 400 million people.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're certainly not questioning the latter fact: Facebook's success has been awe-inspiring.  Given the significant concerns about privacy online in general and at Facebook in particular, however, it seems reasonable to ask what the company's reaction -- and Mark's reaction -- is to the reported behavior above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the past, Facebook has told us: &quot;Facebook respects user privacy and access to site usage and profile information is restricted at the company. Any Facebook employees found to be engaged in improper access to user data will be disciplined or terminated.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is clear that the events described above would be a direct violation of Facebook's current policy, which has now been in place for several years. The policy was not in place at the time of the events described above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A source close to the company suggests that it was the fallout from early privacy violations like this one -- fallout that has included reputational damage to Mark Zuckerberg and expensive and prolonged litigation with ConnectU -- that has shaped Facebook's current privacy policies and made Mark the CEO he is today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don't miss:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2018 17:20:24 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ljk</dc:creator>
<og:title> In 2004, Mark Zuckerberg Broke Into A Facebook User's Private Email Account</og:title>
<og:description>In the spring of 2004, Mark Zuckerberg used data from his successful new web site, TheFacebook.com, to hack into the email accounts of two Harvard Crimson...</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>http://www.businessinsider.com/how-mark-zuckerberg-hacked-into-the-harvard-crimson-2010-3</og:url>
<og:image>http://static3.businessinsider.com/image/4b8d5b1d7f8b9a8043ab0400-1190-625/in-2004-mark-zuckerberg-broke-into-a-facebook-users-private-email-account.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.businessinsider.com/how-mark-zuckerberg-hacked-into-the-harvard-crimson-2010-3/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Publishers Haven&amp;#039;t Realized How Big a Deal GDPR Is</title>
<link>https://baekdal.com/strategy/publishers-havent-realized-just-how-big-a-deal-gdpr-is/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://baekdal.com/strategy/publishers-havent-realized-just-how-big-a-deal-gdpr-is/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;On May 25, 2018, the new EU General Data Protection Regulation (better known as GDPR) comes into effect, and I'm quite worried about how this will impact publishers because most don't seem to be even close to compliant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem with GDPR is that most publishers see it as an IT/administrative burden. They think the only thing they need to do is set up some databases and do some other IT things ... and then redesign their privacy page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I'm not seeing, however, is any real change to the way publishers use data, the business models they have that rely on data, or any consideration as to what impact this will have on their editorial strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, in this article, I'm going to talk about GDPR as a concept in relation to media trends, and consider what this means for your editorial strategies. I hope I can help you realize just how big a change this actually is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mind you, I'm not a lawyer. I am a media analyst. I do not claim to be an expert in all the nuances of GDPR. My focus is to talk about strategies, user behaviors, business models, etc. But, I am also a publisher, so my knowledge of GDPR is based on the work that I have put into making sure that my site will be compliant (which I'm still in the process of doing).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to get legal advice on how to be compliant, you need to get in contact with a lawyer or a consultant with a specific focus on the legal aspects of this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now, let's talk about this from a strategy perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Don't try to avoid GDPR&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I hear people discuss GDPR I have noticed that almost everyone talks about it in the legal sense. What I mean is that people are discussing what the technicalities of the law are, what exceptions or loopholes it has, and how you could get away with using these exceptions to continue to do the things you have always done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And sure enough, there may be ways to classify some data as 'legitimate interest' so that you don't have to ask people whether you can collect their data or not, and there may be ways that you can designate the 3rd party services that you use as co-controllers, or some other workarounds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You also may be able to argue that you have terms of use with your 3rd party service that says they can't use the data they are getting from you, even though you know you don't actually have any control, and that they are using it anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Legally, you may be able to find enough exceptions and loopholes to do all of this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, there are two major reasons why thinking about GDPR this way is the wrong strategy to have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The overall trend in the market&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first major reason is the overall trend about privacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you look at what is happening around us, you can see very clear signals that the public has had enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, for instance, we see that a majority of people who install an ad blocker don't actually do it to block ads (that's just an added bonus). They are actually doing it to block tracking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What people are reacting to is not just what Facebook is doing, but how every publisher is using a very large number of 3rd party trackers, where neither the publisher or the reader has any control over what is actually happening with this data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.baekdal.com/_img/2018/GDPR3.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;We also see this trend in many other aspects of online behavior. Think about how many people have locked and set their social profiles to 'private'. Think about how people are using services like Snapchat, Instagram Stories, or Twitch live streaming ... all services that, by default, delete what you have posted so that it can't be turned into a privacy violation later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trend here is really clear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you then, as a publisher, just implement GDPR by taking advantage of all the exceptions or loopholes, so that you continue to load 38 trackers into your site and do it like it's all 'business as usual', you will be fighting against this trend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other words, you become the bad guy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Google and Facebook know this&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other very important factor here is to look at big tech companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Companies like Google and Facebook are perhaps those who have benefited the most from being able to collect data from multiple sources, so you would think that they would do everything they can to try to use every loophole GDPR has.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What we are seeing, however, is a very different outcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me just remind you of the basic principles of GDPR in a simplified way:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Everything must be consent based.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can only collect what is adequate, necessary, and not excessive in relation to the specific service you offer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People have the right to transparency.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People have the right to be forgotten.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IP addresses are also considered to be personal information.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;Obviously, there are a lot of exceptions here, and different ways of defining things. For instance, the definition of consent is not necessarily a 'direct consent'.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a person visits a web shop to buy a product, they will enter their home address so that you can send it to them. This is considered to be a form of consent. So you don't have to ask people for consent separately to save their address.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is also the question about the right for people to delete their data. This is not actually possible in many cases, because other laws require publishers to keep the data. One example is that publishers are required to keep data related to accounting and taxes. So, there is a lot of data that you can't delete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But think about this in relation to a new visitor. Someone that you have no prior relationship with (a first time visitor). What data can you actually collect and use for that person?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The answer is ... &lt;strong&gt;nothing!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You cannot use any personal identifying data from any visitor who is a one-time visitor. You cannot load any 3rd party service, because by doing that you would be sending personally identifying data to those services (like people's IP address). You cannot even do personally identifying internal analytics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason is that a first time visitor hasn't done anything that could be considered consent, so you have nothing to work with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't think publishers realize just what this means.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Essentially, it means that you can't load any 3rd party service into your site. You can't load advertising from your ad partners (via their scripts), you can't add social widgets, you can't add a quiz to your articles that is using some 3rd party service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or put it simply, you can't do any of this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.baekdal.com/_img/2018/GDPR3.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;At this point, you are probably thinking that I'm being overly dramatic, and that I should just calm down because this is not really what this means. And, again, you might argue that there are ways around this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But this is where the actions of Google and Facebook come into play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google is obviously one of the companies the EU will watch the most, so when Google looked at GDPR they basically came to the conclusion that there was no way around it without resulting in lengthy and likely very expensive legal fights. Fights that they would be attacked with in the press, that would also cause a drop in trust from their users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, Google has come to the same conclusion that I have, which is that they &lt;strong&gt;can't do anything until you have given them consent&lt;/strong&gt;. And, as a result, Google has now implemented a system so that when you visit them, you are presented with a box that looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.baekdal.com/_img/2018/GDPR2.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;With this box, Google is explicitly and openly asking you for consent to how Google is tracking you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This also extends beyond Google's own sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For instance, when publishers are using Google Adsense, it used to be that this interaction would track people across the web. But now, because of GDPR, Google has announced that it will no longer be based on &lt;a href=&quot;https://pagefair.com/blog/2018/googles-nonpersonal-ads/#_ftn1&quot;&gt;any personally identifying data&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason is, again, that Google can't be sure that publishers have obtained the correct level of consent before the ads are shown. So, Google is trying to get ahead of this by just getting rid of the problem altogether.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's the same with Facebook. They too are moving to a consent based baseline for how they do everything. And, they are also stopping their practice of &lt;a href=&quot;https://digiday.com/marketing/facebooks-shutdown-third-party-data-affects-brands/?utm_campaign=digidaydis&amp;amp;utm_source=twitter&amp;amp;utm_medium=social&quot;&gt;buying personal data from data brokers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As someone living in Europe, this has always been a huge violation of privacy. But what Facebook has now realized is that, with GDPR, doing something like this would be in direct violation of the law. Specifically, it's a violation because people have not given their consent for their data to be used this way. And on top of this, the rule that you can only collect data &lt;strong&gt;relevant to the service you offer&lt;/strong&gt; is incompatible with the practice of buying up vast amounts of random data about people from data brokers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So Facebook is &lt;strong&gt;ending this&lt;/strong&gt; instead of trying to fight it (which would only result in more negative press, loss of trust by its users, and penalties from the EU).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My point here is that the tech companies have decided to rethink the way they are doing privacy. Obviously there are a ton of things that still need to be done, neither Facebook or Google is in the clear. But when we combine what Google and Facebook are now saying with the overall trend of what the public demands, it's pretty clear to see where this is heading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this brings us back to publishers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have yet to see any publisher who is actually changing what they are doing. Every single media site that I visit is still loading tons of 3rd party trackers. They are still not asking people for consent, in fact most seem to think they already have people's consent, and when questioned about trackers, they can just say: &quot;We use 3rd party services, and we refer to their privacy statements.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This doesn't work under GDPR, because, as a publisher you are a &lt;strong&gt;data-controller&lt;/strong&gt;, whereas all the 3rd party tools you use are the &lt;strong&gt;data-processors&lt;/strong&gt;. And it's the data-controller who is responsible for obtaining consent, for providing transparency, for giving people access to their data, and to make sure that all the data, regardless of where it is stored, is under your control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, this is a whole new reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically, what publishers need to do is think about their audience in four different segments:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;One-time users&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Limited interaction users&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Full interaction users&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cancelled users&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;And the way to think of each is like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;One-time users&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One-time users includes all one-time visits and all the visits where people have &lt;strong&gt;not done anything to give you their consent&lt;/strong&gt;. This means you cannot load any 3rd party tools. All your ads have to be delivered via 1st party means (so no 3rd party ad code) and it cannot contain any personally identifying information. You cannot automatically load embedded content (because then you are sending data to those sites), you can't load social widgets, etc. And for your own sites, you can only do non-identifying analytics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Essentially, you need to do this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.baekdal.com/_img/2018/GDPR1.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Of course, making this change will have a dramatic impact on your revenue for single-visit traffic, because you basically have to design your ad model to work completely differently from how it works today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Limited interaction users&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Limited interaction users are those who have signed up for a limited part of your site. Like when people have signed up for a newsletter, or when they have bought access to one of your guides, but haven't yet become a full subscriber.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this you have an &lt;strong&gt;implied consent&lt;/strong&gt;, but it's limited to that specific service that you provide. For instance, if people sign up to your newsletter, you cannot claim that they have also given you consent to load a ton of 3rd party trackers that do many other things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember, GDPR limits your data to only what is relevant for what people have requested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, this is a pretty big deal for publishers, because this too dramatically changes how we think about data. In the past, we considered all data to be 'fair game' as long as people had done anything on our site. In the future, this argument will no longer work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your use of data has to be specific, limited, and relevant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Full interaction users&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Full interaction users are people who have signed up for a full account, and with that agreed to have everything you offer available to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this, you have a much wider scope to work with, but it still doesn't give you free reign to just add a ton of 3rd party tracking scripts to your site. Each has to be relevant to what you offer. Each one has to be limited to only collect what is relevant to each individual publisher, and you are still responsible for transparency, data control, and everything else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What full interaction &lt;em&gt;does&lt;/em&gt; give you is the ability to use data across what you do. With limited interaction, you can only use the data in relation to that one thing that people have signed up for, but full subscribers are people who expect things to work as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Cancelled users&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With cancelled users, we are basically back to where we started. With this, I mean that as soon as people cancel their accounts, you have to delete their information (except the data that you are legally required to keep, like accounting data).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, all your personally identifying analytics for that person; all their personal settings; your advertising profiling data, and so forth ... all that has to be deleted when people cancel their subscriptions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, this is a pretty big shift in how things used to be done, and it impacts things that we don't even consider today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Be a part of the solution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I said in the beginning, this article is not supposed to be a legal guide to help you navigate GDPR. What I have done is take an overview of the concept of GDPR, in relation to the trend of privacy, and with the behavior that we see from major tech companies. I have also considered what it is that our readers actually expect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it's pretty clear that our readers don't expect us to just continue with what we have always done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;True, you may be able to find loopholes and exceptions that may allow you to legally do something, but do you really want be &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; company?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My advice to you is rethink your approach to GDPR. This is your chance to be a &lt;strong&gt;part of the solution&lt;/strong&gt;, rather than being part of the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can embrace this trend to build trust and to show our readers that we respect them. We can use this to build services that have privacy built in as a feature, as a way to give people better use of data by giving them better control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think of this as the turning point of privacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So publishers have to rethink technical platforms &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; their business and editorial platforms. Your advertising models have to be more 1st party focused, where the focus is on the context rather than personal profiling, simply because first-time visitors see the most advertising.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This requires a change in the business models and the partners you work with, but it also requires a different focus editorially. We are so used to just publishing random content at scale, because that's the way the old ad models were optimized. The new ad models place more emphasis on context, so we need to raise our contextual editorial focus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More importantly, though, the future of data will shift more towards owned relationships, like what you offer for your full subscribers, which again changes the way you think about data and editorial strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data suddenly becomes a subscriber feature, because those are the only times where you have full consent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a big deal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The media has a long history of not changing in time, and most of those times we could argue that it was because we didn't know what the future would bring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time we know. So, my advice to you is to change now. Don't wait to see what happens. Don't try to just do what you have always done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just change.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2018 16:44:03 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>transpute</dc:creator>
<og:title>Publishers Haven't Realized Just How Big a Deal GDPR is</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://baekdal.com/strategy/publishers-havent-realized-just-how-big-a-deal-gdpr-is/</og:url>
<og:image>https://cdn.baekdal.com/_img/2018/GDPRfront.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>The European Privacy Regulation is changing the game.</og:description>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://baekdal.com/strategy/publishers-havent-realized-just-how-big-a-deal-gdpr-is/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>America should borrow from Europe’s data-privacy law</title>
<link>https://www.economist.com/news/leaders/21739961-gdprs-premise-consumers-should-be-charge-their-own-personal-data-right</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.economist.com/news/leaders/21739961-gdprs-premise-consumers-should-be-charge-their-own-personal-data-right</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;AMERICA rarely looks to the bureaucrats of Brussels for guidance. Commercial freedom appeals more than &lt;em class=&quot;Italic&quot;&gt;dirigisme&lt;/em&gt;. But when it comes to data privacy, the case for copying the best bits of the European Union’s approach is compelling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) is due to come into force next month. It is rules-heavy and has its flaws, but its premise that consumers should be in charge of their personal data is the right one. The law lets users gain access to, and to correct, information that firms hold on them. It gives consumers the right to transfer their data to another organisation. It requires companies to define how they keep data secure. And it lets regulators levy big fines if firms break the rules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;newsletter-form newsletter-form--inline&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;newsletter-form__message&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get our daily newsletter&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upgrade your inbox and get our Daily Dispatch and Editor's Picks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;latest-updates-panel__container latest-updates-panel__container--blog-post&quot;&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;latest-updates-panel__body&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;latest-updates-panel-card__wrapper&quot; readability=&quot;-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;latest-updates-panel__article-link&quot; readability=&quot;27&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;latest-updates-panel-card__title&quot;&gt;Homo sapiens spread to Asia earlier than once believed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;latest-updates-panel-card__wrapper&quot; readability=&quot;-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;latest-updates-panel__article-link&quot; readability=&quot;27&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;latest-updates-panel-card__title&quot;&gt;$15m is available to solve a burning problem&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;latest-updates-panel-card__wrapper&quot; readability=&quot;-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;latest-updates-panel__article-link&quot; readability=&quot;27&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;latest-updates-panel-card__title&quot;&gt;A plan that needs more money&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;latest-updates-panel-card__wrapper&quot; readability=&quot;-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;latest-updates-panel__article-link&quot; readability=&quot;27&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;latest-updates-panel-card__title&quot;&gt;“Killing Eve” is another triumph for Phoebe Waller-Bridge&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;latest-updates-panel-card__wrapper&quot; readability=&quot;-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;latest-updates-panel__article-link&quot; readability=&quot;27&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;latest-updates-panel-card__title&quot;&gt;America vows to respond to a suspected chemical attack in Syria&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;latest-updates-panel-card__wrapper&quot; readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;latest-updates-panel__article-link&quot; readability=&quot;29&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;latest-updates-panel-card__title&quot;&gt;Hungary’s illiberal prime minister, Viktor Orban, wins a landslide&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;America has enacted privacy rules in areas such as health care. But it has never passed an overarching data-protection law. The latest attempt, the Consumer Privacy Bill of Rights, introduced in 2012 by the Obama administration, died a slow death in Congress. The GDPR should inspire another try.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The failings of America’s self-regulatory approach are becoming clearer by the week. Large parts of the online economy are fuelled by data that consumers spray around without thought. Companies’ arcane privacy policies obfuscate what they do with their users’ information, which often amounts to pretty much anything they please. Facebook is embroiled in crisis after news that data on 87m users had been passed to a political-campaign firm. Identity-theft is widespread; the annual cost to American consumers exceeds $16bn, according to some estimates. On March 29th Under Armour, a clothing brand, said that hackers had gained access to information about 150m users of its MyFitnessPal app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These scandals are changing the calculus about the benefits of self-regulation. Opponents of privacy legislation have long argued that the imposition of rules would keep technology companies from innovating. Yet as trust leaches out of the system, innovation is likely to suffer. If consumers fret about what smartphone apps may do with their data, fewer new offerings will take off—especially in artificial intelligence. It emerged this week that Grindr, a dating app aimed at gay people, had been sharing details of users’ HIV status with other firms. Tim Cook, the chief executive of Apple (which, admittedly, has sold itself on the idea that its customers’ data should not be a source of profit), has called privacy a “human right”. Even Mark Zuckerberg, Facebook’s boss, has signalled an openness to regulation. It is striking that many of the firms preparing for the GDPR’s arrival in Europe enthuse that the law has forced them to put their data house in order (see &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.economist.com/news/business/21739985-complying-will-be-hard-businesses-it-will-bring-benefits-too-europes-tough-new&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The need to minimise legal fragmentation only adds to the case for America to adopt bits of the GDPR. One reason behind the new rules in the EU was to harmonise data-protection laws so that firms can do business across Europe more easily. America is moving in the opposite direction. States that have detected a need for greater privacy are drafting their own laws. California, for instance, has pending legislation that would establish a data-protection authority to regulate how the state’s big tech firms use Californians’ personal data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Internationally, too, America is increasingly an outlier. Any American firm that serves European customers will soon have no choice but to comply with the GDPR; some firms plan to employ the rules worldwide. Other countries are adopting GDPR-style laws. A similar regime on both sides of the Atlantic would help keep data flowing across borders. The alternative, of a regulatory patchwork, would make it harder for the West to amass a shared stock of AI training data to rival China’s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;xhead&quot;&gt;Putting the personal into data&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;America need not adopt the GDPR wholesale. The legislation is far from perfect. At nearly 100 articles long, it is too complex and tries to achieve too many things. The compliance costs for smaller firms, in particular, look burdensome. In addition, parts of the GDPR are out of step with America’s constitutional guarantee of free speech: a “right to be forgotten” of the kind that the new law enshrines will not fly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But these are arguments for using the GDPR as a template, not for ignoring the issue of data protection. If America continues on today’s path, it will fail to protect the privacy of its citizens and long-term health of its firms. America’s data economy has thrived so far with hardly any rules. That era is over.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2018 13:54:38 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>kushti</dc:creator>
<og:description>The GDPR’s premise, that consumers should be in charge of their own personal data, is the right one</og:description>
<og:image>https://cdn.static-economist.com/sites/default/files/images/print-edition/20180407_LDD002_0.jpg</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.economist.com/news/leaders/21739961-gdprs-premise-consumers-should-be-charge-their-own-personal-data-right</og:url>
<og:title>America should borrow from Europe’s data-privacy law</og:title>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.economist.com/news/leaders/21739961-gdprs-premise-consumers-should-be-charge-their-own-personal-data-right</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Robert Langlands, who linked number theory, analysis, and geometry (2015)</title>
<link>http://projects.thestar.com/math-the-canadian-who-reinvented-mathematics/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://projects.thestar.com/math-the-canadian-who-reinvented-mathematics/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;first-word&quot;&gt;Robert Langlands&lt;/span&gt; enjoys daily walks up Mount Royal. At 78, he climbs with sure steps, weaving along beaten paths to the cemeteries on the mountain’s north side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He takes those hikes when he is back at his Montreal condo, between semesters at the renowned Institute for Advanced Studies in Princeton, N.J., where Langlands has been a professor for more than 40 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His destination, the bright summer day when the Star first caught up with him, was the gravesite of writer Mordecai Richler, on a spot called Rose Hill. It was hot, the air was alive with birds, and tombstones rose and fell as if on a wave of green. Death seemed almost acceptable. But Langlands strolls the graveyards for a different kind of inner peace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“If you’re lucky, it’s a way to stop thinking,” he says. “The wheels don’t stop so easily after a while.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Langlands, a Canadian, is one of the world’s great mathematicians. His universe is the outer limits of pure mathematics, a rarefied realm where abstract objects exist, infinity is corralled and symmetry reigns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1967, as a young professor at Princeton University, he revolutionized the ancient discipline. He discovered patterns in highly esoteric objects called automorphic forms and motives, and he restructured mathematics with two dazzling theories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They indicated what mathematician Edward Frenkel calls “the source code of all mathematics,” and are credited with linking math’s main branches — number theory (once called arithmetic), harmonic analysis, which includes calculus, and geometry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://projects.thestar.com/math-the-canadian-who-reinvented-mathematics/img/edward-frenkel.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Edward Frenkel&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Russian-born mathematician Edward Frenkel, a math superstar and professor at the University of California, Berkeley, calls Canadian Robert Langlands &quot;a modern-day Einstein.&quot; (Elizabeth Lippman)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To mathematicians, this is mind-blowing stuff. The branches deal with completely different things: number theory is about, yes, numbers, harmonic analysis studies motion and geometry deals with shapes. They may as well be different planets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Suddenly, you have a teleportation device that enables you to go — boom — from one place to another,” says Frenkel, a Russian-born mathematician at the University of California at Berkeley, describing the math-warping impact of Langlands’ conjectures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The theories have not been fully proven. But every time they’ve been tested, they work. Frenkel is convinced the conjectures lay the groundwork for a “Grand Unified Theory of Mathematics,” although some aspects remain beyond Langlands’ embrace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“He was a visionary,” Frenkel adds in a phone interview from California. “He pointed us into a direction where we can go and find the truth, find out what’s really going on. It’s about seeing the world in the right light.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resistance from eminent academic quarters was stiff. But Langlands’ new order eventually evolved into a vast area of research known as the Langlands Program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frenkel, a driving force in the program, pushed its boundaries further a decade ago. He landed a multi-million-dollar grant from the U.S. Defence Advanced Research Projects Agency (DARPA). The mandate is to apply Langlands’ conjectures to the search for physics’ Holy Grail — a theory that unifies laws governing all known physical interactions in the universe. Physicists in the DARPA research include Edward Witten, a leading “superstring” theorist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unifying nature’s fundamental forces — gravity, electromagnetism, the strong and weak nuclear forces — was a goal that eluded Albert Einstein. If Langlands’ theories help make it happen, the cosmic symmetry will come with a poetic touch: Langlands’ office in Princeton is the same one Einstein occupied during the later part of his two decades at the Institute for Advanced Studies, until his death in 1955.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“He’s like a modern-day Einstein,” says Frenkel, author of &lt;em&gt;Love and Math&lt;/em&gt;, a book about the Langlands Program. “But everybody knows about Einstein and nobody knows about Langlands. Why is that?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That kind of talk makes Langlands cringe. He’s sure of his achievements but skeptical about their value in the real world. Pure math is an adventure of the mind, unconcerned with applications. He’s even uncomfortable with the program that bears his name, believing its expansion into the field of differential geometry — a branch that uses calculus to study the properties of geometric shapes — has been poorly thought out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of all, he recognizes his work is complete nonsense to all but a tiny clique.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“What normal person cares whether the square root of two is a rational number?” he asks, referring to numbers than can be written as fractions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No doubt even high school math is anathema to the many who remember it as an instrument of torture. Yet math-based algorithms increasingly dominate daily life, from stock market trading to Internet searches to online payments. Math geeks are cashing in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the initiated few, the attraction is as old as philosophy. Math is the language of absolute truths: in no universe can 2 + 2 equal 5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Jim Arthur, a professor at the University of Toronto, math reveals the beauty and symmetry of the universe in ways that “almost overwhelm your sense of esthetics.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If philosophers can ever swoon, Bertrand Russell came close when he exalted math as “the true spirit of delight.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Langlands has his feet more firmly on the ground. Since Plato, many mathematicians have considered math objects and equations to be as real as gravity, waiting to be discovered. Langlands instead sees them as human inventions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A certain distress has therefore entered his life of late. He’s focused on adding what he can toward a complete proof of his conjectures, but age is playing tricks. The objects he once easily manipulated — the equations that produce shapes like weird doughnuts and tubes that curve into infinity — are losing their solidity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It happens when you get old,” he says after reaching Richler’s grey tombstone. “You have less assurance about what’s in your head. Did I turn off the tap?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At times, the opposite happens. He awakes and for some moments finds a world where mathematical entities seem as real as the furniture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s nightmarish,” he says. “It must have something to do with madness. If in the middle of the night you wake up and there’s some fusion between the mathematical objects and the real world, then you’re mad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“And if you’re lucky, it’s just fatigue and not some permanent dysfunction.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://projects.thestar.com/math-the-canadian-who-reinvented-mathematics/img/jim-arthur.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Jim Arthur, University of Toronto&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;University of Toronto mathematician Jim Arthur, who had Robert Langlands as his PhD thesis adviser, predicts that Langlands' theories will eventually help solve some fundamental problems in mathematics. (Marta Iwanek/Toronto Star)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;first-word&quot;&gt;Robert Langlands&lt;/span&gt; was reluctant when I first contacted him about this story, not least because I know nothing about math. He assigned me homework: if I was “at all serious,” I should consult a collection of his writings on the Institute for Advanced Studies website, and speak with Jim Arthur, “the leading mathematician in Canada.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After all that, little more than the surface of things made sense to me. At one point, I triggered an email disagreement by connecting motives found in geometric shapes with spectra, the information in waves and frequencies. Langlands dismissed the link; Arthur insisted on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“A motive is supposed to come with a product of l-adic Galois representations, whose Frobenius eigenvalues would be related to Hecke eigenvalues by reciprocity?” Arthur wrote. “But could we not argue that the latter are closely related to quantum mechanics-like spectra, being ‘momentum observables’ in the sense that they commute with the Laplacian/Hamiltonian?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other words, I would probably understand nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Months later, I stepped into Langlands’ comfortable old condo in Montreal’s leafy Outremont neighbourhood. “I don’t know quite why you’re undertaking this project,” he said, laughing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Langlands is tall and active for his years. He hikes and cycles regularly with his wife, Charlotte, around Vermont and Quebec, but the years when they did so across Europe are over. He fears the joy nature brought him may be lost to future generations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“In what sense survival will be possible is by no means clear to me,” he says. “The frivolity of Canadians with respect to climate change is especially shocking.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He is not afraid to speak his mind. He has described mathematicians as “egotistical creatures,” has lamented an “endemic sense of mediocrity” among Canadians and confesses to being “a little bit caustic” with peers slow to see the full potential of his ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“He’s clearly one of the most important living mathematicians,” Frenkel says. “His legend precedes him. But the question is, ‘Do mathematicians really know what he has done?’ It’s like having a famous writer but no one has read his books.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Langlands often notes he’s not the modest type. But he’s more inclined to stress the enormous work needed to prove his conjectures than the successes so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Presumably, with time, it will be a big part of mathematics,” he says of his theories. “It has to be said, however, that these questions are not very important for the world.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We sat in Langlands’ living room, decorated with stone and clay sculptures by his wife. He began with a five-minute primer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://projects.thestar.com/math-the-canadian-who-reinvented-mathematics/img/robert-langlands-yale-paper.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Problems in the Theory of Automorphic Forms by Robert Langlands&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;The 1970 Yale University paper in which Robert Langlands set out his groundbreaking theories. (Rich Schultz/AP)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“So, you’ve been to school; you took Euclidean geometry?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I took it,” I said, assuming I must have, despite not recalling a thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“There are various things in Euclid that remain important to this day . . . It is proved that the square root of 2 is an irrational number. So, what we’ll be dealing with when we talk about these things is the study of irrational numbers.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He added that ancient Greeks were troubled by the baffling number pi, another irrational number, before asking, “Cartesian geometry — did you learn anything about that? A point in a plane has coordinates x and y? And that you can write a circle with x² + y² = r²?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I can recall sitting in that class,” I said, lying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Newton’s calculus, he then noted, is about velocity and acceleration. Temperatures at various points of the Earth can be treated as functions. And matrixes have something called eigenvalues, numbers detected, for example, when a guitar string is plucked. With that, the lesson was over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I told him about Grade 4, the year math died for me. The teacher divided the class into two teams and for whatever reason made me the captain of one. The game was, ostensibly, to learn multiplication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The daily ritual had the teams line up at different ends of the room. The teacher would flash a card, say, 8 x 4 =, and the first to shout the answer won. The captains squared off first, and every morning the room echoed with my rival’s answer while I stood frozen with my mouth slightly open. At some point, I quite reasonably decided, to hell with math.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Langlands wasn’t moved: “Well, I cried when they wouldn’t accept me in the church choir, so?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robert Phelan Langlands was born in New Westminster, B.C. As a child, he wanted to become a Catholic priest and built an altar in his room. When he was 9, the family moved to White Rock, a resort town near the U.S. border. His parents opened a shop that sold construction materials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was shortly after Second World War. Saturday evenings, the young Langlands admired the swagger and freedom of bigger boys cruising the town’s main drag. He would return the next morning to collect empty beer bottles and recycle each for a penny or two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He delivered the Vancouver Sun. He changed the marquee at the local movie theatre three times a week in exchange for watching the films free. By 13, his free time was spent helping out at his parents’ store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was smart enough to skip a grade in high school, but frustrated teachers who believed he was coasting. “It was a country school,” he says. “It probably wasn’t too hard to be intellectually outstanding.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He thought of dropping out. In Grade 12, an English teacher announced to the class that if Langlands didn’t go to university, he would be wasting God-given talents. Flattered, Langlands applied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By then, he had met Charlotte, with whom he would eventually have four children. Her father owned a book filled with biographies of Marx, Einstein and other great thinkers. It inspired Langlands to become a savant. “In the 18th century sense of the word,” he explains, “the notion of being a learned man.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He would become fluent in French, Russian, German and Turkish, and well-versed in their literature. Frenkel, who exchanges emails with Langlands in Russian, speculates that his versatility with languages may have had something to do with his ability to see connections in disparate fields of mathematics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He completed his undergraduate degree at the University of British Columbia. His 1960 PhD thesis at Yale University analyzed the obscure domain of “Semi groups and representation of Lie groups.” It was spotted by a mathematician at Princeton University and, without having applied, Langlands was offered a job as an instructor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He taught at Princeton and later Yale until 1972, when he became a professor at the Institute for Advanced Studies. He would win almost a dozen major math awards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The American Mathematical Society, in giving Langlands its first award in 1988, applauded his “revolutionary” insights. His “path-blazing work” was celebrated in 1996 when he became the first Canadian to win the coveted Wolf Prize. The $1 million (U.S.) Shaw Prize, which he shared with British mathematician Richard Taylor in 2007, praised Langlands for having “initiated a unifying vision of mathematics that has greatly extended the legacy of mathematics of previous centuries.” The Langlands Program, the citation added, “has guided mathematicians for the past 40 years and will continue to do so for years to come.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I like mathematics to this day,” Langlands says. “I feel at ease with it. I never doubted myself. I never really found a case where somebody else knew better than I did what was going on. Although I didn’t understand everything, by and large I was right.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;first-word&quot;&gt;In 1966&lt;/span&gt;, Langlands almost abandoned mathematics. Deep mysteries in number theory discouraged him. He decided on a change of scenery and applied for a job in Turkey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The decision itself freed me and I began to amuse myself with mathematics without any grand hopes or serious intentions,” he said in written answers to a 2010 UBC interview.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inspiration struck during the Christmas break, in an empty, grand old building on the Princeton campus, as Langlands gazed at a garden through leaded windows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He described his revelation in a Jan. 16, 1967 letter to André Weil, a giant in the field of number theory: “If you are willing to read it as pure speculation,” he wrote Weil, “I would appreciate that; if not — I am sure you have a waste basket handy.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three years later, after he’d returned from Turkey, Langlands published his two theories, called functoriality and reciprocity, under the title “Problems in the Theory of Automorphic Forms.” Math would never be the same again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://projects.thestar.com/math-the-canadian-who-reinvented-mathematics/img/christine-langlands-scultpure.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sculture by Christine Langlands&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;A bronze bust of Professor Weil, a giant in the field of numbers theory, done by Charlotte Langlands, the wife of Professor Robert Langlands. (Rich Schultz/AP)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Automorphic forms can be thought of as fundamental particles in harmonic analysis, which deals in part with waves and frequencies. In a symphony orchestra, automorphic forms issue instructions and work with eigenvalues — the different speeds a violin string moves when struck, for instance — to produce the notes played.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The number of automorphic forms is infinite and each gives different instructions. The data they produce is spectral, the kind that comes from waves and frequencies. Langlands used a method known as the “theory of continuous groups” to link and arrange automophic forms in ways no one knew possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time, he cast his gaze on another branch of mathematics — number theory — and recognized patterns in even more esoteric entities called motives. They’re considered the indivisible building blocks of all geometric forms, from circles to bizarre shapes. They too are infinite, although some mathematicians aren’t convinced they exist. Langlands corralled and classified those, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He also discovered a symmetry between automorphic forms and motives, what Frenkel would later describe as the teleportation device between different worlds. Langlands saw that for every automorphic form issuing instructions, there is a motive issuing those same instructions but going about it in an entirely different way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Langlands’ conjectures work at levels beyond the immediate grasp of most mathematicians. A leading expert in the field is Jim Arthur, who developed the so-called Arthur-Selberg trace formula needed to apply functoriality. At his University of Toronto office, he spent hours trying to explain the conjectures to me, somehow showing not the slightest frustration. Eventually, he asked me, “Can you hear the shape of a drum?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://projects.thestar.com/math-the-canadian-who-reinvented-mathematics/img/langlands-drum-video-still.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Robert Langlands&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;A formula that uses spectral data from a sound wave could help understand the shape of the drum that produced it. (Ainsley Ashby-Snyder)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine standing at a spot where you hear the beat but can’t see the drum. Suddenly you have a formula that lets you use spectral data from the sound wave to figure out the exact shape of the drum that produced it. Likewise, information about the shape of the drum lets you anticipate its sound.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Langlands’ insights work that kind of magic at far more abstract levels, between representations of what are called Galois groups and Lie groups. They point the way to “all the secrets of the arithmetic world,” Arthur says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If different mathematical objects are suddenly found to share the same identity, calculations and answers from one branch of math can be used in another. “One can think about these objects in an entirely different way,” Langlands says. Theoretical dead ends are overcome, new areas of research are opened and age-old mathematical conundrums appear in a new light.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1994, functoriality was used by British mathematicians Andrew Wiles and Richard Taylor to solve a famous, 330-year-old brain teaser known as “Fermat’s Last Theorem” — an achievement celebrated in the mathematical world like a Super Bowl winning touchdown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arthur, winner of the 2015 Wolf Prize in math, suspects the conjectures will eventually help solve other fundamental problems, perhaps even the 150-year-old Reimann hypothesis on prime numbers — a whole number that can be divided evenly only by one or itself. The hypothesis gives a remarkably accurate approximation for the number of primes less than any given larger number, such as 10 to the 100th power. But it remains a conjecture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“People would sell their souls to prove this,” Arthur says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet few mathematicians applauded Langlands’ discovery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“People didn’t get it,” says Arthur, who had Langlands as his PhD thesis adviser. “It was way ahead of its time.” It took four decades for the theories to be widely recognized, although important resistance persists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I’ve had very prominent people — and you might recognize the names — leave a lecture in anger,” says Langlands, naming, when pressed, leading French mathematician Jean-Pierre Serre.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Asking academics to radically change assumptions that built their careers is rarely easy. The conjectures also require thinking on a grand scale, a challenge in a discipline fragmented with siloed specialists. “What the farmer doesn’t recognize, he won’t eat,” Langlands says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When mathematicians do take a bite, Langlands doesn’t always get his due. He suspects the Shaw Prize he shared was initially intended solely for Taylor, until someone convinced the selection committee that functoriality wasn’t Taylor’s idea. “I was a tag-along, I think. So it rather irritated me.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;André Weil, who died in 1998, used Langlands’ ideas unattributed, to the point where some number theorists began referring to them as the Weil conjecture. Langlands eventually reminded Weil of his 1967 letter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://projects.thestar.com/math-the-canadian-who-reinvented-mathematics/img/robert-langlands-letter-to-andre-weil.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Robert Langlands' letter to Andre Weil&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;The cover letter Robert Langlands wrote to André Weil, a giant in the field of number theory, on Jan. 16, 1967, in which Langlands introduced his two theories that would revolutionize mathematics. (Rich Schultz/AP)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those who embrace his theories have expanded them to include geometry and, more recently, quantum physics through Frenkel’s DARPA grant. Frenkel likes to quote Galileo to emphasize the natural bond between math and physics: “The laws of Nature are written in the language of mathematics.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spectacular discoveries in physics have been foretold by mathematics. One of history’s foremost mathematicians, the German Carl Friedrich Gauss, calculated in the early 1800s a theorem on the intrinsic curvature of space, echoed in Einstein’s theory of relativity almost a century later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the early 1960s, American physicist Murray Gell-Mann used the math principles of group theory to organize composite particles called hadrons and to predict the existence and distribution of sub-atomic quarks. Experiments several years later confirmed both the organizing pattern and the quarks. He received the Nobel Prize in physics for this work in 1969.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Mathematics allows you to see the invisible,” Frenkel says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The link currently exciting some physicists involves a “duality” found between the forces of electricity and magnetism. These forces are said to be symmetrical — they affect each other in the same way. In quantum physics, this duality is central to the quest for a theory that unites all known physical interactions in the universe, from the stars to the smallest particles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The symmetry between electricity and magnetism parallels one that exists in Langlands’ conjectures, involving mathematical groups that associate with automorphic forms. String theorist Edward Witten of the Institute for Advanced Studies describes the existence of this analog as “amazing.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We of course don’t know how the story will develop from here,” he says in an email to the Star. “Maybe the physics will shed light on number theory, maybe number theory will produce insights that will help physicists. Maybe for a long time we won’t know and the two parts of the picture will just develop mostly independently of each other.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arthur won’t be surprised if physicists eventually discover that math’s elusive motives exist as fundamental particles in the universe. Langlands dismisses that as sentimental fantasy. He’s convinced the majority of physicists, despite Witten’s giant reputation, see little value in applying his work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He would prefer that mathematicians in the Langlands Program focus on finding a complete proof of functoriality using Arthur’s trace formula. That requires command of high-level mathematics understood “only by a fairly small number of people,” Langlands told me in an email. “The result is that a good deal of the literature accessible to mathematicians as a whole is made up of a little real knowledge held together by guesswork.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back on Mount Royal, Langlands doesn’t need the sight of tombstones to remind him he won’t be the one to prove his conjectures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://projects.thestar.com/math-the-canadian-who-reinvented-mathematics/img/robert-langlands-richler-tombstone.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Langlands at the gravesite of writer Mordecai Richler&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Robert Langlands visits the grave of writer Mordecai Richler on Mount Royal in Montreal. (Sandro Contenta/Toronto Star)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I think I know what the decisive step would be, but it would take a very long time to clear out all the underbrush,” he says, estimating he would need 20 years of concentrated work. “It’s a little presumptuous to think I’ll have that much time.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, he wants to rework the way Frenkel and others have linked his conjectures to differential geometry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“If they have to use the name Langlands Program,” says the man who remodeled mathematics, “I’d just as soon like it.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2018 13:35:20 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mathgenius</dc:creator>
<og:title>The Canadian who reinvented mathematics | Toronto Star</og:title>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>http://projects.thestar.com/math-the-canadian-who-reinvented-mathematics/</og:url>
<og:description>Canadian Robert Langlands is 'like a modern-day Einstein,' who has devoted his life to the limits of pure mathematics</og:description>
<og:image>http://projects.thestar.com/math-the-canadian-who-reinvented-mathematics/img/langlands-hero-recrop.jpg</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://projects.thestar.com/math-the-canadian-who-reinvented-mathematics/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ask HN: Recommendations for Peer to Peer Frameworks?</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16785878</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16785878</guid>
<description>&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;&lt;td readability=&quot;37&quot;&gt;I'm looking for peer to peer framework recommendations to build a distributed app. In particular, a framework that supports seeds and peer discovery, message passing, maybe firewall / UPNP support, etc.
&lt;p&gt;I'm not particular about language (Java, Go, Javascript, etc), since it's for a new project. I found this thread from 2016 (https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=11145691), it had some interesting recommendations, but quite a few were out of date, and with the big push to distributed apps nowadays, I thought it might be a good time to readdress the topic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the solutions form the other thread or that I've found:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Smokesignal (Javascript / Node, not updated in &amp;gt;10 months) https://github.com/marcelklehr/smokesignal&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- ZeroTier: https://www.zerotier.com/product-netcon.shtml&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Maki: https://maki.io&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Telehash: http://telehash.org/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- A whole host of blockchain projects, Bitcoin, Ethereum, HyperLedger, Scorex (Scala blockchain)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin is an interesting option, it certainly has a large user base and is well tested and secure code, but forking it has it's own set of issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2018 12:49:54 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>zilchers</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16785878</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The enemy within: Gut bacteria drive autoimmune disease</title>
<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2018/03/180308143102.htm</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2018/03/180308143102.htm</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;first&quot;&gt;Bacteria found in the small intestines of mice and humans can travel to other organs and trigger an autoimmune response, according to a new Yale study. The researchers also found that the autoimmune reaction can be suppressed with an antibiotic or vaccine designed to target the bacteria, they said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;text&quot; readability=&quot;82&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The findings, published in &lt;em&gt;Science&lt;/em&gt;, suggest promising new approaches for treating chronic autoimmune conditions, including systemic lupus and autoimmune liver disease, the researchers said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gut bacteria have been linked to a range of diseases, including autoimmune conditions characterized by immune system attack of healthy tissue. To shed light on this link, a Yale research team focused on Enterococcus gallinarum, a bacterium they discovered is able to spontaneously &quot;translocate&quot; outside of the gut to lymph nodes, the liver, and spleen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In models of genetically susceptible mice, the researchers observed that in tissues outside the gut, &lt;em&gt;E. gallinarum&lt;/em&gt; initiated the production of auto-antibodies and inflammation -- hallmarks of the autoimmune response. They confirmed the same mechanism of inflammation in cultured liver cells of healthy people, and the presence of this bacterium in livers of patients with autoimmune disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through further experiments, the research team found that they could suppress autoimmunity in mice with an antibiotic or a vaccine aimed at &lt;em&gt;E. gallinarum&lt;/em&gt;. With either approach, the researchers were able to suppress growth of the bacterium in the tissues and blunt its effects on the immune system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;When we blocked the pathway leading to inflammation, we could reverse the effect of this bug on autoimmunity,&quot; said senior author Martin Kriegel, M.D.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;The vaccine against &lt;em&gt;E. gallinarum&lt;/em&gt; was a specific approach, as vaccinations against other bacteria we investigated did not prevent mortality and autoimmunity,&quot; he noted. The vaccine was delivered through injection in muscle to avoid targeting other bacteria that reside in the gut.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Kriegel and his colleagues plan further research on E. gallinarum and its mechanisms, the findings have relevance for systemic lupus and autoimmune liver disease, they said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Treatment with an antibiotic and other approaches such as vaccination are promising ways to improve the lives of patients with autoimmune disease,&quot; he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;story_source&quot; readability=&quot;27.133333333333&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Story Source:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.yale.edu/2018/03/08/enemy-within-gut-bacteria-drive-autoimmune-disease&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Materials&lt;/a&gt; provided by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.yale.edu&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yale University&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Original written by Ziba Kashef. &lt;em&gt;Note: Content may be edited for style and length.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2018 11:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>montrose</dc:creator>
<og:title>The enemy within: Gut bacteria drive autoimmune disease</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2018/03/180308143102.htm</og:url>
<og:image>/images/2018/03/180308143102_1_540x360.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>Bacteria found in the small intestines of mice and humans can travel to other organs and trigger an autoimmune response, according to a new study. The researchers also found that the autoimmune reaction can be suppressed with an antibiotic or vaccine designed to target the bacteria, they said.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2018/03/180308143102.htm</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Middle-Class Families Increasingly Look to Community Colleges</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/04/05/education/learning/community-colleges-middle-class-families.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2018/04/05/education/learning/community-colleges-middle-class-families.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;281&quot; data-total-count=&quot;1722&quot; id=&quot;story-continues-2&quot;&gt;“This is about social norms,” said Sara Goldrick-Rab, a professor of higher education policy and sociology at Temple University in Philadelphia. “More middle-class parents are saying, I’m not succumbing to the idea that the only acceptable education is an expensive one.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4 class=&quot;story-subheading story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;16&quot; data-total-count=&quot;1738&quot;&gt;Free Initiatives&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;193&quot; data-total-count=&quot;1931&quot;&gt;In recent years, Pasadena City College has had a 320 percent increase in students whose parents make more than $100,000 a year, to 828 students last year from 197 in 2007. And it’s not alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;541&quot; data-total-count=&quot;2472&quot;&gt;A 2017 study that looked at tax records and college attendance data found that hundreds of two-year colleges are now magnets for well-off students, with many — like Williston State College in North Dakota, and Colorado Northwestern Community College in Rangely — having clocked notable increases. More recently, colleges like Northern Virginia Community College have reported their own increases. The number of first-time students there whose family income is $60,000 or above rose 69 percent, to 6,104 this past year from 3,610 in 2010.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;story-ad-1&quot; class=&quot;story-ad ad ad-placeholder nocontent robots-nocontent&quot;&gt;

&lt;a class=&quot;visually-hidden skip-to-text-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/04/05/education/learning/community-colleges-middle-class-families.html#story-continues-3&quot;&gt;Continue reading the main story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;80&quot; data-total-count=&quot;2552&quot; id=&quot;story-continues-3&quot;&gt;[&lt;strong&gt;READ MORE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/04/05/education/learning/colleges-adapt-changing-students.html&quot;&gt;With Changing Students and Times, Colleges Are Going Back to School&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;474&quot; data-total-count=&quot;3026&quot;&gt;Academics who study college pricing say they think the phenomenon is likely to take off further as more cities, states and institutions start free programs like the one Gov. Jerry Brown of California &lt;a href=&quot;https://leginfo.legislature.ca.gov/faces/billTextClient.xhtml?bill_id=201720180AB19&quot;&gt;signed into law&lt;/a&gt; in October. Already, some free community college initiatives have become magnets for middle-class students. Oregon is making changes to its program, &lt;a href=&quot;https://oregonstudentaid.gov/oregon-promise.aspx&quot;&gt;Oregon Promise&lt;/a&gt;. But last school year, the majority of the $11.8 million in aid went to upper-income families.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;131&quot; data-total-count=&quot;3157&quot;&gt;Ms. Shahverdian is taking advantage of a free-college program Pasadena began, as it waits for the state to fund Mr. Brown’s plan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;239&quot; data-total-count=&quot;3396&quot;&gt;And this fall, Princeton will join a growing group of selective colleges that are focusing more on transfer students. The initiative is directed at attracting more low-income students, but middle-class ones are also likely to see benefits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;166&quot; data-total-count=&quot;3562&quot;&gt;To lure students, some two-year colleges are starting to look a lot like their four-year peers, offering study abroad programs, modern dorms and renovated cafeterias.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;visually-hidden&quot;&gt;Photo&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/04/08/education/learning/08TRANSFER-1/08TRANSFER-1-master675.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;media-viewer-candidate&quot; data-mediaviewer-src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/04/08/education/learning/08TRANSFER-1/08TRANSFER-1-superJumbo.jpg&quot; data-mediaviewer-caption=&quot;Pasadena City College, a two-year public institution, has a 53-acre campus.&quot; data-mediaviewer-credit=&quot;Emily Berl for The New York Times&quot; itemprop=&quot;url&quot; itemid=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/04/08/education/learning/08TRANSFER-1/08TRANSFER-1-master675.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption-text&quot;&gt;Pasadena City College, a two-year public institution, has a 53-acre campus.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;visually-hidden&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt; Emily Berl for The New York Times&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;415&quot; data-total-count=&quot;3977&quot;&gt;“We don’t have lazy rivers and climbing walls,” said Scott Ralls, the president of Northern Virginia Community College, which consists of six campuses outside of Washington that have become magnets for the area’s middle-class students. But the college does have an honors program, a hockey team and a new 80,000-square-foot fine arts center, with a campus bookstore, a fitness center and a multipurpose gym.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;201&quot; data-total-count=&quot;4178&quot;&gt;As for Pasadena, the outdoor Olympic-size swimming pool is hard to miss, along with sign-up sheets for tennis and fencing, and coding clubs. Nearby, students can grab coffee at the campus espresso bar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;354&quot; data-total-count=&quot;4532&quot;&gt;“We want to serve everyone in this community,” said the school’s superintendent-president, Rajen Vurdien. That includes a club that supports students who have recently been released from prison, a club to aid recently arrived immigrants and a tutoring collective. There are signs for the campus food pantry and pamphlets for the free dental clinic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;story-subheading story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;12&quot; data-total-count=&quot;4544&quot;&gt;Melting Pots&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;351&quot; data-total-count=&quot;4895&quot;&gt;Ariana Woodworth, a first-year student who graduated last year from South Pasadena High School and wants to transfer to the Parsons School of Design in Manhattan when she finishes at Pasadena City College, says being thrown into the melting pot that is community college has been an important plus. Her high school was mostly middle class and wealthy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;story-ad-2&quot; class=&quot;story-ad ad ad-placeholder nocontent robots-nocontent&quot;&gt;

&lt;a class=&quot;visually-hidden skip-to-text-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/04/05/education/learning/community-colleges-middle-class-families.html#story-continues-4&quot;&gt;Continue reading the main story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;127&quot; data-total-count=&quot;5022&quot; id=&quot;story-continues-4&quot;&gt;Still, going 15 minutes from home for college, while many of her classmates were heading across the country, “took a toll.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;29&quot; data-total-count=&quot;5051&quot;&gt;“It was rough,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;175&quot; data-total-count=&quot;5226&quot;&gt;And not everyone thought it was a great idea. Ms. Shahverdian said one classmate at La Cañada told her: “Oh, that’s good for you. But I would never be able to do that.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;interactive-headline&quot;&gt;Learning: A Special Section&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;interactive-graphic&quot; readability=&quot;19.086294416244&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Welcome to the new Learning section — a deep dive into the joys, excitement, challenges and opportunities in the world of education and learning. This is the first of four refreshed and redesigned sections we will publish this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Drawing on the commitment to the subject and the expertise across The New York Times, we want Learning to be a place where educators, students and parents can join a vigorous conversation around the best ways to educate people, whether children or adults. (You can reach us at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:learningsection@nytimes.com&quot;&gt;learningsection@nytimes.com&lt;/a&gt; with comments and ideas.) - &lt;em&gt;Jane Bornemeier, Editor&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;268&quot; data-total-count=&quot;5494&quot;&gt;Nshan Boiadjian, 20, is expected to graduate in May from Valencia College in Orlando, Fla., with his associate degree in general studies. “A lot of people think if you don’t go to a big, hot-shot university, your education is garbage,” he said. “It’s not.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;253&quot; data-total-count=&quot;5747&quot;&gt;A self-proclaimed “talker,” Mr. Boiadjian said he benefited from the small class sizes common at Valencia and the engaged teachers whose focus was their work in the classroom, not their research. Few community college professors do outside research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;164&quot; data-total-count=&quot;5911&quot;&gt;He recalls spending hours after one mythology class debating the origins of Buddhism with a professor and several other energized students. “We went on and on.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;153&quot; data-total-count=&quot;6064&quot;&gt;Valencia has recently become one of a growing number of community colleges to administer a bachelor’s degree, and Mr. Boiadjian has decided to stay on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;352&quot; data-total-count=&quot;6416&quot;&gt;Community colleges face significant graduation challenges, though. Nationally, just 6 percent of community college students get a bachelor’s degree within five years, according to data from 2004 through 2008 from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://nces.ed.gov/&quot;&gt;National Center for Education S&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://nces.ed.gov/&quot;&gt;tatistics&lt;/a&gt;. For students whose parents have degrees, the outcomes are slightly better, but not by much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;343&quot; data-total-count=&quot;6759&quot;&gt;Mia Fleming, an international business major at Pepperdine University, thinks she knows why. During her two years at Merced College, a 15,000-student commuter college north of Fresno, she saw how a lean roster of guidance counselors made it challenging to stay focused and motivated. She said she needed to “really seek out” good teachers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;visually-hidden&quot;&gt;Photo&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/04/08/education/learning/08TRANSFER-2/08TRANSFER-2-blog427.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;media-viewer-candidate&quot; data-mediaviewer-src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/04/08/education/learning/08TRANSFER-2/08TRANSFER-2-superJumbo.jpg&quot; data-mediaviewer-caption=&quot;Ariana Woodworth is a first-year student at Pasadena City College and wants to transfer to the Parsons School of Design in Manhattan.&quot; data-mediaviewer-credit=&quot;Emily Berl for The New York Times&quot; itemprop=&quot;url&quot; itemid=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/04/08/education/learning/08TRANSFER-2/08TRANSFER-2-blog427.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption-text&quot;&gt;Ariana Woodworth is a first-year student at Pasadena City College and wants to transfer to the Parsons School of Design in Manhattan.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;visually-hidden&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt; Emily Berl for The New York Times&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;447&quot; data-total-count=&quot;7206&quot;&gt;Nicole Figueroa is in her third year at Pasadena as a communication studies major, and she hopes to become the first person in her family to get a four-year degree. She has no issues with attending a community college that serves middle-class students, as long as administrators do not lose sight of their work with low-income ones. The school offers an abundance of key services, she said, but needs to get better at “putting them out there.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;story-ad-3&quot; class=&quot;story-ad ad ad-placeholder nocontent robots-nocontent&quot;&gt;

&lt;a class=&quot;visually-hidden skip-to-text-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/04/05/education/learning/community-colleges-middle-class-families.html#story-continues-5&quot;&gt;Continue reading the main story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;story-subheading story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;21&quot; data-total-count=&quot;7227&quot;&gt;Cost-Benefit Analysis&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;133&quot; data-total-count=&quot;7360&quot; id=&quot;story-continues-5&quot;&gt;Middle-class parents who send their children to community colleges say it can send a powerful message to them about personal finance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;427&quot; data-total-count=&quot;7787&quot;&gt;John Riordan is a management consultant from a Washington suburb, with Northern Virginia Community College down the road from his house. One of his sons is there now and has his sights on a degree from the University of Virginia. Mr. Riordan’s daughter will begin community college in the fall. He says it is valid to debate the merits of the University of Virginia for two or four years and suspects that four may be better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;69&quot; data-total-count=&quot;7856&quot;&gt;“But do a cost-benefit analysis. Is it 20 times better?” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;194&quot; data-total-count=&quot;8050&quot;&gt;Lynn O’Shaughnessy, the author of “The College Solution: A Guide for Everyone Looking for the Right School at the Right Price,” cautions that saving money can come with some unknown costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;298&quot; data-total-count=&quot;8348&quot;&gt;While many community colleges have clearly marked pathways to graduation and transfer agreements with highly prestigious four-year schools, not all do. And some students discover that the two years of classes they took “saving money” need to be retaken when they transfer to a four-year school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;350&quot; data-total-count=&quot;8698&quot;&gt;Byria Hamblin, a graduate of Lone Star College, near Houston, did not let that happen during her two years there, and she is a now a political science major at Tulane University in New Orleans. Ms. Hamblin, an award-winning debater in high school, said she had always thought she would go straight to a four-year school. But the prices blew her away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;360&quot; data-total-count=&quot;9058&quot;&gt;While at Lone Star, she was agitated by Instagram photos of her high school classmates. One friend went to Columbia University and spent a lot of time “living an urban lifestyle,” and another went to George Washington University in Washington, where he explored the capital. When classmates were home for breaks, they were not always kind about her choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;221&quot; data-total-count=&quot;9279&quot;&gt;But once Ms. Hamblin got to Tulane, which costs more than $50,000 a year, the tables turned. When she tells her new friends there where she spent her first two years, she often hears, “I really should have done that.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;visually-hidden skip-to-text-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/04/05/education/learning/community-colleges-middle-class-families.html#whats-next&quot;&gt;Continue reading the main story&lt;/a&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2018 11:09:58 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ColMustang</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/04/05/education/learning/community-colleges-middle-class-families.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Middle-Class Families Increasingly Look to Community Colleges</og:title>
<og:description>With college prices in the hundreds of thousands of dollars, more middle-class families are looking for ways to spend less for quality education.</og:description>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/04/08/education/learning/08transfer-4/08transfer-4-facebookJumbo-v3.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/04/05/education/learning/community-colleges-middle-class-families.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>