<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Indian police open case against hundreds in Kashmir for using VPN</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/18/indian-police-open-case-against-hundreds-in-kashmir-for-using-vpn/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/18/indian-police-open-case-against-hundreds-in-kashmir-for-using-vpn/</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;speakable-summary&quot;&gt;Local authorities in India-controlled Kashmir have opened a case against hundreds of people who used virtual private networks (VPNs) to circumvent a social media ban in the disputed Himalayan region in a move that has been denounced by human rights and privacy activists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tahir Ashraf, who heads the police cyber division in Srinagar, said on Tuesday that the authority had identified and was probing hundreds of suspected users who he alleged misused social media to promote “unlawful activities and secessionist ideology.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Monday, the police said they had also seized “a lot of incriminating material” under the Unlawful Activities Prevention Act (UAPA), the nation’s principal counter-terrorism law. Those found guilty could be jailed up to seven years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Taking a serious note of misuse of social media, there have been continuous reports of misuse of social media sites by the miscreants to propagate the secessionist ideology and to promote unlawful activities,” the region’s police said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The move comes weeks after the Indian government restored access to several hundred websites, including some shopping websites such as Amazon India and Flipkart and select news outlets. Facebook, Twitter and other social media services remain blocked, and mobile data speeds remain capped at 2G speeds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One analysis found that 126 of 301 websites that had been unblocked were only &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.medianama.com/2020/01/223-analysis-of-whitelisted-urls-in-jammu-and-kashmir-how-usable-are-they/&quot;&gt;usable to “some degree.”&lt;/a&gt; To bypass the censorship on social media and access news websites, many in the disputed region, home to more than 7 million people, &lt;a href=&quot;https://thewire.in/tech/kashmir-internet-vpn-firewall&quot;&gt;began using VPN services&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;India &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2019/12/19/india-gets-more-aggressive-with-internet-shutdowns-to-curb-protests/&quot;&gt;banned internet access in Jammu and Kashmir in early August last year&lt;/a&gt; after New Delhi revoked Kashmir’s semi-autonomous status. The Indian government said the move was justified to maintain calm in the region — months later India’s apex court criticized the government for &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/10/internet-shutdown-supreme-court-india-kashmir/&quot;&gt;imposing a blanket internet ban for an indefinite period&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The Government of India has almost total control over what information is coming out of the region,” said Avinash Kumar, executive director of human rights campaign group Amnesty International India.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“While the Government has a duty and responsibility to maintain law and order in the state, filing cases under counter-terrorism laws such as UAPA over vague and generic allegations and blocking social media sites – is not the solution. The Indian government needs to put humanity first and let the people of Kashmir speak,” he urged the government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mishi Choudhary, executive director of New Delhi-based Software Law and Freedom Centre, said that the authority did not need to chase people who are using VPNs, and should restore internet access like any other democratic society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Any alleged rumors can be addressed by putting out accurate and more information through the same social media platforms. Content-based restrictions on speech can only be allowed within the restrictions established by the Constitution and not in an ad hoc manner,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 21:25:20 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jmsflknr</dc:creator>
<og:title>Indian police open case against hundreds in Kashmir for using VPN – TechCrunch</og:title>
<og:description>Local authorities in India-controlled Kashmir have opened a case against hundreds of people who used virtual private networks (VPNs) to circumvent a social media ban in the disputed Himalayan region in a move that has been denounced by human rights and privacy activists. Tahir Ashraf, who heads the…</og:description>
<og:image>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/GettyImages-1175975278.jpg?w=599</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2020/02/18/indian-police-open-case-against-hundreds-in-kashmir-for-using-vpn/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/18/indian-police-open-case-against-hundreds-in-kashmir-for-using-vpn/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Help the Graphics team track down an interesting WebRender bug</title>
<link>https://mozillagfx.wordpress.com/2020/02/18/challenge-snitch-on-the-glitch-help-the-graphics-team-track-down-an-interesting-webrender-bug/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://mozillagfx.wordpress.com/2020/02/18/challenge-snitch-on-the-glitch-help-the-graphics-team-track-down-an-interesting-webrender-bug/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;For the past little while, we have been tracking some interesting WebRender bugs that people are reporting in release. Despite best efforts, we have been unable to determine clear steps to reproduce these issues and have been unable to find a fix for them. Today we are announcing a special challenge to the community – help us track down steps to reproduce (a.k.a STR) for this bug and you will win some special, limited edition Firefox Graphics team swag! Read on for more details if you are interested in participating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What we know so far about the bug&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Late last year we started seeing reports of random UI glitching bugs that people were seeing in release. You can check out some of the reports on &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1604492&quot;&gt;Bugzilla&lt;/a&gt;. Here is what we know so far about this bug:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;At seemingly random intervals, either two things seem to happen:
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-image&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;1308&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://mozillagfx.wordpress.com/screen-shot-glitch/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://mozillagfx.files.wordpress.com/2020/02/screen-shot-glitch.jpg&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;3838,2160&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;screen-shot-glitch&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://mozillagfx.files.wordpress.com/2020/02/screen-shot-glitch.jpg?w=300&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://mozillagfx.files.wordpress.com/2020/02/screen-shot-glitch.jpg?w=1024&quot; src=&quot;https://mozillagfx.files.wordpress.com/2020/02/screen-shot-glitch.jpg?w=1024&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-1308&quot; width=&quot;570&quot; height=&quot;321&quot; srcset=&quot;https://mozillagfx.files.wordpress.com/2020/02/screen-shot-glitch.jpg?w=1024 1024w, https://mozillagfx.files.wordpress.com/2020/02/screen-shot-glitch.jpg?w=570 570w, https://mozillagfx.files.wordpress.com/2020/02/screen-shot-glitch.jpg?w=1140 1140w, https://mozillagfx.files.wordpress.com/2020/02/screen-shot-glitch.jpg?w=150 150w, https://mozillagfx.files.wordpress.com/2020/02/screen-shot-glitch.jpg?w=300 300w, https://mozillagfx.files.wordpress.com/2020/02/screen-shot-glitch.jpg?w=768 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 570px) 100vw, 570px&quot;/&gt;Glitches!&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-image&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;1310&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://mozillagfx.wordpress.com/attachment/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://mozillagfx.files.wordpress.com/2020/02/attachment.png&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1915,1035&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;attachment&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://mozillagfx.files.wordpress.com/2020/02/attachment.png?w=300&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://mozillagfx.files.wordpress.com/2020/02/attachment.png?w=1024&quot; src=&quot;https://mozillagfx.files.wordpress.com/2020/02/attachment.png?w=1024&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-1310&quot; width=&quot;570&quot; height=&quot;307&quot; srcset=&quot;https://mozillagfx.files.wordpress.com/2020/02/attachment.png?w=1024 1024w, https://mozillagfx.files.wordpress.com/2020/02/attachment.png?w=568 568w, https://mozillagfx.files.wordpress.com/2020/02/attachment.png?w=1136 1136w, https://mozillagfx.files.wordpress.com/2020/02/attachment.png?w=150 150w, https://mozillagfx.files.wordpress.com/2020/02/attachment.png?w=300 300w, https://mozillagfx.files.wordpress.com/2020/02/attachment.png?w=768 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 570px) 100vw, 570px&quot;/&gt;Black boxes!&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The majority of the reports we have seen so far have come from people using NVIDIA graphics cards, although we have seen reports come in of this happening on &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1604931&quot;&gt;Intel&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1605196&quot;&gt;AMD&lt;/a&gt; as well. That could be though because the majority of the people we have officially shipped WR to in release are on NVIDIA cards.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There doesn’t seem to be one clear driver version correlated to this bug, so we are not sure if it is a driver bug.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All reporters so far have been using Windows 10&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No one who has reported the bug thus far has been able to determine clear and consistent STR, and no one on the Graphics team has found a way to reproduce it either. We all use WebRender daily and none of us have encountered the bug.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How can you help?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without having a way to reliably reproduce this bug, we are at a loss on how to solve it. So we decided to hold a challenge to engage the community further to help us understand this bug better. If you are interested in helping us get to the root of this tricky bug, please do the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Download &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/en-CA/firefox/channel/desktop/&quot;&gt;Firefox Nightly&lt;/a&gt; (if you don’t already use it)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ideally you are using Windows 10 (but if you see this bug on other platforms, we are interested in hearing about it!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ensure WebRender is enabled
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Go to about:config and set gfx.webrender.all to true, then restart your browser&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you encounter the bug, help us by &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/enter_bug.cgi?product=Core&amp;amp;component=Graphics%3A+WebRender&quot;&gt;filing a bug in Bugzilla&lt;/a&gt; with the following details:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;What website are you on when the bug happens?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does it seem to happen when specific actions are taken?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How frequently does the bug happen and can you ‘make’ it happen?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Attach the contents of your about:support as a text file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The main thing we really need are consistent steps that result in the bug showing up. We will send some limited edition Graphics swag to the first 3 bug reporters who can give us consistent STR!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Even if you can’t easily find STR, we are still interested in hearing about whether you see this bug!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Challenge guidelines&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The winners of this challenge will be chosen based on the following criteria:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The bug report contains clear and repeatable steps to make the bug happen
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;This can include things like having a specific hardware configuration, using certain add ons and browsing certain sites – literally anything as long as it can reliably and consistently cause the bug to appear&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BONUS: A member of the Graphics team can follow your steps and can also make the bug appear&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We will choose &lt;strong&gt;the first 3 reporters who can meet this criteria&lt;/strong&gt; (we say 3 because it is possible there is more than one bug and more than one way to reproduce it)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Winners will receive special limited edition Graphics Team swag! (t-shirt and stickers)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Update: we have created the channel &lt;a href=&quot;https://matrix.to/#/!qaAtjMWizEgMcVSbNH:mozilla.org?via=mozilla.org&amp;amp;via=matrix.org&amp;amp;via=mayeul.net&quot;&gt;#gfx-wr-glitch:mozilla.org&lt;/a&gt; on Matrix so you can ask questions/chat with us there. For more info about how to joing Matrix, check out: &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.mozilla.org/Matrix&quot;&gt;https://wiki.mozilla.org/Matrix&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;jp-post-flair&quot; class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-like-enabled sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;robots-nocontent sd-block sd-social sd-social-icon-text sd-sharing&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Share this:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-block sd-like jetpack-likes-widget-wrapper jetpack-likes-widget-unloaded&quot; id=&quot;like-post-wrapper-40065927-1303-5e4c888d67d13&quot; data-src=&quot;//widgets.wp.com/likes/index.html?ver=20190321#blog_id=40065927&amp;amp;post_id=1303&amp;amp;origin=mozillagfx.wordpress.com&amp;amp;obj_id=40065927-1303-5e4c888d67d13&quot; data-name=&quot;like-post-frame-40065927-1303-5e4c888d67d13&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Like this:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;likes-widget-placeholder post-likes-widget-placeholder&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;button&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Like&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;loading&quot;&gt;Loading...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 19:42:20 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Santosh83</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Challenge: Snitch on the glitch! Help the Graphics team track down an interesting WebRender bug…</og:title>
<og:url>https://mozillagfx.wordpress.com/2020/02/18/challenge-snitch-on-the-glitch-help-the-graphics-team-track-down-an-interesting-webrender-bug/</og:url>
<og:description>For the past little while, we have been tracking some interesting WebRender bugs that people are reporting in release. Despite best efforts, we have been unable to determine clear steps to reproduc…</og:description>
<og:image>https://mozillagfx.files.wordpress.com/2020/02/attachment.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://mozillagfx.wordpress.com/2020/02/18/challenge-snitch-on-the-glitch-help-the-graphics-team-track-down-an-interesting-webrender-bug/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>MVC is dead, it&amp;#039;s time to MOVE on (2012)</title>
<link>https://cirw.in/blog/time-to-move-on</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://cirw.in/blog/time-to-move-on</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;MVC is a phenomenal idea. You have models, which are nice self-contained bits of state, views which are nice self-contained bits of UI, and controllers which are nice self-contained bits of …&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m certainly not the first person to notice this, but the problem with MVC as given is that you end up stuffing too much code into your controllers, because you don’t know where else to put it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To fix this I’ve been using a new pattern: &lt;strong&gt;MOVE&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;M&lt;/strong&gt;odels, &lt;strong&gt;O&lt;/strong&gt;perations, &lt;strong&gt;V&lt;/strong&gt;iews, and &lt;strong&gt;E&lt;/strong&gt;vents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;a href=&quot;https://cirw.in/images/move.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Architecture of a MOVE app&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cirw.in/images/move.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Architecture of a MOVE app&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll define the details in a minute, but this diagram shows the basic structure of a MOVE application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Models encapsulate everything that your application knows.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Operations encapsulate everything that your application does.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Views mediate between your application and the user.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Events are used to join all these components together safely.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;In order to avoid spaghetti code, it’s also worth noting that there are recommendations for what objects of each type are allowed to do. I’ve represented these as arrows on the diagram. For example, views are allowed to listen to events emitted by models, and operations are allowed to change models, but models should not refer to either views or operations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The archetypal model is a “user” object. It has at the very least an email address, and probably also a name and a phone number.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a MOVE application models only wrap knowledge. That means that, in addition to getters and setters, they might contain functions that let you check “is this the user’s password?”, but they don’t contain functions that let you save them to a database or upload them to an external API. That would be the job of an operation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A common operation for applications is logging a user in. It’s actually two sub-operations composed together: first get the email address and password from the user, second load the “user” model from the database and check whether the password matches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Operations are the doers of the MOVE world. They are responsible for making changes to your models, for showing the right views at the right time, and for responding to events triggered by user interactions. In a well factored application, each sub-operation can be run independently of its parent; which is why in the diagram events flow upwards, and changes are pushed downwards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What’s exciting about using operations in this way is that your entire application can itself be treated as an operation that starts when the program boots. It spawns as many sub-operations as it needs, where each concurrently existing sub-operation is run in parallel, and exits the program when they are all complete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The login screen is a view which is responsible for showing a few text boxes to the user. When the user clicks the “login” button the view will yield a “loginAttempt” event which contains the username and password that the user typed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything the user can see or interact with should be powered by a view. They not only display the state of your application in an understandable way, but also simplify the stream of incoming user interactions into meaningful events. Importantly views don’t change models directly, they simply emit events to operations, and wait for changes by listening to events emitted by the models.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The “loginAttempt” event is emitted by the view when the user clicks login. Additionally, when the login operation completes, the “currentUser” model will emit an event to notify your application that it has changed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Listening on events is what gives MOVE (and MVC) the inversion of control that you need to allow models to update views without the models being directly aware of which views they are updating. This is a powerful abstraction technique, allowing components to be coupled together without interfering with each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t wish to be misunderstood as implying that MVC is bad; it truly has been an incredibly successful way to structure large applications for the last few decades. Since it was invented however, new programming techniques have become popular. Without closures (or anonymous blocks) event binding can be very tedious; and without deferrables (also known as deferreds or promises) the idea of treating individual operations as objects in their own right doesn’t make much sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To re-iterate: MVC is awesome, but it’s designed with decades old technologies. MOVE is just a update to make better use of the new tools we have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside&gt;P.S. I'm not the only one beginning to think this way either, if you like the idea of MOVE you should check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bitlove/objectify&quot;&gt;objectify&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://collectiveidea.com/blog/archives/2012/06/28/wheres-your-business-logic/&quot;&gt;interactions&lt;/a&gt; which try to add some of the benefits of MOVE to existing MVC applications. Please &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/conradirwin&quot;&gt;let me know&lt;/a&gt; if you have other links that should be here!&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;aside&gt;P.P.S This blog post has been translated into Japanese no fewer than twice: &lt;a href=&quot;http://d.hatena.ne.jp/nowokay/20120704#c&quot;&gt;d.hatena.ne.jp&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.neo.jp/dnblog/index.php?module=Blog&amp;amp;blog=pg&amp;amp;action=CommentPostDo&amp;amp;entry_id=3442&quot;&gt;blog.neo.jp&lt;/a&gt;, and also into &lt;a href=&quot;http://habrahabr.ru/post/147038/&quot;&gt;Russian&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://woonohyo.tistory.com/39&quot;&gt;Korean&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alanchavez.com/mvc-esta-muerto-es-tiempo-de-darle-paso-a-una-alternativa-move/&quot;&gt;Spanish&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks!&lt;/aside&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 16:57:50 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>pcr910303</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://cirw.in/blog/time-to-move-on</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Computer vision basics in Excel, using just formulas</title>
<link>https://github.com/amzn/computer-vision-basics-in-microsoft-excel</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/amzn/computer-vision-basics-in-microsoft-excel</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;By &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/alokgovil/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Alok Govil&lt;/a&gt;, Principal Engineer, Amazon&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Collaborator: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/venkataramanansubramanian/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Venkataramanan Subramanian&lt;/a&gt;, Principal Engineer, Amazon&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Computer Vision is often seen by software developers and others as a hard field to get into. In this article, we'll learn Computer Vision from basics using sample algorithms implemented within Microsoft Excel, using a series of one-liner Excel formulas. We'll use a surprise trick that helps us implement and visualize algorithms like Face Detection, Hough Transform, etc., within Excel, with no dependence on any script or a third-party plugin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/amzn/computer-vision-basics-in-microsoft-excel/blob/master/img/Excel-Trick.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/amzn/computer-vision-basics-in-microsoft-excel/raw/master/img/Excel-Trick.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Microsoft Excel Trick for Spreadsheet Images&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Figure 1: Outline of the steps to visualize a spreadsheet as an image. The spreadsheet, and thereby the image, is then manipulated step by step using formulas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Selected Feedback Quotes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Its amazing to see an image show up on the Excel sheet as you zoom out and numbers appear as you zoom back in.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Very cool to see that with 'simple' Excel formulas you can do some real computer vision.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;... never thought you can explain CV through simple Excel formulas and transformations. Hats-off :)&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;... used Excel to explain the core concepts and algorithms so clear that I feel I could start working with it right now! ...&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;I've been wanting to learn how CV works for a while, and this was probably the best transition from data to visuals I've ever seen.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Just incredible build up from small to great one step at a time.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Preview of what we will achieve&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will see how to detect a face using a toy example: (Below are screenshots of Excel shreadsheets.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/amzn/computer-vision-basics-in-microsoft-excel/blob/master/img/Face-Detection.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/amzn/computer-vision-basics-in-microsoft-excel/raw/master/img/Face-Detection.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Face Detection in Microsoft Excel&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will also see how to find edges and lines:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/amzn/computer-vision-basics-in-microsoft-excel/blob/master/img/Edges.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/amzn/computer-vision-basics-in-microsoft-excel/raw/master/img/Edges.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Edge Detection in Microsoft Excel&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/amzn/computer-vision-basics-in-microsoft-excel/blob/master/img/Lines.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/amzn/computer-vision-basics-in-microsoft-excel/raw/master/img/Lines.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Lines in Microsoft Excel&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Expectations from the audience&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No prior background in Computer Vision should be needed to follow the material. It is assumed that the audience knows Microsoft Excel basics and can read its documentation, or search online for interpreting the formulas used. &lt;a href=&quot;https://exceljet.net/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Exceljet&lt;/a&gt; is a great resource for the latter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some mathematical understanding would be needed: Those who won't know what weighted average is won't be able to follow much. Understanding of partial derivatives would be helpful but not required. Most complex mathematical concept used is &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eigenvalues_and_eigenvectors&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;eigenvalues&lt;/a&gt;, but again the readers should be able to follow even if they do not know or remember the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Instructions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The crux of the material is in the Excel files (*.xlsx) available below for downloading. These are self-explanatory with notes inserted within. Please follow the sheets step-by-step. You may need to change zoom levels as per your monitor resolution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/amzn/computer-vision-basics-in-microsoft-excel/blob/master/img/Hough-Transform-50p.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/amzn/computer-vision-basics-in-microsoft-excel/raw/master/img/Hough-Transform-50p.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot of an Excel file&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Software requirements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The work was created using Excel 2016 on Windows; it should however open in other versions of Excel (tested with Excel 2007 on Windows, and Excel for Mac).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the files open in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.documentfoundation.org/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;LibreOffice&lt;/a&gt; (tested in version 6.4.0.3 (x64)), it is slow to the level of being unusable. We have not tested in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openoffice.org/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Apache OpenOffice&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Relevant Excel Formula Options&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before opening the Excel file(s), change Excel Formula Calculation to &quot;Manual&quot; since some calculations (Hough Transform specifically) are time-consuming (say an hour). Then trigger recalculation manually as per need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/amzn/computer-vision-basics-in-microsoft-excel/blob/master/img/Excel-Formulas-Change-to-Manual.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/amzn/computer-vision-basics-in-microsoft-excel/raw/master/img/Excel-Formulas-Change-to-Manual.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Excel Formulas, Change to Manual&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, uncheck &quot;Recalculate workbook before saving&quot;, else Excel will recalculate all the formulas every time you save the files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/amzn/computer-vision-basics-in-microsoft-excel/blob/master/img/Dont-Recalculate-Workbook-before-Saving.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/amzn/computer-vision-basics-in-microsoft-excel/raw/master/img/Dont-Recalculate-Workbook-before-Saving.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Don't Recalculate Workbook before Saving&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: Be sure to revert these settings once you are done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those familiar with R1C1 formula reference style in Excel, or those adventurous, should try switching to it by looking in Excel options and turning it on. See the screenshot below and check the box to enable it. This changes the formulas from &quot;D5&quot; type format to a relative style like &quot;R[-1]C[2]&quot; (absolute references also allowed as &quot;R4C5&quot; for example), bringing it closer to programming languages and aiding understanding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/amzn/computer-vision-basics-in-microsoft-excel/blob/master/img/Excel-R1C1-Formula-Reference-Style.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/amzn/computer-vision-basics-in-microsoft-excel/raw/master/img/Excel-R1C1-Formula-Reference-Style.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Excel R1C1 Formula Reference Style&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Downloads&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The full Excel file is more than 50 MB in size. The same content is also available in smaller parts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following can be downloaded by right-clicking. Alternatively, on left-clicking, Github will take you to preview page from where the raw *.xlsx files can be downloaded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Questions and Answers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of the following would make sense only after going through the Excel files above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Q1: How was the image data imported into Excel?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can follow this blog: &lt;a href=&quot;https://alvinalexander.com/blog/post/java/getting-rgb-values-for-each-pixel-in-image-using-java-bufferedi&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://alvinalexander.com/blog/post/java/getting-rgb-values-for-each-pixel-in-image-using-java-bufferedi&lt;/a&gt; and output data into a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Comma-separated_values&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;CSV file&lt;/a&gt; which Excel readily opens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are two more images imported into Excel, ready for use: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/amzn/computer-vision-basics-in-microsoft-excel/blob/master/Image-Einstein.xlsx&quot;&gt;Einstein&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/amzn/computer-vision-basics-in-microsoft-excel/blob/master/Image-Pillars.xlsx&quot;&gt;Pillars&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that the Face Detection parameters used in the Excel files would likely fail to detect Einstein's face as the Haar-like features were fine-tuned by hand for detecting Mona Lisa's face in just that image. However, the method can again be easily fine-tuned for Einstein's face, and, when the parameters are &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Viola%E2%80%93Jones_object_detection_framework#Components_of_the_framework&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;calculated using Machine Learning&lt;/a&gt;, it works on most frontal-looking faces (assuming not occluded, not too small, etc.). See question #4 below for further details on this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Q2: Are the techniques presented still relevant, or are they replaced by deep neural networks?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The techniques are still relevant. Neural networks are taking over for all complex computer vision problems, especially those unsolved by the classical techniques. For simpler operations, the classical solutions are faster to put together and are usually computationally more efficient. Also, classical techniques are still the default choice for edge devices (smartphones, web clients) though modern techniques are making an entry notably via hardware acceleration (e.g., &lt;a href=&quot;https://petewarden.com/2018/06/11/why-the-future-of-machine-learning-is-tiny/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://petewarden.com/2019/04/14/what-machine-learning-needs-from-hardware/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Q3: Why was the green channel of the image used, and not red or blue? How can I represent color images in Excel in this fashion?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of the three primary color channels, red, green and blue, green contributes the most to luminosity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ideally, the image should be converted to grayscale first, or luminosity values should be computed (see &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/CIE_1931_color_space&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;). This was skipped just for simplicity of explanation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/amzn/computer-vision-basics-in-microsoft-excel/blob/master/img/Why-Green.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/amzn/computer-vision-basics-in-microsoft-excel/raw/master/img/Why-Green.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Why Green?&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One way of representing color images in Excel is referenced in the answer to the question #7 below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Q4: Why was the watermark face on the ID not detected and yet Mona Lisa's was?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We demonstrated the core concept of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Viola%E2%80%93Jones_object_detection_framework&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;a popular face detection algorithm&lt;/a&gt; using just three &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Haar-like_feature&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Haar-like features&lt;/a&gt; and two stages, which were hand-crafted to detect the face of Mona Lisa in that specific image. The actual features as well as the stages are in practice calculated using Machine Learning, which commonly results in a few thousands of such features, as well as over ten stages. Then the system is able to detect over 99% of the nearly frontal looking faces (while a separate pre-trained model is available for faces looking nearly sideways in &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/OpenCV&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;OpenCV&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The face shadow on the right would still be missed by the algorithm since such face images are not included in the training data. My educated guess further will be that to detect such shadowed faces, the algorithm described would not do a good job, and using neural networks would be recommended. Likewise, the algorithm we demonstrated is outperformed by a neural networks for &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://vis-www.cs.umass.edu/lfw/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Labeled faces in the wild&lt;/a&gt;&quot; dataset where faces are often partially occluded too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Q5: In the OCR example, how do you chose the mask and its orientation?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For document &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Optical_character_recognition&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;OCR&lt;/a&gt; (as opposed to &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scene_text&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;scene text&lt;/a&gt; recognition), the document itself is typically straightened first before character recognition is performed for the characters in the document. Therefore, the characters are expected to be nearly upright.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the talk, a toy example was shown using a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Convolutional_neural_network&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;single convolutional&lt;/a&gt; neuron to recognize an 'E'. Neural networks use a number of layers of neurons for the task to recognize all characters of interest. The same neural network then outputs which character is present at the input. You can imagine this as having a separate simple neural network like for 'E' for recognizing each character of interest. The combined neural network would, however, have several neurons shared in the path for recognizing each character.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See also the Q&amp;amp;A below for more on character recognition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Q6: How well does the OCR approach here work on different fonts?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the talk, we used a single &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Convolutional_neural_network&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;convolutional neuron&lt;/a&gt; to identify an uppercase 'E' as an example. The actual systems still commonly use neural networks (not just a single neuron) for the purpose, and that performs well across fonts and languages. Some additional details are present below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the talk, a single neuron was used to both scan the image and recognize the letter. Typically, scanning text of different sizes is done separately using various methods. Once every character of text is isolated, it is re-scaled to a fixed size and then a neural network is used to identify the letter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Handwriting recognition is harder, unsurprisingly. The best performance is reached when the pen strokes data is available as a function of time (e.g., when recognizing handwriting input on a touch-screen). References are readily available online for further reading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the example shown in the talk, even the weights of that single neuron were hand-crafted, not actually learned using a training algorithm. Even a single neuron would do better that the demo when actually trained.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Q7: How did you come up with the idea for using Microsoft Excel for this?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About 1.5 years back, we had to give an introductory talk on Computer Vision to a wide audience within Amazon, many of whom would have been completely unfamiliar with the subject. We thought about starting from the very basics by showing that an image is essentially a 2D array of numbers (for each color channel for color images) and thought about showing these using Excel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Hmm! If the numbers are in Excel, I could do more with it&quot; ... That was the &quot;A-ha&quot; moment. :-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It took about seven hours to create the first fully functional version for that talk, which did not include Face Detection and Text recognition. The latter took about eight more hours for the first version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have since then discovered several related works that represent images in Excel using this technique:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Q8: Can I use the materials for teaching?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please see the License summary and details below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Q9: Are there specialized interactive developer environments for Computer Vision?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mathworks.com/products/matlab.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Matlab&lt;/a&gt; has traditionally been used for this as it has many Computer Vision functions built-in natively or in toolboxes. Function &quot;imshow&quot; can be used to instantly display array data as an image.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python- and Notebooks-based tooling is also very popular.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Q10: Is that your passport information on the slides?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, however, all critical information in the image has been changed like passport number, signatures, etc., including in the machine-readable lines at the bottom of the image.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Q11: Why does Hough Transform show artifacts for +/- 45°?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please refer to the answer here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/33983389/hough-line-transform-artifacts-at-45-degree-angle&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/33983389/hough-line-transform-artifacts-at-45-degree-angle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Additional Resources and References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Books&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below are two freely-downloadable good books on classical Computer Vision (i.e., before deep learning came into the field):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://szeliski.org/Book/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Computer Vision: Algorithms and Applications&lt;/a&gt;, Richard Szeliski (2010): This books provides a summary of many computer vision techniques along with research results from academic papers. The diagrams in the book by themselves are worth browsing through to understand the state of the art in the field till 2010 when the book was published. The book usually does 'not' give enough detail to allow someone to implement the methods described, though appropriate references are cited.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/book/10.1007%2F978-1-4302-5930-5&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Computer Vision Metrics&lt;/a&gt;: Survey, Taxonomy, and Analysis, Scott Krig (2014): This book provides a good top-level view of computer vision, though often mixed on details.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;For practical implementation, there are many books on OpenCV, a common Computer Vision library like &lt;a href=&quot;http://shop.oreilly.com/product/0636920044765.do&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Learning OpenCV 3: Computer Vision in C++ with the OpenCV Library&lt;/a&gt;, Gary Bradski, Adrian Kaehler&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Selected Articles and Blogs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;License Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Copyright 2018-20 Amazon.com, Inc. or its affiliates. All Rights Reserved. SPDX-License-Identifier: CC-BY-NC-SA-4.0&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is made available under the Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International Public License. See the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/amzn/computer-vision-basics-in-microsoft-excel/blob/master/LICENSE&quot;&gt;LICENSE&lt;/a&gt; file. It cannot be used for commercial training or lectures.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 16:49:46 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>alok-g</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars2.githubusercontent.com/u/8594673?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>amzn/computer-vision-basics-in-microsoft-excel</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/amzn/computer-vision-basics-in-microsoft-excel</og:url>
<og:description>Computer Vision Basics in Microsoft Excel (using just formulas) - amzn/computer-vision-basics-in-microsoft-excel</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/amzn/computer-vision-basics-in-microsoft-excel</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>New AMD EPYC-based Compute Engine family, now in beta</title>
<link>https://cloud.google.com/blog/products/compute/announcing-the-n2d-vm-family-based-on-amd</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://cloud.google.com/blog/products/compute/announcing-the-n2d-vm-family-based-on-amd</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;At Google Cloud, we want you to be able to choose the best VMs for your workloads. Today, we’re excited to announce a new addition to our &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/compute/docs/machine-types&quot;&gt;general purpose VMs&lt;/a&gt;: the N2D family, built atop 2nd Gen AMD EPYC™ Processors. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;N2D VMs are a great option for both general-purpose workloads and workloads that require high memory bandwidth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;General-purpose workloads that require a balance of compute and memory, like web applications and databases, can benefit from N2D’s performance,  price, and features. N2D VMs are designed to provide you with the same features as N2 VMs including local SSD, custom machine types, and transparent maintenance through live migration, while features like large machine types with up to an industry-leading 224 vCPUs, the largest general purpose VM on Compute Engine. At the same time, N2D instances provide savings of up to 13% over comparable N-series instances, and up to a 39% performance improvement on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eembc.org/coremark/&quot;&gt;Coremark&lt;/a&gt; benchmark compared to comparable N1 instances&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HPC workloads such as crash analysis, financial modeling, rendering and reservoir analysis, will benefit from the N2D machine types configured with 128 and 224 vCPUs, which offer up to 70% higher platform memory bandwidth than comparable N1 instances. This, combined with higher core counts, provides over a 100% performance improvement on a variety of representative benchmarks, including Gromacs and NAMD, compared to n1-standard-96 vCPUs. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;N2D machine type details&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;N2D VMs are now available in beta from us-central1, asia-southeast1, and europe-west4, with more regions on the way! You can launch them on-demand or as &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/preemptible-vms/&quot;&gt;preemptible VMs.&lt;/a&gt; When you sign up for &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/compute/docs/instances/signing-up-committed-use-discounts&quot;&gt;committed use discounts&lt;/a&gt;, you can save up to 55% for three-year commitments versus on-demand pricing. Long-running N2D VMs can take advantage of &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/compute/docs/sustained-use-discounts&quot;&gt;sustained use discounts&lt;/a&gt;, and automatically save up to 20%. You can also configure N2D VMs as predefined machine types with vCPU to memory ratios of 1:1, 1:4, and 1:8,  up to 224 vCPUs. You can also create custom machine types with N2Ds, helping you meet the needs of diverse workloads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Get started&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s easy to get started with N2D VMs—simply visit the &lt;a href=&quot;https://console.cloud.google.com/&quot;&gt;Google Cloud Console&lt;/a&gt; and launch one! To learn more about N2D VMs or other Compute Engine VM options, check out our &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/compute/docs/machine-types&quot;&gt;machine types&lt;/a&gt; and our &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/compute/all-pricing&quot;&gt;pricing&lt;/a&gt; pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;sub&gt;1. N2D-standard-32 performed 39% better than N1-standard-32 when evaluated using Coremark.&lt;/sub&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 16:31:03 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>cvallejo</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:title>Announcing the N2D VM family based on AMD | Google Cloud Blog</og:title>
<og:description>N2D VMs are the first AMD-based instances on Google Cloud.</og:description>
<og:image>https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-cloudblog-publish/images/gcp_compute.max-2200x2200.jpg</og:image>
<og:url>https://cloud.google.com/blog/products/compute/announcing-the-n2d-vm-family-based-on-amd/</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://cloud.google.com/blog/products/compute/announcing-the-n2d-vm-family-based-on-amd</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Kickstarter employees vote to unionize</title>
<link>https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/3a8pp5/kickstarter-employees-win-historic-union-election</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/3a8pp5/kickstarter-employees-win-historic-union-election</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Kickstarter employees voted to form a union with the Office and Professional Employees International Union, which represents more than 100,000 white collar workers. The final vote was 46 for the union, 37 against, a historic win for unionization efforts at tech companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kickstarter workers are now the first white collar workers at a major tech company to successfully unionize in the United States, sending a message to other tech workers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Everyone was crying [when the results were announced],” Clarissa Redwine, a Kickstarter United organizers who was fired in September, told Motherboard. “I thought it would be close, but I also knew we were going to win. I hope other tech workers feel emboldened and know that it’s possible to fight for your workplace and your values. I know my former coworkers will use a seat at the table really well.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Today we learned that in a 46 to 37 vote, our staff has decided to unionize,&quot; Kickstarter's CEO Aziz Hasan said in a statement. &quot;We support and respect this decision, and we are proud of the fair and democratic process that got us here. We’ve worked hard over the last decade to build a different kind of company, one that measures its success by how well it achieves its mission: helping to bring creative projects to life. Our mission has been common ground for everyone here during this process, and it will continue to guide us as we enter this new phase together.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The union at the Brooklyn-based crowd-funding platform arrives during a period of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2019/dec/22/tech-worker-activism-2019-what-we-learned&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;unprecedented labor organizing&lt;/a&gt; among engineers and other white collar tech workers at Google, Amazon, Microsoft and other prominent tech companies—around issues like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/11/01/technology/google-walkout-sexual-harassment.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;sexual harassment&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/amazon-employees-letter-protest-palantir-ice-camps-2019-7?r=US&amp;amp;IR=T&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;ICE contracts&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2020/01/26/amazon-employees-plan-mass-defiance-company-communications-policy-support-colleagues/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;carbon emissions&lt;/a&gt;. Between 2017 and 2019, the number of protest actions led by tech workers nearly tripled. In 2019 alone, tech workers led more than 100 actions, according to &lt;a href=&quot;https://collectiveactions.tech/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;the online database&lt;/a&gt; “Collective Actions in Tech.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I feel like the most important issues [for us] are around creating clearer policies and support for reporting workplace issues and creating clearer mechanisms for hiring and firing employees,” said RV Dougherty, a former trust and safety analyst and core organizer for Kickstarter United who quit in early February. &quot;Right now so much depends on what team you’re on and if you have a good relationship with your manager... We also have a lot of pay disparity and folks who are doing incredibe jobs but have been kept from getting promoted because they spoke their mind, which is not how Kickstarter should work.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the days leading up to Kickstarter vote count, Motherboard &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/3a8vyk/kickstarter-hired-a-law-firm-that-advertises-maintaining-a-union-free-workplace&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;revealed that Kickstarter&lt;/a&gt; hired Duane Morris, a Philadelphia law firm that specializes in labor management relations and “maintaining a union-free workplace.” Kickstarter confirmed to Motherboard that it first retained the services of Duane Morris in 2018 before it knew about union organizing at the company, but would not go into detail about whether the firm had advised the company on how to defeat the union and denied any union-busting activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dating back to its 2009 founding, &lt;a href=&quot;https://slate.com/technology/2019/09/kickstarter-turmoil-union-drive-historic-tech-industry.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Kickstarter has tried&lt;/a&gt; to distinguish itself as a progressive exception to Silicon Valley tech companies. In 2015, the company’s leadership announced it had become a “public benefit corporation.” “Benefit Corporations are for-profit companies that are obligated to consider the impact of their decisions on society, not only shareholders,” the senior leadership &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kickstarter.com/blog/kickstarter-is-now-a-benefit-corporation&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;wrote&lt;/a&gt; at the time. The company &lt;a href=&quot;https://slate.com/technology/2019/09/kickstarter-turmoil-union-drive-historic-tech-industry.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;has been hailed&lt;/a&gt; as one of the most ethical places to work in tech.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indeed, rather than dedicate its resources to maximizing profit, Kickstarter has fought for progressive causes, like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/etsy-kickstarter-sue-fcc-net-neutrality-repeal-2018-3&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;net neutrality&lt;/a&gt;, and against the &lt;a href=&quot;https://slate.com/technology/2019/09/kickstarter-turmoil-union-drive-historic-tech-industry.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;anti-trans bathroom&lt;/a&gt; law in North Carolina.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But in 2018, a heated disagreement broke out between employees and management about whether to leave a project called “Always Punch Nazis” on the platform, according to &lt;a href=&quot;https://slate.com/technology/2019/09/kickstarter-turmoil-union-drive-historic-tech-industry.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;reporting in Slate&lt;/a&gt;. When &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.breitbart.com/tech/2018/08/10/kickstarter-ignores-terms-of-service-with-always-punch-nazis-project/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Breitbart said&lt;/a&gt; the project violated Kickstarter’s terms of service by inciting violence, management initially planned to remove the project, but then reversed its decision after protest from employees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the controversy, employees announced their intentions to unionize with OPEIU Local 153 in March 2019. And the company made it clear that it did not believe a union was right for Kickstarter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a letter to creators, Kickstarter’s CEO Aziz Hasan wrote in September that “The union framework is inherently adversarial.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“That dynamic doesn’t reflect who we are as a company, how we interact, how we make decisions, or where we need to go,&quot; the company’s CEO Aziz Hasan wrote to creators in September. &quot;We believe that in many ways it would set us back.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In September, Kickstarter &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/a35jpg/heres-what-the-ceo-of-kickstarter-said-to-creators-about-firing-union-organizers&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;fired two employees&lt;/a&gt; on its union organizing committee within 8 days, informing a third that his role was no longer needed at the company. Following outcry from prominent creators, the company insisted that the two firings were &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/a35jpg/heres-what-the-ceo-of-kickstarter-said-to-creators-about-firing-union-organizers&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;related to job performance&lt;/a&gt;, not union activity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The two fired workers filed federal unfair labor practice charges with the National Labor Review Board (NLRB), claiming the company retaliating them for union organizing in violation of the National Labor Relations Act. (Those charges have yet to be resolved.) Days later, the company &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/9ken8v/kickstarter-workers-just-asked-for-union-recognition-despite-pushback-from-ceo&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;denied a request&lt;/a&gt; from the union, Kickstarter United, for voluntary recognition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The decision to unionize at Kickstarter follows a series of victories for union campaigns led by blue collar tech workers. Last year, 80 Google contractors in Pittsburgh, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vox.com/recode/2019/12/31/21043467/google-union-cafeteria-workers-unionized-alphabet-silicon-valley-mountainview&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;2,300 cafeteria workers&lt;/a&gt; at Google in Silicon Valley, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/dyggwv/e-scooter-workers-just-formed-their-first-union&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;roughly 40 Spin e-scooter&lt;/a&gt; workers in San Francisco voted to form the first unions in the tech industry. In early February, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/qjdvgm/instacart-workers-win-historic-union-election&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;15 employees at the delivery app Instacart&lt;/a&gt; in Chicago successfully unionized, following a fierce anti-union campaign run by management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/07/08/technology/tech-companies-union-organizing.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;some accounts&lt;/a&gt;, the current wave of white collar tech organizing began in early 2018 when the San Francisco tech company Lanetix &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/story/labor-board-backs-startup-engineers-fired-unionizing/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;fired its entire 14-software engineer&lt;/a&gt; staff after they filed to unionize with Communications Workers of America (CWA). Later, the company was forced to &lt;a href=&quot;https://finance.yahoo.com/news/tech-company-pays-775-000-101037684.html?guccounter=1&amp;amp;guce_referrer=aHR0cHM6Ly93d3cuZ29vZ2xlLmNvbS8&amp;amp;guce_referrer_sig=AQAAABlLYuyKBo-YvYR1F2HIXk6w2Z_AFFm3sLN-mcZh-6cq3aOPjwYcSN3KxmQiriaW1VK7QDQ4ZsA-q0LJhI5CKsABQVYpBwVWlC3lLqfijfZq5FM3VtsBYdTucJHlDuvFQGhXwytglA6eAt9fePY7BnmT4QFQRw4j3ueLW1G7ygAs&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;cough up $775,000&lt;/a&gt; to settle unfair labor practice charges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update: This story has been updated with comment from Kickstarter.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 16:03:31 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>danso</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Kickstarter Employees Win Historic Union Election</og:title>
<og:image>https://video-images.vice.com/test-uploads/articles/5e4bfc1801624d009dc291c3/lede/1582042097052-Image-from-iOS-7.jpeg?crop=1xw:0.4214xh;0xw,0.193xh&amp;resize=1200:*</og:image>
<og:url>https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/3a8pp5/kickstarter-employees-win-historic-union-election</og:url>
<og:description> The final vote was 46 for the union, 37 against, a historic win for unionization efforts at tech companies.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/3a8pp5/kickstarter-employees-win-historic-union-election</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>JWT is Awesome</title>
<link>https://thehftguy.com/2020/02/18/jwt-is-awesome-heres-why/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://thehftguy.com/2020/02/18/jwt-is-awesome-heres-why/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here’s my take on JWT* and why I think it’s amazing&lt;/strong&gt;, after having migrated hundreds of applications in JP Morgan from a legacy authentication solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*JWT = &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/JSON_Web_Token&quot;&gt;JSON Web Token&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;1) Pro: JWT is standardized and supported in most languages&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For applications to have authentication, this requires developers to tightly integrate authentication when writing the application. Authentication code is tough work as anybody who ever had to do it can attest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JWT can take a lot of that pain away. &lt;strong&gt;JWT has ready-to-use libraries for most languages and they pretty much just work&lt;/strong&gt;. See a list on &lt;a href=&quot;https://jwt.io/#libraries-io&quot;&gt;https://jwt.io/#libraries-io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even better, it is a standardized format with &lt;strong&gt;examples and documentation freely available on the internet.&lt;/strong&gt; Any trouble with it and &lt;strong&gt;help is only a Google search away&lt;/strong&gt;. That wouldn’t be the case with any in-house developed alternative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;2) Pro: JWT supports user attributes out-of-the box&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Authentication is to guarantee who the user is? A user is usually represented by some sort of unique user identifier.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most authentication solutions provide the user identifier, only the user identifier, and that’s exactly where they fall short.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Turns out a user is more than an identifier!&lt;/strong&gt; From a decade working around development and authentication, I can tell &lt;strong&gt;there are at least 3 things needed to cover most application use cases.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A unique user identifier&lt;/strong&gt;. A unique identifier per user, meant for computers. Usually an id number straight out of a user database.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A display name&lt;/strong&gt;. A string to display back to the user that should make sense to themselves, meant for human comprehension. Usually a combination of first/middle/last names or an email address.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;An email address&lt;/strong&gt;. The email address of the user. Usually needed by a fair amount of applications/reports/systems to email the user after some actions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Having additional user attributes is trivial with JWT tokens and they can easily be used (by developers) in applications.&lt;/strong&gt; A JWT token is basically a JSON key=value structure, with some of the keys being standardized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If it were not for JWT, developers would have to not only integrate some made-up authentication system, but also some made up user attributes system, in order to perform the simplest of task like showing the user its own name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;3) Pro: JWT is unicode friendly out-of-the-box&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JWT and JSON underneath are explicitly utf-8. They handle non-English names well.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actually it’s more than that. They are &lt;strong&gt;strictly&lt;/strong&gt; unicode and from day one, so pretty much always work and in all programming languages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, JWT libraries in python (2.7) and C++ work with unicode strings. This is great because it doesn’t leave a choice to developers, they MUST handle unicode somewhat or the application WILL blow up right away (type error and such).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This and the rise of python 3 will eventually get the world to a place where applications work with non-English characters. Well, at least not mangling the user name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be clear. The biggest obstacle to internationalization is programming languages themselves, see &lt;code&gt;str()&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;std::string()&lt;/code&gt;, that don’t support non-English out-of-the-box at all. Even if one is willing to go the extra mile to make it work, they quickly hit a wall because every other function and library is implicitly limited to “standard” strings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;4) Pro: JWT doesn’t DDoS authentication servers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is the most common recurring source of company wide outage?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[To clarify, I mean truly major outages, not like just one application or ten being down.]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[building up the tension]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You guessed it, &lt;strong&gt;it’s the authentication system. If authentication services are down, everything else is down&lt;/strong&gt;. Well, it’s up but may not be quite usable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Needless to say, this happened before and will happen again. Buggy applications DDoSing critical services in an infinite loop is a source of issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JWT can totally alleviate this. JWT tokens are signed by an asymmetric keys and can be verified offline by applications. No need to call an external service and have a gigantic single point of failure.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-image&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;12778&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://thehftguy.com/galaxy_map_auth_center/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://thehftguy.files.wordpress.com/2020/02/galaxy_map_auth_center.png&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;640,480&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;galaxy_map_auth_center&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://thehftguy.files.wordpress.com/2020/02/galaxy_map_auth_center.png?w=300&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://thehftguy.files.wordpress.com/2020/02/galaxy_map_auth_center.png?w=640&quot; src=&quot;https://thehftguy.files.wordpress.com/2020/02/galaxy_map_auth_center.png?w=640&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-12778&quot; srcset=&quot;https://thehftguy.files.wordpress.com/2020/02/galaxy_map_auth_center.png 640w, https://thehftguy.files.wordpress.com/2020/02/galaxy_map_auth_center.png?w=150 150w, https://thehftguy.files.wordpress.com/2020/02/galaxy_map_auth_center.png?w=300 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px&quot;/&gt;Authentication is the single most important thing in the universe and without authentication the universe stops running. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.atlasoftheuniverse.com/galaxy.html&quot;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;5) Pro: Dramatic decrease in latency&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Putting aside DDoS scenarios. &lt;strong&gt;Latency during normal operation is an important concern.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider that everything nowadays is a mesh of services (#Microservice). When a user sends a request, the web server calls another service, that calls another service, that calls a database…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each step may involve some authentication check. &lt;strong&gt;Even if a single check is quick (below 100 milliseconds), this is not as quick when repeated N times.&lt;/strong&gt; What about 99% latency? What if systems are under load and take whole second(s) to complete? You guessed it, latency can add up really quickly and it’s not great at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JWT tokens can be verified offline by applications, making the latency effectively zero. Once again, JWT shines.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How long should a HTTP call take by the way? One may be tempted to say a few milliseconds, roughly the time to open a connection and check if token is in Redis. But that doesn’t consider multi data center scenarios. For global companies -I hope most companies hope to serve users in the US and the EU (if not Asia)- there are datacenters in and across continents, meaning l&lt;strong&gt;atency in the tens and in the hundreds of milliseconds respectively.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fun fact&lt;/strong&gt;: Did you know that Australia is a continent? People always forget about it. Being 12 000 km from North America, network round trip time is a minimum of 80 milliseconds. Bet users there can feel the latency every time they click a button on a US website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;6) Pro: JWT is secure&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HTTPS, HMAC and asymmetric keys. It’s all basic and proven.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’d try to roll your own, either you’d end up with pretty much the same, or you’d follow top stack overflow answers -that have not been updated in the past 10 years- and end up with obsolete insecure stuff (#&lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/4388908/what-is-md5-for&quot;&gt;MD5&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;7) Pro: Don’t roll your own&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alright, let’s roll our own authentication tokens.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So… quick thinking… we need to have some sort of tokens with:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;a user identifier in the token,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a way to retrieve user attributes (another system?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;when was the token created (iat) and is it still valid (exp)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;which settings were used (alg + kid), (really hard to do future upgrade if missing)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;what created the token and why (issuer + aud) (probably don’t care about that)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sounds about right, so let’s put that in a dict and pickle it.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;lt;/beginning of rant&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.python.org/3/library/pickle.html&quot;&gt;OMG DON’T PICKLE DATA. PICKLING IS INSECURE.&lt;/a&gt; Pickling doesn’t generate an innocent string but python code to (re)generate the object. Parsing back is executing that python code, any python code really. Wherever pickle is used in any capacity, users can simply send arbitrary commands and they will get executed on the authentication servers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;12785&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://thehftguy.com/vulnerabilities_everywhere/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://thehftguy.files.wordpress.com/2020/02/vulnerabilities_everywhere.jpg&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;735,500&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;vulnerabilities_everywhere&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://thehftguy.files.wordpress.com/2020/02/vulnerabilities_everywhere.jpg?w=300&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://thehftguy.files.wordpress.com/2020/02/vulnerabilities_everywhere.jpg?w=735&quot; src=&quot;https://thehftguy.files.wordpress.com/2020/02/vulnerabilities_everywhere.jpg?w=735&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-12785&quot; srcset=&quot;https://thehftguy.files.wordpress.com/2020/02/vulnerabilities_everywhere.jpg 735w, https://thehftguy.files.wordpress.com/2020/02/vulnerabilities_everywhere.jpg?w=150 150w, https://thehftguy.files.wordpress.com/2020/02/vulnerabilities_everywhere.jpg?w=300 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 735px) 100vw, 735px&quot;/&gt;Pickle, number #1 source of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Arbitrary_code_execution&quot;&gt;critical vulnerabilities&lt;/a&gt; in python applications since 1991.
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, moving on… you’re probably fine if not working in Python, or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.elttam.com/blog/ruby-deserialization/&quot;&gt;Ruby&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;lt;/end of rant&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The end result is something like a key=value structure to be serialized and signed somehow.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guess what is JWT? &lt;strong&gt;JWT is basically a JSON encoded object that’s signed.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Might as well go with that, no need to reinvent the wheel.&lt;/strong&gt; They probably gave some thoughts to common use cases and edge cases, unlike this 5 minutes brainstorming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;8) Myth: JWT is decentralized. (It is not unless you make it so)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve said that JWT allow to verify tokens offline, in a decentralized fashion. &lt;strong&gt;Fact is, JWT can be fully centralized. Here’s how.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JWT is most often used alongside OpenID Connect. JWT defines a token format and OpenID Connect defines API to initiate authentication over HTTP. See related article on &lt;a href=&quot;https://thehftguy.com/2019/01/02/the-difference-between-id_token-and-access_token-in-openid-connect/&quot;&gt;the difference between id_token and access_token in OpenID Connect&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When using OpenID Connect, the server usually provides a &lt;code&gt;/userinfo&lt;/code&gt; endpoint&lt;/strong&gt; like &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://example.com/oauth2/v2.0/userinfo&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://example.com/oauth2/v2.0/userinfo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt; . This endpoint will return user attributes when called with a user token. Note that few attributes -if any- are usually stored inside tokens in order to keep them small.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It’s possible to operate in a centralized fashion by (exclusively) verifying tokens through the &lt;code&gt;/userinfo&lt;/code&gt; endpoint, rather than verifying token signatures offline.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Both modes of operation are supported in most setups. To prevent either, disable the &lt;code&gt;/userinfo&lt;/code&gt; endpoint or do not distribute public signing keys.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;9) Myth: JWT doesn’t support logout or invalidation. (It can with OpenID Connect)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JWT tokens are emitted and valid for some amount of time. See issued at and expires on attributes in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://openid.net/specs/openid-connect-core-1_0.html#IDToken&quot;&gt;JWT standard&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;code&gt;iat&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;exp&lt;/code&gt;). It’s fair to say that tokens are not meant to be invalidated. They’re rather intended to live for a defined period of time, that ought to be reasonably short.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It’s entirely possible to have centralized logout and invalidation if that’s all one wishes to have.&lt;/strong&gt; See above “&lt;em&gt;JWT is (not) decentralized&lt;/em&gt;“. This simply requires to operate centrally with the &lt;code&gt;/userinfo&lt;/code&gt; endpoint. The OIDC server should also be configured to expose the &lt;code&gt;/logout&lt;/code&gt; endpoint to be able to close sessions (not all OIDC providers support it). That’s it. It’s build-in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: One stupid alternative that I strongly advise against, but that people often talk about on the internet, is to maintain some blacklist of tokens (in some databases or Redis). Then comes the trouble of maintaining another anti-authentication system and integrating it in libraries and applications (All applications will connect to a Redis somehow? That is always online and globally distributed?). &lt;strong&gt;If centralized logout is an absolute must have, then setup OIDC to work centrally and let the OIDC server do the work it’s meant to do.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last but not least. It’s possible to invalidate all (current) authentication tokens at once. Simply rotate the signing keys. Previously created tokens won’t be accepted as valid anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;10) Con: JWT token Size&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One minor downside of JWT tokens is their size. &lt;strong&gt;A typical token is 500 to 1000 bytes in practice. It could be considered fairly large when compared to a blackbox token like a 128 bits integer or a GUID.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arbitrary user attributes can be set in tokens. They could easily consume multiple kilobytes and upward if not careful and that will cause issues down the line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Attributes should be kept to a minimum to limit token size.&lt;/strong&gt; Enabling all optional attributes is an anti-pattern, &lt;strong&gt;only enable needed attributes selectively&lt;/strong&gt;. Tokens are not suited to store long strings. For example a postal address, let alone multiple addresses, is not a good fit for token attributes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over HTTP, authentication tokens are passed through the &lt;code&gt;Cookie&lt;/code&gt; or the &lt;code&gt;Authorization&lt;/code&gt; header. &lt;strong&gt;HTTP request headers are limited to 8 kB in most web servers, covering normal HTTP request headers and all user cookies and the token if any.&lt;/strong&gt; The limit can easily be reached accidentally. Applications running on the same domain, as in &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://internal.example.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://internal.example.com/&lt;/a&gt;...&lt;/code&gt;, are sharing the same cookie namespace and are more likely to run into issues for using numerous or large cookies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was a lot of pros and two myths busted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did I say JWT is awesome?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long live JWT! …unless the token was logged out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;jp-post-flair&quot; class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-rating-enabled sd-like-enabled sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;robots-nocontent sd-block sd-social sd-social-icon sd-sharing&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Share this article:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-block sd-like jetpack-likes-widget-wrapper jetpack-likes-widget-unloaded&quot; id=&quot;like-post-wrapper-108084023-12777-5e4c88f059264&quot; data-src=&quot;//widgets.wp.com/likes/index.html?ver=20190321#blog_id=108084023&amp;amp;post_id=12777&amp;amp;origin=thehftguy.wordpress.com&amp;amp;obj_id=108084023-12777-5e4c88f059264&amp;amp;domain=thehftguy.com&quot; data-name=&quot;like-post-frame-108084023-12777-5e4c88f059264&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Like this:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;likes-widget-placeholder post-likes-widget-placeholder&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;button&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Like&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;loading&quot;&gt;Loading...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 09:01:12 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>hieudang9</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>JWT is Awesome: Here's Why</og:title>
<og:url>https://thehftguy.com/2020/02/18/jwt-is-awesome-heres-why/</og:url>
<og:description>Here’s my take on JWT* and why I think it’s amazing, after having migrated hundreds of applications in JP Morgan from a legacy authentication solution. *JWT = JSON Web Token 1) Pro: JWT…</og:description>
<og:image>https://thehftguy.files.wordpress.com/2020/02/vulnerabilities_everywhere.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://thehftguy.com/2020/02/18/jwt-is-awesome-heres-why/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Docker for Windows won&amp;#039;t run if Razer Synapse driver management tool is running</title>
<link>https://twitter.com/Foone/status/1229641258370355200</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://twitter.com/Foone/status/1229641258370355200</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Foone/status/1229641258370355200&quot;&gt;https://twitter.com/Foone/status/1229641258370355200&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=22354449&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=22354449&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 325&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 160&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 08:41:55 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>edward</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://mobile.twitter.com/Foone/status/1229641258370355200</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Facebook asks for a moat of regulations it already meets</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/17/regulate-facebook/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/17/regulate-facebook/</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;speakable-summary&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;featured__span-first-words&quot;&gt;It’s suspiciously convenient&lt;/span&gt; that Facebook already fulfills most of the regulatory requirements it’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://about.fb.com/news/2020/02/online-content-regulation/&quot;&gt;asking&lt;/a&gt; governments to lay on the rest of the tech industry. Facebook CEO Mark Zuckerberg is in Brussels lobbying the European Union’s regulators as they form new laws to govern artificial intelligence, content moderation and more. But if they follow &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://crunchbase.com/organization/facebook&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;facebook&quot;&gt;Facebook’s&lt;/a&gt; suggestions, they might reinforce the social network’s power rather than keep it in check by hamstringing companies with fewer resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We already saw this happen with GDPR. The idea was to strengthen privacy and weaken exploitative data collection that tech giants like Facebook and Google depend on for their business models. The result was that Facebook and Google actually gained or only slightly lost EU market share while all other adtech vendors got wrecked by the regulation, according to &lt;a href=&quot;https://whotracks.me/blog/gdpr-what-happened.html&quot;&gt;WhoTracksMe&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_1947513&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; readability=&quot;31.420689655172&quot;&gt;&lt;img aria-describedby=&quot;caption-attachment-1947513&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-1947513 size-large&quot; src=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Google-Facebook-Market-Share-GDPR.png?w=680&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;680&quot; height=&quot;363&quot; srcset=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Google-Facebook-Market-Share-GDPR.png 1372w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Google-Facebook-Market-Share-GDPR.png?resize=150,80 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Google-Facebook-Market-Share-GDPR.png?resize=300,160 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Google-Facebook-Market-Share-GDPR.png?resize=768,410 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Google-Facebook-Market-Share-GDPR.png?resize=680,363 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Google-Facebook-Market-Share-GDPR.png?resize=50,27 50w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p id=&quot;caption-attachment-1947513&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;GDPR went into effect in May 2018, hurting other adtech vendors’ EU market share much worse than Google and Facebook. Image credit: &lt;a href=&quot;https://whotracks.me/blog/gdpr-what-happened.html&quot;&gt;WhoTracksMe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tech giants like Facebook have the profits lawyers, lobbyists, engineers, designers, scale and steady cash flow to navigate regulatory changes. Unless new laws are squarely targeted at the abuses or dominance of these large companies, their collateral damage can loom large. Rather than spend time and money they don’t have in order to comply, some smaller competitors will fold, scale back or sell out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But at least in the case of GDPR, everyone had to add new transparency and opt out features. If Facebook’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://about.fb.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Charting-A-Way-Forward_Online-Content-Regulation-White-Paper-1.pdf&quot;&gt;slate of requests&lt;/a&gt; goes through, it will sail forward largely unperturbed while rivals and upstarts scramble to get up to speed. I made this argument in March 2018 in my post &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/03/25/the-regulation-moat/&quot;&gt;“Regulation could protect Facebook, not punish it.”&lt;/a&gt; Then GDPR did exactly that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Update: There is still a chance that Facebook gets penalized for violating GDPR and its Europe launch of &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/13/facebook-dating-launch-blocked-in-europe-after-it-fails-to-show-privacy-workings/&quot;&gt;Facebook Dating&lt;/a&gt; was halted last week due to the EU’s investigation.]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_1947525&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; readability=&quot;30.270676691729&quot;&gt;&lt;img aria-describedby=&quot;caption-attachment-1947525&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-1947525 size-large&quot; src=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Google-Facebook-EU-Market-Share-GDPR.png?w=680&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;680&quot; height=&quot;574&quot; srcset=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Google-Facebook-EU-Market-Share-GDPR.png 890w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Google-Facebook-EU-Market-Share-GDPR.png?resize=150,127 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Google-Facebook-EU-Market-Share-GDPR.png?resize=300,253 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Google-Facebook-EU-Market-Share-GDPR.png?resize=768,648 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Google-Facebook-EU-Market-Share-GDPR.png?resize=680,574 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Google-Facebook-EU-Market-Share-GDPR.png?resize=50,42 50w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p id=&quot;caption-attachment-1947525&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Google gained market share and Facebook only lost a little in the EU following GDPR. Everyone else fared worse. Image via &lt;a href=&quot;https://whotracks.me/blog/gdpr-what-happened.html&quot;&gt;WhoTracksMe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That doesn’t mean these safeguards aren’t sensible for everyone to follow. But regulators need to consider what Facebook &lt;em&gt;isn’t&lt;/em&gt; suggesting if it wants to address its scope and brazenness, and what timelines or penalties would be feasible for smaller players.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we take a quick look at what Facebook is proposing, it becomes obvious that it’s self-servingly suggesting what it’s already accomplished:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;User-friendly channels for reporting content &lt;/strong&gt;– Every post and entity on Facebook can already be &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/help/1753719584844061?helpref=page_content&quot;&gt;flagged&lt;/a&gt; by users with an explanation of why&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;External oversight of policies or enforcement &lt;/strong&gt;– Facebook is finalizing its independent &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/28/under-consideration/&quot;&gt;Oversight Board&lt;/a&gt; right now&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Periodic public reporting of enforcement data&lt;/strong&gt; – Facebook publishes a &lt;a href=&quot;https://transparency.facebook.com/community-standards-enforcement&quot;&gt;twice-yearly report&lt;/a&gt; about enforcement of its Community Standards&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Publishing their content standards&lt;/strong&gt; – Facebook &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/communitystandards/recentupdates/&quot;&gt;publishes&lt;/a&gt; its standards and notes updates to them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Consulting with stakeholders when making significant changes&lt;/strong&gt; – Facebook consults a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/help/222332597793306&quot;&gt;Safety Advisory Board&lt;/a&gt; and will have its new Oversight Board&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Creating a channel for users to appeal a company’s content removal decisions&lt;/strong&gt; – Facebook’s Oversight Board will &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/11/15/facebook-oversight-body/&quot;&gt;review content removal appeals&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Incentives to meet specific targets such as keeping the prevalence of violating content below some agreed threshold&lt;/strong&gt; – Facebook already &lt;a href=&quot;https://about.fb.com/news/2019/11/community-standards-enforcement-report-nov-2019/&quot;&gt;touts&lt;/a&gt; how 99% of child nudity content and 80% of hate speech removed was detected proactively, and that it deletes 99% of ISIS and Al Qaeda content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_1892467&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; readability=&quot;35&quot;&gt;&lt;img aria-describedby=&quot;caption-attachment-1892467&quot; class=&quot;size-large wp-image-1892467&quot; src=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/gettyimages-961424292.jpg?w=680&quot; alt=&quot;gettyimages 961424292&quot; width=&quot;680&quot; height=&quot;470&quot; srcset=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/gettyimages-961424292.jpg 730w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/gettyimages-961424292.jpg?resize=150,104 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/gettyimages-961424292.jpg?resize=300,208 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/gettyimages-961424292.jpg?resize=680,470 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/gettyimages-961424292.jpg?resize=50,35 50w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p id=&quot;caption-attachment-1892467&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Facebook CEO Mark Zuckerberg at the European Union headquarters in Brussels, May 22, 2018. (Photo credit: JOHN THYS/AFP/Getty Images)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, Facebook asks that the rules for what content should be prohibited on the internet “recognize user preferences and the variation among internet services, can be enforced at scale, and allow for flexibility across language, trends and context.” That’s a lot of leeway. Facebook already allows different content in different geographies to comply with local laws, lets Groups self-police themselves more than the News Feed and Zuckerberg has voiced support for &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2017/02/16/facebook-nudity-filter/&quot;&gt;customizable filters on objectionable content with defaults set by local majorities&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“…Can be enforced at scale” is a last push for laws that wouldn’t require tons of human moderators to enforce what might further drag down Facebook’s share price. “100 billion piece of content come in per day, so don’t make us look at it all.” Investments in safety for elections, content, and cybersecurity &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/29/facebook-earnings-q4-2019/&quot;&gt;already dragged Facebook’s profits down&lt;/a&gt; from growth of 61% year-over-year in 2019 to just 7% in 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be clear, it’s great that Facebook is doing any of this already. Little is formally required. If the company was as evil as some make it out to be, it wouldn’t be doing any of this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then again, Facebook earned $18 billion in profit in 2019 off our data while repeatedly proving it hasn’t adequately protected it. The $5 billion fine and settlement with the FTC where Facebook has pledged to build more around privacy and transparency shows it’s still playing catch-up given its role as a ubiquitous communications utility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s plenty more for EU and hopefully U.S. regulators to investigate. Should Facebook pay a tax on the use of AI? How does it treat and pay its human content moderators? Would requiring users to be &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/12/friends-wherever/&quot;&gt;allowed to export their interoperable friends list&lt;/a&gt; promote much-needed competition in social networking that could let the market compel Facebook to act better?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the EU internal market commissioner Thierry Breton &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/17/facebook-pushes-eu-for-dilute-and-fuzzy-internet-content-rules/&quot;&gt;told reporters&lt;/a&gt; following Zuckerberg’s meetings with regulators, “It’s not for us to adapt to those companies, but for them to adapt to us.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed breakout&quot; readability=&quot;7.3025641025641&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-width=&quot;550&quot; data-dnt=&quot;true&quot; readability=&quot;8.2153846153846&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Unemployment is the top risk of AI. I think a tax on its use by big companies could help pay for job retraining the world will desperately need&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Josh Constine (@JoshConstine) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/JoshConstine/status/1229515851239313408?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;February 17, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 05:44:19 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ajaviaad</dc:creator>
<og:title>Facebook asks for a moat of regulations it already meets – TechCrunch</og:title>
<og:description>It’s suspiciously convenient that Facebook already fulfills most of the regulatory requirements it’s asking governments to lay on the rest of the tech industry. Facebook CEO Mark Zuckerberg is in Brussels lobbying the European Union’s regulators as they form new laws to govern art…</og:description>
<og:image>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/facebook-regulation.png?w=711</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2020/02/17/regulate-facebook/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/17/regulate-facebook/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Real Time Person Removal from Complex Video</title>
<link>https://github.com/jasonmayes/Real-Time-Person-Removal</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/jasonmayes/Real-Time-Person-Removal</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Removing people from complex backgrounds in real time using TensorFlow.js in the web browser using JavaScript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What can this do?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This code attempts to learn over time the makeup of the background of a video such that I can attempt to remove any humans from the scene. This is all happening in real time, in the browser, using TensorFlow.js. #MadeWithTFJS&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an experiment. It may not be perfect in all situations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/4972997/74691149-882fce00-5196-11ea-80bc-f1b9cb3ff275.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/4972997/74691149-882fce00-5196-11ea-80bc-f1b9cb3ff275.gif&quot; alt=&quot;disappearing people&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Live Demos&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go ahead and try it right now in your own web browser. Pick your preference and give me a fork / like :-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Codepen.io: &lt;a href=&quot;https://codepen.io/jasonmayes/pen/GRJqgma&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://codepen.io/jasonmayes/pen/GRJqgma&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glitch.com: &lt;a href=&quot;https://glitch.com/~disappearing-people&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://glitch.com/~disappearing-people&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Usage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to use in your own projects. Code is released under Apache licence. If you decide to use my code please consider giving me a shout out! Would love to see what others create with it :-) Thanks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 05:03:32 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>aliabd</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars1.githubusercontent.com/u/4972997?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>jasonmayes/Real-Time-Person-Removal</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/jasonmayes/Real-Time-Person-Removal</og:url>
<og:description>Removing people from complex backgrounds in real time using TensorFlow.js in the web browser - jasonmayes/Real-Time-Person-Removal</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/jasonmayes/Real-Time-Person-Removal</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>