<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Keyboard Service Program for MacBook and MacBook Pro</title>
<link>https://www.apple.com/support/keyboard-service-program-for-macbook-and-macbook-pro/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.apple.com/support/keyboard-service-program-for-macbook-and-macbook-pro/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Apple has determined that a small percentage of the keyboards in certain MacBook and MacBook Pro models may exhibit one or more of the following behaviors:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;square&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;Letters or characters repeat unexpectedly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Letters or characters do not appear&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Key(s) feel &quot;sticky&quot; or do not respond in a consistent manner&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Apple or an Apple Authorized Service Provider will service eligible MacBook and MacBook Pro keyboards, free of charge. The type of service will be determined after the keyboard is examined and may involve the replacement of one or more keys or the whole keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Eligible Models&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To identify your computer's model and to see if it is eligible for this program, choose Apple () menu &amp;gt; About This Mac. Eligible models are listed below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;square&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;MacBook (Retina, 12-­inch, Early 2015)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MacBook (Retina, 12­-inch, Early 2016)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MacBook (Retina, 12-­inch, 2017)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MacBook Pro (13­-inch, 2016, Two Thunderbolt 3 Ports)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MacBook Pro (13-­inch, 2017, Two Thunderbolt 3 Ports)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MacBook Pro (13-­inch, 2016, Four Thunderbolt 3 Ports)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MacBook Pro (13-­inch, 2017, Four Thunderbolt 3 Ports)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MacBook Pro (15-­inch, 2016)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MacBook Pro (15-­inch, 2017)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Note: No other Mac notebook models are part of this program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Service Process&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please choose one of the options below for service. Your MacBook or MacBook Pro will be examined prior to any service to verify that it is eligible for this program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The type of service will be determined after the keyboard is examined and may involve the replacement of one or more keys or the whole keyboard. The service turn-around time may vary depending upon the type of service and availability of replacement parts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To prepare your unit for service, please &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.apple.com/mac-backup&quot;&gt;backup your data&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: If your MacBook or MacBook Pro has any damage which impairs the service, that issue will need to be repaired first. In some cases, there may be a cost associated with the repair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Additional Information&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This worldwide Apple program does not extend the standard warranty coverage of your MacBook or MacBook Pro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you believe your MacBook or MacBook Pro was affected by this issue, and you paid to have your keyboard repaired, you can &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/support/keyboard-service-program-for-macbook-and-macbook-pro/#cas,prkeys:PF2,cid:SC0998,sid:99980&quot;&gt;contact Apple about a refund&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The program covers eligible MacBook and MacBook Pro models for 4 years after the first retail sale of the unit.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2018 21:05:45 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>minimaxir</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.apple.com/support/keyboard-service-program-for-macbook-and-macbook-pro/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>IRC.com Bought by London Trust Media, Pledges an IRC Revival</title>
<link>https://irc.com</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://irc.com</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;What if I told you, there is a world that values you - for your thoughts, your opinions and who you are?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There is.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's a beautiful world, and for me, more importantly, it is the world that I have to thank for its consequence of keeping me alive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A score ago, I took my first steps into IRC. On cin.il.us.DAL.net, I connected to IRC and somehow found myself in a random IRC channel without any participants. Out of the blue, some random person must have typed /list and found the channel and joined out of curiosity. However it happened, this person who I will never know, spent an hour teaching me how to use IRC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a minority growing up in the middle of America, racism was a thing, and it would be a lie if I said that I never shed a tear over this. In this turbulent world, where but few genes dictate our outer appearance, and chimpanzees share 99% of the same DNA as us, somehow, we're only focused on what our &lt;strong&gt;eyes are see&lt;/strong&gt;ing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On IRC, on the other hand, I was accepted, listened to, and spoken to. IRC adopted me. IRC accepted me. And above all, IRC befriended me, without hesitation. I have met many friends on IRC.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I joined teams, from DALnet help teams to anime fansubbing groups. I was taught how to code. I learned so many different points of views.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IRC truly grew me as a person.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, I'm strong. Today, I'm confident. Today, I am social.&lt;br /&gt;Today, I am patient. Today, I am accepting. Today, I have a cause.&lt;br /&gt;This would not be the case, if yesterday, for me, was not IRC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will do unto others as I would like done to myself. IRC created me. And for this reason, I pledge to revive IRC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IRC, is a transcended level of humanity, that values you for all the other genes and experiences that make you, you - unlike the &quot;real&quot; world which is utterly focused on nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When people tell you, it's what's on the inside that counts, they are telling you to get into IRC. It's a world, that values you, for you. Putting our money where our mouths are, through London Trust Media Holdings and myself, funding, sponsorships, and other contributions have been and will continue to be provided to IRC clients like KiwiIRC and weechat, IRC networks like freenode, snoonet, DALnet, and EuropNet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, I'd like to introduce a few new projects that we are soon launching alongside notable IRC communities:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;IRC.com (A professional, friendly network for huge communities)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IRC University - Free Education for the World (Seeking top expert Ph. D professors to teach - &lt;a href=&quot;mail:hello@irc.com&quot;&gt;email us!&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IRC Gaming (We're going to have literally hundreds of thousands in cash prizes!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IRC Ventures (VC/Incubation on IRC!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IRC Foundation (Donating and supporting existing great IRC projects!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Providing IRC bouncer (always on connectivity) support to all IRC networks and keeping it open!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;In other words, IRC is here, and IRC is &lt;strong&gt;backed&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yours truly,&lt;br /&gt;Andrew Lee&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Co-founder, &lt;a href=&quot;https://londontrustmedia.com/&quot;&gt;London Trust Media Holdings&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2018 17:39:58 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>metabrew</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://irc.com/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Supreme Court Rules Police Need Warrant to Track Your Cellphone</title>
<link>https://www.npr.org/2018/06/22/605007387/supreme-court-rules-police-need-warrant-to-get-location-information-from-cell-to</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.npr.org/2018/06/22/605007387/supreme-court-rules-police-need-warrant-to-get-location-information-from-cell-to</guid>
<description>&lt;div id=&quot;res622546002&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap image large&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;imagewrap&quot; data-crop-type=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2018/06/22/ap_17326610471272_wide-066f86346e1f329dee0cedd309f13a38b92a1e8c-s1100-c15.jpg&quot; data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2018/06/22/ap_17326610471272_wide-066f86346e1f329dee0cedd309f13a38b92a1e8c-s1100.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img lazyOnLoad&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;credit-caption&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-wrap&quot; readability=&quot;6.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image caption&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The U.S. Supreme Court ruled that police need a warrant to obtain cellphone location information routinely collected by wireless providers. &lt;strong class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Carolyn Kaster/AP&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong class=&quot;hide-caption&quot;&gt;hide caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;strong class=&quot;toggle-caption&quot;&gt;toggle caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Carolyn Kaster/AP&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;enlarge_measure&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img_wrap&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2018/06/22/ap_17326610471272_wide-066f86346e1f329dee0cedd309f13a38b92a1e8c-s1200.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;enlarge_html&quot; readability=&quot;6.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image_data&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;The U.S. Supreme Court ruled that police need a warrant to obtain cellphone location information routinely collected by wireless providers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Carolyn Kaster/AP&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Updated at 5:32 p.m. ET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a landmark decision, the U.S. Supreme Court ruled Friday that police must obtain a search warrant to access an individual's cellphone location information. The 5-4 decision imposes new limits on law enforcement's ability to get at the increasing amount of data that private companies amass in the modern technological age.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cellphone providers routinely keep location information for customers to help improve service. And until now, the prevailing legal theory was that if an individual voluntarily shares his information with a third party — for instance, by signing up for cellphone service — police can get that information without a search warrant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A near-perfect tool&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;res622546977&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap internallink insettwocolumn inset2col&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bucket img&quot;&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;featuredStackSquareImage567348000&quot; href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/2017/11/29/567348000/justices-may-impose-new-limits-on-government-access-to-cellphone-data&quot; data-metrics=&quot;{&amp;quot;category&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Story to Story&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;action&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Click Internal Link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;label&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https:\/\/www.npr.org\/2017\/11\/29\/567348000\/justices-may-impose-new-limits-on-government-access-to-cellphone-data&amp;quot;}&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2017/11/29/gettyimages-881766280_sq-24171dff41a0ba50ea93e7ae463e7d53b0bd69e0-s100-c15.jpg&quot; data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2017/11/29/gettyimages-881766280_sq-24171dff41a0ba50ea93e7ae463e7d53b0bd69e0-s100.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img lazyOnLoad&quot; alt=&quot;Justices May Impose New Limits On Government Access To Cellphone Data&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Friday, the Supreme Court blew a hole in that theory. Writing for the court majority, Chief Justice John Roberts said that cellphone location information is a &quot;near perfect&quot; tool for government surveillance, analogous to an electronic monitoring ankle bracelet. The writers of the Constitution, he said, would certainly have understood that an individual has a privacy interest in the day-to-day, hour-to-hour and even minute-to-minute records of his whereabouts — a privacy interest that requires the government to get a search warrant before gaining access to that information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case before the court was brought by Timothy Carpenter, prosecuted as a ringleader in a series of armed robberies in Michigan and Ohio. Cell tower information placed him at the robbery sites, and this information became damning evidence at his trial. Carpenter appealed his conviction, contending that police unconstitutionally invaded his privacy without getting a search warrant first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id=&quot;ad-backstage-wrap&quot; aria-label=&quot;advertisement&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Supreme Court agreed on Friday, declaring that the routine court order that police obtained in Carpenter's case required only a showing that police were seeking relevant information. A search warrant requires that police meet a far higher standard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&quot;Big Brother is coming&quot;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Big Brother is coming and we need to stop it. That seems to be the big takeaway from the opinion,&quot; said Orin Kerr, Fourth Amendment scholar at the University of Southern California. &quot;It almost reflects an anxiety about technology thwarting privacy. If we don't stop the government here, what will they be able to do?&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;This is a landmark privacy case,&quot; said Jameel Jaffer, director of the Knight First Amendment Institute at Columbia University. &quot;It's also a very significant case for First Amendment freedoms — that is, for the freedoms of speech and the press and association. A government that can track your every movement without a warrant is a government that can freely monitor activist political associations, or monitor government employees' contacts with the press.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Jaffer conceded that the decision poses practical problems. &quot;It's going to be hard to apply this framework to new facts,&quot; he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Protecting privacy from progress&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chief Justice Roberts cast the decision as a narrow one. He said it does not disturb &quot;the routine use&quot; of subpoenas to obtain financial, bank and other business records, nor does it prevent police from obtaining cell location records without a warrant in emergency circumstances, such as when police are faced with a fleeing suspect, a kidnapping or threats of imminent danger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roberts also said Friday's decision does not call into question the use of security cameras and other techniques, and it &quot;does not consider other collection techniques involving foreign affairs and national security.&quot; What it does do, he said, is &quot;ensure that the progress of science does not erode the Fourth Amendment&quot; guarantee of privacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roberts, a conservative, was joined in the majority by liberal justices Ruth Bader Ginsburg, Stephen Breyer, Sonia Sotomayor and Elena Kagan. The court's four other conservative justices — Anthony Kennedy, Clarence Thomas, Samuel Alito and Neil Gorsuch — adamantly dissented, each writing separately to indicate his strong disagreement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&quot;A blizzard of litigation&quot;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kennedy's dissent noted that &quot;cell site records are created, kept, owned and controlled by cellphone service providers, who even sell this information to third parties.&quot; Therefore, he said, Carpenter cannot claim ownership or possession of the records and has no control over them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alito chimed in even more strongly. &quot;The Court's reasoning fractures two fundamental pillars of Fourth Amendment law, and in doing so, it guarantees a blizzard of litigation while threatening many legitimate and valuable investigative practices upon which law enforcement has rightfully come to rely,&quot; he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He called the majority decision &quot;mystifying&quot; and &quot;puzzling,&quot; and he noted that service providers routinely charge cellphone users a fee to inspect their own records. &quot;It would be very strange if the owner of the records were required to pay in order to inspect his own property,&quot; Alito said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thomas said that the case should turn not on whether a search occurred but on whose property was searched, and &quot;the Fourth Amendment guarantees individuals the right to be secure from searches of their persons, houses, papers and effects.&quot; Here, he said, the records don't belong to Carpenter but rather to the service provider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gorsuch put forth an entirely different argument that no other member of the court embraced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;An open box&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ed McAndrew, a former federal cybercrime prosecutor, agreed with some of the dissenters' concerns. He noted that cell location information is often gathered in the early stages of an investigation when there isn't enough information for a search warrant. The same is true in terrorism and national security investigations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;The national security context is only going to be different if we're dealing with foreign nationals,&quot; McAndrew said. &quot;If we're dealing with American citizens, the Fourth Amendment principle is going to apply.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, cellphone data are more reliable than more traditional sources of information, he said. &quot;[Data] are better witnesses than human beings ... who may be biased, may be uncooperative, may have a faulty memory.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Justice Breyer, who joined Friday's majority opinion, may have foreseen some of these problems at oral argument. &quot;This is an open box,&quot; he said. &quot;We know not where we go.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Friday's decision may limit the government's access to cellphone data, it has no impact on the ability of private companies to amass, use and sell their customers' information. That is because the Fourth Amendment only limits government conduct, not private conduct. Only Congress, in enacting legislation, can limit how private companies amass and use information.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2018 14:58:51 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>gok</dc:creator>
<og:title>In Major Privacy Win, Supreme Court Rules Police Need Warrant To Track Your Cellphone</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.npr.org/2018/06/22/605007387/supreme-court-rules-police-need-warrant-to-get-location-information-from-cell-to</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>The sharply divided justices ruled that police need a search warrant to obtain cellphone location data.</og:description>
<og:image>https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2018/06/22/ap_17326610471272_wide-066f86346e1f329dee0cedd309f13a38b92a1e8c.jpg?s=1400</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.npr.org/2018/06/22/605007387/supreme-court-rules-police-need-warrant-to-get-location-information-from-cell-to</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Show HN: Material Dashboard – Free Admin for Bootstrap 4, React, Angular, Vue.js</title>
<link>https://github.com/creativetimofficial/material-dashboard</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/creativetimofficial/material-dashboard</guid>
<description>&lt;h3&gt;README.md&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;markdown-body entry-content&quot; itemprop=&quot;text&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/a1e47f0e762084cf4c3d64a5715d936e53669f0c/68747470733a2f2f696d672e736869656c64732e696f2f62616467652f76657273696f6e2d322e312e302d626c75652e737667&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/a1e47f0e762084cf4c3d64a5715d936e53669f0c/68747470733a2f2f696d672e736869656c64732e696f2f62616467652f76657273696f6e2d322e312e302d626c75652e737667&quot; alt=&quot;version&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/version-2.1.0-blue.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/890acbdcb87868b382af9a4b1fac507b9659d9bf/68747470733a2f2f696d672e736869656c64732e696f2f62616467652f6c6963656e73652d4d49542d626c75652e737667&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/890acbdcb87868b382af9a4b1fac507b9659d9bf/68747470733a2f2f696d672e736869656c64732e696f2f62616467652f6c6963656e73652d4d49542d626c75652e737667&quot; alt=&quot;license&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/license-MIT-blue.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/creativetimofficial/material-dashboard/blob/master&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/cf5119bbe70444ce01791efb790539354a5e4ef7/68747470733a2f2f696d672e736869656c64732e696f2f6769746875622f6973737565732f637265617469766574696d6f6666696369616c2f6d6174657269616c2d64617368626f6172642e7376673f6d61784167653d32353932303030&quot; alt=&quot;GitHub issues open&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/issues/creativetimofficial/material-dashboard.svg?maxAge=2592000&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/creativetimofficial/material-dashboard/blob/master&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/f834b420324cae45939928758ed676832535be4f/68747470733a2f2f696d672e736869656c64732e696f2f6769746875622f6973737565732d636c6f7365642d7261772f637265617469766574696d6f6666696369616c2f6d6174657269616c2d64617368626f6172642e7376673f6d61784167653d32353932303030&quot; alt=&quot;GitHub issues closed&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/issues-closed-raw/creativetimofficial/material-dashboard.svg?maxAge=2592000&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitter.im/creative-tim/material-dashboard?utm_source=share-link&amp;amp;utm_medium=link&amp;amp;utm_campaign=share-link&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/eeadf374eecb8ed6f5f3676ff9860f81e64c2b2a/68747470733a2f2f6261646765732e6769747465722e696d2f4e49542d6467702f47656e6572616c2e737667&quot; alt=&quot;Join the chat at https://gitter.im/NIT-dgp/General&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://badges.gitter.im/NIT-dgp/General.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://discord.gg/E4aHAQy&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/b12a95e20b7ca35f918c0ab5103fe56b6f44c067/68747470733a2f2f696d672e736869656c64732e696f2f62616467652f636861742d6f6e253230646973636f72642d3732383964612e737667&quot; alt=&quot;Chat&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/chat-on%20discord-7289da.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/creativetimofficial/material-dashboard/blob/master/assets/github/product.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/creativetimofficial/material-dashboard/raw/master/assets/github/product.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Product Gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Material Dashboard is a free Material Bootstrap Admin with a fresh, new design inspired by Google's Material Design. We are very excited to introduce our take on the material concepts through an easy to use and beautiful set of components. Material Dashboard was built over the popular Bootstrap framework and it comes with a couple of third-party plugins redesigned to fit in with the rest of the elements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Material Dashboard makes use of light, surface and movement. The general layout resembles sheets of paper following multiple different layers, so that the depth and order is obvious. The navigation stays mainly on the left sidebar and the content is on the right inside the main panel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This product came as a result of users asking for a material dashboard after we released our successful &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.creative-tim.com/product/material-kit&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Material Kit&lt;/a&gt;. We developed it based on your feedback and it is a powerful bootstrap admin dashboard, which allows you to build products like admin panels, content managements systems and CRMs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Material Dashboard comes with 5 color filter choices for both the sidebar and the card headers (blue, green, orange, red and purple) and an option to have a background image on the sidebar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Material Dashboard uses a framework built by our friend &lt;a href=&quot;http://fezvrasta.github.io/bootstrap-material-design/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Federico - Bootstrap Material Design&lt;/a&gt;, who did an amazing job creating the backbone for the material effects, animations, ripples and transitions. Big thanks to his team for the effort and forward thinking they put into it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Special thanks go to: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mouse0270/bootstrap-notify&quot;&gt;Robert McIntosh&lt;/a&gt; for the notification system. &lt;a href=&quot;https://gionkunz.github.io/chartist-js/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Chartist&lt;/a&gt; for the wonderful charts. We are very excited to share this dashboard with you and we look forward to hearing your feedback!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find the Github Repo here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Versions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.creative-tim.com/product/material-dashboard&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/creativetimofficial/material-dashboard/raw/master/assets/github/html.png&quot; width=&quot;60&quot; height=&quot;60&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.creative-tim.com/product/material-dashboard-react&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/creativetimofficial/material-dashboard/raw/master/assets/github/react.svg?sanitize=true&quot; width=&quot;60&quot; height=&quot;60&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.creative-tim.com/product/vue-material-dashboard&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/creativetimofficial/material-dashboard/raw/master/assets/github/vuejs.png&quot; width=&quot;60&quot; height=&quot;60&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.creative-tim.com/product/material-dashboard-angular2&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/creativetimofficial/material-dashboard/raw/master/assets/github/angular.png&quot; width=&quot;60&quot; height=&quot;60&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;HTML&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;React&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Vue&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Angular&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.creative-tim.com/product/material-dashboard&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/creativetimofficial/material-dashboard/raw/master/assets/github/opt_md_thumbnail.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Material Dashboard HTML&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.creative-tim.com/product/material-dashboard-react&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/creativetimofficial/material-dashboard/raw/master/assets/github/opt_mdr_thumbnail.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Material Dashboard React&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.creative-tim.com/product/vue-material-dashboard&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/creativetimofficial/material-dashboard/raw/master/assets/github/opt_md_vue_thumbnail.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Vue Material Dashboard &quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.creative-tim.com/product/material-dashboard-angular2&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/creativetimofficial/material-dashboard/raw/master/assets/github/opt_md_angular_thumbnail.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Material Dashboard Angular&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Demo&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://demos.creative-tim.com/material-dashboard/examples/dashboard.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;View More&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Quick start&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick start options:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Documentation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The documentation for the Material Dashboard is hosted at our &lt;a href=&quot;https://demos.creative-tim.com/material-dashboard/docs/2.0/getting-started/introduction.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;File Structure&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within the download you'll find the following directories and files:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;material-dashboard/
├── assets/
|   ├── css/
|   |   ├── bootstrap.min.css
|   |   ├── material-dashboard.css
|   |   └── demo.css
|   ├── js/
|   |   ├── bootstrap-notify.js
|   |   ├── bootstrap.min.js
|   |   ├── chartist.min.js
|   |   ├── demo.js
|   |   ├── jquery-3.1.0.min.js
|   |   ├── material-dashboard.js
|   |   └── material.min.js
|   ├── sass/
|   |    ├── md
|   |    └── material-dashboard.scss
|   └── img/
|
├── documentation/
├── examples/

&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Browser Support&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At present, we officially aim to support the last two versions of the following browsers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/creativetimofficial/material-dashboard/blob/master/assets/github/chrome.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/creativetimofficial/material-dashboard/raw/master/assets/github/chrome.png&quot; width=&quot;64&quot; height=&quot;64&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/creativetimofficial/material-dashboard/blob/master/assets/github/firefox.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/creativetimofficial/material-dashboard/raw/master/assets/github/firefox.png&quot; width=&quot;64&quot; height=&quot;64&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/creativetimofficial/material-dashboard/blob/master/assets/github/edge.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/creativetimofficial/material-dashboard/raw/master/assets/github/edge.png&quot; width=&quot;64&quot; height=&quot;64&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/creativetimofficial/material-dashboard/blob/master/assets/github/safari.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/creativetimofficial/material-dashboard/raw/master/assets/github/safari.png&quot; width=&quot;64&quot; height=&quot;64&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/creativetimofficial/material-dashboard/blob/master/assets/github/opera.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/creativetimofficial/material-dashboard/raw/master/assets/github/opera.png&quot; width=&quot;64&quot; height=&quot;64&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Reporting Issues&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We use GitHub Issues as the official bug tracker for the Material Dashboard. Here are some advices for our users that want to report an issue:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Make sure that you are using the latest version of the Material Dashboard. Check the CHANGELOG from your dashboard on our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.creative-tim.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Providing us reproducible steps for the issue will shorten the time it takes for it to be fixed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some issues may be browser specific, so specifying in what browser you encountered the issue might help.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Technical Support or Questions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have questions or need help integrating the product please &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.creative-tim.com/contact-us&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;contact us&lt;/a&gt; instead of opening an issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Licensing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Useful Links&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More products from Creative Tim: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.creative-tim.com/products&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://www.creative-tim.com/products&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tutorials: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCVyTG4sCw-rOvB9oHkzZD1w&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCVyTG4sCw-rOvB9oHkzZD1w&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Freebies: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.creative-tim.com/products&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://www.creative-tim.com/products&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Affiliate Program (earn money): &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.creative-tim.com/affiliates/new&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://www.creative-tim.com/affiliates/new&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Social Media:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twitter: &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/CreativeTim&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://twitter.com/CreativeTim&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/CreativeTim&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.facebook.com/CreativeTim&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dribbble: &lt;a href=&quot;https://dribbble.com/creativetim&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://dribbble.com/creativetim&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google+: &lt;a href=&quot;https://plus.google.com/+CreativetimPage&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://plus.google.com/+CreativetimPage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instagram: &lt;a href=&quot;https://instagram.com/creativetimofficial&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://instagram.com/creativetimofficial&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2018 12:38:34 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>axelut</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars3.githubusercontent.com/u/20172349?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>creativetimofficial/material-dashboard</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/creativetimofficial/material-dashboard</og:url>
<og:description>material-dashboard - Material Dashboard - Open Source Bootstrap 4 Material Design Admin</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/creativetimofficial/material-dashboard</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Personalisation Is Asymmetric Psychological Warfare</title>
<link>https://shkspr.mobi/blog/2018/06/personalisation-is-asymmetric-psychological-warfare/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://shkspr.mobi/blog/2018/06/personalisation-is-asymmetric-psychological-warfare/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Another privacy nightmare. An &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/what-the-airline-knows-about-the-guy-in-seat-14c-1529499085&quot;&gt;airline wants its cabin crew to know your birthday and favourite drinks order, to better personalise its service to you&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first instinct is to recoil in horror. It sounds like every dystopian sci-fi epic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; do I feel this way? Partly it is the lack of genuine personality behind the interaction. It is the Uncanny Valley of sincerity. When Facebook wishes you happy birthday, it is a purely mechanical response - not an outpouring of genuine feeling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's also the issue of &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; they do this. At a base level, it is money. They want you to feel a positive association with their &quot;brand&quot; so that you will spend money with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They are hijacking your emotions. Nothing new here - the half-naked woman on a billboard trying to get you to buy car insurance, the catchy pop-song designed to make you pick one brand of cola over another, the ruggedly handsome man telling you how white your shirts can be...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But in the airline example, there is a sinister asymmetry. They know &lt;em&gt;everything&lt;/em&gt; about you - and you know &lt;em&gt;nothing&lt;/em&gt; about them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's correct that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine as you get on the plane you smile at the pilot, glance at your phone, and say &quot;Hope this landing is smoother than your last few, Sandra! Still, you should be fine as you only had two gin-and-tonics last night.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the cabin crew serves you a drink &quot;Dave! Can I get more peanuts? I know you're on your final warning from HR - and I'd hate for someone to put in another complaint.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Would paranoid flyers only only get on flights if they knew that the pilot was under 55 years old? Would they refuse to fly if the pilot had recently gone through a divorce and lost custody of their kids?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Would people use social engineering to get an upgrade (&quot;happy birthday flight crew! I baked you your favourite pecan pie!&quot;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of these feel distasteful to me - but it is the logical conclusion. If you want to artificially personalise our markets, we should be able to turn the tables on you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;footer class=&quot;entry-footer&quot;/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2018 12:19:24 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>edent</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Personalisation is Asymmetric Psychological Warfare</og:title>
<og:url>https://shkspr.mobi/blog/2018/06/personalisation-is-asymmetric-psychological-warfare/</og:url>
<og:description>Another privacy nightmare. An airline wants its cabin crew to know your birthday and favourite drinks order, to better personalise its service to you. My first instinct is to recoil in horror. It s…</og:description>
<og:image>https://shkspr.mobi/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/hostess-1046859_640.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-GB</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://shkspr.mobi/blog/2018/06/personalisation-is-asymmetric-psychological-warfare/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Google Engineers Refused to Build Security Tool to Win Military Contracts</title>
<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-06-21/google-engineers-refused-to-build-security-tool-to-win-military-contracts</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-06-21/google-engineers-refused-to-build-security-tool-to-win-military-contracts</guid>
<description>&lt;aside class=&quot;left-column&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;share-article-button&quot; data-variation=&quot;basic-article&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SHARE THIS ARTICLE&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, a group of influential software engineers in Google’s cloud division surprised their superiors by refusing to work on a cutting-edge security feature. Known as “air gap,” the technology would have helped Google win sensitive military contracts. The coders weren’t persuaded their employer should be using its technological might to help the government wage war, according to four current and former employees. After hearing the engineers’ objections, Urs Hölzle, Google’s top technical executive, said the air gap feature would be postponed, one of the people said. Another person familiar with the situation said the group was able to reduce the scope of the feature.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The act of rebellion ricocheted around the company, fueling a growing resistance among employees with a dim view of Google’s yen for multi-million-dollar government contracts. The engineers became known as the “Group of Nine” and were lionized by like-minded staff. The current and former employees say the engineers’ work boycott was a catalyst for larger protests that convulsed the company’s Mountain View, California, campus and ultimately forced executives to let a lucrative Pentagon contract called Project Maven expire without renewal. They declined to name the engineers and requested anonymity to discuss a private matter.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Internal disputes are common at Alphabet  Inc.’s Google, which gives employees ample space to air grievances. But dissent is on the rise (as it is at other tech companies). Last month, in a highly unusual move, a Google employee proposed that executive compensation be tied to efforts to make the company more diverse and inclusive. That proposal was easily voted down by shareholders, but the engineers’ boycott could actually hamper Google’s ability to compete. Big federal contracts often require certification to handle sensitive data—authorizations that rivals Amazon.com Inc. and Microsoft Corp. have, but Google doesn't. Without certain measures including air gap technology, Google may struggle to win portions of the Joint Enterprise Defense Infrastructure, or JEDI, a Pentagon deal worth upwards of $10 billion.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It's unclear if Google has abandoned air gap technology or is still planning to build it over employees’ objections. The feature is not technically very difficult, so Google could easily find other engineers to do the work. While over 4,000 people at the company signed a petition against Project Maven, that’s roughly 5 percent of total full-time staff. A company spokesperson declined to comment. &lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Google cloud chief Diane Greene has expressed continued interest in working with government. Federal agencies are among the largest spenders on corporate computing and starting to gravitate toward cloud services. In March, Greene and her deputies &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.blog.google/topics/google-cloud/extending-gcp-security-us-government-customers-through-fedramp-authorization/&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;proudly touted&lt;/a&gt; Google's new approvals under FedRAMP, federal compliance standards for information technology. Google was approved FedRAMP “Moderate,” a designation required for almost 80 percent of government cloud contracts. Google cloud staff said internally that the Project Maven deal was “fast-tracking” higher FedRAMP authorization, according to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://gizmodo.com/google-plans-not-to-renew-its-contract-for-project-mave-1826488620&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;Gizmodo report&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now, Google falls short of rivals. Both Microsoft's Azure and Amazon Web Services (AWS) have “High” certificates that authorize them to hold sensitive or classified data and sell to bodies like the Central Intelligence Agency. To do so, both companies had to set up a separate service called a government cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A critical component of that service is the air gap. Put simply, it physically separates computers from others on a network. So rather than store data from multiple companies on a single server or system, as the commercial cloud providers typically do, a company or agency can place its data and computing processes in isolation on a single piece of hardware. That separation is particularly desirable for agencies in national security, says Michael Carter, vice president of Coalfire, a cybersecurity firm. “Amazon and Azure can literally say, ‘This is your rack,’” he says. “In the government, they want to know where their data is. So if you want to wipe it, go wipe it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In sales pitches, Google touts the security features of its cloud service. In a March press briefing, company executives noted how their artificial intelligence software could spot cybersecurity attacks early. “We think that Google cloud is today the most secure cloud out there,” Hölzle said during the briefing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The entities most likely to require air-gap security systems are government agencies or financial firms. While experts debate the technology’s merits, it does give customers “psychological” comfort, according to Jim Reavis, who runs Cloud Security Alliance, an industry group. “They’re used to having their own computer that they look at, their own blinking light,” he says. “I do question whether or not that’s useful security.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greene and other Google executives will have to persuade employees it’s possible to bid for government contracts without violating Google’s new ethical standards. After pledging not to renew the Project Maven contract, which involves using artificial intelligence to analyze drone footage, the company &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-06-07/google-renounces-ai-for-weapons-but-will-still-sell-to-military&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;issued&lt;/a&gt; a set of AI principles this month that prohibit weapons work. But they don’t rule out selling to the military, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-06-04/google-staff-ai-revolt-puts-pentagon-cloud-deals-in-jeopardy&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Google continues to pursue&lt;/a&gt; other Defense Department cloud contracts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We are still doing everything we can within these guidelines to support our government, the military and our veterans,” Greene wrote in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.blog.google/topics/google-cloud/incorporating-googles-ai-principles-google-cloud/&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt; on June 7. “For example, we will continue to work with government organizations on cybersecurity, productivity tools, healthcare, and other forms of cloud initiatives.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several Googlers protesting Project Maven have complained about poor communication from senior leaders. Most staff outside the cloud unit were unaware of the contract until February—five months after it was signed—when questions about the deal began circulating more widely on internal message boards. At one point, Greene told staff the deal was worth a meager $9 million. Subsequent reports revealed Google expected the contract to rake in $15 million and grow to as much as $250 million.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google has yet to address these reports publicly. But on June 8, a day after the company issued its ethical charter, Greene addressed the discrepancy in an internal note. “In speaking about Maven, I did not always have accurate information,” she wrote in an email viewed by Bloomberg News. “For example, I said the contract was $9 [million] when it actually was a different number.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google employees have a history of objecting on ethical grounds. After the Edward Snowden revelations in 2013, several engineers confronted Hölzle about allegations the company had assisted the government in its surveillance program. They threatened to resign, telling Hölzle, “this isn't why we signed up for the company,” according to a former senior executive who attended the meeting. Hölzle voiced his support for the engineers, this person says.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The latest confrontation at Google coincides with growing concern about the entire industry’s relationship with the U.S. government. Civil rights groups have targeted Amazon for selling facial recognition tech to police departments. Microsoft faced similar heat for its work with the U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some Google employees resigned over the Project Maven deal. Tyler Breisacher, a software developer on Google infrastructure who left in April, cited the lack of clear communications about the contract and how Google's software was being used. Management, he says, appeared surprised at the response from employees once they shared more about the program. “It seems like they weren't expecting it to be as controversial as it was,” he says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Breisacher, who joined Google in 2011, says the company has changed. Earlier, if employees felt a decision was bad for Google, its users or the broader world, they had their leaders’ ears. “It felt like you were really listened to,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;inline-newsletter&quot; data-state=&quot;ready&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Greene wrote in the internal email that she wanted to address the “trust issue that has developed” in the past five months. She said she regretted not emailing earlier to correct her misstatement about the size of the Project Maven deal. “In the past, I would have,” Greene wrote, “but in the current climate of leaks, the sense was that it would be a mistake to do because the correction would leak and start another ‘press cycle’ that would not be good for any of us.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;— With assistance by Alistair Barr, and Naomi Nix&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(&lt;span itemprop=&quot;description&quot;&gt;Updates with cloud CEO comment in 11th paragraph.&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2018 04:18:27 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>dsr12</dc:creator>
<og:description>A work boycott from the Group of Nine is yet another hurdle to the company’s efforts to compete for sensitive government work.</og:description>
<og:image>https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/i674AyUcypO0/v0/1200x900.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>Google Engineers Refused to Build Security Tool to Win Military Contracts</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-06-21/google-engineers-refused-to-build-security-tool-to-win-military-contracts</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-06-21/google-engineers-refused-to-build-security-tool-to-win-military-contracts</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>One Island Grows 80% of the World’s Vanilla</title>
<link>https://www.atlasobscura.com/articles/where-is-vanilla-grown</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.atlasobscura.com/articles/where-is-vanilla-grown</guid>
<description>&lt;img class=&quot;article-image with-structured-caption lazy&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.atlasobscura.com/assets/blank-11b9c95a68e295dddd0ea924647536578ce285b2c8469a223c01df1ff3166af1.png&quot; alt=&quot;The economics of vanilla are complicated and grim.&quot; width=&quot;auto&quot; data-kind=&quot;article-image&quot; id=&quot;article-image-56809&quot; data-src=&quot;https://assets.atlasobscura.com/article_images/56809/image.jpg&quot;/&gt;The economics of vanilla are complicated and grim. &lt;a class=&quot;caption-credit&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.gettyimages.com/license/965725146&quot;&gt;Gamma-Rapho/Getty Images&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;item-body-text-graf&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;section-start-text&quot;&gt;Last week, the Wisconsin-based business&lt;/span&gt; Penzey’s Spices sent out emails emblazoned with a frown emoji. The occasion was a several dollars per ounce hike in the price of vanilla. Founder Bill Penzey wrote a brief explanation: Madagascar, where &lt;a href=&quot;http://time.com/5308143/vanilla-price-climate-change-madagascar/&quot;&gt;80 percent of the world’s vanilla&lt;/a&gt; comes from, has been going through a rough patch. A perfect storm of drought and a pair of cyclones hit vanilla farmers hard. The rippling effects have disrupted everything from the supply chains of massive multinational companies to the flavoring in fudge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;item-body-text-graf&quot;&gt;But how did one island come to dominate the vanilla industry? And why is one kilogram of “plain vanilla” now more valuable than &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.com/news/business-44006176?ns_campaign=bbcnews&amp;amp;ns_source=twitter&amp;amp;ocid=socialflow_twitter&amp;amp;ns_mchannel=social&quot;&gt;one kilogram of silver&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;article-image with-structured-caption lazy&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.atlasobscura.com/assets/blank-11b9c95a68e295dddd0ea924647536578ce285b2c8469a223c01df1ff3166af1.png&quot; alt=&quot;A flowering &amp;lt;em&amp;gt;Vanilla planiflolia.&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&quot; width=&quot;auto&quot; data-kind=&quot;article-image&quot; id=&quot;article-image-56778&quot; data-src=&quot;https://assets.atlasobscura.com/article_images/56778/image.jpg&quot;/&gt;A flowering &lt;em&gt;Vanilla planiflolia.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;caption-credit&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/mmmavocado/6998639545&quot;&gt;mmmavocado/CC BY 2.0&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;item-body-text-graf&quot;&gt;After all, vanilla isn’t even native to Madagascar. The main source of vanilla is the &lt;em&gt;Vanilla planiflolia&lt;/em&gt; orchid. Long cultivated in Mexico, the flavoring from its long pods was used in rituals and in the traditional Aztec drink of ground, spiced chocolate. As Spain’s conquistadors dismantled the Aztec empire in the 16th century, they sent Mexican silver, chocolate, and vanilla back to Europe. Vanilla, with its floral, subtle taste, quickly became a favorite, especially as an accompaniment to chocolate and cream. But when Europeans tried to grow it in their botanical gardens &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.smithsonianmag.com/science-nature/bittersweet-story-vanilla-180962757/&quot;&gt;and their colonies&lt;/a&gt;, the long pods didn’t develop. Vanilla’s main pollinator was back in Mexico: the Melipona bee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;article-image with-structured-caption lazy&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.atlasobscura.com/assets/blank-11b9c95a68e295dddd0ea924647536578ce285b2c8469a223c01df1ff3166af1.png&quot; alt=&quot;A vanilla orchid climbing a forest tree.&quot; width=&quot;auto&quot; data-kind=&quot;article-image&quot; id=&quot;article-image-56776&quot; data-src=&quot;https://assets.atlasobscura.com/article_images/56776/image.jpg&quot;/&gt;A vanilla orchid climbing a forest tree. &lt;a class=&quot;caption-credit&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/dinesh_valke/6935168603&quot;&gt;dinesh_valke/CC BY-SA 2.0&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;item-body-text-graf&quot;&gt;Without pollination, vanilla production was mostly limited to Mexico. But other regions were desperate to grow valuable vanilla, and plants were shipped to likely climates around the world. In 1841, one young innovator figured out an unlikely solution. Edmond Albius was a 12-year-old slave on the French-controlled island of Réunion, in the Indian Ocean. Using a stick and his thumb, Albius pushed together the male anthers and female stigma of the vanilla flower, pollinating it efficiently. Mass vanilla production suddenly became possible, especially in hot, humid climates. Tiny Réunion fits the bill, but so does another, much larger island a few hundred miles to the east: Madagascar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;item-body-text-graf&quot;&gt;The reason that Madagascar is still on top of the vanilla game is grim: According to &lt;em&gt;The Financial Times,&lt;/em&gt; it’s one of the few regions with the right climate that is also poor enough to make laborious &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ft.com/content/02042190-65bc-11e8-90c2-9563a0613e56&quot;&gt;hand-pollination affordable&lt;/a&gt;. While other countries, such as India, have dabbled in heavy vanilla production, huge swings in the international price make it a dangerous crop to grow widely. Many farmers choose to stick to other crops. This concentration of vanilla production makes the industry and prices even more precarious—currently, events in Madagascar have led to some ice cream parlors losing money on each scoop of vanilla.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;article-image with-structured-caption lazy&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.atlasobscura.com/assets/blank-11b9c95a68e295dddd0ea924647536578ce285b2c8469a223c01df1ff3166af1.png&quot; alt=&quot;In Madagascar, cured vanilla pods are sorted for sale.&quot; width=&quot;auto&quot; data-kind=&quot;article-image&quot; id=&quot;article-image-56775&quot; data-src=&quot;https://assets.atlasobscura.com/article_images/56775/image.jpg&quot;/&gt;In Madagascar, cured vanilla pods are sorted for sale. &lt;a class=&quot;caption-credit&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Woman_sorting_vanilla_in_Sambava_Madagascar.jpg&quot;&gt;Lemurbaby/CC BY-SA 3.0&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;item-body-text-graf item-body-last&quot;&gt;Vanilla has long been one of the world’s priciest seasonings. Artificial vanillas have abounded for centuries, made with everything from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.atlasobscura.com/foods/castoreum-beaver-musk-vanilla&quot;&gt;beaver pelvis glands&lt;/a&gt; to petroleum products. But with demand for natural flavors booming, high prices are inspiring vanilla heists everywhere from farms in Madagascar to spice &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.woodtv.com/news/kent-county/woman-accused-of-embezzling-139k-in-vanilla-beans/1220376883&quot;&gt;companies in Michigan&lt;/a&gt;. Though a little vanilla goes a long way, there’s no sign that our craving for vanilla is going anywhere soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Gastro Obscura covers the world’s most wondrous food and drink.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.atlasobscura.com/newsletters/gastro-obscura&quot;&gt;Sign up for our email, delivered twice a week&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2018 03:54:15 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>sndean</dc:creator>
<og:title>Why One Island Grows 80% of the World's Vanilla</og:title>
<og:url>http://www.atlasobscura.com/articles/where-is-vanilla-grown</og:url>
<og:image>https://assets.atlasobscura.com/media/W1siZiIsInVwbG9hZHMvYXNzZXRzL2U3ZGZjODA3LTJlMzMtNGM1Mi1iNDhmLTM2NzhkMDkxNTA2ZDI0OWUyZDU0YzUxYjAxMjVmNF9HZXR0eUltYWdlcy05NjU3MjUxNDYuanBnIl0sWyJwIiwiY29udmVydCIsIi1xdWFsaXR5IDgxIC1hdXRvLW9yaWVudCJdLFsicCIsInRodW1iIiwiNjAweD4iXV0/GettyImages-965725146.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>Now, it's more valuable than silver.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.atlasobscura.com/articles/where-is-vanilla-grown</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Twitter ‘smytes’ customers</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2018/06/21/twitter-smytes-customers/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2018/06/21/twitter-smytes-customers/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/twitter/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;twitter&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; today &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/06/21/twitter-acquires-anti-abuse-technology-provider-smyte/&quot;&gt;announced it was acquiring&lt;/a&gt; the “trust and safety as a service” startup &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.smyte.com/solutions&quot;&gt;Smyte&lt;/a&gt; to help it better address issues related to online abuse, harassment, spam, and security on its platform. But it also decided to immediately shut down access to &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/smyte/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;smyte&quot;&gt;Smyte’s&lt;/a&gt; API without warning, leaving Smyte’s existing customers no time to transition to a new service provider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The change left Smyte’s current customer base stranded, with production issues related to the safety of their own platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Needless to say, many were not happy about this situation and took to Twitter to register their complaints.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Smyte’s website, its clients included Indiegogo, GoFundMe, npm, Musical.ly, TaskRabbit, Meetup, OLX, ThredUp, YouNow, 99 Designs, Carousell, and Zendesk – big name brands that used Smyte’s feature set in a variety of ways to combat fraud, abuse, harassment, scams, spam, and other security issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Twitter had earlier told TechCrunch that it would be “winding down” Smyte’s business with existing clients, what that apparently meant was that it was going to announce the acquisition, then effectively shut off the lights over at Smyte and leave everyone in the lurch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to reports from those affected, Smyte disabled access to its API with very little warning to clients, and without giving them time to prepare. Customers got a phone call, and then – boom – the service was gone. Clients had multi-year contracts in some cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And again, to reiterate, Smyte is a provider of anti-abuse and anti-fraud protections – not something any business would shut off overnight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In npm’s case, it even led to a production outage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twitter declined to comment, but we understand it was making phone calls to affected Smyte customers today to match them with new service providers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The decision to &lt;del&gt;smite&lt;/del&gt; &lt;em&gt;smyte&lt;/em&gt; an existing customer base the minute the startup joined Twitter isn’t a good look for either company, and is especially ironic in light of Twitter’s promises of “trust and safety” improvements in the months to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trust, huh?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s how it works?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed breakout&quot; readability=&quot;9.1028938906752&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-width=&quot;550&quot; data-dnt=&quot;true&quot; readability=&quot;11.498392282958&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Holy shit Twitter bought Smyte and immediately shut it down. We had a 3 years contract with them and they just disappeared overnight. No communication at all, they just turned their servers off, closed our shared support channel and walked away. What the actual fuck&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Giacomo Gatelli (@arthens) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/arthens/status/1009925187364458496?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;June 21, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed breakout&quot; readability=&quot;7.3254545454545&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-width=&quot;550&quot; data-dnt=&quot;true&quot; readability=&quot;8.6181818181818&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Wait…so did &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/HelloSmyte?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@HelloSmyte&lt;/a&gt; just shut down it's service entirely today with no warning after &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Twitter?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@Twitter&lt;/a&gt; bought them? What about their customers that rely on them for advanced moderation and the safety of their platforms? &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/smyte?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#smyte&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Michael Ehinger (@MichaelEhinger) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/MichaelEhinger/status/1009839657222361088?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;June 21, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed breakout&quot; readability=&quot;8.5821428571429&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-width=&quot;550&quot; data-dnt=&quot;true&quot; readability=&quot;10.489285714286&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;A vendor notified us of their acquisition at 6am this morning and shut down their APIs 30 minutes later, creating a production outage for npm (package publishes and user registrations). The sheer unprofessionalism of this is blowing my mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Laurie Voss (@seldo) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/seldo/status/1009873821141118976?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;June 21, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed breakout&quot; readability=&quot;8.0830188679245&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-width=&quot;550&quot; data-dnt=&quot;true&quot; readability=&quot;9.5094339622642&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;It takes weeks to negotiate and sign an acquisition. You didn't find out at 6am. You couldn't give us a week? Even a couple of hours to take your service out of our critical path and avoid an outage? Fucking shocking behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Laurie Voss (@seldo) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/seldo/status/1009874222154305537?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;June 21, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed breakout&quot; readability=&quot;7.4583333333333&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-width=&quot;550&quot; data-dnt=&quot;true&quot; readability=&quot;8.390625&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Damage is done already anyway. We had the same experience; luckily we were only using them in an async capacity so it didn't take us offline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Jeff Goldschrafe (@jgoldschrafe) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jgoldschrafe/status/1009947081987878912?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;June 21, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;embed breakout&quot; readability=&quot;7.5377358490566&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-width=&quot;550&quot; data-dnt=&quot;true&quot; readability=&quot;8.8679245283019&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Hey &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/HelloSmyte?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@HelloSmyte&lt;/a&gt; , it's a massive bummer that you couldn't give your customers any notice before turning everything off. Is there anything you can do to help us out?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Dennis Hotson (@dennishotson) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/dennishotson/status/1009798866743394305?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;June 21, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed breakout&quot; readability=&quot;6.7723880597015&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-width=&quot;550&quot; data-dnt=&quot;true&quot; readability=&quot;7.2238805970149&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Thanks for just shutting off service at 615am this morning with 7 minutes notice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Curtis Schofield (@curtisjennings) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/curtisjennings/status/1009846671746916352?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;June 21, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed breakout&quot; readability=&quot;9.0740740740741&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-width=&quot;550&quot; data-dnt=&quot;true&quot; readability=&quot;11.796296296296&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;This was the worst experience, especially with an acquisition, that we've ever encountered with a partner. We were given less than a half an hour notice before the entire system was shut down, leading to immediate payflow &amp;amp; platform issues with a hefty cost &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/nokok?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#nokok&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/Smyte?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#Smyte&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/fail?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#fail&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Kerry Barker (@kerryjunebug) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/kerryjunebug/status/1010015074310688768?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;June 22, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update, 6/22/18. 3:42 PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twitter has released a statement regarding this situation, which was shared via the Twitter account of Mike Montano, VP of Twitter’s Engineering team, just now. He writes “There have been concerns around how we’re transitioning Smyte’s customers. We could have done better and are learning from this experience. Here’s the email I just sent to our team.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The full email and tweet is below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed breakout&quot; readability=&quot;7.2101167315175&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-width=&quot;550&quot; data-dnt=&quot;true&quot; readability=&quot;8.4824902723735&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;There have been concerns around how we're transitioning Smyte's customers. We could have done better and are learning from this experience. Here's the email I just sent to our team. &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/5GPWAjScGE&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/5GPWAjScGE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Mike Montano (@michaelmontano) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/michaelmontano/status/1010246307984769024?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;June 22, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2018 03:28:51 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>panarky</dc:creator>
<og:title>Twitter ‘smytes’ customers</og:title>
<og:description>Twitter today announced it was acquiring the “trust and safety as a service” startup Smyte to help it better address issues related to online abuse, harassment, spam, and security on its platform. But it also decided to immediately shut down access to Smyte’s API without warning, …</og:description>
<og:image>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/gettyimages-668798001.jpg?w=602</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2018/06/21/twitter-smytes-customers/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2018/06/21/twitter-smytes-customers/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>I Stop Celebrities from Blowing Their Money</title>
<link>https://www.thecut.com/2018/06/how-do-celebrities-spend-their-money.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.thecut.com/2018/06/how-do-celebrities-spend-their-money.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;clay-paragraph&quot; data-editable=&quot;text&quot; data-uri=&quot;www.thecut.com/_components/clay-paragraph/instances/cjineenn6000lymyes94oyl84@published&quot; data-word-count=&quot;83&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;After rising through the ranks at a Hollywood business management agency, Kristin Lee founded her own accounting firm,&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://klbmllc.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;KLBM&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Today, the 35 year-old manages finances for mix of high-level artists and entertainers — actors, recording artists, producers, writers, and athletes with personal net worths ranging from $1 million to $50 million (and no, she can’t name names). Here, she talks to My Two Cents columnist Charlotte Cowles about what it’s like to handle celebrities’ money — and keep them from blowing it all.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;clay-paragraph&quot; data-editable=&quot;text&quot; data-uri=&quot;www.thecut.com/_components/clay-paragraph/instances/cjineeq4f001639604wwoyh21@published&quot; data-word-count=&quot;117&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I know many things about my clients&lt;/strong&gt; that nobody else does, even their families and closest friends. Business managers are all-seeing. For example, we get all of our clients’ mail — bills, fan mail, business-related mail, everything. Nothing goes to their homes. One reason for that is to protect their privacy, but we also want to be the first and main point of contact for anything financial. We oversee payments for their mortgages, phone, rent, utilities, and all the little things that keep their lives going and the lights on. Our clients could be anywhere in the world, on set somewhere or on tour for months, and we don’t want that stuff stacking up in their houses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;clay-paragraph&quot; data-editable=&quot;text&quot; data-uri=&quot;www.thecut.com/_components/clay-paragraph/instances/cjineeq7i001l39604znpdfjh@published&quot; data-word-count=&quot;102&quot;&gt;I do a lot of hand-holding. Sometimes a client will call me and ask, “What’s my Social Security number? Can you send me my insurance card?” Or, “How much money do I have?” These are intelligent people, but they are artists, and some of them want to keep the business aspect at arm’s length. I just want to make sure they’re being smart. They might have gotten an eight-digit advance to make an album, but that album cycle — including a tour and everything — could be two years long, so the advance has to last. And everyone always forgets about taxes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside data-uri=&quot;www.thecut.com/_components/pull-quote/instances/cjioi9jao00113i602dzvfc56@published&quot; class=&quot;pull-quote&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; data-editable=&quot;inlineGroup&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;I do a lot of hand-holding. Sometimes a client will call me and ask, “What’s my Social Security number?”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;clay-paragraph&quot; data-editable=&quot;text&quot; data-uri=&quot;www.thecut.com/_components/clay-paragraph/instances/cjineeq5h00193960rwjyg4ta@published&quot; data-word-count=&quot;133&quot;&gt;Overspending can happen so fast. Most of my clients blow money on pretty standard stuff: the fancy cars, the house, the home renovations, the clothes, the shoes, feeling the need to add extra personnel or production to things. They like to hit their Soho House and their clubs and treat everybody. I recently got an Amex bill for one of my clients who had spent more than $3,000 in one night at 1 Oak. I got worried that it was fraudulent, because he doesn’t normally do that kind of thing, and when I texted him to ask, he felt so guilty. He was like, “Oh God, I was so out of control that night. I was buying drinks for everyone. I can’t believe I did that.” It’s hard to not get swept up.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;clay-paragraph&quot; data-editable=&quot;text&quot; data-uri=&quot;www.thecut.com/_components/clay-paragraph/instances/cjineeq5e00183960sxo51zhc@published&quot; data-word-count=&quot;103&quot;&gt;I’ve trained most of my clients to call me before they do anything frivolous. I would much rather get the phone call saying, “Hey, I really, really, really want to buy this vintage Porsche,” instead of, “Hey, I just bought this vintage Porsche.” Most of the time, I can talk them off the ledge if it’s a bad idea. I’ll say, “You &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt;, but I wouldn’t.” They respect my opinion when I say, “I would not do this personally,” and that’s gratifying. But I hate getting the phone call &lt;em&gt;after&lt;/em&gt; money’s already gone. Then there’s a cash crunch that’s a mess to fix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;clay-paragraph&quot; data-editable=&quot;text&quot; data-uri=&quot;www.thecut.com/_components/clay-paragraph/instances/cjineeq5j001a3960umgmh4zc@published&quot; data-word-count=&quot;119&quot;&gt;I don’t want to blame anything on the Kardashians, but the pressure to emulate that lifestyle is infectious, and some of my clients don’t realize that other celebrities are getting a lot of stuff for free. There are celebrities who get paid to be courtside at basketball games, $25,000 or $50,000 just to sit there for two hours. And not only that, they’ll get an entire box of designer clothes shipped to their house so they can pick out what to wear, for free. It’s impossible to keep up with that, but it’s natural to want to. My clients experience the same social pressures that we all feel, in normal life, except for them it’s amplified and more public.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;clay-paragraph&quot; data-editable=&quot;text&quot; data-uri=&quot;www.thecut.com/_components/clay-paragraph/instances/cjineeq5l001b39606hayvvo8@published&quot; data-word-count=&quot;174&quot;&gt;I’ve had clients fight me when I say that they can’t afford something. In those cases, I will insist that they put it in writing. I will ask them to email me so that I can write back to say that I think their decision is unwise, because I’ve got to cover myself. I don’t want to end up being in the news, like, “My business manager let me spend all of my money,” when I didn’t. Right now, I have a client who’s doing really well, and he’s been hanging out with a bunch of high-level entertainment guys who fly around on jets and have multiple homes. My client isn’t at that point yet, but he’s gotten a taste of it, and now every two weeks he wants to talk about buying some crazy villa in Hawaii or Spain. I’m just trying to hold him off from doing it for as long as I can, but at a certain point there will be nothing I can do to stop him. It’s his money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;clay-paragraph&quot; data-editable=&quot;text&quot; data-uri=&quot;www.thecut.com/_components/clay-paragraph/instances/cjineeq5c00173960i1py1mzy@published&quot; data-word-count=&quot;69&quot;&gt;When I have to be the naysayer, I do try to be very honest. I once got a client’s Amex bill with a weird $60,000 charge on it, and he was like, “Oh yeah, I bought a couple of Jet Skis.” I was like, “What?!” And he had been riding them around uninsured! I was like, “Oh, that’s so bad. All of it.” I don’t work with him anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;clay-paragraph&quot; data-editable=&quot;text&quot; data-uri=&quot;www.thecut.com/_components/clay-paragraph/instances/cjineeq5p001c39607hzxi83r@published&quot; data-word-count=&quot;86&quot;&gt;One thing that’s surprisingly &lt;em&gt;in&lt;/em&gt;expensive for a lot of our clients is health insurance. The insurance policy for members of SAG-AFTRA is amazing. For the money, it is the best health insurance out there. It’s only about $400 per quarter for an individual, so you’re looking at about $1,200 or $1,500 a year for the best PPO coverage in the country. It travels with you everywhere, and you have access to emergency care facilities and 24/7 mental-health care. It’s great. I wish I could get it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;clay-paragraph&quot; data-editable=&quot;text&quot; data-uri=&quot;www.thecut.com/_components/clay-paragraph/instances/cjineeq6e001d396075f48nnc@published&quot; data-word-count=&quot;75&quot;&gt;I try to make clients take ownership of their money. I’m big on communication. I’ll say, “You spent $6,000 on Ubers this month. If you keep doing that, you’ll spend $72,000 on Ubers this year.” It’s not about shaming anyone. It’s just about helping them take a step back and think, &lt;em&gt;Okay. Where would I rather be spending this money? Or maybe I’m okay with this expense, but I need to cut back somewhere else.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;clay-paragraph&quot; data-editable=&quot;text&quot; data-uri=&quot;www.thecut.com/_components/clay-paragraph/instances/cjineeq6m001f3960zsv7dxjp@published&quot; data-word-count=&quot;102&quot;&gt;The old-school accountant approach is to protect clients from themselves. Like, “We don’t want them to know this money’s here, because then they will spend it.” I understand that, but I disagree with it. I think the better approach is to educate clients, not shield them like they’re children who can’t make decisions for themselves. Sometimes we’ll get a client who says, “I don’t even have a log-in to my bank account,” and that’s just bananas to me. They have a right to know what’s coming in and going out. I don’t think that they need to be treated with kid gloves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;clay-paragraph&quot; data-editable=&quot;text&quot; data-uri=&quot;www.thecut.com/_components/clay-paragraph/instances/cjineeq6j001e3960dolwqq7h@published&quot; data-word-count=&quot;100&quot;&gt;It is easy to become enmeshed in clients’ lives. I had one client who was young and impressionable and became very successful very quickly, and he was getting pulled in different directions by the people around him. He and I clicked and became very close. He bought a house and was away a lot, so I was at his house every single day, helping to oversee contractors, pick out windows, pick out drapes. I was a big part of his life. He died suddenly, and it crushed me. I felt like I had failed him, or could have done more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;clay-paragraph&quot; data-editable=&quot;text&quot; data-uri=&quot;www.thecut.com/_components/clay-paragraph/instances/cjineeq6n001g39600gqlk618@published&quot; data-word-count=&quot;110&quot;&gt;Sometimes I do need to intervene with a client and say, “Hey, business aside, as a friend and someone who cares about you, I think you’re making some bad life decisions right now. Maybe it’s time to make some changes.” I had to stop working with a client after having that conversation with him. He decided to step out of the entertainment industry for a while and focus on himself and his health. I was like, “I think that’s great,” and we parted ways. So it was a positive thing, overall. Mental health can be a major concern; if a client is in a dark bad place, they often can’t work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;clay-paragraph&quot; data-editable=&quot;text&quot; data-uri=&quot;www.thecut.com/_components/clay-paragraph/instances/cjineeq6p001i3960ralxy5cs@published&quot; data-word-count=&quot;222&quot;&gt;When I get a client who’s the next big thing, everyone wants a piece of it, and people come out of the woodwork. Not everyone has good intentions. I see a lot of opportunistic businesspeople as well as toxic relationships. The latter can be tough. My client will have this hot new girlfriend and he’s all about her, but I’m like, “She is actually bleeding you dry.” I saw a woman come out of nowhere and start dating one of my clients when he was at the top of his game. She’d never even seen him perform or heard of his music or anything, but she moved to L.A. and picked out their house and all this new furniture. They had a huge wedding. Then, when the money dried up, she completely bailed. It was one of the grossest things I’ve ever seen. I would love to give everybody the benefit of the doubt, but our clients are extra exposed. And I feel for them; it’s got to be difficult to wonder, &lt;em&gt;Does this person love me for my money and my status, or do they love&lt;/em&gt; me? And of course, I don’t have the right to tell anybody, “I think this person is bad for you.” I’d probably be fired. When people are in love, they don’t want to hear it.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p class=&quot;clay-paragraph&quot; data-editable=&quot;text&quot; data-uri=&quot;www.thecut.com/_components/clay-paragraph/instances/cjineeq6o001h3960j8avyttb@published&quot; data-word-count=&quot;74&quot;&gt;I encourage my clients to save, and also to reinvest in themselves. That might mean funding a new business venture or taking acting lessons; it’s important that they’re staying in touch with their creativity. I don’t want one of my clients to wake up one day and say, “I’m tired of the entertainment business. I just want to disappear.” People get burnt out, and trying something new is not easy, especially if you’re famous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;clay-paragraph&quot; data-editable=&quot;text&quot; data-uri=&quot;www.thecut.com/_components/clay-paragraph/instances/cjineeq7c001j3960pnwecydi@published&quot; data-word-count=&quot;115&quot;&gt;Luckily, I haven’t had any clients get seriously blackmailed. I once had a client who left his laptop with all his music on it in the back of an SUV in Las Vegas, and the driver was trying to get us to pay him to give it back. We ended up giving him a little bit of money as a thank-you, but not what he initially asked for. Recently, we’ve had threats made against some of our female artists. We called the FBI and the LAPD and beefed up security. You can’t take these things as empty threats. It costs extra money to take precautions, but it’s better to know you’re doing everything you can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;clay-paragraph&quot; data-editable=&quot;text&quot; data-uri=&quot;www.thecut.com/_components/clay-paragraph/instances/cjineeq7h001k3960ilngs3yj@published&quot; data-word-count=&quot;132&quot;&gt;I don’t really get envious of what my clients have. After a while, the dollar amounts become kind of abstract. Numbers are numbers, and they don’t lie — they all add up, and that’s the most important thing at the end of the day. I focus on accuracy. The clients are human beings; they’re not defined by their contracts or their salary. So I try not to think about that too much, and my own life is pretty good. I charge a 5 percent commission rate, which is pretty standard, and I’m happy with where we are and what I have. Every once in a while I’m like, “Damn, that’s a nice car. That would be fun to own.” But I think that’s human nature, and I know I don’t need it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;single-related-story&quot; data-uri=&quot;www.thecut.com/_components/single-related-story/instances/cjioi1xv600113i60gljcepny@published&quot; data-editable=&quot;url&quot; data-track-type=&quot;article-list&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;single-related-story-label&quot;&gt;Related&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;single-related-story-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.thecut.com/2018/04/what-its-really-like-to-have-a-trust-fund.html&quot; data-track-type=&quot;article-link&quot; data-track-component-name=&quot;single-related-story&quot; data-track-page-uri=&quot;www.thecut.com/_pages/cjgmf75d800yb0uy6d7n3towe@published&quot; data-track-headline=&quot;What It’s Really Like to Have a Trust Fund&quot; data-track-component-title=&quot;related&quot;&gt;What It’s Really Like to Have a Trust Fund&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2018 01:04:22 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>wallflower</dc:creator>
<og:title>I Stop Celebrities From Blowing Their Money</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.thecut.com/2018/06/how-do-celebrities-spend-their-money.html</og:url>
<og:description>Inside the life of a Hollywood accountant.</og:description>
<og:image> https://pixel.nymag.com/imgs/fashion/daily/2018/06/20/20-hollywood.w1200.h630.jpg</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.thecut.com/2018/06/how-do-celebrities-spend-their-money.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>YouTube (Un)Blocks Blender Videos</title>
<link>https://www.blender.org/media-exposure/youtube-blocks-blender-videos-worldwide/?updated</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.blender.org/media-exposure/youtube-blocks-blender-videos-worldwide/?updated</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thursday June 21 2018, by Ton Roosendaal&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last night all videos came back (except the one from Andrew Price, which still is blocked in USA).&lt;br/&gt;According to another person in Youtube we now *do* have to sign the other agreement as well. &lt;a href=&quot;http://download.blender.org/institute/Contract%20between%20Google%20and%20Blender%20Foundation.pdf&quot;&gt;You can read it here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure if we should accept this. Will be studied on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday 17h, June 20 2018, by Ton Roosendaal&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None of our videos play still.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday 10.30h, June 20 2018, by Ton Roosendaal&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last night the Youtube Support team contacted Francesco Siddi by phone. As we understand it now it’s a mix of coincidences, bad UIs, wrong error messages, ignorant support desks and our non-standard decision to not monetize a popular Youtube channel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The coincidence is that Youtube is rolling out their subscription system in Europe (and Netherlands). This subscription system will allow users to stream music and enjoy Youtube ad-free. They updated terms and conditions for it and need to get monetized channel owners to approve that. Coincidentally our channel was set to allow monetization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.blender.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Screen-Shot-2018-06-20-at-10.34.06-289x512.png?x10773&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignright size-medium wp-image-59931&quot; width=&quot;289&quot; height=&quot;512&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.blender.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Screen-Shot-2018-06-20-at-10.34.06-289x512.png 289w, https://www.blender.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Screen-Shot-2018-06-20-at-10.34.06.png 582w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 289px) 100vw, 289px&quot;/&gt;The bad UI was that the ‘please accept the new terms’ button was only visible if you go the new Youtube “Content Manager” account, which I was not aware of and which is not active when you login to Youtube using the Foundation account to manage videos. The channel was also set to monatization mode which has no option to reset it. To make us even more confused, yesterday the system generated the wrong agreement to be signed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Image: after logging in to the Foundation account, the menu “Switch Accounts” – shows the option to login as “Content Manager”).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because of not accepting the new terms, the wrong error message was to put all videos on “Not available in your country” mode, which usually signals that there is a copyright issue. Similar happened for Andrew Price’s video last year, which (according to our new contact) was because of a trademark dispute but that was never made explicit to us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All support desk people we contacted (since December last year) couldn’t find out what was wrong. They didn’t know that not accepting ‘terms and conditions’ could be causing this. Until yesterday they thought there was a technical error.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After reviewing the new terms and conditions (which basically is to accept the subscription system, I decided to accept that. According to the new Youtube contact our channel then would be back in a few hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just while writing this, the video thumbnails appeared to be back! They don’t play yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tuesday (afternoon) 19 June 2018, by Ton Roosendaal&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are doing a PeerTube test on &lt;a href=&quot;https://video.blender.org/&quot;&gt;video.blender.org&lt;/a&gt;. It is running on one of our own servers, in a European datacenter. Just click around and have some fun. We’re curious to see how it holds!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://video.blender.org&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.blender.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Screen-Shot-2018-06-19-at-16.09.12-1280x591.png?x10773&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-large wp-image-59928 aligncenter&quot; width=&quot;1280&quot; height=&quot;591&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.blender.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Screen-Shot-2018-06-19-at-16.09.12-1280x591.png 1280w, https://www.blender.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Screen-Shot-2018-06-19-at-16.09.12-512x236.png 512w, https://www.blender.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Screen-Shot-2018-06-19-at-16.09.12-768x355.png 768w, https://www.blender.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Screen-Shot-2018-06-19-at-16.09.12.png 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1280px) 100vw, 1280px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tuesday 19 June 2018, by Ton Roosendaal&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last night we received a contract from Google. &lt;a href=&quot;http://download.blender.org/institute/Contract%20between%20Google%20and%20Blender%20Foundation.pdf&quot;&gt;You can read it here&lt;/a&gt;. It’s six pages of legal talk, but the gist of the agreement appears to be about Blender Foundation accepting to monetize content on its Youtube channel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, BF already has an ad-free Youtube account since 2008. We have monetizing disabled, but it looks like Google is going to change this policy. For example, we now see a new section on our channel settings page: “Monetization enabled”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.blender.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Screen-Shot-2018-06-19-at-12.25.40.png?x10773&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.blender.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Screen-Shot-2018-06-19-at-12.25.40-512x436.png?x10773&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-medium wp-image-59917 aligncenter&quot; width=&quot;512&quot; height=&quot;436&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.blender.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Screen-Shot-2018-06-19-at-12.25.40-512x436.png 512w, https://www.blender.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Screen-Shot-2018-06-19-at-12.25.40-768x654.png 768w, https://www.blender.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Screen-Shot-2018-06-19-at-12.25.40.png 892w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 512px) 100vw, 512px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;However, the actual advertisement option is disabled in the advanced settings:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.blender.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Screen-Shot-2018-06-19-at-12.23.43.png?x10773&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.blender.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Screen-Shot-2018-06-19-at-12.23.43-512x98.png?x10773&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-medium wp-image-59918 aligncenter&quot; width=&quot;512&quot; height=&quot;98&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.blender.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Screen-Shot-2018-06-19-at-12.23.43-512x98.png 512w, https://www.blender.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Screen-Shot-2018-06-19-at-12.23.43-768x147.png 768w, https://www.blender.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Screen-Shot-2018-06-19-at-12.23.43.png 1012w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 512px) 100vw, 512px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now there’s another issue. Last year we were notified by US Youtube visitors that a very popular Blender Conference talk wasn’t visible for them – the talk Andrew Price gave in 2016; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vM39qhXle4g&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&amp;amp;t=0s&quot;&gt;The 7 Habits of Highly Effective Artists&lt;/a&gt;. It had over a million views already.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With our channel reaching &amp;gt; 100k subscribers, we have special priority support. So we contacted them to ask what was wrong. After a couple of mails back and forth, the reply was as follows (22 dec 2017):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;14.183006535948&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Thanks for your continued support and patience.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;I’ve received an update from our experts stating that you need to&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/youtube/answer/94522?hl=en&quot;&gt;enable ads for your video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;. Once you enable, your video will be available in the USA.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;If there’s anything else you’d need help with, please feel free to write back to us anytime as we are available 24/7 to take care of every partner’s concerns.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Appreciate your understanding and thanks for being our valuable partner. Have an amazing day!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which was quite a surprising statement for us. My reply therefore was (22 dec 2017):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m chairman of the Blender Foundation. We choose to use a 100% ad-free channel for our work, this to emphasis our public benefit and non-profit goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to your answer we are being forced to enable advertising now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would like to know where this new Youtube policy has been published and made official.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We then had every other month a reply like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;5.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Please allow me some time to work with specialists on your issue. I’ll investigate further and will reach back to you with an update at the earliest possible.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Appreciate your patience and understanding in the interim.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just last week, June 12, I mailed them again to ask for the status of this issue. The reply was:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;I completely understand your predicament. Apologies for the unusual delay in hearing back from the Policy team. I’ve escalated this issue for further investigation and assistance. Kindly bear with us while we get this fixed.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Appreciate your understanding in this regard.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then on June 15th the entire channel went black.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To us it is still unclear what is going on. It could be related to Youtube’s new “subscription” system. It can also be just a human error or a bug; our refusal to monetize videos on a massively popular channel isn’t common.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However – it remains a fair and relevant question to Google: do you allow adfree channels without monetization? Stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monday 18 June 2018, by Francesco Siddi&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since a few days all Blender videos on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/BlenderFoundation/featured)&quot;&gt;OFFICIAL BLENDER CHANNEL&lt;/a&gt; have been blocked worldwide without explanation. We are working with YouTube to resolve the issue, but the support has been less than stellar. In the meantime you can find most of the videos on &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.blender.org&quot;&gt;cloud.blender.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/J6ecEv7lOzg&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 23:15:04 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ycnews</dc:creator>
<og:title> YouTube Blocks Blender Videos Worldwide — blender.org</og:title>
<og:description>Home of the Blender project - Free and Open 3D Creation Software</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.blender.org/media-exposure/youtube-blocks-blender-videos-worldwide/</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.blender.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Screen-Shot-2018-06-19-at-13.36.05-500x200.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.blender.org/media-exposure/youtube-blocks-blender-videos-worldwide/?updated</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>