<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>OpenStreetMap Is in Trouble</title>
<link>https://blog.emacsen.net/blog/2018/02/16/osm-is-in-trouble/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.emacsen.net/blog/2018/02/16/osm-is-in-trouble/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I was a contributor for OpenStreetMap for a long time, and I advocated for OpenStreetMap for a long time, but the project has stalled while the proprietary mapping world has continued to improve in data quality. For those of us who care about Free and Open data, this is a problem. In this article, I explore the reasons why I think OSM has stalled, as well as solutions to get the project back on track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was a contributor to the OpenStreetMap project from 2008 until roughly 2016. I was heavily invested in the project. In that time, I mapped, organized mapping groups in two cities, contributed to the founding of OpenStreetMap US, a non-profit dedicated to OpenStreetMap in the United States, gave talks on and about OpenStreetMap, contributed to the OpenStreetMap.org codebase, mentored two students for OSM through Google Summer of Code, started a working group dedicated to import of data into OpenStreetMap in the US, created and coordinated a massive bot run in the US, moderated the Reddit page &lt;a href=&quot;https://reddit.com/r/openstreetmap&quot;&gt;r/OpenStreetMap&lt;/a&gt; and was a member of the OpenStreetMap Data Working Group, which gave me escalated privileges (both politically and technically) for the project. There are few parts of OpenStreetMap where I didn't have some either direct or indirect involvement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm also the author of an article called &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.emacsen.net/blog/2014/01/04/why-the-world-needs-openstreetmap/&quot;&gt;Why the World Needs OpenStreetMap&lt;/a&gt;, which appeared in two large publications, The Guardian Online and Gizmodo, was on the front page of Hacker News twice and translated into at least four different languages. I was a proud OpenStreetMap advocate!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I criticize the project, I want to state emphatically that I still believe wholeheartedly in the core principles of OpenStreetMap. We need a Free as in Freedom geographic dataset just as much today as we did in the past. When I wrote my article about OSM in 2012, self-driving cars and other services were still a dream. Today the importance of having a highly accurate, libre geographic dataset is more important than ever, and I support those working to make it happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said, while I still believe in the goals of OpenStreetMap, I feel the OpenStreetMap project is currently unable to fulfill that mission due to poor technical decisions, poor political decisions, and a general malaise in the project. I'm going to outline in this article what I think OpenStreetMap has gotten wrong. It's entirely possible that OSM will reform and address the impediments to its success- and I hope it does. We need a Free as in Freedom geographic dataset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As long as this post is, it's not a comprehensive list of all the problems with the project, only the ones I found most directly affect the project's success and that I wasn't able to address myself during my time on the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;When the World Needs a Map, Give them a Database&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first problem that I feel plagues OSM is that the OpenStreetMap Foundation views the mission of the project to provide the world a geographic database, but not geographic services. OSM gives people the tools to create their own map rather than offering them a simple, out of the box solution. Providing the ability for individuals and organizations to make their own map may work well for some, but it discourages small and medium size organizations from using OSM and thus engaging with the project. And even if they do use our data, their engagement is through a third party, rather than directly with us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you go to OpenStreetMap.org, you see a map and a few extras, such as a search window, along with a few extra buttons such as &quot;Log In&quot; and &quot;Edit.&quot; It would be reasonable to assume that OpenStreetMap is a map, like Google Maps or other map projects, but while there is a map on OpenStreetMap.org, OpenStreetMap doesn't want you to use it. Instead, they want you to use the information from OpenStreetMap to make your own map, or find someone else to make the map for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you find this strange or confusing, you're not alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A map is nothing more than a visualization of a collection of facts. We can understand this in terms of geometry. Let's imagine a furniture store called Frita's Furniture. Our map is a simple two-dimensional plane just like we had in geography class, and it's at 10,10. We might also imagine a road called Main Street that runs from location 2, 9 all the way down to 15, 9.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The location of the store and the road are geographic facts, but if we wanted to represent this data visually, we'd typically use a map. We'd choose just how to draw the road. Would we use a simple line or a more road-line picture? How wide should the line be? What color would it be? Where would we put the name of the road? We could put it across the line, or alongside it, or some other way entirely. And do we want to represent the store as a dot, or an icon of a store?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Years ago, map makers would handle this process manually, but with computers, we generally call this process map rendering, and there are many decisions around the rendering of a map, such the usage of the map, local conventions and even just keeping within a given organization's map style.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But most people don't care about any of this. They just want a map. OSM has a map on its website but discourages its use by third parties. Instead, users are expected to either find a commercial service to render the map for them or else do it themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project leaders claim that this is because they want people using OpenStreetMap to understand the difference between the geographic data and its visual representation and to encourage a free market ecosystem of rendered map providers, but it's also a fact that many of the individuals who push for this separation also sell commercial map services. I explore this conflict of interest later in this post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Unclear Usage Policies&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mentioned earlier that OSM discouraged use of its maps on other websites. It does this through technically enforced usage policies. Understanding a usage policy is usually a straightforward process. An individual or organization gets permission to use a service a certain amount. We could imagine this being done by the number of map requests, or by bandwidth, etc. But OSM's usage policy is entirely different. They allow but discourage the use of the free map and then disallow any single application that is using over 5% of the map bandwidth. This policy is bizarre on several levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To understand why this is so strange, we can use an analogy. Let's imagine that I make ice cream. I put the recipe for my ice cream outside my house and suggest people make their own. I also offer free samples out of my home. Above my door, I hang a sign saying &quot;Please don't ask for free samples&quot;. Then when people come in and ask for a sample, I give it to them. People may spread the word about my free ice cream and suggest their friends use it. Imagine we have a person named Fred who is a fan of my ice cream and recommends that all his friends go to my house for ice cream. I continue to dish out free ice cream to anyone who asks. But if one individual like Fred refers too many people to me, I will cut off access to everyone Fred sent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthering this analogy, I will tell Fred's friends that they've eaten too much free ice cream, instead of telling Fred. And how many people is too many people? The answer for OpenStreetMap is anything over five percent of the total amount of free ice cream that I've dished out that day. Fred has no idea how many people I've served, so the only thing he can do is ultimately not refer people to my house.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This analogy works because no since no single service knows what any other service is doing, there's no way to know how many other applications have requested how many map requests. Also, since the top services and applications will change over time, you may be fine one day and in trouble the next. Again, there's no way to know. And when you do cross the line of using the service too much, your users would get an unfriendly message about unavailability, not you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OSM could create standard usage policy, spelling out exactly how much free usage is allowed. It could also choose to create &quot;premium membership&quot; and encourage people to use its tile service (rendered map) service, but right now, using OSM tiles without going through a third party is hard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;A Bad Geocoder&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you type an address into a map and it gives you the location, that is called Geocoding. When your GPS or phone knows where you are and gives you a building or street address, that is called Reverse Geocoding. The geocoder featured on OpenStreetMap.org is called Nominatim, and it's awful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nominatim is not the only OSM geocoder. Much like the map rendering, it is possible to write your own or use a commercial geocoding service. But Nomatim is the most popular geocoder available for OpenStreetMap, it's used on the website and Nominatim is the service that is listed on OpenStreetMap.org under its APIs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In its defense, let me say that Geocoding is hard and Nominatim itself is quite complex; its almost a feat of engineering. The developers who work on it put enormous effort into writing Nominatim. The problem is that such software needs to be maintained or sometimes replaced entirely to be useful. While there have been Nominatim maintainers, it's not been given the time or attention that it needs and deserves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To understand why Nominatim is bad, one has to understand how most people use a geocoder. They're most often looking up a business or something vague like &quot;Staples downtown Springfield&quot;. That simple three letter query is asking quite a bit. It is asking the computer to know what Springfield is and to limit the query to that. It's then asking to limit it to (or near!) an area called &quot;downtown&quot;, and finally, it's limiting results to Staples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Nomintim can't handle such queries. It can barely handle simple address queries, such as &quot;123 Main Street&quot;. As an example, if I typed an address into Nominatim near my location in New York City, it might come up with a result in Iowa, which for whatever reason, it's more inclined to offer me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I try to specify my location as &quot;Manhattan&quot;, as of the time of this writing Nomintim will first assume that I mean Manhattan, Kansas, ignoring both the prominence of Manhattan in New York and the fact that the query itself is originating from New York City. Worse still, it's not possible to search for intersections. If I type &quot;53rd and 6th, New York City&quot; into Nominatim, it doesn't understand it. Even if I try to refine the search as &quot;53rd Street and 6th Avenue, New York City&quot;, it doesn't work. Intersections are not addresses to Nominatim. It doesn't understand stores, or &quot;near&quot; or categories such as &quot;restaurant&quot;. The results it comes up with are often irrelevant, and the service is quite slow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While other geocoders for OSM exist, such as Pelias and Photon, only Nominatim is run and supported by the OSM Foundation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;No moderation/review model&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most significant technical problems with OSM is the lack of a review model, that is for a change to the map to be staged and then reviewed before being applied. Not having this functionality caused ripples of problems throughout the system, some of which I'll discuss here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;New mapper problem&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Editing on OSM can be challenging for a beginner, and as the project tried to attract new mappers (editor contributors), we would run into people who just mapped incorrectly. Unfortunately, because OSM's data model doesn't include a review stage bad edits are committed to the map and often left undiscovered, or even if they're removed, the original editor doesn't usually see why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having the ability for a mapper to contribute changes and then have those changes be reviewed would have potentially left the map with higher quality data and a sort of mentorship model between new contributors and more experienced editors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hoped that this would be improved when I mentored a feature placed into OpenStreetMap called &quot;Changeset Comments&quot;, in which users could leave feedback for one another's changes. Unfortunately, this ended up not being something many people used constructively, and it was a mess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Without Moderation, Bots are Hard&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bots could be very useful in OSM in finding mistakes caused either by inaccurate data sources or by editing blunders. For example, if there was a road named &quot;Main Street&quot; connected to another road called &quot;Main Stret,&quot; it was likely a spelling error and should be corrected. But it would be a good thing if changes were reviewed by a human being first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But since OSM doesn't provide any mechanism for reviewed edits, these kinds of suggested changes don't exist. Either bot edits are executed without oversight, which could lead to errors, or they aren't done at all and the project misses out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Imports are Difficult&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imports are challenging for a variety of reasons, but having a moderation or review model would make things much easier by allowing changes to be staged. The inability to stage and review massive changes to the map have caused problems in the past and many bad imports go unnoticed. If the project instead required that a human review edits before being committed to the system, bad imports could be detected before they cause problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to the lack of staging inside OSM itself, staging systems have been written for other OSM related projects. These systems often require editors to then manually place those changes in OSM. This process is labor intensive and makes some imports so challenging that they die before they begin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Vandalism is hard to manage&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like Wikipedia, OSM has people who purposefully vandalize the project. Vandals have a variety of motivations. Some vandals are your run of the mill Internet trolls who enjoy causing problems. Sometimes a company wants something on the map despite community consensus against it and change the map to suit their needs, even if the project as a whole is against it. Sometimes mappers use OSM to make political statements such as in the case of disputed territories, and sometimes a geospatially based game, such as Pokemon Go, will use OSM to generate its data and players find that they can change the map to gain an advantage. Whatever the reason, OSM has vandals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vandalism is difficult in OSM because without a moderation system, it has to be &quot;cleaned up&quot; rather than prevented in the first place. Detecting vandalism is difficult. Several people ran monitoring tools to try to find problematic edits and imports. I was one of those people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if problematic edits are detected, removing then means making even more edits. The history of the project is littered with lots of small changes that are only there to remove some previous change. Worse still, if the vandalism isn't detected early then someone else might modify an object that was previously vandalized, creating a situation in which either a tool or a person would have to separate the good edits from the bad, a manual process that can be labor intensive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A moderation tool would prevent much of this. Many vandals would find that their work would not get into the database and would move on. While some malicious edits would still get through, we would be able to address a majority before it became a problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;External Tools are Hard&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of my contributions to OpenStreetMap was working to improve MapRoutlette, a tool which helps find problems in OSM and offers users the opportunity to fix them. One feature that we wanted in MapRoutlette was to be able to present users with simple &quot;Yes/No&quot; type questions. Unfortunately, while not impossible this would have been a complicated task in OpenStreetMap. If these edits could have gone to a moderation queue, we could have been more confident, and possibly not needed MapRoutlette at all in some cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many developers wanted to solve this same problem, offering the ability to add helpful but anonymous edits to the project. But since OpenStreetMap requires every edit be committed by an individual user, rather than a company or bot account, the barrier of entry for casual mappers was often too high.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;OSM's Lack of Layers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most geographic databases use a layered approach to represent different features. One layer may represent political boundaries; another may represent the road network, a third may represent water features, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of the traditional layers, OSM chooses to use a single layer and then tags (key/value pairs) on individual objects. At first this seems like a good idea, but ultimately it ends up creating a huge mess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Tools are Harder to Write&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine if we wanted to write an editor for OSM that only worked with the road network. This task would seem straightforward in that we would just need to extract features that correspond are tagged as road, such as &lt;code&gt;highway=*&lt;/code&gt;. Unfortunately, it's not that simple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, an editor that edits these road features must not only pick up the roads (&lt;em&gt;ways&lt;/em&gt; in OSM terminology) but also the points (&lt;em&gt;nodes&lt;/em&gt;) that make up that road. Secondly, if the road is particularly complicated, it may be represented as a &lt;em&gt;relation&lt;/em&gt;. Editing this way is time consuming but straightforward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is not as straightforward is that a feature such as a road may also be playing double-duty as another feature, such as a political boundary, as may any of its associated features. Editing roads may inadvertently result in changing a political boundary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having map features that represent such radically different meaning puts an onus on both tool makers and the individual editor working on OSM to be aware of any changes they make possibly having consequences that go beyond what they think they're doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Imports Are Difficult Without Layers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the keys of the Free and Open Source software movements have been code reuse, the idea that you can integrate software together from different sources and have it work seamlessly together. One would think that it would be much the same with geographic data, but because of the lack of layers, it's very challenging to import data into OSM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without layers, it's difficult to extract a specific region by feature and analyze or replace that. Instead, because of its complex tagging system, it needs to be analyzed as a whole. Imports are possible but made more difficult without layers to make the job of data analysis by isolation easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;No Support For Observational, or Other Datasets&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the core tenants of OpenStreetMap is that it only stores persistent, personally verifiable data. The only exceptions to this are political boundaries- and even these exceptions can be problematic. Unfortunately, this also presents a problem with third parties want to use OSM for things outside of the project scope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an example, let's take Pokemon Go. Pokemon Go is an augmented reality game in which real-life features are connected with imaginary creatures in which the player must battle and collect. The frequency and location of where these creatures appear is based on various map features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pokemon Go players wanted to use OSM to document the location of creatures to make it easier for other players to find rare creatures and improve their collection. OSM disallows this kind of data in the same way that it might for bird watchers- while it's interesting, the impermanence of this data made it a poor candidate for the project and thus the data would be immediately removed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it doesn't have to be something as trivial as a game- layers could also allow other specialized data such as potholes, red light cameras or even bird or animal sightings. It would make the project useful to many more people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Lack of Permanent IDs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In any database, objects have an ID field, usually a numeric value to look the record up by. OSM is no different and every object inside OSM has an ID field. Unfortunately, in OSM the ID fields represent the low-level objects rather than any high-level concept. This creates a huge problem. I will call this idea a &quot;Conceptual Object&quot;, and show how the lack of permanent IDs for them is problematic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Diving Deeper&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To understand why the lack of permanent IDs is a problem, we have to dive a little deeper into how OSM works. While many of these low-level details are beyond the scope of this article, I will present the basics of how OSM stores information. A point in OSM is called a &lt;em&gt;node&lt;/em&gt;, and every node has an ID. Points may be collected into a line, and that line is called a &lt;em&gt;way&lt;/em&gt;, and collections of nodes and ways may be combined into a more complex object called a &lt;em&gt;relation&lt;/em&gt;. A relation may also contain other relations. Nodes, ways, and relations all have ID fields.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To illustrate this, let's think of a building, that building has properties. The building is at a certain location, it's a specific size, shape, and has an address. If it's large enough, it may have multiple addresses. But the concept of the building is unified. In OSM, that building could be represented by a single node, representing the address. Or a building may be represented by a way of the building outline, or a building may be represented by a relation, encompassing details of the various building elevations, levels, and roof types. The problem is that if I'm doing a lookup, there is no straightforward way to ask about the building. Instead, I will have to look at aspects of the building, such as its address, or its location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;History Lost&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As strange as this may seem, it's entirely possible in OpenStreetMap to take a node from one side of the world, move it to the other side of the world and use it for something else entirely. For example, it is technically possible to take a part of a house, move it to another continent and use it as part of a road. While this is highly unusual, this is not disallowed. If I look at the history of the node, I will see it move. While this may keep the history of the element, it does not keep the conceptual history of an object.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, if we start with a representation of an object being the building as a single node, then move to a complex relation, that won't be reflected in the object history, and thus the changes over time are lost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Permanent IDs on conceptual objects could help with this by providing a history of what the data represents rather than just the data itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Import Conflation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amongst other problems, not having a permanent ID for a conceptual object in OSM is the challenging of conflating objects in OSM to objects in other datasets. For example, if we're given a building database from a local government, each building in that dataset will have an ID. We will want to compare that ID to our existing objects. Unfortunately, to do that, we're left with two choices- either we create a new identifier (key) in which to do the conflation, or we have to use the second dataset's ID inside OSM- neither of which is an optimal solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;It's Hard to Build Connections to Other Datasets&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many people have envisioned projects that connect to OSM to offer reviews or other data associated with OSM, but without a permanent ID, this is not practical. Objects in OpenStreetMap may contain some data such as cuisine type or opening hours along with the name and address, but the review site will need to be able to have a permanent link to objects in OSM, which it can't currently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;No Standards in Data Representation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In OpenStreetMap, there are no formal standards in the project for the representation of features on the map. As an example, let's take the example of a sidewalk. Sidewalks are useful things to have on a map because they tell us if the road is pedestrian friendly. Sometimes sidewalks are represented by an attribute on the road itself. Sometimes sidewalks are represented as a line (way) that runs parallel to the road. Sometimes those ways have the name of the street as their own name, and sometimes they don't have any name at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are a mapper, this is confusing, since there's no one standard way to map things. If you're trying to build tools to work with OpenStreetMap, the lack of standardization of data across the project makes it challenging to work with as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is an informal process for data representation, mainly done on the Wiki, but because this isn't formally enforced, and changing data en mass may be considered a form of vandalism, data consumers are forced to write tools that accept many representations of the same data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The APIs are Slow to Evolve&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of writing, the current official OpenStreetMap API is 0.6. The API hasn't version hasn't changed since 2009. While a stable API can be a good thing for a mature software project, in the case of OpenStreetMap, this is as more a reflection of poor project management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An API is part of a protocol that either allows a client to talk to a server or for servers to communicate with each other. In this case, we're talking about OpenStreetMap's editing API which is used between OSM and editing software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The OpenStreetMap editing API is very powerful and complete, but it has some design choices that made sense in 2009 that have largely been replaced by better technical options in nine years since. These include small changes, such as the data serialization format, as well as more significant changes such as the internal data representation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an example, in 2012 there have been several proposals made to create a new datatype called an a &lt;em&gt;area&lt;/em&gt; that would greatly simplify the representation of certain types of geographic features. Despite this and the offer of technical help, the project has not made any significant progress on this or other important technical issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;OSM has Hidden Gatekeepers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dovetailing on the previous section, we have to ask why the project has not made more technical progress, and the answer is that sadly the keys to the OSM castle largely do not lie in the hands of the OpenStreetMap Foundation, but instead in the hands of one or two individuals who act as gatekeepers to the project's source code and infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While it's not uncommon for a Free Software or Open Source project to have a &quot;Benevolent Dictator for Life&quot;, these roles are often replaced by a more formal structure as the needs of the project grow. In the case of OpenStreetMap, there is a formal entity which owns the data, called the OpenStreetMap Foundation. But at the same time, the ultimate choices for the website, the geographic database and the infrastructure are not under the direct control of the Foundation, but instead rest largely on one individual, who (while personally friendly) ranges from skeptical to openly hostile to change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a former professional system administrator, I relate strongly to these types of individuals. At the same time, the desires of them need to be balanced by the overall needs of the project to make progress and keep momentum to keep its userbase happy and engaged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is not the case here, and it's to the detriment of the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The OpenStreetMap Foundation Culture&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would be easy to think about the OpenStreetMap Foundation (the OSMF) as similar to the Wikipedia Foundation, but aside from the high-level view of being the holder of Free Data, the two projects are managed radically differently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Wikipedia Foundation is a multi-million dollar organization that not only manages Wikipedia but other projects as well, such as the lesser known Wikidata and Wikinews. These projects aid in the organization's broad mission to provide high-quality information to the world. To serve this mission, Wikipedia spends a great deal of money on its infrastructure as well as directing and funding development of new tools for the community to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OpenStreetMap, on the other hand, relies primarily on donated hosting services and runs on a shoestring budget. It has no paid employees and does not fund or direct the development of its software base.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This has lead to some organizations trying to take up the mantle and improve the situation, including an organization that I helped found called OpenStreetMap US, which is a US based non-profit organization focused on promoting OSM in the United States. Among our goals for the organization was to fill in the gaps of development and mapping resources by the OSMF, which we partially succeeded in doing, but because of the fragmentation of organizations, we were less successful than we hoped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to OpenStreetMap US and other &quot;chapters&quot; around the world, there is the Humanitarian OpenStreetMap Team, whose mission it is to help promote OSM in developing nations and rally the OSM community during humanitarian crises. There is no reason that HOT needed to be an independent organization other than the unwillingness by the OSMF to expand its role. Even Steve Coast, one of the founders of OpenStreetMap saw and tried to address this problem with his organization, &quot;Map Club.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The obvious question is why the OpenStreetMap leadership takes the positions that it does, despite the clear need for change. The answers in my view are commercialism in the project, along with a cultural desire to retain the feel of the project's early days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While there are companies built around Wikipedia's engine (the Wikimedia Server), there are not many companies making money from repackaging Wikipedia. OpenStreetMap, on the other hand, has a commercial ecosystem around it, largely from the business of creating customized maps for customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of the founders of the project, as well as others, have launched commercial services around OSM. Unfortunately, this creates an incentive to keep the project small and limited in scope to map up the gap with commercial services which they can sell. This also applies to HOT, which has a financial incentive to get grant money for itself and not have those resources going to the OSMF.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to these conflicts of interest is a desire to keep the project small in scope by senior members of the community who see the project as being about people and the mapping hobby and want to avoid imports or other activity that could be seen as removing the human factor from the project. They also see the dangers inherent in creating an organizational structure that demands money and fears it would create a perpetual cycle of needing to find donors simply to support a management layer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I disagree and view the lack of a more active structure by the OSMF as the cause of the project's both stagnation and significant commercial influence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The World Had Changed&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When OSM was launched, governments did not release their data under free licenses. They only began doing so &lt;em&gt;because&lt;/em&gt; OSM exists now as competition. Yet due to the problems I've outlined, OSM imports are difficult, and updating imports, once they get in OSM is nearly impossible. This is a critical problem for the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, when OSM was launched, drones were not cheap and available. AI wasn't able to do good visual detection of roads, and flying cars were still science fiction. Now all of these tools exist, and yet OSM is still stuck largely editing by hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If OSM relies exclusively on manual labor and be unable to work with other datasets, its data quality will continue to decline and the project will ultimately stagnate and fail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Just the Roadblocks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It may appear at first that this article is a comprehensive list of everything I find wrong with OSM. It's not. There are many more concerns I have about the project, but I've limited my article to the scope of concerns I have that I feel are stopping the entire project from progressing. There will be time to fix the small issues if (and only if) the project as a whole succeeds. If it doesn't, then the small nit-picky problems are going to be irrelevant anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's my sincere hope that this article will be a call-to-action for OSM. There are many brilliant and inspiring individuals in the project. If I'm am a pun, I hope OSM will once again find its &lt;em&gt;way&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 18:34:32 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>emacsen</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.emacsen.net/blog/2018/02/16/osm-is-in-trouble/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>U.S. Charges 13 Russians, 3 Companies for Interfering with Election</title>
<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-02-16/mueller-indicts-13-russians-for-hacking-during-u-s-election-jdq8fyg0</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-02-16/mueller-indicts-13-russians-for-hacking-during-u-s-election-jdq8fyg0</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;U.S. Special Counsel Robert Mueller unveiled the details of a widespread and coordinated campaign by Russians to influence the U.S. presidential election in favor of &lt;a itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/billionaires/id/1252249&quot; title=&quot;Billionaire Profile&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Donald Trump&lt;/a&gt;, delivering on his initial mandate by the Justice Department.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;In an indictment announced Friday in Washington, Mueller describes a years-long, multimillion-dollar conspiracy by hundreds of Russians aimed at criticizing Hillary Clinton and supporting Senator Bernie Sanders and Trump. Mueller charged 13 Russian nationals and three Russian entities and accused them of defrauding the U.S. government by interfering with the political process.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Prosecutors provided a remarkably detailed picture of how Russians used social media, fake rallies and secretive operatives in the U.S. to create “political intensity” by backing radical groups, opposition social movements and disaffected voters. The outreach from the Russians included direct contact with over 100 Americans.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This “information warfare” by the Russians didn’t affect the outcome of the presidential election, Deputy Attorney General Rod Rosenstein told reporters. Trump and his Republican supporters have repeatedly denounced the Mueller investigation as a “witch hunt” and have denied any collusion. The indictment cites no instances of Russians coordinating directly with the Trump campaign.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Still, the accusations detail unprecedented foreign attempts to influence the outcome of a U.S. election, including the manipulation of accounts at big U.S. companies like Facebook, Twitter, PayPal and Instagram. Those companies will continue to face pressure to clamp down on fraudulent accounts or risk a government crackdown as intelligence officials have warned that Russians are already engaged in influencing the 2018 midterm elections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;lazy-img-324057794&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/i_tSQ7F_cXvE/v1/60x-1.jpg&quot; data-native-src=&quot;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/i_tSQ7F_cXvE/v1/-1x-1.jpg&quot; class=&quot;lazy-img__image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;news-figure-caption-text caption&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/features/trump-daily/&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Follow the Trump Administration’s Every Move&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The president has been briefed on the indictment, the White House said. The Russian government called the accusations absurd. Mueller’s office said that none of the defendants was in custody. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond the 13 people indicted, Mueller announced the Feb. 12 guilty plea of a California man for identity theft, Richard Pinedo, who is cooperating with prosecutors. The indictment of Russian individuals and companies also suggests a broader conspiracy than Mueller charged, saying grand jurors heard about others involved in the scheme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Richard Painter, who was the chief ethics adviser in the George W. Bush administration, said the lack of any evidence of collusion in the indictment wasn’t the final word by prosecutors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“They’re charging what they know,” he said. “The contact with the Trump campaign might be unwitting in this case, but that doesn’t mean that the collaboration issue is finished.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.justice.gov/file/1035477/download&quot; title=&quot;Click here for indictment&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;Click here to read the indictment in full.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Internet Research Agency, a Russian organization, and the defendants began working in 2014 to interfere in U.S. elections, according to the indictment. They used false personas and social media while also staging political rallies and communicating with “unwitting individuals” associated with the Trump campaign, it said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a Feb. 10, 2016, planning memo, the Russians were instructed to “use any opportunity to criticize Hillary and the rest (except Sanders and Trump -- we support them).”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The operations also denigrated candidates including Ted Cruz and Marco Rubio, Trump’s rivals in the 2016 Republican primary, the indictment said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The efforts included contact with “unwitting” Trump campaign officials, with the goal of “impairing, obstructing, and defeating the lawful government functions” including the election.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-tout-type=&quot;story&quot;&gt;&lt;a itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/politics/articles/2018-02-16/mueller-s-case-of-russian-meddling-in-u-s-election-highlights&quot; title=&quot;Click for full story&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Mueller’s Case of Russian Meddling in U.S. Election: Highlights&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The group bought advertisements on U.S. social media and created numerous Twitter accounts designed to appear as if they were U.S. groups or people, according to the indictment. One fake account, @TEN_GOP account, attracted more than 100,000 online followers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Russians tracked the metrics of their effort in reports and budgeted for their efforts. Some traveled to the U.S. to gather intelligence for the surreptitious campaign, according to the indictment. They used stolen U.S. identities, including fake drivers licenses, and contacted news media outlets to promote their activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In September 2016, the group ordered one worker to “intensify criticizing Hillary Clinton” after a review found insufficient anti-Clinton activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The effort went well beyond social media. The Russian effort included organizing rallies for Trump and paying Americans to participate in them or perform tasks at them. One American was paid to build a cage on a flatbed truck; another was paid to portray Clinton in a prison uniform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rallies were promoted with Facebook ads. Paid ads included this one on Oct. 19, 2016: “Hillary is a Satan, and her crimes and lies had proved just how evil she is.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-tout-type=&quot;story&quot;&gt;&lt;a itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/politics/articles/2018-02-16/mueller-charges-against-russians-highlight-florida-trump-rallies&quot; title=&quot;Click for full story&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Mueller Charges Against Russians Highlight Florida Trump Rallies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the election, the group organized both pro- and anti-Trump rallies, including a “Trump is NOT my President” rally in New York the week after the election and one in Charlotte, North Carolina, the following week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Russian organization had settled on Trump as their favored candidate by at least April 2016 and began producing and purchasing ads promoting the reality-TV star to voters and “expressly opposing Clinton,” according to the indictment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In June 2016, the defendants allegedly posed as grassroots activists using the account @March_for_Trump to contact a volunteer for the Trump campaign in New York. The volunteer agreed to provide signs for their “March for Trump” rally, according to the indictment. By August, the accused Russians were communicating with unwitting Trump campaign staff involved in local community outreach to discuss their fraudulent “Florida Goes Trump” rallies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two years before the election, the Russians began monitoring groups that use social media sites to influence U.S. politics and social issues, tracking the size of groups and how popular they were with their audiences, according to the indictment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;‘Drop Phones’&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several Russians traveled around the U.S. to gather intelligence for their operation, posing as U.S. political and social activists. They used clandestine methods to communicate and gather information, employing special cameras, “drop phones” and “evacuation scenarios” to ensure security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Russians set up Facebook and Instagram groups with names that targeted such issues as immigration, religion and the Black Lives Matter movement. They also controlled numerous Twitter groups that appeared to be controlled by U.S. people, such as “Tennessee GOP.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They spent thousands of dollars a month to buy advertisements on social media groups, while carefully tracking the size of U.S. audiences they reached, according to the indictment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-tout-type=&quot;story&quot;&gt;&lt;a itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/politics/articles/2018-02-16/these-are-the-russians-accused-of-meddling-in-the-2016-election&quot; title=&quot;Click for full story&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;These Are the Russians Accused of Meddling in the 2016 Election&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of the people and companies charged in Friday’s indictment were connected in some way to the Internet Research Agency, a company widely reported to be a front for Russian government influence campaigns on social media. The company and 12 of its current or former executives and employees were charged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;inline-newsletter&quot; data-state=&quot;ready&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Prosecutors also charged Yevgeniy Viktorivich Prigozhin, a Russian restaurateur and caterer widely known as “Putin’s chef” for hosting his state dinners with foreign dignitaries, and two of his companies. The companies, Concord Catering and Concord Management and Consulting, have Russian government contracts. The special counsel alleges that they provided the financing for the Internet Research Agency’s operations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Americans are very impressionable people, they see what they want to see. I have great respect for them. I’m not at all upset that I ended up on this list. If they want to see the devil - let them see it,” Prigozhin told RIA Novosti.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;— With assistance by Jeffrey Grocott, Erik Larson, Andrew M Harris, Christian Berthelsen, Tom Schoenberg, Ksenia Galouchko, and Greg Farrell&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 17:54:44 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>uptown</dc:creator>
<og:description>U.S. Special Counsel Robert Mueller unveiled the details of a widespread and coordinated campaign by Russians to influence the U.S. presidential election in favor of Donald Trump, delivering on his initial mandate by the Justice Department.</og:description>
<og:image>https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/iYIokJzDQaDI/v1/1200x800.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>Mueller Accuses Russians of Pro-Trump, Anti-Clinton Meddling</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-02-16/u-s-charges-13-russians-3-companies-for-hacking-election</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-02-16/u-s-charges-13-russians-3-companies-for-hacking-election</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>I&amp;#039;ve never felt less in control of my own hardware</title>
<link>https://kimonote.com/@mildbyte/ive-never-felt-less-in-control-of-my-own-hardware-14804/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://kimonote.com/@mildbyte/ive-never-felt-less-in-control-of-my-own-hardware-14804/</guid>
<description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once upon a time I bought a car. I drove it straight out of the dealership and parked it on my driveway. This is a thought experiment, as youth in the UK can't afford neither a car nor a driveway and I can't drive, but bear with me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I bought a car and I drove it around for a few months or so and life was great. It did everything I wanted it to do, it never stalled and never broke down. One day, I got an e-mail from the dealership saying that they'd need to update my car. Sure, I thought, and drove there to get it &quot;updated&quot;. They didn't let me look at what they were doing with the car, saying that they were performing some simple maintenance. Finally, I got my car back, without seeing any visible changes, and drove it back home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This happened a few more times over the next several months. I'd get an e-mail from the dealer, drive the car back to them, have a cup of coffee or three while they were working, and then get the car back. Sometimes I'd get it back damaged somehow, with a massive dent on the side, and the dealership staff would just shrug and say that those were the manufacturer's instructions. Then a few days later, I'd get summoned again and after another update cycle the dent would be gone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At some point, I stopped bothering and after a few missed calls from the dealership my car stopped working completely. I phoned the dealership again and sure, they said that the car wouldn't work until another update. Great. I had the car towed to the dealership and drove back without any issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One night I got woken up by a weird noise outside my house. I looked out the window and saw that some people in dark overalls were around my car, doing something to it. I ran out, threatening to call the police. They laughed and produced IDs from the dealership, telling me that since people were frustrated with having to update their cars so often, they'd do it for them in order to bother them less.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I sighed and went back to sleep. This continued for quite some time, with the mechanics working on my car every week or so. I'd invite them for tea and they would refuse, quoting terms of service and all that sort of thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One day I woke up to a car covered in ads that seemed to be related to what I was browsing last night. There wasn't anything controversial, thankfully, but it was still a bit unsettling. The dealership support staff said it was to offer me products relevant to my interests. I asked if I could take them down and got told that it was a part of the whole offering and the vehicle wouldn't work without them. So I had to drive to work surrounded by more pictures of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2017/aug/28/trivago-girl-gabrielle-miller&quot;&gt;Trivago woman&lt;/a&gt; that I was comfortable with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a year or so, the manufacturer had innovated some more. When I got into the car and turned the ignition key, a bunch of mechanics appeared seemingly out of nowhere, and picked the car up, ready to drag it as per my instructions. Turns out, the night before they had removed the engine and all the useful parts from the vehicle, turning it into a &quot;thin client&quot;. It was supposed to make sure that when there was an issue with the car, they could debug it centrally and not bother all their customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, one morning I got into the car and nothing happened. Turns out, the manufacturer was acquired by a larger company last night and their service got shut down. I sat at the wheel, dreading being late for work again, and suddenly woke up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;meanwhile-in-the-real-world&quot;&gt;Meanwhile in the real world&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once upon a time I opened a new tab in Firefox on my Android phone to find out that besides a list of my most visited pages to choose from, there also was a list of things &quot;suggested by Pocket&quot;. What the hell was Pocket, why was it suggesting me things and, more importantly, how the hell did it get into my Firefox?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember when pushing code to the user's device was a big deal. You'd go to the vendor's website, download an executable, launch it, go through an InstallShield (or a NullSoft) install wizard if you were lucky and only then you would get to enjoy the new software. You'd go through the changelogs and get excited about the bugfixes or new features. And if you weren't excited, you wouldn't install the new version at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember when I went through my Linux phase and was really loving package managers. It was a breath of fresh air back then, a single &lt;code&gt;apt-get upgrade&lt;/code&gt; updating all my software at once. And then Android and Apple smartphones came around and they had exactly the same idea of a centralized software repository. How cool was that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm not sure when mobile devices started installing updates by default. I think around 2014 my Android phone would still meekly ask to update all apps and that was an opportunity for me to reestablish my power over my device and go through all the things I wasn't using anymore and delete them. In 2016, when I got a new phone, the default setting changed and I would just wake up to my device stating, &quot;Tinder has been updated. Deal with it&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it's been the case on the desktop too. I realised that Firefox and Chrome hadn't been pestering me about updates for quite a while now and, sure, they've been updating themselves. I like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2017/12/16/16784628/mozilla-mr-robot-arg-plugin-firefox-looking-glass&quot;&gt;Mr Robot&lt;/a&gt;, but I like it in my media player, not in my browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's not even about automatic updates. I could disable them, sure, but I would quickly fall behind the curve, with services that I'm accessing stopping supporting my client software. In fact, it's not even about browsers. I'm pretty sure I wouldn't be able to use Skype 4 (the last decent version), that is, if I could find where to download it. As another example, I recently launched OpenIV, a GTA modding tool, at which point it told me &quot;There's a new version available. I won't start until you update&quot;. Uuh, excuse me? Sure, I could find a way around this, but still, it's not pleasant being told that what's essentially a glorified WinRAR that was fine the night before can't run without me updating it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(as an aside, WinRAR now seems to be monetized by having ads on its &quot;please buy WinRAR&quot; dialog window.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I go to a Web page, gone are the days of the server sending me some HTML and my browser rendering it the way I wanted. No, now the browser gets told &quot;here's some JavaScript, go run it. Oh, here's a CDN, go download some JavaScript from there and run it, too. Oh, here a DoubleClick ad server, go get some pictures that look like Download buttons from over there and put them over here. Also, here's the CSRF token. If you don't quote at it at me the next time, I'll tell you to go away. Oh yeah, also set this cookie. Oh, and append this hexadecimal string to the URL so that we can track who shared this link and where. The HTML? Here's your HTML. But the JavaScript is supposed to change the DOM around, so go run it. It changes your scrolling behaviour, too, so you get a cool parallax effect as you move around the page. You'll love it.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a developer, I love web applications. If a customer is experiencing an issue, I don't need to get them to send me logs or establish which version of the software they're running. I just go to my own server logs, see what request they're making and now I am able to reproduce the issue in my own environment. And with updates now getting pushed out to users' devices automatically, there are fewer and fewer support issues which can be resolved by saying &quot;update to the newest version&quot; and instead I can spend time on better pursuits. Finally, I don't need to battle with WinAPI or Qt or Swing or any other GUI framework: given enough CSS and a frontend JavaScript framework du jour, things can look roughly the same on all devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, that leaves users at the mercy of the vendor. What used to be code running on their own hardware is now code running on the vendor's hardware or code that the vendor tells their hardware to run. So when they end up in a place with no Internet connection or the vendor goes out of business, the service won't work at all instead of working poorly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the way, here's an idea on how to come up with new business ideas. Look at the most popular Google services and have a quick think about how you would write a replacement for them. When they inevitably get sunsetted, do so and reap kudos. For example, I'm currently writing a browser addon that replaces the &quot;View Image&quot; button from Google Image search results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, it's not just an issue with applications. Once upon a time in early 2017, I came home from work to find my laptop, that had been on standby, decided to turn itself on and install a Windows 10 update. The way I found that out was because the login screen had changed and it was using a different time format. And then things became even weirder as I realised that all the shortcuts on my desktop and in the Start Menu were missing. In fact, it was almost as if someone broke into my house and reimaged my whole hard drive. Strangely enough, all the software and the data was still there, tucked away in &lt;code&gt;C:\Program Files&lt;/code&gt; and its friends, it's just that Windows wasn't aware of it. Thankfully, running a System Restore worked and the next update didn't have these problems, but since then I stopped allowing automatic updates. Except there's no way I can figure out what a given update does anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm really scared of my phone right now. Here it is, lying by my side, and I've no idea what's going on in its mind and what sort of information it's transferring and to where. When I was a kid and got gifted my father's old Nokia 6600, I was excited about having a fully fledged computer in my pocket, something with a real multitasking operating system that I could easily write software for. Now, I'm no longer so sure.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 17:03:03 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mildbyte</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://kimonote.com/@mildbyte/ive-never-felt-less-in-control-of-my-own-hardware-14804/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>How to Study Mathematics (2017)</title>
<link>https://www.math.uh.edu/~dblecher/pf2.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.math.uh.edu/~dblecher/pf2.html</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;meta http-equiv=&quot;Content-Type&quot; content=&quot;text/html; charset=utf-8&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;GENERATOR&quot; content=&quot;Mozilla/4.51 [en] (X11; U; Linux 2.0.36 i686) [Netscape]&quot; /&gt;&lt;title&gt;How to Study Mathematics&lt;/title&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot; readability=&quot;314.89019239794&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lawrence Neff Stout,&lt;br /&gt;Department of Mathematics,&lt;br /&gt;Illinois Wesleyan University,&lt;br /&gt;Bloomington, Il 61702-2900&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This essay describes a number of strategies for studying college level mathematics. It has sections entitled&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.math.uh.edu/~dblecher/pf2.html#differences&quot;&gt;How is college mathematics different?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.math.uh.edu/~dblecher/pf2.html#definitions&quot;&gt;What should you do with a definition&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.math.uh.edu/~dblecher/pf2.html#theorems&quot;&gt;Theorems, Propositions, Lemmas, and Corollaries&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.math.uh.edu/~dblecher/pf2.html#fit&quot;&gt;Fitting the subject together&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.math.uh.edu/~dblecher/pf2.html#proofs&quot;&gt;How to make sense of a proof&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.math.uh.edu/~dblecher/pf2.html#technique&quot;&gt;Developing technique&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.math.uh.edu/~dblecher/pf2.html#final&quot;&gt;A few final suggestions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.iwu.edu/%7Elstout&quot;&gt;Return&lt;/a&gt; to L.N. Stout's home page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;h2&gt;How is college mathematics different from high school math?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In high school mathematics much of your time was spent learning algorithms and manipulative techniques which you were expected to be able to apply in certain well-defined situations. This limitation of material and expectations for your performance has probably led you to develop study habits which were appropriate for high school mathematics but may be insufficient for college mathematics. This can be a source of much frustration for you and for your instructors. My object in writing this essay is to help ease this frustration by describing some study strategies which may help you channel your abilities and energies in a productive direction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first major difference between high school mathematics and college mathematics is the amount of emphasis on what the student would call theory---the precise statement of definitions and theorems and the logical processes by which those theorems are established. To the mathematician this material, together with examples showing why the definitions chosen are the correct ones and how the theorems can be put to practical use, is the essence of mathematics. A course description using the term ``rigorous'' indicates that considerable care will be taken in the statement of definitions and theorems and that proofs will be given for the theorems rather than just plausibility arguments. If your approach is to go straight to the problems with only cursory reading of the ``theory'' this aspect of college math will cause difficulties for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second difference between college mathematics and high school mathematics comes in the approach to technique and application problems. In high school you studied one technique at a time---a problem set or unit might deal, for instance, with solution of quadratic equations by factoring or by use of the quadratic formula, but it wouldn't teach both and ask you to decide which was the better approach for particular problems. To be sure, you learn individual techniques well in this approach, but you are unlikely to learn how to attack a problem for which you are not told what technique to use or which is not exactly like other applications you have seen. College mathematics will offer many techniques which can be applied for a particular type of problem---individual problems may have many possible approaches, some of which work better than others. Part of the task of working such a problem lies in choosing the appropriate technique. This requires study habits which develop judgment as well as technical competence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will take up the problem of how to study mathematics by considering specific aspects individually. First we will consider definitions---first because they form the foundation for any part of mathematics and are essential for understanding theorems. Then we'll take up theorems, lemmas, propositions, and corollaries and how to study the way the subject fits together. The subject of proofs, how to decipher them and why we need them, comes next. And finally, we will discuss development of judgment in problem solving.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.math.uh.edu/~dblecher/pf2.html#top&quot;&gt;To contents&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What should you do with a definition?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A definition in mathematics is a precise statement delineating and naming a concept by relating it to previously defined concepts or such undefined concepts as ``number'' or ``set.'' Careful definitions are necessary so that we know exactly what we are talking about. Unfortunately, for many of the concepts in undergraduate mathematics the definition is rather difficult to understand, so often at low levels an intuitive feeling for the meaning of a term is all that is given or required. This intuitive feeling, while necessary, is not sufficient at the college level. This means that you need to grapple with and master the formal statement of definitions and their meanings. How do you do it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Step 1. Make sure you understand what the definition says.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This sounds obvious, but it can cause some difficulties, particularly for definitions with complicated logical structure (like the definition of the limit of a function at a point in its domain). Definitions are not a good place to practice your speed reading. In general there are no wasted words or extraneous symbols in established definitions and the easily overlooked small words like &lt;em&gt;and, or, if ... then, for all,&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;there is&lt;/em&gt; are your clues to the logical structure of the definition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First determine what general class of things is being talked about: the definition of a polynomial describes a particular kind of algebraic expression; the definition of a continuous function specifies a kind of function; the definition of a basis for a vector space specifies a kind of set of vectors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next decipher the logical structure of the definition. What do you have to do to show that a member of your general class of things satisfies the definition: what do you have to do to show that an expression is a polynomial, or a function is continuous, or a set of vectors is a basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Step 2. Determine the scope of the definition with examples.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most definitions have standard examples that go with them. While these are useful, they may lead you to expect that all examples look like the standard example. To understand a definition you should make up your own examples: find three examples that do satisfy the definition but which are as different as possible from each other; find two examples of items in the general class described by the definition which do not satisfy it. Prove that your five examples do what you think they do---such proofs are usually short, follow the structure of the definition quite closely, and help immensely in understanding the definition. These examples should be neatly written up so that you can refer to them later. Your own examples will have more meaning for you than mine or the book's when it comes time to review.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Step 3. Memorize the exact wording of the definition.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This step may sound petty, but the use of definitions demands knowledge of exactly what they say. For this reason you can count on being asked for the statement of any definition on an exam. The importance of precise wording should have been made clear by your examples in step 2 and it certainly is essential in the proof of theorems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Solid knowledge of definitions is more than a third of the battle. Time spent gaining such knowledge is not wasted.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.math.uh.edu/~dblecher/pf2.html#top&quot;&gt;To contents&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Theorems, Propositions, Lemmas, and Corollaries&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Occasionally definitions are useful in and of themselves, but usually we need to relate them to each other and to general problems before they can be made to work for us. This is the role of theory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The relative importance and the intended use of statements which are then proved is hinted at by the names they are given. Theorems are usually important results which show how to make concepts solve problems or give major insights into the workings of the subject. They often have involved and deep proofs. Propositions give smaller results, often relating different definitions to each other or giving alternate forms of the definition. Proofs of propositions are usually less complex than the proofs of theorems. Lemmas are technical results used in the proofs of theorems. Often it is found that the same trick is used several times in one proof or in the proof of several theorems. When this happens the trick is isolated in a lemma so that its proof will not have to be repeated every time it is used. This often makes the proofs of theorems shorter and, one hopes, more lucid. Corollaries are immediate consequences of theorems either giving special cases or highlighting the interest and importance of the theorem. If the author or instructor has been careful (not all authors and instructors are) with the use of these labels, they will help you figure out what is important in the subject.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The steps to understanding and mastering a theorem follow the same lines as the steps to understanding a definition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Step 1. Make sure you understand what the theorem says.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part of this is a vocabulary problem. Theorems use terms which have been given precise meanings by definitions. So you may need to review the definitions to understand the words in a theorem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next you need to understand the logical structure of the theorem: what are the hypotheses and what are the conclusions? If you have several hypotheses, must they all be satisfied (that is, do they have an  &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; between them) or will it suffice to have only some of them (an  &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;or&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; between them)? In most cases theorems require that all of their hypotheses be satisfied. A theorem tells you nothing about a situation which does not satisfy the hypothesis. The hypothesis tells you what you must show in order for the theorem to apply to a particular case. The conclusions tell you what the theorem tells you about each case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Step 2. Determine how the theorem is used.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This involves finding examples of problems for which the theorem gives a technique for finding the answer. Make up your own problems and show how the theorem helps with them. Again writing this down will help solidify the theorem in your mind and make it easier to review.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Step 3. Find out what the hypotheses are doing there.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a little tricky and is probably more important in advanced courses than in beginning courses. What you do is find examples (either your own or someone else's) to show that if individual hypotheses are omitted the conclusion can be false. For instance, in calculus many theorems have a hypothesis that the functions involved be continuous; why does the theorem fail if this hypothesis is left out? Usually an example will make this clearer than an examination of how the hypothesis was used in the proof will. A catalog of such examples can be very useful. See for instance the books Counterexamples in Analysis and Counterexamples in Topology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In some cases a hypothesis is included just because it makes an otherwise complicated proof easy. This means that you may not be able to find examples which illustrate that each hypothesis is essential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Step 4. Memorize the statement of the theorem.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are going to use a theorem you need to know exactly what it says. Pay particular attention to hypotheses. We will take up proofs later, but for now let me note that it is not a good idea to try to memorize the proof of a theorem. What you want to do is understand the proof well enough that you can prove the theorem yourself.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.math.uh.edu/~dblecher/pf2.html#top&quot;&gt;To contents&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Fitting the subject together&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mathematics is not a collection of miscellaneous techniques but rather a way of thinking---a unified subject. Part of the task of studying mathematics is getting the various definitions and theorems properly related to each other. This is particularly important at the end of a course, but it will help you make sense of the content and organization of a subject if you keep the overall organization in mind as you go along. There are two techniques I know of which help with this process: working backwards and definition-theorem outlines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Step 1. Working backwards&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In general there is very little difficulty recognizing a major result when you get to it. A good way of seeing how a subject works is to examine the proof of a major result and see what previous results were used in it. Then trace these results back to earlier results used to prove them. Eventually you will work your way back to definitions (unless there are theorems given without proof---in calculus, for instance, the proof of the intermediate value theorem is often omitted because it requires a deeper understanding of the real numbers than is usually available at the beginning of calculus 1). This information can be put into a sort of genealogy chart for results which helps you see at a glance how the results fit together. It helps to have descriptive names for your theorems and lemmas. Such a chart might look sort of like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
  
 
 
Mean Value Theorem
      Rolle's Theorem
           Candidate Lemma
                Meaning of the sign of the derivative
                     Definition of derivative
                Definition of max and min
      Existence  of  max  and  min   for  continuous  functions  on [a, b]
                Definition of max and min
                Definition of closed interval
                Least upper bound axiom
                Definition of continuity
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With such a road map through the theory you should be able to tell how you got where you are, if not where you are headed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Step 2. Make a definition-theorem outline.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After you have worked backwards to the definitions for each of your major theorems in a section you should have a good idea of which results are needed before others can be proved. Some definitions will not make sense until certain theorems are proved (dimension of a vector space is an example: you can't give a number a name until you know you are talking about a unique number, and that requires a theorem). A definition theorem outline is an arrangement of the results in an order so that each result is introduced before it is needed in a proof. It should contain the precise statements of all definitions and theorems and a sketch of the proof of each theorem. A sketch of a proof will show which earlier results were used and how they were combined. It will usually omit calculations simplifying forms of expressions and routine checks that hypotheses are satisfied. This outline is both a good way to start a review and a useful thing to have to refer to.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.math.uh.edu/~dblecher/pf2.html#top&quot;&gt;To contents&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How to make sense of a proof&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;College level mathematics demands that the student work through (or at least sit through) many proofs. This is often unpopular, I think largely because it is hard work to follow a proof, hard work of an unfamiliar kind. Proof is largely absent or at most optional in high school math; it is neither absent nor optional in college mathematics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Step 1. Make sure you know what the theorem says.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have the hypotheses mixed up with the conclusions you will not know what assumptions may be made nor will you know what conclusion you are trying to reach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Step 2. Make a general outline of the proof.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is what you would do in a definition theorem outline. See what the previous results used are and find out what the basic strategy of the proof is. On this pass through omit the details, else you miss the direction of the road by too close examination of the bricks in the pavement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most theorems have the form of implications: if the hypotheses are true, then the conclusion follows. The easiest structure for a proof to use is to assume the hypotheses and combine them, using previous results, to reach the conclusion through a chain of implications. Some proofs use other strategies: contrapositive argument, reductio ad absurdum, mathematical induction, perhaps even Zorn's lemma (a form of the axiom of choice). The more complicated kinds of proofs will need to be discussed in class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Step 3. Fill in all of the details.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you understand the strategy of the proof concentrate on its tactics. Almost all expositions of proofs in undergraduate mathematics textbooks (and all expositions at higher levels) leave out many routine steps. An expression will be simplified without showing exactly how to get from one line to the next. Fill in these details. A theorem will be quoted and applied without explicitly checking all of its hypotheses. Check them. Some parts of the proof will be outlined with the details left to the reader. Put in those details. When you finish you should know why each step follows from what came before. You may not see how anyone could have thought to do the proof that way, but you should be able to see that it is correct.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Why bother with proofs at all?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the mathematics major this question is easy to answer---a large portion of mathematics consists of proofs. The mathematician enjoys the logical puzzle which must be solved to find a proof and obtains aesthetic satisfaction from elegance in proofs. The student who wants to major in mathematics should do so because of ability in deciphering and producing proofs and enjoyment derived from proof well done. The major should also have skill in solving problems and finding applications as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But many of you will say ``I'm not a math major; I want applications so that I can use tools from mathematics in my field'' or ``I'm just taking this course because it's a requirement in my major and I sort of liked math in high school.'' Why should you learn about proof?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The applications you meet in other fields are not likely to look exactly like the math textbook applications, which are chosen for their appeal to a traditional audience (largely engineers) and for their representative character. Other applications work similarly, though not exactly the same way. This means that you need to learn how to apply the concepts in your math courses to situations not discussed in those courses. (There is no way that a course could discuss every possible known application: about 500 papers appear every two weeks with applications, and those are just the applications published in the ``mathematical'' literature!) To do so you need the best possible understanding of the mathematics you want to apply. Certainly this means that you need to know the hypotheses of theorems so that you don't apply them where they won't work. It is helpful to know the proof so that you can see how to circumvent the failed hypothesis if necessary. One of the major pitfalls of applied mathematics, particularly as practiced by nonmathematicians, is the danger of conveniently overlooking the assumptions of a mathematical model. (Mathematicians trying to do applied mathematics are more likely to fall into the trap of making models which have no relationship to reality.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many applications consist of recognizing the definition of a mathematical concept phrased in the terms of another discipline---the more familiar you are with the definition, the more likely you are to be able to recognize the disguised version elsewhere. The nuances of definitions are made most clear in the proofs of propositions relating definitions and pointing out unexpected equivalent variants, some of which may look more like a situation in another discipline than the precise form used in your math class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arguments for theory as an aid to application rest on an obvious premise: it is much easier to apply something you understand thoroughly. This is, however, a better argument for care in learning the statements of theorems than it is for spending time understanding proofs. The best justification for the inclusion of proof in math classes is more philosophical:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Proof is the ultimate test of validity in mathematics.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once one accepts the logical processes involved in a proof no further observation or change in fashion will change the validity of a mathematical result. No other discipline has such an immutable criterion for validity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The major benefit derived from an education is the ability to think clearly and make considered judgment. Each discipline should teach a body of material, appropriate modes of thought in dealing with that material, and a means for determining the validity of the conclusions reached. A chemistry curriculum with no lab work would be seriously deficient since experiment is the test of validity in science. Similarly mathematics without proof is severely deficient, indeed it is not mathematics.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.math.uh.edu/~dblecher/pf2.html#top&quot;&gt;To contents&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Developing technique&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About a third to a half of any math course deals with technique---the process of making theorems work for you in specific situations rather than in the general setting in which they are usually stated. Sometimes this is fairly easy: many proofs give explicit constructions which you follow for the special case. In these situations the only problems are with algebraic and trigonometric manipulations and keeping track of where you are in the process. In other situations (technique of integration is a good example) there are lots of approaches which might apply to a given problem and several tricks which might be used to make the problem more tractable. For these you need to develop judgment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Step 1. Read through the theorems and examples.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some students make the whole process of learning how to do problems more difficult by acting like it had no connection with the other material in the course. Often problems follow a pattern which is given explicitly in the proof of the major theorem they follow. Knowing the general pattern in advance is easier than trying to find it by trial and error.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Step 2. Work enough problems to master the technique.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this stage you should work enough problems so that the single technique which the problems illustrate is firmly in your mind. Since you have ultimate responsibility for your education, you should take the initiative to work enough problems for your own practice needs. This may well be more problems than are assigned to be turned in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Step 3. Work a few problems in as many different ways as possible.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Too often the practice obtained in step 2 leads the student to think that there is only one approach to each problem. Sometimes one approach is easy and another is complicated, but often several different attacks will work equally well. Complicated approaches give the student practice in solving problems which take more than one step and more than one technique.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Step 4. Make yourself a set of randomly chosen problems.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One difficulty with learning many techniques to solve a particular kind of problem is that you have to figure out which technique to use before you can get to work on a solution. This is exacerbated by the tendency for problems to be grouped so that the appropriate technique to use is the one which immediately preceded the problem set. Putting two or three problems from each of the problem sets in a chapter on technique on 3 by 5 cards and then shuffling the cards will give you a set of problems on which to practice deciding which technique to use.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.math.uh.edu/~dblecher/pf2.html#top&quot;&gt;To contents&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;A few final suggestions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mathematical prose has a very low redundancy rate and mathematics is a very cumulative subject. Pay close attention as you read---once introduced, a concept is rarely repeated and it will be assumed later. Allow yourself adequate time to read the book before starting the problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Few students write fast enough to get complete and readable notes in class. For this reason it is useful to go back over your class notes shortly after each class and make a complete, clean copy with all of the definitions and theorems clearly stated. This practice will also help you identify parts you don't understand so you can ask your professor about them in a timely fashion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do not let yourself fall behind. Mathematics requires precision, habits of clear thought, and practice. Cramming for an exam will not only fail to produce the desired result on the exam, it will also reinforce a bad habit---that of trying to do mathematics by memorization rather than understanding. A good night's sleep and a clear head will serve you better than last minute memorization.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.math.uh.edu/~dblecher/pf2.html#top&quot;&gt;To contents&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;address&gt;lstout@sun.iwu.edu&lt;/address&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 14:53:50 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>kenny87</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.math.uh.edu/~dblecher/pf2.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Facebook ordered to delete illegally collected data by Belgian court</title>
<link>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2018/feb/16/facebook-ordered-stop-collecting-user-data-fines-belgian-court</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2018/feb/16/facebook-ordered-stop-collecting-user-data-fines-belgian-court</guid>
<description>&lt;header class=&quot;content__head content__head--article tonal__head tonal__head--tone-news&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;content__headline-standfirst-wrapper&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;tonal__standfirst u-cf&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content__standfirst&quot; data-link-name=&quot;standfirst&quot; data-component=&quot;standfirst&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Social network instructed to delete illegally collected data or face €100m in fines after it loses case over consent and tracking&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;u-responsive-ratio&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;maxed responsive-img&quot; itemprop=&quot;contentUrl&quot; alt=&quot;Facebook&quot; src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/322719401053edcb22d42f01c4c7eb5c6b68867f/0_405_4126_2476/master/4126.jpg?w=300&amp;amp;q=55&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;usm=12&amp;amp;fit=max&amp;amp;s=b8630c397d66ec01a6b71cfc5af0074c&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;show-caption&quot; class=&quot;mobile-only u-h reveal-caption__checkbox&quot;/&gt; ‘The cookies and pixels we use are industry standard technologies and enable hundreds of thousands of businesses to grow,’ said Richard Allan, Facebook’s vice president of public policy for EMEA. Photograph: Sascha Steinbach/EPA&lt;/header&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/facebook&quot; data-link-name=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; data-component=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; has been ordered by a Belgian court to stop collecting data on users or face daily fines of €250,000 a day, or up to €100m.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The court ruled on Friday that Facebook had broken privacy laws by tracking people on third-party sites in the latest salvo in a long-running battle between the Belgian commission for the protection of privacy (CPP) and the social network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Facebook informs us insufficiently about gathering information about us, the kind of data it collects, what it does with that data and how long it stores it,” the court said. “It also does not gain our consent to collect and store all this information.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook has also been ordered to delete all data it had gathered illegally on Belgian citizens, including people who were not users of the social network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The social media firm uses different methods to track the online behaviour of people if they are not on the company’s web site by placing cookies and invisible pixels on third party web sites, the court said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Richard Allan, Facebook’s vice president of public policy for EMEA, said the company was disappointed with the verdict and intended to appeal: “The cookies and pixels we use are industry standard technologies and enable hundreds of thousands of businesses to grow their businesses and reach customers across the EU.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We require any business that uses our technologies to provide clear notice to end-users, and we give people the right to opt-out of having data collected on sites and apps off Facebook being used for ads.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Belgium v Facebook&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The battle between Belgium and Facebook has been running since 2015, when the CPP commissioned a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2015/mar/31/facebook-tracks-all-visitors-breaching-eu-law-report&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;report by researchers from the University of Leuven&lt;/a&gt;, which found that Facebook’s tracking of all visitors without explicit consent using cookies breached EU law. The CPP, which does not have powers to directly penalise companies, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2015/jun/15/belgium-facebook-court-privacy-breaches-ads&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;took Facebook to court&lt;/a&gt; later that year for its alleged “trampling” over Belgian and EU privacy law after failing to come to an agreement with the social network following the report’s findings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Belgian court &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2015/nov/10/belgian-court-orders-facebook-to-stop-tracking-non-members&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;ordered Facebook to stop tracking non-members&lt;/a&gt; at the end of 2015, threatening fines. Facebook appealed against the court’s ruling at the start of 2016, disputing that Belgium had jurisdiction over the social network as its European operations were headquartered in Dublin. Facebook also &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2016/jan/29/facebook-belgian-tracking-english-court-ruling-cookie-browser&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;disputed the use of English&lt;/a&gt; in the ruling including the words “browser” and “cookie”, which the social network said was against Belgian law that stipulates only Dutch, French or German may be used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook then won on appeal, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2016/jun/30/facebook-wins-appeal-against-belgian-privacy-watchdog-over-tracking&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;overturning the decision&lt;/a&gt; that blocked it from using its so-called “datr cookies” to track the internet activity of logged-out users in Belgium. That appeal has now been overturned, with the court backing the findings of the CPP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is just one of many battles Facebook is fighting in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/europe-news&quot; data-link-name=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; data-component=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Europe&lt;/a&gt; as the political winds have turned against the big US technology firms. The EU and European nations continually criticise Facebook for failing to do enough to tackle the rise of take news and to deal with extremist content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its WhatsApp messenger is also &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2017/oct/26/whatsapp-facebook-eu-data-article-29-working-party-taskforce-sharing-user&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;facing a task force&lt;/a&gt; from the European data regulator, the Article 29 Working Party, over its failure to adequately address concerns about getting user consent to share data with Facebook. The social network’s default privacy settings and use of personal data were recently &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2018/feb/12/facebook-personal-data-privacy-settings-ruled-illegal-german-court&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;ruled illegal by a Berlin court&lt;/a&gt; in Germany. France has also ordered the company &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2017/dec/19/france-orders-whatsapp-stop-sharing-user-data-facebook-without-consent&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;to stop its sharing of WhatsApp user data&lt;/a&gt;, while Facebook &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/business/2017/may/18/facebook-fined-eu-whatsapp-european-commission&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;was fined £94m&lt;/a&gt; by the EU for providing “misleading” information in its takeover of WhatsApp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is all on the eve of the introduction of tough new European data privacy rules, called the General Data Protection Regulation, which come into force on 25 May. Allan said: “We are preparing for the new General Data Protection Regulation with our lead regulator the Irish Data Protection Commissioner. We’ll comply with this new law, just as we’ve complied with existing data protection law in Europe.”&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 14:42:42 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>317070</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://www.theguardian.com/technology/2018/feb/16/facebook-ordered-stop-collecting-user-data-fines-belgian-court</og:url>
<og:description>Social network instructed to delete illegally collected data or face €100m in fines after it loses case over consent and tracking</og:description>
<og:image>https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/322719401053edcb22d42f01c4c7eb5c6b68867f/0_405_4126_2476/master/4126.jpg?w=1200&amp;h=630&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;fit=crop&amp;crop=faces%2Centropy&amp;bm=normal&amp;ba=bottom%2Cleft&amp;blend64=aHR0cHM6Ly91cGxvYWRzLmd1aW0uY28udWsvMjAxOC8wMS8zMS9mYWNlYm9va19kZWZhdWx0LnBuZw&amp;s=3876a6717915416fe0eeb4b5ac1d83d1</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Facebook ordered to stop collecting user data by Belgian court</og:title>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2018/feb/16/facebook-ordered-stop-collecting-user-data-fines-belgian-court</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>ISP Spying</title>
<link>https://harrisonsand.com/your-isp-is-spying-on-you/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://harrisonsand.com/your-isp-is-spying-on-you/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;A while back I decided to no longer use the router given to me by my ISP. You may want to consider doing the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had read one too many &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2016/11/notorious-iot-botnets-weaponize-new-flaw-found-in-millions-of-home-routers/&quot;&gt;articles&lt;/a&gt; about the crappy security in consumer routers, and came to the conclusion that I wanted more control over my home network. I eventually landed on a pfSense-based solution, but this sparked my interest and I wanted to see how the ISP supplied router actually worked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;howmyispworks&quot;&gt;How my ISP Works&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I live in Norway, and recieve FTTH services from &lt;a href=&quot;https://no.wikipedia.org/wiki/Altibox&quot;&gt;Altibox&lt;/a&gt; (Norwegian). Services are delivered through three separate 802.1Q VLANs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;100 - traditional phone and CPE (router) management&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;101 - IPTV&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;102 - internet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Additionally, customers can manage their router, wireless settings, etc. though the customer portal on the ISPs website.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://harrisonsand.com/content/images/2018/02/altibox_portal.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;altibox_portal&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Right off the bat some questions come to mind about how that communication between the router and customer portal looks...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;history&quot;&gt;History&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To give some background - most, if not all major ISPs source their customer premise equipment (CPE) from third party vendors. ZyXEL in my case. That is, they purchase pre-built, out of the box solutions to manage customer routers. This may include everything from the delivery of branded hardware, to the backend systems that centrally manage the vast number of devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why? It normally comes down to cost. It doesn't really make sense to start from scratch, hire your own developers, worry about support, etc... when you can just outsource the whole thing for a fraction of the cost. This doesn't inherently have to be a bad business model; you don't see too many people building their own cars to get to work. Though on the flip side, it's absolutely &lt;strong&gt;critical&lt;/strong&gt; that a company thoroughly understands what they are purchasing and that they have the in house technical expertise to actually follow up and challenge the vendor. You don't just go to a dealership and purchase a car because the salesman said it was the best thing since sliced bread. You need to do your homework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, takeaways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;A lot of ISPs have similar solutions, and this problem won't just affect my tiny ISP in Norway (430,000 customers in 2016)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most ISPs don't fully understand what they are selling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;trafficanalysis&quot;&gt;Traffic Analysis&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Naturally, I set up a SPAN port on my switch and loaded up a packet capture. Honing in on the management traffic, I found a XML-based protocol called &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/TR-069&quot;&gt;TR-069&lt;/a&gt;. This is a common protocol, used by ISPs around the world to manage customer routers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mixed somewhere in between the &lt;strong&gt;unencrypted HTTP traffic&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;plaintext admin passwords&lt;/strong&gt; was something I found to be a bit more interesting. Altibox periodically collects a list of all devices that are/were connected to my private home network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;ParameterValueStruct&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;Name&amp;gt;InternetGatewayDevice.LANDevice.1.Hosts.Host.18.X_ZyXEL_IconIndex&amp;lt;/Name&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;Value xsi:type=&quot;xsd:unsignedInt&quot;&amp;gt;0&amp;lt;/Value&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ParameterValueStruct&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ParameterValueStruct&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;Name&amp;gt;InternetGatewayDevice.LANDevice.1.Hosts.Host.18.MACAddress&amp;lt;/Name&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;Value xsi:type=&quot;xsd:string&quot;&amp;gt;5C:E0:C5:[removed]&amp;lt;/Value&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ParameterValueStruct&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ParameterValueStruct&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;Name&amp;gt;InternetGatewayDevice.LANDevice.1.Hosts.Host.18.X_ZyXEL_DeviceName&amp;lt;/Name&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;Value xsi:type=&quot;xsd:string&quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/Value&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ParameterValueStruct&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ParameterValueStruct&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;Name&amp;gt;InternetGatewayDevice.LANDevice.1.Hosts.Host.18.LeaseTimeRemaining&amp;lt;/Name&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;Value xsi:type=&quot;xsd:int&quot;&amp;gt;0&amp;lt;/Value&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ParameterValueStruct&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ParameterValueStruct&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;Name&amp;gt;InternetGatewayDevice.LANDevice.1.Hosts.Host.18.X_ZyXEL_SessionNum&amp;lt;/Name&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;Value xsi:type=&quot;xsd:unsignedInt&quot;&amp;gt;109&amp;lt;/Value&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ParameterValueStruct&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ParameterValueStruct&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;Name&amp;gt;InternetGatewayDevice.LANDevice.1.Hosts.Host.18.Active&amp;lt;/Name&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;Value xsi:type=&quot;xsd:boolean&quot;&amp;gt;0&amp;lt;/Value&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ParameterValueStruct&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ParameterValueStruct&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;Name&amp;gt;InternetGatewayDevice.LANDevice.1.Hosts.Host.18.IPAddress&amp;lt;/Name&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;Value xsi:type=&quot;xsd:string&quot;&amp;gt;192.168.10.172&amp;lt;/Value&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ParameterValueStruct&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ParameterValueStruct&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;Name&amp;gt;InternetGatewayDevice.LANDevice.1.Hosts.Host.18.AddressSource&amp;lt;/Name&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;Value xsi:type=&quot;xsd:string&quot;&amp;gt;DHCP&amp;lt;/Value&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ParameterValueStruct&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ParameterValueStruct&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;Name&amp;gt;InternetGatewayDevice.LANDevice.1.Hosts.Host.18.HostName&amp;lt;/Name&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;Value xsi:type=&quot;xsd:string&quot;&amp;gt;harrison-pc&amp;lt;/Value&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ParameterValueStruct&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ParameterValueStruct&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;Name&amp;gt;InternetGatewayDevice.LANDevice.1.Hosts.Host.18.InterfaceType&amp;lt;/Name&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;Value xsi:type=&quot;xsd:string&quot;&amp;gt;Ethernet&amp;lt;/Value&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ParameterValueStruct&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If that made your eyes hurt, a quick summary is that they collect:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The device's hostname - this is whatever you set it to, but is often the name of the owner (for example &quot;harrison-pc&quot; or &quot;Harrison's iPhone&quot;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The device's MAC address - a unique identifier tied to the network card&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Active true/false - this reports if the device is activly connected to the network or not&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The devices internal IP address&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;consequences&quot;&gt;Consequences&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's a reasonable chance you might be thinking &quot;Why does this matter?&quot; or &quot;What does this mean for me?&quot; Realistically speaking, chances are nothing bad will happen to you because of this. But there are several reasons to still be concerned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In theory, there are some scenarios where this data could become interesting. With the data you could for example: infer the people you know based on who connects to your network, and which networks you connect to. You could also piece together behavior patterns based on when people are connected and at home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It goes a bit further when you think about who has access to this data. To begin it might just be your ISP, but it could also be sold to third parties for marketing purposes or otherwise. Add the potential for data breaches in there and the consequences become slightly more interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And to top it all off, there's no &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt; business requirement for this information to be collected in the first place. You could argue it's for technical support or diagnostics, but that would only be a once-off requirement and not sent on regular intervals. You could also ask the customer for their approval first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chances are this data is being collected for marketing purposes, just because they can, or the functionality was on by default and they don't know about it or just left it the way it was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With all that said you probably wouldn't want some dude sitting outside your house taking notes of when you leave and come home, and making lists of who your visitors are. It's just plain creepy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;legality&quot;&gt;Legality&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been in contact with the Norwegian Data Protection Authority - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.datatilsynet.no&quot;&gt;Datatilsynet&lt;/a&gt; in regards to my findings. They have provided helpful guidance on the matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In additon, I have contacted Altibox directly asking them explain the data collection. Their response was professional, though I don't necessarily agree with all of their points. Potentially some gaps between policies and reality...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Viken Fiber works to deliver Altibox services)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;Hi, thanks for your inquiry

The following is collected from Altibox managed access point (WiFi router):
Software and hardware version, equipment Mac address, time up, temperature, CPU
statistics, memory statistics, connection statistics, number of processes running,
logical interface IP, uplink media type (fiber or copper), Altibox DNS time to
respond, switchport and radio error statistics aggregated and per connected device.


The information is used only for error checking and correcting activities, 
and only when initiated by end customer.
- Data is saved for a maximum of 21 days.
- Data is collected and stored using dedicated hardware.
- Data is limited and accessed using dedicated frontend software and individual user authorization.
- All data requests are logged
- All external data are encrypted

This is in accordance with the Norwegian Personal data act § 8 and Altibox general terms paragraph 26.
https://www.altibox.no/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/Altibox_almvilkaar2017.pdf
https://lovdata.no/dokument/NL/lov/2000-04-14-31/KAPITTEL_2#§8

Best regards
Viken Fiber AS
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/General_Data_Protection_Regulation&quot;&gt;European data protection regulations (GDPR)&lt;/a&gt; that come into affect this year could also have influence on the legality of this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end, there are some obvious areas for improvement from Altibox's side, but at the same time I don't have the means to make a determination either way on the matter. I do however know it's just plain creepy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 08:07:59 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>early</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Your ISP is Probably Spying On You</og:title>
<og:description>A while back I decided to no longer use the router given to me by my ISP. You may want to consider doing the same.</og:description>
<og:url>http://harrisonsand.com/your-isp-is-spying-on-you/</og:url>
<og:image>http://harrisonsand.com/content/images/2018/02/IMG_1069.jpg</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://harrisonsand.com/your-isp-is-spying-on-you/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Benjamin Franklin method for learning more from programming books</title>
<link>http://www.pathsensitive.com/2018/01/the-benjamin-franklin-method-of-reading.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.pathsensitive.com/2018/01/the-benjamin-franklin-method-of-reading.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Let’s face it, programming books suck. Those general books on distributed systems or data science or whatever can be tomes for a lifetime, but, with few exceptions, there’s something about the books on how to write code in a language/framework/database/cupcake-maker, the ones with the animal covers and the cutesy sample apps, they just tend to be so forgettable, so trite, so….uneducational.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think I’ve figured out why I don’t like them, and it’s not just that they teach skills rapidly approaching expiration. It’s their pedagogical approach. The teaching algorithm seems to be: write these programs where we’ve told you everything to do, and you’ll come out knowing this language/framework/database/cupcake-maker. Central to these books are the long code listings for the reader to reproduce. Here’s an example, from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.railstutorial.org/book/advanced_login#sec-forgetting_users&quot;&gt;one of the better books in this category&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;18&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span&gt;class&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;User&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;ApplicationRecord&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;attr_accessor&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;:remember_token&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;before_save&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;self&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;email&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;email&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;downcase&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;validates&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;:name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;span&gt;presence&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;length&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;maximum&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;50&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;VALID_EMAIL_REGEX&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;/\A[\w+\-.]+@[a-z\d\-.]+\.[a-z]+\z/i&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;validates&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;:email&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;presence&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;length&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;maximum&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;255&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;},&lt;/span&gt;
                    &lt;span&gt;format:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;with&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;VALID_EMAIL_REGEX&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;},&lt;/span&gt;
                    &lt;span&gt;uniqueness&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;case_sensitive:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;false&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;has_secure_password&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;validates&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;:password&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;presence&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;length&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;minimum&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;6&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

  &lt;span&gt;# …another 30 lines follows...&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traditionally, there are two ways to study a page like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Type out every line of code &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copy+paste the code from their website, maybe play around and make small changes &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;Approach #1 is a method that, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.blogger.com/&quot;&gt;like a lecture&lt;/a&gt;, causes the code to go from the author’s page to the reader’s screen without passing through the heads of either. The second is like trying to learn how to make a car by taking apart a seatbelt and stereo: you’re just toying with small pieces. Neither is a sound way to learn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you had an expert tutor, they wouldn’t teach you by handing you a page of code. Still, these books are what we have. How can we read them in a way that follows the principles of learning? Read on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Mental Representations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to K. Anders Ericsson in his book Peak, expertise is a process of building mental representations. We can see this because expert minds store knowledge in a compressed fashion. Musicians can memorize a page of music far faster than a page of random notes. Expert chess players told to memorize a board position will do much better than amateurs, but, when they make a mistake, they’ll misplace whole groups of pieces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is possible because music and chess positions have structure that makes them look very different from a page of random notes or a random permutation of pieces. Technically speaking, they have lower &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Perplexity&quot;&gt;perplexity&lt;/a&gt; than random noise. So, even though there are 26 letters in the English alphabet, Claude Shannon showed that the information content of English is about 1 bit per letter: given a random prefix of a paragraph, people can guess the next letter about half the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is why a programmer skilled in a technology can look at code using it and read through it like fiction, only pausing at the surprising bits, while the novice is laboring line-by-line. This is also why a s&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cs.technion.ac.il/~yahave/papers/pldi14-statistical.pdf&quot;&gt;mart code-completion tool &lt;/a&gt;can guess a long sequence of code from the first couple lines. With a better mental representation, understanding code is simply less work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;246&quot; src=&quot;https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/HKSIE2WwzQ1Dcy5a44Q_VdYa2Xa7bB3mHtawUEOIFw0wwXZVOsIWU9NziprAG_5ecdihSfvgoQ0h5yV_JyNYmvsronm1ODIpj2CjwqMcWyAs8eL0y5ErLyLKIqXNLSkPZDcpWfDK&quot; width=&quot;640&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(How do these mental representations work? My officemate Zenna Tavares argues they are &lt;a href=&quot;https://openreview.net/pdf?id=BJVEEF9lx&quot;&gt;distribution-sensitive data structures&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is exactly what’s missing from the “just type out the code” approach: there’s nothing forcing your mind to represent the program as anything better than a sequence of characters. Yet being able to force your mind to do this would mean being able to learn concepts more rapidly. Here’s a 200 year-old idea for doing so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Benjamin Franklin Method&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t know what’s more impressive: that Benjamin Franklin became a luminary in everything from politics to physics, or that he did this without modern educational techniques such as schools, teachers, or StackOverflow. As part of this, he discovered a powerful method of self-study. I’ll let him speak for himself (or go read &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/personal-growth/the-benjamin-franklin-method-how-to-actually-learn-to-write-1ac4ebc7c3a7&quot;&gt;someone else’s summary&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot; readability=&quot;24&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About this time I met with an odd volume of the Spectator. It was the third. I had never before seen any of them. I bought it, read it over and over, and was much delighted with it. I thought the writing excellent, and wished, if possible, to imitate it. With this view I took some of the papers, and, making short hints of the sentiment in each sentence, laid them by a few days, and then, without looking at the book, try'd to compleat the papers again, by expressing each hinted sentiment at length, and as fully as it had been expressed before, in any suitable words that should come to hand. Then I compared my Spectator with the original, discovered some of my faults, and corrected them.&lt;/p&gt;
—Benjamin Franklin, Autobiography&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This process is a little bit like being a human autoencoder. An autoencoder is a neural network that tries to produce output the same as its input, but passing through an intermediate layer which is too small to fully represent the data. In doing so, it’s forced to learn a more compact representation. Here, the neural net in question is that den of dendrons in your head.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;K. Anders Ericsson likens it to how artists practice by trying to imitate some famous work. Mathematicians are taught to attempt to prove most theorems themselves when reading a book or paper --- even if they can’t, they’ll have an easier time compressing the proof to its basic insight. I used this process to get a better eye for graphical design; it was like LASIK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the basic version idea applied to programming books is particularly simple yet effective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Here’s how it works:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read your programming book as normal. When you get to a code sample, read it over&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then close the book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then try to type it up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simple, right? But try it and watch as you’re forced to learn some of the structure of the code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a lot like the way you may have already been doing it, just with more learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Acknowledgments&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Andrew Sheng and &lt;a href=&quot;http://wsmoses.com/&quot;&gt;Billy Moses&lt;/a&gt; for comments on previous drafts of this post.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 05:16:09 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>nancyhua</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://www.pathsensitive.com/2018/01/the-benjamin-franklin-method-of-reading.html</og:url>
<og:title>The Benjamin Franklin Method of Reading Programming Books</og:title>
<og:description>Let’s face it, programming books suck. Those general books on distributed systems or data science or whatever can be tomes for a lifetime, b...</og:description>
<og:image>https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/HKSIE2WwzQ1Dcy5a44Q_VdYa2Xa7bB3mHtawUEOIFw0wwXZVOsIWU9NziprAG_5ecdihSfvgoQ0h5yV_JyNYmvsronm1ODIpj2CjwqMcWyAs8eL0y5ErLyLKIqXNLSkPZDcpWfDK=w1200-h630-p-k-no-nu</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.pathsensitive.com/2018/01/the-benjamin-franklin-method-of-reading.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why I don&amp;#039;t use my real photo when messaging with customers on my website</title>
<link>https://www.kapwing.com/blog/why-i-dont-use-my-real-photo/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.kapwing.com/blog/why-i-dont-use-my-real-photo/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I’m a 24-year-old female web developer and founder of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kapwing.com&quot;&gt;Kapwing&lt;/a&gt;, an early-stage software startup. When my co-founder, Eric, and I launched the website in October, we decided to add a chat messenger so that users could message us directly with feedback, feature requests, and bugs. In this post, I’ll tell the story of how user responses changed when we changed the photo and gender of our website’s customer support agent.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;background&quot;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, Kapwing is a more full-featured online video editor, but at first, it was just a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kapwing.com/meme-maker&quot;&gt;meme maker&lt;/a&gt;. When we launched the MVP, we integrated with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.drift.com&quot;&gt;Drift&lt;/a&gt;, a messaging widget for websites, so we could connect with our users in real-time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/SGadUZy.png&quot; alt=&quot;Chat box on Kapwing&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When users come to our website (usually because they Google something like “How to make a video meme”), a chat window pops up in the bottom right corner of the screen with my photo and pre-set welcome message. Users can respond to, dismiss, or ignore the chat box. Since users can report their pain points in real time, many of the comments and questions have been useful as we try to fix bugs and prioritize new features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;as-julia-enthoven&quot;&gt;As “Julia Enthoven”&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we first added the chat box, I set up a ‘Welcome’ message, added my real name, and posted my LinkedIn photo, not thinking anything of it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/3pgYpnT.png&quot; alt=&quot;Drift welcome message&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of our website users didn’t message back, but some did, and we benefited a lot from feedback in the early stages of the website. But I also got a surprising number of offensive comments. Just about twice a day, a user responded to my welcome message with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Rude comments: Aggressive threats and name calling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Heckling and sexual harassment: People commenting on my looks, making sexual jokes, asking me out, sending suggestive photos and emojis, and generally creeping on me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trolls: Offensive and sarcastic nonsense&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some examples:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I generally have tough skin for these sorts of things, and, for about a month, I mostly just laughed and ignored the messages. I alternated between my social media feeds full of #MeToo statuses and the Drift app full of heckling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, on Nov 30, I got seven crude insults from users before showing up to the office. Annoyed, I told Eric I wanted to make a change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;as-eric-lu&quot;&gt;As “Eric Lu”&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/Utzb0SF.png&quot; alt=&quot;Eric Lu&quot;/&gt; We decided to switch to my co-founder’s photo and name to see if it would help reduce the amount of harassment. I would still be the one receiving and responding to messages, but users would think they were chatting with “Eric Lu.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of the harassment instantly dried up. Under Eric’s name, I got equally as many questions about our video editor from frustrated and happy users. But four days later I hadn’t gotten any obnoxious or lewd comments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/yEtgHbr.png?1&quot; alt=&quot;Kind2&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Result&lt;/strong&gt;: In seven days as “Eric Lu”, I got only one rude-ish message, and it was less severe or personal than comments I’d gotten before. This was the worst:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/OeWdtJT.png?1&quot; alt=&quot;Rude1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/Tacu8C0.png?1&quot; alt=&quot;Rude2&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;as-rachel-gray&quot;&gt;As “Rachel Gray”&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/nLkEi0U.jpg?1&quot; alt=&quot;Rachel profile&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The impact of changing from my own photo to Eric’s was so dramatic that we decided to investigate further. I found a stock photo of a blonde woman who was attractive in an obvious way and chose a stock name - “Rachel Gray” - to see how users’ responses compared. I switched our message avatar from Eric to “Rachel,” and immediately - less than one hour in after changing the photo - the heckling and name-calling resumed:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Result&lt;/strong&gt;: Rachel had it worse than I did. When I counted after three weeks of messaging with Rachel’s name and photo, I saw that we got about 50% more crude, aggressive, and nonsense messages with her avatar compared to mine. People asked her to go on dates, demanded that she share nude photos, and pleaded for all kinds of sexual favors. People called her names, cursed her out, asked her where she lived, and threatened her and the website. Mean, lewd messages came in from all over the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other than the creeps, trolls, and bullies, I didn’t notice a shift in the types of questions people were asking - users with problems on Kapwing still asked Rachel for help. But we didn’t analyze the volume of messages, so I can’t say if Rachel got more or fewer messages overall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;as-team-kapwing&quot;&gt;As “Team Kapwing”&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/9TCCt6j.jpg?1&quot; alt=&quot;Team Kapwing profile pic&quot;/&gt; For the last experimental iteration, we changed the photo to our website logo, the androgynous “Kapwing kitten,” with the name “Team Kapwing”. Team Kapwing was up for three weeks (from just before Christmas into January).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Result&lt;/strong&gt;: Users acted more respectful and friendly than they had towards Rachel. People still complained, reported bugs, and got frustrated when things broke - we had a server malfunction that broke the website for several hours in December - but users comments weren’t personal. Apparently, people don’t hit on cats, so I was mostly free from harassment for a while. &lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/gGjcays.png?1&quot; alt=&quot;When I mistakenly told a user my name&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over these three month, more than 55,000 people have visited the Kapwing website and have made more than 100,000 videos. To date, we’ve had more than 2,100 messages. Our informal study on the name and appearance of the customer support agent implied a bias against women: &lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/P4QCWO4.png&quot; alt=&quot;Chatbox sexism graphic&quot;/&gt; Of course, our experiment wasn’t a rigorous scientific study. Since we did not run the conditions at the same time, there were other variables at work. For example, we ran the Drift experiment over the holidays, which probably changes usage patterns and people’s overall mood/stress levels. We were also growing Kapwing, adding features that appealed to new audiences, and steadily increasing our website traffic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have three brothers, majored in computer science, and now am starting a company from a Silicon Valley VC office, so I’ve dealt with my fair share of sexism through the years. But this is the first time I have experienced first-hand how differently I would be treated if I could change my gender, at least on the internet. Naively, I was shocked and intrigued by how much more respectful people were to Eric than to me behind the anonymity of a chat box. In the end, we landed on “Team Kapwing” as our messaging support agent, although it’s still always me who talks to users. Here are some takeaways for other website owners:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you’re a female with a chat box, you might want a pseudonym&lt;/strong&gt;: Hiding behind Kapwing’s logo and company name on our messenger makes customer support easier and less discouraging. With the “Team Kapwing” name, people tend to assume that the person responding to them is a dude.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Consider the appearance of your support agents&lt;/strong&gt;: Your customers want someone who looks trustworthy and real, not cute or fake. Represent yourself as an on-brand expert in whatever industry your business operates in and experiment with different faces to see what works best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Customer support is very human&lt;/strong&gt;: Even though the internet puts distance and anonymity between website creators and their users, remember that there are humans on both sides of the screen. People love to chat, tease, and make friends, even if they know nothing about each other. They make spelling mistakes, jump to conclusions, use emojis and slang, and can be inpatient and insensitive. Although users are sometimes hurtful, it’s fun (and sometimes a waste of time) to connect directly with the real people using your product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading! Keep reading this blog to follow along as Eric and I grow Kapwing to ramen profitability.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 03:35:49 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>bemmu</dc:creator>
<og:title>Why I don't use my real photo when messaging with customers on my website · Kapwing Blog</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.kapwing.com/blog/why-i-dont-use-my-real-photo/</og:url>
<og:image>https://i.imgur.com/22cf8A1.png</og:image>
<og:description>We changed the photo and name of our customer support agent four times to see how it changed users' responses. This is the story of how gender matters when chatting with users on the internet.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.kapwing.com/blog/why-i-dont-use-my-real-photo/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Show HN: Bookmarklet to view full size photos from Google Images</title>
<link>https://d3vr.github.io/viewimage/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://d3vr.github.io/viewimage/</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://d3vr.github.io/viewimage/&quot;&gt;https://d3vr.github.io/viewimage/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16389609&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16389609&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Points: 203&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 50&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 03:21:22 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>d3vr</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://d3vr.github.io/viewimage/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>A man who got away with $242M using ‘black magic’</title>
<link>http://www.bbc.com/news/stories-42878021</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.bbc.com/news/stories-42878021</guid>
<description>&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape has-caption full-width lead&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                &lt;img class=&quot;js-image-replace&quot; alt=&quot;Foutanga Babani Sissoko&quot; src=&quot;https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/320/cpsprodpb/132C8/production/_100063587_dba82216-9aec-4897-8b51-c05655c1c7cd.jpg&quot; width=&quot;976&quot; height=&quot;549&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
            
            &lt;figcaption class=&quot;media-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image caption&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;media-caption__text&quot;&gt;
                    Photo: Miami Herald
                &lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;story-body__introduction&quot;&gt;One day in August 1995 a man called Foutanga Babani Sissoko walked into the head office of the Dubai Islamic Bank and asked for a loan to buy a car. The manager agreed, and Sissoko invited him home for dinner. It was the prelude, writes the BBC's Brigitte Scheffer, to one of the most audacious confidence tricks of all time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over dinner, Sissoko made a startling claim. He told the bank manager, Mohammed Ayoub, that he had magic powers. With these powers, he could take a sum of money and double it. He invited his Emirati friend to come again, and to bring some cash.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Black magic is condemned by Islam as blasphemous. Even so, there's still a widespread belief in it, and Ayoub was taken in by the colourful and mysterious businessman from a remote village in Mali.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When he arrived at Sissoko's house the next time, carrying his money, a man burst out of a room saying a spirit - a djinn - had just attacked him. He warned Ayoub not to anger the djinn, for fear his money would not be doubled. So Ayoub left his cash in the magic room, and waited.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He said he saw lights and smoke. He heard the voices of spirits. Then there was silence.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The money had indeed doubled. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ayoub was delighted - and the heist could begin.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;He believed it was Black Magic - that Mr Sissoko could double the money,&quot; says Alan Fine, a Miami attorney the bank later asked to investigate the crime.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;So he would send money to Mr Sissoko - the bank's money - and he expected it to come back in double the amount.&quot; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Between 1995 and 1998, Ayoub made 183 transfers into Sissoko's accounts around the world. Sissoko was also running up big credit card bills - in the millions according to Fine - which Ayoub would settle on his behalf. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape no-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
        &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 1998 I was living in Dubai, and I heard rumours that the bank was in trouble. When a newspaper reported that the bank was having cashflow problems, crowds of people gathered outside, waiting to withdraw their money.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Dubai authorities downplayed the crisis. They called it &quot;a little difficulty that did not lead to any financial losses either in the bank's investments or depositors' accounts&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But this wasn't true.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;The people who owned the bank took a huge, huge hit. It was not covered by insurance,&quot; says Fine. &quot;The bank was saved because the government stepped in to help. But they gave up a lot of their equity in the bank for that to happen.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And where was Foutanga Babani Sissoko? By this time, he was far away.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the beauties of his scheme was that he did not need to be in Dubai to keep receiving the money.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-with-caption&quot; readability=&quot;-24&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;player-with-placeholder&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img class=&quot;media-placeholder player-with-placeholder__image narrative-video-placeholder&quot; src=&quot;https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/images/ic/720x405/p05y9086.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Media playback is unsupported on your device&lt;/p&gt;
      
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;figcaption class=&quot;media-with-caption__caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Media caption&lt;/span&gt;How did the &quot;black magic&quot; trick work?&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;In November 1995, only weeks after putting on the magic display for Mohammed Ayoub, Sissoko visited another bank in New York, and did much more than open an account.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;He walked into Citibank one day, no appointment, met a teller and he ended up marrying her,&quot; says Alan Fine. &quot;And there's reason to believe she made his relationship with Citibank more comfortable, and he ended up opening an account there through which, from memory, I'm just going to say more than $100m was wire transferred into the United States.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In fact, according to a case brought by the Dubai Islamic Bank against Citibank, more than $151m &quot;was debited by Citibank from DIB's correspondent account without proper authorisation&quot;. The case was later dropped.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr class=&quot;story-body__line&quot;/&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;story-body__crosshead&quot;&gt;Find out more &lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can watch &lt;strong&gt;The Voodoo Bank Heist &lt;/strong&gt;on BBC World News on Sat 17 Feb 2018&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;at 09:10, 20:10 and 02:10 GMT or &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/n3ct3sdx&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link&quot;&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt; for local times &lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr class=&quot;story-body__line&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sissoko paid his new wife more than half a million dollars for her help.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;I don't know under what legal regime he married her but he called her a wife and she believed she was a wife,&quot; says Fine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;She understood that there were many other wives. Some from Africa, some from Miami, some from New York.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-portrait has-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
            &lt;figcaption class=&quot;media-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image caption&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;media-caption__text&quot;&gt;
                    Photo: Miami Herald
                &lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the bank's money rolling in, Sissoko could fulfil his dream of opening an airline for West Africa. He bought a used Hawker-Siddeley 125 and a pair of old Boeing 727s. This was the birth of Air Dabia, named after his village in Mali.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But in July 1996, Sissoko made a serious mistake as he tried to buy two Huey helicopters dating from the Vietnam War, for reasons that remain unclear. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;His explanation of why he wanted them was emergency air ambulance. But the helicopters he was looking at were pretty big helicopters, they were not the kind that you see running back and forth to hospitals and trauma centres in the United States, they were much bigger than that,&quot; says Fine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Because they could be refitted as gunships, the helicopters needed a special export licence. Sissoko's men tried to speed things up by offering a $30,000 bribe to a customs officer. Instead, they got themselves arrested. And Interpol issued a warrant for Sissoko's arrest too. He was caught in Geneva, where he'd gone to open another bank account.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tom Spencer, a Miami lawyer who was asked to represent Sissoko, vividly remembers going to meet him in Geneva's Champ-Dollon prison.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;I talked with the prison warden, who asked me whether or not Sissoko was going to go to the United States,&quot; Spencer says.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;I said, 'Well, you know, we'll see.' And he said, 'Well, please delay it as long as possible.' And I said, 'Well why?' And he said, 'Because he's flying in fantastic meals from Paris every night, for us.' And that was my first bizarre encounter with Baba Sissoko.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape has-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
            &lt;figcaption class=&quot;media-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image caption&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;media-caption__text&quot;&gt;
                    The Miami court where Sissoko stood trial (now closed)
                &lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sissoko was quickly extradited to the US, where he started to mobilise influential supporters.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The readiness of diplomats to vouch for Sissoko shocked the judge presiding over his bail hearing. And Tom Spencer was stunned when a former US senator, Birch Bayh, announced he was joining Sissoko's defence team.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Well, you have to ask yourself, why would anyone get involved for a foreign national who has no apparent value to the United States?&quot; says Fine. &quot;I don't know the answer to the question. But it's an interesting one to pose.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The US government wanted Sissoko held in custody, but he was bailed for $20m (£14.5m) - a Florida record at the time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then he went on a spending spree.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;aside class=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;quote-inner&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;icon-quote&quot;/&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;He would come in and buy two three four cars at the same time... the money was like wind&lt;footer&gt;Ronil Dufrene, Car dealer&lt;/footer&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;His defence team was rewarded with Mercedes or Jaguar cars. But that was just the start. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sissoko spent half a million dollars in one jewellery store alone, Fine recalls, and hundreds of thousands in others. In one men's clothing store he spent more than $150,000.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;He would come in and buy two three four cars at the same time, come back another week and buy two three four cars at the same time. It was just, the money was like wind,&quot; says car dealer Ronil Dufrene.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He calculates that he sold Sissoko between 30 and 35 cars in total.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sissoko became a Miami celebrity. He already had several wives, but that didn't stop him marrying more - and housing them in some of the 23 apartments he rented in the city.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;'Playboy' is the right word to describe him. Because he is very elegant. And handsome. And he dresses with great style. He blew a lot of money in Miami,&quot; says Sissoko's cousin, Makan Mousa.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sissoko was also giving away large sums to good causes. His trial was approaching, and he knew the value of good publicity. In one case witnessed by his cousin, he gave £300,000 ($413,000) to a high-school band that needed money to travel to New York for a Thanksgiving Day parade. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape has-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
                 &lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image copyright&lt;/span&gt;
                 &lt;span class=&quot;story-image-copyright&quot;&gt;BBC Sport&lt;/span&gt;
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
            &lt;figcaption class=&quot;media-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image caption&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;media-caption__text&quot;&gt;
                    Sissoko donated a large sum of money to a high school band in Miami (Photo: Miami Herald)
                &lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another of his defence lawyers, Prof H T Smith, remembers that on Thursdays he would drive around giving money to homeless people.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;I was thinking, is this some modern day Robin Hood? Why would you steal money and give it away? It doesn't make any sense,&quot; he says.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;The [Miami] Herald did a story just after he left, and I think - I don't want to exaggerate but I think they said they could chronicle like $14m he gave away. He was only here 10 months. That's over a million dollars a month.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Alan Fine took a slightly more cynical view.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;So much of what he did was for image and to perpetuate a belief that he was a very powerful man and fabulously wealthy. He would give away money, but… to my knowledge it was never done in a way that he didn't get publicity for it.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Despite this PR drive, when Sissoko's case came to court he disregarded his lawyers' advice and pleaded guilty.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Maybe he calculated that this would provoke fewer questions about his finances.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The sentence was 43 days in prison and a $250,000 fine - paid, of course, by the Dubai Islamic Bank, though without its knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After serving only half this sentence, he was given early release in return for a $1m payment to a homeless shelter. The rest he was meant to serve under house arrest in Mali.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Instead he returned home to a hero's welcome.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape has-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
            &lt;figcaption class=&quot;media-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image caption&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;media-caption__text&quot;&gt;
                    Photo: Miami Herald
                &lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was around this time that the Dubai Islamic Bank's auditors began to notice that something was wrong. Ayoub was getting nervous, and Sissoko had stopped answering his calls.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally he confessed to a colleague, who asked how much was missing. Too ashamed to say, Ayoub wrote it on a scrap of paper - 890 million dirhams, the equivalent of $242m (£175m).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He was found guilty of fraud and given three years in jail. It's rumoured he was also forced to undergo an exorcism, to cure him of his belief in black magic.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sissoko has never faced justice. In his absence, a Dubai court sentenced him to three years for fraud and practising magic. Interpol issued an arrest warrant and he remains a wanted man.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I found transcripts from other trials at which Sissoko failed to appear, including one in Paris. His lawyer claimed he was a scapegoat for Ayoub's actions and the bank's money had gone elsewhere, but the court didn't swallow it and convicted him of money-laundering.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape has-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
            &lt;figcaption class=&quot;media-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image caption&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;media-caption__text&quot;&gt;
                    Sissoko was a member of Parliament for 12 years
                &lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;For 12 years, between 2002 and 2014, Sissoko was a member of parliament in Mali, which gave him immunity from prosecution. For the last four years, no longer an MP, he has been protected by the fact that Mali has no extradition treaty with any other country.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Dubai Islamic Bank, nonetheless, is still pursuing him through the courts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape no-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
        &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;I flew to Mali's capital, Bamako, to find people who might tell me about Sissoko.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I tracked down his seamstress, who remembered him fondly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;The last time I saw him, two or three years ago, I made him a suitcase of clothes. If he didn't give out presents, he wasn't happy. It's his style. He loves to give things to people,&quot; she said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I also found his driver, Lukali Ibrahim.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;The good thing about him is that when things are going well you can expect a lot of presents from him. He likes to help people with their problems,&quot; he said. &quot;The bad thing, I can tell you a few. This is someone who always gives people hope but instead of telling you the truth, he's just leading you on.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the market I found a goldsmith who had only praise for a client who would call and ask him to make presents for his friends.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I also heard that he could be found living near his native village, Dabia, which had given its name to Sissoko's short-lived airline, near Mali's border with Guinea and Senegal.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After a long drive I found a house that fitted the description I'd been given.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape has-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
            &lt;figcaption class=&quot;media-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image caption&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;media-caption__text&quot;&gt;
                    Sissoko's home in Mali
                &lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;Suddenly, surrounded by armed guards, there he was. Babani Sissoko, in person, now perhaps 70 years old.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He agreed to an interview. The atmosphere was edgy and slightly surreal. He began by telling me about his entry into the world.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;My name is Sissoko Foutanga Dit Babani. You know, the day I was born all the villages round here burned down. The villagers went round shouting, 'Marietto has had a boy.' The fire leapt and leapt. There used to be a lot of bush around.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He then talked about his efforts to rebuild the village, which began in 1985, and about the money he made. At one point he had been worth $400m, he said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape has-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
            &lt;figcaption class=&quot;media-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image caption&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;media-caption__text&quot;&gt;
                    Sissoko says he was once worth $400m - but that he is poor now
                &lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;Eventually, I asked about the $242m he had received from the Dubai Islamic Bank.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Madame, this $242m, this is a slightly crazy story. The gentlemen from the bank should explain how they lost all that money. I mean the $242m. Listen, how could that money have left the bank the way it did? That's the problem. It's not this man alone [Ayoub] who authorises the transfers. When the bank transfers money it's not just one person who does it. Several people have to do it.&quot; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I pointed out to him that Mohammed Ayoub had claimed at his trial that Sissoko had put him under a spell.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;The gentleman you're talking about, I've seen him and met him,&quot; he said. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But the heist, he denied.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;The only contact I had with him was when I went to buy a car. The bank bought it for me and I repaid the loan. It was a Japanese car.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Had he controlled people by means of black magic?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Madame, if a person had that kind of power, why would he work? If you have that kind of power you can stay where you are and rob all the banks of the world. In the United States, France, Germany, everywhere. Even here in Africa. You could rob all the banks you want.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I asked him if he was still rich.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;His answer was blunt.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;No I'm not rich any longer. I'm poor.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Defying Interpol, Sissoko has spent a remarkable 20 years on the run, even if he has squandered all his money and can never leave Mali.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He has never spent a day in jail for the black magic bank heist.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;story-body__crosshead&quot;&gt;You may also like:&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul class=&quot;story-body__unordered-list&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/magazine-32481834&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link&quot;&gt;The bombshell bandit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/magazine-39849458&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link&quot;&gt;How I took my family on the run for 19 years&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Join the conversation - find us on &lt;/i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/BBCStories/&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link-external&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;i&gt;, &lt;/i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/bbcstories/&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link-external&quot;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;&lt;i&gt;, &lt;/i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCcgKRB26m6M3okTSP7C_UwA&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link-external&quot;&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;i&gt; and &lt;/i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/bbcstories&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link-external&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;i&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape no-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
        &lt;/figure&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 02:35:35 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>goodcanadian</dc:creator>
<og:title>The playboy who got away with $242m</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>How Foutanga Babani Sissoko pulled off one of the most audacious confidence tricks of all time.</og:description>
<og:url>http://www.bbc.com/news/stories-42878021</og:url>
<og:image>https://ichef-1.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/132C8/production/_100063587_dba82216-9aec-4897-8b51-c05655c1c7cd.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.bbc.com/news/stories-42878021</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>