<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Spyder – a free and open source scientific environment written in Python</title>
<link>https://www.spyder-ide.org/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.spyder-ide.org/</guid>
<description>&lt;div readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Download&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ready to give Spyder a try? Let's get started!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;section-download-main&quot; data-section=&quot;download-main&quot; readability=&quot;61.165111940299&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;center&quot; readability=&quot;25.753731343284&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Want to join the community of scientists, engineers and analysts all around the world using Spyder? Click the button below to download the suggested installer for your platform; we offer standalone installers on Windows and macOS. For Linux, we recommend the cross-platform Anaconda distribution, which includes Spyder and many other useful packages for scientific Python. You can also try out Spyder right in your web browser by &lt;a href=&quot;https://mybinder.org/v2/gh/spyder-ide/binder-environments/spyder-stable?urlpath=git-pull%3Frepo%3Dhttps%253A%252F%252Fgithub.com%252Fjuanis2112%252FSpyder-Workshop%26urlpath%3Ddesktop%252F%26branch%3DSolutions&quot;&gt;launching it on Binder&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a detailed guide on the many different methods of obtaining Spyder, please refer to our full &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.spyder-ide.org/current/installation.html&quot;&gt;installation instructions&lt;/a&gt;, and check out our &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/spyder-ide/spyder/releases/latest&quot;&gt;release page&lt;/a&gt; for links to all our installers. These approaches are generally intended for experienced users and those with specific needs, so we recommend sticking with the recommended installer unless you have a specific reason to go with another. Happy Spydering!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;macOS Big Sur users&lt;/strong&gt;: Full support for macOS 11 Big Sur will be included in Spyder 4.2.1, scheduled for release on December 18, 2020. However, see &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.spyder-ide.org/current/faq.html#troubleshooting-macos-bigsur&quot;&gt;our FAQ question on Big Sur&lt;/a&gt; for how to get it working right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 19:30:41 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jka</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.spyder-ide.org/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Fecal transplant turns cancer immunotherapy non-responders into responders</title>
<link>https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2021-02/uop-ftt012921.php</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2021-02/uop-ftt012921.php</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;VIDEO: &lt;/strong&gt;Fecal transplant changes the gut microbiome, turning cancer immunotherapy non-responders into responders. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eurekalert.org/multimedia/pub/254962.php&quot;&gt;view &lt;span class=&quot;no-break-text&quot;&gt;more &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;209.6214050651&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PITTSBURGH, Feb. 4, 2021 - Researchers at UPMC Hillman Cancer Center and the National Cancer Institute (NCI) demonstrate that changing the gut microbiome can transform patients with advanced melanoma who never responded to immunotherapy--which has a failure rate of 40% for this type of cancer--into patients who do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The results of this proof-of-principle phase II clinical trial were published online today in Science. In this study, a team of researchers from UPMC Hillman administered fecal microbiota transplants (FMT) and anti-PD-1 immunotherapy to melanoma patients who had failed all available therapies, including anti-PD-1, and then tracked clinical and immunological outcomes. Collaborators at NCI analyzed microbiome samples from these patients to understand why FMT seems to boost their response to immunotherapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;FMT is just a means to an end,&quot; said study co-lead author Diwakar Davar, M.D., a medical oncologist and member of the Cancer Immunology and Immunotherapy Program (CIIP) at UPMC Hillman and assistant professor of medicine at the University of Pittsburgh School of Medicine. &quot;We know the composition of the intestinal microbiome--gut bacteria--can change the likelihood of responding to immunotherapy. But what are 'good' bacteria? There are about 100 trillion gut bacteria, and 200 times more bacterial genes in an individual's microbiome than in all of their cells put together.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fecal transplant offers a way to capture a wide array of candidate microbes, testing trillions at once, to see whether having the &quot;good&quot; bacteria on board could make more people sensitive to PD-1 inhibitors. This study is among the first to test that idea in humans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Davar and colleagues collected fecal samples from patients who responded extraordinarily well to anti-PD-1 immunotherapy and tested for infectious pathogens before giving the samples, through colonoscopy, to advanced melanoma patients who had never previously responded to immunotherapy. The patients were then given the anti-PD-1 drug pembrolizumab. And it worked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Out of 15 advanced melanoma patients who received the combined FMT and anti-PD-1 treatment, six showed either tumor reduction or disease stabilization lasting more than a year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;The likelihood that the patients treated in this trial would spontaneously respond to a second administration of anti-PD-1 immunotherapy is very low,&quot; said study co-senior author Hassane Zarour, M.D., a cancer immunologist and co-leader of the CIIP at UPMC Hillman as well as a professor of medicine at Pitt. &quot;So, any positive response should be attributable to the administration of fecal transplant.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Analysis of samples taken from FMT recipients in this study revealed immunologic changes in the blood and at tumor sites suggesting increased immune cell activation in responders as well as increased immunosuppression in non-responders. Artificial intelligence linked these changes to the gut microbiome, likely caused by FMT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Davar and Zarour hope to run a larger trial with melanoma patients, as well as evaluating whether FMT may be effective in treating other cancers. Ultimately, their goal is to replace FMT with pills containing a cocktail of the most beneficial microbes for boosting immunotherapy--but that's still several years away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Even if much work remains to be done, our study raises hope for microbiome-based therapies of cancers,&quot; said Zarour, who holds the James W. and Frances G. McGlothlin Chair in Melanoma Immunotherapy Research at UPMC Hillman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;###&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additional authors on the study include Amiran Dzutsev, M.D., John McCulloch, Ph.D., Richard Rodriguez, M.B.A., Jonathan Badger, Ph.D., Marie Vetizou, Ph.D., Alicia Cole, Miriam Fernandes, Ph.D., Stephanie Prescott, M.S.N., C.R.N.P., Rachel Costa, M.S., Ascharya Balaji and Giorgio Trinchieri, M.D., of the National Cancer Institute; Joe-Marc Chauvin, Ph.D., Robert Morrison, M.D., Richelle Deblasio, Carmine Menna, Quanquan Ding, Ph.D., Ornella Pagliano, Bochra Zidi, Ph.D., Shuowen Zhang, Hong Wang, Ph.D., Scarlett Ernst, Amy Rose, Yana Najjar, M.D., and John Kirkwood, M.D., of UPMC Hillman Cancer Center; Andrey Morgun, M.D., Ph.D., of Oregon State University; Ivan Vujkovic-Cvijin, Ph.D., and Yasmine Belkaid, Ph.D., of the National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases; and Amir Borhani, M.D., Marc Schwartz, M.D., and Howard Dubner, M.D., of Pitt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Funding for this study was provided by Merck and the NCI (R01 CA222203 and P30 CA047904).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To read this release online or share it, visit &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.upmc.com/media/news/020421-Davar-Zarour-Science&quot;&gt;http://www.&lt;wbr/&gt;upmc.&lt;wbr/&gt;com/&lt;wbr/&gt;media/&lt;wbr/&gt;news/&lt;wbr/&gt;020421-Davar-Zarour-Science&lt;/a&gt; [when embargo lifts].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About UPMC Hillman Cancer Center&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UPMC Hillman Cancer Center is the region's only National Cancer Institute-designated Comprehensive Cancer Center and is one of the largest integrated community cancer networks in the United States. Backed by the collective strength of UPMC--which is ranked No. 15 for cancer care nationally by U.S. News &amp;amp; World Report - and the University of Pittsburgh School of Medicine, UPMC Hillman Cancer Center has nearly 80 locations throughout Pennsylvania, Ohio, New York, and Maryland, with cancer centers and partnerships internationally. The more than 2,000 physicians, researchers, and staff are leaders in molecular and cellular cancer biology, cancer immunology, cancer virology, biobehavioral cancer control, and cancer epidemiology, prevention, and therapeutics. UPMC Hillman Cancer Center is transforming cancer research, care, and prevention -- one patient at a time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About the University of Pittsburgh School of Medicine&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As one of the nation's leading academic centers for biomedical research, the University of Pittsburgh School of Medicine integrates advanced technology with basic science across a broad range of disciplines in a continuous quest to harness the power of new knowledge and improve the human condition. Driven mainly by the School of Medicine and its affiliates, Pitt has ranked among the top 10 recipients of funding from the National Institutes of Health since 1998. In rankings recently released by the National Science Foundation, Pitt ranked fifth among all American universities in total federal science and engineering research and development support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Likewise, the School of Medicine is equally committed to advancing the quality and strength of its medical and graduate education programs, for which it is recognized as an innovative leader, and to training highly skilled, compassionate clinicians and creative scientists well-equipped to engage in world-class research. The School of Medicine is the academic partner of UPMC, which has collaborated with the University to raise the standard of medical excellence in Pittsburgh and to position health care as a driving force behind the region's economy. For more information about the School of Medicine, see &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.medschool.pitt.edu&quot;&gt;http://www.&lt;wbr/&gt;medschool.&lt;wbr/&gt;pitt.&lt;wbr/&gt;edu&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.upmc.com/media&quot;&gt;http://www.&lt;wbr/&gt;upmc.&lt;wbr/&gt;com/&lt;wbr/&gt;media&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contact: Erin Hare&lt;br/&gt;Mobile: 412-738-1097&lt;br/&gt;E-mail: &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:HareE@upmc.edu&quot;&gt;HareE@upmc.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contact: Cyndy Patton&lt;br/&gt;Mobile: 412-415-6085&lt;br/&gt;E-mail: &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:PattonC4@upmc.edu&quot;&gt;PattonC4@upmc.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 15:53:46 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>CharlesW</dc:creator>
<og:title>Fecal transplant turns cancer immunotherapy non-responders into responders</og:title>
<og:description>A phase II clinical trial shows that changing the gut microbiome through fecal transplant can transform cancer patients who never responded to immunotherapy into patients who do.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2021-02/uop-ftt012921.php</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.eurekalert.org/multimedia/pub/web/254964_web.jpg</og:image>
<og:type>video.other</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2021-02/uop-ftt012921.php</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Veloren – Open-source MMORPG written in Rust</title>
<link>https://veloren.net/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://veloren.net/</guid>
<description>&lt;div id=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;thumbnail&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://veloren.net/devblog-105/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.discordapp.net/attachments/634860358623821835/805527343970910228/screenshot_1612041532893.png?width=192&amp;amp;height=108&quot; width=&quot;192&quot; height=&quot;108&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;overview&quot; readability=&quot;13&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;title&quot;/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week we hear about the progress of an attack rework by @Sam. @Christof describes the progress on travelling merchants. @Dumbeldor describes recent changes to Torvus. - AngelOnFira, TWiV Editor Contributor Work Thanks to this week's contributors, @Sam…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;3 minute read&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;01 February 2021&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;thumbnail&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://veloren.net/devblog-104/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.discordapp.net/attachments/634860358623821835/803763464832286780/screenshot_1611702209375.png?width=192&amp;amp;height=108&quot; width=&quot;192&quot; height=&quot;108&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;overview&quot; readability=&quot;13&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;title&quot;/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This edition of TWiV marks two years of weekly blog posts! Although not as large as the 100th post, this one is still special to me. I remember two years ago, I had a semester off school and I wanted to start working on a side project. I had found Veloren…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;3 minute read&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;25 January 2021&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;thumbnail&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://veloren.net/devblog-103/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.discordapp.net/attachments/541307708146581519/801973331750158347/103.jpg?width=192&amp;amp;height=108&quot; width=&quot;192&quot; height=&quot;108&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;overview&quot; readability=&quot;13&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;title&quot;/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week, we see lots of new art coming into Veloren. Skill trees have been merged. @Christof continues his weekly writeups on economic simulation. @Yakei talks about new improvements to CI. - AngelOnFira, TWiV Editor Contributor Work Thanks to this week…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;6 minute read&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;18 January 2021&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 15:38:22 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>agluszak</dc:creator>
<og:title>Veloren</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://veloren.net/</og:url>
<og:image>https://veloren.net/Logo_Square.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://veloren.net/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Elements of Computing Systems, Second Edition</title>
<link>https://mitpress.mit.edu/books/elements-computing-systems-second-edition</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://mitpress.mit.edu/books/elements-computing-systems-second-edition</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A new and extensively revised edition of a popular textbook used in universities, coding boot camps, hacker clubs, and online courses.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best way to understand how computers work is to build one from scratch, and this textbook leads learners through twelve chapters and projects that gradually build the hardware platform and software hierarchy for a simple but powerful computer system. In the process, learners gain hands-on knowledge of hardware, architecture, operating systems, programming languages, compilers, data structures and algorithms, and software engineering. Using this constructive approach, the book introduces learners to a significant body of computer science knowledge and demonstrates how theoretical and applied techniques taught in other computer science courses fit into the overall picture. The outcome of these efforts is known as &lt;em&gt;Nand to Tetris&lt;/em&gt;: a journey that starts with the most elementary logic gate, called &lt;em&gt;Nand&lt;/em&gt;, and ends, twelve projects later, with a general-purpose computer system capable of running &lt;em&gt;Tetris&lt;/em&gt;. The first edition of this popular textbook inspired Nand to Tetris classes in universities, coding boot camps, hacker clubs, and online course platforms. This second edition has been extensively revised. It has been restructured into two distinct parts—part I, Hardware, and part II, Software—with six projects in each part. All chapters and projects have been rewritten, with an emphasis on separating abstraction from implementation, and many new sections, figures, and examples have been added. Substantial new appendixes offer focused presentation on technical and theoretical topics.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 14:45:28 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>VitalyAnkh</dc:creator>
<og:type>books.book</og:type>
<og:url>https://mitpress.mit.edu/books/elements-computing-systems-second-edition</og:url>
<og:title>The Elements of Computing Systems, Second Edition</og:title>
<og:description>A new and extensively revised edition of a popular textbook used in universities, coding boot camps, hacker clubs, and online courses. The best way to understand how computers work is to build one from scratch, and this textbook leads learners through twelve chapters and projects that gradually build the hardware platform and software hierarchy for a simple but powerful computer system. In the process, learners gain hands-on knowledge of hardware, architecture, operating systems, programming languages, compilers, data structures and algorithms, and software engineering. Using this constructive approach, the book introduces learners to a significant body of computer science knowledge and demonstrates how theoretical and applied techniques taught in other computer science courses fit into the overall picture. The outcome of these efforts is known as Nand to Tetris: a journey that starts with the most elementary logic gate, called Nand, and ends, twelve projects later, with a general-purpose computer system capable of running Tetris. The first edition of this popular textbook inspired Nand to Tetris classes in universities, coding boot camps, hacker clubs, and online course platforms. This second edition has been extensively revised. It has been restructured into two distinct parts—part I, Hardware, and part II, Software—with six projects in each part. All chapters and projects have been rewritten, with an emphasis on separating abstraction from implementation, and many new sections, figures, and examples have been added. Substantial new appendixes offer focused presentation on technical and theoretical topics.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://mitpress.mit.edu/books/elements-computing-systems-second-edition</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Homebrew 3.0</title>
<link>https://brew.sh/2021/02/05/homebrew-3.0.0/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://brew.sh/2021/02/05/homebrew-3.0.0/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Today I’d like to announce Homebrew 3.0.0. The most significant changes since 2.7.0 are official Apple Silicon support and a new bottle format in formulae.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Major changes and deprecations since 2.7.0:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other changes since 2.7.0 I’d like to highlight are the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to all our hard-working maintainers, contributors, sponsors and supporters for getting us this far. Particular thanks on Homebrew 3.0.0 go to MacStadium and Apple for providing us with a lot of Apple Silicon hardware and Cassidy from Apple for helping us in many ways with this migration. Enjoy using Homebrew!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 12:57:37 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>blucell</dc:creator>
<og:title>3.0.0</og:title>
<og:description>Today I’d like to announce Homebrew 3.0.0. The most significant changes since 2.7.0 are official Apple Silicon support and a new bottle format in formulae.</og:description>
<og:url>https://brew.sh/2021/02/05/homebrew-3.0.0/</og:url>
<og:image>https://brew.sh/assets/img/homebrew-social-card.png</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://brew.sh/2021/02/05/homebrew-3.0.0/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Google, Apple cave to Pakistan pressure to take down apps by Ahmadiyya Muslims</title>
<link>https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/meghara/pakistan-forced-down-ahmadiyya-apps</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/meghara/pakistan-forced-down-ahmadiyya-apps</guid>
<description>&lt;div data-keywords=&quot;skincare&quot; data-module=&quot;subbuzz-text&quot; readability=&quot;127.0350877193&quot;&gt;
  
  




&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Over the last two years,&lt;/b&gt; the government of Pakistan has forced Google and Apple to take down apps in the country created by developers based in other nations who are part of a repressed religious minority.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The move is part of a &lt;a href=&quot;https://apnews.com/article/religion-pakistan-freedom-of-religion-3fbecffb2b0a1152f8524d6af325a3c2&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;crackdown&lt;/a&gt; led by the country’s telecommunications regulator targeting the Ahmadiyya Muslim community. Adherents, called Ahmadis, number about 4 million in Pakistan. Though Ahmadis identify as Muslim, Pakistan’s government views them as heretics, and a 1984 ordinance forbids them from “posing” as Muslims, adopting Islamic religious practices, and referring to their houses of worship as mosques. Pakistan is the only country to declare that Ahmadis are not Muslim.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ahmadis have faced persecution for decades, including &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.com/news/10190389&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;an attack in 2010 that killed 93 people&lt;/a&gt;. But the pressure on multinational tech companies from Pakistan’s telecom regulator, the Pakistan Telecommunication Authority (PTA), signals &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amnesty.org/en/latest/news/2021/02/pakistan-persecution-of-ahmadis-must-end-as-authorities-attempt-shutdown-of-us-website/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;a new willingness&lt;/a&gt; to target religious minorities beyond its borders. It is also one of the first examples of governments using anti-blasphemy rules to force international tech companies to censor content.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At issue are seven religious apps created by the Ahmadi community in the United States, published under the name “Ahmadiyya Muslim Community.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Three of the apps contain “the exact same [Arabic] text found universally in all versions of the Holy Quran,” as well as commentary from the Ahmadi perspective, according to their descriptions. They are still available on app stores in other countries. All of these have been taken down by Google in Pakistan. In addition, there are four other apps, which include an FAQ on Islam and a weekly Urdu-language news magazine, that the PTA is pressuring Google to remove, but which have not been taken down.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Asked to comment, a PTA spokesperson directed BuzzFeed News to the department's website.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Our services make search results, videos, apps, and other content broadly available, subject to local laws, taking into account human rights standards,” a Google spokesperson told BuzzFeed News. “We challenge government orders whenever appropriate, and when we’re required to remove apps and other types of content that don’t violate our policies, we try to do so in the least restrictive way possible.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Apple did not respond to requests for comment, but a notice from Apple to the app developers, dated May 17, 2019, said it was taking one of their apps down from its store in Pakistan because it “includes content that is illegal.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pakistan most recently sent takedown notices for Ahmadi content to Google and Wikipedia on Dec. 25, 2020, according to a PTA &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/PTAofficialpk/status/1342379237471186946&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;press release&lt;/a&gt;. Two days later, Google took one of the Qur’an apps down, said Harris Zafar, a spokesperson for the Ahmadiyya Muslim Community in the United States. (There’s no indication that Wikipedia took down any Ahmadi content in response to the request, but the Wikimedia Foundation did not return a request for comment.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A few weeks later, a group of Ahmadi community leaders spoke with Google executives.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“[Google] indicated that they had raised the human rights concerns to PTA but were told that they would have to stop their business in Pakistan if they did not remove the Ahmadi content,” Zafar said. “We were certainly surprised … We thought once we raised the human rights aspect, they would do what is right.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The PTA also ordered shut a US-based Ahmadi site, &lt;a href=&quot;https://trueislam.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;TrueIslam.com&lt;/a&gt;, threatening its administrators with criminal charges that carry a $3 million fine. The decision may not be enforceable, since the people who run the site, including Zafar, do not live in Pakistan. But it does mean they may face charges if they travel there, which means Zafar can't visit his extended family.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“This is a disturbing development and nothing short of an attempt to weaponize Pakistan’s blasphemy laws against US citizens,” wrote a lawyer who represents the site’s administrators in a letter to Pakistani authorities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div data-retailers=&quot;Amazon&quot; data-keywords=&quot;cleaning,fast fashion&quot; data-module=&quot;subbuzz-text&quot; readability=&quot;93.808844507846&quot;&gt;
  
  




&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Pakistan is one&lt;/b&gt; of several countries, including &lt;a href=&quot;https://jsis.washington.edu/news/chinese-data-localization-law-comprehensive-ambiguous/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;China&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.engage.hoganlovells.com/knowledgeservices/news/vietnam-quick-to-enforce-new-cybersecurity-law&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Vietnam&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://uk.practicallaw.thomsonreuters.com/Cosi/SignOn?redirectId=rt_905e5ae7-604c-4308-8ac8-169090b6f1ac&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Germany&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.huntonprivacyblog.com/2019/04/05/nigeria-issues-new-data-protection-regulation/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Nigeria&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lexology.com/library/detail.aspx?g=5b43dda3-d68f-4f5b-8767-9846b649b5d9&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Russia&lt;/a&gt;, that have data localization rules to exercise greater control over tech platforms. When tech companies store data or have offices in a country, they must comply with local laws.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The PTA &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/article/pakistan-socialmedia-censorship-idUSL8N2I53OW&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;issued new rules&lt;/a&gt; late last year that give it broader powers to block online content. Those rules allowed it to censor content online that could, in its view, harm the government or threaten the security of Pakistan.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Asia Internet Coalition, an industry group whose members include Amazon, Apple, Facebook, and Google, opposed the decision, writing in a letter to the regulator on Dec. 5 that the rules would “prevent Pakistani citizens from accessing a free and open internet.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Zafar said the PTA had been pressuring Google since 2018 and Apple since 2019. Ahmadi developers have made other versions of the Qur'an app in the years since, each of which the companies have taken down following PTA orders.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Google took the Ahmadiyya community’s first Qur’an app down in September 2018. After objections, Google reinstated the app and held a meeting between the company and the developers the following March.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to notes from the meeting, a Google executive asked if they would consider taking the word “Muslim” out of their name to avoid offending Pakistan’s government.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“No,” one of Zafar’s colleagues, an Ahmadi lawyer, replied. “This decision will have a major impact, a precedent that will empower Pakistan to continue with this, due to validation from one of the world’s major corporations.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The meeting ended without a resolution, Zafar said, and in October 2019, Google took the app down again. Apple removed the same app from its store in May.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Zafar said he was disappointed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“All Google has done is capitulate to PTA and censor our community,” Zafar said. “This exacerbates the human rights abuses against us as it validates Pakistan’s basis of the persecution. If there are alternative solutions, we would like to hear them, but to date Google has offered no alternatives.” ●&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 12:11:08 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>shalmanese</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/meghara/pakistan-forced-down-ahmadiyya-apps</og:url>
<og:image>https://img.buzzfeed.com/buzzfeed-static/static/2021-02/4/21/enhanced/cc78f6165d8e/longform-original-88-1612474654-11.jpg?crop=1373:719;116,203</og:image>
<og:title>Pakistan Forced Down Apps Made By A Persecuted Religious Minority</og:title>
<og:description>The Pakistan Telecommunication Authority has used anti-blasphemy rules to target members of the Ahmadiyya community.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/meghara/pakistan-forced-down-ahmadiyya-apps</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>FOSDEM 2021</title>
<link>https://fosdem.org/2021/schedule</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://fosdem.org/2021/schedule</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;info-block&quot; readability=&quot;14.344370860927&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;more-info&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Quick links:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;26.242320819113&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every year, FOSDEM hosts a wide variety of activities. This page gives an overview with links to further information about scheduled events. &lt;strong&gt;All times CET (UTC+1).&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FOSDEM is a rather busy conference. This edition features 676 speakers, 764 events, and 114 tracks. We do our best to provide you with as much information and navigation options about the schedule as we can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Activities take place in &lt;a href=&quot;https://fosdem.org/2021/schedule/rooms/&quot;&gt;110 rooms&lt;/a&gt;. An &lt;a href=&quot;https://fosdem.org/2021/schedule/roomtracks/&quot;&gt;overview of the room occupation by track&lt;/a&gt; is available, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are essentially the following categories of sessions and activities: &lt;a href=&quot;https://fosdem.org/2021/schedule/#maintracks&quot;&gt;main tracks&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://fosdem.org/2021/schedule/#devrooms&quot;&gt;developer rooms&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://fosdem.org/2021/schedule/#lightningtalks&quot;&gt;lightning talks&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://fosdem.org/2021/schedule/#stands&quot;&gt;stands&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://fosdem.org/2021/schedule/#certification&quot;&gt;certification exams&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a complete (but crowded) overview, there is also a &lt;a href=&quot;https://fosdem.org/2021/schedule/events/&quot;&gt;page that lists all events&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br/&gt;A &lt;a href=&quot;https://fosdem.org/2021/schedule/speakers/&quot;&gt;list of all speakers&lt;/a&gt; is available, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the event, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://fosdem.org/2021/schedule/streaming/&quot;&gt;live streaming page&lt;/a&gt; is also updated every few minutes to show you what is currently scheduled in each room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Main tracks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;q&gt;main tracks&lt;/q&gt; consist of series of talks that are organised by topic, where the FOSDEM program committee selects suggestions and actively invites speakers on those topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this edition the main tracks are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Developer rooms&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The vast majority of events (talks, hacking sessions, open discussions) are held in so-called &lt;q&gt;developer rooms&lt;/q&gt; (&lt;q&gt;devrooms&lt;/q&gt;), which are organized and managed by open source projects themselves, or even associations between several such projects on a common topic in order to foster collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the list of the devrooms that are present at this edition of FOSDEM, in alphabetical order:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h3&gt;Lightning talks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lightning talk is a very popular format, used at many conferences, where speakers have a mere 15 minutes at their disposal to showcase an open source project, an idea, or a concept thereof.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While that brief lapse of time may seem awkward, it almost always leads the presenters to concentrate on the absolute essence and what is really important, which is why it is often a much appreciated approach, as is the wide variety of the topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are currently &lt;a href=&quot;https://fosdem.org/2021/schedule/track/lightning_talks/&quot;&gt;21 lightning talks in the schedule&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Stands&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stands offer a unique chance to get in touch with developers or project members, and discover at a glance what they do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the list of the stands that are present at this edition of FOSDEM, in alphabetical order:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h3&gt;Certification Exams&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several certification organizations provide FOSDEM visitors with the opportunity of taking certification exams during the conference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further details are available on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://fosdem.org/2021/certification/&quot;&gt;certification page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;label label-info&quot;&gt;Certification exams have not been scheduled yet.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The FOSDEM Fringe&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The FOSDEM Fringe consists of independent events involving free and open source software taking place in the days around the FOSDEM weekend. Why not extend your trip?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further details are available on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://fosdem.org/2021/fringe/&quot;&gt;FOSDEM Fringe page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Mobile Apps&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People have submitted a variety of &lt;a href=&quot;https://fosdem.org/2021/schedule/mobile/&quot;&gt;apps for mobile devices&lt;/a&gt; that display the FOSDEM schedule.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Raw schedule data&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The schedule data is available in:&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 10:29:32 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Dowwie</dc:creator>
<og:title>FOSDEM 2021 - Schedule</og:title>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:image>https://fosdem.org/2021/assets/style/logo-gear-7204a6874eb0128932db10ff4030910401ac06f4e907f8b4a40da24ba592b252.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://fosdem.org/2021/schedule/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Factorio Future Plans</title>
<link>https://www.factorio.com/blog/post/fff-365</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.factorio.com/blog/post/fff-365</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Hello,&lt;br /&gt;the 1.1 release is the final release of the vanilla game. It will be maintained, so bugfixes, simple modding interface additions, or minor tweaks can happen, but that's about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;h3&gt;The future&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what are we going to do? There are several possibilities. Retiring is not really an option for several reasons, not going insane being one of them. There are some smaller experiments outside the Factorio realm that we want to do, but apart from that, we still want to extend the game. There is a large pool of ideas, so all we have to do is to just pick from the most potent ones. But the question is: How to package them?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are basically 4 options:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Free updates forever&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Factorio 2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Small DLC packs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One big expansion pack&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Free updates forever&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of games do it, notably Minecraft and Terraria. They do really well, so the model works, but I believe that it is not the best way to go for us, as we are a little bit more of a niche game with a smaller but more dedicated audience. This means that the room for expansion in the sense of getting more players is limited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Factorio 2&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem with a sequel is that it is expected to be very different in many ways, and technically a different game (Starcraft 1→2). Sequels that mainly just extend the content, but reuse most of the stuff from the previous installment were common in oldschool games (Baldur's gate 1→2, Fallout 1→2, Doom 1→2), but I'm afraid that this is not the expectation today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The point is, that making a 'New Factorio' is exact opposite of what we want to do. Finally, the base game is in a state that we are happy with, things like Graphics, tutorials, engine, multiplayer etc. Specifically we spent most of the effort in the last year on finalising the GUI, and the last thing we want to do is to throw it all away for the sake of changing stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Small DLC packs&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally, as a player, I'm not big fan of a lot of small DLC packs. It gets cluttered, it gets harder to keep track of what I have, what features is in which pack, and what do I need to buy in order to play with a friend etc. Not even mentioning the developer pain of having small independent chunks of content that need to be compatible and balanced in every possible combination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;One big expansion pack&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This seems to fit the best. We could focus purely on extending what we have and make new content, which we want to do so dearly! It would be one well-defined product that would be significant enough to recapture peoples attention, and it would be compatible with our workflow. Technically, it would be &quot;just&quot; a new version of the game, so all the infrastructure of mods being updated, multiplayer etc. would just work the same as it worked until now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, Expansion pack it is!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This immediately creates two main questions: &lt;strong&gt;What&lt;/strong&gt; will it contain and &lt;strong&gt;when&lt;/strong&gt; is it coming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What?&lt;/strong&gt; It is way too early to show any of the plans, and since we want to keep the iterative process of expanding things that prove to be the most fun, the plan is quite loose anyway.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When?&lt;/strong&gt; All I can say is, that we are starting work on it now, and we don't think that it will take less than a year to develop. I'm personally very curious how the theory of getting more efficient once the engine is solid will hold.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Looking for humans&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We don't want to discriminate, so if a talented animal or AI applies, we will happily give it a job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since we are finally going to add new content and we are financially doing quite okay, it is the best time to invest into reinforcing our team. One of the steps we have already taken is hiring a concept artist, he might be known to you under the nick of &lt;a href=&quot;https://mods.factorio.com/user/Earendel&quot;&gt;Earendel&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;3D artists&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We made a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.artstation.com/jobs/l6Ra&quot;&gt;job listing&lt;/a&gt;, and we have already hired 2 out of the many applicants, please welcome Jerzy and Lucas! However this is still far from enough, so we are looking for more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The full listing is on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.artstation.com/jobs/l6Ra&quot;&gt;ArtStation page&lt;/a&gt; and also on &lt;a href=&quot;https://factorio.com/job/3D-artist&quot;&gt;our website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Operations developer&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have a lot of build servers, deployment processes, web servers, office network storage, etc. We would like someone to reinforce our DevOps team and help us maintain and develop our processes and systems. It will involve working with our CI and deploy scripts, as well as being available in emergencies to put out fires. Our physical servers often need maintenance and repair, so general computer building and repair experience is required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are interested or know someone who is, you can find the full details &lt;a href=&quot;https://factorio.com/job/operations-developer&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;C++ programmer&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We don't need programmers that much at this moment, but someone exceptionally skilled can always find a place here. Bonus points for Linux/macOS specialists, as we are lacking these now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Final numbers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;8 years of Factorio in numbers&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The initial Factorio commit was done 31.3.2012, so Factorio was in the development for 8 years 10 months. I did this kind of comparison in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.factorio.com/blog/post/fff-223&quot;&gt;FFF-223&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.factorio.com/blog/post/fff-81&quot;&gt;FFF-81&lt;/a&gt;, I hope you don't mind if I compare it with the current state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our effort in numbers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;In development for 1106 → 2099 → &lt;strong&gt;3233&lt;/strong&gt; days.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;88 → 221 → &lt;strong&gt;411&lt;/strong&gt; public releases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;14 082 → 34 686 → &lt;strong&gt;57 932&lt;/strong&gt; commits in the master branch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;204 917 → 465 550 → &lt;strong&gt;856 800&lt;/strong&gt;. lines of code, 546 339 → 1 258 939 → &lt;strong&gt;2 340 804&lt;/strong&gt; words and 7 693 483 → 17 517 675 → &lt;strong&gt;35 216 019&lt;/strong&gt; characters, this is equivalent to 15 → 35 → &lt;strong&gt;70&lt;/strong&gt; average books.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;20 791 → 56 947 → &lt;strong&gt;87 703&lt;/strong&gt; different sprites with 54 114 147 → 336 907 147 → &lt;strong&gt;945 930 442&lt;/strong&gt; non empty pixels.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1492 → 5034 → &lt;strong&gt;8688&lt;/strong&gt; resolved bugs (only counting those reported on our forums).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3027 → 7670 → &lt;strong&gt;13 265&lt;/strong&gt; lines in the changelog.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Results in:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;56 500 → 341 000 → &lt;strong&gt;799 000&lt;/strong&gt; Youtube videos&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;403 000 → 1 900 000 → &lt;strong&gt;2 670 000&lt;/strong&gt; Google hits of Factorio.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;75 146 → 303 773 → &lt;strong&gt;483 539&lt;/strong&gt; forum posts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0 → 11 704 → &lt;strong&gt;38 870&lt;/strong&gt; years of combined playtime played on Steam.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and finally 74 914 → 1 200 000+ → &lt;strong&gt;2 500 000+&lt;/strong&gt; copies sold.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;This leads me to different kind of comparisons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;2.7 → 0.42 → &lt;strong&gt;0.34&lt;/strong&gt; lines of code per one buyer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;12.7 → 16.5 → &lt;strong&gt;17.9&lt;/strong&gt; commits per day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2.7 → 6 → &lt;strong&gt;9.2&lt;/strong&gt; Youtube videos per one sprite&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0 → 2.3 → &lt;strong&gt;4.4&lt;/strong&gt; years of playtime per resolved bug report&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0 → 4 → &lt;strong&gt;8&lt;/strong&gt; months of Steam playtime per one commit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0 → 9.1 → &lt;strong&gt;37&lt;/strong&gt; days of Steam play for each line of code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0 → 18.2 → &lt;strong&gt;21.5&lt;/strong&gt; minutes for each pixel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;I could go on like this for a while :) But mainly, it makes me realize, that making changes, improving things, and fixing even small annoyances in the game is worth it. Also, it seems like we generally doubled everything in 2 years, which sounds like a good progression, lets see where we get in the next 2 years :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Final words&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are going to stop Friday Facts for a while (again), and there are more reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;We need to focus on experimenting and iterating design ideas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If we show something that ends up being removed or replaced, it can feel like a broken promise, and we learned that it is generally the worst thing we can do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We don't want to start building hype too early and drive attention away from the finished Factorio.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some of the additions require extending the engine, but some of them could be reproduced with mods to a certain extent. We have experience with people trying to use mods to emulate our future changes before they are released. This has a few problems, people playing with these emulations can have altered expectations for the expansion, and it also wouldn't feel that new anymore.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;But still, there are many interesting topics related to designing and implementing the planned features, so as the release approaches, we will be more than happy to present a peek into the process, and discuss some of the content additions. That is to say, Friday Facts will start-up again once the time is right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thank you all for being with us on this journey, and we look forward to what the future may bring. As always, let us know what you think at the usual places.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 09:53:47 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>parsecs</dc:creator>
<og:title>Friday Facts #365 - Future plans | Factorio</og:title>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:image>https://cdn.factorio.com/assets/img/blog/fff-365-thumb.png</og:image>
<og:description>Hello, the 1.1 release is the final release of the vanilla game. It will be maintained, so bugfixes, simple modding interface additions, or minor tweaks can happen, but that's about it. The future So, what are we going to do? There are several possibilities. Retiring is not really an option for several reasons, not going insane being one of them. There are some smaller experiments outside the Factorio realm that we want to do, but apart from that, we still want to extend the game. There is a large pool of ideas, so all we have to do is to just pick from the most potent ones. But the question is: How to package them? There are basically 4 options: Free updates forever Factorio 2 Small DLC packs One big expansion pack Free...</og:description>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.factorio.com/blog/post/fff-365</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The man who produced Steve Jobs’ keynotes for 20 years (2018)</title>
<link>https://www.cake.co/conversations/jNZlq6j/the-man-who-produced-steve-jobs-keynotes-for-20-years</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.cake.co/conversations/jNZlq6j/the-man-who-produced-steve-jobs-keynotes-for-20-years</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;post-body&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;cakedoc&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cakedoc-paragraph&quot;&gt;Wayne Goodrich was the producer for every keynote Steve gave after his return to Apple. Before that, Wayne helped him create presentations at NeXT and Pixar. He is writing a book about what it was like on the inside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cakedoc-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a panel conversation, which works the same on Cake as panels do in the real world: the audience may be vast, but it’s in everyone’s interest to let the panel speak. You can add energy to Wayne’s fascinating stories in this conversation with emojis like&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;inline-emoji cp-1f631&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;inline-emoji-text&quot;&gt;😱&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;em&gt;, just like clapping and laughing does in a physical-world panel. To post comments &amp;amp; questions check out&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cake.co/conversations/2Jf7ksx/questions-comments-about-the-wayne-goodrich-panel&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;this conversation&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;. &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cakedoc-paragraph&quot;&gt;Wayne, we knew each other at NeXT when you were working in hardware product marketing. At the time, I had the harrowing but amazing experience of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cake.co/conversations/rZXhqtP/that-time-i-had-steve-jobs-keynote-at-unix-expo&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;helping Steve do his Unix Expo keynote&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;cakedoc-attachments&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;cakedoc-image-link&quot; href=&quot;https://cake.imgix.net/m/QLZzngCrcmXX_1531329024912.png&quot; itemprop=&quot;sharedContent&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/ImageObject&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;cakedoc-image&quot; data-smartimage-js=&quot;true&quot; src=&quot;https://cake.imgix.net/m/QLZzngCrcmXX_1531329024912.png?fit=max&amp;amp;fm=pjpg&amp;amp;h=640&amp;amp;q=65&amp;amp;w=680&quot;/&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;cakedoc-image&quot; src=&quot;https://cake.imgix.net/m/QLZzngCrcmXX_1531329024912.png?fit=max&amp;amp;fm=pjpg&amp;amp;h=640&amp;amp;q=65&amp;amp;w=680&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;post-body&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;cakedoc&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cakedoc-paragraph&quot;&gt;I was, but when NeXT stopped making hardware they laid me off. A week later, Steve called me and started to say “okay Wayne, we need to...” I interjected “what do you mean we need to? You laid me off.” He said “oh” and then click. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cakedoc-paragraph&quot;&gt;Eight months later I heard from my brother, who was still working customer support, “Steve wants you to call. He won’t call you but you should call him.” The result of that conversation led to working directly with Steve on all his most important presentations at Pixar and Apple for nearly the next two decades. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;cakedoc-attachments&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;cakedoc-image-link&quot; href=&quot;https://cake.imgix.net/m/mg9r4Mmq9NF9_1531329508101.jpeg&quot; itemprop=&quot;sharedContent&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/ImageObject&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;cakedoc-image&quot; data-smartimage-js=&quot;true&quot; src=&quot;https://cake.imgix.net/m/mg9r4Mmq9NF9_1531329508101.jpeg?fit=max&amp;amp;fm=pjpg&amp;amp;h=640&amp;amp;q=65&amp;amp;w=680&quot;/&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;cakedoc-image&quot; src=&quot;https://cake.imgix.net/m/mg9r4Mmq9NF9_1531329508101.jpeg?fit=max&amp;amp;fm=pjpg&amp;amp;h=640&amp;amp;q=65&amp;amp;w=680&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;post-body&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;cakedoc&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cakedoc-paragraph&quot;&gt;And now you’re writing a book about it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;post-body&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;cakedoc&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cakedoc-paragraph&quot;&gt;Yes, I’m working on it because I was a a unique Insider for 20 years and I'm disappointed at the liberties that people like Aaron Sorkin have taken. I would have gladly helped tell the story the way it really happened, or at least lent some credibility to the parts that should have been historically correct.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;post-body&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;cakedoc&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cakedoc-paragraph&quot;&gt;I spoke to Andy Hertzfeld about that. He said Aaron explained that he was making a painting, not a photograph. It’s not supposed to be a documentary, so he felt he had creative license.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;cakedoc-attachments&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;cakedoc-image-link&quot; href=&quot;https://cake.imgix.net/m/LJ88BGP2DN4b_1531330037651.jpeg&quot; itemprop=&quot;sharedContent&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/ImageObject&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;cakedoc-image&quot; data-smartimage-js=&quot;true&quot; src=&quot;https://cake.imgix.net/m/LJ88BGP2DN4b_1531330037651.jpeg?fit=max&amp;amp;fm=pjpg&amp;amp;h=640&amp;amp;q=65&amp;amp;w=680&quot;/&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;cakedoc-image&quot; src=&quot;https://cake.imgix.net/m/LJ88BGP2DN4b_1531330037651.jpeg?fit=max&amp;amp;fm=pjpg&amp;amp;h=640&amp;amp;q=65&amp;amp;w=680&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;post-body&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;cakedoc&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cakedoc-paragraph&quot;&gt;I know they're making movies, but let's at least get some of the real stuff in there about who Steve was. Let's not purposely put fictitious information into the world that people are going to believe was reality. That’s just wrong in my opinion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;post-body&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;cakedoc&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cakedoc-paragraph&quot;&gt;I’ve heard people say that Steve’s iPhone launch was the greatest presentation in business history. It had heroes and villains, plot twists, humorous sidebars… Did the time you and Steve spend with Pixar influence his keynotes?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;cakedoc-attachments&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;cakedoc-image-link&quot; href=&quot;https://cake.imgix.net/m/SdQxm9XxprMv_1531330726448.png&quot; itemprop=&quot;sharedContent&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/ImageObject&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;cakedoc-image&quot; data-smartimage-js=&quot;true&quot; src=&quot;https://cake.imgix.net/m/SdQxm9XxprMv_1531330726448.png?fit=max&amp;amp;fm=pjpg&amp;amp;h=640&amp;amp;q=65&amp;amp;w=680&quot;/&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;cakedoc-image&quot; src=&quot;https://cake.imgix.net/m/SdQxm9XxprMv_1531330726448.png?fit=max&amp;amp;fm=pjpg&amp;amp;h=640&amp;amp;q=65&amp;amp;w=680&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;post-body&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;cakedoc&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cakedoc-paragraph&quot;&gt;Oh, absolutely! If you look at the primitive narratives in Steve’s presentations at NeXT, you can see the influence that our experience at Pixar had on the storytelling over time that resulted in events like the iPhone launch.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cakedoc-paragraph&quot;&gt;What few people realize is that, like Pixar movies, there is a color scheme throughout the 90 minutes, and an emotional ramp. And yes there are heroes and villains, action sequences, humor and plot twists. You have to be careful not to wear the audience out. You have to manage building to a climax. Steve understood this better than anyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;post-body&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;cakedoc&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cakedoc-paragraph&quot;&gt;How much time went into preparing the iPhone demo?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;post-body&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;cakedoc&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cakedoc-paragraph&quot;&gt;Quite a lot! That’s the thing, no other CEO would have imagined spending the time Steve invested in his keynotes. For the most important ones, we started 3 or so months out. He would run the company until maybe 2:00 pm and then spend a few hours with me. Then he may start in again in the evening, me at my house and him at his, and we’d stay up until midnight. Sometimes we’d be at it again at 6 am. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cakedoc-paragraph&quot;&gt;I saw part of my job—and Steve never knew this—as managing his emotional ramp to the event. I’ve even described my job much like being a product manager. There were all kinds of things that could mess that up: the product timing, or the photos that were taken weren’t good enough, or he had a bad day, or we didn’t have all the assets he needed… or at times too many! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cakedoc-paragraph&quot;&gt;With movies, you never want anything to affect suspension of belief. You want your audience to stay in that magical moment and not think about how things are done.  With the iPhone, we wanted to show that if you rotate your phone to landscape mode, the photo would automatically rotate too. But we were not projecting a video of the actual iPhone that Steve was holding in his hand, only the video from the iPhone. That would have made it shaky on the big screen with distracting reflections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cakedoc-paragraph&quot;&gt;So we showed a graphic of an iPhone, to look like the Keynote slides, and projected Steve’s demo iPhone screen into the exact right position in the graphic. The trick was that when Steve rotated the iPhone to landscape mode, the right thing to do to keep customers in the moment was to rotate the iPhone graphic with its inserted video feed rotating in sync as well. But how?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;cakedoc-attachments&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;cakedoc-image-link&quot; href=&quot;https://cake.imgix.net/m/FYLjTlvKhnRr_1531331370341.png&quot; itemprop=&quot;sharedContent&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/ImageObject&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;cakedoc-image&quot; data-smartimage-js=&quot;true&quot; src=&quot;https://cake.imgix.net/m/FYLjTlvKhnRr_1531331370341.png?fit=max&amp;amp;fm=pjpg&amp;amp;h=640&amp;amp;q=65&amp;amp;w=680&quot;/&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;cakedoc-image&quot; src=&quot;https://cake.imgix.net/m/FYLjTlvKhnRr_1531331370341.png?fit=max&amp;amp;fm=pjpg&amp;amp;h=640&amp;amp;q=65&amp;amp;w=680&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;post-body&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;cakedoc&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cakedoc-paragraph&quot;&gt;It took a month for one of the brilliant Apple engineers to work out how to do this. It looked natural to the audience and no one had to think about how it happened. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cakedoc-paragraph&quot;&gt;When Steve saw this happen he first time, he knew it’d be magic and it had to be shown live. He rotated it back and forth several times in his demo and no one ever questioned what they were seeing because it looked exactly they way it should.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cakedoc-paragraph&quot;&gt;If I remember, the internal estimate of the marketing power of the iPhone demo Steve did that day was in excess of $1 billion of PR spend from demo until we shipped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;cakedoc-attachments&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;cakedoc-image-link&quot; href=&quot;https://cake.imgix.net/m/DYlF8vV1XR09_1531331556178.png&quot; itemprop=&quot;sharedContent&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/ImageObject&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;cakedoc-image&quot; data-smartimage-js=&quot;true&quot; src=&quot;https://cake.imgix.net/m/DYlF8vV1XR09_1531331556178.png?fit=max&amp;amp;fm=pjpg&amp;amp;h=640&amp;amp;q=65&amp;amp;w=680&quot;/&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;cakedoc-image&quot; src=&quot;https://cake.imgix.net/m/DYlF8vV1XR09_1531331556178.png?fit=max&amp;amp;fm=pjpg&amp;amp;h=640&amp;amp;q=65&amp;amp;w=680&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;post-body&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;cakedoc&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cakedoc-paragraph&quot;&gt;Amazing! Did he take feedback from other people at Apple as the presentation was being constructed?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;post-body&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;cakedoc&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cakedoc-paragraph&quot;&gt;He did. We learned from the creative process Pixar uses: iteration in front of people who can shape it by adding constructive feedback. We held high level slide and demo reviews in the town hall facility with people from each group that would be affected by the presentation. These would happen usually a week or two before the event and rehearsals onsite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;post-body&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;cakedoc&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cakedoc-paragraph&quot;&gt;Steve was incredibly demanding when I was at NeXT and a lot of people didn’t last. How did you make it 20 years?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;post-body&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;cakedoc&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cakedoc-paragraph&quot;&gt;I know that I quit 3 times, one kind of officially via email to HR. God only knows how many times I was actually yelled at and fired but it never went anywhere. Essentially I never really wanted to leave so I didn’t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;post-body&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;cakedoc&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cakedoc-paragraph&quot;&gt;That’s insane. I read an interview of Andy Cunningham who said, “I loved working for Steve Jobs even though he fired me 5 times.” What do you mean it never went anywhere?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;post-body&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;cakedoc&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cakedoc-paragraph&quot;&gt;One afternoon he told me, “God dammit, Wayne. I want you to fucking go home right now and tell me why I shouldn’t fire you tomorrow.” So I went home that night and I probably worked on 15 or 16 versions of an email trying to explain everything. But then I just decided to say “Steve, you know how I feel, but you’re the boss. You let me know tomorrow whether I’m fired or not.” I never heard another word about it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The mythology of him mostly comes from individuals that didn't survive around him. The people who got close knew the rules, knew how to work with him, knew his core desires and what he was trying to achieve. They never really had problems with it.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cakedoc-paragraph&quot;&gt;Someone told me early on that if you do something great, you just have to acknowledge it yourself because you’re not going to get it from him except on a rare occasion. A lot of people who weren’t used to that would come in to present their product plan or whatever, and they would be seeking to make themselves look good and get praise from Steve. If he got a whiff of that, he would rip you down a peg. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He was usually right because the person usually didn’t do a great job. Those are the ones who flamed out and then had the horrible things to say because they couldn’t admit to themselves that they couldn’t cut the mustard.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He was a complex individual but he always desired the best out of everybody. He was ultimately very caring. He had his own relationship with my daughter from the age of 4 years old and let her come to rehearsals and events. He even asked her opinion a few times when the team couldn’t decide between particular graphics to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;cakedoc-attachments&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;cakedoc-image-link&quot; href=&quot;https://cake.imgix.net/m/j4D3PCrR4Pyl_1531332483022.jpeg&quot; itemprop=&quot;sharedContent&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/ImageObject&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;cakedoc-image&quot; data-smartimage-js=&quot;true&quot; src=&quot;https://cake.imgix.net/m/j4D3PCrR4Pyl_1531332483022.jpeg?fit=max&amp;amp;fm=pjpg&amp;amp;h=640&amp;amp;q=65&amp;amp;w=680&quot;/&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;cakedoc-image&quot; src=&quot;https://cake.imgix.net/m/j4D3PCrR4Pyl_1531332483022.jpeg?fit=max&amp;amp;fm=pjpg&amp;amp;h=640&amp;amp;q=65&amp;amp;w=680&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;post-body&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;cakedoc&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cakedoc-paragraph&quot;&gt;Give us an example of when he went off on you because he expected better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;post-body&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;cakedoc&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cakedoc-paragraph&quot;&gt;When we launched the Lifesaver iMacs (the color ones), Steph Adams [Owner of Adams &amp;amp; Asscociates—the outside production company for Apple] and I were trying to bring them out from behind the screen and raise them up out of their pedestals. A week before the event and we were still struggling to synchronize them and make the motion smooth. This was before computer-controlled movement machinery was readily available.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After mentioning this to Steve, he literally says, “I know the guys from Cirque du Soleil, why don’t you call them?” With one week left, we couldn’t do that so we stuck with our way. It was a hand-crank thing. When you looked at it close, it was really bad. But when you were in the audience, you couldn’t tell unless you knew what to look for. However, Steve was on the stage watching these things not perfectly aligned with a little bit of stuttering. He wasn’t happy and we could see it in the video feed we were watching.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The show went off, no one ever noticed or mentioned it in the press, but yet he noticed. He pulled me and Steph aside. There were people all around so he didn’t scream or yell at us. It was one of those “I’m really disappointed. At any other time I’d probably fire you.” For ten minutes he went on and on. We looked at each other and just melted into the floor.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But we came back the next show having done our research. We now had the beginnings of our computer-controlled systems. We could bring things from the back of the stage, under the stage, or out of a cabinet—and twirl them as they emerged. Cirque du Soleil couldn’t do it better than we did it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As I look back, if we had not been berated so much, we wouldn’t have seen that these were amazing products and they could have been launched so much better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;cakedoc-attachments&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;cakedoc-image-link&quot; href=&quot;https://cake.imgix.net/m/wl9s4Lpk9wHX_1531333042972.jpeg&quot; itemprop=&quot;sharedContent&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/ImageObject&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;cakedoc-image&quot; data-smartimage-js=&quot;true&quot; src=&quot;https://cake.imgix.net/m/wl9s4Lpk9wHX_1531333042972.jpeg?fit=max&amp;amp;fm=pjpg&amp;amp;h=640&amp;amp;q=65&amp;amp;w=680&quot;/&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;cakedoc-image&quot; src=&quot;https://cake.imgix.net/m/wl9s4Lpk9wHX_1531333042972.jpeg?fit=max&amp;amp;fm=pjpg&amp;amp;h=640&amp;amp;q=65&amp;amp;w=680&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;post-body&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;cakedoc&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cakedoc-paragraph&quot;&gt;When I did his keynotes at NeXT, I don’t remember him ever being scripted. Did that change?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;post-body&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;cakedoc&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cakedoc-paragraph&quot;&gt;That’s the thing most executives don’t get. We never wrote a script. The preview monitor was just the next slide coming up. The Keynote development, the slide sequencing, the simplifying and honing were all part of his method for being as empathetic, emotive, charismatic and precise as he was on stage. It came from time spent working on the story with his slides, then rehearsing and rehearsing and rehearsing. Not from a script.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was just part of him. There is a dichotomy in the world about the mythology surrounding him. A big part of his legacy comes from what people saw of him on stage. He was at his absolute best then. He was putting 110% of himself into it because he didn’t want to let the rest of the company down. He was introducing his creations to the world, they were like his children. Steve had an immediate trust factor with the audience because he was so bare and open at those moments in time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After each show he would come to the back of the stage and ask Steph and I to grade him. And we would say it was a B, or B- or solid A. He really wanted to know how he did so if not great, he/we could do better next time. If you watch different keynotes, you can see that he had different emotional ramps depending on whether it was a product he was totally into or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;post-body&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;cakedoc&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cakedoc-paragraph&quot;&gt;Has the world ever seen anyone like him?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;cakedoc-attachments&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;cakedoc-image-link&quot; href=&quot;https://cake.imgix.net/m/gFPJXjSc51Ts_1531333686530.jpeg&quot; itemprop=&quot;sharedContent&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/ImageObject&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;cakedoc-image&quot; data-smartimage-js=&quot;true&quot; src=&quot;https://cake.imgix.net/m/gFPJXjSc51Ts_1531333686530.jpeg?fit=max&amp;amp;fm=pjpg&amp;amp;h=640&amp;amp;q=65&amp;amp;w=680&quot;/&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;cakedoc-image&quot; src=&quot;https://cake.imgix.net/m/gFPJXjSc51Ts_1531333686530.jpeg?fit=max&amp;amp;fm=pjpg&amp;amp;h=640&amp;amp;q=65&amp;amp;w=680&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;post-body&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;cakedoc&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cakedoc-paragraph&quot;&gt;I don’t think so in business. I would get calls asking “Can you help us do a keynote like Steve?” (which we affectionately called Stevenotes). But they always had the expectation that I would write a script and build the slides in their entirety. They had no understanding of what it really took to master this medium. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;post-body&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;cakedoc&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cakedoc-paragraph&quot;&gt;Why are you writing this book?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;post-body&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;cakedoc&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cakedoc-paragraph&quot;&gt;Something hit me during the memorial at Stanford when I was among the 400 or so close friends and colleagues he had worked with. Each of them had ten or maybe a hundred stories to tell about Steve. If that’s not a testament to someone’s character, then what is? That’s how you know someone left a mark, made a difference, changed things. I got goosebumps when I thought about that.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I thought that I should write many of my stories, events and moments that I shared with Steve in some form that others might enjoy. I’ve told many of these stories to friends in person and they usually say, “you should write a book!”. So I’m working on one.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There’s a lot of information out there from journalists or impressions from his presentations. But stories from people who worked closely with him for decades fill in the painting, as you mentioned earlier Chris, of who he really was. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 06:29:10 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>allenleein</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.cake.co/conversations/jNZlq6j/the-man-who-produced-steve-jobs-keynotes-for-20-years</og:url>
<og:title>The man who produced Steve Jobs’ keynotes for 20 years.</og:title>
<og:description>Wayne Goodrich was the producer for every keynote Steve gave after his return to Apple. Before that, Wayne helped him create presentations at NeXT and Pixar. He is writing a book about what it was …</og:description>
<og:image>https://cake.imgix.net/m/QLZzngCrcmXX_1531329024912.png?auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;h=1000&amp;w=1000</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.cake.co/conversations/jNZlq6j/the-man-who-produced-steve-jobs-keynotes-for-20-years</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>A Flash Player emulator written in Rust</title>
<link>https://github.com/ruffle-rs/ruffle</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/ruffle-rs/ruffle</guid>
<description>&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ruffle.rs&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/db67b8ee0c359b0a33cbfa59202f3e01fe2474d20f1eeb08604ae89f54f87daa/68747470733a2f2f727566666c652e72732f6173736574732f6c6f676f2e706e67&quot; alt=&quot;Ruffle&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://ruffle.rs/assets/logo.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ruffle-rs/ruffle/actions&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/088ddff15eab9fe495b95fcc04a84a934e768d68283ebad2ddb8fc81dd21f7da/68747470733a2f2f696d672e736869656c64732e696f2f6769746875622f776f726b666c6f772f7374617475732f727566666c652d72732f727566666c652f54657374253230527573743f6c6162656c3d727573742532306275696c64&quot; alt=&quot;Rust Build Status&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/workflow/status/ruffle-rs/ruffle/Test%20Rust?label=rust%20build&quot;/&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/32e5d2c570e6a23739b150582ee477aa3f6201b22a0ae0f37872c6410ebb6c38/68747470733a2f2f696d672e736869656c64732e696f2f6769746875622f776f726b666c6f772f7374617475732f727566666c652d72732f727566666c652f546573742532305765623f6c6162656c3d7765622532306275696c64&quot; alt=&quot;Web Build Status&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/workflow/status/ruffle-rs/ruffle/Test%20Web?label=web%20build&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://discord.gg/J8hgCQN&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/66ffac9aaf36d34e6c6abc4dfed60a992e025e5d9cdbc2ae436c3eb5e92fb1de/68747470733a2f2f696d672e736869656c64732e696f2f646973636f72642f363130353331353431383839353831303636&quot; alt=&quot;Ruffle Discord&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/discord/610531541889581066&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ruffle.rs&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://ruffle.rs/demo&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;demo&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ruffle-rs/ruffle/releases&quot;&gt;nightly builds&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ruffle-rs/ruffle/wiki&quot;&gt;wiki&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ruffle is an Adobe Flash Player emulator written in the Rust programming language. Ruffle targets both the desktop and the web using WebAssembly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Project status&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ruffle is in the proof-of-concept stage and can currently run early Flash animations and games. Basic ActionScript 1.0/2.0 support is in place and improving; ActionScript 3.0 support is forthcoming. For more info, read the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ruffle-rs/ruffle/wiki/Roadmap&quot;&gt;project roadmap&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Using Ruffle&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The easiest way to try out Ruffle is to visit the &lt;a href=&quot;https://ruffle.rs/demo/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;web demo page&lt;/a&gt;, then click the &quot;Browse...&quot; button to load an SWF file of your choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ruffle.rs/#releases&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Nightly builds&lt;/a&gt; of Ruffle are available for desktop and web platforms including the browser extension.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more detailed instructions, see our &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ruffle-rs/ruffle/wiki/Using-Ruffle&quot;&gt;wiki page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Building from source&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rust-lang.org/tools/install&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Follow the official guide&lt;/a&gt; to install Rust for your platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Desktop&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;cargo run --package=ruffle_desktop -- test.swf&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Web or Extension&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Follow &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ruffle-rs/ruffle/blob/master/web/README.md#building-from-source&quot;&gt;the instructions in the web directory&lt;/a&gt; for building either the web or browser extension version of Ruffle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Scanner&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have a collection of &quot;real world&quot; SWFs to test against, the scanner may be used to benchmark ruffle's parsing capabilities. Provided with a folder and an output filename, it will attempt to read all of the flash files and report on the success of such a task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;cargo run --package=ruffle_scanner -- folder/with/swfs/ results.csv&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Exporter&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have a swf and would like to capture an image of it, you may use the exporter tool. This currently requires hardware acceleration, but can be run headless (with no window).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;cargo run --package=exporter -- path/to/file.swf&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;cargo run --package=exporter -- path/to/file.swf path/to/screenshots --frames 5&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Structure&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;core&lt;/code&gt; contains the core emulator and common code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;desktop&lt;/code&gt; contains the desktop client (uses &lt;code&gt;wgpu-rs&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ruffle-rs/ruffle/blob/master/web&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;web&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; contains the web client and browser extension (uses &lt;code&gt;wasm-bindgen&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;scanner&lt;/code&gt; contains a utility to bulk parse swf files&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;exporter&lt;/code&gt; contains a utility to generate PNG screenshots of a swf file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Sponsors&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can support the development of Ruffle via &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sponsors/ruffle-rs&quot;&gt;GitHub Sponsors&lt;/a&gt;. Your sponsorship will help to ensure the accessibility of Flash content for the future. Thank you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sincere thanks to the diamond level sponsors of Ruffle:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newgrounds.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/95ecbb189b1ea25d9e1efca7e41007ca11f72a31c80dfbc0f1cc073c896c84ac/68747470733a2f2f727566666c652e72732f6173736574732f73706f6e736f72732f6e657767726f756e64732e706e67&quot; alt=&quot;Newgrounds.com&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://ruffle.rs/assets/sponsors/newgrounds.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cpmstar.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/fa20a63cbbd370bc6d4891438e60d3f927ca1e78f32f22e94bf2de5e39b4d594/68747470733a2f2f727566666c652e72732f6173736574732f73706f6e736f72732f63706d737461722e706e67&quot; alt=&quot;CPMStar&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://ruffle.rs/assets/sponsors/cpmstar.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://deepnight.net&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/b9c833d495720e03e9c4d50dc9768f3f7bf1b3ae46c33f3a7f194ad725cef1f0/68747470733a2f2f727566666c652e72732f6173736574732f73706f6e736f72732f646565706e696768742e706e67&quot; alt=&quot;Sébastien Bénard&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://ruffle.rs/assets/sponsors/deepnight.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.crazygames.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/6cbba638ebd505feef8d07342c3da110cf0c1199d18b7cd3d214c59f764247a8/68747470733a2f2f727566666c652e72732f6173736574732f73706f6e736f72732f6372617a7967616d65732e706e67&quot; alt=&quot;Crazy Games&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://ruffle.rs/assets/sponsors/crazygames.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coolmathgames.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/a27cadb44811b6947b29716331bd1a22e71d60b2fa47c09bf42cb939d3d699dd/68747470733a2f2f727566666c652e72732f6173736574732f73706f6e736f72732f636f6f6c6d61746867616d65732e706e67&quot; alt=&quot;Cool Math Games&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://ruffle.rs/assets/sponsors/coolmathgames.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/dde1faa77d2fb9471309ced079442f90d94014797f5fe0ab333bf5ef75360fc8/68747470733a2f2f727566666c652e72732f6173736574732f73706f6e736f72732f6e79742e706e67&quot; alt=&quot;The New York Times&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://ruffle.rs/assets/sponsors/nyt.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.armorgames.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/b7d4bd7469cd83826485c848454c72bf610b4060be44ec113f30eded0955898a/68747470733a2f2f727566666c652e72732f6173736574732f73706f6e736f72732f61726d6f7267616d65732e706e67&quot; alt=&quot;Armor Games&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://ruffle.rs/assets/sponsors/armorgames.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Licensed under either of&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;at your option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Contribution&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ruffle welcomes contribution from everyone. See CONTRIBUTING.md for help getting started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unless you explicitly state otherwise, any contribution intentionally submitted for inclusion in the work by you shall be dual licensed as above, without any additional terms or conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The entire Ruffle community, including the chat room and GitHub project, is expected to abide by the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rust-lang.org/policies/code-of-conduct&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt; that the Rust project itself follows.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 05:55:37 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>known</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/50037962?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>ruffle-rs/ruffle</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/ruffle-rs/ruffle</og:url>
<og:description>A Flash Player emulator written in Rust. Contribute to ruffle-rs/ruffle development by creating an account on GitHub.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/ruffle-rs/ruffle</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>