<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Top ten most popular docker images each contain at least 30 vulnerabilities</title>
<link>https://snyk.io/blog/top-ten-most-popular-docker-images-each-contain-at-least-30-vulnerabilities/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://snyk.io/blog/top-ten-most-popular-docker-images-each-contain-at-least-30-vulnerabilities/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Snyk’s annual State of Open Source Security report 2019.&lt;br/&gt;This report is split into several posts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or download our lovely handcrafted pdf report which contains all of this information and more in one place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;btn-small&quot; href=&quot;https://bit.ly/SoOSS2019&quot;&gt;DOWNLOAD THE STATE OF OPEN SOURCE SECURITY REPORT 2019!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The adoption of application container technology is increasing at a remarkable rate and is expected to grow by a further 40% in 2020, according to 451 Research. It is common for system libraries to be available in many docker images, as these rely on a parent image that is commonly using a Linux distribution as a base.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Docker images almost always bring known vulnerabilities alongside their great value&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve scanned through ten of the most popular images with Snyk’s recently released &lt;a href=&quot;https://snyk.io/blog/container-vulnerability-management-for-developers/&quot;&gt;docker scanning capabilities&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The findings show that in every docker image we scanned, we found vulnerable versions of system libraries. The official Node.js image ships 580 vulnerable system libraries, followed by the others each of which ship at least 30 publicly known vulnerabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone wp-image-8032&quot; src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/snyk/image/upload/v1551121069/Number_of_OS_vulnerabilities_by_docker_image.png&quot; alt=&quot;Number of OS vulnerabilities by docker image&quot; width=&quot;1200&quot; height=&quot;563&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Snyk recently released its container vulnerability management solution to empower developers to fully own the security of their dockerized applications. Using this new capability, developers can find known vulnerabilities in their docker base images and fix them using Snyk’s remediation advice. Snyk suggests either a minimal upgrade, or alternative base images that contain fewer or even no vulnerabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fix can be easy if you’re aware. 20% of images can fix vulnerabilities simply by rebuilding a docker image, 44% by swapping base image&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on scans performed by Snyk users, we found that 44% of docker image scans had known vulnerabilities, and for which there were newer and more secure base image available. This remediation advise is unique to Snyk. Developers can take action to upgrade their docker images.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Snyk also reported that 20% of docker image scans had known vulnerabilities that simply required a rebuild of the image to reduce the number of vulnerabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The current Long Term Support (LTS) version of the Node.js runtime is version 10. The image tagged with 10 (i.e: node:10) is essentially an alias to node:10.14.2- jessie (at the time that we tested it) where jessie specifies an obsolete version of Debian that is no longer actively maintained.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you had chosen that image as a base image in your Dockerfile, you’d be exposing yourself to 582 vulnerable system libraries bundled with the image. Another option is to use the node:10-slim image tag which provides slimmer images without unnecessary dependencies (for example: it omits the main pages and other assets). Choosing node:10-slim however would still pull in 71 vulnerable system libraries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most vulnerabilities originate in the base image you selected. For that reason, remediation should focus on base image fixes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The node:10-alpine image is a better option to choose if you want a very small base image with a minimal set of system libraries. However, while no vulnerabilities were detected in the version of the Alpine image we tested, that’s not to say that it is necessarily free of security issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alpine Linux handles vulnerabilities differently than the other major distros, who prefer to backport sets of patches. At Alpine, they prefer rapid release cycles for their images, with each image release providing a system library upgrade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone wp-image-8033&quot; src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/snyk/image/upload/v1551121266/Number_of_vulnerabilities_by_node_image_tag.png&quot; alt=&quot;Number of vulnerabilities by node image tag&quot; width=&quot;587&quot; height=&quot;637&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, Alpine Linux doesn’t maintain a security advisory program, which means that if a system library has vulnerabilities, Alpine Linux will not issue an official advisory about it; Alpine Linux will mitigate the vulnerability by creating a new base image version including a new version of that library that fixes the issue, if one is available (as opposed to backporting as mentioned).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no guarantee that the newer fixed version, of a vulnerable library will be immediately available on Alpine Linux, although that is the case many times. Despite this, if you can safely move to the Alpine Linux version without breaking your application, you can reduce the attack surface of your environment because you will be using fewer libraries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The use of an image tag, like node:10, is in reality an alias to another image, which constantly rotates with new minor and patched versions of 10 as they are released.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone wp-image-8034&quot; src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/snyk/image/upload/v1551121369/Docker_terminal_screenshot.png&quot; alt=&quot;Docker terminal screenshot&quot; width=&quot;1200&quot; height=&quot;860&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A practice that some teams follow is to use a specific version tag instead of an alias so that their base image would be node:10.8.0-jessie for example. However, as newer releases of Node 10 are released, there is a good chance those newer images will include fewer system library vulnerabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using the Snyk Docker scanning features we found that when a project uses a specific version tag such as node:10.8.0-jessie, we could then recommend newer images that contain fewer vulnerabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is an increase in the number of vulnerabilities reported for system libraries, affecting some of the popular Linux distributions such as Debian, RedHat Enterprise Linux and Ubuntu. In 2018 alone we tracked 1,597 vulnerabilities in system libraries with known CVEs assigned for these distros, which is more than four times the number of vulnerabilities compared to 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone wp-image-8029&quot; src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/snyk/image/upload/v1551120743/Linux_OS_vulnerabilities_steadily_increasing.png&quot; alt=&quot;Linux OS vulnerabilities steadily increasing&quot; width=&quot;788&quot; height=&quot;562&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we look at the breakdown of vulnerabilities (high and critical) it is clear that this severity level is continuing to increase through 2017 and 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone wp-image-8030&quot; src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/snyk/image/upload/v1551120779/High_and_critical_vulnerabilities_in_system_libraries.png&quot; alt=&quot;High and critical vulnerabilities in system libraries&quot; width=&quot;665&quot; height=&quot;713&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Continue reading:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;btn-small&quot; href=&quot;https://bit.ly/SoOSS2019&quot;&gt;DOWNLOAD THE STATE OF OPEN SOURCE SECURITY REPORT 2019!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 16:24:41 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>vinnyglennon</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Top ten most popular docker images each contain at least 30 vulnerabilities | Snyk</og:title>
<og:description>we found that 44% of docker image scans had known vulnerabilities, and for which there were newer and more secure base image available. Most vulnerabilities originate in the base image you selected. For that reason, remediation should focus on base image fixes.</og:description>
<og:url>https://snyk.io/blog/top-ten-most-popular-docker-images-each-contain-at-least-30-vulnerabilities/</og:url>
<og:image>https://snyk.io/wp-content/uploads/the-state-op-open-source-4-small.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://snyk.io/blog/top-ten-most-popular-docker-images-each-contain-at-least-30-vulnerabilities/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Show HN: Zero Server – Zero configuration web framework</title>
<link>https://zeroserver.io/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://zeroserver.io/</guid>
<description>&lt;h4&gt;Installation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can install &lt;code&gt;zero&lt;/code&gt; globally by:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-sh&quot;&gt;npm install -g zero
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Hello World&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's start by making a website that tells us server time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First we need to create an API endpoint in Node.js to tell us time in JSON.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create a new folder and add a new file &lt;code&gt;time.js&lt;/code&gt; in that folder. In this file, export a function that accepts &lt;code&gt;Request&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Response&lt;/code&gt; objects (&lt;a href=&quot;https://expressjs.com/en/4x/api.html#res&quot;&gt;like Express&lt;/a&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-js&quot;&gt;// time.js
const moment = require(&quot;moment&quot;)

module.exports = (req, res) =&amp;gt; {
  var time = moment().format('LT');   // 11:51 AM
  res.send({time: time })
}
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once saved, you can &lt;code&gt;cd&lt;/code&gt; into that folder and start the server like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-sh&quot;&gt;zero
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Running this command will automatically install any dependencies (like &lt;em&gt;momentjs&lt;/em&gt; here) and start the web server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open this URL in the browser: &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:3000/time&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;http://localhost:3000/time&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You just created an API endpoint 🎉:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://zeroserver.io/assets/images/timeapi.png&quot; alt=&quot;Time API&quot; title=&quot;Time API&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep the server running. Now let's consume our API from a React page, create a new file &lt;code&gt;index.jsx&lt;/code&gt; and add the following code:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-jsx&quot;&gt;// index.jsx
import React from 'react'

export default class extends React.Component {
  static async getInitialProps(){
    var json = await fetch(&quot;/time&quot;).then((resp) =&amp;gt; resp.json())
    return {time: json.time}
  }

  render() {
    return &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Current time is: {this.props.time}&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
  }
}
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a standard React component. With one additional hook for initial data population:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;getInitialProps&lt;/code&gt; is an &lt;code&gt;async&lt;/code&gt; static method which is called by &lt;code&gt;zero&lt;/code&gt; when the page loads. This method can return a plain object which populates &lt;code&gt;props&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now go to this URL: &lt;code&gt;http://localhost:3000/&lt;/code&gt; and you should see the current server time rendered by React while &lt;code&gt;fetch&lt;/code&gt;-ing an API endpoint you created earlier:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://zeroserver.io/assets/images/timejsx.png&quot; alt=&quot;Time In React&quot; title=&quot;Time In React&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;zero&lt;/code&gt; automatically bundles your code and supports server-side rendering. You don't need to fiddle with webpack anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's it! You just created a web application.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 15:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>asadlionpk</dc:creator>
<og:description>Zero is a web framework to simplify modern web development. It allows you to build your application without worrying about package management or routing.</og:description>
<og:title>Zero Server</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://zeroserver.io/</og:url>
<og:image>https://zeroserver.io/assets/favicon.png</og:image>
<dc:identifier>https://zeroserver.io/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>This Startup Does Not Exist</title>
<link>https://thisstartupdoesnotexist.com/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://thisstartupdoesnotexist.com/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;
		&lt;h2 class=&quot;theme-title&quot;&gt;Oyoloo is more than just Streamliner&lt;/h2&gt;
		&lt;h5 class=&quot;description&quot;&gt;Messenger, Community and Education are just a few characteristic of Oyoloo. But we offer a lot more!&lt;/h5&gt;
	&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;theme-blog-content&quot;&gt;
		&lt;div class=&quot;theme-features-content container&quot;&gt;
			&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;col-xs-12 col-md-4 feature-box&quot;&gt;
					&lt;div class=&quot;theme-info&quot;&gt;
						
							&lt;h4 class=&quot;info-title&quot;&gt;Enthralling&lt;/h4&gt;
							
					&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;col-xs-12 col-md-4 feature-box&quot;&gt;
					&lt;div class=&quot;theme-info&quot;&gt;
						
							&lt;h4 class=&quot;info-title&quot;&gt;Gratifying&lt;/h4&gt;
							
					&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;col-xs-12 col-md-4 feature-box&quot;&gt;
					&lt;div class=&quot;theme-info&quot;&gt;
						
							&lt;h4 class=&quot;info-title&quot;&gt;Attainable&lt;/h4&gt;
							
					&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 12:53:47 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>oschn</dc:creator>
<dc:language>de-DE</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://thisstartupdoesnotexist.com/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Wage Stagnation</title>
<link>https://slatestarcodex.com/2019/02/25/wage-stagnation-much-more-than-you-wanted-to-know/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://slatestarcodex.com/2019/02/25/wage-stagnation-much-more-than-you-wanted-to-know/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;em&gt;[Epistemic status: I am basing this on widely-accepted published research, but I can’t guarantee I’ve understood the research right or managed to emphasize/believe the right people. Some light editing to bring in important points people raised in the comments.]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You all know this graph:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://slatestarcodex.com/blog_images/main_graph.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Median wages tracked productivity until 1973, then stopped. Productivity kept growing, but wages remained stagnant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is called “wage decoupling”. Sometimes people talk about wages decoupling from GDP, or from GDP per capita, but it all works out pretty much the same way. Increasing growth no longer produces increasing wages for ordinary workers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is this true? If so, why?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. What Does The Story Look Like Across Other Countries And Time Periods?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s a broader look, from 1800 on:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://slatestarcodex.com/blog_images/historical.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It no longer seems like a law of nature that productivity and wages are coupled before 1973. They seem to uncouple and recouple several times, with all the previous graphs’ starting point in 1950 being a period of unusual coupledness. Still, the modern uncoupling seems much bigger than anything that’s happened before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What about other countries? This graph is for the UK (you can tell because it spells “labor” as “labour”)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://slatestarcodex.com/blog_images/decoupling_uk.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It looks similar, except that the decoupling starts around 1990 instead of around 1973.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here’s Europe:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://slatestarcodex.com/blog_images/decoupling_europe.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is only from 1999 on, so it’s not that helpful. But it does show that even in this short period, France remains coupled, Germany is decoupled, Spain is…doing whatever Spain is doing, and Italy is so pathetic that the problem never even comes up. Overall not sure what to think about these.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Could Apparent Wage Decoupling Be Because Of Health Insurance?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along with wages, workers are compensated in benefits like health insurance. Since health insurance has skyrocketed in price, this means total worker compensation has gone up much more than wages have. This could mean workers are really getting compensated much more, even though they’re being paid the same amount of money. This view has sometimes been associated with economist Glenn Hubbard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a few lines of argument that suggest it’s not true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;First&lt;/u&gt;, wage growth has been worst for the lowest-paid workers. But the lowest-paid workers don’t usually get insurance at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://slatestarcodex.com/blog_images/healthcare1.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://slatestarcodex.com/blog_images/productivity_class.PNG&quot;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Second&lt;/u&gt;, the numbers don’t really add up. Median household income in 1973 was about $48,000 in today’s dollars. Since then, productivity has increased by between 70% and 140% (EVERYBODY DISAGREES ON THIS NUMBER), so if median income had kept pace with productivity it should be between $82,000 and $115,000. Instead, it is $59,000. So there are between $23,000 and $67,000 of missing income to explain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The average health insurance policy &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.peoplekeep.com/blog/what-percent-of-health-insurance-is-paid-by-employers&quot;&gt;costs&lt;/a&gt; about $7000 per individual or $20000 per family, of which employers pay $6000 and $14000 respectively. But as mentioned above, many people do not have employer-paid insurance at all, so the average per person cost is less than that. Usually only one member of a household will pay for family insurance, even if both members work; sometimes only one member of a household will buy insurance at all. So the average cost of insurance to a company per employee is well below the $6000 to $14000 number. If we round it off to $6000 per person, that only explains a quarter of the lowest estimate of the productivity gap, and less than a tenth of the highest estimate. So it’s unlikely that this is the main cause.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Third&lt;/u&gt;, some people have tried measuring productivity vs. total compensation, with broadly similar results:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://slatestarcodex.com/blog_images/epi_compensation.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://slatestarcodex.com/blog_images/heritage_compensation.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://slatestarcodex.com/blog_images/fed_compensation.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first graph is from the left-wing &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epi.org/blog/professor-hubbards-claim-about-wage-and-compensation-stagnation-is-not-true/&quot;&gt;Economic Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;, whose bias is towards proving that wage stagnation is real and important. The second graph is from the right-wing &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.heritage.org/jobs-and-labor/report/productivity-and-compensation-growing-together&quot;&gt;Heritage Foundation&lt;/a&gt;, whose bias is towards proving that wage stagnation is fake and irrelevant. The third graph is from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://research.stlouisfed.org/publications/economic-synopses/2016/08/12/labor-compensation-and-labor-productivity-recent-recoveries-and-the-long-term-trend/&quot;&gt;US Federal Reserve&lt;/a&gt;, a perfectly benevolent view-from-nowhere institution whose only concern is the good of the American people. All three agree that going from earnings to total compensation alone closes only a small part of the gap. The EPI also mentions that most of the difference between earnings and compensation opened up in the 1960s and stayed stable thereafter (why? haven’t health insurance costs gone up more since then), which further defeats this as an explanation for post-1973 trends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We shouldn’t dismiss this as irrelevant, because many things that close only a small part of the gap may, when added together, close a large part of the gap. But this doesn’t do much on its own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Could Apparent Wage Decoupling Be An Artifact Of Changing Demographics?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The demographics of the workforce have changed a lot since 1973; for example, more workers are women and minorities. If women and minorities get paid less, then as more of them enter the workforce, the lower “average” wages will go (without any individual getting paid less). If they gradually enter the workforce at the same rate that wages are increasing, this could look like wages being stagnant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But if we disaggregate statistics by race and gender, we don’t see this. &lt;a href=&quot;https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2011/06/the-great-male-stagnation.html&quot;&gt;Here’s&lt;/a&gt; average male wage over the relevant time period:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://slatestarcodex.com/blog_images/male_income.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/wonk/wp/2013/08/28/these-seven-charts-show-the-black-white-economic-gap-hasnt-budged-in-50-years/?noredirect=on&amp;amp;utm_term=.3be74828d84f&quot;&gt;here’s&lt;/a&gt; average income disaggregated by race:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://slatestarcodex.com/blog_images/race_income.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The patterns for whites and men are the same as the general pattern.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is one unusual thing in this area. &lt;a href=&quot;https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2011/06/the-great-male-stagnation.html&quot;&gt;Here’s&lt;/a&gt; the pattern for women:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://slatestarcodex.com/blog_images/female_income.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Women’s income is rising at almost the same rate as productivity! This is pretty interesting, but as far as I can tell it’s just because women’s career prospects have been improving over time because of shifting cultural attitudes, affirmative action, and the increasing dominance of female-friendly service and education-heavy jobs. I’m not sure this has any greater significance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did increased female participation in the workforce increase the supply of labor and so drive the price of labor down? There’s a tiny bit of evidence for that &lt;a href=&quot;https://aneconomicsense.org/2016/03/20/there-is-no-reason-to-expect-increased-labor-force-participation-rates-to-be-a-source-of-spectacular-growth/&quot;&gt;in the data&lt;/a&gt;, which show female workforce participation started rising much faster around 1973, with a corresponding increase in total workforce. But this spurt trailed off relatively quickly, and female participation has been declining since about 2000, and the wage stagnation trend continues. I don’t want to rule out the possibility that this was part of what made 1973 in particular such a strong inflection point, but even if it was, it’s long since been overwhelmed by other factors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Could Apparent Wage Decoupling Be An Artifact Of How We Measure Inflation?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Martin Feldstein is a Harvard economics professor, former head of the National Bureau of Economic Researchers, former head of the President’s Council of Economic Advisors, etc. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nber.org/feldstein/WAGESandPRODUCTIVITY.meetings2008.pdf&quot;&gt;He believes&lt;/a&gt; that apparent wage stagnation is an artifact of mismeasurement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His argument is pretty hard for me to understand, but as best I can tell, it goes like this. In order to calculate wage growth since 1973, we take the nominal difference in wages, then adjust for inflation. We calculate wage inflation with something called the Consumer Price Index, which is the average price of lots of different goods and services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But in order to calculate productivity growth since 1973, we use a different index, the “nonfarm business sector output price index”, which is based on how much money companies get for their products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These should be similar if consumers are buying the same products that companies are making. But there can be some differences. For example, if you’re looking at US statistics only, then some businesses may be selling to foreign markets with different inflation rates, and some consumers may be buying imported goods from countries with different inflation rates. Also (and I’m not sure I understand this right), if people own houses, CPI pretends they are paying market rent to avoid ignoring housing costs, but PPI doesn’t do this. Also, PPI is not as good at including services as CPI. So consumer and producer price indexes differ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, consumer inflation has been larger than producer inflation since 1973. So when we adjust wages for consumer inflation, they go way down, but when we adjust productivity for producer-inflation, it only goes down a little. This means that these different inflation indices make it look like productivity has risen much faster than wages, but actually they’ve risen the same amount.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As per Feldstein:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;17&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The level of productivity doubled in the U.S. nonfarm business sectorbetween 1970 and 2006. Wages, or more accurately total compensation per hour, increased at approximately the same annual rate during that period if nominal compensation is adjusted for inflation in the same way as the nominal output measure that is used to calculate productivity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More specifically, the doubling of productivity represented a 1.9 percent annual rate of increase. Real compensation per hour rose at 1.7 percent per year when nominal compensation is deflated using the same nonfarm business sector output price index. In the period since 2000, productivity rose much more rapidly (2.9 percent ayear) and compensation per hour rose nearly as fast (2.5 percent a year).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is the CPI increasing so much faster than business-centered inflation indices?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://slatestarcodex.com/blog_images/price_indices.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Federal Reserve &lt;a href=&quot;https://files.stlouisfed.org/files/htdocs/publications/es/03/ES0305.pdf&quot;&gt;blames tech&lt;/a&gt;. The services-centered CPI has comparatively little technology. The goods-heavy PPI (a business-centered index of inflation) has a lot of it. Tech is going down in price (how much did a digital camera cost in 1990? How about now?) so the PPI stays very low while the CPI keeps growing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How much does this matter?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The left-leaning Economic Policy Institute &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epi.org/publication/ib330-productivity-vs-compensation/&quot;&gt;says&lt;/a&gt; it explains 34% of wage decoupling:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://slatestarcodex.com/blog_images/epi_feldstein.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The right-leaning Heritage Foundation says it explains more:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://slatestarcodex.com/blog_images/heritage_feldstein.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we estimate the size of the gap as 70 pp (between total compensation CPI and productivity), switching to the top IPD measure closes 67% of the gap; switching to the PCE measure explains 37% of the gap. I’m confused because the EPI is supposedly based on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.csls.ca/ipm/23/IPM-23-Mishel-Gee.pdf&quot;&gt;Mishel and Gee&lt;/a&gt;, who say they have used the GDP deflator, which is the same thing as the IPD which the Heritage Foundation says they use. I think the difference is that Mishel and Gee haven’t already applied the change from wages to total compensation when they estimate percent of the gap closed? But I’m not sure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One other group has tried to calculate this: &lt;a href=&quot;http://cep.lse.ac.uk/pubs/download/dp1246.pdf&quot;&gt;Pessoa and Van Reenan: Decoupling Of Wage Growth And Productivity Growth? Myth And Reality&lt;/a&gt;. According to a summary I read, they believe 40% of wage decoupling is because of these inflation related concerns, but I have trouble finding that number in the paper itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.urban.org/sites/default/files/publication/65351/2000331-Beyond-the-Wage-Stagnation-Story.pdf&quot;&gt;the CBO looks into&lt;/a&gt; the same issue. They’re not talking about it relative to productivity, but they say that technical inflation issues mean that the standard wage stagnation story is false, and wages have really grown 41% from 1979 – 2013. Since productivity increased somewhere between 70% and 100% during that time, this seems similar to some of the other estimates – inflation technicalities explain between 1/3 and 2/3 of the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone I read seems to agree this issue exists and is interesting, but I’m not sure I entirely understand the implications. Some people say that this completely debunks the idea of wage decoupling and it’s actually only half or a third what the raw numbers say. Other people seem to agree that a big part of wage decoupling is these inflation technicalities, but suggest that although they have important technical implications, if you want to know how the average worker on the street is doing the CPI is still the way to go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Superstar economist Larry Summers (with Harvard student Anna Stansbury) comes the closest to having a real opinion on this &lt;a href=&quot;https://piie.com/system/files/documents/wp18-5.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When investigating consumers’ experienced rise in living standards as in Bivens and Mishel (2015), a consumer price deflator is appropriate; however, as Feldstein (2008) argues, when investigating factor income shares a producer price deflator is more appropriate because it reflects the real cost to firms of employing workers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am a little confused by this. On the one hand, I do want to investigate consumers’ experienced rise (or lack thereof) in living standards. This is the whole point – the possibility that workers’ living standards haven’t risen since 1973. But most people nowadays work in services. If you deflate their wages with an index used mostly for goods, are you just being a moron and ensuring you will be inaccurate?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Summers and Stansbury continue:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;18&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lawrence (2016) analyzes this divergence more recently, comparing average compensation to net productivity, which is a more accurate reflection of the increase in income available for distribution to factors of production. Since depreciation has accelerated over recent decades, using gross productivity creates a misleadingly large divergence between productivity and compensation. Lawrence finds that net labor productivity and average compensation grew together until 2001, when they started to diverge i.e. the labor share started to fall. Many other studies also find a decline in the US labor share of income since about 2000, though the timing and magnitude is disputed (see for example Grossman et al 2017, Karabarbounis and Neiman 2014, Lawrence 2015, Elsby Hobijn and Sahin 2013, Rognlie 2015, Pessoa and Van Reenen 2013).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I intepret this correctly, it looks like it’s saying that the real decoupling happened in 2000, not in 1973. I see a lot of papers saying the same thing, and I don’t understand where they’re diverging from the people who say it happened in 1973. Maybe they’re using Feldstein’s method of calculating inflation? I think this must be true – if you look at the Heritage Foundation graph above, “total compensation measured with Feldstein’s method” and productivity are exactly equal to their 1973 level in 2000, but diverge shortly thereafter so that today compensation has only grown 77% compared to productivity’s 100%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, Summers and Stansbury go on to give basically exactly the same “Why have wages been basically stagnant since 1973? Why are they decoupled from productivity?” narrative as everyone else, so it sure doesn’t look like they think any of this has disproven that. It looks like maybe they think Feldstein is right in some way that doesn’t matter? But I don’t know enough economics to figure out what that way would be. And it looks like Feldstein &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/are-us-middle-class-incomes-stagnating-by-martin-feldstein-2015-07?barrier=accesspaylog&quot;&gt;believes&lt;/a&gt; his rightness matters very much, and other economists like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.econlib.org/archives/2015/03/the_bizarre_way.html&quot;&gt;Scott Sumner&lt;/a&gt; seem to agree. And I cannot find anyone, anywhere, who wants to come out and say explicitly that Feldstein’s argument is wrong and we should definitely measure wage stagnation the way everyone does it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My conclusions from this section, such as they are, go:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1. Arcane technical points about inflation might explain between 33% and 66% of the apparent wage stagnation/decoupling.&lt;br/&gt;2. “Explain” may not mean the same as “explain away”, and it’s not completely clear how these points relate to anything we care about&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Could Wage Decoupling Be Explained By Increasing Labor-Vs-Capital Inequality?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Economists divide inequality into two types. Wage inequality is about how much different wage-earners (or salary-earners, here the terms are used interchangeably) make relative to each other. Labor-vs-capital inequality is about how much wage earners earn vs. how much capitalists get in profits. These capitalists are usually investors/shareholders, but can also be small business owners (or, sometimes, large business owners). Since tycoons like Jeff Bezos and Mark Zuckerberg get most of their compensation from stocks, they count as “capitalists” even if they are paid some token salary for the work they do running their companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the labor-vs-capital split for the US over the relevant time period; note the very truncated vertical axis:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://slatestarcodex.com/blog_images/labor_capital.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This type of inequality was about the same in the early 1970s as in the early 2000s, and has no clear inflection point around 1973, so it probably didn’t start this trend off. But it did start seriously decreasing around 2000, the same time people who use the more careful inflation methodology say wages and productivity &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; decoupled. And obviously labor getting less money in general is the sort of thing that makes wages go down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is labor-vs-capital inequality increasing? For the long story, read Piketty (&lt;a href=&quot;https://slatestarcodex.com/2018/06/24/book-review-capital-in-the-twenty-first-century/&quot;&gt;my review&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://slatestarcodex.com/2018/06/26/list-of-passages-i-highlighted-in-my-copy-of-capital-in-the-twenty-first-century/&quot;&gt;highlights&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://slatestarcodex.com/2018/06/28/highlights-from-the-comments-on-piketty/&quot;&gt;comments&lt;/a&gt;). But the short story includes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today’s wage inequality is tomorrow’s labor-vs-capital inequality. If some people get paid more than others, they can invest, their savings will compound, and they will have more capital. As wage inequality increases (see below), labor-vs-capital inequality does too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tech industry is more capital-intensive than labor-intensive. For example, Apple has 100,000 employees and makes $250 billion/year, compared to WalMart with 2 million employees and $500 billion/year – in other words, Apple makes $2.5 million per employee compared to Wal-Mart’s $250,000. Apple probably pays its employees more than Wal-Mart does, but not ten times more. So more of Apple’s revenue goes to capital compared to Wal-Mart’s. As tech becomes more important than traditional industries, capital’s share of the pie goes up. This is probably a big reason why capital has been doing so well since 2000 or so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s an iconoclastic strain of thought that says most of the change in labor-vs-capital is just housing. Houses count as capital, so as housing costs rise, so does capital’s share of the economy. Read Matt Ronglie’s work (&lt;a href=&quot;http://mattrognlie.com/piketty_diminishing_returns.pdf&quot;&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.brookings.edu/bpea-articles/deciphering-the-fall-and-rise-in-the-net-capital-share/&quot;&gt;summary&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vox.com/2015/4/1/8320937/this-26-year-old-grad-student-didnt-really-debunk-piketty-but-what-he&quot;&gt;Voxsplainer&lt;/a&gt;) for more. Since houses are neither involved in corporate productivity nor in wages, I’m not sure how this affects wage-productivity decoupling if true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever the cause, the papers I read suggest that increasing labor-vs-capital inequality explains maybe 10-20% of of decoupling, almost all concentrated in the 2000 – present period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Could Wage Decoupling Be Explained By Increasing Wage Inequality?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other part of the two-pronged inequality picture above. This one seems more important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One way economists look at this is in the difference between the &lt;em&gt;median&lt;/em&gt; wage and the &lt;em&gt;average&lt;/em&gt; wage:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://slatestarcodex.com/blog_images/epi_average.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add in the other things we talked about – the health insurance, the inflation technicalities, the declining share of labor – and the “””average””” worker is doing almost as well as they were in 1973. In fact, this is almost tautologically true. If the entire pie is growing by X amount, and labor’s relative share of the pie is staying the same, then labor should be getting the same absolute amount, and (ignoring changes in the number of laborers) the average laborer should get the same amount.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the decline in median wage is a mean vs. median issue. A few high-earners are taking a lot of the pie, keeping the mean constant but lowering the median. How high?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://slatestarcodex.com/blog_images/epi_percent.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember, productivity has grown by 70-100% through this period. So even though the top 5% have seen their incomes grow by 69%, they’re still not growing as fast as productivity. The top 1% have grown a bit faster than productivity, although still not that much. The top 0.1% are doing really well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is generally considered the most important cause of wage stagnation and wage decoupling, other than among the iconoclasts who think the inflation issues are more important. Above, I referred to a few papers that tried to break down the importance of each cause. EPI thinks wage inequality explains 47% of the problem. Pessoa and Van Reenen think it explains more like 20% according to Mishel’s summary (my eyeballing of the paper suggests more like 33%, but I am pretty uncertain about this).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Is Wage Inequality Increasing Because Of Technology?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s one story about why wage inequality is increasing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the old days, people worked in factories. A slightly smarter factory worker might be able to run the machinery a little better, or do something else useful, but in the end everyone is working on the same machines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the modern economy, factory workers are being replaced by robots. This creates very high demand for skilled roboticists, who get paid lots of money to run the robots in the most efficient way, and very low demand for factory workers, who need to be retrained to be fast food workers or something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or, in the general case, technology separates people into the winners (the people who are good with technology and who can use it to do jobs that would have taken dozens or hundreds of people before) and the losers (people who are not good with technology, and so their jobs have been automated away).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From an OECD paper:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Common explanations for increased wage inequality such as skill-biased technological change and globalisation cannot plausibly account for the disproportionate wage growth at the very top of the wage distribution. Skill-biased technological change and globalisation may both raise the relative demand for high-skilled workers, but this should be reflected in broadly rising relative wages of high-skilled workers rather than narrowly rising relative wagesof top-earners. Brynjolfsson and McAfee (2014) argue that digitalisation leads to “winner-takes-most” dynamics, with innovators reaping outsize rewards as digital innovations are replicable at very low cost and have a global scale. Recent studies provide evidence consistent with “winner-take-most” dynamics, in the sense that productivity of firms at the technology frontier has diverged from the remaining firms and that market shares of frontier firms have increased (Andrews et al., 2016). This type of technological change may allow firms at the technology frontier to raise the wages of its key employees to “superstar” levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It…sounds like they’re saying that technological change can’t be the answer, then giving arguments for why the answer is technological change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think this is just the authors’ poor writing skills, and that the real argument is less confusing. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.huffingtonpost.com/nathan-newman/great-decoupling-of-wages_b_7451212.html&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Huffington Post&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is surprisingly helpful, describing it as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What this means is that skilled professionals are not just winning out over working class stiffs, but the richest of the top 0.01 percent are winning out over the professional class as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://piie.com/system/files/documents/wp18-5.pdf&quot;&gt;That Larry Summers paper&lt;/a&gt; mentioned before becomes relevant here again. It argues that wages and productivity are not decoupled – which I know is a pretty explosive thing to say three thousand words in to an essay on wage decoupling, but let’s hear him out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He argues that apparent decoupling between productivity and wages could result either from literal decoupling – that is, none of the gains of increasing productivity going to workers – or from unrelated trends – for example, increasing productivity giving workers an extra $1000 at the same time as something else causes workers to lose $1000. If a company made $1000 extra and the boss pocketed all of it and didn’t give workers any, that would be literal decoupling. If a company made $1000 extra, it gave workers $1000 extra, but globalization means there’s less demand for workers and so salaries would otherwise have dropped by $1000, so now they stay the same, that’s an unrelated trend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Summers and Stansbury investigate this by seeing if wages increase more during the short periods between 1973 and today when productivity is unusually high, and if they stagnate more (or decline) during the short periods when it is unusually low. They find this is mostly true:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We find substantial evidence of linkage between productivity and compensation: Over 1973–2016, one percentage point higher productivity growth has been associated with 0.7 to 1 percentage points higher median and average compensation growth and with 0.4 to 0.7 percentage points higher production/nonsupervisory compensation growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;S&amp;amp;S are very careful in this paper and have already adjusted for health insurance issues and inflation calculation issues. They find that once you adjust for this, productivity and wages are between 40% and 100% coupled, depending on what measure you use. (I don’t exactly understand the difference between the two measures they give; surely taking the median worker is already letting you consider inequality and you shouldn’t get so much of a difference by focusing on nonsupervisory workers?) As mentioned before, they finds the coupling is much less since 2000. They also find similar results in most other countries: whether or not those countries show apparent decoupling, they remain pretty coupled in terms of actual productivity growth:wage growth correlation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They argue that if technology/automation were causing rising wage inequality or rising labor-capital inequality, then median wage should decouple from productivity fastest during the periods of highest productivity growth. After all, productivity growth represents the advance of labor-saving technology. So periods of high productivity growth are those where the most new technology and automation are being deployed, so if this is what’s driving wages down, wages should decrease fastest during this time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They test this a couple of different ways, and find that it is false before the year 2000, but somewhat true afterwards, mostly through labor-capital inequality. They don’t really find that technology drives wage inequality at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I understand why technology would mean decoupling happens fastest during the highest productivity growth. But I’m not sure I understand what they mean when they say there is no decoupling and productivity growth translates into wage growth? Shouldn’t this disprove &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; posited causes of decoupling so far, including policy-based wage inequality? I’m not sure. S&amp;amp;S don’t seem to think so, but I’m not sure why. Overall I find this paper confusing, but I assume its authors know what they’re doing so I will accept its conclusions as presented.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So it sounds like, although technology probably explains some top-10% people doing moderately better than the rest, it doesn’t explain the stratospheric increase in the share of the 1%, which is where most of the story lies. I would be content to dismiss this as unimportant, except that…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://slatestarcodex.com/blog_images/wage_igm.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;…all the world’s leading economists disagree.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe when they say “income inequality”, they’re talking about a more intuitive view of income inequality where some programmers make $150K and some factory workers make $30K and this is unequal and that’s important – even though it is not related to the larger problem of why everybody except the top 1% is making much less than predicted. I’m not sure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel bad about dismissing so many things as “probably responsible for a few percent of the problem”. It seems like a cop-out when it’s hard to decide whether something is really important or not. But my best guess is still that this is probably responsible for a few percent of the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8. Is Wage Inequality Increasing Because Of Policy Changes?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello! We are every think tank in the world! We hear you are wondering whether wage inequality is increasing because of policy changes! Can we offer you nine billion articles proving that it definitely is, and you should definitely be very angry? Please can we offer you articles? Pleeeeeeeeaaase?!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presentations of this theory usually involve some combination of policies – decreasing union power, low minimum wages, greater acceptance of very high CEO salary – that concentrate all gains in the highest-paid workers, usually CEOs and executives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have trouble making the numbers add up. Vox has a cute thought experiment &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vox.com/2014/8/6/5970815/what-if-walmarts-ceo-took-a-pay-cut-for-his-workers&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; where they imagine the CEO of Wal-Mart redistributing his entire salary to all Wal-Mart workers equally, possibly after having been visited by three spirits. Each Wal-Mart employee would make an extra $10. If the spirits visited all top Wal-Mart executives instead of just the CEO, the average employee would get $30. This is obviously not going to single-handedly bring them to the middle-class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vox uses such a limited definition of “top executive” that only five people are included. What about Wal-Mart’s 1%?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Wal-Mart 1% will include 20,000 people. To reach the 1% in the US, you need to make $400,000 per year; I would expect Wal-Mart’s 1% to be lower, since Wal-Mart is famously a bad place to work that doesn’t pay people much. Let’s say $200,000. That means the Wal-Mart 1% makes a total of $4 billion. If their salary were distributed to all 2 million employees, those employees would make an extra $2,000 per year; maybe a 10% pay raise. And of course even in a perfectly functional economy, we couldn’t pay Wal-Mart management literally $0, so the real number would be less than this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe the problem is that Wal-Mart is just an unusually employee-heavy company. What about Apple? Their CEO makes $12 million per year. If that were distributed to their 132,000 employees, they would each make an extra $90.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How many total high-paid executives does Apple have? It &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/apple-google-amazon-hiring-mbas-2017-4&quot;&gt;looks like&lt;/a&gt; Apple hires up to 130 MBAs from top business schools per year; if we imagine they last 10 years each, they might have 1000 such people, making them a “top 1%”. If these people get paid $500,000 each, they could earn 5 billion total. That’s enough to redistribute $40,000 to all Apple employees, which is starting to look like the level we would need to explain a lot of wage decoupling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not super-happy with this – I’m only getting the numbers to work by choosing a company I knew beforehand had an unusually low number of employees. Some commenters bring up the possibility that I’m missing stocks and stock options, which make up most of the compensation of top executives. I’m not sure whether this gets classified as income (in which case it could help explain income inequality) or as capital (in which case it would get filed under labor-vs-capital inequality). I’m also not sure whether Apple giving Tim Cook lots of stocks takes money out of the salary budget that could have gone to workers instead. For now let’s just accept that the difference between mean and median income shows that &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; has to be happening to drive up the top 1% or so of salaries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What policies are most likely to have caused this concentration of salaries at the top?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://slatestarcodex.com/blog_images/union.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many people point to a decline in unions. This decline does not really line up with the relevant time period – it started in the early 1960s, when productivity and wages were still closely coupled. But it could be a possible contributor. Economics Policy Institute &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epi.org/publication/union-decline-lowers-wages-of-nonunion-workers-the-overlooked-reason-why-wages-are-stuck-and-inequality-is-growing/&quot;&gt;cites some work&lt;/a&gt; saying it may explain up to 10% of decoupling &lt;em&gt;even for non-union members&lt;/em&gt;, since the deals struck by unions set norms that spread throughout their industries. A group of respected economists including David Card &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nber.org/papers/w9473.pdf&quot;&gt;looks into the issue&lt;/a&gt; and finds similar results, saying that the decline of unions may explain about 14% or more of increasing wage inequality (remember that wage inequality is only about 40% of decoupling, so this would mean it only explains about 5% of decoupling). The conservative Heritage Foundation &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.heritage.org/jobs-and-labor/report/what-unions-do-how-labor-unions-affect-jobs-and-the-economy&quot;&gt;has many bad things to say about unions&lt;/a&gt; but grudgingly admits they may raise salaries by up to 10% among members (they don’t address non-members). Based on all this, it seems plausible that deunionization may explain about 5-10% of decoupling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another relevant policy that could be shaping this issue is the minimum wage. EPI notes that although the minimum wage never goes down in nominal terms, if it doesn’t go up then it’s effectively going down in real terms and relative to productivity. This certainly sounds like the sort of thing that could increase wage inequality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://slatestarcodex.com/blog_images/minimum_wage.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But let’s look at that graph by percentiles again:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://slatestarcodex.com/blog_images/epi_percent.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wage stagnation is barely any better for the 90th percentile worker than it is for the people at the bottom. And the 90th percentile worker isn’t making minimum wage. This may be another one that adds a percentage point here and there, but it doesn’t seem too important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can’t find anything about it on EPI, but Thomas Piketty thinks that tax changes were an important driver of wage inequality. I’ll quote my previous &lt;a href=&quot;https://slatestarcodex.com/2018/06/24/book-review-capital-in-the-twenty-first-century/&quot;&gt;review of his book&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He thinks that executive salaries have increased because – basically – corporate governance isn’t good enough to prevent executives from giving themselves very high salaries. Why didn’t executives give themselves such high salaries before? Because before the 1980s the US had a top tax rate of 80% to 90%. As theory predicts, people become less interested in making money when the government’s going to take 90% of it, so executives didn’t bother pulling the strings it would take to have stratospheric salaries. Once the top tax rate was decreased, it became worth executives’ time to figure out how to game the system, so they did. This is less common outside the Anglosphere because other countries have different forms of corporate governance and taxation that discourage this kind of thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Piketty does some work to show that increasing wage inequality in different countries is correlated with those countries’ corporate governance and taxation policies. I don’t know if anyone has checked how that affects wage decoupling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9. Conclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1. Contrary to the usual story, wages have not stagnated since 1973. Measurement issues, including wages vs. benefits and different inflation measurements, have made things look worse than they are. Depending on how you prefer to think about inflation, median wages have probably risen about 40% – 50% since 1973, about half as much as productivity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2. This leaves about a 50% real decoupling between median wages and productivity, which is still enough to be serious and scary. The most important factor here is probably increasing wage inequality. Increasing labor-capital inequality is a less important but still significant factor, and it has become more significant since 2000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3. Increasing wage inequality probably has a lot to do with issues of taxation and corporate governance, and to some degree also with issues surrounding unionization. It probably has less to do with increasing technology and automation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4. If you were to put a gun to my head and force me to break down the importance of various factors in contributing to wage decoupling, it would look something like (warning: very low confidence!) this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;– Inflation miscalculations: 35%&lt;br/&gt;– Wages vs. total compensation: 10%&lt;br/&gt;– Increasing labor vs. capital inequality: 15%&lt;br/&gt;—- (Because of automation: 7.5%)&lt;br/&gt;—- (Because of policy: 7.5%)&lt;br/&gt;– Increasing wage inequality: 40%&lt;br/&gt;—- (Because of deunionization: 10%)&lt;br/&gt;—- (Because of policies permitting high executive salaries: 20%)&lt;br/&gt;—- (Because of globalization and automation: 10%)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This surprises me, because the dramatic shift in 1973 made me expect to see a single cause (and &lt;a href=&quot;https://slatestarcodex.com/2015/02/14/how-likely-are-multifactorial-trends/&quot;&gt;multifactorial trends should be rare in general&lt;/a&gt;, maybe, I think). It looks like there are two reasons why 1973 seems more important than it is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, most graphs trying to present this data begin around 1950. If they had begun much earlier than 1950, they would have showed several historical decouplings and recouplings that make a decoupling in any one year seem less interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, 1973 was the year of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/1973_oil_crisis&quot;&gt;1973 Oil Crisis&lt;/a&gt;, the fall of Bretton Woods, and the end of the gold standard, causing a general discombobulation to the economy that lasted a couple of years. By the time the economy recombobulated itself again, a lot of trends had the chance to get going or switch direction. For example, here’s inflation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://slatestarcodex.com/blog_images/cpi_history.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5. Inflation issues and wage inequality were probably most important in the first half of the period being studied. Labor-vs-capital inequality was probably most important in the second half.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6. Continuing issues that confuse me:&lt;br/&gt;– How much should we care about the difference between inflation indices? If we agree that using CPI to calculate this is dumb, should we cut our mental picture of the size of the problem in half?&lt;br/&gt;– Why is there such a difference between the Heritage Foundation’s estimate of how much of the gap inconsistent deflators explain (67%) and the EPI’s (34%)? Who is right?&lt;br/&gt;– Does the Summers &amp;amp; Stansbury paper argue against policy-based wage inequality as a cause of median wage stagnation, at least until 2000?&lt;br/&gt;– Are there enough high-paid executives at companies that, if their money were redistributed to all employees, their compensation would have increased significantly more in step with productivity? If so, where are they hiding? If not, what does “increasing wage inequality explains X% of decoupling” mean?&lt;br/&gt;– What caused past episodes of wage decoupling in the US? What ended them?&lt;br/&gt;– How do we square the apparent multifactorial nature of wage decoupling with its sudden beginning in 1973 and with the general argument against multifactorial trends?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 11:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>myle</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Wage Stagnation: Much More Than You Wanted To Know</og:title>
<og:url>https://slatestarcodex.com/2019/02/25/wage-stagnation-much-more-than-you-wanted-to-know/</og:url>
<og:description>[Epistemic status: I am basing this on widely-accepted published research, but I can’t guarantee I’ve understood the research right or managed to emphasize/believe the right people. Som…</og:description>
<og:image>https://slatestarcodex.com/wp-content/themes/two_column_pujugama/images/codex_spotlight.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://slatestarcodex.com/2019/02/25/wage-stagnation-much-more-than-you-wanted-to-know/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Linux Desktop Setup</title>
<link>https://hookrace.net/blog/linux-desktop-setup/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://hookrace.net/blog/linux-desktop-setup/</guid>
<description>&lt;span class=&quot;post-date&quot;&gt;2019-01-15 · &lt;a href=&quot;https://hookrace.net/blog/programming/&quot;&gt;Programming&lt;/a&gt; · &lt;a href=&quot;https://hookrace.net/blog/frugality/&quot;&gt;Frugality&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My software setup has been surprisingly constant over the last decade, after a few years of experimentation since I initially switched to Linux in 2006. It might be interesting to look back in another 10 years and see what changed. A quick overview of what’s running as I’m writing this post:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://hookrace.net/public/linux-desktop/htop.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://hookrace.net/public/linux-desktop/htop_small.png&quot; alt=&quot;htop overview&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;motivation&quot;&gt;Motivation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My software priorities are, in no specific order:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Programs should run on my local system so that I’m in control of them, this excludes cloud solutions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Programs should run in the terminal, so that they can be used consistently from anywhere, including weak computers or a phone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keyboard focused is nearly automatic by using terminal software. I prefer to use the mouse where it makes sense only, reaching for the mouse all the time during typing feels like a waste of time. Occasionally it took me an hour to notice that the mouse wasn’t even plugged in.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ideally use fast and efficient software, I don’t like hearing the fan and feeling the room heat up. I can also keep running older hardware for much longer, my 10 year old Thinkpad x200s is still fine for all the software I use.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be composable. I don’t want to do every step manually, instead automate more when it makes sense. This naturally favors the shell.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;operating-systems&quot;&gt;Operating Systems&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had a hard start with Linux 12 years ago by removing Windows, armed with just the &lt;a href=&quot;https://gentoo.org/&quot;&gt;Gentoo Linux&lt;/a&gt; installation CD and a printed manual to get a functioning Linux system. It took me a few days of compiling and tinkering, but in the end I felt like I had learnt a lot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven’t looked back to Windows since then, but I switched to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.archlinux.org/&quot;&gt;Arch Linux&lt;/a&gt; on my laptop after having the fan fail from the constant compilation stress. Later I also switched all my other computers and private servers to Arch Linux. As a rolling release distribution you get package upgrades all the time, but the most important breakages are nicely reported in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.archlinux.org/news/&quot;&gt;Arch Linux News&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One annoyance though is that Arch Linux removes the old kernel modules once you upgrade it. I usually notice that once I try plugging in a USB flash drive and the kernel fails to load the relevant module. Instead you’re supposed to reboot after each kernel upgrade. There are a few &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/archlinux/comments/4zrsc3/keep_your_system_fully_functional_after_a_kernel/&quot;&gt;hacks&lt;/a&gt; around to get around the problem, but I haven’t been bothered enough to actually use them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similar problems happen with other programs, commonly Firefox, cron or Samba requiring a restart after an upgrade, but annoyingly not warning you that that’s the case. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.suse.com/&quot;&gt;SUSE&lt;/a&gt;, which I use at work, nicely warns about such cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the &lt;a href=&quot;https://ddnet.tw/&quot;&gt;DDNet&lt;/a&gt; production servers I prefer &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.debian.org/&quot;&gt;Debian&lt;/a&gt; over Arch Linux, so that I have a lower chance of breakage on each upgrade. For my firewall and router I used &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openbsd.org/&quot;&gt;OpenBSD&lt;/a&gt; for its clean system, documentation and great &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openbsd.org/faq/pf/&quot;&gt;pf firewall&lt;/a&gt;, but right now I don’t have a need for a separate router anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;window-manager&quot;&gt;Window Manager&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I started out with Gentoo I quickly noticed the huge compile time of KDE, which made it a no-go for me. I looked around for more minimal solutions, and used &lt;a href=&quot;http://openbox.org/wiki/Main_Page&quot;&gt;Openbox&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://fluxbox.org/&quot;&gt;Fluxbox&lt;/a&gt; initially. At some point I jumped on the tiling window manager train in order to be more keyboard-focused and picked up &lt;a href=&quot;https://dwm.suckless.org/&quot;&gt;dwm&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://awesomewm.org/&quot;&gt;awesome&lt;/a&gt; close to their initial releases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end I settled on &lt;a href=&quot;https://xmonad.org/&quot;&gt;xmonad&lt;/a&gt; thanks to its flexibility, extendability and being written and configured in pure &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.haskell.org/&quot;&gt;Haskell&lt;/a&gt;, a great functional programming language. One example of this is that at home I run a single 40” 4K screen, but often split it up into four virtual screens, each displaying a workspace on which my windows are automatically arranged. Of course xmonad has a &lt;a href=&quot;http://hackage.haskell.org/package/xmonad-contrib-0.15/docs/XMonad-Layout-LayoutScreens.html&quot;&gt;module&lt;/a&gt; for that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://robm.github.io/dzen/&quot;&gt;dzen&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/brndnmtthws/conky&quot;&gt;conky&lt;/a&gt; function as a simple enough status bar for me. My entire conky config looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;out_to_console yes
update_interval 1
total_run_times 0

TEXT
${downspeed eth0} ${upspeed eth0} | $cpu% ${loadavg 1} ${loadavg 2} ${loadavg 3} $mem/$memmax | ${time %F %T}
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And gets piped straight into dzen2 with &lt;code&gt;conky | dzen2 -fn '-xos4-terminus-medium-r-normal-*-12-*-*-*-*-*-*-*' -bg '#000000' -fg '#ffffff' -p -e '' -x 1000 -w 920 -xs 1 -ta r&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One important feature for me is to make the terminal emit a beep sound once a job is done. This is done simply by adding a &lt;code&gt;\a&lt;/code&gt; character to the &lt;code&gt;PR_TITLEBAR&lt;/code&gt; variable in zsh, which is shown whenever a job is done. Of course I disable the actual beep sound by blacklisting the &lt;code&gt;pcspkr&lt;/code&gt; kernel module with &lt;code&gt;echo &quot;blacklist pcspkr&quot; &amp;gt; /etc/modprobe.d/nobeep.conf&lt;/code&gt;. Instead the sound gets turned into an urgency by urxvt’s &lt;code&gt;URxvt.urgentOnBell: true&lt;/code&gt; setting. Then xmonad has an urgency hook to capture this and I can automatically focus the currently urgent window with a key combination. In dzen I get the urgent windowspaces displayed with a nice and bright &lt;code&gt;#ff0000&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final result in all its glory on my Laptop:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://hookrace.net/public/linux-desktop/laptop.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://hookrace.net/public/linux-desktop/laptop_small.png&quot; alt=&quot;Laptop screenshot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hear that &lt;a href=&quot;https://i3wm.org/&quot;&gt;i3&lt;/a&gt; has become quite popular in the last years, but it requires more manual window alignment instead of specifying automated methods to do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I realize that there are also terminal multiplexers like &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tmux/tmux/wiki&quot;&gt;tmux&lt;/a&gt;, but I still require a few graphical applications, so in the end I never used them productively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;terminal-persistency&quot;&gt;Terminal Persistency&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to keep terminals alive I use &lt;a href=&quot;http://dtach.sourceforge.net/&quot;&gt;dtach&lt;/a&gt;, which is just the detach feature of screen. In order to make every terminal on my computer detachable I wrote a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/def-/tach/blob/master/tach&quot;&gt;small wrapper script&lt;/a&gt;. This means that even if I had to restart my X server I could keep all my terminals running just fine, both local and remote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;shell--programming&quot;&gt;Shell &amp;amp; Programming&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/bash/&quot;&gt;bash&lt;/a&gt; I use &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zsh.org/&quot;&gt;zsh&lt;/a&gt; as my shell for its huge number of features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a terminal emulator I found &lt;a href=&quot;http://software.schmorp.de/pkg/rxvt-unicode.html&quot;&gt;urxvt&lt;/a&gt; to be simple enough, support Unicode and 256 colors and has great performance. Another great feature is being able to run the urxvt client and daemon separately, so that even a large number of terminals barely takes up any memory (except for the scrollback buffer).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is only one font that looks absolutely clean and perfect to me: &lt;a href=&quot;http://terminus-font.sourceforge.net/&quot;&gt;Terminus&lt;/a&gt;. Since it’s a bitmap font everything is pixel perfect and renders extremely fast and at low CPU usage. In order to switch fonts on-demand in each terminal with &lt;code&gt;CTRL-WIN-[1-7]&lt;/code&gt; my ~/.Xdefaults contains:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;URxvt.font: -xos4-terminus-medium-r-normal-*-14-*-*-*-*-*-*-*
dzen2.font: -xos4-terminus-medium-r-normal-*-14-*-*-*-*-*-*-*

URxvt.keysym.C-M-1: command:\033]50;-xos4-terminus-medium-r-normal-*-12-*-*-*-*-*-*-*\007
URxvt.keysym.C-M-2: command:\033]50;-xos4-terminus-medium-r-normal-*-14-*-*-*-*-*-*-*\007
URxvt.keysym.C-M-3: command:\033]50;-xos4-terminus-medium-r-normal-*-18-*-*-*-*-*-*-*\007
URxvt.keysym.C-M-4: command:\033]50;-xos4-terminus-medium-r-normal-*-22-*-*-*-*-*-*-*\007
URxvt.keysym.C-M-5: command:\033]50;-xos4-terminus-medium-r-normal-*-24-*-*-*-*-*-*-*\007
URxvt.keysym.C-M-6: command:\033]50;-xos4-terminus-medium-r-normal-*-28-*-*-*-*-*-*-*\007
URxvt.keysym.C-M-7: command:\033]50;-xos4-terminus-medium-r-normal-*-32-*-*-*-*-*-*-*\007

URxvt.keysym.C-M-n: command:\033]10;#ffffff\007\033]11;#000000\007\033]12;#ffffff\007\033]706;#00ffff\007\033]707;#ffff00\007
URxvt.keysym.C-M-b: command:\033]10;#000000\007\033]11;#ffffff\007\033]12;#000000\007\033]706;#0000ff\007\033]707;#ff0000\007
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For programming and writing I use &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vim.org/&quot;&gt;Vim&lt;/a&gt; with syntax highlighting and &lt;a href=&quot;http://ctags.sourceforge.net/&quot;&gt;ctags&lt;/a&gt; for indexing, as well as a few terminal windows with grep, sed and the other usual suspects for search and manipulation. This is probably not at the same level of comfort as an IDE, but allows me more automation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One problem with Vim is that you get so used to its key mappings that you’ll want to use them everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.python.org/&quot;&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://nim-lang.org/&quot;&gt;Nim&lt;/a&gt; do well as scripting languages where the shell is not powerful enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;system-monitoring&quot;&gt;System Monitoring&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://hisham.hm/htop/&quot;&gt;htop&lt;/a&gt; (look at the background of that site, it’s a live view of the server that’s hosting it) works great for getting a quick overview of what the software is currently doing. &lt;a href=&quot;http://lm-sensors.org/&quot;&gt;lm_sensors&lt;/a&gt; allows monitoring the hardware temperatures, fans and voltages. &lt;a href=&quot;https://01.org/powertop/&quot;&gt;powertop&lt;/a&gt; is a great little tool by Intel to find power savings. &lt;a href=&quot;https://dev.yorhel.nl/ncdu&quot;&gt;ncdu&lt;/a&gt; lets you analyze disk usage interactively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://nmap.org/&quot;&gt;nmap&lt;/a&gt;, iptraf-ng, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tcpdump.org/&quot;&gt;tcpdump&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wireshark.org/&quot;&gt;Wireshark&lt;/a&gt; are essential tools for analyzing network problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are of course many more great tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;mails--synchronization&quot;&gt;Mails &amp;amp; Synchronization&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On my home server I have a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fetchmail.info/&quot;&gt;fetchmail&lt;/a&gt; daemon running for each email acccount that I have. Fetchmail just retrieves the incoming emails and invokes &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.procmail.org/&quot;&gt;procmail&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;#!/bin/sh&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; i in /home/deen/.fetchmail/*&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;FETCHMAILHOME&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$i&lt;/span&gt; /usr/bin/fetchmail -m &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'procmail -d %T'&lt;/span&gt; -d 60
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;done&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The configuration is as simple as it could be and waits for the server to inform us of fresh emails:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;poll imap.1und1.de protocol imap timeout 120 user &quot;dennis@felsin9.de&quot; password &quot;XXX&quot; folders INBOX keep ssl idle
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My &lt;code&gt;.procmailrc&lt;/code&gt; config contains a few rules to backup all mails and sort them into the correct directories, for example based on the mailing list id or from field in the mail header:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;MAILDIR=/home/deen/shared/Maildir
LOGFILE=$HOME/.procmaillog
LOGABSTRACT=no
VERBOSE=off
FORMAIL=/usr/bin/formail
NL=&quot;
&quot;

:0wc
* ! ? test -d /media/mailarchive/`date +%Y`
| mkdir -p /media/mailarchive/`date +%Y`

# Make backups of all mail received in format YYYY/YYYY-MM
:0c
/media/mailarchive/`date +%Y`/`date +%Y-%m`

:0
* ^From: .*(.*@.*.kit.edu|.*@.*.uka.de|.*@.*.uni-karlsruhe.de)
$MAILDIR/.uni/

:0
* ^list-Id:.*lists.kit.edu
$MAILDIR/.uni-ml/

[...]
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To send emails I use &lt;a href=&quot;https://marlam.de/msmtp/&quot;&gt;msmtp&lt;/a&gt;, which is also great to configure:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;account default
host smtp.1und1.de
tls on
tls_trust_file /etc/ssl/certs/ca-certificates.crt
auth on
from dennis@felsin9.de
user dennis@felsin9.de
password XXX

[...]
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But so far the emails are still on the server. My documents are all stored in a directory that I synchronize between all computers using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cis.upenn.edu/~bcpierce/unison/&quot;&gt;Unison&lt;/a&gt;. Think of Unison as a bidirectional interactive &lt;a href=&quot;https://rsync.samba.org/&quot;&gt;rsync&lt;/a&gt;. My emails are part of this documents directory and thus they end up on my desktop computers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This also means that while the emails reach my server immediately, I only fetch them on deman instead of getting instant notifications when an email comes in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From there I read the mails with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mutt.org/&quot;&gt;mutt&lt;/a&gt;, using the sidebar plugin to display my mail directories. The &lt;code&gt;/etc/mailcap&lt;/code&gt; file is essential to display non-plaintext mails containing HTML, Word or PDF:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;text/html;w3m -I %{charset} -T text/html; copiousoutput
application/msword; antiword %s; copiousoutput
application/pdf; pdftotext -layout /dev/stdin -; copiousoutput
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;news--communication&quot;&gt;News &amp;amp; Communication&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://newsboat.org/&quot;&gt;Newsboat&lt;/a&gt; is a nice little RSS/Atom feed reader in the terminal. I have it running on the server in a &lt;code&gt;tach&lt;/code&gt; session with about 150 feeds. Filtering feeds locally is also possible, for example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;ignore-article &quot;https://forum.ddnet.tw/feed.php&quot; &quot;title =~ \&quot;Map Testing •\&quot; or title =~ \&quot;Old maps •\&quot; or title =~ \&quot;Map Bugs •\&quot; or title =~ \&quot;Archive •\&quot; or title =~ \&quot;Waiting for mapper •\&quot; or title =~ \&quot;Other mods •\&quot; or title =~ \&quot;Fixes •\&quot;&quot;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use &lt;a href=&quot;https://irssi.org/&quot;&gt;Irssi&lt;/a&gt; the same way for communication via IRC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;calendar&quot;&gt;Calendar&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.roaringpenguin.com/products/remind&quot;&gt;remind&lt;/a&gt; is a calendar that can be used from the command line. Setting new reminders is done by editing the &lt;code&gt;rem&lt;/code&gt; files:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;# One time events
REM 2019-01-20 +90 Flight to China %b

# Recurring Holidays
REM 1 May +90 Holiday &quot;Tag der Arbeit&quot; %b
REM [trigger(easterdate(year(today()))-2)] +90 Holiday &quot;Karfreitag&quot; %b

# Time Change
REM Nov Sunday 1 --7 +90 Time Change (03:00 -&amp;gt; 02:00) %b
REM Apr Sunday 1 --7 +90 Time Change (02:00 -&amp;gt; 03:00) %b

# Birthdays
FSET birthday(x) &quot;'s &quot; + ord(year(trigdate())-x) + &quot; birthday is %b&quot;
REM 16 Apr +90 MSG Andreas[birthday(1994)]

# Sun
SET $LatDeg 49
SET $LatMin 19
SET $LatSec 49
SET $LongDeg -8
SET $LongMin -40
SET $LongSec -24

MSG Sun from [sunrise(trigdate())] to [sunset(trigdate())]
[...]
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately there is no Chinese Lunar calendar function in remind yet, so Chinese holidays can’t be calculated easily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use two aliases for remind:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;rem -m -b1 -q -g
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;to see a list of the next events in chronological order and&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;rem -m -b1 -q -cuc12 -w$(($(tput cols)+1)) | sed -e &quot;s/\f//g&quot; | less
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;to show a calendar fitting just the width of my terminal:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://hookrace.net/public/linux-desktop/remcal.png&quot; alt=&quot;remcal&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;dictionary&quot;&gt;Dictionary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tsdh/rdictcc&quot;&gt;rdictcc&lt;/a&gt; is a little known dictionary tool that uses the excellent dictionary files from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dict.cc/&quot;&gt;dict.cc&lt;/a&gt; and turns them into a local database:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;$ rdictcc rasch
====================[ A =&amp;gt; B ]====================
rasch:
    - apace
    - brisk [speedy]
    - cursory
    - in a timely manner
    - quick
    - quickly
    - rapid
    - rapidly
    - sharpish  [Br.]  [coll.]
    - speedily
    - speedy
    - swift
    - swiftly
rasch [gehen]:
    - smartly [quickly]
Rasch {n} [Zittergras-Segge]:
    - Alpine grass [Carex brizoides]
    - quaking grass sedge [Carex brizoides]
Rasch {m} [regional] [Putzrasch]:
    - scouring pad
====================[ B =&amp;gt; A ]====================
Rasch model:
    - Rasch-Modell {n}
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;writing-and-reading&quot;&gt;Writing and Reading&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a simple todo file containing my tasks, that is basically always sitting open in a Vim session. For work I also use the todo file as a “done” file so that I can later check what tasks I finished on each day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For writing documents, letters and presentations I use &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.latex-project.org/&quot;&gt;LaTeX&lt;/a&gt; for its superior typesetting. A simple letter in German format can be set like this for example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-latex&quot; data-lang=&quot;latex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;\documentclass&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;[paper = a4, fromalign = right]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;scrlttr2&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;\usepackage&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;german&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;\usepackage&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;eurosym&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;\usepackage&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;[utf8]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;inputenc&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;\setlength&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;\parskip&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;}{&lt;/span&gt;6pt&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;\setlength&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;\parindent&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;}{&lt;/span&gt;0pt&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;\setkomavar&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;fromname&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;}{&lt;/span&gt;Dennis Felsing&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;\setkomavar&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;fromaddress&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;}{&lt;/span&gt;Meine Str. 1&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;\\&lt;/span&gt;69181 Leimen&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;\setkomavar&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;subject&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;}{&lt;/span&gt;Titel&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;\setkomavar*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;enclseparator&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;}{&lt;/span&gt;Anlagen&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;\makeatletter&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;\@&lt;/span&gt;setplength&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;refvpos&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;}{&lt;/span&gt;89mm&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;\makeatother&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;\begin&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;document&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;\begin&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;letter&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;Herr Soundso&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;\\&lt;/span&gt;Deine Str. 2&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;\\&lt;/span&gt;69121 Heidelberg&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;\opening&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;Sehr geehrter Herr Soundso,&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

Sie haben bei mir seit dem Bla Bla Bla.

Ich fordere Sie hiermit zu Bla Bla Bla auf.

&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;\closing&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;Mit freundlichen Grüßen&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;\end&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;letter&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;\end&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;document&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further example documents and presentations can be found over at &lt;a href=&quot;http://felsin9.de/nnis/research/&quot;&gt;my private site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To read PDFs &lt;a href=&quot;https://pwmt.org/projects/zathura/&quot;&gt;Zathura&lt;/a&gt; is fast, has Vim-like controls and even supports two different PDF backends: Poppler and MuPDF. &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.gnome.org/Apps/Evince&quot;&gt;Evince&lt;/a&gt; on the other hand is more full-featured for the cases where I encounter documents that Zathura doesn’t like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;graphical-editing&quot;&gt;Graphical Editing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gimp.org/&quot;&gt;GIMP&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://inkscape.org/&quot;&gt;Inkscape&lt;/a&gt; are easy choices for photo editing and interactive vector graphics respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In some cases &lt;a href=&quot;https://imagemagick.org/Usage/&quot;&gt;Imagemagick&lt;/a&gt; is good enough though and can be used straight from the command line and thus automated to edit images. Similarly &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.graphviz.org/&quot;&gt;Graphviz&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://sourceforge.net/projects/pgf/&quot;&gt;TikZ&lt;/a&gt; can be used to draw graphs and other diagrams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;web-browsing&quot;&gt;Web Browsing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a web browser I’ve always used &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/new/&quot;&gt;Firefox&lt;/a&gt; for its extensibility and low resource usage compared to Chrome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/5digits/dactyl&quot;&gt;Pentadactyl&lt;/a&gt; extension development stopped after Firefox switched to Chrome-style extensions entirely, so I don’t have satisfying Vim-like controls in my browser anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mpv.io/&quot;&gt;mpv&lt;/a&gt; with hardware decoding allows watching videos at 5% CPU load using the &lt;code&gt;vo=gpu&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;hwdec=vaapi&lt;/code&gt; config settings. &lt;code&gt;audio-channels=2&lt;/code&gt; in mpv seems to give me clearer downmixing to my stereo speakers / headphones than what PulseAudio does by default. A great little feature is exiting with &lt;code&gt;Shift-Q&lt;/code&gt; instead of just &lt;code&gt;Q&lt;/code&gt; to save the playback location. When watching with someone with another native tongue you can use &lt;code&gt;--secondary-sid=&lt;/code&gt; to show two subtitles at once, the primary at the bottom, the secondary at the top of the screen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My wirelss mouse can easily be made into a remote control with mpv with a small &lt;code&gt;~/.config/mpv/input.conf&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;MOUSE_BTN5 run &quot;mixer&quot; &quot;pcm&quot; &quot;-2&quot;
MOUSE_BTN6 run &quot;mixer&quot; &quot;pcm&quot; &quot;+2&quot;
MOUSE_BTN1 cycle sub-visibility
MOUSE_BTN7 add chapter -1
MOUSE_BTN8 add chapter 1
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://rg3.github.io/youtube-dl/&quot;&gt;youtube-dl&lt;/a&gt; works great for watching videos hosted online, best quality can be achieved with &lt;code&gt;-f bestvideo+bestaudio/best --all-subs --embed-subs&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a music player &lt;a href=&quot;http://moc.daper.net/&quot;&gt;MOC&lt;/a&gt; hasn’t been actively developed for a while, but it’s still a simple player that plays every format conceivable, including the strangest Chiptune formats. In the AUR there is a &lt;a href=&quot;https://aur.archlinux.org/packages/moc-pulse/&quot;&gt;patch&lt;/a&gt; adding PulseAudio support as well. Even with the CPU clocked down to 800 MHz MOC barely uses 1-2% of a single CPU core.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://hookrace.net/public/linux-desktop/moc.png&quot; alt=&quot;moc&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My music collection sits on my home server so that I can access it from anywhere. It is mounted using &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/libfuse/sshfs&quot;&gt;SSHFS&lt;/a&gt; and automount in the &lt;code&gt;/etc/fstab/&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;root@server:/media/media  /mnt/media  fuse.sshfs noauto,x-systemd.automount,idmap=user,IdentityFile=/root/.ssh/id_rsa,allow_other,reconnect 0 0
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;cross-platform-building&quot;&gt;Cross-Platform Building&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Linux is great to build packages for any major operating system except Linux itself! In the beginning I used &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.qemu.org/&quot;&gt;QEMU&lt;/a&gt; to with an old Debian, Windows and Mac OS X VM to build for these platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nowadays I switched to using chroot for the old Debian distribution (for maximum Linux compatibility), &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mingw.org/&quot;&gt;MinGW&lt;/a&gt; to cross-compile for Windows and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tpoechtrager/osxcross&quot;&gt;OSXCross&lt;/a&gt; to cross-compile for Mac OS X.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The script used to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ddnet/ddnet-scripts/blob/master/ddnet-release.sh&quot;&gt;build DDNet&lt;/a&gt; as well as the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ddnet/ddnet-scripts/blob/master/ddnet-lib-update.sh&quot;&gt;instructions for updating library builds&lt;/a&gt; are based on this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;backups&quot;&gt;Backups&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As usual, we nearly forgot about backups. Even if this is the last chapter, it should not be an afterthought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wrote &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/def-/rrb/blob/master/rrb&quot;&gt;rrb&lt;/a&gt; (reverse rsync backup) 10 years ago to wrap rsync so that I only need to give the backup server root SSH rights to the computers that it is backing up. Surprisingly rrb needed 0 changes in the last 10 years, even though I kept using it the entire time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The backups are stored straight on the filesystem. Incremental backups are implemented using hard links (&lt;code&gt;--link-dest&lt;/code&gt;). A simple &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/def-/rrb/blob/master/config.example&quot;&gt;config&lt;/a&gt; defines how long backups are kept, which defaults to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;KEEP_RULES&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=(&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;se&quot;&gt;\&lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;7&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;7&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;se&quot;&gt;\ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# One backup a day for the last 7 days&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;31&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;8&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;se&quot;&gt;\ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# 8 more backups for the last month&lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;365&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;11&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;se&quot;&gt;\ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# 11 more backups for the last year&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;1825&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;4&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;se&quot;&gt;\ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# 4 more backups for the last 5 years&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since some of my computers don’t have a static IP / DNS entry and I still want to back them up using rrb I use a reverse SSH tunnel (as a systemd service) for them:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-cfg&quot; data-lang=&quot;cfg&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;[Unit]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;Description&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;Reverse SSH Tunnel&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;After&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;network.target&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;[Service]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;ExecStart&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;/usr/bin/ssh -N -R 27276:localhost:22 -o &quot;ExitOnForwardFailure yes&quot; server&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;KillMode&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;process&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;Restart&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;always&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;[Install]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;WantedBy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;multi-user.target&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now the server can reach the client through &lt;code&gt;ssh -p 27276 localhost&lt;/code&gt; while the tunnel is running to perform the backup, or in &lt;code&gt;.ssh/config&lt;/code&gt; format:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;Host cr-remote
  HostName localhost
  Port 27276
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While talking about SSH hacks, sometimes a server is not easily reachable thanks to some bad routing. In that case you can route the SSH connection through another server to get better routing, in this case going through the USA to reach my Chinese server which had not been reliably reachable from Germany for a few weeks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;Host chn.ddnet.tw
  ProxyCommand ssh -q usa.ddnet.tw nc -q0 chn.ddnet.tw 22
  Port 22
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading my random collection of tools. I probably forgot many programs that I use so naturally every day that I don’t even think about them anymore. Let’s see how stable my software setup stays in the next years. If you have any questions, feel free to get in touch with me at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:dennis@felsin9.de&quot;&gt;dennis@felsin9.de&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments on &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19253072&quot;&gt;Hacker News&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 09:39:52 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>def-</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://hookrace.net/blog/linux-desktop-setup/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Running a Bakery on Emacs and PostgreSQL</title>
<link>https://bofh.org.uk/2019/02/25/baking-with-emacs/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://bofh.org.uk/2019/02/25/baking-with-emacs/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Just over a year ago now, I finally opened the bakery I’d been dreaming of for years. It’s been a big change in my life, from spending all my time sat in front of a computer, to spending most of it making actual stuff. And stuff that makes people happy, at that. It’s been a huge change, but I can’t think of a single job change that’s ever made me as happy as this one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the big changes that came with going pro was that suddenly I was having to work out how much stuff I needed to mix to fill the orders I needed. On the face of it, this is really simple, just work out how much dough you need, then work out what quantities to mix to make that much dough. Easy. You can do it with a pencil and paper. Or, in traditional bakers’ fashion, by scrawling with your finger on a floured work bench.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that’s how I coped for a few weeks early on. But I kept making mistakes, which makes for an inconsistent product (bread is very forgiving, you have to work quite hard to make something that isn’t bread, but consistency &lt;em&gt;matters&lt;/em&gt;). I needed to automate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d been on one of Bread Matters’ “Baking for a Living” courses and as part of the course materials had received a copy of a spreadsheet that could be used to go from a list of orders to a list of ingredients to mix alongside accurate costings and other useful bits and bobs. It was great and certainly opened my eyes to the possibilities for automation of this part of the job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then I tried to add a new recipe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spreadsheets aren’t my favourite computational model so maybe it was just my lack of experience with them, but adding a new recipe was like pulling teeth; lots of tedious copying, pasting and repetition of formulae. It just seemed wrong, especially as the underlying computations were so straightforward (ish). There had to be a better way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key insight is that a bakery formula is so cliched that it can be represented as data. Here’s the formula for seedy malt loaves:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;recipe&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;ingredient&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;quantity&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Small Seedy Malt&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Seedy malt dough&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;.61 kg&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Large Seedy Malt&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Seedy malt dough&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;.92 kg&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;Of course, that’s not the full set of formulae, because it doesn’t tell you how to make ‘Seedy malt dough’, but that’s just another formula, which consists of flour, water, starter, salt and a multiseed ‘soaker’, where the starter and the soaker are the results of other formulae, which are (finally) made from basic ingredients. I did consider reaching for the object oriented hammer at this point, but thought that I might be able to do everything I needed without leaving SQL. It was relatively straightforward to move the shape of the calculations in the Bread Matters spreadsheet into my database schema, the only real sticking point being the recursive nature of the formulae, but it turns out that recursive queries are a thing in modern SQL, albeit a little tricky to get absolutely right first time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re curious about the details of the schema, you can find it in my &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pdcawley/bakehouse&quot;&gt;github repo&lt;/a&gt; for the bakery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So now, a few days before a bake, I’d setup my &lt;code&gt;production_order&lt;/code&gt; table with the orders for the bake, and run a query on the &lt;code&gt;production_list&lt;/code&gt; view to find out what I needed to mix when. And all was great. Well, sort of. I had to add a bit extra onto the quantities in the initial starter mix to allow for the bits that get stuck to the bowl and lost to the final dough, and it was all very well until I wanted to bake two days in a row (a bake is a two day process from mixing the starters on a Wednesday evening, through mixing, fermenting and shaping on Thursday to baking the resulting loaves at four on Friday morning). But, vitally, it was much, much easier to add and adjust formulae, and the limitations were no worse than the limitations of the spreadsheet. All was well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s the nature of business that you need to keep records. How much got baked? How much sold? Did we clean the floor? Were there any accidents? What sort? How do we prevent them next time? The list is endless. It all needs to be recorded, for both legal and pragmatic reasons. So I started a day book. This is just an .org file. Every day I come into the bakery, I run &lt;code&gt;org-capture&lt;/code&gt; and I get a template for the day’s entry in the daybook, which I fill in as the day goes on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the features of org-mode is &lt;code&gt;org-babel&lt;/code&gt;, a literate programming environment, which lets me write something like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-org&quot; data-lang=&quot;org&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;#+begin_src &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;sql&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;SELECT&lt;/span&gt; ingredient, quantity
  &lt;span&gt;FROM&lt;/span&gt; bakehouse.production_list
 &lt;span&gt;WHERE&lt;/span&gt; work_date &lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;'today'&lt;/span&gt;;
&lt;span&gt;#+end_src&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and then, with the cursor somewhere in the code block, hit &lt;code&gt;C-c C-c&lt;/code&gt; whereupon Emacs will run that SQL against the bakery database and populate a table like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;ingredient&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;quantity&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Old starter&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Water&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2.08&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;White flour&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2.6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;…&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;…&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;If that were all org-mode did to assist, it’d be awesome enough, but the queries I make are a little more complex than that, the current version of the database understands about dates and can cope with overlapping bakes, but all that makes the queries a little more complex. Org-mode helps with that too, because I can file away snippets of code in a ‘library of babel’ and just reference them from the daybook. And I can set arbitrary variables at any point in the hierarchy of the document.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I have a bit of code in my emacs config that tweaks the day’s entry in a daybook like so:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-emacs-lisp&quot; data-lang=&quot;emacs-lisp&quot;&gt;  (defun pdc//in-bakery-daybook? ()
    &lt;span&gt;&quot;Are we in the bakery daybook?&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
    (&lt;span&gt;equal&lt;/span&gt; (&lt;span&gt;buffer-name&lt;/span&gt;) &lt;span&gt;&quot;CAPTURE-loafery-daybook.org&quot;&lt;/span&gt;))

  (defun pdc/set-daybook-entry-properties ()
    &lt;span&gt;&quot;Set the properties we rely on in our boilerplated daybook queries&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
    (save-excursion
      (while (not (&lt;span&gt;looking-at&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;&quot;*+ [[:digit:]]\\{4\\}\\(-[[:digit:]]\\{2\\}\\)\\{2\\}&quot;&lt;/span&gt;))
        (org-up-element))
      (let ((entry-date (first (s-split &lt;span&gt;&quot; &quot;&lt;/span&gt; (org-entry-get (&lt;span&gt;point&lt;/span&gt;) &lt;span&gt;&quot;ITEM&quot;&lt;/span&gt;)))))
        (org-entry-put
         (&lt;span&gt;point&lt;/span&gt;)
         &lt;span&gt;&quot;header-args+&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
         (&lt;span&gt;format&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;&quot;:var work_date=\&quot;'%s'\&quot;&quot;&lt;/span&gt; entry-date)))
      (org-babel-execute-subtree)))

  (defun pdc/org-capture-before-finalize-daybook-entry ()
    (when (pdc//in-bakery-daybook?)
      (pdc/set-daybook-entry-properties)))

  (add-hook &lt;span&gt;'org-capture-before-finalize-hook&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span&gt;#'&lt;/span&gt;pdc/org-capture-before-finalize-daybook-entry)&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It won’t win any code beauty contests, but it does the job of setting a &lt;code&gt;work_date&lt;/code&gt; variable for the day’s entry and running any code in the subtree as part of the capture process. The capture template has lines like &lt;code&gt;#+call:mixes()&lt;/code&gt;, which call the stored code snippets, that reference the variable set in the current subtree and so make the query for the right day. This means that all I have to do to know what I should be doing when I get into the bakehouse is to run an org-capture and check the resulting entry in my daybook. Provided, that is, that I’ve added the appropriate rows to the database.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;next-steps&quot;&gt;Next steps&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The software isn’t done, of course, no software ever is. But it’s good enough that it’s been managing my mixes without a hitch for the last few months, telling me what to pack for which customer and generally removing the need to work anything out with a pencil and paper. It’s nowhere near as mature or capable of commercial production management software, but it fits me. I understand what it does and why, how it does it, the limitations it has and how to work around them. When it becomes annoying enough, I might sit down and work out how to fix it, but I’ll do that when I’m in the right frame of mind. My current list of niggles looks something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;&lt;dt&gt;Accounting&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;The database already knows how to do costings based on raw ingredient costs etc, but I should probably be able to use it to keep my books as well, using &lt;code&gt;org-ledger&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Parametric recipes&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;At a certain point, it becomes easier to mix a ‘stiff starter’ in my mixer than it is to just mix the usual wet starter by hand. This breakpoint comes at around 3kg of flour. Right now, I manage this by looking at the mixes for my starters and, if it looks like a lot, changing the order to use 2-stage versions of the formulae and running the query again. I think it should be possible to automate this through a more sophisticated query, but I need to work that out.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Better scheduling&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;things get weird if a batch of dough would be more than I can mix in a single go. Right now there are other physical limitations that mean that I simply can’t make that much bread anyway, but once I get a few more bannetons and racks, this will become a much more pressing issue.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Order management&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Right now, I manage orders through Postico talking to the database, which is okay, but a little frustrating in places. An autocompleting environment for orders within emacs would be a much neater way to manage things.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;putting-the-personal-in-personal-computing&quot;&gt;Putting the personal in personal computing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Computers are amazing. They are versatile tools even if you don’t know how to program them, because there’s almost always an app for what you want, or something close enough that you cant work around its infelicities. It’s quite remarkable the things that folks can do with their kit with no programming skill at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But… learn to program, and a whole other vista of possibility opens up to you. With good programmable tooling you’re only really limited by your skill and understanding. Instead of accommodating yourself to your software, you can accommodate your software to you, and make the right functionality trade-offs for you. There’s a brilliant commercial piece of music looping sofware I use that could be massively more brilliant if there were a way of picking up the tempo automatically from the first recorded loop - it would free me from having to sing to a click and generally make the whole process easier. The developers have other (understandable) priorities, like porting the app to windows. And they’re not wrong to do so. There were folk clamoring for a windows version, and if a developer isn’t making money from a commercial application, then development will stop. I’m definitely not complaining, the feature is not so dramatically necessary that I’m prepared to spend the time learning how to do real time music programming in order to implement it, but if I want software to dance to &lt;em&gt;my&lt;/em&gt; tune then doing it myself is the only way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So… choose tools that let you program them. I choose emacs and PostgreSQL, you might choose vim and SQLite or Atom and a NoSQL database, or you might just live in your Smalltalk image. Once you start to see your computing environment as truly soft and malleable, you can do amazing things, assisted by a computer that is truly &lt;em&gt;yours&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 09:06:18 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>flocial</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://bofh.org.uk/2019/02/25/baking-with-emacs/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Universal Binaries Using WASM</title>
<link>https://github.com/wasmerio/wasmer</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/wasmerio/wasmer</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;Box-body p-6&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;markdown-body entry-content&quot; itemprop=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://wasmer.io&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/wasmerio/wasmer/master/logo.png&quot; alt=&quot;Wasmer logo&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://circleci.com/gh/wasmerio/wasmer/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/d485b1e206b858beff9b7fa0c2117d9c7e69fc05/68747470733a2f2f696d672e736869656c64732e696f2f636972636c6563692f70726f6a6563742f6769746875622f7761736d6572696f2f7761736d65722f6d61737465722e737667&quot; alt=&quot;Build Status&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/circleci/project/github/wasmerio/wasmer/master.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/wasmerio/wasmer/blob/master/LICENSE&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/eb374d925576cf2f0cf67c18eaf31c3f5a257417/68747470733a2f2f696d672e736869656c64732e696f2f6769746875622f6c6963656e73652f7761736d6572696f2f7761736d65722e737667&quot; alt=&quot;License&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/license/wasmerio/wasmer.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://spectrum.chat/wasmer&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/3cc3d27f23a2c3948de24fc02c58bc576655d621/68747470733a2f2f77697468737065637472756d2e6769746875622e696f2f62616467652f62616467652e737667&quot; alt=&quot;Join the Wasmer Community&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://withspectrum.github.io/badge/badge.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://wasmer.io/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Wasmer&lt;/a&gt; is a standalone JIT WebAssembly runtime, aiming to be fully compatible with Emscripten, Rust and Go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Install Wasmer with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
curl https://get.wasmer.io -sSfL &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; sh
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NEW ✨&lt;/strong&gt;: You can now embed Wasmer in your Rust application, check our &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/wasmerio/wasmer-rust-example&quot;&gt;example repo&lt;/a&gt; to see how!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Usage&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wasmer can execute both the standard binary format (&lt;code&gt;.wasm&lt;/code&gt;) and the text format defined by the WebAssembly reference interpreter (&lt;code&gt;.wat&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once installed, you will be able to run any WebAssembly files (&lt;em&gt;including nginx and Lua!&lt;/em&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt; Run Lua&lt;/span&gt;
wasmer run examples/lua.wasm

&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt; Run nginx&lt;/span&gt;
wasmer run examples/nginx/nginx.wasm -- -p examples/nginx -c nginx.conf
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Code Structure&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wasmer is structured into different directories:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/wasmerio/wasmer/blob/master/src&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;src&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: code related to the Wasmer executable itself&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/wasmerio/wasmer/blob/master/lib&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;lib&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: modularized libraries that Wasmer uses under the hood&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/wasmerio/wasmer/blob/master/examples&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;examples&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: some useful examples to getting started with Wasmer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Dependencies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building Wasmer requires &lt;a href=&quot;https://rustup.rs/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;rustup&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To build on Windows, download and run &lt;a href=&quot;https://win.rustup.rs/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;rustup-init.exe&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; then follow the onscreen instructions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To build on other systems, run:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
curl https://sh.rustup.rs -sSf &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; sh
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Other dependencies&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please select your operating system:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;macOS&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have &lt;a href=&quot;https://brew.sh/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Homebrew&lt;/a&gt; installed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
brew install cmake
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or, in case you have &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.macports.org/install.php&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;MacPorts&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
sudo port install cmake
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Debian-based Linuxes&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
sudo apt install cmake
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Windows (MSVC)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Windows support is &lt;em&gt;highly experimental&lt;/em&gt;. Only simple Wasm programs may be run, and no syscalls are allowed. This means nginx and Lua do not work on Windows. See &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/wasmerio/wasmer/issues/176&quot;&gt;this issue&lt;/a&gt; regarding Emscripten syscall polyfills for Windows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Install &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.python.org/downloads/release/python-2714/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Python for Windows&lt;/a&gt;. The Windows x86-64 MSI installer is fine. Make sure to enable &quot;Add python.exe to Path&quot; during installation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Install &lt;a href=&quot;https://git-scm.com/download/win&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Git for Windows&lt;/a&gt;. Allow it to add &lt;code&gt;git.exe&lt;/code&gt; to your PATH (default settings for the installer are fine).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Install &lt;a href=&quot;https://cmake.org/download/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;CMake&lt;/a&gt;. Ensure CMake is in your PATH.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Building&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wasmer is built with &lt;a href=&quot;https://crates.io/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Cargo&lt;/a&gt;, the Rust package manager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt; checkout code&lt;/span&gt;
git clone https://github.com/wasmerio/wasmer.git
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;cd&lt;/span&gt; wasmer

&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt; install tools&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt; make sure that `python` is accessible.&lt;/span&gt;
cargo install --path &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Testing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/wasmerio/wasmer/tree/master/lib/spectests/spectests&quot;&gt;spec tests&lt;/a&gt; we can ensure 100% compatibility with the WebAssembly spec test suite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tests can be run with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you need to regenerate the Rust tests from the spec tests you can run:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
make spectests
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also run integration tests with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
make integration-tests
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Benchmarking&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Benchmarks can be run with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
cargo bench --all
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Roadmap&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wasmer is an open project guided by strong principles, aiming to be modular, flexible and fast. It is open to the community to help set its direction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below are some of the goals of this project (in order of priority):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Architecture&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you would like to know how Wasmer works under the hood, please see &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/wasmerio/wasmer/blob/master/ARCHITECTURE.md&quot;&gt;ARCHITECTURE.md&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wasmer is primarily distributed under the terms of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://opensource.org/licenses/MIT&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;MIT license&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/wasmerio/wasmer/blob/master/LICENSE&quot;&gt;LICENSE&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/wasmerio/wasmer/blob/master/ATTRIBUTIONS.md&quot;&gt;ATTRIBUTIONS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 06:39:04 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>grey-area</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars1.githubusercontent.com/u/44205449?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>wasmerio/wasmer</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/wasmerio/wasmer</og:url>
<og:description>Universal Binaries Powered by WebAssembly. Contribute to wasmerio/wasmer development by creating an account on GitHub.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/wasmerio/wasmer</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>How the Varroa Mite’s True Diet Was Discovered</title>
<link>https://entomologytoday.org/2019/02/21/inside-look-how-varroa-mite-diet-discovered/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://entomologytoday.org/2019/02/21/inside-look-how-varroa-mite-diet-discovered/</guid>
<description>&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_10804&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; readability=&quot;39&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://entomologytoday.org/2019/02/21/inside-look-how-varroa-mite-diet-discovered/lt-sem-bee-with-mite/&quot;&gt;&lt;img aria-describedby=&quot;caption-attachment-10804&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;10804&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://entomologytoday.org/2019/02/21/inside-look-how-varroa-mite-diet-discovered/lt-sem-bee-with-mite/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/entomologytoday.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/LT-SEM-bee-with-mite.jpg?fit=1000%2C747&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1000,747&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;LT-SEM bee with mite&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;In this colorized image of a honey bee, taken via low-temperature scanning electron microscope, a &amp;lt;em&amp;gt;Varroa&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt; mite (arrow) can be seen tucked between the bee’s abdominal segments. (Photo credit: USDA-ARS, Electron and Confocal Microscopy Unit, Beltsville, Maryland)&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/entomologytoday.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/LT-SEM-bee-with-mite.jpg?fit=390%2C291&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/entomologytoday.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/LT-SEM-bee-with-mite.jpg?fit=878%2C656&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-10804 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/entomologytoday.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/LT-SEM-bee-with-mite.jpg?resize=878%2C656&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; alt=&quot;LT-SEM bee with mite&quot; width=&quot;878&quot; height=&quot;656&quot; srcset=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/entomologytoday.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/LT-SEM-bee-with-mite.jpg?w=1000&amp;amp;ssl=1 1000w, https://i2.wp.com/entomologytoday.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/LT-SEM-bee-with-mite.jpg?resize=390%2C291&amp;amp;ssl=1 390w, https://i2.wp.com/entomologytoday.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/LT-SEM-bee-with-mite.jpg?resize=768%2C574&amp;amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i2.wp.com/entomologytoday.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/LT-SEM-bee-with-mite.jpg?resize=107%2C80&amp;amp;ssl=1 107w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 878px) 100vw, 878px&quot; data-recalc-dims=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;caption-attachment-10804&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;In this colorized image of a honey bee, taken via low-temperature scanning electron microscope, a &lt;em&gt;Varroa&lt;/em&gt; mite (arrow) can be seen tucked between the bee’s abdominal segments. (Photo credit: USDA-ARS, Electron and Confocal Microscopy Unit, Beltsville, Maryland)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;By Samuel Ramsey, Ph.D., Ron Ochoa, Ph.D., Joe Mowery, Chris Pooley, Connor Gulbronson, Ph.D., and Gary Bauchan, Ph.D.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Varroa destructor&lt;/em&gt;, a mite that feeds on honey bees, is the greatest single driver of the global honey bee health decline. For years, scientists and bee keepers were told that the &lt;em&gt;Varroa&lt;/em&gt; mite feeds on hemolymph (the bee’s blood) based on scientific research done long ago. However, for our research team led by Samuel Ramsey, Ph.D., this did not make sense, as the mite’s digestive system and mouthparts just did not seem like they were structured properly for blood feeding. Their closest evolutionary relatives were not blood feeders either. As pointed out by insect-rearing expert Allen Cohen, Ph.D., even their excrement was all wrong for them to be blood feeders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, how and on what exactly do these mites feed? Our discovery is documented in &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1818371116&quot;&gt;a paper published in late January in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ramsey, then a Ph.D. student of Dennis vanEngelsdorp, Ph.D., at the University of Maryland, College Park, began his inquiry with a simple question: Are &lt;em&gt;Varroa&lt;/em&gt; mites feeding in only one spot? If the mites can feed anywhere on honey bees (&lt;em&gt;Apis mellifera&lt;/em&gt;) like a tick can on a person, then they are likely feeding on a tissue available all over the bee’s body (like hemolymph). However, if the mites feed only in one spot, maybe they are feeding on a tissue specific to that location. Out of 104 observations, the mites on adult bees were only found underneath the abdominal plates of their host. Ramsey considered that this might be their feeding site but knew he would need some help to prove it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This led Ramsey to the office of Ron Ochoa, Ph.D., research entomologist at the Systematic Entomology Lab and the Electron and Confocal Microscopy Unit (ECMU) of the U.S. Department of Agriculture’s Agricultural Research Service (USDA-ARS) in Beltsville, Maryland, and the leading mite expert at the USDA-ARS. In addition, to the idea that &lt;em&gt;Varroa&lt;/em&gt; mites only feed on the hemolymph of developing larvae and pupae, researchers were questioning whether the mites feed on adult bees at all. Some had already concluded that feeding only occurs on immature bees because they were never seen feeding on adult bees and because we have long been referring to the life stage of mites found on adult bees as “phoretic,” a term that denotes a nonfeeding stage that uses another organism as a mode of transit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gary Bauchan, Ph.D., director of the ECMU, Ochoa, and Ramsey used liquid nitrogen to instantly freeze honey bees that had mites in the region Ramsey proposed feeding was occurring. The exact position of the mites on the honey bees was imaged in a low-temperature scanning electron microscope (LT-SEM). The frozen bees were then removed from the LT-SEM and the mites carefully detached from the bees. During this process, Ramsey monitored Ochoa’s exposure time to the liquid nitrogen to avoid burning himself while he removed the mites from the frozen bees—a manual process that had to be done in approximately 10 seconds. The bees were then returned to the LT-SEM and the location where the mite was located was imaged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mite presses itself so tightly to the soft membrane between the bee’s abdominal plates that it leaves a distinct impression of its legs and palps and a mouth-shaped wound in the membrane. Additionally, at this feeding site the ambulacra (foot pads) from the front legs remained stuck to the bees’ membrane, allowing us to quickly orient ourselves to the positioning of the mite’s body relative to the bee’s. We repeated this procedure 10 times to prove this was where the mites were feeding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_10806&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; readability=&quot;39&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://entomologytoday.org/2019/02/21/inside-look-how-varroa-mite-diet-discovered/lt-sem-mite-wound-on-bee/&quot;&gt;&lt;img aria-describedby=&quot;caption-attachment-10806&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;10806&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://entomologytoday.org/2019/02/21/inside-look-how-varroa-mite-diet-discovered/lt-sem-mite-wound-on-bee/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/entomologytoday.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/LT-SEM-mite-wound-on-bee.jpg?fit=1000%2C735&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1000,735&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;LT-SEM mite wound on bee&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;In this colorized image taken via low-temperature scanning electron microscope, a &amp;lt;em&amp;gt;Varroa&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt; mite’s impression left on the abdominal wall of a honey bee is visible. White arrows identify foot pads of the mite that remained attached following removal of the mite. The black arrow identifies the mite’s feeding site. (Photo credit: USDA-ARS, Electron and Confocal Microscopy Unit, Beltsville, Maryland) &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/entomologytoday.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/LT-SEM-mite-wound-on-bee.jpg?fit=390%2C287&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/entomologytoday.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/LT-SEM-mite-wound-on-bee.jpg?fit=878%2C645&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-10806 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/entomologytoday.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/LT-SEM-mite-wound-on-bee.jpg?resize=878%2C645&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; alt=&quot;LT-SEM mite wound on bee&quot; width=&quot;878&quot; height=&quot;645&quot; srcset=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/entomologytoday.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/LT-SEM-mite-wound-on-bee.jpg?w=1000&amp;amp;ssl=1 1000w, https://i0.wp.com/entomologytoday.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/LT-SEM-mite-wound-on-bee.jpg?resize=390%2C287&amp;amp;ssl=1 390w, https://i0.wp.com/entomologytoday.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/LT-SEM-mite-wound-on-bee.jpg?resize=768%2C564&amp;amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/entomologytoday.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/LT-SEM-mite-wound-on-bee.jpg?resize=109%2C80&amp;amp;ssl=1 109w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 878px) 100vw, 878px&quot; data-recalc-dims=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;caption-attachment-10806&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;In this colorized image taken via low-temperature scanning electron microscope, a &lt;em&gt;Varroa&lt;/em&gt; mite’s impression left on the abdominal wall of a honey bee is visible. White arrows identify foot pads of the mite that remained attached following removal of the mite. The black arrow identifies the mite’s feeding site. (Photo credit: USDA-ARS, Electron and Confocal Microscopy Unit, Beltsville, Maryland)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A longitudinal section via freeze fracture directly through the bee and its attached mite confirmed in detail that &lt;em&gt;Varroa&lt;/em&gt;‘s relatively short mouthparts (200 microns) come to rest just inside of the bee, which is an area surrounded by fat body tissue and hemolymph, leaving us with the conclusion that the mites are feeding on adult bees. It further suggested to us that the mites could be feeding on a nutrient-dense organ called the fat body, which is analogous to the mammalian liver.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_10805&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; readability=&quot;39&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://entomologytoday.org/2019/02/21/inside-look-how-varroa-mite-diet-discovered/lt-sem-cross-section-of-mite-on-bee/&quot;&gt;&lt;img aria-describedby=&quot;caption-attachment-10805&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;10805&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://entomologytoday.org/2019/02/21/inside-look-how-varroa-mite-diet-discovered/lt-sem-cross-section-of-mite-on-bee/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://i1.wp.com/entomologytoday.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/LT-SEM-cross-section-of-mite-on-bee.jpg?fit=1000%2C754&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1000,754&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;LT-SEM cross-section of mite on bee&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;This longitudinal freeze-fracture image, taken via low-temperature scanning electron microscope, reveals a cross-section of a &amp;lt;em&amp;gt;Varroa&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt; mite (red) in between the abdominal segments of a honey bee. (Photo credit: USDA-ARS, Electron and Confocal Microscopy Unit, Beltsville, Maryland)&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://i1.wp.com/entomologytoday.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/LT-SEM-cross-section-of-mite-on-bee.jpg?fit=390%2C294&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://i1.wp.com/entomologytoday.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/LT-SEM-cross-section-of-mite-on-bee.jpg?fit=878%2C662&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-10805 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://i1.wp.com/entomologytoday.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/LT-SEM-cross-section-of-mite-on-bee.jpg?resize=878%2C662&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; alt=&quot;LT-SEM cross-section of mite on bee&quot; width=&quot;878&quot; height=&quot;662&quot; srcset=&quot;https://i1.wp.com/entomologytoday.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/LT-SEM-cross-section-of-mite-on-bee.jpg?w=1000&amp;amp;ssl=1 1000w, https://i1.wp.com/entomologytoday.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/LT-SEM-cross-section-of-mite-on-bee.jpg?resize=390%2C294&amp;amp;ssl=1 390w, https://i1.wp.com/entomologytoday.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/LT-SEM-cross-section-of-mite-on-bee.jpg?resize=768%2C579&amp;amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i1.wp.com/entomologytoday.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/LT-SEM-cross-section-of-mite-on-bee.jpg?resize=106%2C80&amp;amp;ssl=1 106w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 878px) 100vw, 878px&quot; data-recalc-dims=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;caption-attachment-10805&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;This longitudinal freeze-fracture image, taken via low-temperature scanning electron microscope, reveals a cross-section of a &lt;em&gt;Varroa&lt;/em&gt; mite (red) in between the abdominal segments of a honey bee. (Photo credit: USDA-ARS, Electron and Confocal Microscopy Unit, Beltsville, Maryland)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To determine if fat body was being consumed, the team had to get a closer look. Joe Mowery, support scientist at the ECMU, and Ramsey collected and prepared specimens by affixing the feeding mite onto the bee with cyanoacrylate glue prior to processing. Then, ultra-thin sections were obtained and studied using a transmission electron microscope (TEM). Clear evidence was discerned that mites were breaking down and removing fat body tissue via extra-oral digestion (and creating an entry point for colonies of microbes).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_10807&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; readability=&quot;37&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://entomologytoday.org/2019/02/21/inside-look-how-varroa-mite-diet-discovered/semi-thin-section-of-mite-on-bee/&quot;&gt;&lt;img aria-describedby=&quot;caption-attachment-10807&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;10807&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://entomologytoday.org/2019/02/21/inside-look-how-varroa-mite-diet-discovered/semi-thin-section-of-mite-on-bee/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://i1.wp.com/entomologytoday.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/semi-thin-section-of-mite-on-bee.jpg?fit=1000%2C552&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1000,552&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;semi-thin section of mite on bee&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;This semi-thin-section bright-field microscopy image shows a &amp;lt;em&amp;gt;Varroa&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt; mite in between the abdominal segments of a honey bee as well as the wound site and fat bodies. (Photo credit: USDA-ARS, Electron and Confocal Microscopy Unit, Beltsville, Maryland)&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://i1.wp.com/entomologytoday.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/semi-thin-section-of-mite-on-bee.jpg?fit=390%2C215&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://i1.wp.com/entomologytoday.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/semi-thin-section-of-mite-on-bee.jpg?fit=878%2C485&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-10807 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://i1.wp.com/entomologytoday.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/semi-thin-section-of-mite-on-bee.jpg?resize=878%2C485&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; alt=&quot;semi-thin section of mite on bee&quot; width=&quot;878&quot; height=&quot;485&quot; srcset=&quot;https://i1.wp.com/entomologytoday.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/semi-thin-section-of-mite-on-bee.jpg?w=1000&amp;amp;ssl=1 1000w, https://i1.wp.com/entomologytoday.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/semi-thin-section-of-mite-on-bee.jpg?resize=390%2C215&amp;amp;ssl=1 390w, https://i1.wp.com/entomologytoday.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/semi-thin-section-of-mite-on-bee.jpg?resize=768%2C424&amp;amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i1.wp.com/entomologytoday.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/semi-thin-section-of-mite-on-bee.jpg?resize=145%2C80&amp;amp;ssl=1 145w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 878px) 100vw, 878px&quot; data-recalc-dims=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;caption-attachment-10807&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;This semi-thin-section bright-field microscopy image shows a &lt;em&gt;Varroa&lt;/em&gt; mite in between the abdominal segments of a honey bee as well as the wound site and fat bodies. (Photo credit: USDA-ARS, Electron and Confocal Microscopy Unit, Beltsville, Maryland)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While observation and electron microscopy had produced clear evidence for fat body feeding, the research turned to Connor Gulbronson, Ph.D., Oak Ridge Institute for Science and Education post-doctoral fellow with the USDA-ARS Floral and Nursery Plants Research Unit (located within the ECMU), and his expertise in fluorescence and confocal microscopy to determine if fat body is the primary tissue consumed. Ramsey generated a diet containing two fluorescent biostains to label the bee’s hemolymph (yellow) and fat body (red). Gulbronson developed protocols to bleach the exoskeletons of the mites, allowing the internal structures to be imaged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bees with their glowing innards were then exposed to hungry &lt;em&gt;Varroa.&lt;/em&gt; The results were stunning. Gulbronson and Ramsey imaged mites with brilliantly red fluorescing digestive systems with very little discernible fluorescence in the yellow range. To be sure the biostains were staining the correct tissues, each bee was dissected and imaged as well for comparison with the fluorescence inside the mites. This work provided the clearest evidence yet that the mites were primarily consuming fat body tissue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_10808&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; readability=&quot;38&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://entomologytoday.org/2019/02/21/inside-look-how-varroa-mite-diet-discovered/fluorescent-mite-with-bee-fat-body-consumed/&quot;&gt;&lt;img aria-describedby=&quot;caption-attachment-10808&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;10808&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://entomologytoday.org/2019/02/21/inside-look-how-varroa-mite-diet-discovered/fluorescent-mite-with-bee-fat-body-consumed/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/entomologytoday.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/fluorescent-mite-with-bee-fat-body-consumed.jpg?fit=1000%2C1013&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1000,1013&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;fluorescent mite with bee fat body consumed&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;In this fluorescent microscopy image of a &amp;lt;em&amp;gt;Varroa&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt; mite, fat body consumed by the mite is labeled via red fluorescent stain inside the gut of a dissected mite. (USDA-ARS, Electron and Confocal Microscopy Unit, Beltsville, Maryland)&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/entomologytoday.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/fluorescent-mite-with-bee-fat-body-consumed.jpg?fit=390%2C395&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/entomologytoday.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/fluorescent-mite-with-bee-fat-body-consumed.jpg?fit=878%2C889&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-10808 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/entomologytoday.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/fluorescent-mite-with-bee-fat-body-consumed.jpg?resize=878%2C889&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; alt=&quot;fluorescent mite with bee fat body consumed&quot; width=&quot;878&quot; height=&quot;889&quot; srcset=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/entomologytoday.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/fluorescent-mite-with-bee-fat-body-consumed.jpg?w=1000&amp;amp;ssl=1 1000w, https://i2.wp.com/entomologytoday.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/fluorescent-mite-with-bee-fat-body-consumed.jpg?resize=390%2C395&amp;amp;ssl=1 390w, https://i2.wp.com/entomologytoday.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/fluorescent-mite-with-bee-fat-body-consumed.jpg?resize=768%2C778&amp;amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i2.wp.com/entomologytoday.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/fluorescent-mite-with-bee-fat-body-consumed.jpg?resize=79%2C80&amp;amp;ssl=1 79w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 878px) 100vw, 878px&quot; data-recalc-dims=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;caption-attachment-10808&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;In this fluorescent microscopy image of a &lt;em&gt;Varroa&lt;/em&gt; mite, fat body consumed by the mite is labeled via red fluorescent stain inside the gut of a dissected mite. (USDA-ARS, Electron and Confocal Microscopy Unit, Beltsville, Maryland)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All facets of this project had lined up pointing to one conclusion, but Ramsey wanted to be sure that this tissue clearly consumed in adult bees was the same tissue consumed in developing larvae and pupae. To determine this relationship, Ramsey developed a novel &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; rearing system, which mimicked the brood cells in which immature honey bees develop, and constructed decoy pupae to mimic the mite’s host. This allowed Ramsey and lab technicians Judith Joklik and David Lim to undertake the tedious task of feeding the mites diets composed of the different tissues of interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mites fed exclusively honey bee hemolymph starved quickly and produced very few eggs, no different from the control group given no food at all. However, mites fed exclusively fat body survived substantially better than all other treatments and produced far more eggs. This was the first time anyone had was able to rear &lt;em&gt;Varroa&lt;/em&gt; mites &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; without directly feeding on bees. These discoveries provided the study with the very last line of evidence needed to say conclusively that &lt;em&gt;Varroa&lt;/em&gt; are not blood-feeders but rather feed on fat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_10802&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; readability=&quot;36&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://entomologytoday.org/2019/02/21/inside-look-how-varroa-mite-diet-discovered/mite-feeding-setup/&quot;&gt;&lt;img aria-describedby=&quot;caption-attachment-10802&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;10802&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://entomologytoday.org/2019/02/21/inside-look-how-varroa-mite-diet-discovered/mite-feeding-setup/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/entomologytoday.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/mite-feeding-setup.jpg?fit=1000%2C501&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1000,501&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1.9&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;SM-G925V&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1465623457&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;4.3&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;200&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.016666666666667&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;mite feeding setup&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Researchers studying the feeding behavior of the &amp;lt;em&amp;gt;Varroa destructor&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt; mite devised an &amp;lt;em&amp;gt;in vitro&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt; rearing system that mimicked the brood cells of honey bees (&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;Apis mellifera&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;) with decoy pupae inside to feed the mites bee hemolymph and fat body tissue. (Photo originally published in Ramsey et al 2019, &amp;lt;em&amp;gt;Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;. Republished with permission.)&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/entomologytoday.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/mite-feeding-setup.jpg?fit=390%2C195&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/entomologytoday.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/mite-feeding-setup.jpg?fit=878%2C440&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-10802 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/entomologytoday.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/mite-feeding-setup.jpg?resize=878%2C440&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; alt=&quot;mite feeding setup&quot; width=&quot;878&quot; height=&quot;440&quot; srcset=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/entomologytoday.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/mite-feeding-setup.jpg?w=1000&amp;amp;ssl=1 1000w, https://i0.wp.com/entomologytoday.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/mite-feeding-setup.jpg?resize=390%2C195&amp;amp;ssl=1 390w, https://i0.wp.com/entomologytoday.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/mite-feeding-setup.jpg?resize=768%2C385&amp;amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/entomologytoday.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/mite-feeding-setup.jpg?resize=160%2C80&amp;amp;ssl=1 160w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 878px) 100vw, 878px&quot; data-recalc-dims=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;caption-attachment-10802&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Researchers studying the feeding behavior of the &lt;em&gt;Varroa destructor&lt;/em&gt; mite devised an &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; rearing system that mimicked the brood cells of honey bees (&lt;em&gt;Apis mellifera&lt;/em&gt;) with decoy pupae inside to feed the mites bee hemolymph and fat body tissue. (Photo originally published in Ramsey et al 2019, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences&lt;/em&gt;. Republished with permission.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Collectively, this multi-disciplinary approach of feeding assays, observational analysis, and various microscopy technologies generated a paradigm shift in our understanding of how, where, and what the &lt;em&gt;Varroa&lt;/em&gt; mite obtains when parasitizing host honey bees. This research provides a path forward for the development of strategies to controlling this major pest of honey bees worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_10803&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; readability=&quot;49&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://entomologytoday.org/2019/02/21/inside-look-how-varroa-mite-diet-discovered/usda-ars-varroa-team/&quot;&gt;&lt;img aria-describedby=&quot;caption-attachment-10803&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;10803&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://entomologytoday.org/2019/02/21/inside-look-how-varroa-mite-diet-discovered/usda-ars-varroa-team/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/entomologytoday.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/USDA-ARS-Varroa-team.jpg?fit=1000%2C532&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1000,532&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1.8&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;iPhone 7&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1503504056&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;3.99&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;32&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.041666666666667&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;USDA-ARS Varroa team&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Members of the Electron and Confocal Microscopy Unit (ECMU) &amp;lt;em&amp;gt;Varroa&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt; research team at the U.S. Department of Agriculture’s Agricultural Research Service (USDA-ARS). Standing (left to right): Chris Pooley, IT specialist; Gary Bauchan, ECMU director; Joe Mowery, transmission electron microscope specialist; and Connor Gulbronson, Ph.D., Oak Ridge Institute for Science and Education post-doctoral fellow. Sitting (left to right): Ron Ochoa, Ph.D., entomologist and acarologist, USDA-ARS Systematic Entomology Lab, and Samuel Ramsey, Ph.D., then a doctoral student at the University of Maryland. (Photo credit: USDA-ARS, Electron and Confocal Microscopy Unit, Beltsville, Maryland. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/entomologytoday.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/USDA-ARS-Varroa-team.jpg?fit=390%2C207&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/entomologytoday.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/USDA-ARS-Varroa-team.jpg?fit=878%2C467&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-10803 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/entomologytoday.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/USDA-ARS-Varroa-team.jpg?resize=878%2C467&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; alt=&quot;USDA-ARS Varroa team&quot; width=&quot;878&quot; height=&quot;467&quot; srcset=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/entomologytoday.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/USDA-ARS-Varroa-team.jpg?w=1000&amp;amp;ssl=1 1000w, https://i2.wp.com/entomologytoday.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/USDA-ARS-Varroa-team.jpg?resize=390%2C207&amp;amp;ssl=1 390w, https://i2.wp.com/entomologytoday.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/USDA-ARS-Varroa-team.jpg?resize=768%2C409&amp;amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i2.wp.com/entomologytoday.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/USDA-ARS-Varroa-team.jpg?resize=150%2C80&amp;amp;ssl=1 150w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 878px) 100vw, 878px&quot; data-recalc-dims=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;caption-attachment-10803&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Members of the Electron and Confocal Microscopy Unit (ECMU) &lt;em&gt;Varroa&lt;/em&gt; research team at the U.S. Department of Agriculture’s Agricultural Research Service (USDA-ARS). Standing (left to right): Chris Pooley, IT specialist; Gary Bauchan, ECMU director; Joe Mowery, transmission electron microscope specialist; and Connor Gulbronson, Ph.D., Oak Ridge Institute for Science and Education post-doctoral fellow. Sitting (left to right): Ron Ochoa, Ph.D., entomologist and acarologist, USDA-ARS Systematic Entomology Lab, and Samuel Ramsey, Ph.D., then a doctoral student at the University of Maryland. (Photo credit: USDA-ARS, Electron and Confocal Microscopy Unit, Beltsville, Maryland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Samuel Ramsey, Ph.D.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;, is a post-doctoral researcher in the Entomology Department at the University of Maryland, in College Park, Maryland. Email: &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:insectious@gmail.com&quot;&gt;insectious@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ron Ochoa, Ph.D.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;, is a research entomologist at the Systematic Entomology Lab of the U.S. Department of Agriculture’s Agricultural Research Service (USDA-ARS), in&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Beltsville, Maryland. Email: &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:ron.ochoa@ars.usda.gov&quot;&gt;ron.ochoa@ars.usda.gov&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;Joe Mowery&lt;/strong&gt; is a support scientist at the USDA-ARS Electron and Confocal Microscopy Unit (ECMU) in Beltsville, Maryland. Email: &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:joseph.mowery@ars.usda.gov&quot;&gt;joseph.mowery@ars.usda.gov&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;Chris Pooley&lt;/strong&gt; is an IT specialist at the USDA-ARS ECMU. Email: &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:chris.pooley@ars.usda.gov&quot;&gt;chris.pooley@ars.usda.gov&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;Connor Gulbronson, Ph.D.&lt;/strong&gt;, is an Oak Ridge Institute for Science and Education post-doctoral fellow at the USDA-ARS Floral and Nursery Plants Research Unit in Beltsville, Maryland. Email: &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:connor.gulbronson@ars.usda.gov&quot;&gt;connor.gulbronson@ars.usda.gov&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;Gary Bauchan, Ph.D.&lt;/strong&gt;, is director of the USDA-ARS ECMU. Email: &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:gary.bauchan@ars.usda.gov&quot;&gt;gary.bauchan@ars.usda.gov&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;robots-nocontent sd-block sd-social sd-social-icon sd-sharing&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Share this:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;jp-relatedposts-headline&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Related&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 05:24:05 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>sohkamyung</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>An Inside Look at How the Varroa Mite's True Diet Was Discovered</og:title>
<og:description>Some researchers willing to question conventional wisdom, some crafty experimentation, and some high-tech microscopic imagery all add up to a discovery about the Varroa destructor mite that upends years of understanding about how it parasitizes honey bees.</og:description>
<og:url>https://entomologytoday.org/2019/02/21/inside-look-how-varroa-mite-diet-discovered/</og:url>
<og:image>https://i1.wp.com/entomologytoday.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/LT-SEM-cross-section-of-mite-on-bee.jpg?fit=1000%2C754&amp;ssl=1</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://entomologytoday.org/2019/02/21/inside-look-how-varroa-mite-diet-discovered/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Humans who are not concentrating are not general intelligences</title>
<link>https://srconstantin.wordpress.com/2019/02/25/humans-who-are-not-concentrating-are-not-general-intelligences/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://srconstantin.wordpress.com/2019/02/25/humans-who-are-not-concentrating-are-not-general-intelligences/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, OpenAI came out with a &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.openai.com/better-language-models/&quot;&gt;new language model&lt;/a&gt; that automatically synthesizes text, called GPT-2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s disturbingly good.  You can see some examples (cherry-picked, by their own admission) in OpenAI’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.openai.com/better-language-models/&quot;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; and in the related &lt;a href=&quot;https://d4mucfpksywv.cloudfront.net/better-language-models/language_models_are_unsupervised_multitask_learners.pdf&quot;&gt;technical paper.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not going to write about the machine learning here, but about the examples and what we can infer from them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The scary thing about GPT-2-generated text is that it flows very naturally if you’re just skimming, reading for writing style and key, evocative words.  The “unicorn” sample reads like a real science press release. The “theft of nuclear material” sample reads like a real news story. The “Miley Cyrus shoplifting” sample reads like a real post from a celebrity gossip site.  The “GPT-2” sample reads like a real OpenAI press release. The “Legolas and Gimli” sample reads like a real fantasy novel. The “Civil War homework assignment” reads like a real C-student’s paper.  The “JFK acceptance speech” reads like a real politician’s speech.  The “recycling” sample reads like a real right-wing screed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I just skim, without focusing, they all look &lt;em&gt;totally normal. &lt;/em&gt;I would not have noticed they were machine-generated. I would not have noticed anything amiss about them at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But if I read with focus, I notice that they don’t make a lot of logical sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For instance, in the unicorn sample:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The scientist named the population, after their distinctive horn, Ovid’s Unicorn. These four-horned, silver-white unicorns were previously unknown to science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wait a second, “Ovid” doesn’t refer to a “distinctive horn”, so why would naming them “Ovid’s Unicorn” be naming them after a distinctive horn?  Also, you just said they had &lt;em&gt;one &lt;/em&gt;horn, so why are you saying they have &lt;em&gt;four &lt;/em&gt;horns in the next sentence?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While their origins are still unclear, some believe that perhaps the creatures were created when a human and a unicorn met each other in a time before human civilization. According to Pérez, “In South America, such incidents seem to be quite common.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wait, &lt;em&gt;unicorns &lt;/em&gt;originated from the interbreeding of humans and … unicorns?  That’s circular, isn’t it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or, look at the GPT-2 sample:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe this project is the first step in the direction of developing large NLP systems without task-specific training data. That is, we are developing a machine language system in the generative style with no explicit rules for producing text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Except the second sentence &lt;em&gt;isn’t &lt;/em&gt;a restatement of the first sentence — “task-specific training data” and “explicit rules for producing text” aren’t synonyms!  So saying “That is” doesn’t make sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or look at the LOTR sample:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aragorn drew his sword, and the Battle of Fangorn was won. As they marched out through the thicket the morning mist cleared, and the day turned to dusk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah, day doesn’t turn to dusk in the &lt;em&gt;morning&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or in the “resurrected JFK” sample:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(1) The brain of JFK was harvested and reconstructed via tissue sampling. There was no way that the tissue could be transported by air. (2) A sample was collected from the area around his upper chest and sent to the University of Maryland for analysis. A human brain at that point would be about one and a half cubic centimeters. The data were then analyzed along with material that was obtained from the original brain to produce a reconstruction; in layman’s terms, a “mesh” of brain tissue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His brain tissue was harvested…from his chest?!  A human brain is one and a half cubic centimeters?!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, ok, this isn’t actually human-equivalent writing ability. OpenAI doesn’t claim it is, for what it’s worth — I’m not trying to diminish their accomplishment, that’s not the point of this post.  The point is, &lt;em&gt;if you skim text, you miss obvious absurdities&lt;/em&gt;.  The point is &lt;em&gt;OpenAI HAS achieved the ability to pass the Turing test against humans on autopilot&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The point is, I know of a few people, acquaintances of mine, who, even when asked to try to find flaws, &lt;em&gt;could not detect anything weird or mistaken in the GPT-2-generated samples&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are probably a lot of people who would be completely taken in by literal “fake news”, as in, computer-generated fake articles and blog posts.  This is pretty alarming.  Even more alarming: unless I make a conscious effort to read carefully, &lt;em&gt;I would be one of them&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robin Hanson’s post &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.overcomingbias.com/2017/03/better-babblers.html&quot;&gt;Better Babblers&lt;/a&gt; is very relevant here.  He claims, and I don’t think he’s exaggerating, that a lot of human speech is simply generated by “low order correlations”, that is, generating sentences or paragraphs that are statistically likely to come after previous sentences or paragraphs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After eighteen years of being a professor, I’ve graded &lt;em&gt;many&lt;/em&gt; student essays. And while I usually try to teach a deep structure of concepts, what the median student actually learns seems to mostly be a set of low order correlations. They know what words to use, which words tend to go together, which combinations tend to have positive associations, and so on. But if you ask an exam question where the deep structure answer differs from answer you’d guess looking at low order correlations, most students usually give the wrong answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simple correlations also seem sufficient to capture most polite conversation talk, such as the weather is nice, how is your mother’s illness, and damn that other political party. Simple correlations are also most of what I see in inspirational TED talks, and when public intellectuals and talk show guests pontificate on topics they really don’t understand, such as quantum mechanics, consciousness, postmodernism, or the need always for more regulation everywhere. After all, media entertainers don’t need to understand deep structures any better than do their audiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me call styles of talking (or music, etc.) that rely mostly on low order correlations “babbling”. Babbling isn’t meaningless, but to ignorant audiences it often appears to be based on a deeper understanding than is actually the case. When done well, babbling can be entertaining, comforting, titillating, or exciting. It just isn’t usually a good place to learn deep insight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used to half-joke that the &lt;a href=&quot;http://sebpearce.com/bullshit/&quot;&gt;New Age Bullshit Generator&lt;/a&gt; was &lt;em&gt;actually useful &lt;/em&gt;as a way to get myself to feel more optimistic. The truth is, it isn’t quite good enough to match the “aura” or “associations” of genuine, human-created inspirational text. GPT-2, though, &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also suspect that the “lyrical” or “free-associational” function of poetry is adequately matched by GPT-2.  The &lt;a href=&quot;http://antinegationism.tumblr.com/post/182901133106/an-eternal-howl&quot;&gt;autocompletions of &lt;em&gt;Howl &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;read a lot like Allen Ginsberg — they just don’t imply the same beliefs about the world.  (&lt;em&gt;Moloch whose heart is crying for justice!&lt;/em&gt; sounds rather positive.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve noticed that I cannot tell, from casual conversation, whether someone is intelligent in the IQ sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve interviewed job applicants, and perceived them all as “bright and impressive”, but found that the vast majority of them could not solve a simple math problem.  The ones who could solve the problem didn’t appear any “brighter” in conversation than the ones who couldn’t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve taught public school teachers, who were &lt;em&gt;incredibly &lt;/em&gt;bad at formal mathematical reasoning (I know, because I graded their tests), to the point that I had not realized humans could be that bad at math — but it had &lt;em&gt;no &lt;/em&gt;effect on how they came across in friendly conversation after hours. They didn’t seem “dopey” or “slow”, they were witty and engaging and warm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve read the personal blogs of intellectually disabled people — people who, by definition, score poorly on IQ tests — and &lt;em&gt;they &lt;/em&gt;don’t read as any less funny or creative or relatable than anyone else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever ability IQ tests and math tests measure, I believe that lacking that ability doesn’t have &lt;em&gt;any &lt;/em&gt;effect on one’s ability to make a good social impression or even to “seem smart” in conversation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If “human intelligence” is about reasoning ability, the capacity to detect whether arguments make sense, then you simply do not need human intelligence to create a linguistic style or aesthetic that can fool our pattern-recognition apparatus if we don’t concentrate on parsing content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also noticed, upon reading GPT2 samples, just how often my brain slides from focused attention to just skimming. I read the paper’s sample about Spanish history with interest, and the GPT2-generated text was obviously absurd. My eyes glazed over during the sample about video games, since I don’t care about video games, and the machine-generated text looked totally unobjectionable to me. My brain is constantly making evaluations about what’s worth the trouble to focus on, and what’s ok to tune out. GPT2 is actually really useful as a *test* of one’s level of attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is related to my hypothesis in &lt;a href=&quot;https://srconstantin.wordpress.com/2017/10/10/distinctions-in-types-of-thought/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://srconstantin.wordpress.com/2017/10/10/distinctions-in-types-of-thought/&lt;/a&gt; that effortless pattern-recognition is what machine learning can do today, while effortful attention, and explicit reasoning (which seems to be a subset of effortful attention) is generally beyond ML’s current capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beta waves in the brain are usually associated with focused concentration or active or anxious thought, while alpha waves are associated with the relaxed state of being awake but with closed eyes, before falling asleep, or while dreaming. Alpha waves sharply reduce after a subject makes a mistake and begins paying closer attention. I’d be interested to see whether ability to tell GPT2-generated text from human-generated text correlates with alpha waves vs. beta waves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first-order effects of highly effective text-generators are scary. It will be incredibly easy and cheap to fool people, to manipulate social movements, etc. There’s a lot of opportunity for bad actors to take advantage of this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second-order effects might well be good, though. If only conscious, focused logical thought can detect a bot, maybe some people will become more aware of when they’re thinking actively vs not, and will be able to flag when they’re not really focusing, and distinguish the impressions they absorb in a state of autopilot from “real learning”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mental motion of “I didn’t really parse that paragraph, but sure, whatever, I’ll take the author’s word for it” is, in my introspective experience, absolutely identical to “I didn’t really parse that paragraph because it was bot-generated and didn’t make any sense so I couldn’t possibly have parsed it”, except that in the first case, I assume that the error lies with me rather than the text.  This is not a safe assumption in a post-GPT2 world. Instead of “default to humility” (assume that when you don’t understand a passage, the passage is true and you’re just missing something) the ideal mental action in a world full of bots is “default to null” (if you don’t understand a passage, assume you’re in the same epistemic state as if you’d never read it at all.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe practice and experience with GPT2 will help people get better at doing “default to null”?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;wpcnt&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wpa wpmrec&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;wpa-about&quot;&gt;Advertisements&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;jp-post-flair&quot; class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-like-enabled sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;robots-nocontent sd-block sd-social sd-social-icon-text sd-sharing&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Share this:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-block sd-like jetpack-likes-widget-wrapper jetpack-likes-widget-unloaded&quot; id=&quot;like-post-wrapper-67143906-9297-5c75d35cdb211&quot; data-src=&quot;//widgets.wp.com/likes/index.html?ver=20180319#blog_id=67143906&amp;amp;post_id=9297&amp;amp;origin=srconstantin.wordpress.com&amp;amp;obj_id=67143906-9297-5c75d35cdb211&quot; data-name=&quot;like-post-frame-67143906-9297-5c75d35cdb211&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Like this:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;likes-widget-placeholder post-likes-widget-placeholder&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;button&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Like&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;loading&quot;&gt;Loading...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 03:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jseliger</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Humans Who Are Not Concentrating Are Not General Intelligences</og:title>
<og:url>https://srconstantin.wordpress.com/2019/02/25/humans-who-are-not-concentrating-are-not-general-intelligences/</og:url>
<og:description>Recently, OpenAI came out with a new language model that automatically synthesizes text, called GPT-2. It’s disturbingly good.  You can see some examples (cherry-picked, by their own admissio…</og:description>
<og:image>https://secure.gravatar.com/blavatar/e6f1f7f1406d0a73a37a43771ed072ba?s=200&amp;ts=1551225692</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://srconstantin.wordpress.com/2019/02/25/humans-who-are-not-concentrating-are-not-general-intelligences/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Go 1.12 Released</title>
<link>https://blog.golang.org/go1.12</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.golang.org/go1.12</guid>
<description>&lt;h3 class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.golang.org/go1.12&quot;&gt;Go 1.12 is released&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;date&quot;&gt;25 February 2019&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today the Go team is happy to announce the release of Go 1.12. You can get it from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://golang.org/dl/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;download page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For details about the changes in Go 1.12, see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://golang.org/doc/go1.12&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Go 1.12 release notes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the highlights include &lt;a href=&quot;https://golang.org/doc/go1.12#tls_1_3&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;opt-in support for TLS 1.3&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://golang.org/doc/go1.12#modules&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;improved modules support&lt;/a&gt; (in preparation &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.golang.org/modules2019&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;for being the default in Go 1.13&lt;/a&gt;), support for &lt;code&gt;windows/arm&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://golang.org/doc/go1.12#darwin&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;improved macOS &amp;amp; iOS forwards compatibility.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As always, we also want to thank everyone who contributed to this release by writing code, filing bugs, providing feedback, and/or testing the betas and release candidates. Your contributions and diligence helped to ensure that Go 1.12 is as stable as possible. That said, if you do notice any problems, please &lt;a href=&quot;https://golang.org/issues/new&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;file an issue&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enjoy the new release!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;author&quot;&gt;By Andrew Bonventre&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 01:13:10 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>crawshaw</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.golang.org/go1.12</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>