<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>RedisGraph: A High Performance In-Memory Graph Database as a Redis Module</title>
<link>http://redisgraph.io/design/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://redisgraph.io/design/</guid>
<description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Graph based data is everywhere now days, Facebook, Google, Twitter and Pinterest are only a few who've realize the power behind relationship data and are utilizing it to the fullest, as a direct result we see a rise both in interest and variety of graph data solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the introduction of &lt;a href=&quot;http://antirez.com/news/106&quot;&gt;Redis Modules&lt;/a&gt; we've seen the great potential of introducing a graph data structure to Redis arsenal, a native C implementation with emphasis on performance was developed to bring new graph database capabilities to Redis, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://redismodules.com/modules/redis-graph/&quot;&gt;RedisGraph&lt;/a&gt; is now available as an open source project on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/swilly22/redis-module-graph&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this document we'll discuss the internal design and feature of RedisGraph and demonstrate its current capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;redisgraph-at-a-glance&quot;&gt;RedisGraph At-a-Glance&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RedisGraph is a graph database developed from scratch on top of Redis, using the new Redis Modules API to extend Redis with new commands and capabilities. Its main features include: - Simple, fast indexing and querying - Data stored in RAM, using memory-efficient custom data structures - On disk persistence - Tabular result sets - Simple and popular graph query language (Cypher) - Data Filtering, Aggregation and ordering&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-little-taste-redisgraph-in-action&quot;&gt;A Little Taste: RedisGraph in Action&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s look at some of the key concepts of RedisGraph using this example over the redis-cli tool:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;constructing-a-graph&quot;&gt;Constructing a graph:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a common concept to represent entities as nodes within a graph, In this example, we'll create a small graph with both actors and movies as its entities, an &quot;act&quot; relation will connect actors to movies they casted in. We use the graph.QUERY command to issue a CREATE query which will introduce new entities and relations to our graph.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;codehilite&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
graph.QUERY &amp;lt;graph_id&amp;gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'CREATE (:&amp;lt;label&amp;gt; {&amp;lt;attribute_name&amp;gt;:&amp;lt;attribute_value&amp;gt;,...})'&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;codehilite&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
graph.QUERY &amp;lt;graph_id&amp;gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'CREATE (&amp;lt;source_node_alias&amp;gt;)-[&amp;lt;relation&amp;gt; {&amp;lt;attribute_name&amp;gt;:&amp;lt;attribute_value&amp;gt;,...}]-&amp;gt;(&amp;lt;dest_node_alias&amp;gt;)'&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Construct our graph in one go:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;codehilite&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
graph.QUERY IMDB &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'CREATE (aldis:actor {name: &quot;Aldis Hodge&quot;, birth_year: 1986}),&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;                         (oshea:actor {name: &quot;OShea Jackson&quot;, birth_year: 1991}),&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;                         (corey:actor {name: &quot;Corey Hawkins&quot;, birth_year: 1988}),&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;                         (neil:actor {name: &quot;Neil Brown&quot;, birthyear: 1980}),&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;                         (compton:movie {title: &quot;Straight Outta Compton&quot;, genre: &quot;Biography&quot;, votes: 127258, rating: 7.9, year: 2015}),&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;                         (neveregoback:movie {title: &quot;Never Go Back&quot;, genre: &quot;Action&quot;, votes: 15821, rating: 6.4, year: 2016}),&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;                         (aldis)-[act]-&amp;gt;(neveregoback),&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;                         (aldis)-[act]-&amp;gt;(compton),&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;                         (oshea)-[act]-&amp;gt;(compton),&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;                         (corey)-[act]-&amp;gt;(compton),&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;                         (neil)-[act]-&amp;gt;(compton)'&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;querying-the-graph&quot;&gt;Querying the graph:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RedisGraph exposes a subset of openCypher graph language, although only a number of language capabilities are supported there's enough functionality to extract valuable insights from your graphs, to execute a query we use the GRAPH.QUERY command:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;codehilite&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
GRAPH.QUERY &amp;lt;graph_id&amp;gt; &amp;lt;query&amp;gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's execute a number of queries against our movies graph:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find the sum, max, min and avg age of the Straight Outta Compton cast:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;codehilite&quot; readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
GRAPH.QUERY IMDB &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;MATCH (a:actor)-[act]-&amp;gt;(m:movie {title:\&quot;Straight Outta Compton\&quot;})&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;RETURN m.title, SUM(a.age), MAX(a.age), MIN(a.age), AVG(a.age)&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RedisGraph will reply with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;codehilite&quot; readability=&quot;16&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;m.title, SUM(a.age), MAX(a.age), MIN(a.age), AVG(a.age)&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Straight Outta Compton,123.000000,37.000000,26.000000,30.750000&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first row is our result-set hearder which name each column according to the return clause. Second row contains our query result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's try another query, this time we'll find in how many movies each actor played.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;codehilite&quot; readability=&quot;15&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
GRAPH.QUERY IMDB &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;MATCH (actor)-[act]-&amp;gt;(movie) RETURN actor.name, COUNT(movie.title) AS movies_count ORDER BY&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;movies_count DESC&quot;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;actor.name, movies_count&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Aldis Hodge,2.000000&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;O'Shea Jackson,1.000000&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Corey Hawkins,1.000000&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Neil Brown,1.000000&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-theory-ideas-behind-redisgraph&quot;&gt;The Theory: Ideas behind RedisGraph&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Different graph databases uses different structures for representing a graph. Some use adjacency list, others might use an adjacency matrix. Each structure has its advantages and disadvantages. For RedisGraph it was crucial to find a data structure which will enable us to perform fast searches on the graph, and thus we have decided to use a concept called &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Triplestore&quot;&gt;Hexastore&lt;/a&gt; in order to hold all the relationships within the graph.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;graph-representation-hexastore&quot;&gt;Graph representation: Hexastore&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Hexastore is simply a list of triplets, where each triplet is composed of three parts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Subject&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Predicate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Object&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;Where the Subject refers to a source node, predicate represents a relationship and the object refers to a destination node. For each relationship within the graph our hexastore will contain all six permutation of the source node, relationship edge and destination node. For example consider the following relation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;(Aldis_Hodge)-[act]-&amp;gt;(Straight_Outta_Compton)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;where: - Aldis_Hodge is the source node - act is the relationship - Straight_Outta_Compton is the destination node&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All six possibilities of representing this connection are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;codehilite&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
SPO:Aldis_Hodge:act:Straight_Outta_Compton
SOP:Aldis_Hodge:Straight_Outta_Compton:act
POS:act:Straight_Outta_Compton:Aldis_Hodge
PSO:act:Aldis_Hodge:Straight_Outta_Compton
OPS:Straight_Outta_Compton:act:Aldis_Hodge
OSP:Straight_Outta_Compton:Aldis_Hodge:act
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the Hexastore constructed we can easily search our graph, suppose I would like to find the cast of the movie Straight Outta Compton, all I've to do is search my Hexastore for all strings containing the prefix: &lt;code&gt;OPS:Straight_Outta_Compton:act:*&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or if I'm interested in all the movies Aldis Hodge played in, I can search for all strings containing the prefix: &lt;code&gt;SPO:Aldis_Hodge:act:*&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although a Hexastore uses plenty of memory (six triplets for each relation), we're using a trie data structure which is not only fast in terms of search but is also memory efficient as it doesn't create duplication of string prefixes it already seen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;query-language-opencypher&quot;&gt;Query language: openCypher&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a number of Graph Query languages, we didn't want to reinvent the wheel and come up with our own language, and so we've decided to implement a subset of one of the most popular graph query language out there openCypher. The Open-Cypher project provides means to create a parser for the language, although convenient we decided to create our own parser with Lex as a tokenizer and Lemon which generates a C target parser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As mentioned only a subset of the language is supported, but it is our intention to continue adding new capabilities and extend the language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;runtime-query-execution&quot;&gt;Runtime: query execution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's review the steps our module takes when executing a query. Consider the following query which finds all actors who've played alongside Aldis Hodge and are over 30 years old:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;codehilite&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
MATCH (aldis::actor {name:&quot;Aldis Hodge&quot;})-[act]-&amp;gt;(m:movie)&amp;lt;-[act]-(a:actor) WHERE a.age &amp;gt; 30 RETURN m.title, a.name
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RedisGraph will - Parse query, build abstract syntax tree (AST) - Construct a query execution plan composed of: - Label scan operation - Filter operation (filter tree) - Expand operation - Expand into operation - Execute plan - Populate result-set with matching entities attributes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;query-parser&quot;&gt;Query parser&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given a valid query the parser will generate an AST containing six primary nodes one for each clause:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;MATCH&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CREATE&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DELETE&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WHERE&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RETURN&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ORDER&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;Generating an abstract syntax tree is a common way of describing and structuring a language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;filter-tree&quot;&gt;Filter tree&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A query can filter out entities by creating predicates. In our example we're filtering actors which are younger then 30. It's possible to combine predicates using the OR, AND keywords to form granular conditions. During runtime the WHERE clause is used to construct a filter tree. Each node within the tree is either a condition e.g. A &amp;gt; B or an operation (AND/OR). When finding candidate entities they are passed through the tree and get evaluated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;query-processing&quot;&gt;Query processing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The MATCH clause describes relations between queried entities (nodes), a node can have an alias which will allow us to refer to it at later stages within the executing query lifetime (WHERE, RETURN clause), but all nodes must eventually be assign an ID. The process of assigning IDs to nodes is refered to as the search phase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the search we'll be querying the Hexastore for IDs according to the MATCH clause structure. For instance, in our example we'll start our search by looking for movies in which Aldis Hodge played in. For each movie we'll extend our search to find out which other actors played in the current processed movie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you might imagine the search process is a recursive operation which traverse the graph. At each step a new ID is discovered. Once every node has an ID assigned to it we can be assured that current entities have passed our filters. At this point we can extract requested attributes (as specified in the return clause) and append a new record to the final result set.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;benchmarks&quot;&gt;Benchmarks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depending on the underlying hardware results may vary. That said, inserting a new relationship is done in O(1). RedisGraph is able to create 100K new relations within one second.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Retrieving data really depends on the size of the graph and the type of query you're executing. On a small size graph ~1000 entities and ~2500 edges, RedisGraph is able to perform ~65K friend of a friend query every second.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's worth mentioning that besides the hexastore, entities are not indexed. It’s our intention to introduce entities indexing which should decrease query execution time dramatically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;license&quot;&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Redis-Graph is published under AGPL-3.0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although RedisGraph is still a young project, it can be an alternative to other graph databases. With its subset of operations one can use it to analyze and explore its graph data. Being a Redis module this project is accessible from every Redis client without the need to make any adjustments. It's our intention to keep on improving and extending RedisGraph with the help of the open source community.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2018 22:41:32 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>wll</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://redisgraph.io/design/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Breaking a Wine Glass in Python by Detecting the Resonant Frequency</title>
<link>https://www.makeartwithpython.com/blog/break-glass-with-resonant-frequency/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.makeartwithpython.com/blog/break-glass-with-resonant-frequency/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;For &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/zothcorp/&quot;&gt;50 days straight&lt;/a&gt; between January and March of this year, I wrote a creative programming sketch in Python every day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On day six, I tried to write a program to detect the resonant frequency of a glass, and break it. As you can see below, my desktop computer speaker wasn’t quite loud enough to break the glass alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-captioned=&quot;&quot; data-instgrm-permalink=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/BeBckw8jT90/&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;8&quot; readability=&quot;-4.6329113924051&quot;&gt;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In today’s post, I walk through the journey of writing a Python program to break wine glasses on demand, by detecting their resonant frequency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along the way we’ll 3D print a cone, learn about resonant frequencies, and see why I needed an amplifier and compression driver. So, let’s get started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;first-the-inspiration&quot;&gt;First, the Inspiration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/X6iJ0hPpGec&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I first saw the video above, which goes into a lot of detail about how to actually break a wine glass with your voice. A few main points are covered, and Mike Boyd, the creator, quickly touches upon them. He recommends:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Having a real crystal glass&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Preferring a thinner, longer crystal glass&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Striking the glass to get it to resonate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using a spectrum analyzer to find the resonant frequency of the glass&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using a straw to visualize when the glass is resonating&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;With that in order, it wasn’t until I tried breaking my third glass that I realized the last thing that ensures you really break a glass on command:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Having micro abrasions in the glass. It can’t be perfectly new and clean.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Without the micro abrasions (either caused by cleaning the glass with soap and water or a very light sanding), the glass wouldn’t break at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;an-aside-about-how-resonance-works&quot;&gt;An Aside About How Resonance Works&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Mike Boyd breaks the glass in the above video, he’s using the acoustic resonance of the wine glass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crystal wine glasses have a natural frequency of vibration that you can hear when you strike them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any sounds at this frequency have the potential to make the wine glass absorb more energy than at any other frequency. Our hope is that our program and speakers will generate enough energy in the glass to break it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;writing-a-prototype-sketch&quot;&gt;Writing a Prototype Sketch&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After seeing the video and being inspired to try recreating it, I needed to first get a prototype in place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Would I be able to get a straw to resonate like in that example video?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily, my &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.makeartwithpython.com/blog/voice-controlled-flappy-bird/&quot;&gt;Voice Controlled Flappy Bird&lt;/a&gt; post already does the difficult part of detecting the current pitch frequency from a microphone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, hypothetically, striking the wine glass should produce the proper tone to break the glass itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using the pitch detection code, the only thing that would be left is to play out the pitch frequency detected by a microphone. The code is straightforward enough using Pygame, Music21, and PyAudio:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-python highlighter-rouge&quot; readability=&quot;39&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot; readability=&quot;73&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kn&quot;&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nn&quot;&gt;threading&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kn&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Thread&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;kn&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nn&quot;&gt;pygame&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;kn&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nn&quot;&gt;pyaudio&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;kn&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nn&quot;&gt;numpy&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;np&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;kn&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nn&quot;&gt;time&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;kn&quot;&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nn&quot;&gt;rtmidi.midiutil&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kn&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;open_midiinput&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;kn&quot;&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nn&quot;&gt;voiceController&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kn&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;q&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;get_current_note&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;MidiInputHandler&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;object&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;):&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;__init__&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;self&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;port&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;freq&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;):&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;self&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;port&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;port&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;self&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;base_freq&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;freq&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;self&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;_wallclock&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;time&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;time&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;self&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;freq_vals&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;i&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;range&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;6&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)]&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;__call__&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;self&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;event&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;None&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;):&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;global&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;currentFrequency&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;message&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;deltatime&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;event&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;self&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;_wallclock&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;deltatime&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;print&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;%&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;s] @&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;%0.6&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;f &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;%&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;r&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;%&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;self&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;port&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;self&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;_wallclock&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;message&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;))&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;message&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;16&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;self&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;freq_vals&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;message&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;62&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;elif&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;message&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;17&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;self&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;freq_vals&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;message&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;62&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mo&quot;&gt;01&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;elif&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;message&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;18&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;self&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;freq_vals&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;message&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;62&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mo&quot;&gt;005&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;elif&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;message&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;19&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;self&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;freq_vals&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;message&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;62&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mo&quot;&gt;0001&lt;/span&gt; 
        &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;elif&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;message&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;20&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;self&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;freq_vals&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;message&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;62&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mo&quot;&gt;00001&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;new_freq&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;self&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;base_freq&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;i&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;range&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;6&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;):&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;new_freq&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;self&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;freq_vals&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;i&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;currentFrequency&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;new_freq&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;print&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;new_freq&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;port&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;try&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;midiin&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;port_name&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;open_midiinput&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;port&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;except&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;EOFError&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;KeyboardInterrupt&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;):&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;exit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;midiSettings&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;MidiInputHandler&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;port_name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mf&quot;&gt;940.0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;midiin&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;set_callback&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;midiSettings&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;pygame&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;init&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;screenWidth&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;screenHeight&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;512&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;512&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;screen&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;pygame&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;display&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;set_mode&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;((&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;screenWidth&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;screenHeight&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;))&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;clock&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;pygame&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;time&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Clock&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;running&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;True&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;titleFont&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;pygame&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;font&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Font&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;assets/Bungee-Regular.ttf&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;24&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;titleText&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;titleFont&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;render&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;Hit the Glass Gently&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;True&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;128&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;))&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;titleCurr&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;titleFont&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;render&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;True&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;128&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;))&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;noteFont&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;pygame&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;font&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Font&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;assets/Roboto-Medium.ttf&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;55&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;t&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Thread&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;target&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;get_current_note&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;t&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;daemon&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;True&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;t&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;start&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;


&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;low_note&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;high_note&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;have_low&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;False&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;have_high&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;True&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;noteHoldLength&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# how many samples in a row user needs to hold a note&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;noteHeldCurrently&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# keep track of how long current note is held&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;noteHeld&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# string of the current note&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;centTolerance&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# how much deviance from proper note to tolerate&lt;/span&gt;


&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;break_the_internet&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;frequency&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;notelength&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;):&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;p&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;pyaudio&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;PyAudio&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;volume&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mf&quot;&gt;0.9&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# range [0.0, 1.0]&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;fs&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;44100&lt;/span&gt;       &lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# sampling rate, Hz, must be integer&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;duration&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;notelength&lt;/span&gt;   &lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# in seconds, may be float&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;f&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;frequency&lt;/span&gt;        &lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# sine frequency, Hz, may be float&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# generate samples, note conversion to float32 array&lt;/span&gt;
    
    &lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# for paFloat32 sample values must be in range [-1.0, 1.0]&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;stream&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;p&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;open&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;format&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;pyaudio&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;paFloat32&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;channels&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;rate&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;fs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;output&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;True&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# play. May repeat with different volume values (if done interactively)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;samples&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;np&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;sin&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;np&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;pi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;np&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;arange&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;fs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;duration&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;f&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;fs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;))&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;astype&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;np&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;float32&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;stream&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;write&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;volume&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;samples&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    

&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;newFrequency&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;breaking&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;False&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;currentFrequency&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;breaking_zone&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;False&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;super_breaking_zone&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;False&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;noteLength&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mf&quot;&gt;5.0&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;while&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;running&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;event&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;pygame&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;event&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;get&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;():&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;event&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;type&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;pygame&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;QUIT&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;running&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;False&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;event&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;type&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;pygame&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;KEYDOWN&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;event&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;key&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;pygame&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;K_q&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;running&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;False&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;event&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;type&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;pygame&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;KEYDOWN&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;event&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;key&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;pygame&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;K_SPACE&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;newFrequency&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;!=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;breaking&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;True&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;midiSettings&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;base_freq&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;newFrequency&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;currentFrequency&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;newFrequency&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;event&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;type&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;pygame&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;KEYDOWN&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;event&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;key&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;pygame&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;K_s&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;noteLength&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mf&quot;&gt;30.0&lt;/span&gt; 
            &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;breaking_zone&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;True&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;event&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;type&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;pygame&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;KEYDOWN&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;event&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;key&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;pygame&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;K_a&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;super_breaking_zone&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;True&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;noteLength&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mf&quot;&gt;5.0&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;screen&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;fill&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;((&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;))&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;breaking&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;titleCurr&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;titleFont&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;render&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;Current Frequency: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;%&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;f&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;%&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;currentFrequency&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;True&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
                                     &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;128&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;128&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;))&lt;/span&gt;
    
    &lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# our user should be singing if there's a note on the queue&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;else&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;not&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;q&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;empty&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;():&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;b&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;q&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;get&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;pygame&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;draw&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;circle&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;screen&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;128&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;),&lt;/span&gt; 
                               &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;screenWidth&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;//&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;int&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;b&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;'Cents'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;])&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;),&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;300&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;),&lt;/span&gt;
                               &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

            &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;noteText&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;noteFont&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;render&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;b&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;'Note'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;],&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;True&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;128&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;))&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;b&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;'Note'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;noteHeldCurrently&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;noteHeld&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;noteHeld&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;noteHoldLength&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
                    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;titleCurr&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;titleFont&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;render&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;Frequency is: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;%&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;f&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;%&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;b&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;'Pitch'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;frequency&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;True&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
                                                 &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;128&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;128&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;))&lt;/span&gt;
                    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;newFrequency&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;b&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;'Pitch'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;frequency&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;else&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;noteHeldCurrently&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;b&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;'Note'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;noteHeld&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;screen&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;blit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;noteText&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;50&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;400&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;))&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;screen&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;blit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;titleText&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;80&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;))&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;screen&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;blit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;titleCurr&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;120&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;))&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;pygame&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;display&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;flip&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;clock&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tick&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;30&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;breaking&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;break_the_internet&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;currentFrequency&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;noteLength&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, there are a few things to note here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One, I use &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;rtmidi&lt;/code&gt; utility to be able to dial in the resonant frequency using a Midi controller. This lets me adjust the knobs in order to find a place where the straw vibrates the most inside of my wine glass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly, we use &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;pyaudio&lt;/code&gt; to generate our sine wave of the resonant frequency. We could have used another library with more immediate feedback, but this was easiest to get in place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, the way the program works is that you strike the glass, and hopefully the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;voiceController&lt;/code&gt; library detects a resonant frequency. The resonant frequency of wine glasses should be between 600 - 900 Hz. Once you’ve got that, you press the SPACEBAR, and that starts playing that resonant frequency out the speakers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this, I was able to generate the results you see from my daily sketch on my desktop computer speakers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I wasn’t able to break the glass. I had a hunch it was because I wasn’t able to generate the volume necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;bringing-in-the-big-guns&quot;&gt;Bringing in the Big Guns&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I couldn’t get my glass to break with my desktop speakers, I started looking around the web to see how other people have broken glass with speakers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best resource I found was from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.acoustics.salford.ac.uk/acoustics_info/glass/?content=glass3&quot;&gt;University of Salford&lt;/a&gt;. They recommend using a 2” “compression driver in order to get results. So, I went off to Amazon, and picked up a &lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/2pjyzVj&quot;&gt;2” compression driver&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this, the only thing remaining was to get an audio amplifier capable of driving the speaker to an (un)reasonable volume. I used &lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/2plJCNb&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;, and I plan on using both the amplifier and driver in more audio projects in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, I needed to build a stand for the speaker, along with a cone to focus the energy of the wave. For this, I used Blender, along with my Prusa i3 MK2. I printed it in PLA, and it seemed to have done the job well enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.makeartwithpython.com/blog/assets/images/break-glass/speaker.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the speaker cone 3D printed, I was finally ready to build my setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It looks something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.makeartwithpython.com/blog/assets/images/break-glass/diagram.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;It consists of a Snowball USB microphone, plugged into a laptop. The laptop runs the sketch from above, first waiting to detect a resonant frequency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You strike the glass, and if the detected resonant frequency is in the zone you’d expect (again, 600Hz to around 900Hz), you press SPACEBAR to begin playing back that resonant frequency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The audio output is hooked up to an amplifier, and that amplifier is hooked up to the driver with the 3D printed code. That cone is pointed directly at the top of the wine glass, as you saw in the gif in the introduction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that, the glass breaks!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.makeartwithpython.com/blog/assets/images/break-glass/header.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;where-to-go-from-here&quot;&gt;Where to Go From Here&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/burningion/break-glass-with-resonant-frequency&quot;&gt;code&lt;/a&gt;, along with the 3D printable &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/burningion/break-glass-with-resonant-frequency/blob/master/stl/speakerboxxx.stl&quot;&gt;cone STL&lt;/a&gt; is at Github.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The program that finally breaks the glass used in the video is slightly different from what I’ve written above. It doesn’t adjust with the MIDI controller, because I found it wasn’t necessary in my case to adjust the detected frequency. The glass broken anyways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you plan on trying to recreate my experiment, &lt;em&gt;please wear safety glasses and ear protection&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ear damage is accumulative, and not wearing proper ear protection means damaging your ears permanently. So please don’t do that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the glass breaks all over the place, so please wear eye protection too. This project is fun, but not worth getting seriously injured over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re still learning Python and Pygame, or you want a visual introduction to programming, check out my book, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.makeartwithpython.com/book/&quot;&gt;Make Art with Python&lt;/a&gt;. The first three chapters are free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, feel free to share this post with your friends. It helps me to continue making these sort of tutorials.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2018 21:08:31 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>burningion</dc:creator>
<og:title>Breaking a Wine Glass in Python By Detecting the Resonant Frequency</og:title>
<og:description>Detecting the Resonant Frequency of an Object with</og:description>
<og:image>/blog/assets/images/break-glass/header.jpg</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.makeartwithpython.com/blog/break-glass-with-resonant-frequency/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Mathematics for Computer Science: Readings</title>
<link>https://ocw.mit.edu/courses/electrical-engineering-and-computer-science/6-042j-mathematics-for-computer-science-spring-2015/readings/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://ocw.mit.edu/courses/electrical-engineering-and-computer-science/6-042j-mathematics-for-computer-science-spring-2015/readings/</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;help-dismiss&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;javascript:disableHelpPopup();%20trackEvents('Popup%20Don%5C't%20Show','popup%20don%5C't%20show%20Click','Help%20Overlay');&quot;&gt;Don't show me this again&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Welcome!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is one of over 2,200 courses on OCW. Find materials for this course in the pages linked along the left.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MIT OpenCourseWare&lt;/strong&gt; is a free &amp;amp; open publication of material from thousands of MIT courses, covering the entire MIT curriculum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No enrollment or registration.&lt;/strong&gt; Freely browse and use OCW materials at your own pace. There's no signup, and no start or end dates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Knowledge is your reward.&lt;/strong&gt; Use OCW to guide your own life-long learning, or to teach others. We don't offer credit or certification for using OCW.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Made for sharing&lt;/strong&gt;. Download files for later. Send to friends and colleagues. Modify, remix, and reuse (just remember to cite OCW as the source.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;help-engage&quot;&gt;Learn more at &lt;a href=&quot;https://ocw.mit.edu/help/get-started-with-ocw/&quot; onclick=&quot;trackEvents('Popup Get Started','popup get started Click','Help Overlay');&quot;&gt;Get Started with MIT OpenCourseWare&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2018 15:16:03 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>rspivak</dc:creator>
<og:description>This section provides courseware and readings for each session of the course, and the full course textbook.</og:description>
<og:image>https://ocw.mit.edu/courses/electrical-engineering-and-computer-science/6-042j-mathematics-for-computer-science-spring-2015/6-042js15.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://ocw.mit.edu/courses/electrical-engineering-and-computer-science/6-042j-mathematics-for-computer-science-spring-2015/readings/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Repair cafés waging war on throwaway culture</title>
<link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2018/mar/15/can-we-fix-it-the-repair-cafes-waging-war-on-throwaway-culture</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.theguardian.com/world/2018/mar/15/can-we-fix-it-the-repair-cafes-waging-war-on-throwaway-culture</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;drop-cap&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;drop-cap__inner&quot;&gt;A&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; vacuum cleaner, a hair straightener, a laptop, Christmas lights, an e-reader, a blender, a kettle, two bags, a pair of jeans, a remote-control helicopter, a spoon, a dining-room chair, a lamp and hair clippers. All broken.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It sounds like a pile of things that you’d stick in boxes and take to the tip. In fact, it’s a list of things mended in a single afternoon by British volunteers determined to get people to stop throwing stuff away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the Reading Repair Cafe, part of a burgeoning international network aimed at confronting a world of stuff, of white goods littering dumps in west Africa and trash swilling through the oceans in huge gyres.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hair clippers belong to William, who does not want to give his surname but cheerfully describes himself as “mechanically incompetent”. He has owned them for 25 years, but 10 years ago they stopped working and they have been sitting unused in his cupboard ever since.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details data-snippet-id=&quot;a5947407-4f95-41fe-849d-e7d9248ebcb7&quot; data-snippet-type=&quot;guide&quot; class=&quot;atom atom--snippet atom--snippet--guide&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;atom--snippet__label&quot;&gt;Quick guide&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;atom--snippet__headline&quot;&gt;What is the Upside?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;button class=&quot;atom__button atom__button--large atom__button--rounded atom--snippet__handle&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;is-on&quot;&gt; Show&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;is-off&quot;&gt; Hide&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/button&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__body&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__item&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;News doesn't always have to be bad – indeed, the relentless focus on confrontation, disaster, antagonism and blame risks convincing the public that the world is hopeless and there is nothing we can do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This series is an antidote, an attempt to show that there is plenty of hope, as our journalists scour the planet looking for pioneers, trailblazers, best practice, unsung heroes, ideas that work, ideas that might and innovations whose time might have come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Readers can follow up with our Further Reading guides and can also recommend other projects, people and progress that we should report on by contacting us at theupside@theguardian.com&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;footer class=&quot;atom--snippet__footer&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__feedback&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Was this helpful?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__ack&quot; hidden=&quot;&quot; aria-role=&quot;alert&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot;&gt;Thank you for your feedback.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/footer&gt;&lt;/details&gt; Sign up here for a wry weekly email rounding up the best from this series
&lt;p&gt;He sits down at the table of Colin Haycock, an IT professional who volunteers at the repair cafe, which has been running monthly for about four years and is a place where people can bring all manner of household items to be fixed for free. In less than five minutes, Haycock has unscrewed and removed the blades, cleaned out some gunk from inside the machine, oiled the blades, and screwed it all back together. The clippers purr happily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;William looks sheepish; Haycock looks pleased. “I wish they were all that simple,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, the repairers will divert 24kg of waste from going to landfill and save 284kg of CO2. Some items can’t be fixed on the spot – notably a hunting horn split in two, which requires soldering with a blow torch – but very little needs to be thrown away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gabrielle Stanley, who used to run a clothing alterations business, says she was drawn to volunteering at the repair cafe to combat the “throwaway culture” she sees. “You go into certain stores...” - she throws a dark look - “how they can sell clothes for that price, when I couldn’t even buy the fabric for that much? And then you hear about things that happen [in the factories] in the far east.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;u-responsive-ratio&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;gu-image&quot; itemprop=&quot;contentUrl&quot; alt=&quot;Sophie Unwin.&quot; src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/852d27b668f87ee38017b34d6abc59c95225f52f/0_224_6720_4032/master/6720.jpg?w=300&amp;amp;q=55&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;usm=12&amp;amp;fit=max&amp;amp;s=1bf26f561cfaef82e51fda463b1338eb&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

Sophie Unwin, the co-founder of the Remakery in Brixton and the founder of Edinburgh Remakery has been inundated with inquiries about setting up similar enterprises abroad. Photograph: Katherine Anne Rose for the Observer
&lt;p&gt;An estimated &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2017/jul/11/uk-households-binned-300000-tonnes-of-clothing-in-2016&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;300,000 tonnes of clothing was sent to landfill in the UK in 2016&lt;/a&gt; and a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/2017/jul/29/fashion-must-fight-scourge-dumped-clothing-landfill&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;report from Wrap&lt;/a&gt; puts the average lifespan for a piece of clothing in the UK at 3.3 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Globally, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://i.unu.edu/media/unu.edu/news/52624/UNU-1stGlobal-E-Waste-Monitor-2014-small.pdf&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;amount of e-waste generated&lt;/a&gt; is expected to hit 50m tonnes by the end of 2018. This is partly driven by consumers’ eagerness for new products, but there are also concerns about built-in obsolescence, in which manufacturers design products to break down after a certain amount of time and are often difficult or expensive to fix. In December, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2017/dec/21/apple-admits-slowing-older-iphones-because-of-flagging-batteries&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Apple admitted to slowing older models of phones&lt;/a&gt;, though it claimed it did this for operational not obsolescence reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://interactive.guim.co.uk/charts/embed/mar/2018-03-12T10:06:24/embed.html&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Chart&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Repair cafe volunteer Stuart Ward says that when fixing items is actively discouraged by manufacturers, repair becomes a political act. He is vehement about the “right to repair”, a movement opposed to the practices of companies like the machinery company &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2017/mar/06/nebraska-farmers-right-to-repair-john-deere-apple&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;John Deere, which, under copyright laws, doesn’t allow people to fix their own equipment or take them to independent repairers.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You own your equipment, you’re allowed to take a screwdriver to it and play with it,” he says. “It’s something fundamental.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teaching people how to fix their own gear is at the heart of the Edinburgh Remakery, a store on the main street of Leith that is part repair shop, part secondhand store, part repair education centre.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We do the repair in front of a customer, not out in the back, not hidden,” says Sotiris Katsimbas, the lead IT technician at the Remakery. To do this, Katsimbas and his team conduct one-to-one IT repair appointments for a small fee, as do their colleagues who specialise in sewing and furniture repairs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s a matter of confidence. It’s not magic. Someone put it together, someone can take it apart, you only need a Phillips screwdriver and some knowledge,” says Katsimbas as he shows Daniel Turner how to open up his laptop so he can clean out the fluff and dust that is causing the machine to overheat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since it opened in 2012, the Remakery has diverted 205 tonnes of waste that would have ended up in landfill. But the Remakery is unique in that, unlike much of the repair movement, which is volunteer-led, it is a viable business, employing 11 staff and 10 freelancers. Last year the shop had an income of £236,000 – 30% from grants, 70% generated through sales of furniture and electronics, workshops and repair appointments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details data-snippet-id=&quot;eede8699-e98d-47b6-bd5a-433004274a36&quot; data-snippet-type=&quot;guide&quot; class=&quot;atom atom--snippet atom--snippet--guide&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;atom--snippet__label&quot;&gt;Quick guide&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;atom--snippet__headline&quot;&gt;Further reading&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;button class=&quot;atom__button atom__button--large atom__button--rounded atom--snippet__handle&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;is-on&quot;&gt; Show&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;is-off&quot;&gt; Hide&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/button&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__body&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;atom--snippet__image&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://media.guim.co.uk/049cde3821e212153defc5ea6275d9fde38670f4/0_140_4700_2819/140.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot; https://media.guim.co.uk/049cde3821e212153defc5ea6275d9fde38670f4/0_140_4700_2819/140.jpg 140w , https://media.guim.co.uk/049cde3821e212153defc5ea6275d9fde38670f4/0_140_4700_2819/500.jpg 500w , https://media.guim.co.uk/049cde3821e212153defc5ea6275d9fde38670f4/0_140_4700_2819/1000.jpg 1000w , https://media.guim.co.uk/049cde3821e212153defc5ea6275d9fde38670f4/0_140_4700_2819/2000.jpg 2000w , https://media.guim.co.uk/049cde3821e212153defc5ea6275d9fde38670f4/0_140_4700_2819/4700.jpg 4700w&quot; sizes=&quot;100px&quot;/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__item&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to learn how to fix your electronics, the Restart Project runs events to teach people, you can see where their events are &lt;a href=&quot;https://therestartproject.org/&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__item&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to fix something round the house, but don't have the tools you need and can't afford to buy them for a one-off job, you can find a local &lt;a href=&quot;http://localtools.org/find/&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;tool library&lt;/a&gt; where you can hire what you need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__item&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Michelle McGagh spent a year without buying new things, which involved a fair amount of fixing as well as going without, her experiences make for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/money/blog/2016/nov/26/no-spending-year-over-new-way-living-wealthier-wiser&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;fascinating reading&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__credit&quot;&gt;Photograph: Nastco/iStockphoto&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;footer class=&quot;atom--snippet__footer&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__feedback&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Was this helpful?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__ack&quot; hidden=&quot;&quot; aria-role=&quot;alert&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot;&gt;Thank you for your feedback.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/footer&gt;&lt;/details&gt;&lt;p&gt;The financial viability of the shop makes it attractive as a model. In the last year, Sophie Unwin, the co-founder of the Remakery in Brixton and the founder of Edinburgh Remakery is setting up the Remakery network to replicate the work internationally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She has had 53 inquiries from groups interested in setting up similar enterprises in the US, New Zealand, Canada, South Korea, Austria, Ireland, Germany, Australia and elsewhere in the UK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The network will provide toolkits and advice to groups who want to recreate what she has done in Edinburgh. Unwin hopes that these resources will allow other groups to do in two years what it has taken eight years of trial and error and extremely hard graft to achieve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For repairers, fixing things is a way of doing something about an obsession with consumerism that Unwin calls “a kind of sickness in society”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This is our little attempt to push a little bit in this direction,” says Ward. “To say, we can fix this, we can repair things, don’t give up hope.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article is part of a series on possible solutions to some of the world’s most stubborn problems. What else should we cover? Email us at theupside@theguardian.com&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2018 14:05:30 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>wcunning</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://www.theguardian.com/world/2018/mar/15/can-we-fix-it-the-repair-cafes-waging-war-on-throwaway-culture</og:url>
<og:description>When fixing items is actively discouraged by manufacturers, recycling becomes a political act, say Repair Cafe volunteers</og:description>
<og:image>https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/81213fe94f74bb6160d9793e25db1618484e4658/0_0_6720_4032/master/6720.jpg?w=1200&amp;h=630&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;fit=crop&amp;crop=faces%2Centropy&amp;bm=normal&amp;ba=bottom%2Cleft&amp;blend64=aHR0cHM6Ly91cGxvYWRzLmd1aW0uY28udWsvMjAxOC8wMS8zMS9mYWNlYm9va19kZWZhdWx0LnBuZw&amp;s=085001777c8b8c8c6ff2c89ec339d5a4</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Can we fix it? The repair cafes waging war on throwaway culture</og:title>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2018/mar/15/can-we-fix-it-the-repair-cafes-waging-war-on-throwaway-culture</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>50M Facebook profiles harvested for Cambridge Analytica in major data breach</title>
<link>https://www.theguardian.com/news/2018/mar/17/cambridge-analytica-facebook-influence-us-election</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.theguardian.com/news/2018/mar/17/cambridge-analytica-facebook-influence-us-election</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The data analytics firm that worked with Donald Trump’s election team and the winning Brexit campaign harvested millions of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/facebook&quot; data-link-name=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; data-component=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; profiles of US voters, in one of the tech giant’s biggest ever data breaches, and used them to build a powerful software program to predict and influence choices at the ballot box.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A whistleblower has revealed to the &lt;em&gt;Observer&lt;/em&gt; how &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/cambridge-analytica&quot; data-link-name=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; data-component=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Cambridge Analytica&lt;/a&gt; – a company owned by the hedge fund billionaire Robert Mercer, and headed at the time by Trump’s key adviser Steve Bannon – used personal information taken without authorisation in early 2014 to build a system that could profile individual US voters, in order to target them with personalised political advertisements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Christopher Wylie, who worked with a Cambridge University academic to obtain the data, told the &lt;em&gt;Observer&lt;/em&gt;: “We exploited Facebook to harvest millions of people’s profiles. And built models to exploit what we knew about them and target their inner demons. That was the basis the entire company was built on.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Documents seen by the &lt;em&gt;Observer&lt;/em&gt;, and confirmed by a Facebook statement, show that by late 2015 the company had found out that information had been harvested on an unprecedented scale. However, at the time it failed to alert users and took only limited steps to recover and secure the private information of more than 50 million individuals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details data-snippet-id=&quot;0ee855ed-c4df-49ab-8c93-baf93b54276e&quot; data-snippet-type=&quot;profile&quot; class=&quot;atom atom--snippet atom--snippet--profile&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;atom--snippet__label&quot;&gt;Profile&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;atom--snippet__headline&quot;&gt;Cambridge Analytica: the key players&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;button class=&quot;atom__button atom__button--large atom__button--rounded atom--snippet__handle&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;is-on&quot;&gt; Show&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;is-off&quot;&gt; Hide&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/button&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__body&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__item&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__heading&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alexander Nix, CEO&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An Old Etonian with a degree from Manchester University, Nix, 42, worked as a financial analyst in Mexico and the UK before joining SCL, a strategic communications firm, in 2003. From 2007 he took over the company’s elections division, and claims to have worked on 260 campaigns globally. He set up Cambridge Analytica to work in America, with investment from Robert Mercer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__item&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__heading&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aleksandr Kogan, data miner&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aleksandr Kogan was born in Moldova and lived in Moscow until the age of seven, then moved with his family to the US, where he became a naturalised citizen. He studied at the University of California, Berkeley, and got his PhD at the University of Hong Kong before joining Cambridge as a lecturer in psychology and expert in social media psychometrics. He set up Global Science Research (GSR) to carry out CA’s data research. While at Cambridge he accepted a position at St Petersburg State University, and also took Russian government grants for research. He changed his name to Spectre when he married, but later reverted to Kogan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__item&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__heading&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Steve Bannon, former board member&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A former investment banker turned “alt-right” media svengali, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/steve-bannon&quot; data-link-name=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; data-component=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Steve Bannon&lt;/a&gt; was boss at website Breitbart when he met Christopher Wylie and Nix and advised Robert Mercer to invest in political data research by setting up CA. In August 2016 he became Donald Trump’s campaign CEO. Bannon encouraged the reality TV star to embrace the “populist, economic nationalist” agenda that would carry him into the White House. That earned Bannon the post of chief strategist to the president and for a while he was arguably the second most powerful man in America. By August 2017 his relationship with Trump had soured and he was out.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__item&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__heading&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Robert Mercer, investor&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robert Mercer, 71, is a computer scientist and hedge fund billionaire, who used his fortune to become one of the most influential men in US politics as a top Republican donor. An AI expert, he made a fortune with quantitative trading pioneers Renaissance Technologies, then built a $60m war chest to back conservative causes by using an offshore investment vehicle to avoid US tax. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__item&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__heading&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rebekah Mercer, investor&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rebekah Mercer has a maths degree from Stanford, and worked as a trader, but her influence comes primarily from her father’s billions. The fortysomething, the second of Mercer’s three daughters, heads up the family foundation which channels money to rightwing groups. The conservative mega‑donors backed Breitbart, Bannon and, most influentially, poured millions into Trump’s presidential campaign.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;footer class=&quot;atom--snippet__footer&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__feedback&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Was this helpful?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__ack&quot; hidden=&quot;&quot; aria-role=&quot;alert&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot;&gt;Thank you for your feedback.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/footer&gt;&lt;/details&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/03/17/us/politics/cambridge-analytica-trump-campaign.html&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;is reporting&lt;/a&gt; that copies of the data harvested for Cambridge Analytica could still be found online; its reporting team had viewed some of the raw data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data was collected through an app called thisisyourdigitallife, built by academic Aleksandr Kogan, separately from his work at Cambridge University. Through his company Global Science Research (GSR), in collaboration with Cambridge Analytica, hundreds of thousands of users were paid to take a personality test and agreed to have their data collected for academic use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the app also collected the information of the test-takers’ Facebook friends, leading to the accumulation of a data pool tens of millions-strong. Facebook’s “platform policy” allowed only collection of friends’ data to improve user experience in the app and barred it being sold on or used for advertising. The discovery of the unprecedented data harvesting, and the use to which it was put, raises urgent new questions about Facebook’s role in targeting voters in the US presidential election. It comes only weeks after &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2018/feb/16/trump-mueller-russia-indictment-what-does-it-mean&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;indictments of 13 Russians&lt;/a&gt; by the special counsel Robert Mueller which stated they had used the platform to perpetrate “information warfare” against the US.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cambridge Analytica and Facebook are one focus of an inquiry into data and politics by the British Information Commissioner’s Office. Separately, the Electoral Commission is also investigating what role Cambridge Analytica played in the EU referendum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We are investigating the circumstances in which Facebook data may have been illegally acquired and used,” said the information commissioner Elizabeth Denham. “It’s part of our ongoing investigation into the use of data analytics for political purposes which was launched to consider how political parties and campaigns, data analytics companies and social media platforms in the UK are using and analysing people’s personal information to micro-target voters.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Friday, four days after the &lt;em&gt;Observer&lt;/em&gt; sought comment for this story, but more than two years after the data breach was first reported, &lt;a href=&quot;https://newsroom.fb.com/news/2018/03/suspending-cambridge-analytica/&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Facebook announced&lt;/a&gt; that it was suspending Cambridge Analytica and Kogan from the platform, pending further information over misuse of data. Separately, Facebook’s external lawyers warned the &lt;em&gt;Observer&lt;/em&gt; it was making “false and defamatory” allegations, and reserved Facebook’s legal position.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;u-responsive-ratio&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;gu-image&quot; itemprop=&quot;contentUrl&quot; alt=&quot;Steve Bannon&quot; src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/03d9fed82c1fac505b9cb5d47392f348fa724f9d/0_125_3376_4216/master/3376.jpg?w=300&amp;amp;q=55&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;usm=12&amp;amp;fit=max&amp;amp;s=6c31628c73b7e17f5dcf03c2b934267f&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

Key Trump adviser Steve Bannon Photograph: Alain Robert/Sipa/Rex/Shutterstock
&lt;p&gt;The revelations provoked widespread outrage. The Massachusetts Attorney General Maura Healey announced that the state would be launching an investigation. “Residents deserve answers immediately from Facebook and Cambridge Analytica,” she said on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Democratic senator Mark Warner said the harvesting of data on such a vast scale for political targeting underlined the need for Congress to improve controls. He has proposed an Honest Ads Act to regulate online political advertising the same way as television, radio and print. “This story is more evidence that the online political advertising market is essentially the Wild West. Whether it’s allowing Russians to purchase political ads, or extensive micro-targeting based on ill-gotten user data, it’s clear that, left unregulated, this market will continue to be prone to deception and lacking in transparency,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last month both Facebook and the CEO of Cambridge Analytica, Alexander Nix, told a parliamentary inquiry on fake news: that the company did not have or use private Facebook data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simon Milner, Facebook’s UK policy director, when asked if Cambridge Analytica had Facebook data, told MPs: “They may have lots of data but it will not be Facebook user data. It may be data about people who are on Facebook that they have gathered themselves, but it is not data that we have provided.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cambridge Analytica’s chief executive, Alexander Nix, told the inquiry: “We do not work with Facebook data and we do not have Facebook data.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wylie, a Canadian data analytics expert who worked with Cambridge Analytica and Kogan to devise and implement the scheme, showed a dossier of evidence about the data misuse to the &lt;em&gt;Observer&lt;/em&gt; which appears to raise questions about their testimony. He has passed it to the National Crime Agency’s cybercrime unit and the Information Commissioner’s Office. It includes emails, invoices, contracts and bank transfers that reveal more than 50 million profiles – mostly belonging to registered US voters – were harvested from the site in one of the largest-ever breaches of Facebook data. Facebook on Friday said that it was also suspending Wylie from accessing the platform while it carried out its investigation, despite his role as a whistleblower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the time of the data breach, Wylie was a Cambridge Analytica employee, but Facebook described him as working for Eunoia Technologies, a firm he set up on his own after leaving his former employer in late 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The evidence Wylie supplied to UK and US authorities includes a letter from Facebook’s own lawyers sent to him in August 2016, asking him to destroy any data he held that had been collected by GSR, the company set up by Kogan to harvest the profiles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://interactive.guim.co.uk/embed/article-embeds/Sidebar-ca/embed.html&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Cambridge Analytica interactive&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That legal letter was sent several months after the &lt;em&gt;Guardian&lt;/em&gt; first reported the breach and days before it was officially announced that Bannon was taking over as campaign manager for Trump and bringing Cambridge Analytica with him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Because this data was obtained and used without permission, and because GSR was not authorised to share or sell it to you, it cannot be used legitimately in the future and must be deleted immediately,” the letter said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook did not pursue a response when the letter initially went unanswered for weeks because Wylie was travelling, nor did it follow up with forensic checks on his computers or storage, he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“That to me was the most astonishing thing. They waited two years and did absolutely nothing to check that the data was deleted. All they asked me to do was tick a box on a form and post it back.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul-Olivier Dehaye, a data protection specialist, who spearheaded the investigative efforts into the tech giant, said: “Facebook has denied and denied and denied this. It has misled MPs and congressional investigators and it’s failed in its duties to respect the law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It has a legal obligation to inform regulators and individuals about this data breach, and it hasn’t. It’s failed time and time again to be open and transparent.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;element element-pullquote element--supporting&quot;&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;pullquote-paragraph&quot;&gt;We exploited Facebook to harvest millions of profiles. And built models to exploit that and target their inner demons&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;footer&gt;&lt;cite class=&quot;pullquote-cite&quot;&gt;Christopher Wylie&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/footer&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;A majority of American states have laws requiring notification in some cases of data breach, including California, where Facebook is based.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook denies that the harvesting of tens of millions of profiles by GSR and Cambridge Analytica was a data breach. It said in a statement that Kogan “gained access to this information in a legitimate way and through the proper channels” but “did not subsequently abide by our rules” because he passed the information on to third parties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook said it removed the app in 2015 and required certification from everyone with copies that the data had been destroyed, although the letter to Wylie did not arrive until the second half of 2016. “We are committed to vigorously enforcing our policies to protect people’s information. We will take whatever steps are required to see that this happens,” Paul Grewal, Facebook’s vice-president, said in a statement. The company is now investigating reports that not all data had been deleted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kogan, who has previously unreported links to a Russian university and took Russian grants for research, had a licence from Facebook to collect profile data, but it was for research purposes only. So when he hoovered up information for the commercial venture, he was violating the company’s terms. Kogan maintains everything he did was legal, and says he had a “close working relationship” with Facebook, which had granted him permission for his apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details data-snippet-id=&quot;f3bfb547-d871-485d-97ef-51dfb9c158f0&quot; data-snippet-type=&quot;guide&quot; class=&quot;atom atom--snippet atom--snippet--guide&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;atom--snippet__label&quot;&gt;Quick guide&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;atom--snippet__headline&quot;&gt;How the story unfolded&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;button class=&quot;atom__button atom__button--large atom__button--rounded atom--snippet__handle&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;is-on&quot;&gt; Show&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;is-off&quot;&gt; Hide&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/button&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__body&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__item&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In December 2016, while researching the US presidential election, Carole Cadwalladr came across data analytics company Cambridge Analytica, whose secretive manner and chequered track record belied its bland, academic-sounding name.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Her initial investigations uncovered the role of American billionaire Robert Mercer in the US election campaign: his strategic “war” on mainstream media and his political campaign funding, some apparently linked to Brexit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She found the first indications that Cambridge Analytica might have used data processing methods that breached the Data Protection Act. That article prompted Britain’s Electoral Commission and the Information Commissioner’s Office to launch investigations whose remits include Cambridge Analytica’s use of data and its possible links to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/politics/eu-referendum&quot; data-link-name=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; data-component=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Brexit&lt;/a&gt; referendum. These investigations are still continuing, as is a wider ICO inquiry into the use of data in politics.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While chasing the details and ramifications of complex manipulation of both data and funding law, Cadwalladr came under increasing attacks, both online and professionally, from key players.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Leave.EU campaign tweeted a doctored video that showed her being violently assaulted, and the Russian embassy wrote to the Observer to complain that her reporting was a “textbook example of bad journalism”.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But the growing profile of her reports also gave whistleblowers confidence that they could trust her to not only understand their stories, but retell them clearly for a wide audience.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Her network of sources and contacts grew to include not only former employees who regretted their work but academics, lawyers and others concerned about the impact on democracy of tactics employed by Cambridge Analytica and associates.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cambridge Analytica is now the subject of special prosecutor Robert Mueller’s probing of the company’s role in Donald Trump’s presidential election campaign. Investigations in the UK also remain live.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;footer class=&quot;atom--snippet__footer&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__feedback&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Was this helpful?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__ack&quot; hidden=&quot;&quot; aria-role=&quot;alert&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot;&gt;Thank you for your feedback.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/footer&gt;&lt;/details&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Observer&lt;/em&gt; has seen a contract dated 4 June 2014, which confirms SCL, an affiliate of Cambridge Analytica, entered into a commercial arrangement with GSR, entirely premised on harvesting and processing Facebook data. Cambridge Analytica spent nearly $1m on data collection, which yielded more than 50 million individual profiles that could be matched to electoral rolls. It then used the test results and Facebook data to build an algorithm that could analyse individual Facebook profiles and determine personality traits linked to voting behaviour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The algorithm and database together &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2017/may/07/the-great-british-brexit-robbery-hijacked-democracy&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;made a powerful political tool&lt;/a&gt;. It allowed a campaign to identify possible swing voters and craft messages more likely to resonate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The ultimate product of the training set is creating a ‘gold standard’ of understanding personality from Facebook profile information,” the contract specifies. It promises to create a database of 2 million “matched” profiles, identifiable and tied to electoral registers, across 11 states, but with room to expand much further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://interactive.guim.co.uk/uploader/embed/2018/03/ca-who-is-who-zip/giv-3902gJiBgEmGEzJO/&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Key players&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the time, more than 50 million profiles represented around a third of active North American Facebook users, and nearly a quarter of potential US voters. Yet when asked by MPs if any of his firm’s data had come from GSR, Nix said: “We had a relationship with GSR. They did some research for us back in 2014. That research proved to be fruitless and so the answer is no.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cambridge Analytica said that its contract with GSR stipulated that Kogan should seek informed consent for data collection and it had no reason to believe he would not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GSR was “led by a seemingly reputable academic at an internationally renowned institution who made explicit contractual commitments to us regarding its legal authority to license data to SCL Elections”, a company spokesman said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SCL Elections, an affiliate, worked with Facebook over the period to ensure it was satisfied no terms had been “knowingly breached” and provided a signed statement that all data and derivatives had been deleted, he said. Cambridge Analytica also said none of the data was used in the 2016 presidential election.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steve Bannon’s lawyer said he had no comment because his client “knows nothing about the claims being asserted”. He added: “The first Mr Bannon heard of these reports was from media inquiries in the past few days.” He directed inquires to Nix.&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2018 13:54:46 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>tsneed290</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://www.theguardian.com/news/2018/mar/17/cambridge-analytica-facebook-influence-us-election</og:url>
<og:description>Whistleblower describes how firm linked to former Trump adviser Steve Bannon compiled user data to target American voters• How Cambridge Analytica’s algorithms turned ‘likes’ into a political tool</og:description>
<og:image>https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/97532076a6935a1e79eba294437ed91f3eb4df6b/0_626_4480_2688/master/4480.jpg?w=1200&amp;h=630&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;fit=crop&amp;crop=faces%2Centropy&amp;bm=normal&amp;ba=bottom%2Cleft&amp;blend64=aHR0cHM6Ly91cGxvYWRzLmd1aW0uY28udWsvMjAxOC8wMS8zMS9mYWNlYm9va19kZWZhdWx0LnBuZw&amp;s=365825fe053733ae12f9b050f5374594</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Revealed: 50 million Facebook profiles harvested for Cambridge Analytica in major data breach</og:title>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.theguardian.com/news/2018/mar/17/cambridge-analytica-facebook-influence-us-election</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>TinyVM – A small and easy to understand virtual machine in C</title>
<link>https://github.com/jakogut/tinyvm/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/jakogut/tinyvm/</guid>
<description>&lt;h3&gt;README&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;plain&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
TinyVM is a virtual machine with the goal of having a small footprint.
Low memory usage, a small amount of code, and a small binary.

Building can be accomplished on UNIX-like systems with make and GCC.

There are no external dependencies, save the C standard library.

Building can be accomplished using &quot;make,&quot; or &quot;make rebuild&quot;.

To build a debug version, add &quot;DEBUG=yes&quot; after &quot;make&quot;. To build a binary with
profiling enabled, add &quot;PROFILE=yes&quot; after &quot;make&quot;.

I can be reached at &quot;joseph.kogut(at)gmail.com&quot;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2018 12:32:48 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jxub</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars0.githubusercontent.com/u/40163?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>jakogut/tinyvm</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/jakogut/tinyvm</og:url>
<og:description>tinyvm - TinyVM is a small, fast, lightweight virtual machine written in pure ANSI C.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/jakogut/tinyvm/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Nightmare Letter: A Subject Access Request Under GDPR</title>
<link>https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/nightmare-letter-subject-access-request-under-gdpr-karbaliotis/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/nightmare-letter-subject-access-request-under-gdpr-karbaliotis/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I had drafted a letter a few years ago detailing the worst kind of personal information access request that a Canadian company could receive under PIPEDA. I thought it might be useful to update that as a subject access request under GDPR, and present it as a worst-case situation (with thanks to Paul Breitbarth for reviewing this and offering some insights from a regulator's point of view). You might simply use this to make a case to your organization about what it could potentially receive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A more interesting use would be to use this letter for a table-top exercise, similar to those used for data breaches, to see how your organization would respond. It might be very entertaining to have this kind of letter actually sent by a friendly party to your own organization to see exactly how it would be responded to - would the privacy office get alerted? How would the organization respond to someone knowledgeable about both the law and the technologies being used to support data management? Edit as appropriate to create the nightmare of your choosing. A future installment will address the nightmare of rectification, erasure and portability :-).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The nightmare letter:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear Sir/Madam:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am writing to you in your capacity as data protection officer for your company. I am a customer of yours, and in light of recent events, I am making this request for access to personal data pursuant to Article 15 of the &lt;em&gt;General Data Protection Regulation&lt;/em&gt;. I am concerned that your company’s information practices may be putting my personal information at undue risk of exposure or in fact has breached its obligation to safeguard my personal information pursuant to &amp;lt;latest nasty cybersecurity event or thing in the news&amp;gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am including a copy of documentation necessary to verify my identity. If you require further information, please contact me at my address above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would like you to be aware at the outset, that I anticipate reply to my request within one month as required under Article 12, failing which I will be forwarding my inquiry with a letter of complaint to the &amp;lt;appropriate data protection authority&amp;gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please advise as to the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1.   Please confirm to me whether or not my personal data is being processed. If it is, please provide me with the categories of personal data you have about me in your files and databases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a.   In particular, please tell me what you know about me in your information systems, whether or not contained in databases, and including e-mail, documents on your networks, or voice or other media that you may store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b.   Additionally, please advise me in which countries my personal data is stored, or accessible from. In case you make use of cloud services to store or process my data, please include the countries in which the servers are located where my data are or were (in the past 12 months) stored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c.   Please provide me with a copy of, or access to, my personal data that you have or are processing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.   Please provide me with a detailed accounting of the specific uses that you have made, are making, or will be making of my personal data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3.   Please provide a list of all third parties with whom you have (or may have) shared my personal data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a.   If you cannot identify with certainty the specific third parties to whom you have disclosed my personal data, please provide a list of third parties to whom you may have disclosed my personal data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b.   Please also identify which jurisdictions that you have identified in 1(b) above that these third parties with whom you have or may have shared my personal data, from which these third parties have stored or can access my personal data. Please also provide insight in the legal grounds for transferring my personal data to these jurisdictions. Where you have done so, or are doing so, on the basis of appropriate safeguards, please provide a copy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c.   Additionally, I would like to know what safeguards have been put in place in relation to these third parties that you have identified in relation to the transfer of my personal data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4.   Please advise how long you store my personal data, and if retention is based upon the category of personal data, please identify how long each category is retained.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5.   If you are additionally collecting personal data about me from any source other than me, please provide me with all information about their source, as referred to in Article 14 of the GDPR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6.   If you are making automated decisions about me, including profiling, whether or not on the basis of Article 22 of the GDPR, please provide me with information concerning the basis for the logic in making such automated decisions, and the significance and consequences of such processing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7.   I would like to know whether or not my personal data has been disclosed inadvertently by your company in the past, or as a result of a security or privacy breach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a.   If so, please advise as to the following details of each and any such breach:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;                   i.    a general description of what occurred;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;                   ii.    the date and time of the breach (or the best possible estimate);&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;                   iii.    the date and time the breach was discovered;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;                   iv.    the source of the breach (either your own organization, or a third party to whom you have transferred my personal data);&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;                    v.    details of my personal data that was disclosed;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;                    vi.    your company’s assessment of the risk of harm to myself, as a result of the breach;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;                    vii.    a description of the measures taken or that will be taken to prevent further unauthorized access to my personal data;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;                    viii.    contact information so that I can obtain more information and assistance in relation to such a breach, and&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;                     ix.    information and advice on what I can do to protect myself against any harms, including identity theft and fraud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b.   If you are not able to state with any certainty whether such an exposure has taken place, through the use of appropriate technologies, please advise what mitigating steps you have taken, such as&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;                      i.    Encryption of my personal data;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;                      ii.    Data minimization strategies; or,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;                      iii.    Anonymization or pseudonymization;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;                      iv.    Any other means&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8.   I would like to know your information policies and standards that you follow in relation to the safeguarding of my personal data, such as whether you adhere to ISO27001 for information security, and more particularly, your practices in relation to the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a.   Please inform me whether you have backed up my personal data to tape, disk or other media, and where it is stored and how it is secured, including what steps you have taken to protect my personal data from loss or theft, and whether this includes encryption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b.   Please also advise whether you have in place any technology which allows you with reasonable certainty to know whether or not my personal data has been disclosed, including but not limited to the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;                     i.    Intrusion detection systems;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;                     ii.    Firewall technologies;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;                     iii.    Access and identity management technologies;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;                     iv.    Database audit and/or security tools; or,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;                     v.    Behavioural analysis tools, log analysis tools, or audit tools;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;9.   In regards to employees and contractors, please advise as to the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a.   What technologies or business procedures do you have to ensure that individuals within your organization will be monitored to ensure that they do not deliberately or inadvertently disclose personal data outside your company, through e-mail, web-mail or instant messaging, or otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b.   Have you had had any circumstances in which employees or contractors have been dismissed, and/or been charged under criminal laws for accessing my personal data inappropriately, or if you are unable to determine this, of any customers, in the past twelve months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c.   Please advise as to what training and awareness measures you have taken in order to ensure that employees and contractors are accessing and processing my personal data in conformity with the &lt;em&gt;General Data Protection Regulation&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yours Sincerely,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I. Rate&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2018 12:15:09 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jjp</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>The Nightmare Letter: A Subject Access Request under GDPR</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/nightmare-letter-subject-access-request-under-gdpr-karbaliotis</og:url>
<og:description>I had drafted a letter a few years ago detailing the worst kind of personal information access request that a Canadian company could receive under</og:description>
<og:image>https://static.licdn.com/sc/p/com.linkedin.pulse-web%3Apulse-web-static-content%2B0.2.167/f/%2Fpulse-web-frontend%2Fimages%2Fwalter%2Farticle%2Fpublished_on_linkedin.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/nightmare-letter-subject-access-request-under-gdpr-karbaliotis/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>iOS 11 bugs are so common they now appear in Apple ads</title>
<link>https://www.theverge.com/2018/3/16/17131148/apple-ios-11-bug-face-id-ad</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.theverge.com/2018/3/16/17131148/apple-ios-11-bug-face-id-ad</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;0irP7f&quot;&gt;If you blink during Apple’s latest iPhone ad, you might miss a weird little animation bug. It’s right at the end of a slickly produced commercial, where the text from an iMessage escapes the animated bubble it’s supposed to stay inside. It’s a minor issue and easy to brush off, but the fact it’s captured in such a high profile ad just further highlights Apple’s many bugs in iOS 11.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;y8wnPd&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;9to5Mac&lt;/em&gt; writer Benjamin Mayo &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/bzamayo/status/974734836115099649&quot;&gt;spotted the bug&lt;/a&gt; in Apple’s latest ad, and he’s clearly surprised “that this was signed off for the commercial,” especially as he &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/bzamayo/status/927559914792288256&quot;&gt;highlighted it months ago&lt;/a&gt; and has filed a bug report with Apple. It’s just one of many quirks in iOS 11, including strange UI problems in the Music app, regularly &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/tomwarren/status/921016374364917760&quot;&gt;misaligned text in the App Store&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/tomwarren/status/952251306869248002&quot;&gt;vanishing docks&lt;/a&gt;, and rotation issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;RQK6ky&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/-pF5bV6bFOU?rel=0&amp;amp;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;MNSWIj&quot;&gt;It’s easy to dismiss all of these small problems because they’re not the types of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2017/12/2/16727238/apple-macos-ios-software-problems-updates&quot;&gt;Apple security bugs&lt;/a&gt; that have hit the headlines recently, but they all add up to a frustrating experience at times. &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1TDCVavaqDJCFjcQxZsL6InzHxPEYWwMMMh9QtfRGjbY/edit&quot;&gt;Chris Pirillo has been documenting&lt;/a&gt; iOS animation bugs for years now, highlighting the many bugs that have sneaked into iOS recently. “iOS has been performing in an inexplicably jarring manner since iOS 7,” says Pirillo in an open letter to Apple’s software engineering chief Craig Federighi. “Iterations don’t seem to help much, major or minor. Frame drops are now par for the course — irritations that we once slammed Android for.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;RBAUya&quot;&gt;There are signs that Apple is finally about to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2018/1/30/16949802/apple-ios-12-next-version-update-focus-reliability-performance-new-features&quot;&gt;focus on reliability and performance in iOS 12&lt;/a&gt; over new features, though. Reports suggest Apple is delaying some major iOS additions, and planning to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-02-12/how-apple-plans-to-root-out-bugs-revamp-iphone-software&quot;&gt;root out bugs from its software&lt;/a&gt;. Hopefully that will mean less of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2018/2/15/17015654/apple-iphone-crash-ios-11-bug-imessage&quot;&gt;embarrassing bugs that crash iPhones&lt;/a&gt;, but also far less of these weird animation and UI problems that iOS clearly struggles with at times. We’ll probably find out once we hear &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2018/3/13/17115548/apple-wwdc-2018-june-date-san-jose&quot;&gt;more about iOS 12 in June&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2018 08:05:08 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Mononokay</dc:creator>
<og:description>Blink and you’ll miss it</og:description>
<og:image>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/KrkgxxkA4bN4-8jQN8waCiVh0qI=/0x4:1200x632/fit-in/1200x630/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/10441333/DYb0KYDW4AA9wG1.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>iOS 11 bugs are so common they now appear in Apple ads</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.theverge.com/2018/3/16/17131148/apple-ios-11-bug-face-id-ad</og:url>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.theverge.com/2018/3/16/17131148/apple-ios-11-bug-face-id-ad</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Inheritance Often Doesn&amp;#039;t Make Sense</title>
<link>https://www.sicpers.info/2018/03/why-inheritance-never-made-any-sense/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.sicpers.info/2018/03/why-inheritance-never-made-any-sense/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;There are three different types of inheritance going on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ontological&lt;/em&gt; inheritance is about specialisation: this thing is a specific variety of that thing (a football &lt;em&gt;is a&lt;/em&gt; sphere &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; it has this radius)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Abstract data type&lt;/em&gt; inheritance is about substitution: this thing behaves in all the ways that thing does &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; has this behaviour (this is the Liskov substitution principle)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Implementation&lt;/em&gt; inheritance is about code sharing: this thing takes &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; of the properties of that thing &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; overrides or augments them in this way. The inheritance in my post &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sicpers.info/2018/03/on-inheritance/&quot;&gt;On Inheritance&lt;/a&gt; is this type and &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; this type of inheritance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;These are three different, and frequently irreconcilable, relationships. Requiring any, or even all, of them, presents no difficulty. However, requiring &lt;em&gt;one mechanism&lt;/em&gt; support any two or more of them is asking for trouble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A common counterexample to OO inheritance is the relationship between a square and a rectangle. Geometrically, a square &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; a specialisation of a rectangle: every square is a rectangle, not every rectangle is a square. For all s in Squares, s is a Rectangle and width of s is equal to height of s. As a type, this relationship is reversed: you can use a rectangle everywhere you can use a square (by having a rectangle with the same width and height), but you cannot use a square everywhere you can use a rectangle (for example, you can’t give it a different width and height).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice that this is incompatibility between the inheritance directions of the &lt;em&gt;geometric properties&lt;/em&gt; and the &lt;em&gt;abstract data type properties&lt;/em&gt; of squares and rectangles; two dimensions which are completely unrelated to each other and indeed to any form of software implementation. We have so far said nothing about implementation inheritance, so haven’t even considered writing software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smalltalk and many later languages use single inheritance for implementation inheritance, because multiple inheritance is &lt;em&gt;incompatible&lt;/em&gt; with the goal of implementation inheritance due to the diamond problem (traits provide a &lt;em&gt;reliable&lt;/em&gt; way for the incompatibility to manifest, and leave resolution as an exercise to the reader). On the other hand, single inheritance is &lt;em&gt;incompatible&lt;/em&gt; with ontological inheritance, as a square is both a rectangle and an equilateral polygon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Smalltalk blue book describes inheritance &lt;em&gt;solely&lt;/em&gt; in terms of implementation inheritance:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A subclass specifies that its instances will be the same as instances of another class, called its &lt;em&gt;superclass&lt;/em&gt;, except for the differences that are explicitly stated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice what is missing: no mention that a subclass instance must be able to replace a superclass instance everywhere in a program; no mention that a subclass instance must satisfy all conceptual tests for an instance of its superclass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Inheritance&lt;/em&gt; was never a problem: trying to use &lt;em&gt;the same tree&lt;/em&gt; for &lt;em&gt;three different concepts&lt;/em&gt; was the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Favour composition over inheritance” is basically giving up on implementation inheritance. We can’t work out how to make it work, so we’ll avoid it: get implementation sharing by delegation instead of by subclassing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eiffel, and particular disciplined approaches to using languages like Java, tighten up the “inheritance is subtyping” relationship by relaxing the “inheritance is re-use” relationship (if the same method appears twice in unrelated parts of the tree, you have to live with it, in order to retain the property that every subclass is a subtype of its parent). This is fine, as long as you don’t try to &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; model the problem domain using the inheritance tree, but much of the OO literature recommends that you do by talking about domain-driven design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traits approaches tighten up the “inheritance is specialisation” relationship by relaxing the “inheritance is re-use” relationship (if two super categories both provide the same property of an instance of a category, neither is provided and you have to write it yourself). This is fine, as long as you don’t try to &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; treat subclasses as covariant subtypes of their superclasses, but much of the OO literature recommends that you do by talking about Liskov Substitution Principle and how a type in a method signature means that type &lt;em&gt;or any subclass&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What the literature &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; do, I believe, is say “here are the three types of inheritance, focus on any one of them at a time”. I also believe that the &lt;em&gt;languages&lt;/em&gt; should support that (obviously Smalltalk, Ruby and friends &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; support that by not having any type constraints).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;If I’m using inheritance as a code sharing tool, it should not be assumed that my subclasses are also subtypes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If I am using subtypes to tighten up interface contracts, I should be not only &lt;em&gt;allowed&lt;/em&gt; to mark a class anywhere in the tree as a subtype of another class anywhere in the tree, but &lt;em&gt;required&lt;/em&gt; to do so: once again, it should not be assumed that my subclasses are also subtypes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If I need to indicate conceptual specialisation via classes, this should &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; not be assumed to follow the inheritance tree. I should be not only &lt;em&gt;allowed&lt;/em&gt; to mark a class anywhere in the tree as a subset of another class, but &lt;em&gt;required&lt;/em&gt; to do so: once again, it should not be assumed that my subclasses are also specialisations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Your domain model is not your object model. Your domain model is not your abstract data type model. Your object model is not your abstract data type model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now inheritance is easy again.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2018 06:22:42 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>signa11</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Why inheritance never made any sense</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.sicpers.info/2018/03/why-inheritance-never-made-any-sense/</og:url>
<og:description>There are three different types of inheritance going on. Ontological inheritance is about specialisation: this thing is a specific variety of that thing (a football is a sphere and it has this radi…</og:description>
<og:image>https://s0.wp.com/i/blank.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.sicpers.info/2018/03/why-inheritance-never-made-any-sense/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>At My Lai: The Photographer Who Captured the Massacre</title>
<link>https://foto.gettyimages.com/archive/war/my-lai-massacre-anniversary-pictures-ron-haeberle/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://foto.gettyimages.com/archive/war/my-lai-massacre-anniversary-pictures-ron-haeberle/</guid>
<description>&lt;span class=&quot;img-attribution&quot;&gt;Ronald L. Haeberle/The LIFE Images Collection/Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By Evelyn Theiss&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photographs of My Lai by Ron Haeberle&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A note to our readers: This story contains photographs that are violent and disturbing.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;drop-cap&quot;&gt;Ron Haeberle was a combat photographer in Vietnam when he and the Army unit he was riding with — Charlie Company, 1st Battalion, 20th Infantry Regiment — landed near the hamlet of My Lai on the morning of March 16, 1968. Villagers weren't alarmed; American GIs had visited the region near the central Vietnamese coast before, without incident. But within minutes, the troops opened fire. Over the course of the next few hours, they killed old men, women, and children. They raped and tortured. They razed the village. And when Haeberle's shocking photographs of their atrocities were published — more than a year later — the pictures laid bare an appalling truth: American &quot;boys&quot; were as capable of unbridled savagery as any soldiers, anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To mark the 50th anniversary of the massacre, I spoke with Haeberle — in an exclusive interview, at his home in Ohio — about that March morning; the routine Army operation that devolved into a waking nightmare; and how his photos changed the course of the war in Vietnam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://foto.gettyimages.com/photos/horizontalCrop-GYI515288626-story-large.jpg&quot; title=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-asset-id=&quot;515288626&quot; data-is360-image=&quot;false&quot; data-embeddable=&quot;false&quot; data-orientation=&quot;horizontal&quot; class=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;img-attribution&quot;&gt;Bettmann Archive&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I first met Ron Haeberle in 2009 when I was a reporter at the Cleveland Plain Dealer — the newspaper that, in November 1969, first published his My Lai photos. I was assigned to write a story on the 40th anniversary of that landmark exposé, and while much had previously been written about the Plain Dealer reporter who wrote the article that ran alongside Haeberle's photos — Joe Eszterhas, later the screenwriter of &quot;Basic Instinct&quot; and other controversial films — I found almost nothing about the man who took the grisly, iconic pictures at My Lai. Was he still alive? Did he still live in Ohio?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found a name, address, and phone number, but wasn’t sure if it was &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; Ron Haeberle. Knowing that a reticent Haeberle might hang up if I called, I drove to the address, knocked on the door, and introduced myself. It was Ron, all right, and he graciously asked me in. I stayed at his house for two hours, as he told me about My Lai and his own life since 1968. It was his first major interview since the story broke four decades earlier. (He gave the BBC a couple of quotes in 1989, he said, and that was the extent of his contact with the press.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, FOTO asked me to approach Haeberle and ask if he would revisit the story for the 50th anniversary of the massacre. He agreed, and he and I returned to one of the darkest chapters in American history, and his role in bringing it to light.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://foto.gettyimages.com/photos/helicopters-that-brought-company-c-soldiers-to-mylai-for-assualt-picture-id50654720-story-large.jpg&quot; title=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-asset-id=&quot;50654720&quot; data-is360-image=&quot;false&quot; data-embeddable=&quot;false&quot; data-orientation=&quot;horizontal&quot; class=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;img-attribution&quot;&gt;Ronald L. Haeberle/The LIFE Images Collection/Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ron Haeberle was drafted in 1966, after attending Ohio University, where he was a photographer for the school paper. He ended up in Hawaii with the Army’s Public Information Office. By the end of 1967, it was beginning to look like his &quot;tour&quot; would end there — a disappointing prospect. “As a photographer, I wanted to see what was happening in Vietnam for myself,&quot; he told me. He requested a transfer, and was sent to Vietnam. At 26 years old, he was older than most members of Charlie Company, where the average age was just 20.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://foto.gettyimages.com/photos/american-soldier-stoking-fire-of-burning-houses-during-the-my-lai-on-picture-id50654721-story-large.jpg&quot; title=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-asset-id=&quot;50654721&quot; data-is360-image=&quot;false&quot; data-embeddable=&quot;false&quot; data-orientation=&quot;horizontal&quot; class=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;img-attribution&quot;&gt;Ronald L. Haeberle/The LIFE Images Collection/Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Charlie Company had been together for about a year before Haeberle joined it in March 1968. The unit had been in no firefights, but had lost men to booby traps and land mines. When they landed at My Lai, they were primed for action; Viet Cong troops were reported to be hiding in the hamlet. That information was wrong. But in the end, it didn't matter: My Lai was doomed. Within four hours of Charlie Company's arrival, the village's huts were burned to the ground and hundreds of civilians were dead. (The exact number of those murdered is disputed to this day, with the official American estimate running to around 350; the Vietnamese say more than 500 were killed.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Haeberle told me that he had just met the men in his unit that morning. Almost as soon as they landed, he said, “I heard a lot of firing and thought, ‘Hell, we must be in a hot zone.' But after a couple of minutes we weren’t taking any fire, so we started walking toward the village. I saw what appeared to be civilians. Then I saw a soldier firing at them. I could not figure out what was going on. I couldn’t comprehend it.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;graphic-content&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://foto.gettyimages.com/photos/civilians-killed-by-us-army-during-pursuit-of-vietcong-militia-as-per-picture-id50465292-story-large.jpg&quot; title=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-asset-id=&quot;50465292&quot; data-is360-image=&quot;false&quot; data-embeddable=&quot;false&quot; data-orientation=&quot;horizontal&quot; class=&quot; sensitive&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;img-attribution&quot;&gt;Ronald L. Haeberle/The LIFE Images Collection/Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;graphic-content-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;graphic-content-lightbox&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WARNING: GRAPHIC CONTENT&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, show it&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;p&gt;This photograph of murdered villagers in My Lai appeared — in black and white, not in its original color — on the front page of the Cleveland Plain Dealer on November 20, 1969. (Haeberle took the pictures not with his Army-issued Leica camera, but with his own camera, a Nikon.) Most of the victims at My Lai were shot; some were bayoneted. Women and girls were raped, and then killed. At least one soldier later confessed to cutting out villagers' tongues, and scalping others. Of course, My Lai was hardly the only instance of rape, torture, and murder by U.S. troops in Vietnam. But in terms of intensity and scale — and because of Haeberle's memorable photographs — it remains the emblematic massacre of the war.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, Ron Haeberle lives about 40 miles from downtown Cleveland, in an attractive house on a quiet cul de sac. His home is simply furnished, clean, and orderly. Original works of art by Vietnamese artists, mostly abstracts, adorn the walls. One is a delicate needlework portrait of a woman, gracefully reaching an arm toward the sky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;graphic-content&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://foto.gettyimages.com/photos/corpses-of-vietnamese-civilians-killed-by-american-soldiers-during-picture-id50369688-story-large.jpg&quot; title=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-asset-id=&quot;50369688&quot; data-is360-image=&quot;false&quot; data-embeddable=&quot;false&quot; data-orientation=&quot;horizontal&quot; class=&quot; sensitive&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;img-attribution&quot;&gt;Ronald L. Haeberle/The LIFE Images Collection/Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;graphic-content-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;graphic-content-lightbox&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WARNING: GRAPHIC CONTENT&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, show it&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;p&gt;The suddenness of the violence at My Lai was especially terrifying. Haeberle told me that he saw an old man with two small children walking toward U.S. troops, their belongings in a basket. &quot;The old man was shouting, ‘No VC! No VC!' to let the soldiers know he wasn’t Viet Cong,&quot; Haeberle recalled. To his horror, the man and the children were cut down in front of him. &quot;A soldier shot all three,&quot; he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;graphic-content&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://foto.gettyimages.com/photos/vietnamese-civilians-killed-by-us-army-soldiers-during-pursuit-of-picture-id50538002-story-large.jpg&quot; title=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-asset-id=&quot;50538002&quot; data-is360-image=&quot;false&quot; data-embeddable=&quot;false&quot; data-orientation=&quot;horizontal&quot; class=&quot; sensitive&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;img-attribution&quot;&gt;Ronald L. Haeberle/The LIFE Images Collection/Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;graphic-content-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;graphic-content-lightbox&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WARNING: GRAPHIC CONTENT&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, show it&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was more than a year after the massacre before Haeberle approached the Plain Dealer with his photos, but he had begun sharing his My Lai pictures, in slideshow talks to civic groups and even local high schools, after he returned home to northern Ohio in the spring of 1968. The first slides he showed were innocuous: troops with smiling Vietnamese kids; medics helping villagers. Then images of dead and mutilated women and children filled the screen. “There was just disbelief,&quot; Haeberle said of the reaction. &quot;People said, ‘No, no, no. This cannot have happened.'&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://foto.gettyimages.com/photos/group-of-civilian-women-and-children-rounded-up-to-be-killed-by-us-picture-id50654722-story-large.jpg&quot; title=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-asset-id=&quot;50654722&quot; data-is360-image=&quot;false&quot; data-embeddable=&quot;false&quot; data-orientation=&quot;vertical&quot; class=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;img-attribution&quot;&gt;Ronald L. Haeberle/The LIFE Images Collection/Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At one point in the killing spree, Haeberle and Army reporter Jay Roberts came upon a group of villagers huddled in fear after troops assaulted a number of young women. Haeberle took this photo — a tearful, frantic mother filling the center of the frame — and as he and Roberts moved on from the scene, rifle fire exploded behind them. “I thought the soldiers were interrogating them,” Haeberle told me. “Then I heard the firing. I couldn’t turn to look. But out of the corner of my eye, I saw them fall.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Haeberle's picture of terror and distress on these faces, young and old, in the midst of slaughter remains one of the 20th century's most powerful photographs. When the Plain Dealer (and later, LIFE magazine) published it, along with a half-dozen others, the images graphically undercut much of what the U.S. had been claiming for years about the conduct and aims of the conflict. Anti-war protesters needed no persuading, but &quot;average&quot; Americans were suddenly asking, &lt;em&gt;What&lt;/em&gt; are &lt;em&gt;we doing in Vietnam?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;graphic-content&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://foto.gettyimages.com/photos/corpse-of-vietnamese-civilian-killed-by-american-soldiers-during-picture-id50538000-story-large.jpg&quot; title=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-asset-id=&quot;50538000&quot; data-is360-image=&quot;false&quot; data-embeddable=&quot;false&quot; data-orientation=&quot;horizontal&quot; class=&quot; sensitive&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;img-attribution&quot;&gt;Ronald L. Haeberle/The LIFE Images Collection/Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;graphic-content-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;graphic-content-lightbox&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WARNING: GRAPHIC CONTENT&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, show it&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;p&gt;At times, the discovery of a single body was as jarring as coming upon dozens of corpses. Walking toward a dirt road known as Route 521, Haeberle and Jay Roberts noticed a woman in the distance. “She was hiding behind a rock. I saw her stand up, then heard shots,” Haeberle told me, the scene obviously sharp in his mind's eye 50 years later. “I knew she’d been hit because she fell back behind the rock. Later, I found her lying there and took this photo.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;graphic-content&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://foto.gettyimages.com/photos/corpses-of-vietnamese-civilians-killed-by-american-soldiers-during-picture-id50538001-story-large.jpg&quot; title=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-asset-id=&quot;50538001&quot; data-is360-image=&quot;false&quot; data-embeddable=&quot;false&quot; data-orientation=&quot;vertical&quot; class=&quot; sensitive&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;img-attribution&quot;&gt;Ronald L. Haeberle/The LIFE Images Collection/Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;graphic-content-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;graphic-content-lightbox&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WARNING: GRAPHIC CONTENT&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, show it&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;p&gt;Awful images, not all of them captured on camera, remain with Haeberle to this day: a soldier nonchalantly shooting a young boy; another riding a water buffalo, repeatedly stabbing it with his bayonet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The massacre was first reported by journalist Seymour Hersh and distributed by a small wire agency, Dispatch News Service, in the second week of November 1969. (Hersh won the 1970 Pulitzer Prize for International Reporting for his work.) A week after Hersh's article appeared in dozens of papers around the U.S., the Plain Dealer ran its own story — along with Haeberle's photos to bolster the reports of a massacre.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://foto.gettyimages.com/photos/head-of-man-floating-in-well-during-mylai-massacre-picture-id50537996-story-large.jpg&quot; title=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-asset-id=&quot;50537996&quot; data-is360-image=&quot;false&quot; data-embeddable=&quot;false&quot; data-orientation=&quot;horizontal&quot; class=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;img-attribution&quot;&gt;Ronald L. Haeberle/The LIFE Images Collection/Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Haeberle said it was an automatic response to continue taking pictures, even as the brutality escalated. “As a photographer, my role was to capture what was happening during the operation,&quot; he told me. &quot;I did feel that what I was shooting was historic, especially the carnage. I kept thinking, 'This is not right.' It was mind-boggling.&quot; (Above: Haeberle's reflection, with camera, can be seen at the top of this picture, as he photographs a corpse in a well. A soldier had shot an old man and dumped his body. &quot;They told me they threw him down there to poison the water supply,&quot; Haeberle said.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, trying to make sense of the unfathomable, Haeberle recalls the message imparted to so many soldiers before their arrival in Vietnam. &quot;We were told, 'Life is meaningless to these people,'&quot; he said, leaving unspoken the rest of that sentiment: &lt;em&gt;The enemy is not like us. They're not quite human.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://foto.gettyimages.com/photos/american-soldiers-helping-wounded-comrade-during-the-my-lai-massacre-picture-id50654717-story-large.jpg&quot; title=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-asset-id=&quot;50654717&quot; data-is360-image=&quot;false&quot; data-embeddable=&quot;false&quot; data-orientation=&quot;vertical&quot; class=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;img-attribution&quot;&gt;Ronald L. Haeberle/The LIFE Images Collection/Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the photo above, American troops help a wounded comrade at My Lai. According to Haeberle, the soldier shot himself in the foot with his own gun. Haeberle can't say if the injury was a genuine accident or self-inflicted — perhaps a way to &quot;honorably&quot; avoid taking part in the carnage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://foto.gettyimages.com/photos/houses-burned-by-american-soldiers-during-the-my-lai-massacre-on-16-picture-id50537994-story-large.jpg&quot; title=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-asset-id=&quot;50537994&quot; data-is360-image=&quot;false&quot; data-embeddable=&quot;false&quot; data-orientation=&quot;horizontal&quot; class=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;img-attribution&quot;&gt;Ronald L. Haeberle/The LIFE Images Collection/Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the late morning of March 16th, bodies were scattered everywhere in My Lai: some, like those above, were covered with straw and set alight. Elsewhere, soldiers had herded dozens of villagers into a roadside ditch and shot them. A few children survived by hiding under corpses. “Early on, after the old man and those two children were killed, Jay Roberts and I confronted (Charlie Company Capt. Ernest) Medina,&quot; Haeberle said, &quot;and told him what we'd seen.&quot; But Medina could not, or would not, help. Haeberle said that he and Roberts saw Medina again later, in the village, but the captain was on a field radio and would not speak to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Medina faced a court martial in 1971, and was acquitted. (American helicopter pilot Hugh Thompson, gunner Lawrence Colburn, and crew chief Glenn Andreotta, who arrived in the midst of the massacre, were each awarded the Soldier's Medal for heroism on the 30th anniversary of My Lai, in recognition of their attempts to intervene and save villagers' lives, while risking their own.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://foto.gettyimages.com/photos/fort-benning-ga-army-1st-lt-william-l-calley-jr-arrives-january-20th-picture-id515289142-story-large.jpg&quot; title=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-asset-id=&quot;515289142&quot; data-is360-image=&quot;false&quot; data-embeddable=&quot;false&quot; data-orientation=&quot;horizontal&quot; class=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;img-attribution&quot;&gt;Bettmann/Bettmann Archive&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Haeberle's searing photos, along with stories in the Plain Dealer and other outlets in the fall of 1969, sparked outrage and soul-searching in much of America. The Army, meanwhile, had known about the massacre from the start, and had engaged in a long (and ultimately fruitless) cover-up. Of the dozen or so officers and others in Charlie Company who eventually faced court martial, only Lt. William Calley (pictured, center) was convicted. In the spring of 1971 he was found guilty of murder and sentenced to life in prison. President Richard Nixon reduced the sentence to house arrest; Calley served three and a half years in his quarters at Fort Benning, Georgia. He is the only person found guilty in military or criminal court for the atrocities at My Lai.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ron Haeberle never sought the spotlight. But he gets some solace knowing that his pictures mattered. “Photography can be a powerful medium,&quot; he said. &quot;It serves as evidence, as documentation. Without those photos, My Lai would have stayed hidden. Calley would not have been charged. After seeing the pictures, people had to re-think the war.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;inline-img-container&quot; readability=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;side-by-side&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://foto.gettyimages.com/photos/closeCrop-GYI50537998-story-large.jpg&quot; title=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-asset-id=&quot;50537998&quot; data-is360-image=&quot;false&quot; data-embeddable=&quot;false&quot; data-orientation=&quot;horizontal&quot; class=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;p data-img-idx=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;img-attribution&quot;&gt;Ronald L. Haeberle/The LIFE Images Collection/Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;side-by-side&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://foto.gettyimages.com/photos/Ron_Duc-story-large.jpeg&quot; title=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-asset-id=&quot;&quot; data-is360-image=&quot;false&quot; data-embeddable=&quot;false&quot; data-orientation=&quot;horizontal&quot; class=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;p data-img-idx=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;img-attribution&quot;&gt;Courtesy of Ron Haeberle&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;p&gt;Haeberle told me that he returned to My Lai in 2011, where he met Duc Tran Van, a survivor of the massacre. Duc was eight years old in March 1968, and as Haeberle spoke with him, through an interpreter, he realized with a jolt that the woman he had photographed dead behind a rock 43 years earlier was Duc’s mother, Nguyen Thi Tau.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Duc told Haeberle that his mother urged him to run, with his 20-month-old sister, to their grandmother's house. When he heard a helicopter above them, Duc threw himself to the ground to protect his sister, who was already wounded. Haeberle had captured that moment, as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Duc and Haeberle have since become friends (above, right: Haeberle and Duc in Vietnam in 2011), and the Army veteran has visited Duc in Germany, where he now lives. “Duc has a small shrine to his family in his home,” Haeberle said. “I took the last photo of his mother. So I gave him my camera, the Nikon I used at My Lai, for the shrine.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Haeberle is a thoughtful, plainspoken man. When I asked him if the publication of his pictures from My Lai changed the course of his own life, his response was characteristically muted. “How can we know that sort of thing?” he asked me. “What can we really know when we’re looking to the future? The photos made me more well-known than I might have been. But I just kept moving ahead.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://foto.gettyimages.com/photos/this-picture-taken-on-may-8-2014-shows-a-general-view-of-rice-fields-picture-id492383275-story-large.jpg&quot; title=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-asset-id=&quot;492383275&quot; data-is360-image=&quot;false&quot; data-embeddable=&quot;true&quot; data-orientation=&quot;horizontal&quot; class=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;img-attribution&quot;&gt;HOANG DINH NAM/AFP/Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Haeberle left Vietnam in 1968, he flew to his brother’s home in Seattle, overlooking Puget Sound. “I sat without moving, for six hours,” he told me. “The sky and the water were so blue — I looked out the window and just tried to let everything go.&quot; Many others in Charlie Company turned to alcohol and drugs. A number later spoke of the guilt they felt. At least one is known to have committed suicide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Haeberle is 76 years old, retired after years in manufacturing, divorced, with a grown daughter. He skis in winter, and kayaks in summer. An avid cyclist, he often heads west in the spring — Utah, California — for long cycling trips. He likes &quot;feeling like an ant amid the mountains,&quot; he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He has returned to Vietnam (above), and to My Lai several times, and will be there again on the 50th anniversary of the massacre. “The people in My Lai say they forgive us,” he told me. “They are a very forgiving people.” Haeberle has never regretted sharing his photos with the world. But that one act, he said, does not define his life. In his living room, 8,000 miles from My Lai, he said he's proud that he still has &quot;an adventurous spirit&quot; — connecting, for example, with Duc and other survivors in Vietnam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As he spoke, the afternoon light in Ohio was fading. &quot;I'm still learning,&quot; Haeberle said, &quot;about what the world has to offer.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find more about My Lai and its aftermath at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pbs.org/wgbh/americanexperience/films/mylai/&quot;&gt;PBS.org&lt;/a&gt; and at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/1972/01/22/i-coverup&quot;&gt;The New Yorker&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2018 02:08:13 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>user982</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://foto.gettyimages.com/archive/war/my-lai-massacre-anniversary-pictures-ron-haeberle/</og:url>
<og:title>At My Lai: The Photographer Who Captured the Massacre</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:image>https://foto.gettyimages.com/photos/an-american-soldier-firing-his-m16-rifle-during-the-my-lai-massacre-picture-id50654718-share.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>During the Vietnam War, Ron Haeberle documented the murder of civilians by U.S. troops. Fifty years later, he talks with FOTO about how his pictures changed the course of the conflict.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://foto.gettyimages.com/archive/war/my-lai-massacre-anniversary-pictures-ron-haeberle/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>