<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Google Urged the U.S. to Limit Protection for Activist Workers</title>
<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-01-24/google-urged-the-u-s-to-limit-protection-for-activist-workers</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-01-24/google-urged-the-u-s-to-limit-protection-for-activist-workers</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-01-24/google-urged-the-u-s-to-limit-protection-for-activist-workers&quot;&gt;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-01-24/google-urged-the-u-s-to-limit-protection-for-activist-workers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=18987642&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=18987642&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 323&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 82&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2019 11:08:30 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>pseudolus</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bloomberg.com/tosv2.html?vid=&amp;uuid=51719b50-1ff1-11e9-b808-917842c87624&amp;url=L25ld3MvYXJ0aWNsZXMvMjAxOS0wMS0yNC9nb29nbGUtdXJnZWQtdGhlLXUtcy10by1saW1pdC1wcm90ZWN0aW9uLWZvci1hY3RpdmlzdC13b3JrZXJz</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Apple Lays Off 200 Employees from Autonomous Car Unit</title>
<link>https://www.cnbc.com/2019/01/24/apple-lays-off-over-200-from-project-titan-autonomous-vehicle-group.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.cnbc.com/2019/01/24/apple-lays-off-over-200-from-project-titan-autonomous-vehicle-group.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;group&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;inline_quotes&quot; data-gdsid=&quot;8016&quot; data-inline-quote-symbol=&quot;AAPL&quot; href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/quotes/?symbol=AAPL&quot;&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt; dismissed just over 200 employees this week from Project Titan, its stealthy autonomous vehicle group, people familiar with the matter told CNBC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An Apple spokesperson acknowledged the layoffs and said the company still sees opportunity in the space:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;We have an incredibly talented team working on autonomous systems and associated technologies at Apple. As the team focuses their work on several key areas for 2019, some groups are being moved to projects in other parts of the company, where they will support machine learning and other initiatives, across all of Apple,&quot; the spokesperson said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;We continue to believe there is a huge opportunity with autonomous systems, that Apple has unique capabilities to contribute, and that this is the most ambitious machine learning project ever.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;group&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In August, Apple enlisted a &lt;a class=&quot;inline_quotes&quot; data-gdsid=&quot;74213&quot; data-inline-quote-symbol=&quot;TSLA&quot; href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/quotes/?symbol=TSLA&quot;&gt;Tesla&lt;/a&gt; engineering vice president and Apple veteran, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/2018/07/02/tesla-engineering-leader-doug-field-departs.html&quot;&gt;Doug Field&lt;/a&gt;, to lead the Titan team alongside Bob Mansfield. This week's dismissals from the group were seen internally as anticipated restructuring under the relatively new leadership.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other employees who were impacted by the restructuring of Project Titan are staying at Apple, but moving to different parts of the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CEO &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/tim-cook/&quot;&gt;Tim Cook&lt;/a&gt; has been touting Apple's initiatives in health as the key to its future. &quot;I believe, if you zoom out into the future, and you look back, and you ask the question, 'What was Apple's greatest contribution to mankind?' it will be about health,&quot; Cook told CNBC's Jim Cramer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;group&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple executives have been mum in recent months about the company's car prospects, which appear to have been scaled back from the initial rumored vehicle to a focus on software. In 2016, Apple laid off employees from the same group, shifting its strategy. Fully self-driving cars remain experimental, even for major players in the field such as Waymo, Cruise and Tesla.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Venture and strategic investors from the traditional automotive world have poured billions into start-ups developing self-driving vehicles including Zoox, Pony.AI, Aurora, May Mobility and Embark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;— CNBC's Jordan Novet contributed to this report.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2019 06:20:43 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>tmp092</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.cnbc.com/2019/01/24/apple-lays-off-over-200-from-project-titan-autonomous-vehicle-group.html</og:url>
<og:image>https://fm.cnbc.com/applications/cnbc.com/resources/img/editorial/2018/12/04/105608423-1543945404083rts28r8i.1910x1000.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>Apple just dismissed more than 200 employees from its autonomous vehicle group</og:title>
<og:description>The layoffs were billed internally as a restructuring under Titan's relatively new leadership.</og:description>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.cnbc.com/2019/01/24/apple-lays-off-over-200-from-project-titan-autonomous-vehicle-group.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Canadian meat giant Maple Leaf debuts new plant-based burger</title>
<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-01-23/canadian-meat-giant-maple-leaf-debuts-new-plant-based-burger</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-01-23/canadian-meat-giant-maple-leaf-debuts-new-plant-based-burger</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-01-23/canadian-meat-giant-maple-leaf-debuts-new-plant-based-burger&quot;&gt;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-01-23/canadian-meat-giant-maple-leaf-debuts-new-plant-based-burger&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=18983709&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=18983709&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 205&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 156&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2019 22:18:21 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>JumpCrisscross</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bloomberg.com/tosv2.html?vid=&amp;uuid=517aea20-1ff1-11e9-8912-0f2b4d774171&amp;url=L25ld3MvYXJ0aWNsZXMvMjAxOS0wMS0yMy9jYW5hZGlhbi1tZWF0LWdpYW50LW1hcGxlLWxlYWYtZGVidXRzLW5ldy1wbGFudC1iYXNlZC1idXJnZXI=</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Microsoft’s Azure DevOps: An Unsatisfying Adventure</title>
<link>https://toxicbakery.github.io/vsts-devops/microsoft-devops-ci/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://toxicbakery.github.io/vsts-devops/microsoft-devops-ci/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;As a software developer, I know first-hand how difficult it is to build quality products quickly and cheaply. It’s an art form that we sometimes get right, and other times devolves into something akin to the Obama era healthcare government site. Our level of control over the resulting product varies, and blame for failure often falls on the wrong people in the decision-making hierarchy. Microsoft’s Azure DevOps (formerly known as Visual Studio Team Services), despite clearly good intentions, is a perfect storm of bad decisions and poor execution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From a high level, the product looks fantastic. It offers an all-in-one solution to issue tracking, CI, version control, project management, and more. Unfortunately, its complexity is part of its problem. When issues are updated, other screens frequently do not refresh, leaving you unaware of changes. For example, updating hours or setting effort does not trigger graphs to update; a page refresh is still required. While these problems are small when isolated, together they make the product arduous for day to day tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honestly, everything mentioned so far is tolerable, though unfortunate. Every tool has its problems. What really “grinds my gears” is the CI system which they call Pipelines. The CI implementation is, from my perspective, horrifically broken. All the individual problems, such as incomplete Github integration (which they now own, by the way), to the way agents running builds randomly die, to the way it’s the year 2019 and they still don’t offer any form of build caching, combine to create a product that is disappointingly subpar in comparison to other tools such as GitLab, CircleCI, Travis, and others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My primary hope is to help you, the reader, save yourself from some of the mistakes I’ve made using this tool. My secondary hope is to reach someone at Microsoft who makes decisions and convince them to fix these problems ASAP —we are, after all, paying them money for this tool and also paying for every additional agent we [attempt to] use for CI. Lastly, let me clarify that I’ve already contacted support for many issues, with no positive outcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;viewing-your-builds&quot;&gt;Viewing Your Builds&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;1080p-need-not-apply&quot;&gt;1080p Need Not Apply&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Curiously, the build information page hides significant amounts of data if you commit the cardinal sin of not having a big enough monitor. Even with standard 1920x1080 resolution, it’s impossible to see all the columns at once. Surely you are thinking to yourself, “Wow, this guy doesn’t know how to scroll horizontally.” Actually I do, Microsoft doesn’t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://toxicbakery.github.io/vsts-devops/images/issue-hidden-columns-small.png&quot; alt=&quot;Hidden Columns Small&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Barely any information is displayed about each build. Also note, no horizontal scrolling. The blacked-out areas identify some commits and their authors. Additional blackouts hide some of my company’s information and other sensitive information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://toxicbakery.github.io/vsts-devops/images/issue-hidden-columns-large.png&quot; alt=&quot;Hidden Columns Large&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Ah, look at all that beautiful information. Sadly, this window still isn’t large enough to see all of the available columns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of you may be wondering what happens on mobile. Mobile is completely unsupported for the CI area of the tool. Even if you bypass its mobile-friendly views using desktop mode, you can’t change your screen size, and so the majority columns are completely inaccessible. To the best of my knowledge, no native mobile app exists either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://toxicbakery.github.io/vsts-devops/images/issue-mobile-web-site.png&quot; alt=&quot;Mobile Website&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;I hope all you are looking to do is view tasks assigned to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;thou-shall-not-build&quot;&gt;Thou Shall Not Build&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;a-sad-but-true-story&quot;&gt;A Sad but True Story&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Either Microsoft’s network, the CI worker agent service, or some combination of both are completely broken. Using a Microsoft-hosted agent running Linux, you are provisioned a Windows server running Ubuntu in a hypervisor. Generally, build machine instances get approximately 6GB of usable memory and two E5 Xeon Intel cores.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://toxicbakery.github.io/vsts-devops/images/issue-hosted-agent-system-info.png&quot; alt=&quot;Hosted Agent System Information&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Running hosted builds, we experienced a high rate of build failures caused by machines disappearing into the ether. These failures happen at random points, sometimes before the build even starts. The general cause is always the same: “lost communication with the server”. After spending months hoping for this problem to be resolved, asking support for help, and suffering from their rather inadequate issue tracker, we decided to just set up our own self-hosted agent on AWS. We hoped it would fix everything and it did! Our builds were blazing fast and ten minutes later, “lost communication with the server”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://toxicbakery.github.io/vsts-devops/images/issue-lost-communication.png&quot; alt=&quot;Lost communication with server&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the problem runs deeper than just on their hosted agents and it seems to also affect self-hosted ones running on our own instances. Investigating the issue further, I realized our EC2 instance was completely unresponsive. Ok, I thought, I must have gotten a bad server or something must have gone wrong. I terminated the instance, created a new one, and set up the agent again. Surely all would be well now!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a few hours, builds ran smoothly. As expected, eventually the agent died during a build. Builds sat queued, my frustration grew, and AWS notified my instance needed a doctor. After an hour I gave up hope for the unresponsive server and commanded it to reboot. In an attempt to debug the problem I investigated the traditional log locations such as dmesg, kern, and the var log. I was unable to determine any root issue or find any indication of what happened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;checking-on-your-build&quot;&gt;Checking on Your Build&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;to-log-or-not-to-log&quot;&gt;To Log or Not to Log&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most curious implementation decisions is the build log. If you already have the build information page open when a build is triggered, you can see the entire build history. If you are a normal and human don’t peek in on the build for several minutes, you can only see history from the point you loaded the build log for the currently running step. In my primary role as an Android developer, the first build output I see is often something like &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;:app:assembleDebug&lt;/code&gt;, ergo, the beginning of the log is missing. It is possible to refresh the page after the build finishes to view the entire log, but this often turns into an unfortunate time sink.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://toxicbakery.github.io/vsts-devops/images/issue-mid-build-log.png&quot; alt=&quot;Build log starts in the middle&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;dear-cache&quot;&gt;Dear Cache&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;cache-me-ousside&quot;&gt;Cache Me Ousside&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might not believe me when I tell you Microsoft has absolutely no form of build caching. As such, I’ll just link you directly to &lt;a href=&quot;https://visualstudio.uservoice.com/forums/330519-azure-devops-formerly-visual-studio-team-services/suggestions/32044321-improve-hosted-build-agent-performance-with-build&quot;&gt;people begging for it and Microsoft’s insistence they are thinking about implementing it&lt;/a&gt;. They acknowledged they were working on the issue in February 2018. It’s now 2019 and… nothing. This issue, while annoying, actually spins off a completely separate problem. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=azure+devops+504+gateway&quot;&gt;If you search Google&lt;/a&gt;, many users encounter network issues with their builds, myself included. Presumably, the lack of build caching is overwhelming their network and also causing their build servers to get rejected by package repository systems. In our builds, we frequently hit HTTP errors downloading dependencies resulting in flaky builds. We track a high number of build failures due to network issues excluding the percentage of failures attributed to the dreaded “lost communication” message described previously. Sometimes builds even fail to attempt to connect to Github performing the source checkout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s extremely confusing to me that Microsoft, a company which owns their own cloud services, lacks caching in their CI implementation. Other CI offerings on the market like Circle, Travis, Jenkins, etc, all generally have cache implementations and treat it as a fundamental part of the CI process. Please, Microsoft, can we have it now?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;failed-to-build&quot;&gt;Failed to Build&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;github-who&quot;&gt;Github Who?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another interesting implementation issue with CI is the communication (or lack thereof) with Github. When a build fails, such as when the CI system is flaky, re-queuing the build from the dashboard does not update Github on completion. This means you must push either erroneous commits, or force push changes onto pull requests to trigger new builds that will update your Github PR. In practice, this isn’t really an issue since CI systems generally aren’t flaky - or so I thought. As a strong supporter of systems like Travis and Circle, I’ve convinced many people to pony up the money for their services. They generally work well and exhibit none of the issues Microsoft has in regards to manually queued builds not updating Github. Regardless, multiple times a week my coworker and I have to spend extra time to deal with our quality checks blocking pull requests.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2019 22:05:41 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jedikv</dc:creator>
<og:description>As a software developer, I know first-hand how difficult it is to build quality products quickly and cheaply. It’s an art form that we sometimes get right, and other times devolves into something akin to the Obama era healthcare government site. Our level of control over the resulting product varies, and blame for failure often falls on the wrong people in the decision-making hierarchy. Microsoft’s Azure DevOps (formerly known as Visual Studio Team Services), despite clearly good intentions, is a perfect storm of bad decisions and poor execution.</og:description>
<og:title>An Unsatisfying Adventure</og:title>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://toxicbakery.github.io/vsts-devops/microsoft-devops-ci/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Queueing theory: The science of waiting in line</title>
<link>https://www.johndcook.com/blog/2019/01/23/queueing/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.johndcook.com/blog/2019/01/23/queueing/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.johndcook.com/queue.jpeg&quot; width=&quot;587&quot; height=&quot;196&quot; alt=&quot;people standing in line&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-medium&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s a branch of math that studies how people wait in line: &lt;strong&gt;queueing theory&lt;/strong&gt;. It’s not just about people standing in line, but about any system with clients and servers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An introduction to queueing theory, about what you’d learn in one or two lectures, is very valuable for understanding how the world around you works. But after a brief introduction, you quickly hit diminishing return on your effort, unless you want to specialize in the theory or you have a particular problem you’re interested in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The simplest models in queueing theory have nice closed-form solutions. They’re designed to be easy to understand, not to be highly realistic in application. They make simplifying assumptions, and minor variations no longer have nice solutions. But they make very useful &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.johndcook.com/blog/2015/12/03/toy-problems/&quot;&gt;toy models&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the insights from basic queueing theory is that &lt;strong&gt;variability&lt;/strong&gt; in arrival and service times &lt;strong&gt;matters a great deal&lt;/strong&gt;. This is unlike revenue, for example, where you can estimate total revenue simply by multiplying the estimated number of customers by the estimated average revenue per customer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A cashier who can handle a stream of customers &lt;strong&gt;on average&lt;/strong&gt; is in big trouble. If customers arrived at regular intervals and all required the same amount of time to serve, then if things are OK on average, they’re OK. But if there’s not much slack, and there’s the slightest bit of variability in arrival or service times, long lines will form.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I work through a specific example &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.johndcook.com/blog/2008/10/21/what-happens-when-you-add-a-new-teller/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. The example also shows that when a system is near capacity, adding a new server can make a huge improvement. In that example, going from one server to two doesn’t just cut the waiting time in half, but reduces it by a couple orders of magnitude.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned at the beginning, queueing theory doesn’t just apply to shoppers and cashiers. It also applies to diverse situations such as cars entering a highway and page requests hitting a web server. See more on the latter &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.johndcook.com/blog/2009/01/30/server-utilization-joel-on-queuing/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Related posts&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2019 21:18:33 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>chmaynard</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.johndcook.com/blog/2019/01/23/queueing/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Customer Service Agents Can See What You&amp;#039;re Typing in Real Time</title>
<link>https://gizmodo.com/be-warned-customer-service-agents-can-see-what-youre-t-1830688119</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://gizmodo.com/be-warned-customer-service-agents-can-see-what-youre-t-1830688119</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;img-wrapper lazy-image&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-permalink-sub-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;js_lightbox-wrapper lightbox-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.kinja-img.com/gawker-media/image/upload/s--ZfcRn8tE--/c_scale,f_auto,fl_progressive,q_80,w_800/bqusv5kgudajtqrxno2v.png&quot; class=&quot;lazyload ls-lazy-image-tag&quot; data-sizes=&quot;auto&quot; data-width=&quot;3200&quot; data-chomp-id=&quot;bqusv5kgudajtqrxno2v&quot; data-format=&quot;png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Illustration: Jim Cooke (Gizmodo Media Group)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next time you’re chatting with a customer service agent online, be warned that the person on the other side of your conversation might see what you’re typing in real time. A reader sent us the following transcript from a conversation he had with a mattress company after the agent responded to a message he hadn’t sent yet.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;img-wrapper lazy-image&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-permalink-sub-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;js_lightbox-wrapper lightbox-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==&quot; class=&quot;lazyload ls-lazy-image-tag&quot; data-sizes=&quot;auto&quot; data-width=&quot;584&quot; data-chomp-id=&quot;zsm5rs7m8fekhywnzuze&quot; data-format=&quot;jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;swappable-mobile-ad-container&quot; class=&quot;js_ad-mobile-dynamic swappable-mobile-ad-container js_ad-dynamic ad-mobile-dynamic movable-ad&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ad-unit ad-mobile&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ad-mobile-inner&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ad-label proxima&quot;&gt;&lt;small class=&quot;proxima&quot;&gt;Advertisement&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something similar recently happened to HmmDaily’s Tom Scocca. He got &lt;a href=&quot;https://hmmdaily.com/2018/11/26/customer-service-chats-are-watching-you-type-before-you-hit-enter/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; onclick=&quot;window.ga('send', 'event', 'Embedded Url', 'External link', 'https://hmmdaily.com/2018/11/26/customer-service-chats-are-watching-you-type-before-you-hit-enter/', {metric25:1})&quot;&gt;a detailed answer from an agent&lt;/a&gt; one second after he hit send.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Googling led Scocca to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ladesk.com/features/real-time-typing-view/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; onclick=&quot;window.ga('send', 'event', 'Embedded Url', 'External link', 'https://www.ladesk.com/features/real-time-typing-view/', {metric25:1})&quot;&gt;a live chat service&lt;/a&gt; that offers a feature it calls “real-time typing view” to allow agents to have their “answers prepared before the customer submits his questions.” Another live chat service, which lists McDonalds, Ikea, and Paypal as its customers, calls the same feature “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.livechatinc.com/kb/how-to-chat-window/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; onclick=&quot;window.ga('send', 'event', 'Embedded Url', 'External link', 'https://www.livechatinc.com/kb/how-to-chat-window/', {metric25:1})&quot;&gt;message sneak peek&lt;/a&gt;,” saying it will allow you to “see what the visitor is typing in before they send it over.” Salesforce Live Agent also offers “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.salesforce.com/eu/products/service-cloud/features/live-agent/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; onclick=&quot;window.ga('send', 'event', 'Embedded Url', 'External link', 'https://www.salesforce.com/eu/products/service-cloud/features/live-agent/', {metric25:1})&quot;&gt;sneak peak&lt;/a&gt;.”&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the upside, you get fast answers. On the downside, your thought process is being unknowingly observed. For the creators, this is technological magic, a deception that will result, they hope, in amazement and satisfaction. But once revealed by an agent who responds too quickly or one who responds before the question is asked, the trick falls apart, and what is left behind feels distinctly creepy, like a rabbit pulled from a hat with a broken neck. “Why give [customers] a fake ‘Send message’ button while secretly transmitting their messages all along?” asks Scocca.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;js_ad-mobile-dynamic js_ad-dynamic ad-mobile-dynamic movable-ad&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ad-unit ad-mobile&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ad-mobile-inner&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ad-label proxima&quot;&gt;&lt;small class=&quot;proxima&quot;&gt;Advertisement&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This particular magic trick happens thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://nakedsecurity.sophos.com/2013/12/17/are-the-websites-youre-using-tracking-what-you-type/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; onclick=&quot;window.ga('send', 'event', 'Embedded Url', 'External link', 'https://nakedsecurity.sophos.com/2013/12/17/are-the-websites-youre-using-tracking-what-you-type/', {metric25:1})&quot;&gt;JavaScript operating in your browser&lt;/a&gt; and detecting what’s happening on a particular site in real time. It’s also how companies capture information &lt;a href=&quot;https://gizmodo.com/before-you-hit-submit-this-company-has-already-logge-1795906081&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; onclick=&quot;window.ga('send', 'event', 'Embedded Url', 'Internal link', 'https://gizmodo.com/before-you-hit-submit-this-company-has-already-logge-1795906081', {metric25:1})&quot;&gt;you’ve entered into web forms before you’ve hit submit.&lt;/a&gt; Companies could lessen the creepiness by telling people their typing is seen in real time or could eliminate the send button altogether (but that would undoubtedly confuse people, as if &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2016/10/28/us/placebo-buttons-elevators-crosswalks.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; onclick=&quot;window.ga('send', 'event', 'Embedded Url', 'External link', 'https://www.nytimes.com/2016/10/28/us/placebo-buttons-elevators-crosswalks.html', {metric25:1})&quot;&gt;the useless buttons in elevators to “close door” or the placebos to push at crosswalks disappeared overnight.&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lest you think unexpected monitoring is limited to your digital interactions, know that you should be paranoid during telephone chats too. As the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2005/01/11/business/your-call-and-rants-on-hold-will-be-monitored.html?smid=nytcore-ios-share&amp;amp;mtrref=undefined&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; onclick=&quot;window.ga('send', 'event', 'Embedded Url', 'External link', 'https://www.nytimes.com/2005/01/11/business/your-call-and-rants-on-hold-will-be-monitored.html?smid=nytcore-ios-share&amp;amp;mtrref=undefined', {metric25:1})&quot;&gt;New York Times reported over a decade ago&lt;/a&gt;, during those calls where you are reassured of “being recorded for quality assurance purposes,” your conversation while on hold is recorded. So even if there is music playing, monitors &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/NoStupidQuestions/comments/295trs/can_they_hear_me_when_im_on_hold/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; onclick=&quot;window.ga('send', 'event', 'Embedded Url', 'External link', 'https://www.reddit.com/r/NoStupidQuestions/comments/295trs/can_they_hear_me_when_im_on_hold/', {metric25:1})&quot;&gt;may later&lt;/a&gt; listen to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2005/01/11/business/your-call-and-rants-on-hold-will-be-monitored.html?smid=nytcore-ios-share&amp;amp;mtrref=undefined&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; onclick=&quot;window.ga('send', 'event', 'Embedded Url', 'External link', 'https://www.nytimes.com/2005/01/11/business/your-call-and-rants-on-hold-will-be-monitored.html?smid=nytcore-ios-share&amp;amp;mtrref=undefined', {metric25:1})&quot;&gt;you fight with your spouse, sing a song, or swear about the agent you’re talking to&lt;/a&gt;. From the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2005/01/11/business/your-call-and-rants-on-hold-will-be-monitored.html?smid=nytcore-ios-share&amp;amp;mtrref=undefined&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; onclick=&quot;window.ga('send', 'event', 'Embedded Url', 'External link', 'https://www.nytimes.com/2005/01/11/business/your-call-and-rants-on-hold-will-be-monitored.html?smid=nytcore-ios-share&amp;amp;mtrref=undefined', {metric25:1})&quot;&gt;2005 NYT article&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;16&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monitoring is intended to track the performance of call center operators, but the professional snoops are inadvertently monitoring callers, too. Most callers do not realize that they may be taped even while they are on hold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is at these times that monitors hear husbands arguing with their wives, mothers yelling at their children, and dog owners throwing fits at disobedient pets, all when they think no one is listening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;js_ad-mobile-dynamic js_ad-dynamic ad-mobile-dynamic movable-ad&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ad-unit ad-mobile&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ad-mobile-inner&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ad-label proxima&quot;&gt;&lt;small class=&quot;proxima&quot;&gt;Advertisement&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if there is no music playing, the agent may just have &lt;a href=&quot;https://boards.straightdope.com/sdmb/showthread.php?t=611007&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; onclick=&quot;window.ga('send', 'event', 'Embedded Url', 'External link', 'https://boards.straightdope.com/sdmb/showthread.php?t=611007', {metric25:1})&quot;&gt;you on mute&lt;/a&gt; and be listening to you.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;So if you don’t want to be monitored or send secret messages to agents, put your phone on mute while on hold and copy/paste messages from another document to your customer service chatbox. And in general, be nice to customer service agents. It’s not their fault.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2019 21:14:43 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>curtis</dc:creator>
<og:title>Be Warned: Customer Service Agents Can See What You're Typing in Real Time</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:image>https://i.kinja-img.com/gawker-media/image/upload/s--7Uh3levE--/c_fill,fl_progressive,g_center,h_900,q_80,w_1600/bqusv5kgudajtqrxno2v.png</og:image>
<og:url>https://gizmodo.com/be-warned-customer-service-agents-can-see-what-youre-t-1830688119</og:url>
<og:description>Next time you’re chatting with a customer service agent online, be warned that the person on the other side of your conversation might see what you’re typing in real time. A reader sent us the following transcript from a conversation he had with a mattress company after the agent responded to a message he hadn’t sent yet.</og:description>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://gizmodo.com/be-warned-customer-service-agents-can-see-what-youre-t-1830688119</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>WasmWinforms – .NET WinForms in a browser</title>
<link>https://github.com/roozbehid/WasmWinforms</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/roozbehid/WasmWinforms</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;Box-body p-6&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;markdown-body entry-content&quot; itemprop=&quot;text&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Winforms now work in your browser! WasmWinforms is a nuget package that you can install and use your EXACT same code designed for winforms and you get can run it on your browser&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Create a Winforms application from Visual Studio. Note that winforms are full .Net applications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create an empty .Net Core App and add files from full .net application into it. For example, add Form1.cs,Form1.Designer.cs, Form1.resx, Program.cs .You can add those files as links too.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install latest version of Winforms.Wasm nuget from nuget.org.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build your project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can debug Win32 (32bit version) of your code in Visual Studio. (Make sure you have 32bit version of dotnet installed! (it should be in Program Files (x86)\dotnet\dotnet.exe)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Looking at your OUTPUT DIRECTORy\dist\ you will find your index.html to run!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project uses mono to run your C# IL code. Also coming with this distribution are System.Drawing and System.Windows.Forms. Winforms implementation required many other c libraries that I also ported all of them into WebAssembly. You can find out about them looking into their submodules!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project uses another amazing ( :D ) project of mine: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/roozbehid/dotnet-vcxproj&quot;&gt;GCCBuild&lt;/a&gt; which enables you to use any compiler to compile C/C++ code. Meaning you can have Visual Studio C/C++ project files and use them to compile both for Windows/Linux and also WebAssembly. You need to have Emscripten installed, activated and already accessible from your path. First from Visual Studio build for Release-x86 then build for WasmRel-x86. This way you have all libraries compiled for Win32 and also WebAssembly. Using Win32 compiled libraries are way easier to debug and run your applcation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please note that compiling mono-wasm should only be done in WasmRel or WasmDbg targets and it would take a minute or two to complete!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;File issues and submit pull request so it will be faster/less buggy! There are many many bugs and this project/product is not at all recommended for production. It is pre-alpha phase!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well that is a really good question. I dont know. It was fun doing this thing. Maybe call it some useless technology...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2019 19:31:27 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>yread</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars3.githubusercontent.com/u/7875383?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>roozbehid/WasmWinforms</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/roozbehid/WasmWinforms</og:url>
<og:description>C# Winforms for Webassembly. Contribute to roozbehid/WasmWinforms development by creating an account on GitHub.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/roozbehid/WasmWinforms</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez Is Absolutely Right About Racist Algorithms</title>
<link>https://breakermag.com/alexandria-ocasio-cortez-is-absolutely-right-about-racist-algorithms/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://breakermag.com/alexandria-ocasio-cortez-is-absolutely-right-about-racist-algorithms/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Freshman Democratic congresswoman Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez is making headlines on a daily basis, because she’s simultaneously &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rollingstone.com/politics/politics-features/alexandria-ocasio-cortez-media-781571/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;hugely popular&lt;/a&gt; among young progressives, and regularly enraging to conservatives and moderates. In just one of several headline moments from the past few days, Ocasio-Cortez appeared on an MLK Day broadcast with author Ta-Nahesi Coates, and declared that facial recognition technologies “always have these racial inequities that get translated, because algorithms are still made by human beings, and those algorithms are still pegged to basic human assumptions. They’re just automated. And automated assumptions—if you don’t fix the bias, then you’re just automating the bias.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The comments were highlighted on Twitter by Ryan Saavedra, a reporter for the conservative Daily Wire, who commented: “Socialist Rep. Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez (D-NY) claims that algorithms, which are driven by math, are racist.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-width=&quot;550&quot; data-dnt=&quot;true&quot; readability=&quot;8.5027027027027&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Socialist Rep. Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez (D-NY) claims that algorithms, which are driven by math, are racist &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/X2veVvAU1H&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/X2veVvAU1H&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Ryan Saavedra (@RealSaavedra) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/RealSaavedra/status/1087627739861897216?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;January 22, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The implication of Saavedra’s attempted rebuttal (which was followed by a &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/RealSaavedra/status/1087843247840358400&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;classic double-down&lt;/a&gt;) is that mathematics constitutes a kind of objective truth, unswayed by the flawed nature of human judgment. That’s a notion that’s quite widespread in crypto circles, though not usually directly linked to the issue of racism. It’s also total horseshit, and deeply dangerous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone with even a tangential familiarity with computer science will recognize that Saavedra’s counterpoint is based on a fundamental misunderstanding of the nature of computers in general, and artificial intelligence in particular. Rather than emotionless, all-seeing eyes, machine-learning algorithms are better thought of as blind, deaf, silicon-based infants, being fed information about how humans think until they can crudely imitate those patterns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both the data used to train these systems, and the training practices themselves, can pass on human biases about race. Some varieties of the facial-recognition software Ocasio-Cortez was referring to, for example, have been found by MIT and Microsoft researchers to &lt;a href=&quot;http://proceedings.mlr.press/v81/buolamwini18a/buolamwini18a.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;misidentify dark-skinned people&lt;/a&gt; at vastly higher rates than light-skinned people. That’s a near-perfect analogue of white people’s tendency to misidentify people of color, leading to higher rates of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2015/09/20/nyregion/the-science-behind-they-all-look-alike-to-me.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;false arrest&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2017/3/7/14834454/exoneration-innocence-prison-racism&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;conviction&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s hard to describe that as anything other than “a racist algorithm,” but humans are ultimately to blame—apparently the flaw came about because the data sets used to train the software had far more &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.veridiumid.com/blog/racial-profiling-and-biometrics/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;light-skinned males&lt;/a&gt; than members of other groups. Bias can find its way into algorithms in many different ways, though: another great example (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/benjaminopowers/status/1087876426660044800&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;highlighted&lt;/a&gt; by our new intern Benjamin Powers), was a recruiting tool built by Amazon that simply reproduced human recruiters’ bias towards male job-seekers, because it was only trained using selections made by humans biased towards male job-seekers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it’s not all about race and gender. Saavedra was quickly confronted with clear examples of how right Ocasio-Cortez was . . . directly from his own Twitter feed. Saavedra had &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/OsitaNwanevu/status/1087841319219802113&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;repeatedly complained&lt;/a&gt; about supposed bias in social media algorithms, including tweeting that “tech companies tend to be liberal &amp;amp; something is off with their algorithms because they won’t show a lot of content I find by manual search.” There’s not much evidence for this claim of anti-conservative algorithmic bias—content algorithms seem to favor &lt;a href=&quot;http://fortune.com/2018/03/11/youtube-extreme-content/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;extremism in general&lt;/a&gt; more than any particular ideology. But Saavedra is clearly happy to echo Ocasio-Cortez’ points about algorithmic bias, when it suits his narrative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, algorithms aimed at making subtle decisions involving human beings are, mostly, really good at repeating human errors, very fast, many times over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This matters immensely for blockchain entrepreneurs, whose rhetoric often implicitly echoes the idea that math is inherently infallible. That’s perhaps best summed up by the mantra that “code is law” among smart-contracts advocates, a phrase which threatens to conflate the &lt;em&gt;inflexibility&lt;/em&gt; of blockchain transactions with &lt;em&gt;infallibility—&lt;/em&gt;two extremely different things. That blurring might be made easier because crypto is premised on a particular case where code is, in a very limited sense, infallible—cryptography. Cryptography doesn’t involve any real judgment or decision-making, just numerical matching: A hash or a private key are either right or wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But that clarity fails pretty quickly as you move into more complex realms of human life, and crypto and blockchain efforts are aimed at some areas where bias is a clear risk, most obviously finance. Loan and credit decisions have historically been highly subject to human racial and gender bias, and there’s concern that the existing credit-rating system may contain algorithmic elements that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2016/12/how-algorithms-can-bring-down-minorities-credit-scores/509333/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;perpetuate racial bias&lt;/a&gt;. If crypto hopes to break down the power imbalances built into the legacy banking system, that seems like a decent place to put some energy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s also worth noting that there’s something much deeper to the specifically conservative yearning for a perfect, neutral, algorithmic decision-maker. The nature of that yearning may be best captured in the writing of Eliezer Yudkowski, an AI theorist and philosopher. Yudkowski has for more than a decade pursued the possibility of perfect human reasoning, while also believing that we will inevitably create an all-knowing artificial intelligence that will become a sort of super-rational God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saavedra, with his tweet about how algorithms “driven by math” can’t be racist, was echoing Yudkowski’s unending faith in the perfectibility of reason and reasoning technology. It turns out that the possibility that ethics can be computerized and formalized is pretty appealing to arch-conservatives, and Yudkowski’s thought constitutes a core pillar for the Silicon Valley wing of &lt;a href=&quot;https://breakermag.com/heres-the-dark-enlightenment-explainer-you-never-wanted/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;neo-reactionaries&lt;/a&gt; who often refer to themselves as “rationalists.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yudkowski’s rationalism is also, notoriously, fatally flawed: His system of coldly logical reason was by many accounts completely undone by a logical paradox known as &lt;a href=&quot;https://rationalwiki.org/wiki/Roko%27s_basilisk&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Roko’s Basilisk&lt;/a&gt;. The thought experiment is too complicated to unpack here. But it boils down to the irrefutable conclusion, if one proceeds from Yudkowski’s own premises, that any future super-intelligent AI, even a “friendly” one, would endlessly torture a simulated copy of any human that hadn’t worked to create it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s a hell of an endpoint for a system of thought aimed at creating a future rationalist utopia. For super-nerd bonus points, it’s also arguably a spin on Godel’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/G%C3%B6del%27s_incompleteness_theorems&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;incompleteness theorem&lt;/a&gt;, which proved that no purely rational algorithmic system can completely and consistently model reality, or prove its own rationality. The whole thing is worth reading about in the excellent book &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Neoreaction-Basilisk-Essays-Around-Alt-Right-ebook/dp/B0782JDGVQ/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Neoreaction A Basilisk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; But the takeaway is clear enough: Just because something is expressed in numbers doesn’t make it right, or even rational. And rationality itself might not be quite what it’s cracked up to be.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2019 18:59:24 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>StellarTabi</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez Is Absolutely Right About Racist Algorithms</og:title>
<og:url>https://breakermag.com/alexandria-ocasio-cortez-is-absolutely-right-about-racist-algorithms/</og:url>
<og:description>It might sound ridiculous to say math can be racist. But when we rely on it to make decisions, it's just as flawed as we are.</og:description>
<og:image>https://breakermag.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Screen-Shot-2019-01-23-at-12.58.13-PM.png?w=327</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://breakermag.com/alexandria-ocasio-cortez-is-absolutely-right-about-racist-algorithms/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Alarming Decline of Quality Youth Playtime</title>
<link>https://houseoflawandorder.com/the-alarming-decline-of-quality-youth-playtime/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://houseoflawandorder.com/the-alarming-decline-of-quality-youth-playtime/</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;has-drop-cap&quot;&gt;What are your kids going to do after school today? More homework? Hopefully not too much of that. What I mean is &lt;em&gt;after&lt;/em&gt; they’ve finished their homework? Do they have time to play? If so, what kind of things will they be doing? Does it really matter? Does this video change your mind?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;more-429&quot;/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;embed-youtube&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe class=&quot;youtube-player&quot; type=&quot;text/html&quot; width=&quot;676&quot; height=&quot;381&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/1XDVDyDJ3s0?version=3&amp;amp;rel=1&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;autohide=2&amp;amp;showsearch=0&amp;amp;showinfo=1&amp;amp;iv_load_policy=1&amp;amp;wmode=transparent&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I suspect that the hit Netflix show, &lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot; aria-label=&quot;Stranger Things (opens in a new tab)&quot; href=&quot;https://youtu.be/XWxyRG_tckY&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Stranger Things&lt;/a&gt;, resonated with so many adults for one primary reason: it brought them back to the carefree and wonder-filled days of youth back in the 80’s. I know that is exactly what I liked so much about the show. The story line itself was a bit “meh” in my opinion. But the characters, the bike riding, the exploring through the forests surrounding their town, the Dungeons and Dragons sessions, and the general running around and getting into trouble with friends is what made it such a fun show for me. (Disclaimer: I would definitely recommend watching it using a filtering service like &lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot; aria-label=&quot;VidAngel (opens in a new tab)&quot; href=&quot;https://www.vidangel.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;VidAngel&lt;/a&gt; as the language and some of the content is definitely not family friendly!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In case you’re not in a position to watch the above video presently, I’ll describe it briefly. An interviewer asks three generations what they did to play when they were growing up. The oldest generation talks about being outside, picking blueberries, growing watermelons, sledding down snow-covered hills, and more. The middle generation related that they did much of the same, including running from door to door, gathering friends and playing street games or night games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The shocking part comes when the youngest generation in this video is asked the same questions. The discussion almost completely revolves around electronic devices and video games. One child states, “I’d die without my tablet.” Another child explains that he only feels normal when he’s playing video games. The same boy boasts that he watched 23 episodes of a TV series in less than 4 days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Who is to Blame for Kids’ Technology Addictions?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s easy to shake our heads when watching this video and think to ourselves “Geez! Kids today! What is wrong with them?” I know that is frequently my first reaction. However, I’ve thought about this a lot over the years, and I really do think that it’s quite a bit more complex than just blaming kids for being lazy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Parent’s Role&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s face it, we’ve heard a lot about “helicopter parents” over the last few years. And even though it’s hard to admit, most of us have allowed ourselves to become overly protective parents to a great extent. Still, there are many factors out there that contribute to this technology crisis that faces this rising generation. But ultimately, we are in control of what our children are exposed to and what activities they engage in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I think back to my childhood (particularly during the summer break), most days my parents had no idea where we were at. I grew up in a small town in northern Arizona that was surrounded by the largest Ponderosa Pine forest in the world. There were vast expanses of wilderness directly behind my house. On summer days, my friends and I would get on our dirt bikes and follow miles of game trails all through the forest and up to the base of the volcanic boulder mountain where we would drop our bikes and climb massive rocks and cliffs until sunset. It was glorious!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Were my parents negligent to allow us such freedom? Personally, I don’t think so, based on the fact that most of my friends had parents with similar parenting styles. Many of these adults had been raised with the same type of autonomy when they were kids. They were just patterning their own parent’s parenting styles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Give Kids Some Room to Make Mistakes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, however, if I were to learn that my young kids had left the house in the early morning by themselves to rock climb, explore the forest and encounter heaven-knows-what out in the woods, I’d probably start hyperventilating. I mean, they could get hurt! Some predator could be out in the woods and could haul them away. A wild animal could attack them and drag them off. They could fall down a cliff, never to be seen again. There are so many things that could go wrong!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what’s my knee-jerk solution as a parent? Sadly, it’s to keep them at home. When they complain that they’re bored? Tell them to read a book or play a board game. When those get old? Turn on Netflix, Hulu or Amazon Prime. And since Netflix has a “kids area” where we can allow them to watch shows more tailored for kids, we feel safe allowing them some freedom to choose what they want to watch. In the meantime, comfortable that our kids are safe at home, we disappear into our home offices and five hours pass before we realize that the kids haven’t moved off of the couch that whole time. Thus, the results of the Nature Valley video above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So yeah, I get it. It’s very tempting to protect our kids from every conceivable risk out there. But everyone, kids included, need some room to make mistakes and occasionally even get hurt. Immersing them in a virtual world where no physical harm can ever occur sounds good at first. But the danger of them becoming so inexperienced and unprepared for the real world may be an even greater danger than we’ve ever imagined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Technology of Today&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another huge contributor to this problem of our children becoming chained to electronic devices is the technology itself. There is &lt;a href=&quot;http://theconversation.com/the-business-of-addiction-how-the-video-gaming-industry-is-evolving-to-be-like-the-casino-industry-83361&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot; aria-label=&quot;mounting evidence (opens in a new tab)&quot;&gt;mounting evidence&lt;/a&gt; and research that indicates that our kids are in the crosshairs of not-exactly-benign corporations who see them as huge profit centers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, even in the 80’s we had video games (Atari, Nintendo, Sega, etc.). Those games were fun of course. But they were nothing like the games today which are designed by multi-million dollar companies who hire PhD level psychologists to help create games that are wildly popular and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/memory-medic/201705/video-game-addiction&quot;&gt;addicting&lt;/a&gt;. These games can be so immersive, psychologically stimulating and satisfying, that when compared to real life, it’s no wonder our kids never make it into the outdoors. I’ve been sucked in myself. There was a time when I allowed myself to be sucked into video gaming that led me into 3 a.m. video game session when I knew I had to be to work the next day by 8 a.m. It was crazy that the games were so appealing to me that I was willing to slog through a full day of work on less than 5 hours of sleep. And this was when I was a much younger twenty-something who most likely had developed a much better sense of responsibility and understanding of consequences than the typical teenager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Social Media and Smart Devices&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, it’s not just video games that suck youth and adults in. Social media, YouTube, streaming video services like NetFlix, Hulu, and Amazon Prime. Even cable news and sports networks feed us a constant steady diet of highly entertaining, and yes, addicting content. How many of us have binged watched until the wee hours of the morning a show on NetFlix? I remember the first time I binge-watched a series and how amazed I was at my lack of self-control to just turn the TV off! It was the WB series exploring the early days of Superman “Smallville.” It was a fun, but ultimately worthless entertainment experience. I remember thinking to myself, “I can never get those hours of my life back. Was that really worth it in the end?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add to that the fact that children are receiving (at increasingly earlier ages) powerful computers that fit into the palms of their hands that allow 24/7 access to this type of entertainment and social engagement, and you’ve got what we’re seeing today. Something akin to the oft-cited zombie apocalypse!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i1.wp.com/houseoflawandorder.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/village-of-the-damned-original.jpg?fit=676%2C380&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-430&quot; srcset=&quot;https://i1.wp.com/houseoflawandorder.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/village-of-the-damned-original.jpg?w=1600&amp;amp;ssl=1 1600w, https://i1.wp.com/houseoflawandorder.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/village-of-the-damned-original.jpg?resize=300%2C169&amp;amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i1.wp.com/houseoflawandorder.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/village-of-the-damned-original.jpg?resize=768%2C432&amp;amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i1.wp.com/houseoflawandorder.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/village-of-the-damned-original.jpg?resize=1024%2C576&amp;amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i1.wp.com/houseoflawandorder.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/village-of-the-damned-original.jpg?resize=676%2C380&amp;amp;ssl=1 676w, https://i1.wp.com/houseoflawandorder.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/village-of-the-damned-original.jpg?w=1352&amp;amp;ssl=1 1352w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 676px) 100vw, 676px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Making it Real&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, yes. I think our children are up against a massive hurdle with regard to technology. The entertainment is better and more entertaining. And the availability of it is beyond anything we’ve ever experienced. When I grew up, I watched cartoons on Saturday morning. By 10 a.m., the stations had switched their programming to soap operas (gag!), daytime game shows, or Judge Judy type content. There was nothing to be entertained by in the house anymore. So we went outside whether it was cold or hot! Anything to address the oppressive boredom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And guess what? We had fun most of the time. We got hurt, skinned knees, cuts from climbing trees, and even an occasional fist fight between friends when a pick-up basketball game got a little out of hand. But we learned about human interactions in those experiences too. Overall, we experienced the world as it existed. Not as some programmer out in Silicon Valley designed it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite these challenges, this rising generation is not lost. As parents, we still have a great deal of potential influence over our children. It isn’t easy, but there are still many things we can do to ensure that our kids have good, quality playtime. Playtime grounded in reality – not virtual reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In case you haven’t guessed it yet, the aged 1980’s photo at the top of this page is of my best friend growing up, Jim Dillon, and me probably sometime after Christmas checking out each other’s Christmas presents. He was the one that I had so many of my childhood adventures with. I still sometimes can’t resist the temptation to slap on a photo-ruining cheesy smile. But man, I’m digging those sweatsuits!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How to Actually Improve Playtime&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;J&lt;strong&gt;ust Unplug&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps this sounds too simple. But I’m telling you, it works. Yes, there may be anger, tears, begging, and even lots of flailing of limbs. In fact, does this video feel at all familiar to any parents out there? My whole family got a huge kick out of this because we saw so many reflections of ourselves in it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;embed-youtube&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe class=&quot;youtube-player&quot; type=&quot;text/html&quot; width=&quot;676&quot; height=&quot;381&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/OaDPeZQnUHo?version=3&amp;amp;rel=1&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;autohide=2&amp;amp;showsearch=0&amp;amp;showinfo=1&amp;amp;iv_load_policy=1&amp;amp;wmode=transparent&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve all seen it. But come on. As a parent, we know that we have to do hard things. And taking away phones, unplugging video came consoles, setting parental restrictions on streaming devices and smartphones is just part of parenting today. If you’re not doing it, then you are simply conceding your parenting obligations to a stranger who you’ve never met who has no concern for your child beyond what revenue that child can generate for them. Take control and reduce the amount of time your kids are immersed in technology. It’s really that simple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create Meaningful Technology Replacements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So now that you’ve helped your kids unplug, what should they do? Here are a few ideas:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/houseoflawandorder.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Karate.jpg?fit=676%2C518&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-431&quot; srcset=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/houseoflawandorder.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Karate.jpg?w=1024&amp;amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/houseoflawandorder.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Karate.jpg?resize=300%2C230&amp;amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/houseoflawandorder.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Karate.jpg?resize=768%2C588&amp;amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/houseoflawandorder.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Karate.jpg?resize=676%2C518&amp;amp;ssl=1 676w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 676px) 100vw, 676px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Get them a bike, skateboard, or roller blades and introduce them to a new skill.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enroll them (and maybe a friend or two if you can convince them) in a local Girl Scouting or Boy Scouting organization.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sign them up for art classes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have them join a community choir&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enroll them in youth sports leagues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Martial Arts (Karate Kid, anyone?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Help them start a snow-shoveling business or lawn mowing business&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plant a garden or build grow-boxes to teach them the miracle of small-scale real food production&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Talk to some like-minded friends and brainstorm some play-dates for your kids at a local park or swimming pool.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Teach your kids how to responsibly spend money so they feel empowered to walk down to the corner store with friends and buy a Slurpee when they feel like it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Buy a rocket launching set or kites and help them get started in a hobby that they’ve never considered.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduce them to stamp or coin collecting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Call up some family cousins and schedule some time for them to come over and have a Nerf dart-gun war.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Teach them how to cook or prepare their favorite treat or dessert.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Of course, that’s just scratching the surface. Sit down with your spouse or your family and brainstorm for a while. Pick up a calendar, and start penciling some of your ideas into the calendar. That way, the next time your kids say “We’re bored!” you can immediately pick up your list or your calendar and say “Great. I’ve got a plan.” For more ideas, check out an earlier &lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot; aria-label=&quot;article (opens in a new tab)&quot; href=&quot;https://houseoflawandorder.com/making-the-most-of-your-family-time-prioritize-experiences/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; I wrote about how our family does this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There will be resistance, I can assure you. But I can also assure you that your kids will look back on their childhoods with much more fondness than if you just leave them to their electronics. Spend time together. Spend time away from home. Get them out of the house and let them explore the real world. Your kids will have plenty of time in their adult lives to be lost in the virtual world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;robots-nocontent sd-block sd-social sd-social-icon-text sd-sharing&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Share this:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-block sd-like jetpack-likes-widget-wrapper jetpack-likes-widget-unloaded&quot; id=&quot;like-post-wrapper-138273534-429-5c49df057ddd9&quot; data-src=&quot;https://widgets.wp.com/likes/#blog_id=138273534&amp;amp;post_id=429&amp;amp;origin=houseoflawandorder.com&amp;amp;obj_id=138273534-429-5c49df057ddd9&quot; data-name=&quot;like-post-frame-138273534-429-5c49df057ddd9&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Like this:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;button&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Like&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;loading&quot;&gt;Loading...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2019 18:23:02 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>technologyvault</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>The Alarming Decline of Quality, Youth Playtime - House of Law and Order</og:title>
<og:description>Our youth are growing up in a virtual world. What can be done to re-introduce them to the real world? Unplug and calendar up some real activity.</og:description>
<og:url>https://houseoflawandorder.com/the-alarming-decline-of-quality-youth-playtime/</og:url>
<og:image>https://i1.wp.com/houseoflawandorder.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/RobRoy-and-Jim.jpg?fit=604%2C471&amp;ssl=1</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://houseoflawandorder.com/the-alarming-decline-of-quality-youth-playtime/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Oracle allegedly underpaid $400M in wages to underrepresented employees</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2019/01/22/oracle-discrimination-400-million/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2019/01/22/oracle-discrimination-400-million/</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;speakable-summary&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://crunchbase.com/organization/oracle&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;oracle&quot;&gt;Oracle&lt;/a&gt; has allegedly withheld $400 million in wages from racially underrepresented workers (black, Latinx and Asian) as well as women, &lt;a href=&quot;http://src.bna.com/EXa&quot;&gt;the U.S. Department of Labor’s Office of Federal Contract Compliance Programs said in a filing today&lt;/a&gt;. The OFCCP is the office within the DOL that enforces equal pay and ensures government contractors comply with anti-discrimination regulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the OFCCP’s second amended complaint today, the office alleges Oracle “impermissibly denies equal employment opportunity to non-Asian applicants for employment, strongly preferring a workforce that it can later underpay. Once employed, women, Blacks and Asians are systematically underpaid relative to their peers,” the complaint alleges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Allegedly, Oracle’s underpayment of certain employees is driven by the company’s reliance on prior salary information and funneling non-white, non-male employees into lower-paid roles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The department argues that Oracle’s “stark patterns of discrimination” started back in 2013 and continues into the present day. More specifically, the OFCCP alleges Oracle discriminated against black, Asian and female employees. This has all ultimately resulted in the collective loss of more than $400 million for this group of employees, the suit alleges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The office also alleges Oracle discriminates against those who have visas, often putting them in low-level jobs. The vast majority of hires from Oracle’s college recruiting program, the suit alleges, were international students with student visas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“These students required work authorization to remain in the United States after graduation,” the suit alleges. “In other words, Oracle overwhelmingly hires workers dependent upon Oracle for sponsorship to remain in the United States.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The OFCCP filed the suit against Oracle last January, following the Labor Department’s 2014 audit of the company. &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2017/09/29/former-oracle-employees-sue-company-for-alleged-pay-discrimination/&quot;&gt;That suit was followed by an employee-led class-action lawsuit&lt;/a&gt; last September alleging Oracle pays women less than men in similar jobs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oracle is subject to auditing as a result of its contracts with the federal government. Given Oracle’s agreement to provide equal employment opportunity, the OFCCP is asking the Court to require Oracle to pay those affected and correct its “discriminatory compensation and hiring practices.” The office is also demanding that Oracle lose its $100 million worth of annual contracts with the government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oracle, which declined to comment for this story, is not the only company the OFCCP has gone after. A couple of years ago, &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2017/01/05/the-u-s-department-of-labor-is-suing-google-for-compensation-data/&quot;&gt;the office went after Google&lt;/a&gt; in an attempt to obtain compensation data, followed by a claim that Google has systemic gender-based pay inequities. That same year, the office &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2016/09/26/u-s-department-of-labor-sues-palantir-for-racial-discrimination/&quot;&gt;sued Palantir for racial discrimination&lt;/a&gt;. Palantir, several months later, &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2017/04/25/palantir-settles-racial-discrimination-lawsuit-with-the-department-of-labor/&quot;&gt;settled with the DOL&lt;/a&gt;, agreeing to pay $1.7 million in back wages and other types of monetary relief to those affected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update Jan 23. 2019: &lt;/strong&gt;Oracle has since decided to comment. See story below.&lt;/p&gt;



</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2019 17:55:52 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>samfisher83</dc:creator>
<og:title>Oracle allegedly withheld $400 million in wages from underrepresented employees</og:title>
<og:description>Oracle has allegedly withheld $400 million in wages from racially underrepresented workers (black, Latinx and Asian) as well as women, the U.S. Department of Labor’s Office of Federal Contract Compliance Programs said in a filing today. The OFCCP is the office within the DOL that enforces equ…</og:description>
<og:image>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/gettyimages-494272836.jpg?w=599</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2019/01/22/oracle-discrimination-400-million/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2019/01/22/oracle-discrimination-400-million/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>