<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Self Studying the MIT Applied Math Curriculum</title>
<link>https://www.harshsikka.me/self-studying-the-mit-applied-math-curriculum/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.harshsikka.me/self-studying-the-mit-applied-math-curriculum/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wow! This post blew up, if you'd like to get updates on how my progress goes, feel free to subscribe &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.harshsikka.me/#subscribe&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; or follow me on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/HarshSikka&quot;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've decided to engage in a pretty interesting self development project this summer: Completing the requirements for the &lt;a href=&quot;http://math.mit.edu/academics/undergrad/major/course18/applied.php&quot;&gt;MIT Applied Math curriculum&lt;/a&gt; through auditing classes, meeting professors, and completing the &lt;a href=&quot;https://ocw.mit.edu/index.htm&quot;&gt;corresponding OCW course assignments and exams where applicable&lt;/a&gt;. In this post, I'll explain my background and motivations for doing this, as well as the specific courses I'll be taking on my journey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to skip straight to the plan if you don't feel like reading the &quot;why&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-the-hell-would-you-do-this&quot;&gt;Why the hell would you do this?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm a Master's student at Harvard and Georgia Tech studying Machine Learning and Computational Biology. I'm also a research assistant in a few labs, and my work spans Applied Math, Theoretical Neuroscience, and Machine Learning. Previously, I helped start an ML startup. I'm planning on applying to PhD programs this fall!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My journey into Machine Learning has been fairly non traditional, I studied mostly biology and cognitive science in my undergraduate career at UCSD and my internships were always in Product Management. I taught myself to code, mostly application development for web and mobile, and slowly started to see parallels between Information Science and Biology, and was fascinated by Neural Networks. This fascination led me to apply for graduate programs in CS and Biology, and I miraculously was accepted! So, with luck and momentum going my way, I dove deep into deep learning research and taught myself whatever mathematical preliminaries were necessary to make sense of the literature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thing is, I've started to really like math in its own right, and while its certainly not necessary to study large swaths of math beyond a few topics like Linear Algebra, Probability Theory, and a little Vector Calculus, I've found that a lot of the brilliant people around me can dip into different topics in mathematics and make new, interesting breakthroughs in ML.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I like math, and getting a more formal foundation seems useful if I'd like to go even deeper into the research I'm doing and think in new interesting ways. After talking to a few of my mentors and colleagues, including Professors and Grad students at Harvard and MIT, I was recommended to try diving into an undergraduate applied math curriculum. I've been graciously offered the chance to sit in some classes and learn for the sake of learning in my free time, so why not make a fun project out of it and share it with everyone! Maybe you can find something useful here :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-plan&quot;&gt;The Plan&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://math.mit.edu/academics/undergrad/major/course18/applied.php&quot;&gt;MIT Applied Math curriculum&lt;/a&gt; is very well laid out and straightforward, and basically comprises of a collection of core courses and electives to choose from. The courses I'll be taking are mostly available via OCW, and some are offered on campus over the summer, or similar material is being taught at nearby universities. The courses I'm planning on taking currently are as follows, and are a sample track fulfilling the degree requirements, though the specific courses may change if I get feedback that something is better suited for my interests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've included the courses, followed by links to the materials below!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;core-courses&quot;&gt;Core Courses&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Calculus&lt;/strong&gt; - My calculus is quite strong, so I'll likely just review notes and complete the exams for the single and multivariable classes, but the material can be found here - &amp;gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://ocw.mit.edu/courses/mathematics/18-01sc-single-variable-calculus-fall-2010/&quot;&gt;18.01&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://ocw.mit.edu/courses/mathematics/18-02sc-multivariable-calculus-fall-2010/&quot;&gt;18.02&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Differential Equations&lt;/strong&gt; - Though I've taken a differential equations class in my undergrad years, I wasn't really paying attention. So, I'll likely focus on this class to fill my foundations -&amp;gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://ocw.mit.edu/courses/mathematics/18-03-differential-equations-spring-2010/&quot;&gt;18.03&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Linear Algebra&lt;/strong&gt; - My Linear Algebra is similarly strong, so again I'll likely focus on reviewing and taking the exams found here -&amp;gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://ocw.mit.edu/courses/mathematics/18-06sc-linear-algebra-fall-2011/&quot;&gt;18.06&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Complex Variables with Applications -&lt;/strong&gt; This is a required core course that covers complex algebra and functions, analyticity, contour integration, Cauchy's theorem, singularities, Taylor and Laurent series, residues, evaluation of integrals, multivalued functions, potential theory in two dimensions, Fourier analysis and Laplace transforms. It sounds interesting -&amp;gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://ocw.mit.edu/courses/mathematics/18-04-complex-variables-with-applications-fall-2003/&quot;&gt;18.04&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Principles of Discrete Applied Mathematics&lt;/strong&gt; - I've never taken Discrete Math. I taught myself programming and algorithms without a strong mathematical intuition, and I'm looking forward to developing one in this course -&amp;gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://ocw.mit.edu/courses/mathematics/18-310-principles-of-discrete-applied-mathematics-fall-2013/&quot;&gt;18.200&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Principles of Continuum Applied Mathematics&lt;/strong&gt; - Principles of Continuum Applied Mathematics covers fundamental concepts in continuous applied mathematics, including applications from traffic flow, fluids, elasticity, granular flows, etc. It also seems largely useful and is a required course so I'll be taking it! -&amp;gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://ocw.mit.edu/courses/mathematics/18-311-principles-of-applied-mathematics-spring-2014/&quot;&gt;18.300&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;restricted-electives&quot;&gt;Restricted Electives&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the core courses, the curriculum gives students the option of choosing courses from 2 groups, 1. Combinatorics, Computer Science, Probability and Statistics or 2. Numerical Analysis, Physical Mathematics, Nonlinear Dynamics&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4 courses must be taken, with at least 1 from each group. I'll likely be splitting down the middle, as I already have a Computational background that is provided by some of the classes in the first group. The courses I'm tentatively planning on completing are &lt;strong&gt;Probability&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;https://ocw.mit.edu/courses/mathematics/18-440-probability-and-random-variables-spring-2014/&quot;&gt;18.600&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Statistics&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;https://ocw.mit.edu/courses/mathematics/18-650-statistics-for-applications-fall-2016/&quot;&gt;18.650&lt;/a&gt; from the first group, and &lt;strong&gt;Partial Differential Equations&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;https://ocw.mit.edu/courses/mathematics/18-303-linear-partial-differential-equations-fall-2006/&quot;&gt;18.303&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Numerical Analysis&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;https://ocw.mit.edu/courses/mathematics/18-330-introduction-to-numerical-analysis-spring-2012/&quot;&gt;18.330&lt;/a&gt; from the 2nd group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, that's my plan. I'm not shoehorning this into a set period of time, though I will be actively meeting with Professors and auditing classes this summer while completing a research fellowship. I'm really looking forward to exploring and understanding Math, my plan is to share my updates, studies and intuitions here and perhaps they'll even translate into cool new architecture ideas or interesting collaborations!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe after this, I'll take a crack at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://math.mit.edu/academics/undergrad/major/course18/pure.php&quot;&gt;Pure Math curriculum&lt;/a&gt; too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you have any suggestions for me? I'd love to hear them, you can drop me a line on Twitter @harshsikka!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 19:29:45 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>hsikka</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Self Studying the MIT Applied Math Curriculum</og:title>
<og:description>Wow! This post blew up, if you'd like to get updates on how my progress goes, feel free to subscribe here [https://www.harshsikka.me/#subscribe] or follow me on twitter [https://twitter.com/HarshSikka]! I've decided to engage in a pretty interesting self development project this summer: Completing the requirements for the MIT Applied Math curriculum [http://math.mit.edu/academics/undergrad/major/course18/applied.php] through auditing classes, meeting professors, and completing the correspond</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.harshsikka.me/self-studying-the-mit-applied-math-curriculum/</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.harshsikka.me/self-studying-the-mit-applied-math-curriculum/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>TurboTax and H&amp;R Block Saw Free Tax Filing as a Threat</title>
<link>https://www.propublica.org/article/intuit-turbotax-h-r-block-gutted-free-tax-filing-internal-memo</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.propublica.org/article/intuit-turbotax-h-r-block-gutted-free-tax-filing-internal-memo</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;top-notes&quot; readability=&quot;6.1731843575419&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;note&quot; id=&quot;newsletter-txt-note&quot; readability=&quot;7.5977653631285&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ProPublica is a nonprofit newsroom based in New York. Sign up for ProPublica’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://go.propublica.org/20181219-apple&quot;&gt;Big Story&lt;/a&gt; newsletter to receive stories like this one in your inbox as soon as they are published.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;1.0&quot;&gt;Despite signing a deal with the IRS that pledged they would help tens of millions of Americans file taxes for free, tax software giants Intuit, the maker of TurboTax, and H&amp;amp;R Block instead deliberately hid the free option and actively steered customers into paid products, according to an internal document and five current and former employees of the companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;1.1&quot;&gt;H&amp;amp;R Block explicitly instructs its customer service staff to push people away from its free offering, according to internal guidance obtained by ProPublica.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;1.2&quot;&gt;“Do not send clients to this Web Site unless they are specifically calling about the Free File program,” the guidance states, referring to the site with the company’s free option. “We want to send users to our paid products before the free product, if at all possible.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;newsletter newsletter-big-story small right&quot; readability=&quot;27&quot;&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Get Our Top Investigations&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Subscribe to the Big Story newsletter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;3.0&quot;&gt;Steering customers away from TurboTax’s truly free option is a “purposeful strategy,” said a former midlevel Intuit employee. For people who find TurboTax through a search engine or an online ad, “the landing page would direct you through a product flow that the company wanted to ensure would not make you aware of Free File.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;3.1&quot;&gt;When the Free File program launched 16 years ago, it was extolled as the best sort of collaboration between government and private enterprise. With little cost to the IRS, the huge companies that dominate online tax preparation would help millions of Americans file their taxes for free. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.propublica.org/article/congress-is-about-to-ban-the-government-from-offering-free-online-tax-filing-thank-turbotax&quot;&gt;Intuit and the industry&lt;/a&gt; have spent millions lobbying to make the Free File program permanent because it contains a noncompete provision that restricts the IRS from creating its own free, online filing system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;3.2&quot;&gt;But privately, the free filing option is seen for what it is: a threat to the companies’ profits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;3.3&quot;&gt;So the companies had to strike a delicate balance: They wanted to preserve their arrangement with the IRS to ward off government competition, but then they also sought to make sure the program didn’t recruit too many customers who actually got something for free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;3.4&quot;&gt;The companies set out to convert people who qualify for the program into paying customers. Sure enough, use of the Free File program has collapsed. Soon after it was launched in 2003, more than 5 million Americans filed their taxes for free. Now it’s about half as many, according to the latest IRS data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;3.5&quot;&gt;The industry has also succeeded in fending off a pair of grave dangers: the prospect of the government either creating its own easy online filing system or offering tax returns pre-filled with data the IRS already has, a practice common in other countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;3.6&quot;&gt;Now Intuit and H&amp;amp;R Block could be dealt a setback. A bill that would codify the Free File program, which passed the House last month, has stalled in the Senate after ProPublica reported that the companies were making it more difficult for people to find their Free File websites by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.propublica.org/article/turbotax-deliberately-hides-its-free-file-page-from-search-engines&quot;&gt;hiding them from search engines&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;3.7&quot;&gt;Both companies employ similar tactics: They lure customers in with products advertised as “free” but that upsell them to paid products — or hit them with surprise charges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;3.8&quot;&gt;At Intuit, “The entire strategy is make sure people read the word ‘free’ and click our site and never use” an actually free product, the former midlevel employee said. In reality, TurboTax’s Free Edition guides many people to a product that costs them money. It’s only free for people with the simplest tax situations. The “vast majority of people who click that will not pay $0,” the former employee said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;“TurboTax’s recent ads consist entirely of the word “free”&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A TurboTax commercial from 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/7GtJPT3F1uw&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;5.0&quot;&gt;Only a small portion of taxpayers, under 3 million a year, find their way to the program, far below the 100 million who actually qualify. The program is open to anyone who makes under $66,000. The IRS, meanwhile, continues to tout the program as a success, despite its decline. Internal IRS documents show agency officials unconcerned that tens of millions of taxpayers have been drawn to other “free” options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;5.1&quot;&gt;In statements in response to questions from ProPublica, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/5984476-Intuit-Statement-5-1-19.html&quot;&gt;Intuit&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/5985429-HR-Block-5-1-19.html&quot;&gt;H&amp;amp;R Block&lt;/a&gt; both said they were “proud” of the Free File program and cited the fact that millions of taxpayers have used it. They did not specifically address the employee accounts. Intuit’s spokesman said the company “created and paid for 17 marketing initiatives … to raise awareness and educate taxpayers about the IRS Free File program.” He specifically pointed to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aol.com/article/finance/2019/04/10/irs-free-file-alliance-offers-free-tax-filing-including-intuit-turbotax-free-file/23709107/&quot;&gt;press release on AOL.com&lt;/a&gt; about the program “syndicated through AOL at our expense to drive awareness.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;5.2&quot;&gt;The H&amp;amp;R Block spokeswoman said the company’s Free File offering grew 8.3% this year, and “we have updated our search practices to make H&amp;amp;R Block’s Free File offer even easier to find.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;5.3&quot;&gt;An IRS spokesman said the agency “continues to support the Free File program.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;5.4&quot;&gt;At Intuit, it’s an open secret within the company that helping customers find the Free File program would be bad for business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;5.5&quot;&gt;One former marketing employee recalled a May 2017 meeting of a marketing team at TurboTax’s San Diego headquarters. The tax filing season had just ended, and a dozen or so staffers up to the senior manager level were brainstorming. A new employee proposed that customers going through TurboTax’s interview-style filing process who were found to be eligible for Free File get a “hard recommendation” — essentially a pop-up window — to be routed to the truly free product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;5.6&quot;&gt;The response? Laughter, according to the former employee. The meeting quickly moved on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;5.7&quot;&gt;“They have ways of detecting if you’re paying too much, but they just don’t do it,” the former staffer said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;5.8&quot;&gt;As a result, many people end up paying TurboTax even though they could have filed for free. The company won’t say how many people this is, but it is likely in the millions. Dozens of taxpayers have contacted ProPublica to tell &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.propublica.org/article/here-are-your-stories-of-being-tricked-into-paying-by-turbotax-you-often-need-the-money&quot;&gt;their stories of being charged by TurboTax&lt;/a&gt; despite the fact that they earned under $34,000 a year, qualifying them for TurboTax’s Free File product. An 87-year-old retiree with a gross income of $11,000, for example, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.propublica.org/article/here-are-your-stories-of-being-tricked-into-paying-by-turbotax-you-often-need-the-money&quot;&gt;was charged $124.98&lt;/a&gt; to file with TurboTax.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;H&amp;amp;R Block tells staff to steer people away from Free File&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;H&amp;amp;R Block instructs its staff to push people toward its paid products in this internal guidance obtained by ProPublica.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.propublica.org/images/articles/_threeTwo400w/HRB-screenshot.jpg&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;100&quot; srcset=&quot;https://assets.propublica.org/images/articles/_threeTwo400w/HRB-screenshot.jpg 400w, https://assets.propublica.org/images/articles/_threeTwo800w/HRB-screenshot.jpg 800w, https://assets.propublica.org/images/articles/_threeTwo1600w/HRB-screenshot.jpg 1600w, https://assets.propublica.org/images/articles/_threeTwo2000w/HRB-screenshot.jpg 2000w&quot;/&gt;&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;7.0&quot;&gt;At H&amp;amp;R Block, a former veteran staffer called it “company policy” to steer customers away from the Free File option. “The company is making money from the product, and that money is eating into the clients’ refund,” the former staffer said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;7.1&quot;&gt;At Intuit, customers who don’t know about the Free File product will find themselves instead on the “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.propublica.org/article/turbotax-just-tricked-you-into-paying-to-file-your-taxes&quot;&gt;Free Edition&lt;/a&gt;.” There, they are often pushed to buy deluxe versions of TurboTax they might not need. They can be charged a $39.99 “Refund Processing” fee to have the cost of TurboTax deducted from their refund instead of paying upfront. They are also sold side products such as “audit defense,” which offers expert representation in the event of an audit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;7.2&quot;&gt;Executives who have worked at the company boast on resumes reviewed by ProPublica about their success in having diverted customers from “free” offerings to paying products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;7.3&quot;&gt;One former marketing manager described her role as “driving new business growth” through TurboTax Free Edition “while mitigating cannibalization of our paid tax offerings.” Another senior product marketing manager boasted that she had helped develop the “monetization strategy of the TurboTax Free Edition product.” She said she applied the principles of the behavioral economist &lt;a href=&quot;http://danariely.com/&quot;&gt;Dan Ariely&lt;/a&gt; to enhance “TurboTax in-product upsell experiences.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;7.4&quot;&gt;On LinkedIn, Heather Samarin, who was a TurboTax vice president of product management a decade ago, said that she had been “charged with addressing the threat posed by IRS free efile program” and had “revamped TurboTax marketing strategy for low-end tax filers,” driving a “100% increase in revenues.” She did not respond to requests for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;7.5&quot;&gt;At a meeting in 2014, Intuit’s then-Chief Financial Officer Neil Williams described the prospect of the IRS adopting a system of pre-filled returns as an “existential threat” to the company, according to the former midlevel staffer. Williams didn’t respond to requests for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;7.6&quot;&gt;Last summer, according to a former marketing employee, the then-head of TurboTax, Dan Wernikoff, attended a meeting about customers who had unnecessarily selected costlier products like TurboTax Deluxe. These customers had tax situations that qualified them for a cheaper or even free product, and the slides shown at the meeting referred to them as having been “overcharged.” According to the former employee, Wernikoff instructed that going forward, employees should never use the word “overcharged.” Instead, they should say that these customers’ use of products intended for higher-earning customers was “aspirational.” Wernikoff didn’t respond to a request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;7.7&quot;&gt;The IRS’ Free File program peaked early. In 2005, its third year, 5.1 million taxpayers used the program to file a free return. That early success set the program up for plenty of growth, as every year, millions more Americans were moving away from paper to file their tax returns electronically. In 2005, only 68.5 million returns were filed electronically — about half the number filed electronically last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;7.8&quot;&gt;But instead of growing, Free File shrank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pym-src=&quot;https://projects.propublica.org/graphics/embed-free-file-percent?layout=embed&amp;amp;050219&quot;&gt;Loading...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;9.0&quot;&gt;At the IRS, according to internal management reports obtained by ProPublica through a public records request, executives were ambivalent about the program’s decline. The reason for the drop was that companies “now heavily promote free options outside of IRS Free File,” said a report in November 2009. Two years later, as the numbers slid further, a report blamed the “continued migration of taxpayers to other online free services offered in the marketplace.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;9.1&quot;&gt;By 2017, after the number of Free File users had been cut in half from its 2005 peak, IRS executives were claiming the program’s decline was instead proof of its success. As a November 2017 internal report put it: “We believe the continued decrease is a direct result of the increase in free options available in the broad marketplace. Free File has been successful in generating a free marketplace and stimulating that marketplace, perhaps to the program’s detriment.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;9.2&quot;&gt;Yet the same report conceded that the IRS did not have a “quantitative understanding for the decrease in Free File returns” — in other words, the agency had never actually studied why or how taxpayers were lured to other options in the “free marketplace” or whether those options were actually free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;9.3&quot;&gt;One year later, an IRS oversight panel contradicted the report’s rosy conclusions. The panel wrote that the agency “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/5910811-Internal-Revenue-Service-Advisory-Council.html#document/p15/a494005&quot;&gt;does not provide adequate oversight of the Free File program&lt;/a&gt;” and that by failing to have clear goals for the program or checking to make sure the companies were following through on their promises, the IRS was putting “vulnerable taxpayers at risk.” Despite the panel’s criticism, the IRS has not announced any significant reforms to oversight of the program. Last October, the IRS signed a deal with Intuit and the other companies renewing the Free File program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside data-pp-id=&quot;10&quot; data-pp-blocktype=&quot;promo&quot; class=&quot;promo small left&quot;&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Read More&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;story-entry&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;lead-art thumbnail&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;aspect-1-1&quot; href=&quot;https://www.propublica.org/article/turbotax-just-tricked-you-into-paying-to-file-your-taxes&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.propublica.org/images/articles/_oneOne75w/20190422-turbotax-ads-1x1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;75&quot; height=&quot;75&quot; srcset=&quot;https://assets.propublica.org/images/articles/_oneOne75w/20190422-turbotax-ads-1x1.jpg 75w, https://assets.propublica.org/images/articles/_oneOne150w/20190422-turbotax-ads-1x1.jpg 150w&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;11.0&quot;&gt;Intuit’s aggressive lobbying of Congress on tax filing issues is well known inside the company, but it is a topic most employees shy away from discussing openly, according to a former Intuit engineer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;11.1&quot;&gt;One employee recalled longtime Intuit CEO Brad Smith, a folksy leader who often invokes his roots in West Virginia, batting back a question at an employee Q&amp;amp;A about whether the IRS should offer Americans pre-filled tax returns. If that happened, Smith argued, the government would take advantage of people, especially those who don’t speak English. A company spokesman didn’t respond to a question about the episode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;11.2&quot;&gt;Smith presided over a decade of dramatic growth at Intuit before he was succeeded by Sasan Goodarzi this year. Last year, Intuit’s consumer division, which includes TurboTax, reported &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/5955655-Intuit-2018-Annual-Report-on-Form-10-K-PDF.html#document/p41&quot;&gt;$1.6 billion&lt;/a&gt; in operating income.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;11.3&quot;&gt;After ProPublica &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.propublica.org/article/how-to-get-turbotax-refund&quot;&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt; last month that many people had been charged even though they were eligible to file for free, dozens of readers reported receiving refunds. But in recent days, the company created a special team to handle — and deny — refund requests, according to customer service representatives working for Intuit subcontractors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;11.4&quot;&gt;Customer service staff reported being told to blame the 2017 Trump tax law for customers being charged. Multiple readers said they’d been told that the ProPublica stories were “fake news.” Intuit has not answered repeated questions about its refund policy. A spokesman said that no material provided to call agents “included a reference to tax law changes, elected officials or derogatory terms about ProPublica.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;11.5&quot;&gt;Meanwhile, calls to investigate the industry’s attempts to steer taxpayers away from the Free File program are growing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;ad-300&quot;&gt;

&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;13.0&quot;&gt;This week, &lt;a href=&quot;https://projects.propublica.org/represent/members/P000618-katie-porter&quot;&gt;Rep. Katie Porter, D-Calif.&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/RepKatiePorter/status/1122890519636582401&quot;&gt;wrote letters asking&lt;/a&gt; the IRS and Federal Trade Commission to investigate Intuit’s and H&amp;amp;R Block’s attempts to hide their Free File pages from search engines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;13.1&quot;&gt;On Wednesday, New York Gov. Andrew Cuomo requested two state agencies to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.governor.ny.gov/news/governor-cuomo-calls-department-financial-services-and-department-taxation-and-finance&quot;&gt;open an investigation&lt;/a&gt;. In response, the Intuit spokesman said: “Our search and marketing practices around the IRS Free File program have been called into question. These characterizations are untrue and we look forward to sharing the facts with New York regulators.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-pp-blocktype=&quot;copy&quot; data-pp-id=&quot;13.2&quot;&gt;The spokesman didn’t respond to requests to specify which characterizations were untrue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bottom-notes&quot; readability=&quot;5.6502242152466&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;note co-publish&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ariana Tobin contributed to this report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 18:28:24 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>danso</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.propublica.org/article/intuit-turbotax-h-r-block-gutted-free-tax-filing-internal-memo</og:url>
<og:title>TurboTax and H&amp;R Block Saw Free Tax Filing as a Threat — and Gutted It — ProPublica</og:title>
<og:description>An internal document and current and former company employees show the companies steered customers away from the government-sponsored free option and made them pay.</og:description>
<og:image>https://assets.propublica.org/images/articles/20190502-borge-1200x630.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.propublica.org/article/intuit-turbotax-h-r-block-gutted-free-tax-filing-internal-memo</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Facebook Bans Louis Farrakhan, Milo Yiannopoulos, InfoWars and Others</title>
<link>https://edition.cnn.com/2019/05/02/tech/facebook-ban-louis-farrakhan-infowars-alex-jones-milo-laura-loomer/index.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://edition.cnn.com/2019/05/02/tech/facebook-ban-louis-farrakhan-infowars-alex-jones-milo-laura-loomer/index.html</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://edition.cnn.com/2019/05/02/tech/facebook-ban-louis-farrakhan-infowars-alex-jones-milo-laura-loomer/index.html&quot;&gt;https://edition.cnn.com/2019/05/02/tech/facebook-ban-louis-farrakhan-infowars-alex-jones-milo-laura-loomer/index.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19810897&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19810897&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 254&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 429&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 18:21:10 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>aestetix</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.propublica.org/article/intuit-turbotax-h-r-block-gutted-free-tax-filing-internal-memo</og:url>
<og:title>TurboTax and H&amp;R Block Saw Free Tax Filing as a Threat — and Gutted It — ProPublica</og:title>
<og:description>An internal document and current and former company employees show the companies steered customers away from the government-sponsored free option and made them pay.</og:description>
<og:image>https://assets.propublica.org/images/articles/20190502-borge-1200x630.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.propublica.org/article/intuit-turbotax-h-r-block-gutted-free-tax-filing-internal-memo</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Google Will Soon Let You Automatically Scrub Your Location and Web History</title>
<link>https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/pranavdixit/google-will-soon-let-you-automatically-scrub-your-location</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/pranavdixit/google-will-soon-let-you-automatically-scrub-your-location</guid>
<description>&lt;div data-module=&quot;subbuzz-text&quot; readability=&quot;41.060975609756&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s no secret that Google tracks a lot of data about you, from the websites you visit to the videos you watch, the things you’ve searched for, and the places you have visited. Scrubbing this data from your Google account has required you to manually dig into your settings each time. That’s changing soon.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the next few weeks, Google will be &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.google/technology/safety-security/automatically-delete-data/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;rolling out&lt;/a&gt; a feature to users around the world that will let them set this information to be deleted automatically every three or 18 months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div data-module=&quot;subbuzz-text&quot; readability=&quot;53.442020665901&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;We work to keep your data private and secure, and we’ve heard your feedback that we need to provide simpler ways for you to manage or delete it,&quot; Google said in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.google/technology/safety-security/automatically-delete-data/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; published Wednesday.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now, these controls are only coming to your location history and web and app activity, but it’s likely that they’ll come to more of your data history at some point.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scrubbing this information from your Google account will make using Google services slightly less useful. After all, Google uses the data it collects about you to personalize its services by recommending restaurants, movies, music; adding appointments to your calendar; telling you whether it’s going to rain in your city; and, of course, serving you ads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the flip side, being able to get a giant corporation that guzzles all of your data to delete it periodically is a definite plus for privacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 15:37:11 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>siberianbear</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/pranavdixit/google-will-soon-let-you-automatically-scrub-your-location</og:url>
<og:image>https://img.buzzfeed.com/buzzfeed-static/static/2019-05/2/12/campaign_images/buzzfeed-prod-web-01/google-will-soon-let-you-automatically-scrub-your-2-11222-1556814245-0_dblbig.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>Google Will Soon Let You Automatically Scrub Your Location And Web History From Your Account Every Few Months</og:title>
<og:description>It’s a plus for privacy.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/pranavdixit/google-will-soon-let-you-automatically-scrub-your-location</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Microsoft, currently the most valuable company, is having a Nadellaissance</title>
<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2019-05-02/satya-nadella-remade-microsoft-as-world-s-most-valuable-company</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2019-05-02/satya-nadella-remade-microsoft-as-world-s-most-valuable-company</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2019-05-02/satya-nadella-remade-microsoft-as-world-s-most-valuable-company&quot;&gt;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2019-05-02/satya-nadella-remade-microsoft-as-world-s-most-valuable-company&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19807981&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19807981&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 273&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 276&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 14:01:15 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>crones</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bloomberg.com/tosv2.html?vid=&amp;uuid=9e663230-6d36-11e9-8fe5-93e2c4b23dc9&amp;url=L25ld3MvZmVhdHVyZXMvMjAxOS0wNS0wMi9zYXR5YS1uYWRlbGxhLXJlbWFkZS1taWNyb3NvZnQtYXMtd29ybGQtcy1tb3N0LXZhbHVhYmxlLWNvbXBhbnk=</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Stripe’s fifth engineering hub is Remote</title>
<link>https://stripe.com/blog/remote-hub</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://stripe.com/blog/remote-hub</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Stripe has engineering hubs in San Francisco, Seattle, Dublin, and Singapore. We are establishing a fifth hub that is less traditional but no less important: Remote. We are doing this to situate product development closer to our customers, improve our ability to tap the 99.74% of talented engineers living outside the metro areas of our first four hubs, and further our mission of increasing the GDP of the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stripe will hire over a hundred remote engineers this year. They will be deployed across every major engineering workstream at Stripe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;our-users-are-everywhere-we-have-to-be-too&quot;&gt;Our users are everywhere. We have to be, too.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our remotes keep us close to our customers, which is key to building great products. They are deeply embedded in the rhythms of their cities. They see how people purchase food differently in bodegas, konbini, and darshinis. They know why it is important to engineer robustness in the face of slow, unreliable internet connections. They have worked in and run businesses that don’t have access to global payments infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stripe has had hundreds of extremely high-impact remote employees since inception. Historically, they’ve reported into teams based in one of our hubs. We had a strong preference for managers to be located in-office and for teams to be office-centric, to maximize face-to-face bandwidth when doing creative work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we have grown as a company, we have learned some things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One is that the technological substrate of collaboration has gotten &lt;em&gt;shockingly&lt;/em&gt; good over the last decade. Most engineering work at Stripe happens in conversations between engineers, quiet thinking, and turning those thoughts into artifacts. Of these, thinking is the only one that doesn’t primarily happen online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a time when writing on a whiteboard had substantially higher bandwidth than a Word doc over email. Thankfully Google Docs, Slack, git, Zoom, and the like deliver high-bandwidth synchronous collaboration on creative work. The experience of using them is so remarkably good that we only notice it when something is broken. Since you write code via pull requests and not whiteboards, your reviewer needs to have access to the same PR; having access to the same whiteboard is strictly optional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While we did not initially plan to make hiring remotes a huge part of our engineering efforts, our remote employees have outperformed all expectations. Foundational elements of the Stripe technology stack, our products, our business, and our culture were contributed by remotes. We would be a greatly diminished company without them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;stripes-new-remote-engineering-hub&quot;&gt;Stripe’s new remote engineering hub&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have seen such promising results from our remote engineers that we are greatly increasing our investment in remote engineering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We are formalizing our Remote engineering hub.&lt;/strong&gt; It is coequal with our physical hubs, and will benefit from some of our experience in &lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/atlas/guides/scaling-eng&quot;&gt;scaling engineering organizations&lt;/a&gt;. For example, there will be dedicated engineering teams in the Remote hub that exist in no other hub. (Some individuals report to a team located in a different hub, and we expect this will remain common, but the bulk of high-bandwidth coworker relationships are within-hub.) We also have a remote engineering lead, analogous to the site leads we have for our physical hubs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We are expanding the scope we will hire for remotely&lt;/strong&gt;. In addition to hiring engineers, we plan to begin hiring remote product managers, engineering managers, and technical program managers later this year. (We will continue hiring remote employees in non-engineering positions across the company as well.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We intend to expand our remote engineering hiring aggressively.&lt;/strong&gt; We will hire at least a hundred remote engineers this year. We expect to be constrained primarily by our capacity to onboard and support new remote engineers, and we will work to increase that capacity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We will continue to improve the experience of being a remote.&lt;/strong&gt; We have carefully tracked the experience of our remote employees, including in our twice-annual employee survey. Most recently, 73% of engineers at Stripe believe we do a good job of integrating remote employees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great user experiences are made in the tiny details. We care about the details to a degree that is borderline obsessive. A recent example: we wrote code to attach a videoconferencing link to every calendar invitation by default, so that remotes never feel awkward having to ask for one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;more-to-come&quot;&gt;More to come&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are still some constraints on our ambitions. In our first phase, we will be focused primarily on remote engineers in North America, starting with the US and Canada. While we are confident that great work is possible within close time zones, we don’t yet have structures to give remotes a reliably good experience working across large time zone differences. And though we intend to hire remote engineers in Europe and Asia eventually, our hubs in Dublin and Singapore are not sufficiently established to support remotes just yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most engineers working at Stripe are full-time employees, with a full benefits suite. There is substantial organizational, legal, and financial infrastructure required to support each new jurisdiction we hire in, so we have to be measured in how quickly we expand. We can support most US states today, and plan to expand our hiring capabilities to include jurisdictions covering more than 90% of the US population as quickly as possible. We intend, over the longer term, to be everywhere our customers are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will continue encouraging governments worldwide to lower barriers to hiring. Our customers, from startups to international conglomerates, all feel the pain of this. We think making it easier for companies to hire would produce a step-function increase in global GDP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-want-to-talk-to-you&quot;&gt;We want to talk to you&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would love to talk about our Remote hub or &lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/jobs/search?l=remote&quot;&gt;remote positions at Stripe&lt;/a&gt;. Our CEO and co-founder, Patrick Collison, and I will host a remote coffee on May 22, 2019; &lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.events/remote-coffee&quot;&gt;sign up to be invited&lt;/a&gt; to it. We are also, and always, available on the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 12:43:21 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>geordilaforge</dc:creator>
<og:title>Stripe’s fifth engineering hub is Remote</og:title>
<og:url>https://stripe.com/blog/remote-hub</og:url>
<og:description>Stripe has engineering hubs in San Francisco, Seattle, Dublin, and Singapore. We are establishing a fifth hub that is less traditional but no less important: Remote. We are doing this to situate product development closer to our customers, improve our ability to tap the 99.74% of talented engineers living outside the metro areas of our first four hubs, and further our mission of increasing the GDP of the internet. Stripe will hire over a hundred remote engineers this year. They will be deployed across every major engineering workstream at Stripe. ## Our users are everywhere. We have to be, too. Our remotes keep us close to our customers, which is key to building great products. They are deeply embedded in the rhythms of their cities. They see how people purchase food differently in bodegas, konbini, and darshinis. They know why it is important to engineer robustness in the face of slow, unreliable internet connections. They have worked in and run businesses that don’t have access to global payments infrastructure. Stripe has had hundreds of extremely high-impact remote employees since inception. Historically, they’ve reported into teams based in one of our hubs. We had a strong preference for managers to be located in-office and for teams to be office-centric, to maximize face-to-face bandwidth when doing creative work. As we have grown as a company, we have learned some things. One is that the technological substrate of collaboration has gotten *shockingly* good over the last decade. Most engineering work at Stripe happens in conversations between engineers, quiet thinking, and turning those thoughts into artifacts. Of these, thinking is the only one that doesn’t primarily happen online. There was a time when writing on a whiteboard had substantially higher bandwidth than a Word doc over email. Thankfully Google Docs, Slack, git, Zoom, and the like deliver high-bandwidth synchronous collaboration on creative work. The experience of using them is so remarkably good that we only notice it when something is broken. Since you write code via pull requests and not whiteboards, your reviewer needs to have access to the same PR; having access to the same whiteboard is strictly optional. While we did not initially plan to make hiring remotes a huge part of our engineering efforts, our remote employees have outperformed all expectations. Foundational elements of the Stripe technology stack, our products, our business, and our culture were contributed by remotes. We would be a greatly diminished company without them. ## Stripe’s new remote engineering hub We have seen such promising results from our remote engineers that we are greatly increasing our investment in remote engineering. **We are formalizing our Remote engineering hub.** It is coequal with our physical hubs, and will benefit from some of our experience in [scaling engineering organizations](https://stripe.com/atlas/guides/scaling-eng). For example, there will be dedicated engineering teams in the Remote hub that exist in no other hub. (Some individuals report to a team located in a different hub, and we expect this will remain common, but the bulk of high-bandwidth coworker relationships are within-hub.) We also have a remote engineering lead, analogous to the site leads we have for our physical hubs. **We are expanding the scope we will hire for remotely**. In addition to hiring engineers, we plan to begin hiring remote product managers, engineering managers, and technical program managers later this year. (We will continue hiring remote employees in non-engineering positions across the company as well.) **We intend to expand our remote engineering hiring aggressively.** We will hire at least a hundred remote engineers this year. We expect to be constrained primarily by our capacity to onboard and support new remote engineers, and we will work to increase that capacity. **We will continue to improve the experience of being a remote.** We have carefully tracked the experience of our remote employees, including in our twice-annual employee survey. Most recently, 73% of engineers at Stripe believe we do a good job of integrating remote employees. Great user experiences are made in the tiny details. We care about the details to a degree that is borderline obsessive. A recent example: we wrote code to attach a videoconferencing link to every calendar invitation by default, so that remotes never feel awkward having to ask for one. ## More to come There are still some constraints on our ambitions. In our first phase, we will be focused primarily on remote engineers in North America, starting with the US and Canada. While we are confident that great work is possible within close time zones, we don’t yet have structures to give remotes a reliably good experience working across large time zone differences. And though we intend to hire remote engineers in Europe and Asia eventually, our hubs in Dublin and Singapore are not sufficiently established to support remotes just yet. Most engineers working at Stripe are full-time employees, with a full benefits suite. There is substantial organizational, legal, and financial infrastructure required to support each new jurisdiction we hire in, so we have to be measured in how quickly we expand. We can support most US states today, and plan to expand our hiring capabilities to include jurisdictions covering more than 90% of the US population as quickly as possible. We intend, over the longer term, to be everywhere our customers are. We will continue encouraging governments worldwide to lower barriers to hiring. Our customers, from startups to international conglomerates, all feel the pain of this. We think making it easier for companies to hire would produce a step-function increase in global GDP. ## We want to talk to you We would love to talk about our Remote hub or [remote positions at Stripe](https://stripe.com/jobs/search?l=remote). Our CEO and co-founder, Patrick Collison, and I will host a remote coffee on May 22, 2019; [sign up to be invited](https://stripe.events/remote-coffee) to it. We are also, and always, available on the internet.</og:description>
<og:image>https://stripe.com/img/v3/home/social.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://stripe.com/blog/remote-hub</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>GNU Guix 1.0.0 released</title>
<link>https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/blog/2019/gnu-guix-1.0.0-released/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/blog/2019/gnu-guix-1.0.0-released/</guid>
<description>&lt;h2&gt;GNU Guix 1.0.0 released&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;post-metadata centered-text&quot;&gt;Ludovic Courtès — May 2, 2019&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are excited to announce the release of GNU Guix version 1.0.0!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The release comes with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/manual/en/html_node/System-Installation.html&quot;&gt;ISO-9660 installation images&lt;/a&gt;, a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/manual/en/html_node/Running-Guix-in-a-VM.html&quot;&gt;virtual machine image&lt;/a&gt;, and with tarballs to install the package manager on top of your GNU/Linux distro, either &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/manual/en/html_node/Requirements.html&quot;&gt;from source&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/manual/en/html_node/Binary-Installation.html&quot;&gt;from binaries&lt;/a&gt;. Guix users can update by running &lt;code&gt;guix pull&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/static/blog/img/guix-1.0.png&quot; alt=&quot;Guix 1.0!&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One-point-oh always means a lot for free software releases. For Guix, 1.0 is the result of seven years of development, with code, packaging, and documentation contributions made by 260 people, translation work carried out by a dozen of people, and artwork and web site development by a couple of individuals, to name some of the activities that have been happening. During those years we published no less than &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/blog/tags/releases/&quot;&gt;19 “0.x” releases&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We took our time to get there, which is quite unusual in an era where free software moves so fast. Why did we take this much time? First, it takes time to build a community around a GNU/Linux distribution, and a distribution wouldn’t really exist without it. Second, we feel like we’re contributing an important piece to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/gnu/about-gnu.html&quot;&gt;the GNU operating system&lt;/a&gt;, and that is surely intimidating and humbling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last, we’ve been building something new. Of course we stand on the shoulders of giants, and in particular &lt;a href=&quot;https://nixos.org/nix/&quot;&gt;Nix&lt;/a&gt;, which brought the functional software deployment paradigm that Guix implements. But developing Guix has been—and still is!—a challenge in many ways: it’s a &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1305.4584&quot;&gt;programming&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/blog/2017/back-from-gpce/&quot;&gt;language&lt;/a&gt; design challenge, an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/blog/2015/service-composition-in-guixsd/&quot;&gt;operating&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/blog/2017/running-system-services-in-containers/&quot;&gt;system&lt;/a&gt; design challenge, a challenge for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/blog/2016/timely-delivery-of-security-updates/&quot;&gt;security&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/blog/tags/reproducibility/&quot;&gt;reproducibility&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/blog/tags/bootstrapping/&quot;&gt;bootstrapping&lt;/a&gt;, usability, and more. In other words, it’s been a long but insightful journey! :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presumably some of the readers are discovering Guix today, so let’s recap what Guix can do for you as a user. Guix is a complete toolbox for software deployment in general, which makes it different from most of the tools you may be familiar with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/static/blog/img/guix-scope.png&quot; alt=&quot;Guix manages packages, environments, containers, and systems.&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This may sound a little abstract so let’s look at concrete use cases:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;31.101871101871&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;22.128440366972&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As a user&lt;/em&gt;, Guix allows you to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/manual/en/html_node/Invoking-guix-package.html&quot;&gt;install applications and to keep them up-to-date&lt;/a&gt;: search for software with &lt;code&gt;guix search&lt;/code&gt;, install it with &lt;code&gt;guix install&lt;/code&gt;, and maintain it up-to-date by regularly running &lt;code&gt;guix pull&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;guix upgrade&lt;/code&gt;. Guix follows a so-called “rolling release” model, so you can run &lt;code&gt;guix pull&lt;/code&gt; at any time to get the latest and greatest bits of free software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This certainly sounds familiar, but a distinguishing property here is &lt;em&gt;dependability&lt;/em&gt;: Guix is transactional, meaning that you can at any time roll back to a previous “generation” of your package set with &lt;code&gt;guix package --roll-back&lt;/code&gt;, inspect differences with &lt;code&gt;guix package -l&lt;/code&gt;, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another useful property is &lt;em&gt;reproducibility&lt;/em&gt;: Guix allows you to deploy the &lt;em&gt;exact same software environment&lt;/em&gt; on different machines or at different points in time thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/manual/en/html_node/Invoking-guix-describe.html&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;guix describe&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/manual/en/html_node/Invoking-guix-pull.html&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;guix pull&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This, coupled with the fact that package management operations do not require root access, is invaluable notably in the context of high-performance computing (HPC) and reproducible science, which the &lt;a href=&quot;https://guix-hpc.bordeaux.inria.fr/&quot;&gt;Guix-HPC effort&lt;/a&gt; has been focusing on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;12.277539341917&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As a developer&lt;/em&gt;, we hope you’ll enjoy &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/manual/en/html_node/Invoking-guix-environment.html&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;guix environment&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which allows you to spawn one-off software environments. Suppose you’re a GIMP developer: running &lt;code&gt;guix environment gimp&lt;/code&gt; spawns a shell with everything you need to hack on GIMP—much quicker than manually installing its many dependencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developers often struggle to push their work to users so they get quick feedback. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/blog/2017/creating-bundles-with-guix-pack/&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;guix pack&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; provides an easy way to create &lt;em&gt;container images&lt;/em&gt; for use by Docker &amp;amp; co., or even &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/blog/2018/tarballs-the-ultimate-container-image-format/&quot;&gt;standalone relocatable tarballs&lt;/a&gt; that anyone can run, regardless of the GNU/Linux distribution they use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, and you may also like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/manual/en/html_node/Package-Transformation-Options.html&quot;&gt;package transformation options&lt;/a&gt;, which allow you define package variants from the command line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;25.150684931507&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As a system administrator&lt;/em&gt;—and actually, we’re all system administrators of sorts on our laptops!—, Guix’s declarative and unified approach to configuration management should be handy. It surely is a departure from what most people are used to, but it is so reassuring: one configuration file is enough to specify &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/manual/en/html_node/Using-the-Configuration-System.html&quot;&gt;all the aspects of the system config&lt;/a&gt;—services, file systems, locale, accounts—all in the same language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That makes it surprisingly easy to deploy otherwise complex services such as applications that depend on Web services. For instance, setting up &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/manual/en/html_node/Version-Control-Services.html#Cgit-Service&quot;&gt;CGit&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/manual/en/html_node/Monitoring-Services.html#Zabbix-front_002dend&quot;&gt;Zabbix&lt;/a&gt; is a one-liner, even though behind the scenes that involves setting up nginx, fcgiwrap, etc. We’d love to see to what extent this helps people self-host services—sort of similar to what &lt;a href=&quot;https://freedombox.org/&quot;&gt;FreedomBox&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://yunohost.org/&quot;&gt;YunoHost&lt;/a&gt; have been focusing on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/manual/en/html_node/Invoking-guix-system.html&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;guix system&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; you can instantiate a configuration on your machine, or in a virtual machine (VM) where you can test it, or in a container. You can also provision ISO images, VM images, or container images with a complete OS, from the same config, all with &lt;code&gt;guix system&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/guix-refcard.pdf&quot;&gt;quick reference card&lt;/a&gt; shows the important commands. As you start diving deeper into Guix, you’ll discover that many aspects of the system are exposed using consistent &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guile/&quot;&gt;Guile&lt;/a&gt; programming interfaces: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/manual/en/html_node/Defining-Packages.html&quot;&gt;package definitions&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/manual/en/html_node/Services.html&quot;&gt;system services&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/shepherd/&quot;&gt;“init” system&lt;/a&gt;, and a whole bunch of system-level libraries. We believe that makes the system very &lt;em&gt;hackable&lt;/em&gt;, and we hope you’ll find it as much fun to play with as we do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So much for the overview!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those who’ve been following along, a great many things have changed over the last 5 months since the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/blog/2018/gnu-guix-and-guixsd-0.16.0-released/&quot;&gt;0.16.0 release&lt;/a&gt;—99 people contributed over 5,700 commits during that time! Here are the highlights:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The ISO installation image now runs a cute &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/manual/en/html_node/Guided-Graphical-Installation.html&quot;&gt;text-mode graphical installer&lt;/a&gt;—big thanks to Mathieu Othacehe for writing it and to everyone who tested it and improved it! It is similar in spirit to the Debian installer. Whether you’re a die-hard GNU/Linux hacker or a novice user, you’ll certainly find that this makes system installation much less tedious than it was! The installer is fully translated to French, German, and Spanish.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The new &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/manual/en/html_node/Running-GuixSD-in-a-VM.html&quot;&gt;VM image&lt;/a&gt; better matches user expectations: whether you want to tinker with Guix System and see what it’s like, or whether you want to use it as a development environment, this VM image should be more directly useful.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The user interface was improved: aliases for common operations &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/manual/en/html_node/Invoking-guix-package.html&quot;&gt;such as &lt;code&gt;guix search&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;guix install&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; are now available, diagnostics are now colorized, more operations show a progress bar, there’s a new &lt;code&gt;--verbosity&lt;/code&gt; option recognized by all commands, and most commands are now “quiet” by default.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There’s a new &lt;code&gt;--with-git-url&lt;/code&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/manual/en/html_node/Package-Transformation-Options.html&quot;&gt;package transformation option&lt;/a&gt;, that goes with &lt;code&gt;--with-branch&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;--with-commit&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Guix now has a first-class, uniform mechanism to configure &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/manual/en/html_node/Keyboard-Layout.html&quot;&gt;keyboard layout&lt;/a&gt;—a long overdue addition. Related to that, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/manual/en/html_node/X-Window.html&quot;&gt;Xorg configuration&lt;/a&gt; has been streamlined with the new &lt;code&gt;xorg-configuration&lt;/code&gt; record.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We introduced &lt;code&gt;guix pack -R&lt;/code&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/blog/2018/tarballs-the-ultimate-container-image-format/&quot;&gt;a while back&lt;/a&gt;: it creates tarballs containing &lt;em&gt;relocatable&lt;/em&gt; application bundles that rely on user namespaces. Starting from 1.0, &lt;code&gt;guix pack -RR&lt;/code&gt; (like “reliably relocatable”?) generates relocatable binaries that fall back to &lt;a href=&quot;https://proot-me.github.io/&quot;&gt;PRoot&lt;/a&gt; on systems where &lt;a href=&quot;http://man7.org/linux/man-pages/man7/user_namespaces.7.html&quot;&gt;user namespaces&lt;/a&gt; are not supported.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More than 1,100 packages were added, leading to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/packages&quot;&gt;close to 10,000 packages&lt;/a&gt;, 2,104 packages were updated, and several system services were contributed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The manual has been fully translated to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/manual/fr/html_node/&quot;&gt;French&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/manual/de/html_node/&quot;&gt;German&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/manual/es/html_node/&quot;&gt;Spanish&lt;/a&gt; translations are nearing completion, and work has begun on a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/manual/zh-cn/html_node/&quot;&gt;Simplified Chinese&lt;/a&gt; translation. You can help &lt;a href=&quot;https://translationproject.org/domain/guix-manual.html&quot;&gt;translate the manual into your language&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://translationproject.org/html/translators.html&quot;&gt;joining the Translation Project&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;That’s a long list already, but you can find more details in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://git.savannah.gnu.org/cgit/guix.git/tree/NEWS?h=version-1.0.0&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;NEWS&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One-point-oh is a major milestone, especially for those of us who’ve been on board for several years. But with the wealth of ideas we’ve been collecting, it’s definitely not the end of the road!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested in “devops” and distributed deployment, you will certainly be happy to help in that area, those interested in OS development might want to make &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/shepherd/&quot;&gt;the Shepherd&lt;/a&gt; more flexible and snappy, furthering integration with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/blog/2019/connecting-reproducible-deployment-to-a-long-term-source-code-archive/&quot;&gt;Software Heritage&lt;/a&gt; will probably be #1 on the to-do list of scientists concerned with long-term reproducibility, programming language tinkerers may want to push &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/manual/en/html_node/G_002dExpressions.html#G_002dExpressions&quot;&gt;G-expressions&lt;/a&gt; further, etc. Guix 1.0 is a tool that’s both serviceable for one’s day-to-day computer usage and a great playground for the tinkerers among us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether you want to help on design, coding, maintenance, system administration, translation, testing, artwork, web services, funding, organizing a Guix install party… &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/contribute/&quot;&gt;your contributions are welcome&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re humans—don’t hesitate to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/contact/&quot;&gt;get in touch with us&lt;/a&gt;, and enjoy Guix 1.0!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;About GNU Guix&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guix&quot;&gt;GNU Guix&lt;/a&gt; is a transactional package manager and an advanced distribution of the GNU system that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/distros/free-system-distribution-guidelines.html&quot;&gt;respects user freedom&lt;/a&gt;. Guix can be used on top of any system running the kernel Linux, or it can be used as a standalone operating system distribution for i686, x86_64, ARMv7, and AArch64 machines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to standard package management features, Guix supports transactional upgrades and roll-backs, unprivileged package management, per-user profiles, and garbage collection. When used as a standalone GNU/Linux distribution, Guix offers a declarative, stateless approach to operating system configuration management. Guix is highly customizable and hackable through &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/guile&quot;&gt;Guile&lt;/a&gt; programming interfaces and extensions to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://schemers.org&quot;&gt;Scheme&lt;/a&gt; language.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 12:20:18 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>brendyn</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/blog/2019/gnu-guix-1.0.0-released/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>ACLU: Border Agents Violate Constitution When They Search Electronic Devices</title>
<link>https://www.npr.org/2019/05/02/719337356/aclu-border-agents-violate-constitution-when-they-search-electronic-devices</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.npr.org/2019/05/02/719337356/aclu-border-agents-violate-constitution-when-they-search-electronic-devices</guid>
<description>&lt;div id=&quot;res719364526&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap image large&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;imagewrap&quot; data-crop-type=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2019/05/02/ap_17049076292456-98ef10b0a38140d3e3616319050b387595d13762-s1100-c15.jpg&quot; data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2019/05/02/ap_17049076292456-98ef10b0a38140d3e3616319050b387595d13762-s1100.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img lazyOnLoad&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;credit-caption&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-wrap&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image caption&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this 2016 photo, a man holds up his iPhone during a rally in support of data privacy outside the Apple store in San Francisco. Watchdog groups that keep tabs on digital privacy rights are concerned that U.S. Customs and Border Protection agents are searching the phones and other digital devices of international travelers at border checkpoints in U.S. airports. &lt;strong class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Eric Risberg/AP&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong class=&quot;hide-caption&quot;&gt;hide caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;strong class=&quot;toggle-caption&quot;&gt;toggle caption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Eric Risberg/AP&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;enlarge_measure&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img_wrap&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2019/05/02/ap_17049076292456-98ef10b0a38140d3e3616319050b387595d13762-s1200.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;enlarge_html&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image_data&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;In this 2016 photo, a man holds up his iPhone during a rally in support of data privacy outside the Apple store in San Francisco. Watchdog groups that keep tabs on digital privacy rights are concerned that U.S. Customs and Border Protection agents are searching the phones and other digital devices of international travelers at border checkpoints in U.S. airports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Eric Risberg/AP&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The American Civil Liberties Union says it has uncovered new evidence that federal border agents are violating the Constitution when they search travelers' electronic devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ACLU, along with the Electronic Frontier Foundation, sued the federal government in 2017, alleging that its &quot;warrantless and suspicionless searches&quot; of electronic devices at the U.S. ports of entry violated the First and Fourth amendments. Lawyers now say that, through depositions of border agents, they have learned that the scope of the warrantless searches has expanded far beyond the mere enforcement of immigration and customs laws.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Border officers have the authority to search belongings for contraband, or to determine who is admissible into the U.S., the ACLU said. But agents now &quot;claim authority to search travelers' devices for general law enforcement purposes, such as looking for potential evidence of illegal activity beyond violations of immigration and customs laws,&quot; plaintiffs wrote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;That claimed authority extends to enforcing 'hundreds' of federal laws, including tax, bankruptcy, environmental, and consumer protection laws. Defendants' asserted purposes for conducting warrantless or suspicionless device searches also include intelligence gathering or advancing pre-existing investigations.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id=&quot;ad-backstage-wrap&quot; aria-label=&quot;advertisement&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;These practices violate the Fourth Amendment's protection against unreasonable search and seizure, the ACLU wrote. They also violate the First Amendment, attorneys said, because people traveling to the U.S. might censor themselves, knowing that a border agent might look through their phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aclu.org/legal-document/alasaad-v-mcaleenan-memorandum-support-motion-summary-judgment&quot;&gt;filing&lt;/a&gt; this week in the U.S. District Court in Massachusetts, the lawyers asked the government to rule in their favor without a trial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Let's get one thing clear,&quot; the ACLU said in a statement. &quot;The government cannot use the pretext of the 'border' to make an end run around the Constitution.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The government has said its searches are necessary to protect the country. The Department of Homeland Security did not respond to an Associated Press request for comment; ICE and CBP said they would not comment on pending litigation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case was filed on behalf of 11 defendants, including a limousine driver, two journalists, and a NASA engineer. Ten of the plaintiffs are U.S. citizens, and one is a lawful permanent resident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;res719360553&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap internallink insettwocolumn inset2col&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bucket img&quot;&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;featuredStackSquareImage523313829&quot; href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/2017/04/11/523313829/more-travelers-are-being-asked-for-their-cellphones-and-passwords-entering-u-s&quot; data-metrics=&quot;{&amp;quot;category&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Story to Story&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;action&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Click Internal Link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;label&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https:\/\/www.npr.org\/2017\/04\/11\/523313829\/more-travelers-are-being-asked-for-their-cellphones-and-passwords-entering-u-s&amp;quot;}&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2017/04/10/ap_17049076306114_sq-9a9159e6b943039a73cf8bef37a1f35b92d468bf-s100-c15.jpg&quot; data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2017/04/10/ap_17049076306114_sq-9a9159e6b943039a73cf8bef37a1f35b92d468bf-s100.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img lazyOnLoad&quot; alt=&quot;More Travelers Entering U.S. Are Being Asked For Their Cellphones And Passwords&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Searches of international travelers' electronic devices have &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cbp.gov/newsroom/national-media-release/cbp-releases-updated-border-search-electronic-device-directive-and&quot;&gt;spiked&lt;/a&gt; in recent years. According to the lawsuit, border officers searched the smartphones and laptops of more than 33,000 international travelers in 2018 — an increase of almost 400% from three years earlier. Those searches, the complaint says, violate the Fourth Amendment's protections against unreasonable search and seizure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Border searches of electronic devices intrude deeply on the private lives of all travelers and raise unique concerns for the journalists, lawyers, doctors, and others who carry particularly sensitive information about their news sources, clients, and patients,&quot; the attorneys wrote. They argued that the warrantless searches &quot;turn the border into a digital dragnet.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cbp.gov/sites/default/files/assets/documents/2018-Jan/CBP-Directive-3340-049A-Border-Search-of-Electronic-Media-Compliant.pdf&quot;&gt;Customs and Border Protection policy&lt;/a&gt; implemented in 2018 permits two kinds of searches: basic and advanced. In a basic search, an officer looks through an electronic device manually. In an advanced search, the officer connects external equipment to the device in order to review and sometimes copy its contents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CBP policy allows basic searches without any suspicion of wrongdoing; advanced searches require a &quot;reasonable suspicion of activity in violation of the laws enforced or administered by CBP&quot; or a &quot;national security concern.&quot; U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement has a similar policy permitting both basic and advanced searches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a legal filing, the agencies said their searches were &quot;a crucial tool for detecting evidence relating to terrorism and other national security matters&quot; and &quot;can also reveal information about financial and commercial crimes.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But those searches go far beyond what the Constitution allows, the ACLU lawsuit argues. &quot;The government cannot use the border to circumvent the Constitution,&quot; they wrote.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 11:35:56 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>hsnewman</dc:creator>
<og:title>ACLU: Border Agents Violate Constitution When They Search Electronic Devices</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.npr.org/2019/05/02/719337356/aclu-border-agents-violate-constitution-when-they-search-electronic-devices</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>U.S. border agents improperly look for broad evidence of crimes when they search international travelers' phones and laptops without probable cause, civil rights groups argue.</og:description>
<og:image>https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2019/05/02/ap_17049076292456_wide-7c6c13dc4b0d7843466d40edbea084f72bdaca7f.jpg?s=1400</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.npr.org/2019/05/02/719337356/aclu-border-agents-violate-constitution-when-they-search-electronic-devices</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>GitHub Learning Lab</title>
<link>https://lab.github.com/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://lab.github.com/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;There are no simulations or boring tutorials here, just hands-on lessons created with by the GitHub community and taught by the friendly Learning Lab bot.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;33&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col-12 col-md-6 mb-6 mb-md-0 Container-max-400 mx-auto&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;Created with Sketch.
&lt;h3 class=&quot;f2 text-normal my-2 lh-condensed&quot;&gt;Real projects&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-gray&quot;&gt;Learn new skills while working in your own copy of a real project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col-12 col-md-6 Container-max-400 mx-auto mt-n2&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;Created with Sketch.
&lt;h3 class=&quot;f2 text-normal my-2 lh-condensed&quot;&gt;Helpful bot&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-gray&quot;&gt;Our friendly bot provides instructions and feedback throughout your journey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col-12 col-md-6 Container-max-400 mx-auto&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;Created with Sketch.
&lt;h3 class=&quot;f2 text-normal my-2 lh-condensed&quot;&gt;Real workflow&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-gray&quot;&gt;Everything happens in GitHub Issues and Pull Requests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 08:48:22 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>soheilpro</dc:creator>
<og:title>GitHub Learning Lab</og:title>
<og:description>Learn by doing, working with GitHub Learning Lab bot to complete tasks and level up one step at a time.</og:description>
<og:url>https://lab.github.com/</og:url>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:image>https://lab.github.com/public/card.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://lab.github.com/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Use mmap with care</title>
<link>https://www.sublimetext.com/blog/articles/use-mmap-with-care</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.sublimetext.com/blog/articles/use-mmap-with-care</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;When we implemented the git portion of &lt;a href=&quot;https://sublimemerge.com&quot;&gt;Sublime Merge&lt;/a&gt;, we chose to use &lt;code&gt;mmap&lt;/code&gt; for reading git object files. This turned out to be considerably more difficult than we had first thought. Using &lt;code&gt;mmap&lt;/code&gt; in desktop applications has some serious caveats, and here's why:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can follow along with &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sublimehq/mmap-example&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;the example project here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Say you were reading some binary format, data you need throughout some application. You take the easiest approach and use a simple &lt;code&gt;read&lt;/code&gt; to get the full contents of the file. You release your software and someone comes along and says: &quot;I need to parse this 3GB file, but I only have 2GB of memory. Could you make it so that you're not using so much memory?&quot;. Of course you want to help them, so you do some searching and come to the conclusion that memory mapping is the perfect solution to this problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Memory mapped files work by mapping the full file into a virtual address space and then using page faults to determine which chunks to load into physical memory. In essence it allows you to access the file as if you had read the whole thing into memory, without actually doing so. Crucially it requires only a small change to the codebase:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.sublimetext.com/screenshots/use_mmap_with_care/1.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;And with that, you've fixed the memory usage issue. You've fixed the bug, people are happy and all is well until you get another support ticket. Your program is crashing with a SIGBUS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Caveat 1: SIGBUS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SIGBUS (bus error) is a signal that happens when you try to access memory that has not been physically mapped. This is different to a SIGSEGV (segmentation fault) in that a segfault happens when an address is invalid, while a bus error means the address is valid but we failed to read/write.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As it turns out, the ticket comes from someone using a networked drive. Their network happened to disconnect while your memory mapped file was open, and since the file no longer existed the OS couldn't load it into ram for you and gave you a SIGBUS instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because the OS is loading the file on demand, you now have this wonderful issue where any arbitrary read from an address into the memory mapped file can and &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; fail at some point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily on POSIX systems we have signal handlers, and SIGBUS is a signal we can handle. All you need to do is register a signal handler for SIGBUS when the program starts and jump back to our code to handle failures there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.sublimetext.com/screenshots/use_mmap_with_care/2.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sadly our code actually has some edge cases we should consider:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Signal handlers are global, but signals themselves are per-thread. So you need to make sure you're not messing with any other threads by making all our data thread local. Let's also add some robustness by making sure we've called &lt;code&gt;setjmp&lt;/code&gt; before &lt;code&gt;longjmp&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.sublimetext.com/screenshots/use_mmap_with_care/3.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Using &lt;code&gt;setjmp&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;longjmp&lt;/code&gt;ing from a signal handler is actually unsafe. It seems to cause undefined behaviour, especially on MacOS. Instead we must use &lt;code&gt;sigsetjmp&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;siglongjmp&lt;/code&gt;. Since we're jumping out of a signal handler, we need that signal handler to not block any future signals, so we must also pass &lt;code&gt;SA_NODEFER&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;sigaction&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.sublimetext.com/screenshots/use_mmap_with_care/4.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is starting to get quite complicated, especially if you were to have multiple places where a SIGBUS could happen. Let's factor things out into functions to make the logic a little cleaner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.sublimetext.com/screenshots/use_mmap_with_care/5.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;There, now you just need to remember to always call &lt;code&gt;install_signal_handlers&lt;/code&gt; for every application, and wrap all &lt;code&gt;file&lt;/code&gt; accesses with &lt;code&gt;safe_mmap_try&lt;/code&gt;. Annoying, but manageable. So now you've covered POSIX systems, but what about Windows?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Caveat 2: Windows&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Windows doesn't have &lt;code&gt;mmap&lt;/code&gt;, but it does have &lt;code&gt;MapViewOfFile&lt;/code&gt;. Both of these implement memory mapped files, but there's one important difference: Windows keeps a lock on the file, not allowing it to be deleted. Even with the Windows flag &lt;code&gt;FILE_SHARE_DELETE&lt;/code&gt; deletion does not work. This is an issue when we expect another application to delete files from under us, such as git garbage collection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One way around this with the windows API is to essentially disable the system file cache entirely, which just makes everything absurdly slow. The way &lt;a href=&quot;https://sublimemerge.com&quot;&gt;Sublime Merge&lt;/a&gt; handles this is by releasing the memory mapped file on idle. Its not a pretty solution, but it works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Windows also does not have a SIGBUS signal, but you can trivially use structured exception handling in &lt;code&gt;safe_mmap_try&lt;/code&gt; instead:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.sublimetext.com/screenshots/use_mmap_with_care/6.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now all is well, your application functions on Windows. But then you decide that you would like some crash reporting, to make it easier to identify issues in the future. So you add &lt;a href=&quot;https://chromium.googlesource.com/breakpad/breakpad&quot;&gt;Google Breakpad&lt;/a&gt;, but unbeknownst to you you've just broken Linux and MacOS again…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Caveat 3: 3rd Parties&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem with using signal handlers is that they're global, across threads and libraries. If you have or have added a library like Breakpad that uses signals internally you're going to break your previously safe memory mapping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Breakpad registers signal handlers at initialization time on Linux, including one for SIGBUS. These signal handlers override each other, so installation order is important. There is not a nice solution to these types of situations: You can't simply set and reset the signal handler in &lt;code&gt;safe_mmap_try&lt;/code&gt; as that would break multithreaded applications. At Sublime HQ our solution was to turn an unhandled SIGBUS in our signal handler into a SIGSEGV. Not particularly elegant but it's a reasonable compromise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On MacOS things get a little more complicated. XNU, the MacOS kernel, is based on Mach, one of the earliest microkernels. Instead of signals, Mach has an asynchronous, message based exception handling mechanism. For compatibility reasons signals are also supported, with Mach exceptions taking priority. If a library such as Breakpad registers for Mach exception messages, and handles those, it will prevent signals from being fired. This is of course at odds with our signal handling. The only workaround we've found so far involves patching Breakpad to not handle SIGBUS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3rd party libraries are a problem because signals are global state accessible from everywhere. The only available solutions to this are unsatisfying workarounds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Caveat 4: 32bit Support&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Memory mapping may not use physical memory, but it does require virtual address space. On 32bit platforms your address space is ~4GB. So while your application may not use 4GB of memory, it will run out of address space if you try to memory map a too large file. This has the same result as being out of memory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sadly this doesn't have a workaround like the other issues, it is a hard limitation of how memory mapping works. You can now either rewrite the codebase to not memory map the whole file, live with crashes on 32bit systems or not support 32bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With &lt;a href=&quot;https://sublimemerge.com&quot;&gt;Sublime Merge&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sublimetext.com/blog/articles/sublime-text-3-point-2&quot;&gt;Sublime Text 3.2&lt;/a&gt; we took the &quot;no 32bit support&quot; route. &lt;a href=&quot;https://sublimemerge.com&quot;&gt;Sublime Merge&lt;/a&gt; does not have a 32bit build available and Sublime Text disables git integration on 32bit versions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;An Alternative&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mentioned before that you can rewrite your code to not use memory mapping. Instead of passing around a long lived pointer into a memory mapped file all around the codebase, you can use functions such as &lt;code&gt;pread&lt;/code&gt; to copy only the portions of the file that you require into memory. This is less elegant initially than using &lt;code&gt;mmap&lt;/code&gt;, but it avoids all the problems you're otherwise going to have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through some quick benchmarks for the way &lt;a href=&quot;https://sublimemerge.com&quot;&gt;Sublime Merge&lt;/a&gt; reads git object files, &lt;code&gt;pread&lt;/code&gt; was around ⅔ as fast as &lt;code&gt;mmap&lt;/code&gt; on linux. In hindsight it's difficult to justify using &lt;code&gt;mmap&lt;/code&gt; over &lt;code&gt;pread&lt;/code&gt;, but now the beast has been tamed and there's little reason to change any more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you think we've missed something or made a mistake, please leave us a message on the forums. We hope this helps some of you in your future endeavours. If you haven't already, check out our git client &lt;a href=&quot;https://sublimemerge.com&quot;&gt;Sublime Merge&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 07:49:16 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ingve</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.sublimetext.com/blog/articles/use-mmap-with-care</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>