<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Facebook: Let Us Be Part of the Hearing</title>
<link>https://foundation.mozilla.org/campaigns/let-us-be-part-hearing/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://foundation.mozilla.org/campaigns/let-us-be-part-hearing/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://foundation.mozilla.org/campaigns/let-us-be-part-hearing/de/&quot;&gt;Deutsch&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://foundation.mozilla.org/campaigns/let-us-be-part-hearing/fr/&quot;&gt;Français&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zuckerberg is going to the EU but answering questions behind closed doors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To the Conference of Presidents of the European Parliament we urge you to open your meeting with Mark Zuckerberg to the public. The issue of Facebook’s approach to personal data is one that impacts 2 billion people from around the world. The EU is currently leading the world when it comes to privacy, please continue to stay true to that by ensuring that people and the media can also play their roles in ensuring that Facebook continues to keep its promises about improving their approach to privacy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2018 15:17:53 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>dotcoma</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>http://foundation.mozilla.org/campaigns/let-us-be-part-hearing/</og:url>
<og:title>Let Us Be Part of the Hearing</og:title>
<og:description></og:description>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://foundation.mozilla.org/campaigns/let-us-be-part-hearing/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Getting 1Password 7 ready for the Mac App Store</title>
<link>https://blog.agilebits.com/2018/05/10/getting-1password-7-ready-for-the-mac-app-store/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.agilebits.com/2018/05/10/getting-1password-7-ready-for-the-mac-app-store/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;1Password 7 has been in beta for 6 weeks now and the feedback has been fantastic. We are getting close to the official release date and have begun final preparations, including submitting 1Password 7 to the Mac App Store. 🎉&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When 1Password 7 is released it will be available from the Mac App Store as well as our website, and will be available as both a subscription and a standalone license.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When adding 1Password 7 to the Mac App Store we needed to answer the following two questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Should it be a new app?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Should it support both subscriptions and licenses?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ultimately we decided that 1Password 7 will be a new app in the Mac App Store, and available only as a subscription. I know that many of you will be curious about this, so I wanted to share with you why we decided on this approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Mac App Store and upgrades&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Mac App Store is one of the most convenient ways to purchase apps for your Mac. You can purchase with confidence, pay quickly in your local currency, and updates happen automatically. Overall it is a pretty sweet experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The App Store, for all it does well, struggles mightily when a paid upgrade is introduced because it does not allow developers to charge for an update to an existing app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When considering a paid upgrade, developers have two choices: they can re-use their existing app or submit a new one. Both have their pros and cons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Re-using an existing app&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developers are very creative and one approach that some have used to introduce paid upgrades is to re-use their existing app and offer an In-App Purchase to make the upgraded features available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We actually went ahead and gave this an honest, if short-lived, try. Very quickly it became apparent that this would lead to a complete mess of spaghetti code as we tried to encapsulate new features. Worse yet, any significant UI updates (including the many we have in 1Password 7) were next to impossible to add as we’d have to keep the old UI around as well. Ultimately this proved infeasible and all my devs threatened to mutiny. 🙂&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Submitting a new app&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A new app avoids these issues, allowing us to keep our code base clean and my developers happy. It comes at a price though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Introducing a new app means that everyone who wants the upgraded version needs to go back to the Mac App Store, find this new version, and download it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve done this before with 1Password 4 for iOS, and have the scars to prove it. Thousands of customers were confused when trying to update because their 1Password 3 app claimed to be up-to-date. To this day we have customers on 1Password 3 who do not realize a new version is out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be quite honest, one of the main reasons we haven’t had a paid upgrade on the Mac side for all these years is that we were dreading the pain this would cause us and our customers. However the time has come to bite the bullet and have a paid upgrade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To avoid this pain in the future, this will be the last time we will be submitting a new app to the App Store. To make that possible, 1Password 7 will only be available as a subscription in the Mac App Store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Mac App Store for subscriptions only&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1Password subscriptions are eligible for free upgrades, meaning we can keep the same app in the App Store and seamlessly upgrade everyone to the new version as it comes out. This is just one of many the reasons &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.agilebits.com/2017/07/13/why-we-love-1password-memberships/&quot;&gt;why we love memberships&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we were to sell standalone licenses in the Mac App Store we would have these same problems all over again when 1Password 8 is released. Ultimately this is why we decided not to sell licenses through the Mac App Store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While still tough, this decision was easier to make as people looking for licenses will be able to download 1Password 7 directly from our website. I know this isn’t ideal for those who love the Mac App Store and prefer to purchase standalone licenses and I apologize for that. But overall I believe this was the correct decision to make.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll be out at WWDC in a few weeks and would be more than happy to talk further if you have questions or are facing similar decisions with your own apps.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2018 13:53:28 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>okket</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Getting 1Password 7 ready for the Mac App Store - AgileBits Blog</og:title>
<og:description>1Password 7 will be a new app in the Mac App Store, and available only as a subscription. I know that many of you will be curious about this, so I wanted to share with you why we decided on this approach.</og:description>
<og:url>https://blog.agilebits.com/2018/05/10/getting-1password-7-ready-for-the-mac-app-store/</og:url>
<og:image>https://blog.agilebits.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/DevBits-Header.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.agilebits.com/2018/05/10/getting-1password-7-ready-for-the-mac-app-store/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>How I targeted the Reddit CEO with Facebook ads to get an interview at Reddit</title>
<link>http://twicsy-blog.tumblr.com/post/174063770074/how-i-target-the-reddit-ceo-with-facebook-ads-to</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://twicsy-blog.tumblr.com/post/174063770074/how-i-target-the-reddit-ceo-with-facebook-ads-to</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;A bit over 2 years ago I was coming off a failed startup and out looking for new opportunities. I am not a fan of looking for jobs, my style is to target interesting companies and convince them to let me join them in their quest. So I decided to target Reddit because it looked like they were making some new moves. And, because, it’s Reddit!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hatched the hare-brained scheme to write a blog article that might catch the attention of a particular person, get them to read it somehow, and then say “hey kid, I like the cut of your jib, do you want to come help us conquer the world?”. Sure, that person is actually younger than me, but you get the point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to work at Reddit. Well, not just work at Reddit, but develop something very cool at Reddit that I think can make a huge impact on the business. So &lt;a href=&quot;http://twicsy-blog.tumblr.com/post/135712326189/hey-reddit-lets-make-some-recommendations&quot;&gt;I wrote about it&lt;/a&gt;. I knew that the CEO of Reddit was a technical founder, so I put quite a deal of effort into that blog entry to try to impress him. Now, how to get him to see it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first thought was email. I can just email him! But that’s boring. What about getting my article to the top of Hacker News? I bet the CEO (and founder) of Reddit still frequents Hacker News. It is an amazing community, built off an early version of Reddit, and run by Y-Combinator (which incubated Reddit way back when). The problem is, I didn’t think my article would be interesting enough to a large crowd to make it to the top of HN.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I remembered a trick a friend of mine taught me a while back. That friend (who shall remain nameless, unless he wants me to name him) was running a startup and was using a very interesting technique to increase his chances of closing deals. Who wants to buy from a company they have never heard of? Not many people. His strategy was to target prospects (as directly as possible) with Facebook ads about his product so that when he called or met with them, they would already know the name. They probably didn’t know why they knew, but they had seen the name before, and that meant a great deal when meeting or speaking for the first time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I decided I would target the CEO of Reddit with Facebook ads. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But how? I didn’t have a big budget so I needed to be clever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It turns out the Reddit CEO had a public Facebook profile, so I could go there to see details about him. Where he lived. What he was interested in. I took that info to the Facebook platform to help narrow down the campaign. But I didn’t want everyone to click on it, just one person. So I custom tailored the ad to directly target the one person I wanted to read it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Steve: Reddit needs recommendations”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ad reached 197 people. 4 People clicked on it. One of them was the CEO of Reddit. I spent a total of $10.62.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steve Huffman, CEO of Reddit, saw my ad, clicked on it, read (probably skimmed) my article, and liked it well enough to send a note to Reddit HR to contact me about a position.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mission accomplished.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chris Seline&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;P.S. I am out again looking for new opportunities. Drop me a line at my first name at twicsy.com if you like the cut of my jib!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 19 May 2018 23:51:46 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>dumbfounder</dc:creator>
<og:title>How I targeted the Reddit CEO with Facebook ads to get an interview at Reddit</og:title>
<og:url>http://twicsy-blog.tumblr.com/post/174063770074/how-i-targeted-the-reddit-ceo-with-facebook-ads-to</og:url>
<og:description>A bit over 2 years ago I was coming off a failed startup and out looking for new opportunities. I am not a fan of looking for jobs, my style is to target interesting companies and convince them to let...</og:description>
<og:type>tumblr-feed:entry</og:type>
<og:image>http://assets.tumblr.com/images/og/fb_landscape_share.png</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://twicsy-blog.tumblr.com/post/174063770074/how-i-targeted-the-reddit-ceo-with-facebook-ads-to</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Libui: a portable GUI library for C</title>
<link>https://github.com/andlabs/libui</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/andlabs/libui</guid>
<description>&lt;h3&gt;README.md&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;markdown-body entry-content&quot; itemprop=&quot;text&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This README is being written.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://travis-ci.org/andlabs/libui&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/ceaec17edbcdf67d6982929d16f1858734957d1a/68747470733a2f2f7472617669732d63692e6f72672f616e646c6162732f6c696275692e7376673f6272616e63683d6d6173746572&quot; alt=&quot;Build Status, Linux and macOS&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://travis-ci.org/andlabs/libui.svg?branch=master&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ci.appveyor.com/project/andlabs/libui&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/e4d39b38ccb6e6766bd94728a6cf2101ab9a5018/68747470733a2f2f63692e6170707665796f722e636f6d2f6170692f70726f6a656374732f7374617475732f6f75796b37386335326d6d69736133313f7376673d74727565&quot; alt=&quot;Build Status, Windows&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://ci.appveyor.com/api/projects/status/ouyk78c52mmisa31?svg=true&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Announcements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;16 May 2018&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Thanks to @parro-it and @msink, libui now has better CI, including AppVeyor for Windows CI, and automated creation of binary releases when I make a tagged release.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;13 May 2018&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Added new functions to work with uiDateTimePickers: &lt;code&gt;uiDateTimePickerTime()&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;uiDateTimePickerSetTime()&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;uiDateTimePickerOnChanged()&lt;/code&gt;. These operate on standard &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;time.h&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;struct tm&lt;/code&gt;s. Thanks @cody271!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2 May 2018&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;On Windows, you no longer need to carry around a &lt;code&gt;libui.res&lt;/code&gt; file with static builds. You do need to link in the appropriate manifest file, such as the one in the &lt;code&gt;windows/&lt;/code&gt; folder (I still need to figure out exactly what is needed apart from the Common Controls v6 dependency, or at least to create a complete-ish template), or at least include it alongside your executables. This also means you should no longer see random cmake errors when building the static libraries.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;18 April 2018&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Introduced a new &lt;code&gt;uiTimer()&lt;/code&gt; function for running code on a timer on the main thread. (Thanks to @cody271.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;18 March 2018&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Introduced an all-new formatted text API that allows you to process formatted text in ways that the old API wouldn't allow. You can read on the whole API &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/andlabs/libui/blob/8944a3fc5528445b9027b1294b6c86bae03eeb89/ui_attrstr.h&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. There is also a new examples for it: &lt;code&gt;drawtext&lt;/code&gt;, which shows the whole API at a glance. It doesn't yet support measuring or manipulating text, nor does it currently support functions that would be necessary for things like text editors; all of this will be added back later.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;libui also now uses my &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/andlabs/utf&quot;&gt;utf library&lt;/a&gt; for UTF-8 and UTF-16 processing, to allow consistent behavior across platforms. This usage is not completely propagated throughout libui, but the Windows port uses it in most places now, and eventually this will become what libui will use throughout.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Also introduced a formal set of contribution guidelines, see &lt;code&gt;CONTRIBUTING.md&lt;/code&gt; for details. They are still WIP.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;17 February 2018&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The longstanding Enter+Escape crashes on Windows have finally been fixed (thanks to @lxn).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alpha 3.5 is now here.&lt;/strong&gt; This is a quickie release primiarly intended to deploy the above fix to package ui itself. &lt;strong&gt;It is a partial binary release; sorry!&lt;/strong&gt; More new things will come in the next release, which will also introduce semver (so it will be called v0.4.0 instead).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alpha 3.5 also includes a new control gallery example. The screenshots below have not been updated yet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;27 November 2016&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Decided to split the table stuff into its own branch. It will be developed independently of everything else, along with a few other features.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2 November 2016&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Added two new functions to replace the deleted &lt;code&gt;uiWindowPosition()&lt;/code&gt; and friends: &lt;code&gt;uiAreaBeginUserWindowMove()&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;uiAreaBeginUserWindowResize()&lt;/code&gt;. When used in a &lt;code&gt;uiAreaHandler.Mouse()&lt;/code&gt; event handler, these let you initiate a user-driven mouse move or mouse resize of the window at any point in a uiArea.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;31 October 2016&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;@krakjoe noticed that I accidentally used thread-unsafe code in uiQueueMain() on Unix. Fixed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;24 October 2016&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;uiWindowSetContentSize()&lt;/code&gt; on Unix no longer needs to call up the GTK+ main loop. As a result, bugs related to strange behavior using that function (and the now-deleted &lt;code&gt;uiWindowSetPosition()&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;uiWindowCenter()&lt;/code&gt;) should go away. I'll need to go through the bugs to verify as much, though.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;22 October 2016&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Due to being unable to guarantee they will work (especially as we move toward capability-driven window systems like Wayland), or being unable to work without hacking that breaks other things, the following functions have been removed: &lt;code&gt;uiWindowPosition()&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;uiWindowSetPosition()&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;uiWindowCenter()&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;uiWindowOnPositionChanged()&lt;/code&gt;. Centering may come back at some point in the future, albeit in a possibly restricted form. A function to initiate a user move when a part of a uiArea is clicked will be provided soon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;21 October 2016&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;uiDrawTextWeightUltraBold&lt;/code&gt; is now spelled correctly. Thanks to @krakjoe.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;18 June 2016&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;17 June 2016&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CMake 3.1.0 is now required.&lt;/strong&gt; This is due to CMake's rapid development pace in the past few years adding things libui needs to build on as many systems as possible. If your OS is supported by libui but its repositories ship with an older version of CMake, you will need to find an updated one somewhere.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please help &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/andlabs/libui/issues/152&quot;&gt;plan out a better menu API&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5 June 2016&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alpha 3.1 is here.&lt;/strong&gt; This was a much-needed update to Alpha 3 that changes a few things:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The build system is now cmake.&lt;/strong&gt; cmake 2.8.11 or higher is needed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Static linking is now fully possible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MinGW linking is back, but static only.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Old announcements can be found in the ANNOUNCE.md file.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Updates&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note that today's entry (Eastern Time) may be updated later today.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;13 May 2018&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Release builds on Windows with MSVC should be fixed now; thanks @l0calh05t, @slahn, @mischnic, and @zentner-kyle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12 May 2018&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;GTK+ and OS X now have a cleaner build process for static libraries which no longer has intermediate files and differing configurations. As a result, certain issues should no longer be present. New naming rules for internal symbols of libui have also started being drafted; runtime symbols and edge cases still need to be handled (and the rules applied to Windows) before this can become a regular thing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;18 April 2018&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Migrated all code in the &lt;code&gt;common/&lt;/code&gt; directory to use &lt;code&gt;uipriv&lt;/code&gt; prefixes for everything that isn't &lt;code&gt;static&lt;/code&gt;. This is the first step toward fixing static library oddities within libui, allowing libui to truly be safely used as either a static library or a shared library.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;17 June 2016&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;uiMainSteps()&lt;/code&gt; no longer takes any arguments and no longer needs to invoke a function to do the work. You still need to call it, but once you do, it will return immediately and you can then get right to your main loop.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CMake 3.1.0 is now required.&lt;/strong&gt; This is due to CMake's rapid development pace in the past few years adding things libui needs to build on as many systems as possible. If your OS is supported by libui but its repositories ship with an older version of CMake, you will need to find an updated one somewhere.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added &lt;code&gt;uiNewVerticalSeparator()&lt;/code&gt; to complement &lt;code&gt;uiNewHorizontalSeparator()&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;16 June 2016&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Added &lt;code&gt;uiWindowContentSize()&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;uiWindowSetContentSize()&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;uiWindowOnContentSizeChanged()&lt;/code&gt; methods for manipulating uiWindow content sizes. Note the use of &quot;content size&quot;; the size you work with does NOT include window decorations (titlebars, menus, etc.).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added &lt;code&gt;uiWindowFullscreen()&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;uiWindowSetFullscreen()&lt;/code&gt; to allow making fullscreen uiWindows, taking advantage of OS facilities for fullscreen and without changing the screen resolution (!).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added &lt;code&gt;uiWindowBorderless()&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;uiWindowSetBorderless()&lt;/code&gt; for allowing borderless uiWindows.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added &lt;code&gt;uiMainSteps()&lt;/code&gt;. You call this instead of &lt;code&gt;uiMain()&lt;/code&gt; if you want to run the main loop yourself. You pass in a function that will be called; within that function, you call &lt;code&gt;uiMainStep()&lt;/code&gt; repeatedly until it returns 0, doing whatever you need to do in the meantime. (This was needed because just having &lt;code&gt;uiMainStep()&lt;/code&gt; by itself only worked on some systems.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added &lt;code&gt;uiProgressBarValue()&lt;/code&gt; and allowed passing -1 to &lt;code&gt;uiProgressBarSetValue()&lt;/code&gt; to make an indeterminate progress bar. Thanks to @emersion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;15 June 2016&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Added &lt;code&gt;uiFormDelete()&lt;/code&gt;; thanks to @emersion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added &lt;code&gt;uiWindowPosition()&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;uiWindowSetPosition()&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;uiWindowCenter()&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;uiWindowOnPositionChanged()&lt;/code&gt;, methods for manipulating uiWindow position.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;14 June 2016&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;uiDarwinControl now has a &lt;code&gt;ChildVisibilityChanged()&lt;/code&gt; method and a corresponding &lt;code&gt;NotifyVisibilityChanged()&lt;/code&gt; function that is called by the default show/hide handlers. This is used to make visibility changes work on OS X; uiBox, uiForm, and uiGrid all respect these now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The same has been done on the Windows side as well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hiding and showing controls and padding calculations are now correct on Windows at long last.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hiding a control in a uiForm now hides its label on all platforms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;13 June 2016&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;intmax_t&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;uintmax_t&lt;/code&gt; are no longer used for libui API functions; now we use &lt;code&gt;int&lt;/code&gt;. This should make things much easier for bindings. &lt;code&gt;int&lt;/code&gt; should be at least 32 bits wide; this should be sufficient for all but the most extreme cases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12 June 2016&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Added &lt;code&gt;uiGrid&lt;/code&gt;, a new container control that arranges controls in rows and columns, with stretchy (&quot;expanding&quot;) rows, stretchy (&quot;expanding&quot;) columns, cells that span rows and columns, and cells whose content is aligned in either direction rather than just filling. It's quite powerful, is it? =P&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8 June 2016&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Added &lt;code&gt;uiForm&lt;/code&gt;, a new container control that arranges controls vertically, with properly aligned labels on each. Have fun!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6 June 2016&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Added &lt;code&gt;uiRadioButtonsSelected()&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;uiRadioButtonsSetSelected()&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;uiRadioButtonsOnSelected()&lt;/code&gt; to control selection of a radio button and catch an event when such a thing happens.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5 June 2016&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Added &lt;code&gt;uiNewPasswordEntry()&lt;/code&gt;, which creates a new &lt;code&gt;uiEntry&lt;/code&gt; suitable for entering passwords.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added &lt;code&gt;uiNewSearchEntry()&lt;/code&gt;, which creates a new &lt;code&gt;uiEntry&lt;/code&gt; suitable for searching. On some systems, the &lt;code&gt;OnChanged()&lt;/code&gt; event will be slightly delayed and/or combined, to produce a more natural feel when searching.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Old updates can be found in the Changelog.md file.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Runtime Requirements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Windows: Windows Vista SP2 with Platform Update or newer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unix: GTK+ 3.10 or newer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mac OS X: OS X 10.8 or newer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Build Requirements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;All platforms:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;CMake 3.1.0 or newer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Windows: either
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Microsoft Visual Studio 2013 or newer (2013 is needed for &lt;code&gt;va_copy()&lt;/code&gt;) — you can build either a static or a shared library&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MinGW-w64 (other flavors of MinGW may not work) — &lt;strong&gt;you can only build a static library&lt;/strong&gt;; shared library support will be re-added once the following features come in:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/aa375197%28v=vs.85%29.aspx&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Isolation awareness&lt;/a&gt;, which is how you get themed controls from a DLL without needing a manifest&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unix: nothing else specific&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mac OS X: nothing else specific, so long as you can build Cocoa programs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Building&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Out-of-tree builds typical of cmake are preferred:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;$ # you must be in the top-level libui directory, otherwise this won't work
$ mkdir build
$ cd build
$ cmake ..
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pass &lt;code&gt;-DBUILD_SHARED_LIBS=OFF&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;cmake&lt;/code&gt; to build a static library. The standard cmake build configurations are provided; if none is specified, &lt;code&gt;Debug&lt;/code&gt; is used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you use a makefile generator with cmake, then&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;$ make
$ make tester         # for the test program
$ make examples       # for examples
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and pass &lt;code&gt;VERBOSE=1&lt;/code&gt; to see build commands. Build targets will be in the &lt;code&gt;build/out&lt;/code&gt; folder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Project file generators should work, but are untested by me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Windows, I use the &lt;code&gt;Unix Makefiles&lt;/code&gt; generator and GNU make (built using the &lt;code&gt;build_w32.bat&lt;/code&gt; script included in the source and run in the Visual Studio command line). In this state, if MinGW-w64 (either 32-bit or 64-bit) is not in your &lt;code&gt;%PATH%&lt;/code&gt;, cmake will use MSVC by default; otherwise, cmake will use with whatever MinGW-w64 is in your path. &lt;code&gt;set PATH=%PATH%;c:\msys2\mingw(32/64)\bin&lt;/code&gt; should be enough to temporarily change to a MinGW-w64 build for the current command line session only if you installed MinGW-w64 through &lt;a href=&quot;https://msys2.github.io/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;MSYS2&lt;/a&gt;; no need to change global environment variables constantly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Arch Linux&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can be built from AUR: &lt;a href=&quot;https://aur.archlinux.org/packages/libui-git/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://aur.archlinux.org/packages/libui-git/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Documentation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Needs to be written. Consult &lt;code&gt;ui.h&lt;/code&gt; and the examples for details for now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Language Bindings&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;libui was originally written as part of my &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/andlabs/ui&quot;&gt;package ui for Go&lt;/a&gt;. Now that libui is separate, package ui has become a binding to libui. As such, package ui is the only official binding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other people have made bindings to other languages:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;Language&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Bindings&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;C++&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/billyquith/libui-cpp&quot;&gt;libui-cpp&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/aoloe/cpp-libui-qtlike&quot;&gt;cpp-libui-qtlike&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;C# / .NET Framework&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/NattyNarwhal/LibUI.Binding&quot;&gt;LibUI.Binding&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;C# / .NET Core&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/noliar/DevZH.UI&quot;&gt;DevZH.UI&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/benpye/sharpui/&quot;&gt;SharpUI&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tom-corwin/LibUISharp&quot;&gt;LibUISharp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;CHICKEN Scheme&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/wasamasa/libui&quot;&gt;wasamasa/libui&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Crystal&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Fusion/libui.cr&quot;&gt;libui.cr&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Qwerp-Derp/hedron&quot;&gt;hedron&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;D&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Extrawurst/DerelictLibui&quot;&gt;DerelictLibui (flat API)&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mogud/libuid&quot;&gt;libuid (object-oriented)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Euphoria&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ghaberek/libui-euphoria&quot;&gt;libui-euphoria&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Harbour&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/RJopek/HBUI&quot;&gt;HBUI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Haskell&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/beijaflor-io/haskell-libui&quot;&gt;haskell-libui&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;JavaScript&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mavenave/libui.js&quot;&gt;libui.js (merged into libui-node?)&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kusti8/proton-native&quot;&gt;proton-native&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Julia&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/joa-quim/Libui.jl&quot;&gt;Libui.jl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Lua&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/zevv/libuilua&quot;&gt;libuilua&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mdombroski/libui-lua&quot;&gt;libui-lua&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://tset.de/lui/index.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;lui&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Nim&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/nim-lang/ui&quot;&gt;ui&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Node.js&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/parro-it/libui-node&quot;&gt;libui-node&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;PHP&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/krakjoe/ui&quot;&gt;ui&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Python&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/joaoventura/pylibui&quot;&gt;pylibui&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Yardanico/pylibui-cffi&quot;&gt;pylibui-cffi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Ruby&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jamescook/libui-ruby&quot;&gt;libui-ruby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Rust&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pcwalton/libui-rs&quot;&gt;libui-rs&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/arcturu/libui-rs&quot;&gt;arcturu/libui-rs&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/LeoTindall/libui-rs&quot;&gt;LeoTindall/libui-rs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Scala&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/lolgab/scalaui&quot;&gt;scalaui&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Swift&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sclukey/libui-swift&quot;&gt;libui-swift&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Frequently Asked Questions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Why does my program start in the background on OS X if I run from the command line?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OS X normally does not start program executables directly; instead, it uses &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/reference/coreservices/1658613-launch_services?language=objc&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Launch Services&lt;/a&gt; to coordinate the launching of the program between the various parts of the system and the loading of info from an .app bundle. One of these coordination tasks is responsible for bringing a newly launched app into the foreground. This is called &quot;activation&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you run a binary directly from the Terminal, however, you are running it directly, not through Launch Services. Therefore, the program starts in the background, because no one told it to activate! Now, it turns out &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/reference/appkit/nsapplication/1428468-activateignoringotherapps&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;there is an API&lt;/a&gt; that we can use to force our app to be activated. But if we use it, then we'd be trampling over Launch Services, which already knows whether it should activate or not. Therefore, libui does not step over Launch Services, at the cost of requiring an extra user step if running directly from the command line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See also &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/andlabs/libui/pull/20#issuecomment-211381971&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/25318524/what-exactly-should-i-pass-to-nsapp-activateignoringotherapps-to-get-my-appl&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See &lt;code&gt;CONTRIBUTING.md&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Screenshots&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From examples/controlgallery:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/andlabs/libui/blob/master/examples/controlgallery/windows.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/andlabs/libui/raw/master/examples/controlgallery/windows.png&quot; alt=&quot;Windows&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/andlabs/libui/blob/master/examples/controlgallery/unix.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/andlabs/libui/raw/master/examples/controlgallery/unix.png&quot; alt=&quot;Unix&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/andlabs/libui/blob/master/examples/controlgallery/darwin.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/andlabs/libui/raw/master/examples/controlgallery/darwin.png&quot; alt=&quot;OS X&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 19 May 2018 23:38:34 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>axiomdata316</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars2.githubusercontent.com/u/718242?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>andlabs/libui</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/andlabs/libui</og:url>
<og:description>libui - Simple and portable (but not inflexible) GUI library in C that uses the native GUI technologies of each platform it supports.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/andlabs/libui</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>A Wikipedia editor&amp;#039;s long-running campaign</title>
<link>https://wikipedia.fivefilters.org/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://wikipedia.fivefilters.org/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;A Wikipedia editor called &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/User:Philip_Cross&quot;&gt;Philip Cross&lt;/a&gt; (Andrew Philip Cross and later &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/wikipedianhidin&quot;&gt;&quot;Julian&quot;&lt;/a&gt; on Twitter) has a long record of editing the entries of many anti-war figures on the site to include mostly critical commentary while removing positive information contributed by others. At time of writing he is number 308 in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.li/8xKkr&quot;&gt;list of Wikipedians by number of edits&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wikipedia entries very often appear first in search results, and so for many will be the first and only port of call when researching something. People unaware of the political nature of the editing that goes on on the site, in this case supposedly by a single, dedicated editor, are being seriously misled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an &lt;a href=&quot;https://xtools.wmflabs.org/ec/en.wikipedia.org/Philip%20Cross&quot;&gt;active editor for almost 15 years&lt;/a&gt;, Cross is very familiar with some of the more arcane Wikipedia rules and guidelines (along with their obscure acronyms) and uses them to justify removing information he dislikes in favour of his own inclusions. Often in a very subtle manner and over a long period of time. Anyone familiar with the work of the people he targets will recognise how one-sided and distorted those entries become.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cross is, however, much nicer to the entries of people he likes. Former hedge-fund manager and Iraq war supporter Oliver Kamm, and right-wing author Melanie Phillips, both columnists for The Times, are two examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Twitter, where Cross is more provocative and antagonistic, he doesn't hide the fact that he has long-running feuds with many of his targets on Wikipedia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Wikipedianhidin/status/995052717784608769&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://wikipedia.fivefilters.org/tweet-cross-feud.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After &lt;a href=&quot;https://xtools.wmflabs.org/articleinfo/en.wikipedia.org/George_Galloway&quot;&gt;George Galloway&lt;/a&gt;, Media Lens is his second most edited article on the site. Cross is responsible for &lt;a href=&quot;https://xtools.wmflabs.org/articleinfo/en.wikipedia.org/Media_Lens&quot;&gt;almost 80%&lt;/a&gt; of all content on the Media Lens entry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Wikipedianhidin/status/995976016664375299&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://wikipedia.fivefilters.org/tweet-cross-goons.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cross calls his Wikipedia targets 'goons'. The list includes anti-war politician &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/georgegalloway&quot;&gt;George Galloway&lt;/a&gt; former MP &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mwgbanks&quot;&gt;Matthew Gordon-Banks&lt;/a&gt;, historian, human rights activist and former UK ambassador &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/CraigMurrayOrg&quot;&gt;Craig Murray&lt;/a&gt;, investigative journalist &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/NafeezAhmed&quot;&gt;Dr Nafeez Ahmed&lt;/a&gt;, Edinburgh University professor &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Tim_Hayward_&quot;&gt;Tim Hayward&lt;/a&gt;, Sheffield University professor &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/PiersRobinson1&quot;&gt;Piers Robinson&lt;/a&gt;, and media analysis group &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/medialens&quot;&gt;Media Lens&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And he's happy to openly taunt his Wikipedia targets on Twitter:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Wikipedianhidin/status/995947773957689344&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://wikipedia.fivefilters.org/tweet-cross-corbyn.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Wikipedianhidin/status/996049462127747072&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://wikipedia.fivefilters.org/tweet-cross-punk.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How this behaviour doesn't fall foul of Wikipedia's rules, we don't know. Especially as his efforts, in addition to misleading the public, have serious consequences for the people targeted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/NeilClark66/status/997041719614025729&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://wikipedia.fivefilters.org/tweet-clark-stalker.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Tim_Hayward_/status/994300706449510400&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://wikipedia.fivefilters.org/tweet-tim-work.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cross' activities are now finally getting some attention thanks to more of his targets speaking out on Twitter. The story has now also been picked up by RT and the Sunday Herald.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ron McKay writes in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.heraldscotland.com/opinion/16222196.The_Dirty_Diary__Tilda_s_Polanski_shame__wiki_propaganda_wars_and_Lenny_s_brush_with_the_law/&quot;&gt;Sunday Herald&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;25&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within the cyber cloisters of academe Wikiwars are raging, with one Edinburgh professor in particular catching the flak. Tim Hayward is one of the group of academics (his colleague Paul McKeigue is another) who set up the Working Group on Syria, Propaganda and Media – or if you prefer the Times description, Apologists for Assad. The group’s questioning over whether it could be definitively concluded that the Syrian regime was responsible for the Ghouta chemical attack last month (they have also queried the Novichok attack of the Skripals) is apparently what provoked their pillorying in the Thunderer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within hours Hayward’s Wikipedia had been strafed and apparently favourable references removed. Former ambassador Craig Murray is another who claims to have come under “obsessive attack” with his page subject to 107 detrimental changes over three days. The journalist Neil Clark has a similar story about amendments and alterations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don’t have to be a conspiracy theorist to see that there are common threads here. All of those are – (select your own description, anti-war, assiduous, useful idiots?) – prominent campaigners on social media and in the mainstream media vigorously questioning our foreign policy. All have also clashed with Oliver Kamm, a former hedge-fund manager and now Times leader writer and columnist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rt.com/uk/426679-cross-galloway-clark-wikipedia-troll/&quot;&gt;RT piece&lt;/a&gt; opens with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;23&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A mystery online figure called Philip Cross is targeting anti-war and non-mainstream UK figures by prolifically editing their Wikipedia pages – to the point that George Galloway is offering a reward to see him unmasked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Active on Wikipedia since 2004, Philip Cross has been editing wiki entries for nearly 15 years. Recently, trouble has been brewing online, with Cross accused of paying special attention to a cluster of Wikipedia accounts, editing them or deleting chunks of information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pundits like Galloway, academic Tim Hayward, opposition leader Jeremy Corbyn, and ex-UK ambassador to Uzbekistan Craig Murray have fallen in the crosshairs of the editorial mystery man (or perhaps woman) who goes by the name of Philip Cross – and many of them are growing frustrated with the lack of action from Wikipedia to prevent malicious editing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See also this Sputnik &lt;a href=&quot;https://sputniknews.com/analysis/201805161064505256-cross-galloway-wikipedia-obsession/&quot;&gt;interview with George Galloway&lt;/a&gt;. Galloway's Wikipedia entry is Cross' most edited page on the site with &lt;a href=&quot;https://xtools.wmflabs.org/articleinfo/en.wikipedia.org/George_Galloway&quot;&gt;1,796 edits&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far none of this has resulted in any action from Wikipedia, only dismissals from Jimmy Wales, Wikipedia's founder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Wikipedia diffs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Considering Cross' quite open hostility towards the people whose pages he edits on Wikipedia, it should already be apparent that he should not be editing those pages at all. Those demanding diffs (exact changes made in an edit) are really missing the bigger picture here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But let's take a look at just a few of Cross' recent edits. His edit history goes back many years, so this will only be a tiny sample. We encourage those targeted by Cross to send links to edits made to their pages so we can try to highlight them here. Each of the images here shows, on the left, a section of a Wikipedia entry before Cross' edit, and to its right, what Cross changes it to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cross doesn't like Sheffield University professor &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheffield.ac.uk/journalism/staff/piers-robinson&quot;&gt;Piers Robinson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, he edits his Wikipedia entry and removes the fact that Robinson has written for the The Guardian...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Piers_Robinson&amp;amp;diff=prev&amp;amp;oldid=841092325&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://wikipedia.fivefilters.org/diff-robinson.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...and throws in an unsourced claim about journalist Eva Bartlett (someone else he doesn't like) and then tries to make a tenuous, defamatory connection between Robinson and another one of his targets (journalist Vanessa Beeley).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Piers_Robinson&amp;amp;diff=prev&amp;amp;oldid=841092325&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://wikipedia.fivefilters.org/diff-robinson2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cross likes Iraq war supporter, former hedge-fund manager and Times columnist &lt;a href=&quot;http://medialens.org/index.php/alerts/alert-archive/2009/585-dancing-on-a-mass-grave-oliver-kamm-of-the-times-smears-media-lens.html&quot;&gt;Oliver Kamm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So he removes completely the fact that there's an upcoming &lt;a href=&quot;https://fundrazr.com/41BlC1&quot;&gt;court case brought against Kamm&lt;/a&gt; by journalist &lt;a href=&quot;https://neilclark66.blogspot.com&quot;&gt;Neil Clark&lt;/a&gt; for harassment and defamation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Oliver_Kamm&amp;amp;diff=prev&amp;amp;oldid=840385512&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://wikipedia.fivefilters.org/kamm-harassment.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KiXxp89Lzks&quot;&gt;Oliver Kamm&lt;/a&gt; is notable when examining Cross' edits, because, although Kamm himself is not a very significant figure, he appears to be one of Cross' favourite people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Craig Murray &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.craigmurray.org.uk/archives/2016/03/the-astonishing-case-of-the-doppelganger/&quot;&gt;observed&lt;/a&gt; what happened to his Wikipedia entry when he criticised Kamm:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;10.759825327511&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On 7 February I published &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.craigmurray.org.uk/archives/2016/02/lies-correctness-and-oliver-kamm/&quot;&gt;an article&lt;/a&gt; calling out Kamm for publishing a blatant and deliberate lie about me. The very next day, 8 February, my Wikipedia page came under obsessive attack from somebody called Philip Cross who made an astonishing 107 changes over the course of the next three days. Many were very minor, but the overall effect was undoubtedly derogatory. He even removed my photo on the extraordinary grounds that it was “not typical” of me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Media Lens also make an important point on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/medialens/status/997541688271831040&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;6.3185840707965&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The word 'Kamm' appears in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Wikipedia&quot;&gt;@&lt;strong&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; entry for Media Lens &lt;em&gt;twelve&lt;/em&gt; times. 'Media Lens' appears in Oliver Kamm's entry....zero times. Just one reason why &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jimmy_wales&quot;&gt;@&lt;strong&gt;jimmy_wales&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;'s focus on 'diffs' as evidence of bad faith is misplaced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cross likes right-wing Times columnist &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Melanie_Phillips&quot;&gt;Melanie Phillips&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So why should anyone have to learn about Phillips' climate change denial? Cross removed the section wholesale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Melanie_Phillips&amp;amp;diff=prev&amp;amp;oldid=839953938&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://wikipedia.fivefilters.org/diff-philips.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cross doesn't like media analysis group &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.medialens.org&quot;&gt;Media Lens&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So he removes something nice former BBC editor Peter Barron wrote about them...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?diff=708727940&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://wikipedia.fivefilters.org/diff-medialens.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...and changes it to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peter Barron, the former editor of the BBC's ''Newsnight'' commented in November 2005 that although Cromwell and Edwards &quot;are unfailingly polite&quot;, he had received &quot;hundreds of e-mails from sometimes less-than-polite hommes engages - they're almost always men - most of whom don't appear to have watched the programme&quot; as a result of complaints instigated by Media Lens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then, as with many of his other targets, he adds in vacuous complaints from people who prefer to insult and smear rather than engage with substance:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?diff=701175743&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://wikipedia.fivefilters.org/diff-medialens2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite Cross' hostility toward Media Lens and a self-confessed &quot;long standing feud&quot;, he is, remarkably, responsible for the majority (77.8%) of the content on the Media Lens Wikipedia entry:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://wikipedia.fivefilters.org/medialens-editcoverage.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://wikipedia.fivefilters.org/medialens-editcoverage-small.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click the image to expand it (made with &lt;a href=&quot;https://f-squared.org/whovisual/&quot;&gt;WhoColor&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Occasionally, it seems, Cross does get caught out. His recent effort to write the entry for Edinburgh University professor Tim Hayward resulted in another editor &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Tim_Hayward_%28academic%29&amp;amp;type=revision&amp;amp;diff=840499616&amp;amp;oldid=840495581&quot;&gt;reverting the change&lt;/a&gt; with the note:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;6.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;this is all completely overheated; if it's all he is known for, we're headed for BLP1E [&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Biographies_of_living_persons#Subjects_notable_only_for_one_event&quot;&gt;Biographies of living persons#Subjects notable only for one event&lt;/a&gt;]; if it is to be included, it will be worded responsibly and added via consensus&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cross attempted again to get his edit in, and was &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Tim_Hayward_%28academic%29&amp;amp;type=revision&amp;amp;diff=840501478&amp;amp;oldid=840500568&quot;&gt;rebuked again&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;you're not even &lt;em&gt;trying&lt;/em&gt; via a talk-page discussion&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Wikipedia usage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cross is listed number 308 in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.li/8xKkr&quot;&gt;list of Wikipedians by number of edits&lt;/a&gt;. (We're linking to an archived copy here because Cross &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Wikipedia:List_of_Wikipedians_by_number_of_edits/Anonymous&amp;amp;diff=prev&amp;amp;oldid=841543847&quot;&gt;requested&lt;/a&gt; his name be removed from the list after his edits started to get more attention on Twitter.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He is very active on Wikipedia, as his time card shows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://xtools.wmflabs.org/ec-timecard/en.wikipedia.org/Philip%20Cross&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://wikipedia.fivefilters.org/timecard.png&quot; alt=&quot;timecard&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As should be clear by now, this is not a project that Cross takes lightly. He devotes considerable time to it: many hours every day and with the same intensity on weekends as on weekdays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We pulled in the dates from his &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Special:Contributions/Philip_Cross&quot;&gt;user contributions&lt;/a&gt; page and found that Cross had not had a single day off from editing the site in almost 5 years! (Consecutive edit dates between 29 August 2013 and 14 May 2018.) You'd have more free time to spend on leisure activities pursuing a regular full-time job than Cross has editing Wikipedia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Craig Murray writes in his piece &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.craigmurray.org.uk/archives/2018/05/the-philip-cross-affair/&quot;&gt;The Philip Cross Affair&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;19&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The operation runs like clockwork, seven days a week, every waking hour, without significant variation. If Philip Cross genuinely is an individual, there is no denying he is morbidly obsessed. I am no psychiatrist, but to my entirely inexpert eyes this looks like the behaviour of a deranged psychotic with no regular social activities outside the home, no job (or an incredibly tolerant boss), living his life through a screen. I run what is arguably the most widely read single person political blog in the UK, and I do not spend nearly as much time on the internet as “Philip Cross”. My “timecard” would show where I watch football on Saturdays, go drinking on Fridays, go to the supermarket and for a walk or out with the family on Sundays, and generally relax much more and read books in the evenings. Cross does not have the patterns of activity of a normal and properly rounded human being.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Wikipedia sees no problem with all this&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wikipedia user &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/User:KalHolmann&quot;&gt;KalHolmann&lt;/a&gt; tried to &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Wikipedia:Conflict_of_interest/Noticeboard&amp;amp;oldid=841903202#User:Philip_Cross&quot;&gt;alert&lt;/a&gt; Wikipedia admins to some of these problems, but his request to prevent Cross from editing was quickly &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Wikipedia:Conflict_of_interest/Noticeboard&amp;amp;oldid=841903488#User:Philip_Cross&quot;&gt;shut down&lt;/a&gt; with the following response:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zero evidence of COI [Conflict of Interest]. Galloway has picked a fight with Cross, not the other way around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This despite the fact that Cross has himself has &lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.is/4RmUI&quot;&gt;admitted&lt;/a&gt; a &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/_jrvansant/status/997587605519728640&quot;&gt;&quot;big conflict of interest&quot;&lt;/a&gt; (although that hasn't stopped him from continuing to edit these pages).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neil Clark points out how &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/NeilClark66/status/997596295299846144&quot;&gt;absurd&lt;/a&gt; the Wikipedia response is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;6.6022727272727&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‘Philip Cross’ has edited &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/georgegalloway&quot;&gt;@&lt;strong&gt;georgegalloway&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ‘s wikipedia page over 1800 times. George finally responds and offers a £1000 reward for Cross’s identification and it is he who is accused of ‘picking a fight’. This takes victim-blaming to a whole new level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Don't trust what you read on Wikipedia!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please spread the word to anyone who's unaware of the extent to which Wikipedia can be manipulated in this way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:?subject=Time%20to%20ditch%20Wikipedia?&amp;amp;body=Read%20about%20the%20Wikipedia%20campaign%20against%20anti-war%20voices%0D%0A%0D%0Ahttps://wikipedia.fivefilters.org&quot;&gt;Email a friend&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/sharer/sharer.php?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwikipedia.fivefilters.org&quot;&gt;Share on Facebook&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home?status=%23DitchWikipedia+https%3A%2F%2Fwikipedia.fivefilters.org&quot;&gt;Tweet about it&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if you'd like to see some action taken by Wikipedia, please tweet &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jimmy_wales&quot;&gt;Jimmy Wales&lt;/a&gt; and let him know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;More information&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Contact&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you'd like to get in touch about anything here, please email &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:fivefilters@fivefilters.org&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;url&quot;&gt;fivefilters@fivefilters.org&lt;/a&gt; or tweet us &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/fivefilters/&quot;&gt;@fivefilters&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 19 May 2018 19:19:22 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>yasp</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Time to ditch Wikipedia?</og:title>
<og:description>A look at a Wikipedia editor's long-running campaign to discredit anti-war campaigners and journalists</og:description>
<og:url>https://wikipedia.fivefilters.org/</og:url>
<og:image>https://wikipedia.fivefilters.org/share.png</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://wikipedia.fivefilters.org/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>How to disappear from the internet</title>
<link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2018/may/19/exposed-how-to-disappear-from-the-internet</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.theguardian.com/world/2018/may/19/exposed-how-to-disappear-from-the-internet</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;drop-cap&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;drop-cap__inner&quot;&gt;E&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;arly one morning last year, before the birds were up, Tio Bucard, his wife and children skittered down the path from their home in a tiny French village towards a black SUV, its engine running. As Bucard drove to the local airport, he checked his rear-view mirror every few moments to see that he was still being followed by &lt;a href=&quot;https://frankahearn.com/&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Frank Ahearn&lt;/a&gt;, a 54-year-old American with a peppery beard and wraparound sunglasses. Bucard (not his real name) had met Ahearn for the first time only the day before, in the lobby of a Monaco hotel close to Bucard’s office. Now he had entrusted his family’s safety to this former drug addict from the Bronx. Bucard pulled into the airport’s long-term car park. Then he and the family transferred into Ahearn’s hired SUV. As they pulled on to the motorway, Ahearn joked whether, while the family was in hiding, he could look after Bucard’s £5,000 watch, a Bentley Flying B No 3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The watch was a reminder of more plentiful times. Bucard, who raised capital for a private equity firm, had recently found himself on the wrong end of a bad deal. Problems gathered and the firm began to default on payments. One of the slighted investors had, as Bucard puts it, “a shady past” and angry phone calls soon blackened into threats of physical violence. Fearing for his and his family’s safety, Bucard typed the phrase “how to disappear” into &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/google&quot; data-link-name=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; data-component=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt;. Halfway down the first page of results, he saw Ahearn’s name. A former New York skip tracer – a private investigator who finds people who have “skipped” town – turned professional “disappearer”, Ahearn offers a range of freelance services, everything from helping to restore your privacy on the internet to driving your family across Europe and into a new life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“My idea was to go away for three to four months,” Bucard tells me. “Just until I could raise the funds to pay back my investors.” Not wanting to cause alarm, Bucard told his children they were taking an extended vacation. The day before they fled, Ahearn rented an Airbnb in a far-flung city in his name. When the family arrived at the safe house, Ahearn bought new mobile phones and laptops, then schooled the family on the rules of their new life: do use untraceable text-messaging services; don’t use public email servers; do pay in cash; don’t use &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/facebook&quot; data-link-name=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; data-component=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;. After a few days, Ahearn left the Bucards in their temporary accommodation and returned to his home in Madrid, where he lives with his girlfriend. In his wallet, he carried Bucard’s credit card.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When he landed in Spain, Ahearn tried to imagine what a man of Bucard’s wealth might indulge in while on holiday. Then he began a riot of spending: fine clothes, meals out, a king’s ransom of trinkets. “I had a blast with his plastic,” he says. “And that, my friend, is how to leave a trail of super-cool disinformation.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;***&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Money, violence, indiscretion: the motivation for any person who wants to disappear, either physically or digitally, usually wends back to one of these. Whatever the reason and whatever the scale of the ambition – from starting a new life in a foreign country to scrubbing one’s name and address from the phonebook – it has never been harder to vanish. In a world where almost any action outside your garden shed leaves some kind of digital footprint, there is no clear path back to the realm of the unknown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In recent months, the scale of the erosion of our anonymity has become dauntingly clear. In humming, ice-cooled server farms, the monoliths of Silicon Valley gather fat troves of personal information. This much we have known for years – as early as 2010, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/SB10001424052702304772804575558484075236968&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;an investigation found that Facebook apps were routinely collecting information&lt;/a&gt; for internet-tracking companies without our consent – even from private accounts. But the recent &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/news/series/cambridge-analytica-files&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Cambridge Analytica scandal&lt;/a&gt; brought new clarity. Those who downloaded their personal data files found that Facebook and its associated apps had been tracking phone calls, reading messages and plundering phonebooks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This gleeful, grasping attitude to our data is in the social network’s DNA. This year it was revealed that in 2004, while Facebook was still a university campus website on which male students could rate the attractiveness of female students, its founder, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/mark-zuckerberg&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Mark Zuckerberg&lt;/a&gt;, sent an instant message to a friend in which he boasted that he had collected more than 4,000 emails, pictures and addresses of people who had signed up to the service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“What?” Zuckerberg’s friend exclaimed. “How’d you manage that one?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“People just submitted it,” Zuckerberg wrote. “I don’t know why. They ‘trust me’.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Dumb fucks,” he added, after a pause.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;element element-pullquote element--supporting&quot;&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;pullquote-paragraph&quot;&gt;Google likely knows your age, gender, hobbies, career, relationship status, every YouTube video you’ve watched&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;Facebook is not the only harvester of personal information. If Google is the engine that drives the internet, personal information is the oil that makes it purr. Via its Maps app, it knows where you’ve been, how you got there (foot, car, bus, train), how long you stayed and whether or not it was your first visit. The company stores your search history across every device on which you’re logged in, while algorithms reportedly scour your emails for signs that you might be pregnant, engaged or unwell. Google Lens, announced earlier this month, is a visual search engine that provides information about the things you’re looking at through your phone’s camera. Google likely knows your age, gender, hobbies, career, interests, relationship status, every YouTube video you’ve watched, every image you’ve searched for, whether or not you’re depressed and, possibly, even why you’re depressed before you do – and it’s far from the only omniscient god in the digital pantheon. What began as a hopeful, democratic mission to make the internet free for all in the 1990s has, when fed through the late capitalist mincer, resulted in a digital economy that runs on microtransactions of identity. This information, if held by a government, would inspire widespread civil liberty marches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For most of us, the quality and convenience of what we receive in exchange for our secrets is enough that we willingly surrender. But now an increasing number of people are more closely counting the cost – to the point of trying to reclaim our right to be unknown. It’s become a challenge: the woman fleeing an abusive relationship, the elderly victim of identity theft, the stalked celebrity, the school leaver who’s sabotaged their job search with old, embarrassing YouTube videos, already knows just how difficult that can be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;***&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Ahearn finished rehab, aged 17, he had quit pills but was left newly directionless. He took a stopgap job in a New York shoe store. Then, when it closed down, he responded to an advertisement for a private investigator. The job was glamour-less, but Ahearn found it intoxicating nonetheless. He was hired to pose as a stockroom worker for high-end New York stores and catch co-workers stealing the merchandise. He caught 15 employees stealing from one department store, and later busted a 30-man criminal ring at an electronics and furniture warehouse. “Manipulation,” he says. “It’s the first thing I was ever really good at.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details data-snippet-id=&quot;29dfa583-e128-49bf-91c6-9eab9d36d2df&quot; data-snippet-type=&quot;guide&quot; class=&quot;atom atom--snippet atom--snippet--guide&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;atom--snippet__label&quot;&gt;Quick guide&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;atom--snippet__headline&quot;&gt;How to keep a low online profile&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;button class=&quot;atom__button atom__button--large atom__button--rounded atom--snippet__handle&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;is-on&quot;&gt; Show&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;is-off&quot;&gt; Hide&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/button&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__body&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__item&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__heading&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1 Google yourself&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carry out a self-styled “before” audit to see what’s out there. Search for yourself with all name variations, email addresses and residential addresses. You could be shocked by what you find.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__item&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__heading&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2 Delete online accounts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt; All active accounts must be deleted – not deactivated – if you want to use the internet untraceably. Facebook, Amazon, eBay, Netflix, Tinder: they all have to go. It can be difficult to remember every site you have signed up for, so look in your email inbox for newsletters. Unsubscribe and ask to be removed from their data list; the new GDPR update on 25 May 2018 means that sites are legally obliged to do this on request.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__item&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__heading&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3 Contact data brokers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s highly likely that personal data such as home address, email and even your date of birth is being publicly shared online by so-called data broker websites, such as 192.com. Ask for this information to be removed directly from the site, and they should comply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__item&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__heading&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4 Ask to be forgotten&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’ve posted on web forums, you can ask the webmasters to remove your posting. If they prove unresponsive, and data brokers or social media companies fail to remove your information on request, then exercise the “right to be forgotten” by a direct request to Google (search for legal removal request).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__item&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__heading&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5 Create a smoke screen&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, once removed does not mean for ever removed on the internet. You should actively audit yourself every six months and some of the steps may have to be repeated. And if you can’t quite make all the necessary sacrifices, consider setting up a false email address with inaccurate data, amending personal details such as age, sex, name and location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Simon Parkin&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;em&gt;Source: Tony McChrystal, Reputation Defender&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;footer class=&quot;atom--snippet__footer&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__feedback&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Was this helpful?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;atom--snippet__ack&quot; hidden=&quot;&quot; aria-role=&quot;alert&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot;&gt;Thank you for your feedback.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/footer&gt;&lt;/details&gt;&lt;p&gt;After a while, the private detective agency allowed Ahearn to work in the office. There he sat next to a skip tracer. “Skip-tracing is the art of finding people,” he explains. “There are two types of skip tracer: passive ones, who use databases and directories to find people; and aggressive ones, who carry out social engineering to find their prey.” Ahearn would listen as his colleague extracted information about someone by calling utility companies and posing as the target in order to gain access to their phone records and bank details until, finally, he zoned in on a likely hideout address. Ahearn convinced his boss to give him a go. “I was like wildfire,” he recalls. “A natural.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;u-responsive-ratio&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;gu-image&quot; itemprop=&quot;contentUrl&quot; alt=&quot;Bin full of embarrassing search terms&quot; src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/7d73a031cddebaac2ad07975637d0efe2ff3a605/10_522_4663_2798/master/4663.jpg?w=300&amp;amp;q=55&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;usm=12&amp;amp;fit=max&amp;amp;s=e497dec7c9d99b8d29a1643ff3998ef7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

‘You can’t delete information. It’s a case of manipulating what is already out there.’ Photograph: Stephen Lenthall/The Guardian. Set design by Hattie Newman
&lt;p&gt;In 1984, Ahearn left the detective agency and set up as a freelance skip tracer. For a while, business boomed. He would occasionally take short breaks (“Sometimes being so good at something so devious plays on the head”), but then crisis dawned when the laws in America changed, making many of the skip tracers’ techniques illegal. “Life became more difficult,” he recalls. Ahearn moved to Europe, where the laws were less stringent, and then, in the late 1990s, the pendulum swung back. The omnipresence of the mobile phone made it far easier to track individuals, and the creeping ubiquity of social media ushered in a new golden era for the investigator. “I can find you through your mother’s Facebook, a blog you wrote three years ago, an old LinkedIn account,” Ahearn says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2001, he placed an advertisement on a website that provided advice about offshore living. When the website’s owner pointed out that Ahearn’s work finding people might concern its users, who, in many cases, prized anonymity, Ahearn suggested that he write a blogpost on how to disappear instead. “It was a really cheesy article, but it just blew up,” Ahearn recalls. “People from all over the world started contacting me.” Once he had weeded out those individuals looking for an aider and abetter (“If you’re facing law enforcement, I cannot help you; I also stay away from sexual issues”), Ahearn took on his first client: a woman who wanted to escape from her violent partner. “She didn’t want a new identity, just to move away and be sure that the husband couldn’t find her,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the past 15 years, the techniques Ahearn uses to ghost a client have grown in scope and sophistication. But unlike reputation management companies, which typically try to drive harmful or revealing information down search engine results, he favours the use of misinformation – and not just via misdirecting credit card transactions in a foreign city. “You can’t delete information,” he says. “It’s not going away. It’s a case of manipulating what is already out there.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ahearn explains that he might start by taking over your Facebook account, and “creating information” about Sydney, Australia. “I’ll befriend people in Sydney, then create new, fake Facebook accounts who become your friends in Australia.” He then starts up public conversations between these accounts. “You create a fake digital friend and get them to post an update about how they had dinner with you and another fake Facebook friend last night. It’s about offering coherent titbits of information. Deleting stuff is just useless. It’s already [been] there. Perhaps the person looking for you copied the information. So it becomes a game of total misdirection: you have to keep the predator busy.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;***&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If Ahearn is the special forces of the vanishment industry, brought in for the most extreme jobs, a sparse, open-plan office on the outskirts of Liverpool is home to the foot soldiers of this burgeoning industry. Here, at &lt;a href=&quot;https://uk.reputationdefender.com&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Reputation Defender&lt;/a&gt;, a team of 30 or so young men and women scour the internet for personal information – phone numbers, dates of birth, addresses, electoral records – that their clients want removed from the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Managing director Tony McChrystal began working in online privacy and reputation management before there was a name for the industry. In 2008, when he joined the company, then known as Reputation 24/7, as one of its first employees, it had just five clients. “We were living hand to mouth, you know, never sure whether we were going to be able to open the doors the following month,” he says. Today, the company is one of the largest in its field; McChrystal claims that the UK office receives 70 inquiries a day, mostly from individuals who want to become unknown on the internet. To date, the company has served more than a million clients worldwide, and last month it was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.prweek.com/article/1461328/stagwell-acquires-reputationdefender&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;bought by the Washington-based Stagwell Group&lt;/a&gt; for an undisclosed sum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the early years, McChrystal’s clients were typically celebrities, footballers and CEOs: people who wanted specific pieces of professionally damaging information about them – an affair, a failed business deal – pushed down the search engine rankings. In recent years, however, he says that the company mainly works with the kind of “regular” people who might pay for their credit file report every month, and who want a similar reputation or privacy report. For around £600 a year, the company will give you a list of what personal or sensitive information is publicly available. “A lot of the time, they’re scared of identity theft, fraud or even – if their current address is out there – scared of their own personal safety,” McChrystal says. It is surprisingly easy for a criminal to use social media to plan a burglary. “One of our clients’ daughter was on holiday in France recently at the family villa, and she posted geo-tagged pictures on Instagram of the villa alongside pictures of her and her friends wearing expensive jewellery and watches,” McChrystal explains. Within 24 hours of posting, there was a home invasion at the villa and half a million dollars’ worth of jewellery was stolen. “After that, we had to go in and talk about how to manage their privacy settings on their Instagram and Facebook.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tom Powell, who has worked at the company for eight years, says it’s often not any one single piece of information that can endanger an individual, but a concatenation of snippets. “Let’s say I went on holiday tomorrow,” he says. “A burglar gets wind of my trip via a Facebook post in which I mention how many days I’m away for. They then go to 192.com to find my home address. They then take that information to Google Maps, to [use streetview and] check whether I have an alarm. They have days to drive by the house and see if the alarm is flashing, and to carry out a burglary. All this information can be used in concert for malicious intent.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like Ahearn, McChrystal and his team screen the motivations of potential clients. “We probably get two paedophiles call up every day,” he admits. This kind of individual, McChrystal says, will typically claim they are the victim of mistaken identity: someone who shares their name has been accused of something awful. “That kind of thing actually doesn’t happen very often, so we tell them we will have to carry out a police check, and that’s when the conversation breaks down.” Team members refer to a “Who we serve” document, drawn up by the company’s lawyers, which forbids working with criminals who have been convicted of “anything above a misdemeanour”, as well as fraudsters and those who have been accused of sexual misconduct. “It’s not even up for debate. If you were found guilty of physical abuse, that’s relevant information to me. It shouldn’t be forgotten, you know?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google agrees. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2014/may/13/right-to-be-forgotten-eu-court-google-search-results&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;In 2014, the European court of justice ruled&lt;/a&gt; that “irrelevant” and outdated data should be erased on request. In the past four years, the company has received more than 600,000 requests (many of which were submitted by the team at Reputation Defender on behalf of its clients) to delist nearly 2.4m &lt;a href=&quot;https://drive.google.com/file/d/1H4MKNwf5MgeztG7OnJRnl3ym3gIT3HUK/view&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;results from the search engine&lt;/a&gt;. In many cases, Google has successfully argued that the information is in the public interest and that the petitioner does not have the right to be forgotten.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the past two years, however, McChrystal, who deleted his own Facebook account some time ago, has seen a marked increase in approaches from individuals who are not in danger or want a piece of damaging information covered up, but who simply want to reclaim their anonymity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;element element-pullquote element--supporting&quot;&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;pullquote-paragraph&quot;&gt;A new kind of client has become sufficiently unnerved by recent data breaches to spend hundreds on restoring anonymity&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;Emma Jones approached the team last year after one of her closest friends was the victim of identity theft. When Jones Googled herself, she found her name and address posted to various directory sites. “I wasn’t comfortable with my data being on the internet and there being nothing I could do about it,” she says. “I’ve got a young family. I felt exposed.” McChrystal’s team put together a dossier showing all the information on her and her family that was available online, alongside a proposal for how it might be removed or, in the case of social media sites, made private. Jones, who works in marketing, represents a new kind of client: one without a specific privacy problem who has become sufficiently unnerved by recent data breaches that she is willing to spend hundreds of pounds hiring professionals to restore her anonymity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like many people, she once used Facebook as a way of keeping a record of family life. “I’d upload photos of my children every day. I didn’t care whether or not my friends found them interesting. Now I rarely post pictures of my children – maybe the backs of their heads, but that’s it. It should be their choice, not mine. If my daughter comes to me when she is older and asks me why I put all those photos of her on the internet, I have no comeback.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In recent weeks, a grassroots movement has formed &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2018/mar/31/youve-decided-to-delete-facebook-but-what-will-you-replace-it-with&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;around the slogan Delete Facebook&lt;/a&gt; (Zuckerberg claims it has been a failure). For &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2016/jan/10/video-game-makers-meg-jayanth-80-days&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Meg Jayanth&lt;/a&gt;, a writer for video games, the Cambridge Analytica scandal pushed her willingly into Facebook oblivion. “I’d been considering deleting Facebook for at least a year, but my data anxieties were outweighed by convenience,” she told me. “Facebook was the way I stayed in touch with friends and family, and I was reluctant to leave it behind. The Cambridge Analytica news tipped the balance for me, not because it was unexpected, but because it forced me to stop rationalising away my use of the service, and act. I was sick of feeling apprehensive for using a service I didn’t even want to use any more.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;u-responsive-ratio&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;gu-image&quot; itemprop=&quot;contentUrl&quot; alt=&quot;Keyboard going through shredder&quot; src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/3837d62da2936518102dd4059baff20236f6bcf3/297_925_3361_4201/master/3361.jpg?w=300&amp;amp;q=55&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;usm=12&amp;amp;fit=max&amp;amp;s=21750e693b6fbab399347c94f2cc2cb9&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

‘People see the digital realm as being this separate thing. But it’s all the same thing.’ Photograph: Stephen Lenthall/The Guardian. Set design by Hattie Newman
&lt;p&gt;The process of deleting one’s Facebook account is deliberately arcane. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en-gb.facebook.com/help/359046244166395/&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;The social network encourages you to “deactivate” your account, rather than “delete” it&lt;/a&gt;, to leave an open door if you later regret the decision. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en-gb.facebook.com/help/359046244166395/&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Permanent deletion&lt;/a&gt; requires a request be made to the company. If you log in within 14 days of the process being under way (easy to do accidentally if you have the app on your phone or linked accounts that require you to log in via Facebook), the company will automatically cancel your original request.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Jayanth, who holds an Indian passport, the recent news that the US state department &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2018/mar/31/us-visa-social-media-tourism&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;is asking visa applicants to declare their social media accounts&lt;/a&gt; on their forms was a further incentive. “The idea that customs officials might look through your social media, and could potentially make decisions based on whether or not you support the current government is dangerous. That could have a chilling effect on public debate.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;***&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tio Bucard’s experience last year was enough to force a more thorough evaluation of his family’s privacy and safety. They never returned to their house in the French village.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This is something that happens to many of my clients,” Ahearn says. “Disappearing is a trigger that wakes a person up and makes one think carefully about what is next.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ahearn founded a few offshore companies for Bucard, helping him buy a new house, cars and other essentials. He set the family up with a communications protocol, so they could keep in touch with family and business associates. Bucard and his wife decided to take the children out of the French education system and home school them. They took out private medical insurance to remove their names from the health system. To maintain a life of anonymity is an ongoing act of obsession, a symptom of which is often paranoia. Bucard has kept Ahearn on retainer; whenever a new client comes his way, Ahearn runs checks on the person, to make sure they are who they say they are, and not connected in some way to his previous life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;element element-rich-link element--thumbnail element-rich-link--not-upgraded&quot; data-component=&quot;rich-link&quot; data-link-name=&quot;rich-link-1 | 1&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;Complete invisibility is an impossible goal for anyone outside a witness protection programme (“The creme de la creme,” as Ahearn puts it. “If you have that, you have everything”), even for those who have never signed up for a social media or Google account. In Britain, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/electoral-register/opt-out-of-the-open-register&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;unless you opt out when registering to vote&lt;/a&gt;, your data is collected and made available to anyone who wants to buy a copy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“People see the digital realm as being this separate thing, something close to unreal,” Ahearn says. “But it’s all the same thing. Would you put a picture of your child on a billboard next to a highway alongside your family name? Of course not. But people do it online all the time. And it’s not a problem. Until it is.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Some names have been changed&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;bullet&quot;&gt;•&lt;/span&gt; Commenting on this piece? If you would like your comment to be considered for inclusion on Weekend magazine’s letters page in print, please email &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;weekend@theguardian.com&lt;/a&gt;, including your name and address (not for publication).&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 19 May 2018 15:37:26 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>kawera</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://www.theguardian.com/world/2018/may/19/exposed-how-to-disappear-from-the-internet</og:url>
<og:description>Worried about what’s out there about you? You’re not alone. But is it even possible to become a digital ghost?</og:description>
<og:image>https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/54c14350da8d726c795bcd8d4ed933775707153f/0_1969_3983_2390/master/3983.jpg?w=1200&amp;h=630&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;fit=crop&amp;crop=faces%2Centropy&amp;bm=normal&amp;ba=bottom%2Cleft&amp;blend64=aHR0cHM6Ly91cGxvYWRzLmd1aW0uY28udWsvMjAxOC8wMS8zMS9mYWNlYm9va19kZWZhdWx0LnBuZw&amp;s=a115517e4c07065b48688adebd9a9de2</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>'I felt exposed online': how to disappear from the internet</og:title>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2018/may/19/exposed-how-to-disappear-from-the-internet</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>How Judea Pearl Became One of AI&amp;#039;s Sharpest Critics</title>
<link>https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2018/05/machine-learning-is-stuck-on-asking-why/560675/?single_page=true</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2018/05/machine-learning-is-stuck-on-asking-why/560675/?single_page=true</guid>
<description>&lt;section id=&quot;article-section-1&quot;&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Artificial intelligence owes a lot of its smarts to Judea Pearl. In the 1980s he led efforts that allowed machines to reason probabilistically. Now he’s one of the field’s sharpest critics. In his latest book, &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.basicbooks.com/titles/judea-pearl/the-book-of-why/9780465097609/&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'0',r'560675'&quot;&gt;The Book of Why: The New Science of Cause and Effect&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; he argues that artificial intelligence has been handicapped by an incomplete understanding of what intelligence really is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;callout&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r' ',d,r'specquanta',r'0',r' '&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/projects/quanta/&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;inherit&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Quanta&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn.theatlantic.com/assets/media/img/specialreports/bug/2018/01/09/Quanta_Bug.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Articles republished from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.quantamagazine.org/&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'callout',r'0',r'560675'&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Quanta Magazine&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/projects/quanta/&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;inherit&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Three decades ago, a prime challenge in artificial-intelligence research was to program machines to associate a potential cause to a set of observable conditions. Pearl figured out how to do that using a scheme called Bayesian networks. Bayesian networks made it practical for machines to say that, given a patient who returned from Africa with a fever and body aches, the most likely explanation was malaria. In 2011 &lt;a href=&quot;https://amturing.acm.org/award_winners/pearl_2658896.cfm&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'1',r'560675'&quot;&gt;Pearl won the Turing Award&lt;/a&gt;, computer science’s highest honor, in large part for this work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;But as Pearl sees it, the field of AI got mired in probabilistic associations. These days, headlines tout the latest breakthroughs in machine learning and neural networks. We read about computers that can &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.quantamagazine.org/artificial-intelligence-learns-to-learn-entirely-on-its-own-20171018/&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r'',d,r'intext',r'2',r'560675'&quot;&gt;master ancient games&lt;/a&gt; and drive cars. Pearl is underwhelmed. As he sees it, the state of the art in artificial intelligence today is merely a souped-up version of what machines could already do a generation ago: find hidden regularities in a large set of data. “All the impressive achievements of deep learning amount to just curve fitting,” he said recently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section id=&quot;article-section-2&quot;&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;In his new book, Pearl, now 81, elaborates a vision for how truly intelligent machines would think. The key, he argues, is to replace reasoning by association with causal reasoning. Instead of the mere ability to correlate fever and malaria, machines need the capacity to reason that malaria causes fever. Once this kind of causal framework is in place, it becomes possible for machines to ask counterfactual questions—to inquire how the causal relationships would change given some kind of intervention—which Pearl views as the cornerstone of scientific thought. Pearl also proposes a formal language in which to make this kind of thinking possible—a 21st-century version of the Bayesian framework that allowed machines to think probabilistically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Pearl expects that causal reasoning could provide machines with human-level intelligence. They’d be able to communicate with humans more effectively and even, he explains, achieve status as moral entities with a capacity for free will—and for evil. &lt;em&gt;Quanta Magazine&lt;/em&gt; sat down with Pearl at a recent conference in San Diego and later held a follow-up interview with him by phone. An edited and condensed version of those conversations follows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kevin Hartnett:&lt;/strong&gt; Why is your new book called “&lt;em&gt;The Book of Why&lt;/em&gt;”?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Judea Pearl:&lt;/strong&gt; It means to be a summary of the work I’ve been doing the past 25 years about cause and effect, what it means in one’s life, its applications, and how we go about coming up with answers to questions that are inherently causal. Oddly, those questions have been abandoned by science. So I’m here to make up for the neglect of science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section id=&quot;article-section-3&quot;&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hartnett:&lt;/strong&gt; That’s a dramatic thing to say, that science has abandoned cause and effect. Isn’t that exactly what all of science is about?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pearl:&lt;/strong&gt; Of course, but you cannot see this noble aspiration in scientific equations. The language of algebra is symmetric: If &lt;em&gt;x&lt;/em&gt; tells us about &lt;em&gt;y&lt;/em&gt;, then &lt;em&gt;y&lt;/em&gt; tells us about &lt;em&gt;x&lt;/em&gt;. I’m talking about deterministic relationships. There’s no way to write in mathematics a simple fact—for example, that the upcoming storm causes the barometer to go down, and not the other way around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Mathematics has not developed the asymmetric language required to capture our understanding that if &lt;em&gt;x&lt;/em&gt; causes &lt;em&gt;y&lt;/em&gt; that does not mean that &lt;em&gt;y&lt;/em&gt; causes &lt;em&gt;x&lt;/em&gt;. It sounds like a terrible thing to say against science, I know. If I were to say it to my mother, she’d slap me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;But science is more forgiving: Seeing that we lack a calculus for asymmetrical relations, science encourages us to create one. And this is where mathematics comes in. It turned out to be a great thrill for me to see that a simple calculus of causation solves problems that the greatest statisticians of our time deemed to be ill defined or unsolvable. And all this with the ease and fun of finding a proof in high-school geometry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hartnett:&lt;/strong&gt; You made your name in AI a few decades ago by teaching machines how to reason probabilistically. Explain what was going on in AI at the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pearl:&lt;/strong&gt; The problems that emerged in the early 1980s were of a predictive or diagnostic nature. A doctor looks at a bunch of symptoms from a patient and wants to come up with the probability that the patient has malaria or some other disease. We wanted automatic systems, expert systems, to be able to replace the professional—whether a doctor, or an explorer for minerals, or some other kind of paid expert. So at that point, I came up with the idea of doing it probabilistically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section id=&quot;article-section-4&quot;&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Unfortunately, standard probability calculations required exponential space and exponential time. I came up with a scheme called Bayesian networks that required polynomial time and was also quite transparent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hartnett:&lt;/strong&gt; Yet in your new book you describe yourself as an apostate in the AI community today. In what sense?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pearl:&lt;/strong&gt; In the sense that as soon as we developed tools that enabled machines to reason with uncertainty, I left the arena to pursue a more challenging task: reasoning with cause and effect. Many of my AI colleagues are still occupied with uncertainty. There are circles of research that continue to work on diagnosis without worrying about the causal aspects of the problem. All they want is to predict well and to diagnose well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;I can give you an example. All the machine-learning work that we see today is conducted in diagnostic mode—say, labeling objects as “cat” or “tiger.” They don’t care about intervention; they just want to recognize an object and to predict how it’s going to evolve in time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;I felt like an apostate when I developed powerful tools for prediction and diagnosis knowing already that this is merely the tip of human intelligence. If we want machines to reason about interventions (“What if we ban cigarettes?”) and introspection (“What if I had finished high school?”), we must invoke causal models. Associations are not enough—and this is a mathematical fact, not opinion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section id=&quot;article-section-5&quot;&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hartnett:&lt;/strong&gt; People are excited about the possibilities for AI. You’re not?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pearl:&lt;/strong&gt; As much as I look into what’s being done with deep learning, I see they’re all stuck there on the level of associations. Curve fitting. That sounds like sacrilege, to say that all the impressive achievements of deep learning amount to just fitting a curve to data. From the point of view of the mathematical hierarchy, no matter how skillfully you manipulate the data and what you read into the data when you manipulate it, it’s still a curve-fitting exercise, albeit complex and nontrivial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hartnett:&lt;/strong&gt; The way you talk about curve fitting, it sounds like you’re not very impressed with machine learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pearl:&lt;/strong&gt; No, I’m very impressed, because we did not expect that so many problems could be solved by pure curve fitting. It turns out they can. But I’m asking about the future—what next? Can you have a robot scientist that would plan an experiment and find new answers to pending scientific questions? That’s the next step. We also want to conduct some communication with a machine that is meaningful, and meaningful means matching our intuition. If you deprive the robot of your intuition about cause and effect, you’re never going to communicate meaningfully. Robots could not say “I should have done better,” as you and I do. And we thus lose an important channel of communication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hartnett:&lt;/strong&gt; What are the prospects for having machines that share our intuition about cause and effect?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section id=&quot;article-section-6&quot;&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pearl:&lt;/strong&gt; We have to equip machines with a model of the environment. If a machine does not have a model of reality, you cannot expect the machine to behave intelligently in that reality. The first step, one that will take place in maybe 10 years, is that conceptual models of reality will be programmed by humans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;The next step will be that machines will postulate such models on their own and will verify and refine them based on empirical evidence. That is what happened to science; we started with a geocentric model, with circles and epicycles, and ended up with a heliocentric model with its ellipses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Robots, too, will communicate with each other and will translate this hypothetical world, this wild world, of metaphorical models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hartnett:&lt;/strong&gt; When you share these ideas with people working in AI today, how do they react?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pearl:&lt;/strong&gt; AI is currently split. First, there are those who are intoxicated by the success of machine learning and deep learning and neural nets. They don’t understand what I’m talking about. They want to continue to fit curves. But when you talk to people who have done any work in AI outside statistical learning, they get it immediately. I have read several papers written in the past two months about the limitations of machine learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hartnett:&lt;/strong&gt; Are you suggesting there’s a trend developing away from machine learning?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pearl:&lt;/strong&gt; Not a trend, but a serious soul-searching effort that involves asking: Where are we going? What’s the next step?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section id=&quot;article-section-7&quot;&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hartnett:&lt;/strong&gt; That was the last thing I wanted to ask you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pearl:&lt;/strong&gt; I’m glad you didn’t ask me about free will.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hartnett:&lt;/strong&gt; In that case, what do you think about free will?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pearl:&lt;/strong&gt; We’re going to have robots with free will, absolutely. We have to understand how to program them and what we gain out of it. For some reason, evolution has found this sensation of free will to be computationally desirable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hartnett:&lt;/strong&gt; In what way?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pearl:&lt;/strong&gt; You have the sensation of free will; evolution has equipped us with this sensation. Evidently, it serves some computational function&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hartnett:&lt;/strong&gt; Will it be obvious when robots have free will?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pearl:&lt;/strong&gt; I think the first evidence will be if robots start communicating with each other counterfactually, like “You should have done better.” If a team of robots playing soccer starts to communicate in this language, then we’ll know that they have a sensation of free will. “You should have passed me the ball—I was waiting for you and you didn’t!” “You should have” means you could have controlled whatever urges made you do what you did, and you didn’t. So the first sign will be communication; the next will be better soccer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;callout&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;r'article',r' ',d,r'related',#data-omni-index,@data-article-id&quot;&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Related Stories&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2018/02/ai-keeps-mastering-games-but-can-it-win-in-the-real-world/554312/&quot; data-omni-index=&quot;0&quot; data-article-id=&quot;973370&quot; data-omni-click=&quot;inherit&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;242&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn.theatlantic.com/assets/media/img/mt/2018/02/_Laura_Lezza_Getty/thumb_wide_medium.jpg?1522767860&quot; alt=&quot;A human caregiver uses a laptop to operate a robot caregiver in the hallway of a nursing residence.&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hartnett:&lt;/strong&gt; Now that you’ve brought up free will, I guess I should ask you about the capacity for evil, which we generally think of as being contingent upon an ability to make choices. What is evil?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pearl:&lt;/strong&gt; It’s the belief that your greed or grievance supersedes all standard norms of society. For example, a person has something akin to a software module that says, “You are hungry, therefore you have permission to act to satisfy your greed or grievance.” But you have other software modules that instruct you to follow the standard laws of society. One of them is called compassion. When you elevate your grievance above those universal norms of society, that’s evil.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hartnett:&lt;/strong&gt; So how will we know when AI is capable of committing evil?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pearl:&lt;/strong&gt; When it is obvious to us that there are software components that the robot ignores, consistently ignores. When it appears that the robot follows the advice of some software components and not others, when the robot ignores the advice of other components that are maintaining norms of behavior that have been programmed into them or are expected to be there on the basis of past learning. And the robot stops following them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 19 May 2018 15:12:23 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>stevenwoo</dc:creator>
<og:title>How a Pioneer of Machine Learning Became One of Its Sharpest Critics</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2018/05/machine-learning-is-stuck-on-asking-why/560675/</og:url>
<og:image>https://cdn.theatlantic.com/assets/media/img/mt/2018/05/Pearl_Library_2880x1920_2880x1920/facebook.jpg?1526745655</og:image>
<og:description>Judea Pearl helped artificial intelligence gain a strong grasp on probability, but laments that it still can't compute cause and effect.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2018/05/machine-learning-is-stuck-on-asking-why/560675/?single_page=true</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Devices Which Track Cellphones, Intercept Calls Found All Over DC, MD, VA</title>
<link>https://www.nbcwashington.com/investigations/Potential-Spy-Devices-Which-Track-Cellphones-Intercept-Calls-Found-All-Over-DC-Md-Va-482970231.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nbcwashington.com/investigations/Potential-Spy-Devices-Which-Track-Cellphones-Intercept-Calls-Found-All-Over-DC-Md-Va-482970231.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;1&quot;&gt;The technology can be as small as a suitcase, placed anywhere at any time, and it's used to track cell phones and intercept calls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;2&quot;&gt;The News4 I-Team found dozens of potential spy devices while driving around Washington, D.C., Maryland and Northern Virginia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&quot;While you might not be a target yourself, you may live next to someone who is. You could still get caught up,&quot; said Aaron Turner, a leading mobile security expert.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;4&quot;&gt;The device, sometimes referred to by the brand name StingRay, is designed to mimic a cell tower and can trick your phone into connecting to it instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embedded cm photo R&quot; data-cid=&quot;482974551&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;galleryMask&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;310&quot; src=&quot;https://media.nbcwashington.com/images/310*413/catcher+7.JPG&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;6&quot;&gt;The News4 I-Team asked Turner to ride around the capital region with special software loaded onto three cell phones, with three different carriers, to detect the devices operating in various locations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;7&quot;&gt;&quot;So when you see these red bars, those are very high-suspicion events,&quot; said Turner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;8&quot;&gt;If you live in or near the District, your phone has probably been tracked at some point, he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;9&quot;&gt;A recent report by the Department of Homeland Security called the spy devices a real and growing risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;10&quot;&gt;And the I-Team found them in high-profile areas like outside the Trump International Hotel on Pennsylvania Avenue and while driving across the 14th Street bridge into Crystal City. The I-Team got picked up twice while driving along K Street — the corridor popular with lobbyists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;11&quot;&gt;&quot;It looks like they don't consider us to be interesting, so they've dropped us,&quot; Turner remarked looking down at one of his phones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;12&quot;&gt;Every cellphone has a unique identifying number. The phone catcher technology can harness thousands of them at a time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;13&quot;&gt;DHS has warned rogue devices could prevent connected phones from making 911 calls, saying, &quot;If this type of attack occurs during an emergency, it could prevent victims from receiving assistance.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;14&quot;&gt;&quot;Absolutely. That's a worry,&quot; said D.C. Councilwoman Mary Cheh, adding that the spy technology should be a concern for all who live and work in the District.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;15&quot;&gt;The I-Team's test phones detected 40 potential locations where the spy devices could be operating, while driving around for just a few hours.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;17&quot;&gt;&quot;I suppose if you spent more time you'd find even more,&quot; said Cheh. &quot;I have bad news for the public: Our privacy isn't what it once was.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;18&quot;&gt;Especially in her ward, where many of the streets are lined with embassies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;19&quot;&gt;&quot;They're doing the interrogation, or [checking] who we are, and then the white bar represents when they release us,&quot; Turner said as he demonstrated his technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;20&quot;&gt;The phones appeared to remain connected to a fake tower the longest, right near the Russian Embassy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;21&quot;&gt;The I-Team got picked up twice off of International Drive, right near the Chinese and Israeli embassies, then got another two hits along Massachusetts Avenue near Romania and Turkey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;22&quot;&gt;All of those countries have the phone catcher technology, Turner said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embedded cm photo C&quot; data-cid=&quot;482974501&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;galleryMask&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;620&quot; src=&quot;https://media.nbcwashington.com/images/620*349/Cellular+Intercept+Capability+Map+%28002%29.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;24&quot;&gt;&quot;You know governments do this to each other all the time and laws-schmaws,&quot; said Cheh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;25&quot;&gt;Which is a problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;26&quot;&gt;The spy technology poses a risk to national and economic security, but there's little our government can do to stop devices located on foreign soil.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;27&quot;&gt;&quot;A law that we had could not tell these embassies what they can and cannot do,&quot; said Cheh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;28&quot;&gt;The phone catchers can also be combined with other technology to listen-in or grab data from phones that are connected, Turner said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;29&quot;&gt;&quot;Most people don't know about it,&quot; said Alan Butler, senior counsel for the Electronic Privacy Information Center.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;30&quot;&gt;&quot;There's no magic software or setting that protects you from these,&quot; Butler said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;31&quot;&gt;Butler is also a D.C. resident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;32&quot;&gt;&quot;There's a lot to be concerned about,&quot; he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;33&quot;&gt;Particularly since DHS hasn't disclosed how many devices it found or where. The agency also said it did not determine who was operating them, which Butler finds unacceptable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;34&quot;&gt;&quot;I think they should be taking the time and investing the resources to identify them and to flag them to the carriers and find ways to either have them taken down or have them blocked,&quot; he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;35&quot;&gt;Turner said cell carriers can't completely secure our phones because they have to allow for law enforcement access. Plus, even the oldest phones must be able to reach 911, so low-tech vulnerabilities can't be closed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;36&quot;&gt;&quot;I don't think there's a magic fix here,&quot; said Turner. &quot;I don't think Congress can mandate anything to say, Hey, carriers do this right now.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;37&quot;&gt;The good news is about half the devices the I-Team found were likely law enforcement investigating crimes or our government using the devices defensively to identify certain cellphone numbers as they approach important locations, Turner said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;38&quot;&gt;The I-Team test detected devices in operation near Langley, the Pentagon and Fort Myer, but also found them in residential areas like Bethesda's Kenwood neighborhood, near Palisades in DC and along Old Dominion Drive in McLean, which Turner said raised questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;39&quot;&gt;&quot;Maybe someone is involved in high-level negotiations on a business deal, or maybe it's a government employee involved in a regulatory ruling,&quot; he said, adding that he's heard of the devices being used in a corporate espionage situation, which is illegal under United States law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;40&quot;&gt;You can't control which tower your phone attaches to, Turner said, so you can't avoid being caught by a device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;41&quot;&gt;So if you've ever wondered why you just can't make a call from inside your home or office: &quot;It could be why,&quot; said Turner. &quot;[It's] a good reason to have a land line.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;42&quot;&gt;But you can protect your calls and texts by downloading free calling and texting apps that use encryption instead of using the standard ones that come installed on your cellphone, he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;paragraph&quot; data-pnum=&quot;43&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reported by Jodie Fleischer, produced by Rick Yarborough, and shot and edited Jeff Piper.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 class=&quot;copyright&quot;/&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 19 May 2018 13:04:57 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>walterbell</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>The News4 I-Team found dozens of the potential spy devices while driving around Washington, D.C., Maryland and Northern Virginia.</og:description>
<og:title>Potential Spy Devices Which Track Phones Found All Over DMV</og:title>
<og:url>http://www.nbcwashington.com/investigations/Potential-Spy-Devices-Which-Track-Cellphones-Intercept-Calls-Found-All-Over-DC-Md-Va-482970231.html</og:url>
<og:image>https://media.nbcwashington.com/images/1200*675/catcher+4.JPG</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nbcwashington.com/investigations/Potential-Spy-Devices-Which-Track-Cellphones-Intercept-Calls-Found-All-Over-DC-Md-Va-482970231.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Lessons from My Math Degree That Have Nothing to Do with Math</title>
<link>https://medium.com/s/story/6-life-lessons-from-my-math-degree-that-have-nothing-to-do-with-math-d38aba90edfe</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://medium.com/s/story/6-life-lessons-from-my-math-degree-that-have-nothing-to-do-with-math-d38aba90edfe</guid>
<description>&lt;p name=&quot;6553&quot; id=&quot;6553&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf--hasDropCapModel graf--hasDropCap graf--leading&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;graf-dropCap&quot;&gt;P&lt;/span&gt;icture a mathematician. What do you see?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;1f75&quot; id=&quot;1f75&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;I’ll conjure up a popular image. It’s late at night. A figure is hunched over a desk scribbling into a notebook. The room smells like graphite dust, eraser shavings and body odor. Numbers and symbols gleam in the lamplight, and a calculator sits idle nearby towering textbooks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;4e87&quot; id=&quot;4e87&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;It’s not an entirely unjust stereotype. Math attracts its fair share of cave dwellers. (I should know, since I had lecture with them.) So when people discover that I studied applied mathematics in college, I get why they might raise an eyebrow like I’m from a different species.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;8eea&quot; id=&quot;8eea&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;The truth is far less exotic: I chose to study math because I was good at it and thought quantitative skills would bolster my career prospects. As it turns out, I wasn’t very good at it. I got my ass kicked by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.storyofmathematics.com/18th_euler.html&quot; data-href=&quot;http://www.storyofmathematics.com/18th_euler.html&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Euler&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://mathworld.wolfram.com/Eigenvalue.html&quot; data-href=&quot;http://mathworld.wolfram.com/Eigenvalue.html&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;eigenvalues&lt;/a&gt; alike. And although familiarity with statistics has proved marginally useful, I’ve never used 99 percent of the methods, proofs and theorems I painstakingly studied in my college courses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;99c2&quot; id=&quot;99c2&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;There were so many moments that I wished I had picked a different major. Something easier. A little less painful. At times, I hated math. And yet, six years later, I’m so grateful that I studied it. The reasons have nothing to do with numbers and everything to do with life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 name=&quot;2333&quot; id=&quot;2333&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf-after--p&quot;&gt;1. I expect to not get the answer on the first try&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;5135&quot; id=&quot;5135&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;As a kid, I thought I was pretty hot shit, mathematically speaking. If my answer didn’t match the key in the back of the book, I’d blame the book. “Must be a typo,” I’d reassure myself. It was never a typo. I was just wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;8198&quot; id=&quot;8198&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;As a college student, I discovered that the first incorrect answer was a rite of passage — a necessary misstep on the path to truth. This became so ingrained in me that if I got the correct answer on my first attempt, I’d think, “Must be luck.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;551b&quot; id=&quot;551b&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;It might sound pessimistic, but I think it’s pragmatic. I was rarely discouraged, because I never expected a quick win. And if I was correct on the first stab, I was pleasantly surprised. I became well-rehearsed in failed attempts, and so much more patient as a result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 name=&quot;12a7&quot; id=&quot;12a7&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf-after--p&quot;&gt;2. I can tolerate ungodly amounts of frustration&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;f152&quot; id=&quot;f152&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;Writer’s block has nothing on a tough math problem, and I’ve suffered through both. Writer’s block usually boils down to you thinking you’re not good enough. With math, it feels like the universe is mocking your ineptitude.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;c959&quot; id=&quot;c959&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;I’ve torn my hair out while multiplying matrices, watched it flutter onto thrice-erased sheets of paper. It brought me no closer to the solution, and so I couldn’t help but think, “Well, what was the point of that?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;6ae8&quot; id=&quot;6ae8&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;My linear algebra teaching assistant once said, “Math is pain.” I agree. Studying math is masochistic. The trick is to welcome the pain. Invite it inside for Triscuits and gouda. I learned to find fun in frustration, treating it like a game where I would be the eventual victor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;9bf5&quot; id=&quot;9bf5&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;As a result, my tolerance for frustration is so much higher. I’m convinced that the seeds of patience and resilience were planted and sprouted in those math notebooks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 name=&quot;5278&quot; id=&quot;5278&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf-after--p&quot;&gt;3. I attack problems from multiple angles&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;cb07&quot; id=&quot;cb07&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;When I was a kid, my dad had a massive red toolbox filled with wrenches, screwdrivers and various gizmos. It was so big that I needed two hands to hold it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;70f6&quot; id=&quot;70f6&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Studying math was like maintaining a toolbox. Each time I learned something new, into the big red box that newfound knowledge went. Who knew when it would be useful? Long-buried methods could be just the socket wrench I needed later on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;5dd7&quot; id=&quot;5dd7&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;The science of math is grounded in wielding the right tool in the right step. The art lies in knowing which tool to grab. Thing is, when you’re constantly encountering mysterious machinery, it’s difficult to determine which tool fits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;9c6d&quot; id=&quot;9c6d&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;I became adept at trying all sorts of tactics, accustomed to chipping away at a problem from different angles on the promise of a breakthrough. And that simple joy of solving a problem propels me, for there are few better feelings than when the key finally clicks and the lock opens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 name=&quot;4a5e&quot; id=&quot;4a5e&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf-after--p&quot;&gt;4. I check my goddamn work&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;ca7f&quot; id=&quot;ca7f&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;Knowing how to solve problems is Act One. Act Two is not fooling yourself into thinking you know more than you do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;0677&quot; id=&quot;0677&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;The arrogant mathematician is a sloppy one. True mathematicians are skeptics, wary of their own instincts. Even if I knew how to find the solution, I still proceeded with caution. One dropped decimal could blow it all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;f60f&quot; id=&quot;f60f&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Even once I’d solved it, I checked each step again, trying to suss out faulty reasoning or careless mistakes. Sometimes I solved the problem a different way, ensuring that I arrived at the same result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;4b2c&quot; id=&quot;4b2c&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Math reminded me that I’m fallible — prone to all sorts of mishaps and missteps. I shouldn’t cut corners, because walking with practiced care was better than flailing at a full sprint. And just because I arrived at an answer, didn’t immediately make it the right one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 name=&quot;3a89&quot; id=&quot;3a89&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf-after--p&quot;&gt;5. I practice persistence&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;5c7c&quot; id=&quot;5c7c&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;Perhaps you’ve heard the stereotype that Asians are good at math. Let’s just say I have a large sample set and, sure, some Asian math students are very smart. Or at least smarter than me. So is there a gene that imbues Asian people with math talent? I doubt it very much .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;a27a&quot; id=&quot;a27a&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Could it be that some Asian students were raised to be more persistent than Americans? Maybe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;9cdd&quot; id=&quot;9cdd&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/sections/health-shots/2012/11/12/164793058/struggle-for-smarts-how-eastern-and-western-cultures-tackle-learning&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/sections/health-shots/2012/11/12/164793058/struggle-for-smarts-how-eastern-and-western-cultures-tackle-learning&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;a famous study&lt;/a&gt;, classrooms of American and Japanese first graders were given an impossible math problem. The American students gave up after less than 30 seconds, while the Japanese students persisted for an hour before the proctors stopped them to confess that the problem was unsolvable. (How cruel!). The grand difference came down to Asian cultures prioritizing practice and persistence in education, along with embracing that struggle is a large part of the learning process. In the Western world, the idea of inherent intelligence is pushed and prized, which undercuts the importance of educational struggle. I buy that American children are a bunch of cupcakes. Give an American kid a math problem, and chances are they’ll squirm, whine, complain and hit you with that tired refrain: “When am I ever going to use this in the real world?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;266a&quot; id=&quot;266a&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Answering that question directly is a mistake. When are you going to need to factor a polynomial in the “real world”? Maybe never, kid. Especially not with that attitude.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;40b0&quot; id=&quot;40b0&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;But when are you going to face a problem that requires focusing for more than 30 seconds? All the goddamn time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;1389&quot; id=&quot;1389&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;I’m so fortunate that math forced me to practice persistence. It paid massive dividends later, even if I was too immature to recognize it in the moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 name=&quot;ea87&quot; id=&quot;ea87&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--h3 graf-after--p&quot;&gt;6. I know what makes me happy (and what doesn’t)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;28ed&quot; id=&quot;28ed&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;My biggest lesson from math was the most counterintuitive: It wasn’t for me. Although I studied applied mathematics as a 19-year-old, I grew disillusioned with the actual application of it. I wanted to go out into the world and &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; things, not pore over problem sets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;6d7c&quot; id=&quot;6d7c&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;So I tuned out. I mailed in midterms. I submitted half-finished homework, if I turned it in at all. The only time I saw an “A” was at the start of my first name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;362d&quot; id=&quot;362d&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;I was perfectly content being mired in mathematical mediocrity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;e092&quot; id=&quot;e092&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;And that scared the shit out of me. Because I couldn’t ignore the voice deep inside that screamed: &lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;This isn’t what you were meant to do&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;21f6&quot; id=&quot;21f6&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;The truth is, math didn’t move me. My stomach dropped whenever I walked by a classroom and a chalkboard. After each final, with mathematical methods rattling in my head like a tambourine in a dryer, I couldn’t help but think, “So… what do I do with this now?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;75cf&quot; id=&quot;75cf&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;As graduation grew closer, I set one career goal: not dreading going to work in the morning like I did math lecture. Money could never compensate for that feeling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;e8e7&quot; id=&quot;e8e7&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;When I graduated, I closed my math textbooks for good. I discovered new passions, learned new skills and grew in new ways. Six years into my career, I can say that being comfortable with numbers and data has been useful, but what has proved invaluable are the qualities that math imbued in me — patience, attention to detail, humility and persistence. That was the true reward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;3e28&quot; id=&quot;3e28&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;After all that pain, angst and frustration, it may have been cathartic to douse my math textbooks in kerosene and light them on fire. But I kept them instead. They’re on the bottom shelf. Even though I never take them out, I like having them around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;3536&quot; id=&quot;3536&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;For a long time, I thought this was just a collector’s impulse. But I just moved recently and I put my bookshelf back together from top to bottom: first the novels, then the narrative nonfiction and memoirs in the middle. I could’ve sworn I heard the wood creak and the shelves slide forward. It was too top heavy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;4630&quot; id=&quot;4630&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p graf--trailing&quot;&gt;I needed that bottom row of math textbooks. They were my anchor. The bedrock. The foundation for much of what I’ve learned, and a sturdy base for everything still to come.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 19 May 2018 13:01:47 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ginnungagap</dc:creator>
<og:title>Lessons from My Math Degree That Have Nothing to Do with Math</og:title>
<og:url>https://medium.com/s/story/6-life-lessons-from-my-math-degree-that-have-nothing-to-do-with-math-d38aba90edfe</og:url>
<og:image>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*U1Qg4X4sASSwAqoTabd0-w.jpeg</og:image>
<og:description>I’ll conjure up a popular image. It’s late at night. A figure is hunched over a desk scribbling into a notebook. The room smells like graphite dust, eraser shavings and body odor. Numbers and symbols…</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://medium.com/s/story/6-life-lessons-from-my-math-degree-that-have-nothing-to-do-with-math-d38aba90edfe</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Estonia plans to become a free public transport nation</title>
<link>https://popupcity.net/estonia-to-become-the-worlds-first-free-public-transport-nation/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://popupcity.net/estonia-to-become-the-worlds-first-free-public-transport-nation/</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;story clearfix&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tallinn, known for its digital government and successful tech startups, is often referred to as Europe’s innovation capital. Now celebrating five years of free public transport for all citizens, the government is planning to make Estonia the first free public transport nation. Allan Alaküla, Head of Tallinn European Union Office, shares some valuable insights for other cities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Five years ago, citizens of Tallinn were asked in a referendum if free public transport should be realized. Why should citizens be involved in such political decisions?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;“A decision for a long-term project should not only be taken by the current elected council, but it should be locked politically by asking for support from the public. Although a local referendum is not legally binding, the mandate from the popular vote is stronger than just from the council.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_48894&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://popupcity.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Tallinn-2-800x480.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; class=&quot;size-medium wp-image-48894&quot; srcset=&quot;https://popupcity.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Tallinn-2-800x480.jpg 800w, https://popupcity.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Tallinn-2-1400x840.jpg 1400w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;To ride Tallinn’s network of trams, buses and trains for free, you must be registered as a resident, which makes the municipality profit €1,000 from your income tax every year. All you need to do then is getting a €2 green card and carrying your ID on public transport&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How does this work out for the municipality?&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;“There’s no doubt that we not only cover the costs, but also come out with a surplus. We earned double as much as we have lost since introducing free public transport. We’re happy to see that so many people are motivated to register as residents in Tallinn to make use of free public transport.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://popupcity.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Allan-Alak%C3%BCla-800x1200.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;1200&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-medium wp-image-48895&quot; srcset=&quot;https://popupcity.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Allan-Alaküla-800x1200.jpg 800w, https://popupcity.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Allan-Alaküla.jpg 1280w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px&quot;/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who is profiting the most from free buses, trams and trains in Tallinn?&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;“A good thing is, of course, that it mostly appeals to people with lower to medium incomes. But free public transport also stimulates the mobility of higher-income groups. They are simply going out more often for entertainment, to restaurants, bars and cinemas. Therefore they consume local goods and services and are likely to spend more money, more often. In the end this makes local businesses thrive. It breathes new life into the city.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What further actions is Tallinn taking to make the use of individual transport less attractive?&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;“Before introducing free public transport, the city center was crammed with cars. This situation has improved — also because we raised parking fees. When non-Tallinners leave their cars in a park-and-ride and check in to public transport on the same day, they can’t only use public transport for free, but also won’t be charged the parking fee. We noticed that people didn’t complain about high parking fees once we offered them a good alternative.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What inspired the Estonian government to introduce free public transport all over the country?&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;“People in other parts of Estonia started to demand free public transport, too. In Wales, an experiment with free public transport is about to end in May, but has already been extended for another year. Taking this as an example, we would also like to remove the public transport ticketing for all rural connections in Estonia.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://popupcity.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Tallinn-3-800x404.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;404&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-medium wp-image-48896&quot; srcset=&quot;https://popupcity.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Tallinn-3-800x404.jpg 800w, https://popupcity.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Tallinn-3-1400x708.jpg 1400w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What advice would you give to other European cities that are hesitant to implement free transport?&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;“Tallinn’s approach is not a universal solution for all and for some it might be too extreme. We know examples of cities in Poland, Germany and France that already realized free public transport or are considering it. But we’re also seeing plenty of partially free public transport ideas are being executed, ranging from free weekend rides and lower fares in off-peak hours to free public transport for the retired and students. Municipalities should be brave to use their city as a testing ground to find out what system is realistic for them to implement.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Which city will be the next to copy Tallinn’s successful system?&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;“Right now, Paris is considering the introduction of free public transport — mostly to reduce pollution in the city center. Once a city of this size and scale takes the step, other cities will inevitably follow. No doubt about that.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/2jZyJOM&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;EU Green Week 2018&lt;/a&gt; will explore ways in which the European Union is helping cities to become better places to live and work. In a special article series, Pop-Up City will highlight some of the most inspiring green developments from across the continent. Join the #EUGreenWeek conversation on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/search/top/?q=%23EUGreenWeek&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/search?q=%23EUGreenWeek&amp;amp;src=tyah&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/explore/tags/eugreenweek/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;Great and delightful news from Prague: The local transportation company &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ropid.cz/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Ropid&lt;/a&gt; has announced that it will be launching &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.news.com.au/travel/news/prague-plans-subway-love-train-for-czech-singles/story-e6frfq80-1226645720165&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;‘love trains’&lt;/a&gt; in the city’s metro system later this year.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.metro-litteratur.dk/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Metro Litteratur&lt;/a&gt; is a recently launched campaign that helps to promote talented Danish authors, poets and graphic artists by distributing their works at various metro stations in the city of Copenhagen. The program is a collaboration between the Milan-based organization &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.subway-letteratura.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Subway Letteratura&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;http://intl.m.dk/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Copenhagen Metro Authority&lt;/a&gt; and is “a result of a competition held earlier this year, which led to the publication of thirteen small booklets that are offered to passengers free of charge”, writes &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.guerrilla-innovation.com/archives/2011/11/000814.php&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Guerrilla Innovation&lt;/a&gt;. Every booklet is published in 300,000 copies and can be downloaded over &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.metro-litteratur.dk/?cat=25&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;Nairobi’s ad-hoc Matatu bus system is the first ever informal urban transport system brought to Google Maps.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;Truth be told, who wouldn’t love to be all green-savvy and cruise around in an environmental-friendly electric car if you could afford it and spare the time to recharge? But then, there is also the fear of running out of power in the middle of a junction, or worse, in the middle of nowhere. Yet, we all agree that electric cars are a great invention. The city of Gumi in South Korea now put all excuses aside and took public transportation to the next level by enabling public buses to run on electric power. What’s new? They do not have to stop to re-“fuel” – not once.&lt;/span&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 19 May 2018 10:37:25 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>doener</dc:creator>
<og:title>Estonia To Become The World’s First Free Public Transport Nation</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>http://popupcity.net/estonia-to-become-the-worlds-first-free-public-transport-nation/</og:url>
<og:image>https://popupcity.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Tallinn-2-800x480.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>After a successful experiment with free public transport for all citizens in Tallinn, Estonia wants to become the world's first free public transport nation. Allan Alaküla explains why this is a good idea.</og:description>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://popupcity.net/estonia-to-become-the-worlds-first-free-public-transport-nation/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>