<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Shazam-like technology used to identify bars illegally streaming soccer games</title>
<link>https://www.theverge.com/2019/6/12/18662968/la-liga-app-illegal-soccer-streaming-fine</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.theverge.com/2019/6/12/18662968/la-liga-app-illegal-soccer-streaming-fine</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;ZX3QOn&quot;&gt;Spain’s data protection agency has fined the country’s soccer league, LaLiga, €250,000 (about $280,000) for allegedly violating EU data privacy and transparency laws. &lt;a href=&quot;https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fitunes.apple.com%2Fus%2Fapp%2Fla-liga-live-soccer-scores%2Fid545609647%3Fmt%3D8&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The app&lt;/a&gt;, which is used for keeping track of games and stats, was using the phone’s microphone and GPS to track bars illegally streaming soccer games, Spanish newspaper &lt;a href=&quot;https://elpais.com/economia/2019/06/11/actualidad/1560264403_529943.html&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;El País&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; reported.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;hpiBGF&quot;&gt;Using a Shazam-like technology, the app would record audio to identify soccer games, and use the geolocation of the phone to locate which bars were streaming without licenses. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eldiario.es/tecnologia/Liga-Futbol-microfono-telefono-aficionados_0_780772124.html&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;El Diario&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; reports that fans have downloaded that app more than 10 million times, essentially turning them into undercover narcs. The league claims that the app asks for permission to access the phone’s microphone and location, and that the data — which is received as a code, not audio — is only used to detect LaLiga streams. The app does explain in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.laliga.es/aficionesunidas/aviso-legal&quot;&gt;terms of service&lt;/a&gt; that by giving the app permission, users are consenting to LaLiga using their phones to detect fraudulent behavior, like pirated soccer games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;4VSIXb&quot;&gt;However, the Spanish data protection agency claims that the app didn’t make this clear, and has ordered LaLiga to take down the app by June 30th. The league plans to appeal the sanction, claiming that the agency doesn’t fully understand the app’s technology.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 19:24:36 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>rexbee</dc:creator>
<og:description>It used a Shazam-like technology to identify soccer games</og:description>
<og:image>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/MGaCIyuLjcBb5ykFc-U7xgIXrho=/0x215:3000x1786/fit-in/1200x630/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/16335743/671946618.jpg.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>LaLiga’s app listened in on fans to catch bars illegally streaming soccer</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.theverge.com/2019/6/12/18662968/la-liga-app-illegal-soccer-streaming-fine</og:url>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.theverge.com/2019/6/12/18662968/la-liga-app-illegal-soccer-streaming-fine</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The world in which IPv6 was a good design (2017)</title>
<link>https://apenwarr.ca/log/20170810</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://apenwarr.ca/log/20170810</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The world in which IPv6 was a good design&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last November I went to an IETF meeting for the first time. The IETF is an interesting place; it seems to be about 1/3 maintenance grunt work, 1/3 extending existing stuff, and 1/3 blue sky insanity. I attended mostly because I wanted to see how people would react to &lt;a href=&quot;https://datatracker.ietf.org/meeting/97/materials/slides-97-iccrg-bbr-congestion-control&quot;&gt;TCP BBR, which was being presented there for the first time&lt;/a&gt;. (Answer: mostly positively, but with suspicion. It kinda seemed too good to be true.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, the IETF meetings contain lots and lots of presentations about IPv6, the thing that was supposed to replace IPv4, which is what the Internet runs on. (Some would say IPv4 is already being replaced; some would say it has already happened.) Along with those presentations about IPv6, there were lots of people who think it's great, the greatest thing ever, and they're pretty sure it will finally catch on Any Day Now, and IPv4 is just a giant pile of hacks that really needs to die so that the Internet can be elegant again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought this would be a great chance to really try to figure out what was going on. Why is IPv6 such a complicated mess compared to IPv4? Wouldn't it be better if it had just been &lt;a href=&quot;https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc1710&quot;&gt;IPv4 with more address bits&lt;/a&gt;? But it's not, oh goodness, is it ever not. So I started asking around. Here's what I found.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buses ruined everything&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once upon a time, there was the telephone network, which used physical circuit switching. Essentially, that meant moving connectors around so that your phone connection was literally just a very long wire (&quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/OSI_model&quot;&gt;OSI layer&lt;/a&gt; 1&quot;). A &quot;leased line&quot; was a very long wire that you leased from the phone company. You would put bits in one end of the wire, and they'd come out the other end, a fixed amount of time later. You didn't need addresses because there was exactly one machine at each end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually the phone company optimized that a bit. Time-division multiplexing (TDM) and &quot;virtual circuit switching&quot; was born. The phone company could transparently take the bits at a slower bit rate from multiple lines, group them together with multiplexers and demultiplexers, and let them pass through the middle of the phone system using fewer wires than before. Making that work was a little complicated, but as far as we modem users were concerned, you still put bits in one end and they came out the other end. No addresses needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Internet (not called the Internet at the time) was built on top of these circuits. You had a bunch of wires that you could put bits into and have them come out the other side. If one computer had two or three interfaces, then it could, if given the right instructions, forward bits from one line to another, and you could do something a lot more efficient than a separate line between each pair of computers. And so IP addresses (&quot;layer 3&quot;), subnets, and routing were born. Even then, with these point-to-point links, you didn't need MAC addresses, because once a packet went into the wire, there was only one place it could come out. You used IP addresses to decide where it should go after that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, LANs got invented as an alternative. If you wanted to connect computers (or terminals and a mainframe) together at your local site, it was pretty inconvenient to need multiple interfaces, one for each wire to each satellite computer, arranged in a star configuration. To save on electronics, people wanted to have a &quot;bus&quot; network (also known as a &quot;broadcast domain,&quot; a name that will be important later) where multiple stations could just be plugged into a single wire, and talk to any other station plugged into the same wire. These were not the same people as the ones building the Internet, so they didn't use IP addresses for this. They all invented their own scheme (&quot;layer 2&quot;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the early local bus networks was arcnet, which is dear to my heart (I wrote the first Linux arcnet driver &lt;a href=&quot;http://apenwarr.ca/arcnet/howto/intro.html&quot;&gt;and arcnet poetry&lt;/a&gt; way back in the 1990s, long after arcnet was obsolete). Arcnet layer 2 addresses were very simplistic: just 8 bits, set by jumpers or DIP switches on the back of the network card. As the network owner, it was your job to configure the addresses and make sure you didn't have any duplicates, or all heck would ensue. This was kind of a pain, but arcnet networks were usually pretty small, so it was only &lt;em&gt;kind&lt;/em&gt; of a pain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few years later, ethernet came along and solved that problem once and for all, by using many more bits (48, in fact) in the layer 2 address. That's enough bits that you can assign a different (sharded-sequential) address to every device that has ever been manufactured, and not have any overlaps. And that's exactly what they did! Thus the ethernet MAC address was born.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Various LAN technologies came and went, including one of my favourites, IPX (Internetwork Packet Exchange, though it had nothing to do with the &quot;real&quot; Internet) and Netware, which worked great as long as all the clients and servers were on a single bus network. You never had to configure any addresses, ever. It was beautiful, and reliable, and worked. The golden age of networking, basically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, someone had to ruin it: big company/university networks. They wanted to have so many computers that sharing 10 Mbps of a single bus network between them all became a huge bottleneck, so they needed a way to have multiple buses, and then interconnect - &quot;internetwork,&quot; if you will - those buses together. You're probably thinking, of course! Use the Internet Protocol for that, right? Ha ha, no. The Internet protocol, still not called that, wasn't mature or popular back then, and nobody took it seriously. Netware-over-IPX (and the many other LAN protocols at the time) were serious business, so as serious businesses do, they invented their own thing(s) to extend the already-popular thing, ethernet. Devices on ethernet already had addresses, MAC addresses, which were about the only thing the various LAN protocol people could agree on, so they decided to use ethernet addresses as the keys for their routing mechanisms. (Actually they called it bridging and switching instead of routing.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem with ethernet addresses is they're assigned sequentially at the factory, so they can't be hierarchical. That means the &quot;bridging table&quot; is not as nice as a modern IP routing table, which can talk about the route for a whole subnet at a time. In order to do efficient bridging, you had to remember which network bus each MAC address could be found on. And humans didn't want to configure each of those by hand, so it needed to figure itself out automatically. If you had a complex internetwork of bridges, this could get a little complicated. As I understand it, that's what led to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://etherealmind.com/algorhyme-radia-perlman/&quot;&gt;spanning tree poem&lt;/a&gt;, and I think I'll just leave it at that. Poetry is very important in networking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, it mostly worked, but it was a bit of a mess, and you got broadcast floods every now and then, and the routes weren't always optimal, and it was pretty much impossible to debug. (You definitely couldn't write something like traceroute for bridging, because none of the tools you need to make it work - such as the ability for an intermediate bridge to even have an address - exist in plain ethernet.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, all these bridges were hardware-optimized. The whole system was invented by hardware people, basically, as a way of fooling the software, which had no idea about multiple buses and bridging between them, into working better on large networks. Hardware bridging means the bridging could go really really fast - as fast as the ethernet could go. Nowadays that doesn't sound very special, but at the time, it was a big deal. Ethernet was 10 Mbps, because you could maybe saturate it by putting a bunch of computers on the network all at once, not because any one computer could saturate 10 Mbps. That was crazy talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, the point is, bridging was a mess, and impossible to debug, but it was fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Internet over buses&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While all that was happening, those Internet people were getting busy, and were of course not blind to the invention of cool cheap LAN technologies. I think it might have been around this time that the ARPANET got actually renamed to the Internet, but I'm not sure. Let's say it was, because the story is better if I sound confident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At some point, things progressed from connecting individual Internet computers over point-to-point long distance links, to the desire to connect whole LANs together, over point-to-point links. Basically, you wanted a long-distance bridge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might be thinking, hey, no big deal, why not just build a long distance bridge and be done with it? Sounds good, doesn't work. I won't go into the details right now, but basically the problem is &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Network_congestion&quot;&gt;congestion control&lt;/a&gt;. The deep dark secret of ethernet bridging is that it assumes all your links are about the same speed, and/or completely uncongested, because they have no way to slow down. You just blast data as fast as you can, and expect it to arrive. But when your ethernet is 10 Mbps and your point-to-point link is 0.128 Mbps, that's completely hopeless. Separately, the idea of figuring out your routes by flooding all the links to see which one is right - this is the actual way bridging typically works - is hugely wasteful for slow links. And sub-optimal routing, an annoyance on local networks with low latency and high throughput, is nasty on slow, expensive long-distance links. It just doesn't scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily, those Internet people (if it was called the Internet yet) had been working on that exact set of problems. If we could just use Internet stuff to connect ethernet buses together, we'd be in great shape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so they designed a &quot;frame format&quot; for Internet packets over ethernet (and arcnet, for that matter, and every other kind of LAN).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that's when everything started to go wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first problem that needed solving was that now, when you put an Internet packet onto a wire, it was no longer clear which machine was supposed to &quot;hear&quot; it and maybe forward it along. If multiple Internet routers were on the same ethernet segment, you couldn't have them all picking it up and trying to forward it; that way lies packet storms and routing loops. No, you had to choose &lt;em&gt;which&lt;/em&gt; router on the ethernet bus is supposed to pick it up. We can't just use the IP destination field for that, because we're already using that for the &lt;em&gt;final&lt;/em&gt; destination, not the router destination. Instead, we identify the desired router using its MAC address in the ethernet frame.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So basically, to set up your local IP routing table, you want to be able to say something like, &quot;send packets to IP address 10.1.1.1 via the router at MAC address 11:22:33:44:55:66.&quot; That's the actual thing you want to express. This is important! Your destination is an IP address, but your router is a MAC address. But if you've ever configured a routing table, you might have noticed that nobody writes it like that. Instead, because the writers of your operating system's TCP/IP stack are stubborn, you write something like &quot;send packets to IP address 10.1.1.1 via the router at IP address 192.168.1.1.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In truth, that really is just complicating things. Now your operating system has to first look up the ethernet address of 192.168.1.1, find out it's 11:22:33:44:55:66, and finally generate a packet with destination ethernet address 11:22:33:44:55:66 and destination IP address 10.1.1.1. 192.168.1.1 shows up nowhere in the packet; it's just an abstraction at the human level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To do that pointless intermediate step, you need to add ARP (address resolution protocol), a simple non-IP protocol whose job it is to convert IP addresses to ethernet addresses. It does this by broadcasting to everyone on the local ethernet bus, asking them all to answer if they own that particular IP address. If you have bridges, they all have to forward all the ARP packets to all their interfaces, because they're ethernet broadcast packets, and that's what broadcasting means. On a big, busy ethernet with lots of interconnected LANs, excessive broadcasts start becoming one of your biggest nightmares. It's especially bad on wifi. As time went on, people started making bridges/switches with special hacks to avoid forwarding ARP as far as it's technically supposed to go, to try to cut down on this problem. Some devices (especially wifi access points) just make fake ARP answers to try to help. But doing any of that is a hack, albeit sometimes a necessary hack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Death by legacy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time passed. Eventually (and this actually took quite a while), people pretty much stopped using non-IP protocols on ethernet at all. So basically all networks became a physical wire (layer 1), with multiple stations on a bus (layer 2), with multiple buses connected over bridges (gotcha! still layer 2!), and those inter-buses connected over IP routers (layer 3).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a while, people got tired of manually configuring IP addresses, arcnet style, and wanted them to auto-configure, ethernet style, except it was too late to literally do it ethernet style, because a) the devices had already been manufactured with ethernet addresses, not IP addresses, and b) IP addresses were only 32 bits, which is not enough to just manufacture them forever with no overlaps, and c) just assigning IP addresses sequentially instead of using subnets would bring us back to square one: it would just be ethernet over again, and we already have ethernet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So that's where bootp and DHCP came from. Those protocols, by the way, are special kinda like ARP is special (except they pretend not to be special, by technically being IP packets). They have to be special, because an IP node has to be able to transmit them before it has an IP address, which is of course impossible, so it just fills the IP headers with essentially nonsense (albeit nonsense specified by an RFC), so the headers might as well have been left out. (You know these &quot;IP&quot; headers are nonsense because the DHCP server has to open a raw socket and fill them in by hand; the kernel IP layer can't do it.) But nobody would feel nice if they were inventing a whole new protocol that wasn't IP, so they pretended it was IP, and then they felt nice. Well, as nice as one can feel when one is inventing DHCP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I digress. The salient detail here is that unlike real IP services, bootp and DHCP need to know about ethernet addresses, because after all, it's their job to hear your ethernet address and assign you an IP address to go with it. They're basically the reverse of ARP, except we can't say that, because there's a protocol called RARP that is literally the reverse of ARP. Actually, RARP worked quite fine and did the same thing as bootp and DHCP while being much simpler, but we don't talk about that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The point of all this is that ethernet and IP were getting further and further intertwined. They're nowadays almost inseparable. It's hard to imagine a network interface (except ppp0) without a 48-bit MAC address, and it's hard to imagine that network interface working without an IP address. You write your IP routing table using IP addresses, but of course you know you're lying when you name the router by IP address; you're just indirectly saying that you want to route via a MAC address. And you have ARP, which gets bridged but not really, and DHCP, which is an IP packet but is really an ethernet protocol, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, we still have both bridging and routing, and they both get more and more complicated as the LANs and the Internet get more and more complicated, respectively. Bridging is still, mostly, hardware based and defined by IEEE, the people who control the ethernet standards. Routing is still, mostly, software based and defined by the IETF, the people who control the Internet standards. Both groups still try to pretend the other group doesn't exist. Network operators basically choose bridging vs routing based on how fast they want it to go and how much they hate configuring DHCP servers, which they really hate very much, which means they use bridging as much as possible and routing when they have to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, bridging has gotten so completely out of control that people decided to extract the layer 2 bridging decisions out completely to a higher level (with configuration exchanged between bridges using a protocol layered over IP, of course!) so it can be centrally managed. That's called software-defined networking (SDN). It helps a lot, compared to letting your switches and bridges just do whatever they want, but it's also fundamentally silly, because you know what's software defined networking? IP. It is literally and has always been the software-defined network you use for interconnecting networks that have gotten too big. But the problem is, IPv4 was initially too hard to hardware accelerate, and anyway, it didn't get hardware accelerated, and configuring DHCP really is a huge pain, so network operators just learned how to bridge bigger and bigger things. And nowadays big data centers are basically just SDNed, and you might as well not be using IP in the data center at all, because nobody's routing the packets. It's all just one big virtual bus network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is, in short, a mess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Now forget I said all that...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great story, right? Right. Now pretend none of that happened, and we're back in the early 1990s, when most of that had in fact already happened, but people at the IETF were anyway pretending that it hadn't happened and that the &quot;upcoming&quot; disaster could all be avoided. This is the good part!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's one thing I forgot to mention in that big long story above: somewhere in that whole chain of events, &lt;strong&gt;we completely stopped using bus networks&lt;/strong&gt;. Ethernet is not actually a bus anymore. It just &lt;em&gt;pretends&lt;/em&gt; to be a bus. Basically, we couldn't get ethernet's famous &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Carrier-sense_multiple_access_with_collision_detection&quot;&gt;CSMA/CD&lt;/a&gt; to keep working as speeds increased, so we went back to the good old star topology. We run bundles of cables from the switch, so that we can run one cable from each station all the way back to the center point. Walls and ceilings and floors are filled with big, thick, expensive bundles of ethernet, because we couldn't figure out how to make buses work well... at layer 1. It's kinda funny actually when you think about it. If you find sad things funny.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, in a bonus fit of insanity, even wifi - the ultimate bus network, right, where literally everybody is sharing the same open-air &quot;bus&quot; - we almost universally use wifi in a mode, called &quot;infrastructure mode,&quot; which simulates a giant star topology. If you have two wifi stations connected to the same access point, they don't talk to each other directly, even when they can hear each other just fine. They send a packet to the access point, but addressed to the MAC address of the other node. The access point then bounces it back out to the destination node.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HOLD THE HORSES LET ME JUST REVIEW THAT FOR YOU. There's a little catch there. When node X wants to send to Internet node Z, via IP router Y, via wifi access point A, what does the packet look like? Just to draw a picture, here's what we want to happen:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;X -&amp;gt; [wifi] -&amp;gt; A -&amp;gt; [wifi] -&amp;gt; Y -&amp;gt; [internet] -&amp;gt; Z
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Z is the IP destination, so obviously the IP destination field has to be Z. Y is the router, which we learned above that we specify by using its ethernet MAC address in the ethernet destination field. But in wifi, X can't just send out a packet to Y, for various reasons (including that they don't know each other's WPA2 encryption keys). We have to send to A. Where do we put A's address, you might ask?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No problem! 802.11 has a thing called 3-address mode. They add a &lt;em&gt;third&lt;/em&gt; ethernet MAC address to every frame, so they can talk about the real ethernet destination, and the intermediate ethernet destination. On top of that, there are bit fields called &quot;to-AP&quot; and &quot;from-AP,&quot; which tell you if the packet is going from a station to an AP, or from an AP to a station, respectively. But actually they can both be true at the same time, because that's how you make wifi repeaters (APs send packets to APs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of wifi repeaters! If A is a repeater, it has to send back to the base station, B, along the way, which looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;X -&amp;gt; [wifi] -&amp;gt; A -&amp;gt; [wifi-repeater] -&amp;gt; B -&amp;gt; [wifi] -&amp;gt; Y -&amp;gt; [internet] -&amp;gt; Z
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;X-&amp;gt;A uses three-address mode, but A-&amp;gt;B has a problem: the ethernet source address is X, and the ethernet destination address is Y, but the packet on the air is actually being sent from A to B; X and Y aren't involved at all. Suffice it to say that there's a thing called 4-address mode, and it works pretty much like you think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(In 802.11s mesh networks, there's a 6-address mode, and that's about where I gave up trying to understand.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Avery, I was promised IPv6, and you haven't even mentioned IPv6&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, oops. This post went a bit off the rails, didn't it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's the point of the whole thing. The IETF people, when they were thinking about IPv6, saw this mess getting made - and maybe predicted some of the additional mess that would happen, though I doubt they could have predicted SDN and wifi repeater modes - and they said, hey wait a minute, stop right there. We don't need any of this crap! What if instead the world worked like this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;No more physical bus networks (already done!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No more layer 2 internetworks (that's what layer 3 is for)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No more broadcasts (layer 2 is always point-to-point, so where would you send the broadcast to? replace it with multicast instead)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No more MAC addresses (on a point-to-point network, it's obvious who the sender and receiver are, and you can do multicast using IP addresses)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No more ARP and DHCP (no MAC addresses, no so mapping IP addresses to MAC addresses)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No more complexity in IP headers (so you can hardware accelerate IP routing)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No more IP address shortages (so we can go back to routing big subnets again)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No more manual IP address configuration except at the core (and there are so many IP addresses that we can recursively hand out subnets down the tree from there)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Imagine that we lived in such a world: wifi repeaters would just be IPv6 routers. So would wifi access points. So would ethernet switches. So would SDN. ARP storms would be gone. &quot;IGMP snooping bridges&quot; would be gone. Bridging loops would be gone. Every routing problem would be traceroute-able. And best of all, we could drop 12 bytes (source/dest ethernet addresses) from every ethernet packet, and 18 bytes (source/dest/AP addresses) from every wifi packet. Sure, IPv6 adds an extra 24 bytes of address (vs IPv4), but you're dropping 12 bytes of ethernet, so the added overhead is only 12 bytes - pretty comparable to using two 64-bit IP addresses but having to keep the ethernet header. The idea that we could someday drop ethernet addresses helped to justify the oversized IPv6 addresses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would have been beautiful. Except for one problem: it never happened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Requiem for a dream&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One person at work put it best: &quot;layers are only ever added, never removed.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All this wonderfulness depended on the ability to start over and throw away the legacy cruft we had built up. And that is, unfortunately, pretty much impossible. Even if IPv6 hits 99% penetration, that doesn't mean we'll be rid of IPv4. And if we're not rid of IPv4, we won't be rid of ethernet addresses, or wifi addresses. And if we have to keep the IEEE 802.3 and 802.11 framing standards, we're never going to save those bytes. So we will always need the &quot;IPv6 neighbour discovery&quot; protocol, which is just a more complicated ARP. Even though we no longer have bus networks, we'll always need some kind of simulator for broadcasts, because that's how ARP works. We'll need to keep running a local DHCP server at home so that our obsolete IPv4 light bulbs keep working. We'll keep needing NAT so that our obsolete IPv4 light bulbs can keep reaching the Internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that's not the worst of it. The worst of it is we still need the infinite abomination that is layer 2 bridging, because of one more mistake the IPv6 team &lt;em&gt;forgot to fix&lt;/em&gt;. Unfortunately, while they were blue-skying IPv6 back in the 1990s, they neglected to solve the &quot;mobile IP&quot; problem. As I understand it, the idea was to get IPv6 deployed first - it should only take a few years - and then work on it after IPv4 and MAC addresses had been eliminated, at which time it should be much easier to solve, and meanwhile, nobody really has a &quot;mobile IP&quot; device yet anyway. I mean, what would that even mean, like carrying your laptop around and plugging into a series of one ethernet port after another while you ftp a file? Sounds dumb.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The killer app: mobile IP&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, with a couple more decades of history behind us, now we know a few use cases for carrying around a computer - your phone - and letting it plug into one &lt;strike&gt;ethernet port&lt;/strike&gt; wireless access point after another. We do it all the time. And with LTE, it even mostly works! With wifi, it works sometimes. Good, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not really, because of the Internet's secret shame: all that stuff only works because of layer 2 bridging. Internet routing can't handle mobility - at all. If you move around on an IP network, your IP address changes, and that breaks any connections you have open.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Corporate wifi networks fake it for you, bridging their whole LAN together at layer 2, so that the giant central DHCP server always hands you the same IP address no matter which corporate wifi access point you join, and then gets your packets to you, with at most a few seconds of confusion while the bridge reconfigures. Those newfangled home wifi systems with multiple extenders/repeaters do the same trick. But if you switch from one wifi network to another as you walk down the street - like if there's a &quot;Public Wifi&quot; service in a series of stores - well, too bad. Each of those gives you a new IP address, and each time your IP address changes, you kill all your connections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LTE tries even harder. You keep your IP address (usually an IPv6 address in the case of mobile networks), even if you travel miles and miles and hop between numerous cell towers. How? Well... they typically just tunnel all your traffic back to a central location, where it all gets bridged together (albeit with lots of firewalling) into one super-gigantic virtual layer 2 LAN. And your connections keep going. At the expense of a ton of complexity, and a truly embarrassing amount of extra latency, which they would really like to fix, but it's almost impossible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Making mobile IP actually work&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So okay, this has been a long story, but I managed to extract it from those IETF people eventually. When we got to this point - the problem of mobile IP - I couldn't help but ask. What went wrong? Why can't we make it work?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The answer, it turns out, is surprisingly simple. The great design flaw was in how the famous &quot;4-tuple&quot; (source ip, source port, destination ip, destination port) was defined. We use the 4-tuple to identify a given TCP or UDP session; if a packet has those four fields the same, then it belongs to a given session, and we can deliver it to whatever socket is handling that session. But the 4-tuple crosses two layers: internetwork (layer 3) and transport (layer 4). If, instead, we had identified sessions using &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; layer 4 data, then mobile IP would have worked perfectly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's do a quick example. X port 1111 is talking to Y port 80, so it sends a packet with 4-tuple (X,1111,Y,80). The response comes back with (Y,80,X,1111), and the kernel delivers it to the socket that generated the original packet. When X sends more packets tagged (X,1111,Y,80), then Y delivers them all to the same server socket, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, if X hops IP addresses, it gets a new name, say Q. Now it'll start sending packets with (Q,1111,Y,80). Y has no idea what that means, and throws it away. Meanwhile, if Y sends packets tagged (Y,80,X,1111), they get lost, because there is no longer an X to receive them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine now that we tagged sockets without reference to their IP address. For that to work, we'd need much bigger port numbers (which are currently 16 bits). Let's make them, say, 128 or 256 bits, some kind of unique hash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now X sends out packets to Y with tag (uuid,80). Note, the packets themselves still contain the (X,Y) addressing information, down at layer 3 - that's how they get routed to the right machine in the first place. But the kernel doesn't &lt;em&gt;use&lt;/em&gt; the layer 3 information to decide which socket to deliver to; it just uses the uuid. The destination port (80 in this case) is only needed to initiate a new session, to identify what service you want to connect to, and can be ignored or left out after that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the return direction, Y's kernel caches the fact that packets for (uuid) go to IP address X, which is the address it most recently received (uuid) packets from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now imagine that X changes addresses to Q. It still sends out packets tagged with (uuid,80), to IP address Y, but now those packets come from address Q. On machine Y, it receives the packet and matches it to the socket associated with (uuid), notes that the packets for that socket are now coming from address Q, and updates its cache. Its return packets can now be sent, tagged as (uuid), back to Q instead of X. Everything works! (Modulo some care to prevent connection hijacking by impostors.&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's only one catch: that's not how UDP and TCP work, and it's too late to update them. Updating UDP and TCP would be like updating IPv4 to IPv6; a project that sounded simple, back in the 1990s, but decades later, is less than half accomplished (and the first half was the easy part; the long tail is much harder).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The positive news is we may be able to hack around it with yet another layering violation. If we throw away TCP - it's getting rather old anyway - and instead use QUIC over UDP, then we can just stop using the UDP 4-tuple as a connection identifier at all. Instead, if the UDP port number is the &quot;special mobility layer&quot; port, we unwrap the content, which can be another packet with a proper uuid tag, match it to the right session, and deliver those packets to the right socket.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's even more good news: the experimental QUIC protocol already, at least in theory, has the right packet structure to work like this. It turns out you need unique session identifiers (keys) anyhow if you want to use stateless packet encryption and authentication, which QUIC does. So, perhaps with not much work, QUIC could support transparent roaming. What a world that would be!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At that point, all we'd have to do is eliminate all remaining UDP and TCP from the Internet, and then we would definitely not need layer 2 bridging anymore, for real this time, and then we could get rid of broadcasts and MAC addresses and SDN and DHCP and all that stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then the Internet would be elegant again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Edit 2017-08-16:&lt;/strong&gt; It turns out that nothing in this section requires IPv6. It would work fine with IPv4 and NAT, even roaming across multiple NATs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; Edit 2017-08-15:&lt;/strong&gt; Some people asked what &quot;some care to prevent connection hijacking&quot; might look like. There are various ways to do it, but the simplest would be to do something like the SYN-ACK-SYNACK exchange TCP does at connection startup. If Y just trusts the first packet from the new host Q, then it's too easy for any attacker to take over the X-&amp;gt;Y connection by simply sending a packet to Y from anywhere on the Internet. (Although it's a bit hard to guess which 256-bit uuid to fill in.) But if Y sends back a cookie that Q must receive and process and send back to Y, that ensures that Q is at least a man-in-the-middle and not just an outside attacker (which is all TCP would guarantee anyway). If you're using an encrypted protocol (like QUIC&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;), the handshake can also be protected by your session key.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; Edit 2017-10-24:&lt;/strong&gt; Besides QUIC, there are several other candidates for such a protocol, including &lt;a href=&quot;https://cr.yp.to/papers.html#minimalt&quot;&gt;MinimaLT&lt;/a&gt;. I didn't mention MinimaLT originally because it wasn't part of my original conversation with the IETF people, but I don't mean to imply that QUIC is the only possible option as a roaming-capable TCP replacement. In fact, MinimaLT is the first protocol I heard of that elegantly solved the roaming problem. Future solutions that might get adopted, including by QUIC, will likely be modeled after MinimaLT's solution.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 18:22:04 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>beefhash</dc:creator>
<og:title>The world in which IPv6 was a good design</og:title>
<og:description>Last November I went to an IETF meeting for the first time. The IETF is an interesting place; it seems to be about 1/3 maintenance grunt wo...</og:description>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://apenwarr.ca/log/20170810</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Saudi Arabia tracks runaway women by cellphone IMEI</title>
<link>https://www.businessinsider.com/saudi-arabia-imei-track-runaways-2019-5</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.businessinsider.com/saudi-arabia-imei-track-runaways-2019-5</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Women who flee Saudi Arabia expect to be chased.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;They expect their friends to be interviewed, their social media to be scoured, their passports to be frozen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;They mostly do not expect Saudi government agents to hunt down the old box for their iPhone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;But according to multiple sources who spoke with INSIDER, this is what has been happening in Saudi Arabia's quest to track down the growing number of women who flee the country every year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Cellphone packaging can provide information that could — with the help of spy-grade tracking equipment — trace a Saudi runaway to within a few feet of her new location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;The data point being sought is the cellphone's unique 15-digit International Mobile Equipment Identity. Tracking people with IMEI data is not new but is more usually the preserve of militaries or intelligence services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-source-caption&quot;&gt;A stock photograph showing an IMEI number printed on the box for a Samsung Galaxy. &lt;span class=&quot;image-source&quot; data-e2e-name=&quot;image-source&quot;&gt;Shutterstock&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;The fact that such techniques are being employed shows how seriously Saudi Arabia takes &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.economist.com/middle-east-and-africa/2017/03/16/some-saudi-women-are-secretly-deserting-their-country&quot;&gt;the mass escape of as many as 1,000 women each year&lt;/a&gt;, people &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ce_pss/status/1092796685972058116&quot;&gt;it has said are as much of a national security threat as terrorists&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Four women, all of whom fled in the past two years, told INSIDER about their experience of being tracked from their new homes in the West.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Two women who fled together in early 2019 said Saudi security services came to their family homes after they left and demanded to be shown the packaging of their cellphones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;The refugees, who asked to remain anonymous for fear of reprisals, said Saudi agents told their families that the IMEI number was the key to finding and retrieving them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;A third Saudi woman, who was captured by Saudi agents after fleeing, was also told her IMEI number played a part. INSIDER was told her story by Taleb al-Abdulmohsen, an activist based in Germany, who passed her messages on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-source-caption&quot;&gt;A Saudi woman in Riyadh, Saudi Arabia, in 2017. &lt;span class=&quot;image-source&quot; data-e2e-name=&quot;image-source&quot;&gt;Reuters&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;The woman, apprehended in the ex-Soviet nation of Georgia in 2018, was informed by her Georgian state-funded attorney that Saudi intelligence found her IMEI number. Working with the Georgian police, the attorney said, Saudi officials used it to find her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&quot;The Georgian police tracked you upon request from the Saudi government, using an IMEI that they obtained from the packaging box of your cellphone,&quot; she said, paraphrasing what the lawyer told her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;The woman was taken back to Saudi Arabia, where she has remained since.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;A fourth escapee, who was nearly repatriated after fleeing to Australia, also related her story to INSIDER via al-Abdulmohsen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;She too said Saudi agents found her via her IMEI number. She was able to secure asylum before Saudi officials could arrange for her to be sent back, she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;&quot;&gt;'Trivial' work to find a runaway&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;IMEI numbers are commonly written on the SIM tray or behind the battery pack of a cellphone. On the iPhone 6S and earlier models, it's located on the bottom end on the back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-source-caption&quot;&gt;The IMEI number is often printed in the SIM tray. &lt;span class=&quot;image-source&quot; data-e2e-name=&quot;image-source&quot;&gt;Shutterstock&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Tracking people using an IMEI is almost exclusively a tool used by police, national security, and military bodies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;The US National Security Agency uses IMEI numbers from phones belonging to targets in Afghanistan to direct drone strikes, according to &lt;a href=&quot;https://theintercept.com/drone-papers/the-assassination-complex/&quot;&gt;leaked documents published in October 2015 by The Intercept&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Micah Lee, a computer security engineer and journalist, told INSIDER &quot;it would be trivial for Saudi Arabia, as well as any other country, to track someone's physical location if they know the IMEI number of their target's phone.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Read more:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.insider.com/saudi-arabia-to-break-record-for-beheading-people-in-2019-2019-3&quot;&gt;This chart shows how Saudi Arabia is on course to behead more people than ever before in 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&quot;When cellphones connect to towers, they share their IMEI as well as other unique identifiers, which means that local telecommunications companies in Saudi Arabia know the physical location of every phone in the country, and could be compelled to share this information with the government,&quot; Lee said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;The University of Toronto's Citizen Lab project &lt;a href=&quot;https://citizenlab.ca/2018/10/the-kingdom-came-to-canada-how-saudi-linked-digital-espionage-reached-canadian-soil/&quot;&gt;revealed in May&lt;/a&gt; that three critics of the Saudi government had their cellphones hacked by Saudi intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-source-caption&quot;&gt;Iyad el-Baghdadi, an author who is critical of the Saudi state. &lt;span class=&quot;image-source&quot; data-e2e-name=&quot;image-source&quot;&gt;Reuters&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;One, Omar Abdulaziz, is suing the Israeli security company NSO Group, which he says sold Saudi authorities a phone-hacking program called Pegasus. INSIDER understands that the software does not include IMEI tracking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;An NSO Group spokesman told INSIDER that Pegasus was &quot;not a tool to track asylum seekers or political dissidents.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;&quot;&gt;How fleeing women puncture images of Saudi progress&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Going to such elaborate ends to hack dissidents and track down runaway women contradicts the image of cultural progress often projected by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/mohammed-bin-salman-saudi-prince-net-worth-yacht-private-jet-lifestyle-2019-5&quot;&gt;Saudi Crown Prince Mohammed bin Salman&lt;/a&gt;, the kingdom's de facto ruler.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;The perception that women will be given more rights is a key part of the crown prince's formal plan, dubbed Saudi Vision 2030, to modernize the nation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Among the widely publicized gestures were women &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/ap-saudi-women-are-now-driving-as-longstanding-ban-ends-2018-6&quot;&gt;getting the right to drive in June 2018&lt;/a&gt; and a new law that meant men could &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/2019/01/06/saudi-men-can-no-longer-divorce-wives-without-informing-court/&quot;&gt;no longer divorce their wives without their knowledge&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Read more:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.insider.com/uber-lets-female-drivers-saudi-arabia-block-male-passengers-2019-4&quot;&gt;Uber launched a Saudi Arabia-only feature that lets female drivers avoid taking male passengers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;After &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/category/rahaf-al-qunun?r=US&amp;amp;IR=T&quot;&gt;two high-profile escapes in early 2019&lt;/a&gt;, Saudi Arabia's Presidency of State Security &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ce_pss/status/1092796685972058116&quot;&gt;produced a video in February&lt;/a&gt; likening women who run away to jihadist terrorist operatives working for the likes of the Islamic State.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-source-caption&quot;&gt;An image from a Saudi government video warning that women who run away (depicted in the right panel) are as big a threat to Saudi national security as terrorists. &lt;span class=&quot;image-source&quot; data-e2e-name=&quot;image-source&quot;&gt;MOI&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;2019 has seen a sharp increase in the number of women escaping Saudi Arabia in high-profile circumstances, a phenomenon enabled by social media.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;In January, an 18-year-old named Rahaf Mohammed livestreamed her efforts to flee her family and secure asylum, gaining 114,000 followers and sparking large amounts of media interest in the process. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/saudi-diplomat-jokes-thailand-shouldve-taken-rahaf-al-qunun-phone-after-viral-twitter-campaign-saves-her-2019-1?r=US&amp;amp;IR=T&amp;amp;_ga=2.99287326.1623254030.1560264551-2034880592.1556701637&quot;&gt;She said she feared she would be killed if she was forced back to Saudi Arabia&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;After barricading herself in a hotel room at a Bangkok airport, she ultimately received asylum in Canada.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Her new prominence &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/saudi-diplomat-jokes-thailand-shouldve-taken-rahaf-al-qunun-phone-after-viral-twitter-campaign-saves-her-2019-1?r=US&amp;amp;IR=T&quot;&gt;led the Saudi chargé d'affaires in Bangkok, Abdulelah Al-Shuaibi, to joke&lt;/a&gt; that he wished the Thai police &quot;would've taken her phone instead of her passport.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Many female refugees believe they will either be killed by their families, or imprisoned, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thedailybeast.com/saudi-sisters-escape-to-georgia-and-plead-for-asylum-on-twitter&quot;&gt;if they are captured&lt;/a&gt;. One, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dina_Ali_Lasloom#Whereabouts&quot;&gt;Dina Ali Lasloom&lt;/a&gt;, was captured in Manila in April 2017, has not been seen since she was repatriated against her will.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-source-caption&quot;&gt;The Saudi teenager Rahaf Mohammed at Toronto Pearson International Airport. She called herself &quot;one of the lucky ones&quot; on January 12 after fleeing to Canada. &lt;span class=&quot;image-source&quot; data-e2e-name=&quot;image-source&quot;&gt;Reuters&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;The country of Georgia is the most popular destination for fleeing Saudi women because it does not require them to have a visa to enter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Matthew Hickey, a professional hacker with over 15 years of experience, told INSIDER that women fleeing to Georgia couldn't just switch SIM cards to protect themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Read more:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.insider.com/absher-saudi-website-men-control-women-stop-escape-2019-1&quot;&gt;Saudi Arabia runs a huge, sinister online database of women that men use to track them and stop them from running away&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&quot;Putting a new SIM into a phone will change its IMSI number, but the phone will still have the same IMEI number, so cellphone companies can easily see that these different SIM cards are being used in the same phone,&quot; he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-source-caption&quot;&gt;A woman on the phone in Riyadh in 2013. &lt;span class=&quot;image-source&quot; data-e2e-name=&quot;image-source&quot;&gt;Reuters/Faisal Al Nasser&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&quot;The only way for an individual to avoid this type of tracking is to replace the handset, physically remove and replace a chip to obtain a new IMEI, or use a phone which has a reprogrammable IMEI.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Read more:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.insider.com/saudi-hit-squad-khashoggi-death-reportedly-asked-for-bonus-2019-3&quot;&gt;The Saudi hit squad linked to the Khashoggi murder reportedly asked for a performance-related bonus for torturing and kidnapping so many people&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;A Saudi Ministry of Foreign Affairs spokesman directed a request for comment from INSIDER to the Saudi Embassy in Georgia, which did not respond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Do you know anyone who has tried run away from Saudi Arabia?&lt;/strong&gt; Have you run away yourself? Contact this reporter on wbostock@businessinsider.com or Twitter DM at @billbostockUK. You can also &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/how-to-tip-business-insider-securely-guide-signal-securedrop-2017-6?_ga=2.167981415.739369804.1560159515-866151267.1556781751&quot;&gt;contact Business Insider securely via SecureDrop.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 17:46:20 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>onetimemanytime</dc:creator>
<og:title>Saudi Arabia is hunting down women who flee the country by tracking the IMEI number on their cellphones</og:title>
<og:description>Cellphones are often Saudi women's route to independence. But, INSIDER has learned, Saudi Arabia is hunting women via their phone's unique IMEI code.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.businessinsider.com/saudi-arabia-imei-track-runaways-2019-5</og:url>
<og:image>https://amp.businessinsider.com/images/5d00c2884cf27023926e16ad-1334-667.jpg</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.businessinsider.com/saudi-arabia-imei-track-runaways-2019-5</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>To be great, be good repeatably</title>
<link>https://blog.stephsmith.io/how-to-be-great/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.stephsmith.io/how-to-be-great/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Over the years, we’ve all encountered our fair share of successes and failures. As I’ve acquired more of both under my name, I’ve started to contemplate which experiences were truly “great” and why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly enough, I realized that it was not the sporadic highs that were exceptional, but instead the long hauls; the sequences of events that seemed minimal at each juncture, but compounded into major gains. This led me to think further about what &lt;em&gt;greatness&lt;/em&gt; truly means. I’ve come to learn that it’s not about overnight successes or flashes of excellence, but periods of repeatable habits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Perhaps “great’, is just “good”, but repeatable.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;consider-this&quot;&gt;Consider This&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before stepping into the bulk of this article, I want to clarify two things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Greatness is not instantaneous&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Greatness is earned&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first step in becoming great is recognizing that you’re likely not already great. In fact, it comes from recognizing that there is no such thing as greatness at a specific instance in time. Greatness is instead a reflection of a period of effort, since greatness in a single instance can be reduced to luck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, being “great” is not about being better than someone else. It is about being dependable and disciplined, and ultimately it is earned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many people, in theory, want to be “great”. In fact, each month 1000 people search “how to be great”, 260 people search “how to become perfect”, and 2400 people search “how to be the best” every month, looking for discrete answers on how to get from 0 to 1. Yet, many people in life realistically do not want to put in the effort over a sustained period of time to actually get to 1. They are looking for the “secrets to success” that in many ways, do not exist. You know what brings success? Hard work brings success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So before proceeding forward in this article, I implore each of you to consider that if greatness is truly is a reflection of non-instantaneous, earned effort, ask yourself if that’s the life you’d like to live. Ask yourself whether you’d like to spend your days, weeks, months, and years in a constant uphill battle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you ultimately find that you don’t want to do that, that’s fine! It doesn’t make you less of a person. At least you’ve broken from the holding pattern of thinking you want to do X but not understanding why you haven’t gotten there yet. And if that’s the case, go enjoy your Netflix and chill completely guilt free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that in mind, let’s dive into what truly makes someone “great’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;it-s-hard-to-be-consistent&quot;&gt;It’s Hard to be Consistent&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s a false impression that success or notoriety comes with being flashy. This notion comes from the media focusing on outliers, whether it be events or personalities which diverge from the norm. Not only can this encourage people to aim for notoriety just for the sake of it (think Elizabeth Holmes), but it makes the rest of us believe that correlation (of those outliers) is causation; in other words, success of those individuals is due to their offbeat ways. But here’s another storyline: the most sure and therefore the &lt;em&gt;best&lt;/em&gt; way to “success” is through consistency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Until you work as hard as those you admire, don’t explain away their success as luck.”&lt;/em&gt; - James Clear, Atomic Habits&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be clear, consistency isn’t necessarily the easiest way to success, but one that can be achieved with a higher level of certainty, rather than hoping for a lottery win or someone to “discover” you. Continuous effort is a more thoughtful approach that leads to greatness when the following statements are true:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Inputs are consistent over time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Intentional inputs lead to expected outputs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;consistency&quot;&gt;Consistency&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“No one who can rise before dawn three hundred sixty days a year fails to make his family rich”&lt;/em&gt; - Outliers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a famous saying from Napolean Hill which says, &lt;em&gt;“If you cannot do great things, do small things in a great way”&lt;/em&gt;. I would actually argue the quote should be, &lt;em&gt;“If you cannot do great things, do small things a great number of times”.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you don’t have the opportunity to “do great things”, focus on consistently achieving small wins. These small things in fact do not need to be done in a great way, but a good way, repeatably. In fact, I would advise not to focus on perfection, as it is often the enemy of the successful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s glimmer and hoopla around unpredictability, but in reality, it’s much more difficult and therefore impressive, to be predictably good. For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;It’s easy to wake up whenever you “feel like it”.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It’s hard to stick to a routine of getting up at 6AM.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It’s easy to pivot from side project to side project, focusing on the new shiny object of the month.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It’s hard to stick with a side project for years, many of which may not be profitable for a long while.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It’s easy to give up on someone when you hit a roadblock or the next potential partner becomes available.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It’s hard to be faithful and invest in a relationship for decades.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;We normally set out in life with good intentions. We &lt;em&gt;intend&lt;/em&gt; to set a morning routine or work on a business until its profitable or to “love someone forever”. We imagine that as we invest in something, we will naturally continue to move in the right direction. If anything, things will get easier, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/NQV_7RXfM2ZYDJsT4E4JAaAW2i9KphrB7-fE8XveJlrW-Msf1aIot9ayls-wSCWIroq155Fzdz6vE3d8br71E6Tc5sTQRyhnT0Zb6EJCUoV41B5EoZSczjtWcHo9KV-T9c6s16Cb&quot; class=&quot;kg-image&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;The described trajectory is what we perceive on the left. Predictable, linear, and a direct reflection of effort put in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rarely does success in anything look like that.&lt;/strong&gt; Life is a series of tiny nodes that tend to look more like the right hand side. There two key elements worth calling out in the more realistic graph on the right:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Compounding is always present. The earlier steps in any process will be more strenuous, yet it’s difficult to imagine the potential compounding that comes later on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With the ups, there are always downs. This seems obvious, but we often forget this when we are in periods of down. We quit at these local minimums (the highlighted sections in red above), because we cannot see the next peak right around the corner.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; readability=&quot;7.5923566878981&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;a friend just emailed me this note in response to my 'burn out' video. wanted to share;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;'the addiction to having success is what makes you feel unsuccessful at the times when you're not feeling the immediate dopamine hit of your work 'succeeding' at that precise moment.'&lt;/p&gt;
— Casey Neistat (@Casey) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Casey/status/1093520669286064133?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;February 7, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; readability=&quot;10.448275862069&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;We have lost our ability to appreciate delayed gratification and, some of us who struggle with perfectionism, can either create repeatedly until we ‘get it right’ never truly feeling fulfilled with our work, or, we avoid creating all together in fear of failing.&lt;/p&gt;
— Marcio Novelli (@MarcioNovelli) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/MarcioNovelli/status/1093522120536150017?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;February 7, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The local minima are especially psychologically taxing due to something called the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hedonic_treadmill&quot;&gt;Hedonic treadmill&lt;/a&gt; or hedonic adaptation. Essentially, as someone achieves new successes in various aspects of their lives, their baseline shifts to reflect that new level and therefore, their expectations and desires are re-established as well. There is no net gain in happiness and thus, it becomes even more difficult to stay “level-headed” during these down moments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is exactly why a specific search for success can be problematic and instead of looking for unsustainable shortcuts in life, it’s much more effective (and healthy) to aim for continuous habits that bring you success as a byproduct, not as the end goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“The only way to become excellent is to be endlessly fascinated by doing the same thing over and over. You have to fall in love with boredom.” - Atomic Habits, James Clear&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On your journey to greatness, you need to fall in love with the process which includes many local minima and maxima. Staying consistent and pushing through both of these continuously is what will truly differentiate you from those that are simply “good” and isolate you as one of the few that are “great’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;inputs-outputs&quot;&gt;Inputs → Outputs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second important aspect of achieving greatness is acting with intention. Your actions and results will not always reflect your intentions, but as you move towards “greatness”, you should have a better idea of what inputs actually deliver output. You’ll still make mistakes﹣as we all do﹣but you’ll have a better grasp on what is more likely to work out. For example, your success rate may be 30%, versus someone flying blind with a 5% success rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s look at a simple example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine company X has two sales people. Salesperson A happens to land a $1M deal in his first week. However, he struggles to land anything substantial for the next 6 months. Meanwhile, salesperson B manages to develop a process over the first month, bringing in only $100k which he’s able to scale up and double month over month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After six months, this will be the revenue generated by each party.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.stephsmith.io/content/images/2019/05/image-5.png&quot; class=&quot;kg-image&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;You’re probably thinking…”So what? That’s just a classic example of compounding.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes! That’s exactly the point. The best things in life often aren’t miracles, but well-thought out approaches that are sustainable. The same thing is true with businesses, marriages, and just about anything with repeatable elements. If you invest time into solving for what leads to success continuously, you will reap those benefits for years to come. &lt;em&gt;So even in the least quantifiable situations, reflect back on what could’ve made a previous loss a future win.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider the best companies over time. None of them emerged overnight, nor was there a single inflection point that determined the success or notoriety of these companies. The line of separation between the “great” companies of all time and the “not so great”, is their ability to stand the test of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Would you rather be Juicero that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/juicero&quot;&gt;raised $100M&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2017/09/01/rip-juicero-the-400-venture-backed-juice-machine/&quot;&gt;went bankrupt&lt;/a&gt; within a year of its Series C, or Zoom, which &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/zoom-video-communications/funding_rounds/funding_rounds_list#section-funding-rounds&quot;&gt;took almost 8 years to take on more funding than $30M&lt;/a&gt; and is now one of the most profitable and highly sought after “unicorns” in the valley?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On top of consistency, greatness comes from asking the right questions and iterating to learn what inputs drive favourable outputs, and ideally &lt;strong&gt;why&lt;/strong&gt;. “Greatness” comes from an identified or researched process that when followed, has some degree of certainty in the outcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Moving fast and breaking things” is not a strategy, unless you are clearly defining a process of learning so that in the future, you can “move fast and break less of the same things”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-habit-of-progression&quot;&gt;A Habit of Progression&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“The definition of insanity is doing the same thing over and over again, but expecting different results.”&lt;/em&gt; - Albert Einstein&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understand that in order to achieve the things you want in life, you’ll need to establish a &lt;strong&gt;habit of progression&lt;/strong&gt;. You literally need to become good at being decent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is one thing to clarify: this habit of progression must come with the right inputs. Being consistent with something leading you in the wrong direction, will &lt;em&gt;unsurprisingly&lt;/em&gt; lead you in the wrong direction. So if this is the way you are constantly moving (excluding short periods of local minima), pivot until you determine what the right inputs are. I recently stumbled upon a concept of &lt;a href=&quot;https://jdreyespaez.site/zero-acceleration/&quot;&gt;zero acceleration, but non-zero velocity&lt;/a&gt;, which encapsulates this idea well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before you find the path that you want to double down on, this habit of progression takes the form of iteration. I see many people who are stuck in this stage and feel like they’re moving nowhere. Perhaps they go take a degree for a year and find that wasn’t right. Maybe they do and work for a company for two more and realize that wasn’t right either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re struggling to identify the right path, create more nodes of optimization. For example: if you’re making changes every year, you only have maybe 80 in your entire life to make. Instead, try testing things intentionally every month or even every week. Pilot a lot and then double down when you have found your path towards “good”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may ask, “what makes good, good?”. Ask yourself the question: “If I were to continue this everyday for the next year, would I be in a better place?” If the answer is yes, you have a path towards “good”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you have found your inputs, then you’re in a good place to turn those inputs into the right habits through deliberate practice. Ie: you’ll be in a place to shift from good to great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This process of shifting between iteration and consistency is all part of developing a habit of progression. Once you make this habit your north star, you are no longer dependent on that  “one big break” or that one company to “finally give you a chance”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And finally, if you’re reading this advice and think, “I’ve heard this before”, then ask yourself whether you’ve truly acted on this advice. When is the last time you tried iterated and tried new things? When is the last time you found something &lt;em&gt;good&lt;/em&gt; and then truly stuck to it for years?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;two-steps-out&quot;&gt;Two Steps Out&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While you’re moving towards “greatness”, keep in mind that it will likely happen slowly and that’s okay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I think about the growth trajectory of my life and similarly, anyone that I’ve been close with, changes have always happened slowly. Whether it was a close family member falling into deep mental illness or friends building businesses to near-unicorn valuations, nothing ever happened overnight. Even more notably, no one would have ever expected those outcomes years prior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the grand scheme of things, I think it’s because you can ever see two steps out. What do I mean by that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Say that in life there are 100 tiers of happiness. Of course, life is more complicated and dynamic than this view, but bear with me for a minute. Let’s say that you’re on “Tier 57”.  You may be able to see Tier 58 and 59. I think it’s nearly impossible to fully empathize or even comprehend levels 21 and similarly 89, unless of course you’ve been there before. Even if you have, it becomes a distant memory that’s difficult to fully internalize. Remember, the Hedonic treadmill is almost always at play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.stephsmith.io/content/images/2019/06/image-3.png&quot; class=&quot;kg-image&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Why is this important? Everyone wishes to elevate their life and in association, their happiness. For us to reach these top tiers, we cannot hope for this to &lt;em&gt;just happen&lt;/em&gt;. We must expose ourselves to various inputs that may lead to better outputs, and train ourselves to recognize what’s working.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that’s exactly the point of continuous improvement. Since I believe that we can only ever see “two levels out”, we can’t discover these new inputs without slow, but repeatable change. We must explore 58 and then 59 and then all of a sudden, 61 will appear as this new array of opportunity we had never considered before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a more tangible example, when I started working in an office, I simply couldn’t fully visualize remote work. I knew it existed, but I couldn’t truly imagine this new way of living. And even once I started working remotely, it took years of iteration and pivoting to expand into the lifestyle that I now call my own. And of course, there’s probably many more tiers to explore that I simply haven’t visualized yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“To exist is to change, to change is to mature, to mature is to go on creating oneself endlessly.” - Henri Bergson&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s precisely why it’s good to continuously surround yourself with new environments and people, and to focus on slow but steady compounding. I think this tweet from Michael Nielson captures what I’m trying to communicate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; readability=&quot;7.5057915057915&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Since reading this 6 months ago, I've come to think it's half a dozen of the best paragraphs I've ever read on how to get much, much better at anything: (by @autotrnslucence ) &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/dMoEwHtjfU&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/dMoEwHtjfU&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
— michael_nielsen (@michael_nielsen) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/michael_nielsen/status/1074150124169773056?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;December 16, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Try to remind yourself as you’re iterating, that there are new levels that you can’t even conceptualize right now. Regardless of how far along you are, know that these new levels of success will appear as you work towards the next one or two. And soon enough, you’ll be 10 levels ahead of what you could have ever imagined.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;stop-speculating&quot;&gt;Stop Speculating&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“I have seen impractical and improbable things accomplished. All it took to achieve improbable things was an optimistic attitude and a refusal to give up.” - The Woman Who Smashed Codes&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;James Clear, from Atomic Habits mentions a study in which students in Jerrey Uelsmann’s University of Florida photography class were divided into two groups. The first group would be the “quantity” group, while the second would be the “quality” group. The former would be judged solely on the number of photographs they submitted, while the latter would be graded on the excellence of a single image.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The interesting outcome of the experiment was that the best photos were produced not by the quality group, but by the quantity group. Why? While the quality group spent their time speculating what perfection may have been, the quantity group took action in testing what was truly great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“It is easy to get bogged down trying to find the optimal plan for change: the fastest way to lose weight, the best program to build muscle, the perfect idea for a side hustle. We are so focused on figuring out the best approach that we never get around to taking action” - James Clear, Atomic Habits&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other words, the “search” for greatness is often misguided, perhaps because what we imagine to be great, is in fact not that great at all. Instead of speculating what may make you great, get out there and start &lt;strong&gt;doing&lt;/strong&gt;. Do not look for perfection or even greatness, but instead signs of “good” and start making tangible progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; readability=&quot;15.288888888889&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Building products, writing, and painting are not mental excercises, they are physical ones.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reading to improve is like watching someone else workout – it does almost nothing for you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To run better, run.&lt;br/&gt;To paint better, paint.&lt;br/&gt;To write better, write.&lt;br/&gt;To build better, build.&lt;/p&gt;
— Sahil Lavingia (@shl) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/shl/status/1118224158020685824?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;April 16, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-do-you-become-great&quot;&gt;How Do You Become Great?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So if you’re still asking the question, “How do I become great in life?”, I would ask you to reframe the question as “How do I become good in life” or even “How do I become decent” and focus on developing those habits to repeat over time. Transform these habits to be your baseline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember, there is no “magic moment” when you become great, so if you are looking for your path towards greatness, stop looking for “greatness” and consider that your most probable path there is just to focus on what’s good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have an understanding of what inputs equal favourable outputs then continue moving in that direction. As you move past the local minima and maxima, you’ll soon be beating out the 50% that quit at X time, the 75% that quit at Y time, and the 90% that quit at Z time. Soon enough, you’ll be the great one that was once just “good” among the rest, but stuck with it and learned something along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In being consistent over time, you &lt;strong&gt;become&lt;/strong&gt; the outlier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember, &lt;strong&gt;great is just good, but repeatable.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;This article was originally inspired by me trying to more deeply understand what “made people great’, but ended up being a dive into some of the psychology I’ve been experiencing more recently. Over the last few months, I think I’ve been on one of my local minimums in terms of direct “success”, but in writing this I feel motivated to keep pushing to my next local maximum, with the understanding that there will be many more of both moving forward.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested in learning more about habit building and long-term progression, I would recommend the following books:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Power-Habit-What-Life-Business-ebook/dp/B00564GPKY/ref=tmm_kin_swatch_0?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=&amp;amp;sr=&quot;&gt;Power of Habit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Atomic-Habits-Proven-Build-Break/dp/0735211299&quot;&gt;Atomic Habits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Outliers-The-Story-of-Success/dp/B001LNK9C4/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1541756578&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=outliers&quot;&gt;Outliers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;PS: Come say hello &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/stephsmithio/status/1138816442336284672&quot;&gt;on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 17:46:05 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>stephsmithio</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>How to Be Great? Just be Good, Repeatably</og:title>
<og:description>A thought piece on what it takes to truly be great and what that even means in the first place.</og:description>
<og:url>https://blog.stephsmith.io/how-to-be-great/</og:url>
<og:image>https://blog.stephsmith.io/content/images/2019/06/Screen-Shot-2019-06-01-at-6.19.20-PM-3.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.stephsmith.io/how-to-be-great/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Privacy Policies Are an Incomprehensible Disaster</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2019/06/12/opinion/facebook-google-privacy-policies.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2019/06/12/opinion/facebook-google-privacy-policies.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;This policy describes the information we process to support Facebook, Instagram, Messenger and other products and features offered by Facebook (Facebook Products or Products). You can find additional tools and information in the Facebook Settings and Instagram Settings. Return to top What kinds of information do we collect? To provide the Facebook Products, we must process information about you. The types of information we collect depend on how you use our Products. You can learn how to access and delete information we collect by visiting the Facebook Settings and Instagram Settings. Things you and others do and provide. Information and content you provide. We collect the content, communications and other information you provide when you use our Products, including when you sign up for an account, create or share content, and message or communicate with others. This can include information in or about the content you provide (like metadata), such as the location of a photo or the date a file was created. It can also include what you see through features we provide, such as our camera, so we can do things like suggest masks and filters that you might like, or give you tips on using camera formats. Our systems automatically process content and communications you and others provide to analyze context and what's in them for the purposes described below. Learn more about how you can control who can see the things you share. Data with special protections: You can choose to provide information in your Facebook profile fields or Life Events about your religious views, political views, who y(such as racial or ethnic origin, philosophical beliefs or trade union membership) could be subject to special protections under the laws of your country. Networks and connections. We collect information about the people, Pages, accounts, hashtags and groups you are connected to and how you interact with them across our Products, such as people you communicate with the most or groups you are part of. We also collect contact information if you choose to upload, sync or import it from a device (such as an address book or call log or SMS log history), which we use for things like helping you and others find people you may know and for the other purposes listed below. Your usage. We collect information about how you use our Products, such as the types of content you view or engage with; the features you use; the actions you take; the people or accounts you interact with; and the time, frequency and duration of your activities. For example, we log when you're using and have last used our Products, and what posts, videos and other content you view on our Products. We also collect information about how you use features like our camera. Information about transactions made on our Products. If you use our Products for purchases or other financial transactions (such as when you make a purchase in a game or make a donation), we collect information about the purchase or transaction. This includes payment information, such as your credit or debit card number and other card information; other account and authentication information; and billing, shipping and contact details. Things others do and information they provide about you. We also receive and analyze content, communications and information that other people provide when they use our Products. This can include information about you, such as when others share or comment on a photo of you, send a message to you, or upload, sync or import your contact information. Device Information As described below, we collect information from and about the computers, phones, connected TVs and other web-connected devices you use that integrate with our Products, and we combine this information across different devices you use. For example, we use information collected about your use of our Products on your phone to better personalize the content (including ads) or features you see when you use our Products on another device, such as your laptop or tablet, or to measure whether you took an action in response to an ad we showed you on your phone on a different device. Information we obtain from these devices includes: Device attributes: information such as the operating system, hardware and software versions, battery level, signal strength, available storage space, browser type, app and file names and types, and plugins. Device operations: information about operations and behaviors performed on the device, such as whether a window is foregrounded or backgrounded, or mouse movements (which can help distinguish humans from bots). Identifiers: unique identifiers, device IDs, and other identifiers, such as from games, apps or accounts you use, and Family Device IDs (or other identifiers unique to Facebook Company Products associated with the same device or account). Device signals: Bluetooth signals, and information about nearby Wi-Fi access points, beacons, and cell towers. Data from device settings: information you allow us to receive through device settings you turn on, such as access to your GPS location, camera or photos. Network and connections: information such as the name of your mobile operator or ISP, language, time zone, mobile phone number, IP address, connection speed and, in some cases, information about other devices that are nearby or on your network, so we can do things like help you stream a video from your phone to your TV. Cookie data: data from cookies stored on your device, including cookie IDs and settings. Learn more about how we use cookies in the Facebook Cookies Policy and Instagram Cookies Policy. Information from partners. Advertisers, app developers, and publishers can send us information through Facebook Business Tools they use, including our social plug-ins (such as the Like button), Facebook Login, our APIs and SDKs, or the Facebook pixel. These partners provide information about your activities off Facebook—including information about your device, websites you visit, purchases you make, the ads you see, and how you use their services—whether or not you have a Facebook account or are logged into Facebook. For example, a game developer could use our API to tell us what games you play, or a business could tell us about a purchase you made in its store. We also receive information about your online and offline actions and purchases from third-party data providers who have the rights to provide us with your information. Partners receive your data when you visit or use their services or through third parties they work with. We require each of these partners to have lawful rights to collect, use and share your data before providing any data to us. Learn more about the types of partners we receive data from. To learn more about how we use cookies in connection with Facebook Business Tools, review the Facebook Cookies Policy and Instagram Cookies Policy. Return to top How do we use this information? We use the information we have (subject to choices you make) as described below and to provide and support the Facebook Products and related services described in the Facebook Terms and Instagram Terms. Here's how: Provide, personalize and improve our Products. We use the information we have to deliver our Products, including to personalize features and content (including your News Feed, Instagram Feed, Instagram Stories and ads) and make suggestions for you (such as groups or events you may be interested in or topics you may want to follow) on and off our Products. To create personalized Products that are unique and relevant to you, we use your connections, preferences, interests and activities based on the data we collect and learn from you and others (including any data with special protections you choose to provide); how you use and interact with our Products; and the people, places, or things you're connected to and interested in on and off our Products. Learn more about how we use information about you to personalize your Facebook and Instagram experience, including features, content and recommendations in Facebook Products; you can also learn more about how we choose the ads that you see. Information across Facebook Products and devices: We connect information about your activities on different Facebook Products and devices to provide a more tailored and consistent experience on all Facebook Products you use, wherever you use them. For example, we can suggest that you join a group on Facebook that includes people you follow on Instagram or communicate with using Messenger. We can also make your experience more seamless, for example, by automatically filling in your registration information (such as your phone number) from one Facebook Product when you sign up for an account on a different Product. Location-related information: We use location-related information-such as your current location, where you live, the places you like to go, and the businesses and people you're near-to provide, personalize and improve our Products, including ads, for you and others. Location-related information can be based on things like precise device location (if you've allowed us to collect it), IP addresses, and information from your and others' use of Facebook Products (such as check-ins or events you attend). Product research and development: We use the information we have to develop, test and improve our Products, including by conducting surveys and research, and testing and troubleshooting new products and features. Face recognition: If you have it turned on, we use face recognition technology to recognize you in photos, videos and camera experiences. The face-recognition templates we create may constitute data with special protections under the laws of your country. Learn more about how we use face recognition technology, or control our use of this technology in Facebook Settings. If we introduce face-recognition technology to your Instagram experience, we will let you know first, and you will have control over whether we use this technology for you. Ads and other sponsored content: We use the information we have about you-including information about your interests, actions and connections-to select and personalize ads, offers and other sponsored content that we show you. Learn more about how we select and personalize ads, and your choices over the data we use to select ads and other sponsored content for you in the Facebook Settings and Instagram Settings. Provide measurement, analytics, and other business services. We use the information we have (including your activity off our Products, such as the websites you visit and ads you see) to help advertisers and other partners measure the effectiveness and distribution of their ads and services, and understand the types of people who use their services and how people interact with their websites, apps, and services. Learn how we share information with these partners. Promote safety, integrity and security. We use the information we have to verify accounts and activity, combat harmful conduct, detect and prevent spam and other bad experiences, maintain the integrity of our Products, and promote safety and security on and off of Facebook Products. For example, we use data we have to investigate suspicious activity or violations of our terms or policies, or to detect when someone needs help. To learn more, visit the Facebook Security Help Center and Instagram Security Tips. Communicate with you. We use the information we have to send you marketing communications, communicate with you about our Products, and let you know about our policies and terms. We also use your information to respond to you when you contact us. Research and innovate for social good. We use the information we have (including from research partners we collaborate with) to conduct and support research and innovation on topics of general social welfare, technological advancement, public interest, health and well-being. For example, we analyze information we have about migration patterns during crises to aid relief efforts. Learn more about our research programs. Return to top How is this information shared? Your information is shared with others in the following ways: Sharing on Facebook Products People and accounts you share and communicate with When you share and communicate using our Products, you choose the audience for what you share. For example, when you post on Facebook, you select the audience for the post, such as a group, all of your friends, the public, or a customized list of people. Similarly, when you use Messenger or Instagram to communicate with people or businesses, those people and businesses can see the content you send. Your network can also see actions you have taken on our Products, including engagement with ads and sponsored content. We also let other accounts see who has viewed their Facebook or Instagram Stories. Public information can be seen by anyone, on or off our Products, including if they don't have an account. This includes your Instagram username; any information you share with a public audience; information in your public profile on Facebook; and content you share on a Facebook Page, public Instagram account or any other public forum, such as Facebook Marketplace. You, other people using Facebook and Instagram, and we can provide access to or send public information to anyone on or off our Products, including in other Facebook Company Products, in search results, or through tools and APIs. Public information can also be seen, accessed, reshared or downloaded through third-party services such as search engines, APIs, and offline media such as TV, and by apps, websites and other services that integrate with our Products. Learn more about what information is public and how to control your visibility on Facebook and Instagram. Content others share or reshare about you You should consider who you choose to share with, because people who can see your activity on our Products can choose to share it with others on and off our Products, including people and businesses outside the audience you shared with. For example, when you share a post or send a message to specific friends or accounts, they can download, screenshot, or reshare that content to others across or off our Products, in person or in virtual reality experiences such as Facebook Spaces. Also, when you comment on someone else's post or react to their content, your comment or reaction is visible to anyone who can see the other person's content, and that person can change the audience later. People can also use our Products to create and share content about you with the audience they choose. For example, people can share a photo of you in a Story, mention or tag you at a location in a post, or share information about you in their posts or messages. If you are uncomfortable with what others have shared about you on our Products, you can learn how to report the content. Information about your active status or presence on our Products. People in your networks can see signals telling them whether you are active on our Products, including whether you are currently active on Instagram, Messenger or Facebook, or when you last used our Products. Apps, websites, and third-party integrations on or using our Products. When you choose to use third-party apps, websites, or other services that use, or are integrated with, our Products, they can receive information about what you post or share.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 16:28:17 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>tysone</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2019/06/12/opinion/facebook-google-privacy-policies.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Opinion | We Read 150 Privacy Policies. They Were an Incomprehensible Disaster.</og:title>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/06/12/opinion/navarro-copy/navarro-copy-facebookJumbo-v4.png</og:image>
<og:description>The average policy took 18 minutes to finish and required a college-level reading ability.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2019/06/12/opinion/facebook-google-privacy-policies.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Google Photos will stop syncing to Drive</title>
<link>https://gsuiteupdates.googleblog.com/2019/06/google-photos-drive-sync-stopping.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://gsuiteupdates.googleblog.com/2019/06/google-photos-drive-sync-stopping.html</guid>
<description></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 16:08:30 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>vanburen</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Google Photos will stop syncing to Drive on July 10, 2019</og:title>
<og:image>http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-7bZ5EziliZQ/VynIS9F7OAI/AAAAAAAASQ0/BJFntXCAntstZe6hQuo5KTrhi5Dyz9yHgCK4B/s1600/googlelogo_color_200x200.png</og:image>
<og:url>https://gsuiteupdates.googleblog.com/2019/06/google-photos-drive-sync-stopping.html</og:url>
<og:description> What’s changing Starting on July 10, 2019, Google Photos will no longer sync to Google Drive. From that date forward, if you add or delet...</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://gsuiteupdates.googleblog.com/2019/06/google-photos-drive-sync-stopping.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Facebook Emails Could Show Zuckerberg Knew of Questionable Privacy Practices</title>
<link>https://www.wsj.com/articles/facebook-worries-emails-could-show-zuckerberg-knew-of-questionable-privacy-practices-11560353829?mod=rsswn</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.wsj.com/articles/facebook-worries-emails-could-show-zuckerberg-knew-of-questionable-privacy-practices-11560353829?mod=rsswn</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;is-lead-inset&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div data-layout=&quot;header&amp;#10;              &quot; data-layout-mobile=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;&amp;#10;        media-object&amp;#10;        type-InsetMediaIllustration&amp;#10;          header&amp;#10;  article__inset&amp;#10;        article__inset--type-InsetMediaIllustration&amp;#10;          article__inset--lead&amp;#10;  &quot;&gt;
      
      
          
    &lt;div class=&quot;media-object-image enlarge-image renoImageFormat- img-header article__inset__image&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/ImageObject&quot;&gt;
    
      
      &lt;div data-mobile-ratio=&quot;66.66666666666666%&quot; data-layout-ratio=&quot;66.66666666666666%&quot; data-subtype=&quot;photo&quot; class=&quot;image-container  responsive-media article__inset__image__image&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img srcset=&quot;https://images.wsj.net/im-81405?width=140&amp;amp;aspect_ratio=1.5 140w,&amp;#10;https://images.wsj.net/im-81405?width=540&amp;amp;aspect_ratio=1.5 540w,&amp;#10;https://images.wsj.net/im-81405?width=620&amp;amp;aspect_ratio=1.5 620w,&amp;#10;https://images.wsj.net/im-81405?width=700&amp;amp;aspect_ratio=1.5 700w,&amp;#10;https://images.wsj.net/im-81405?width=860&amp;amp;aspect_ratio=1.5 860w,&amp;#10;https://images.wsj.net/im-81405?width=1260&amp;amp;aspect_ratio=1.5 1260w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 140px) 100px,&amp;#10;(max-width: 540px) 500px,&amp;#10;(max-width: 620px) 580px,&amp;#10;(max-width: 700px) 660px,&amp;#10;(max-width: 860px) 820px,&amp;#10;1260px&quot; src=&quot;https://images.wsj.net/im-81405?width=620&amp;amp;aspect_ratio=1.5&quot; data-enlarge=&quot;https://images.wsj.net/im-81405?width=1260&amp;amp;aspect_ratio=1.5&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Facebook CEO Mark Zuckerberg making his keynote speech at a developers’ conference in San Jose,...&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
      &lt;div class=&quot;wsj-article-caption article__inset__image__caption&quot; itemprop=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;
          &lt;span class=&quot;wsj-article-caption-content&quot;&gt;Facebook CEO Mark Zuckerberg making his keynote speech at a developers’ conference in San Jose, Calif., in April. &lt;/span&gt;
          &lt;span class=&quot;wsj-article-credit article__inset__image__caption__credit&quot; itemprop=&quot;creator&quot;&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;wsj-article-credit-tag&quot;&gt;
              Photo: 
            &lt;/span&gt;
        stephen lam/Reuters
          &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      &lt;/div&gt; 
    &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;clearfix byline-wrap&quot;&gt;


      
      &lt;div class=&quot;byline article__byline&quot;&gt;
      
      
          &lt;span&gt;By&lt;/span&gt;
      
                &lt;div class=&quot;author mobile-scrim hasMenu&quot; data-scrim=&quot;{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;author&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;header&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;John D. McKinnon&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;subhead&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;The Wall Street Journal&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;list&amp;quot;:[{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;icon&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;bio&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.wsj.com/news/author/8117&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Biography&amp;quot;},{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;icon&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;twitter&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://twitter.com/johndmckinnon&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;@johndmckinnon&amp;quot;},{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;icon&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;email&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;mailto:John.McKinnon@wsj.com&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;John.McKinnon@wsj.com&amp;quot;}]}&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemprop=&quot;author&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/Person&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;span class=&quot;name&quot; itemprop=&quot;name&quot;&gt;John D. McKinnon&lt;/span&gt;, 
                    &lt;/div&gt;

                &lt;div class=&quot;author mobile-scrim hasMenu&quot; data-scrim=&quot;{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;author&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;header&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Emily Glazer&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;subhead&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;The Wall Street Journal&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;list&amp;quot;:[{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;icon&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;bio&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.wsj.com/news/author/7265&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Biography&amp;quot;},{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;icon&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;twitter&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://twitter.com/EmilyGlazerWSJ&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;@EmilyGlazerWSJ&amp;quot;},{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;icon&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;email&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;mailto:Emily.Glazer@wsj.com&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Emily.Glazer@wsj.com&amp;quot;}]}&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemprop=&quot;author&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/Person&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;span class=&quot;name&quot; itemprop=&quot;name&quot;&gt;Emily Glazer&lt;/span&gt;, 
                    &lt;/div&gt;

                &lt;div class=&quot;author mobile-scrim hasMenu&quot; data-scrim=&quot;{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;author&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;header&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Deepa Seetharaman&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;subhead&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;The Wall Street Journal&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;list&amp;quot;:[{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;icon&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;bio&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.wsj.com/news/author/8237&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Biography&amp;quot;},{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;icon&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;twitter&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://twitter.com/dseetharaman&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;@dseetharaman&amp;quot;},{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;icon&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;facebook&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://facebook.com/deepa.seetharaman&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;deepa.seetharaman&amp;quot;},{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;icon&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;email&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;mailto:deepa.seetharaman@wsj.com&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;deepa.seetharaman@wsj.com&amp;quot;}]}&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemprop=&quot;author&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/Person&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;span class=&quot;name&quot; itemprop=&quot;name&quot;&gt;Deepa Seetharaman&lt;/span&gt; and 
                    &lt;/div&gt;

                &lt;div class=&quot;author mobile-scrim hasMenu&quot; data-scrim=&quot;{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;author&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;header&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Jeff Horwitz&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;subhead&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;The Wall Street Journal&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;list&amp;quot;:[{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;icon&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;bio&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.wsj.com/news/author/8787&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Biography&amp;quot;},{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;icon&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;email&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;mailto:jeff.horwitz@wsj.com&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;jeff.horwitz@wsj.com&amp;quot;}]}&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemprop=&quot;author&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/Person&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;span class=&quot;name&quot; itemprop=&quot;name&quot;&gt;Jeff Horwitz&lt;/span&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;

      &lt;/div&gt;
      
      &lt;time class=&quot;timestamp article__timestamp flexbox__flex--1&quot;&gt;
        Updated June 12, 2019 1:40 p.m. ET
      &lt;/time&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

  

  &lt;div class=&quot;article-content &quot;&gt;

      &lt;p&gt;






            &lt;a href=&quot;https://quotes.wsj.com/FB&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;company-name-type&quot;&gt; Inc.&lt;/span&gt;

      &lt;a href=&quot;https://quotes.wsj.com/FB?mod=chiclets&quot; class=&quot;media-object-chiclet down &quot; data-channel=&quot;/zigman2/quotes/205064656/composite&quot; data-symbol=&quot;FB&quot; data-changepercent=&quot;-1.72&quot;&gt;
        FB &lt;span&gt;-1.72%&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;

      uncovered emails that appear to connect Chief Executive Mark Zuckerberg to potentially problematic privacy practices at the company, according to people familiar with the matter.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;div class=&quot;paywall&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Within the company, the unearthing of the emails in the process of responding to a continuing federal privacy investigation has raised concerns that they would be harmful to Facebook—at least from a public-relations standpoint—if they were to become public, one of the people said.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;The potential impact of the internal emails has been a factor in the tech giant’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/facebook-privacy-settlement-delayed-by-ftc-split-11558725423?mod=article_inline&quot; class=&quot;icon none&quot;&gt;desire to reach a speedy settlement&lt;/a&gt; of the investigation by the Federal Trade Commission, one of the people said. Facebook is operating under a 2012 consent decree with the agency related to privacy, and the emails sent around that time suggest that Mr. Zuckerberg and other senior executives didn’t make compliance with the FTC order a priority, the people said.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;It couldn’t be determined exactly what emails the agency has requested and how many of them relate to Mr. Zuckerberg.&lt;/p&gt;






      &lt;div data-layout=&quot;wrap&amp;#10;              &quot; data-layout-mobile=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;&amp;#10;        media-object&amp;#10;        type-InsetMediaIllustration&amp;#10;          wrap&amp;#10;    scope-web|mobileapps&amp;#10;  article__inset&amp;#10;        article__inset--type-InsetMediaIllustration&amp;#10;            article__inset--wrap&amp;#10;  &quot;&gt;
      
      
          
    &lt;div class=&quot;media-object-image enlarge-image renoImageFormat- img-wrap article__inset__image&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/ImageObject&quot;&gt;
    
      
      &lt;div data-mobile-ratio=&quot;66.66666666666666%&quot; data-layout-ratio=&quot;66.66666666666666%&quot; data-subtype=&quot;photo&quot; class=&quot;image-container  responsive-media article__inset__image__image&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img srcset=&quot;https://images.wsj.net/im-81407?width=140&amp;amp;aspect_ratio=1.5 140w,&amp;#10;https://images.wsj.net/im-81407?width=540&amp;amp;aspect_ratio=1.5 540w,&amp;#10;https://images.wsj.net/im-81407?width=620&amp;amp;aspect_ratio=1.5 620w,&amp;#10;https://images.wsj.net/im-81407?width=700&amp;amp;aspect_ratio=1.5 700w,&amp;#10;https://images.wsj.net/im-81407?width=860&amp;amp;aspect_ratio=1.5 860w,&amp;#10;https://images.wsj.net/im-81407?width=1260&amp;amp;aspect_ratio=1.5 1260w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 140px) 100px,&amp;#10;(max-width: 540px) 500px,&amp;#10;(max-width: 620px) 580px,&amp;#10;(max-width: 700px) 660px,&amp;#10;(max-width: 860px) 820px,&amp;#10;1260px&quot; src=&quot;https://images.wsj.net/im-81407?width=620&amp;amp;aspect_ratio=1.5&quot; data-enlarge=&quot;https://images.wsj.net/im-81407?width=1260&amp;amp;aspect_ratio=1.5&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Mr. Zuckerberg testifying in April 2018 on Capitol Hill regarding Facebook’s use and protection of...&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
      &lt;div class=&quot;wsj-article-caption article__inset__image__caption&quot; itemprop=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;
          &lt;span class=&quot;wsj-article-caption-content&quot;&gt;Mr. Zuckerberg testifying in April 2018 on Capitol Hill regarding Facebook’s use and protection of user data.&lt;/span&gt;
          &lt;span class=&quot;wsj-article-credit article__inset__image__caption__credit&quot; itemprop=&quot;creator&quot;&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;wsj-article-credit-tag&quot;&gt;
              Photo: 
            &lt;/span&gt;
        aaron bernstein/Reuters
          &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      &lt;/div&gt; 




      &lt;p&gt;The FTC investigation began more than a year ago after reports that personal data of tens of millions of Facebook users improperly wound up in the hands of Cambridge Analytica, a data firm that worked on President Trump’s 2016 campaign. The FTC is investigating whether that lapse violated the 2012 consent decree with the agency in which Facebook agreed to better protect user privacy. Since the Cambridge Analytica affair, other privacy missteps have come to light, adding to Facebook’s headaches.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;Facebook has been eager to strike a deal with the FTC and put the Cambridge Analytica scandal behind it. The firm said in April it was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/facebook-sets-aside-3-billion-to-cover-expected-ftc-fine-11556137113?mod=article_inline&quot; class=&quot;icon none&quot;&gt;expecting to pay up to $5 billion&lt;/a&gt; as part of an accord with the agency.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;“We have fully cooperated with the FTC’s investigation to date and provided tens of thousands of documents, emails and files. We are continuing to work with them and hope to bring this matter to an appropriate resolution,” a Facebook spokesperson said on Tuesday in a statement. On Wednesday, after publication of this article, the company sent an additional statement, saying: “At no point did Mark or any other Facebook employee knowingly violate the company’s obligations under the FTC consent order nor do any emails exist that indicate they did.” &lt;/p&gt;






       




      &lt;p&gt;It couldn’t be determined whether any of the emails—which have been described by people familiar with them but not reviewed by The Wall Street Journal—reveal practices that violated the 2012 accord. Any evidence that Mr. Zuckerberg was directly involved in a potential failure on Facebook’s part to honor the terms of its consent decree with the FTC could complicate efforts on both sides to resolve the matter.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;At least some internal emails already provided to the agency show Facebook grappling with gray areas in how it should address privacy under the consent order, with Mr. Zuckerberg closely involved, according to people familiar with the messages.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;In one email exchange from April 2012 that has caught regulators’ attention, according to a person familiar with the matter, Mr. Zuckerberg asked employees about an app that claimed to have built a database stocked with information about tens of millions of Facebook users. The developer had the ability to display that user information to others on its own site, regardless of those users’ privacy settings on Facebook, the person said.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;Mr. Zuckerberg wanted to know if such extensive data collection was possible and if Facebook should do anything to stop developers from displaying that data, the person said.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;Another employee responded to Mr. Zuckerberg’s question, saying it was possible and many developers do the same thing but adding it was a complicated issue, the person said.&lt;/p&gt;






      &lt;div data-layout=&quot;wrap&amp;#10;              &quot; data-layout-mobile=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;&amp;#10;        media-object&amp;#10;        type-InsetRichText&amp;#10;          wrap&amp;#10;    scope-web&amp;#10;  article__inset&amp;#10;        article__inset--type-InsetRichText&amp;#10;            article__inset--wrap&amp;#10;  &quot;&gt;
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
          &lt;div class=&quot;media-object-rich-text&quot;&gt;
    	

&lt;h4&gt;Share Your Thoughts&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;p&gt;Do you think Facebook is committed to protecting user privacy? Why or why not? Join the conversation below. &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      &lt;/div&gt; 




      &lt;p&gt;The discussion continued without Mr. Zuckerberg or anyone else suggesting by email that the company investigate how many other apps were stockpiling user data, the person said. Eventually Facebook suspended the app in question, the person said, adding that it didn’t move aggressively to address the broader problem. &lt;/p&gt;




      




      &lt;p&gt;At the time, Facebook executives were largely focused on increasing the company’s user base and adding advertisers, and appeared to be less diligent about enforcing its data-use rules, developers and former employees have said. The company had repeatedly said it was too slow to react to privacy and security issues. &lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;That email exchange occurred after the FTC’s consent decree had been announced but before it went into effect. The decree says Facebook must honor a user’s privacy settings and not share data without a user’s explicit permission. If it had been in effect at the time, the stockpiling of such user data would potentially have violated it. Mr. Zuckerberg’s message seemed to indicate he was aware of that, according to the person who was familiar with the exchange.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;FTC staffers have been exploring the episode as part of the investigation, the person said.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;A multibillion-dollar civil penalty would be a record for the FTC, but the agency is under pressure from some lawmakers to extract more punitive terms or litigate the matter, since even such a large financial penalty would inflict little pain on the tech giant.&lt;/p&gt;






      &lt;div data-layout=&quot;header&amp;#10;              &quot; data-layout-mobile=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;&amp;#10;        media-object&amp;#10;        type-InsetMediaVideo&amp;#10;          header&amp;#10;    scope-web|mobileapps&amp;#10;  article__inset&amp;#10;        article__inset--type-InsetMediaVideo&amp;#10;            article__inset--header&amp;#10;  &quot;&gt;
      
      
      
          &lt;div class=&quot;media-object-video article__inset__video media-object-video--standard&quot;&gt;
      
  
    &lt;div class=&quot;wsj-article-caption article__inset__video__caption&quot;&gt;
            Facebook’s revenue rose, year on year, 30% in the fourth quarter. WSJ’s Jason Bellini explains why the social network is beating analyst expectations and posting profits amidst all the bad press. Photo illustration: Laura Kammermann (Originally published Jan. 30, 2019)
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      &lt;/div&gt; 




      &lt;p&gt;Some FTC officials have debated whether to name Mr. Zuckerberg as a respondent in the complaint that would be filed by the agency as part of a settlement. If there are documents suggesting Facebook and Mr. Zuckerberg specifically didn’t take regulators seriously, that could complicate those discussions. There is no indication that any of the documents turned over to the FTC show that.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;Facebook has vigorously opposed any efforts to hold Mr. Zuckerberg personally liable as part of a settlement, according to people familiar with the matter.&lt;/p&gt;






      &lt;div data-layout=&quot;wrap&amp;#10;              &quot; data-layout-mobile=&quot;inline&quot; class=&quot;&amp;#10;        media-object&amp;#10;        type-InsetNewsletterSignup&amp;#10;          wrap&amp;#10;    scope-web|mobileapps&amp;#10;  article__inset&amp;#10;        article__inset--type-InsetNewsletterSignup&amp;#10;            article__inset--wrap&amp;#10;  &quot;&gt;
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
          &lt;div class=&quot;strap-container&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4 class=&quot;strap&quot; itemprop=&quot;description&quot;&gt;Newsletter Sign-up&lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    

      
      
      &lt;/div&gt; 




      &lt;p&gt;The FTC alternative of suing Facebook in court holds risks for both sides. Even if it were to win, the agency would likely obtain far less in both monetary penalties and operational changes at Facebook than it could gain through a settlement, legal observers have said. For Facebook, those people said, litigation would make emails involving Mr. Zuckerberg and other senior executives more likely to become public, possibly casting doubt on the company’s renewed public commitment to privacy.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;Mr. Zuckerberg, who last year said he made a “huge mistake” in not focusing on user privacy earlier, has been talking about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/facebook-plans-new-emphasis-on-private-communications-11551899847?mod=article_inline&quot; class=&quot;icon none&quot;&gt;charting a new path for Facebook&lt;/a&gt;. He announced earlier this year that the company would pivot toward encrypted and ephemeral messaging products and would support the U.S. government &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/facebook-chief-mark-zuckerberg-wants-more-internet-regulation-11553999323?mod=article_inline&quot; class=&quot;icon none&quot;&gt;imposing personal-data protection&lt;/a&gt; along the lines of Europe’s existing laws.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;Legal and political efforts in numerous jurisdictions are continuing to explore the company’s past practices.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;Sealed American court documents obtained and made public by the British Parliament show Facebook sought to expand its access to users’ data without informing them and snooped on mobile phone users’ activities on other platforms.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;In the U.S., the attorney general of Washington, D.C., Karl Racine,  is suing the company over the Cambridge Analytica matter, alleging in a recent filing that Facebook’s staffers were aware that its data was being misused for political purposes as early as 2015.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;Facebook is fighting the D.C. lawsuit and has disputed that the company knew of the Cambridge Analytica misconduct in 2015. The company has called the documents obtained by U.K. officials “cherry-picked” and misleading. &lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Write to &lt;/strong&gt;John D. McKinnon at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:john.mckinnon@wsj.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;icon &quot;&gt;john.mckinnon@wsj.com&lt;/a&gt;, Emily Glazer at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:emily.glazer@wsj.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;icon &quot;&gt;emily.glazer@wsj.com&lt;/a&gt; and Deepa Seetharaman at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:Deepa.Seetharaman@wsj.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;icon &quot;&gt;Deepa.Seetharaman@wsj.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;/div&gt;



  &lt;/div&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 15:45:16 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Dajsvaro</dc:creator>
<og:title>Facebook Worries Emails Could Show Zuckerberg Knew of Questionable Privacy Practices </og:title>
<og:description>Facebook uncovered emails that appear to show CEO Mark Zuckerberg’s connection to potentially problematic privacy practices at the company.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.wsj.com/articles/facebook-worries-emails-could-show-zuckerberg-knew-of-questionable-privacy-practices-11560353829</og:url>
<og:image>https://images.wsj.net/im-81405/social</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.wsj.com/articles/facebook-worries-emails-could-show-zuckerberg-knew-of-questionable-privacy-practices-11560353829?mod=rsswn</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>AMD Ryzen 9 3950X is the fastest processor on Geekbench</title>
<link>https://www.techquila.co.in/amd-ryzen-9-3950x-vs-intels-18-core-i9/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.techquila.co.in/amd-ryzen-9-3950x-vs-intels-18-core-i9/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;So, as AMD’s new 16-core Zen 2 flagship has now been officially launched, we now know for a fact that the Ryzen 3000 lineup won’t be limited to the 12-core 3900X. According to AMD’s first-party benchmarks, the Ryzen 9 3950X is faster than Intel’s i9-9960X, but as per a new Geekbench score, the 7nm AMD flagship might be even more powerful in certain scenarios. It scores a mammoth 61,072 points in the multi-core test which is the highest for any consumer CPU, period. The closest Intel competitor is the 18-core i9-9980XE (with 46618 points) which gets left far behind with a margin of more than 14K points, all the while costing more than twice as much (Ryzen 3950X~$749, i9-9980XE~$2000+).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://h3g7w2e9.stackpathcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/image-26-1019x1024.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-29556&quot; srcset=&quot;https://h3g7w2e9.stackpathcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/image-26-1019x1024.png 1019w, https://h3g7w2e9.stackpathcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/image-26-150x150.png 150w, https://h3g7w2e9.stackpathcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/image-26-298x300.png 298w, https://h3g7w2e9.stackpathcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/image-26-768x772.png 768w, https://h3g7w2e9.stackpathcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/image-26-696x700.png 696w, https://h3g7w2e9.stackpathcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/image-26-1068x1074.png 1068w, https://h3g7w2e9.stackpathcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/image-26-418x420.png 418w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1019px) 100vw, 1019px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;The best part is that this is an early sample, slower than the final chips that will hit the market. We are looking at a base clock of 3.29GHz and a boost of 4.29, while the 3950X in its final state runs at 4.7GHz when under load. Despite that, however, the single core performance and the IPC of the 16-core AMD flagship is higher than the 9th Gen Intel lineup. Only the higher clocked i7s and i9s manage to match it in the single-core test. Furthermore, the chip is running on an X470 board and the cache size along with the Matisse codename confirm that this indeed is the Ryzen 9 3950X, and not a future Threadripper part. Here are the multi-core and single-core performance charts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;https://h3g7w2e9.stackpathcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/image-27-1024x990.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-29558&quot; srcset=&quot;https://h3g7w2e9.stackpathcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/image-27-1024x990.png 1024w, https://h3g7w2e9.stackpathcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/image-27-300x290.png 300w, https://h3g7w2e9.stackpathcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/image-27-768x742.png 768w, https://h3g7w2e9.stackpathcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/image-27-696x673.png 696w, https://h3g7w2e9.stackpathcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/image-27-1068x1032.png 1068w, https://h3g7w2e9.stackpathcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/image-27-435x420.png 435w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Related:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.techquila.co.in/10th-gen-intel-i7-10510u-comet-lake-u/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10th Gen Intel i7-10510U (Comet Lake-U) iGPU Trades Blows with AMD Ryzen 7 2700U (Vega 10) and NVIDIA MX250&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://h3g7w2e9.stackpathcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/image-28-1024x1024.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-29559&quot; srcset=&quot;https://h3g7w2e9.stackpathcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/image-28-1024x1024.png 1024w, https://h3g7w2e9.stackpathcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/image-28-150x150.png 150w, https://h3g7w2e9.stackpathcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/image-28-300x300.png 300w, https://h3g7w2e9.stackpathcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/image-28-768x768.png 768w, https://h3g7w2e9.stackpathcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/image-28-696x696.png 696w, https://h3g7w2e9.stackpathcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/image-28-1068x1069.png 1068w, https://h3g7w2e9.stackpathcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/image-28-420x420.png 420w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Looks like Intel won’t be coming out of this one unscathed. What do you think? Will you be buying the Ryzen 9 or do you still trust Intel?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read more:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 14:54:40 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>areejs</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://h3g7w2e9.stackpathcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/AMD-Ryzen-3000-CPU-Official-Video_7.png</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>AMD Ryzen 9 3950X with 61K points is the Fastest Processor on Geekbench, Destroys Intel's 18-Core i9-9980XE</og:title>
<og:description>According to AMD's first-party benchmarks, the Ryzen 9 3950X is faster than Intel's i9-9960X, but as per a new Geekbench score, the 7nm AMD flagship might be even more powerful</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.techquila.co.in/amd-ryzen-9-3950x-vs-intels-18-core-i9/</og:url>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.techquila.co.in/amd-ryzen-9-3950x-vs-intels-18-core-i9/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Hong Kong Police Fire Tear Gas, Rubber Bullets at Protesters</title>
<link>https://www.wsj.com/articles/hong-kong-protest-debate-postponed-on-extradition-bill-as-crowds-swell-in-opposition-11560309637</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.wsj.com/articles/hong-kong-protest-debate-postponed-on-extradition-bill-as-crowds-swell-in-opposition-11560309637</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;is-lead-inset&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div data-layout=&quot;header&amp;#10;              &quot; data-layout-mobile=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;&amp;#10;        media-object&amp;#10;        type-InsetMediaVideo&amp;#10;          header&amp;#10;    scope-web|mobileapps&amp;#10;  article__inset&amp;#10;        article__inset--type-InsetMediaVideo&amp;#10;          article__inset--lead&amp;#10;  &quot;&gt;
      
      
      
          &lt;div class=&quot;media-object-video article__inset__video &quot;&gt;
        
    &lt;div class=&quot;wsj-article-caption article__inset__video__caption&quot;&gt;
            WSJ’s John Lyons reports from the streets of Hong Kong, where police used tear gas and rubber bullets to disperse people protesting against a controversial extradition bill. Photo: Getty Images
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      &lt;/div&gt; 
    &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;clearfix byline-wrap&quot;&gt;


      
      &lt;div class=&quot;byline article__byline&quot;&gt;
      
      
          &lt;span&gt;By&lt;/span&gt;
      
                &lt;div class=&quot;author mobile-scrim hasMenu&quot; data-scrim=&quot;{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;author&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;header&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Natasha Khan&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;subhead&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;The Wall Street Journal&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;list&amp;quot;:[{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;icon&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;bio&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.wsj.com/news/author/8644&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Biography&amp;quot;},{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;icon&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;twitter&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://twitter.com/natashakhanhk&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;@natashakhanhk&amp;quot;},{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;icon&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;email&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;mailto:natasha.khan@wsj.com&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;natasha.khan@wsj.com&amp;quot;}]}&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemprop=&quot;author&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/Person&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;span class=&quot;name&quot; itemprop=&quot;name&quot;&gt;Natasha Khan&lt;/span&gt;, 
                    &lt;/div&gt;

                &lt;div class=&quot;author mobile-scrim hasMenu&quot; data-scrim=&quot;{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;author&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;header&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;John Lyons&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;subhead&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;The Wall Street Journal&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;list&amp;quot;:[{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;icon&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;bio&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.wsj.com/news/author/7683&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Biography&amp;quot;},{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;icon&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;twitter&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://twitter.com/LyonsNotes&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;@LyonsNotes&amp;quot;},{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;icon&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;email&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;mailto:John.Lyons@wsj.com&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;John.Lyons@wsj.com&amp;quot;}]}&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemprop=&quot;author&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/Person&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;span class=&quot;name&quot; itemprop=&quot;name&quot;&gt;John Lyons&lt;/span&gt; and 
                    &lt;/div&gt;

                

      &lt;/div&gt;
      
      &lt;time class=&quot;timestamp article__timestamp flexbox__flex--1&quot;&gt;
        Updated June 12, 2019 8:39 p.m. ET
      &lt;/time&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

  

  &lt;div class=&quot;article-content &quot;&gt;

      &lt;p&gt;HONG KONG—A standoff over China’s encroachment on this city’s legal autonomy deepened, with hundreds of police firing tear gas and rubber bullets at protesters, as the financial center’s Beijing-backed government showed no signs of yielding during a second day of widespread demonstrations. &lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;Wednesday’s protest, which followed &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/massive-crowds-take-to-streets-in-last-fight-for-hong-kong-11560075915?mod=article_inline&quot; class=&quot;icon none&quot;&gt;a mass demonstration by as many as a million people&lt;/a&gt; on Sunday, is the biggest outbreak of public unrest in years and comes as the administration of President Xi Jinping of China moves to bring the former British colony closer to the mainland. At issue is a widely unpopular &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/why-are-people-protesting-in-hong-kong-11560115220?mod=article_inline&amp;amp;mod=article_inline&quot; class=&quot;icon none&quot;&gt;bill that would allow extradition&lt;/a&gt; of alleged criminals to China from Hong Kong, which critics fear will be abused by Beijing for political ends.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;div class=&quot;paywall&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;Mass protests in 2003 and 2012 forced the government to back away from proposed laws on national security and patriotic education in schools. Since 2014, when authorities were unmoved by a 79-day street occupation demanding Beijing grant the city greater democracy, the pendulum has swung toward the government and reduced belief among opposition groups that mass demonstrations can sway policy makers.&lt;/p&gt;






      &lt;div data-layout=&quot;wrap&amp;#10;              &quot; data-layout-mobile=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;&amp;#10;        media-object&amp;#10;        type-InsetDynamic&amp;#10;          wrap&amp;#10;    scope-web|mobileapps&amp;#10;  article__inset&amp;#10;        article__inset--type-InsetDynamic&amp;#10;            article__inset--wrap&amp;#10;  &quot;&gt;
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
        &lt;div class=&quot;dynamic-inset-container article__inset__dynamic&quot;&gt;
            
&lt;/div&gt;

      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      &lt;/div&gt; 




      &lt;p&gt;But the extradition bill has struck a nerve among local people who fear their freedoms are being eroded and revived an opposition movement many had written off as dead. Many protesters said they are unwilling to give up, even if they believe their defiance is futile.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;The clashes, which came after thousands of people blocked key roads, reflect a widening chasm between many Hong Kong residents and their government, which they accuse of trying to rush through fundamental changes to their independent justice system at the behest of China’s leaders. &lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;The protesters occupied streets from dawn on Wednesday and forced the city’s legislature to postpone a debate on the bill as the swarms of people blocked entrances and exits to government headquarters. A session to debate the bill had previously been scheduled to begin Wednesday morning, while the organizers of Sunday’s march have urged continued action until the bill is withdrawn.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;By afternoon, plumes of tear gas filled the air as officers drove back the crowds of mostly young demonstrators, some of whom were wearing masks, goggles and helmets. Police declared a riot and accused protesters, who were largely unarmed, of hurling metal rods and bricks at officers.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;At 10 p.m., 72 people were injured, including two seriously, ranging in age from 15 to 66, according to the Hospital Authority. By midnight, protesters regrouped, with the main arteries of the central business district shut down. Hundreds of demonstrators waited behind metal barriers they had moved to cordon themselves off from lines of police in riot gear.By early Thursday, most remaining protesters had left, some on the last trains and others in cars that had previously been used to block main roads. &lt;/p&gt;






      &lt;div data-layout=&quot;inline&amp;#10;              &quot; data-layout-mobile=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;&amp;#10;        media-object&amp;#10;        type-InsetDynamic&amp;#10;          inline&amp;#10;    scope-web|mobileapps&amp;#10;  article__inset&amp;#10;        article__inset--type-InsetDynamic&amp;#10;            article__inset--inline&amp;#10;  &quot;&gt;
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
        &lt;div class=&quot;dynamic-inset-container article__inset__dynamic&quot;&gt;
            &lt;style type=&quot;text/css&quot; media=&quot;screen,print&quot;&gt;&lt;![CDATA[  /* 4u Graphics Standalone */  @media all and (max-width: 585px) {    body.template-standalone:not(.nc-exp) .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-4u,    body.template-standalone:not(.nc-exp) .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-4u-wrap,    body.template-standalone:not(.nc-exp) .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-4u-margin,    body.template-standalone:not(.nc-exp) .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-4u-bleed,    body.template-standalone:not(.nc-exp) .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-4u-header,    body.template-standalone:not(.nc-exp) .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-4u-inline {      display: block !important;      max-width: 300px;    }    body.template-standalone:not(.nc-exp) .djai2html-tagline {      float: left;    }    body.template-standalone:not(.nc-exp) .djai2html-foot,    body.template-standalone:not(.nc-exp) .djai2html-headline,    body.template-standalone:not(.nc-exp) .djai2html-leadin {      max-width: 300px;      margin-left: auto;      margin-right: auto;    }  }  /* 8u Graphics Standalone */  @media all and (min-width: 666px) and (max-width: 745px) {    body.template-standalone:not(.nc-exp) .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-8u,    body.template-standalone:not(.nc-exp) .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-8u-wrap,    body.template-standalone:not(.nc-exp) .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-8u-margin,    body.template-standalone:not(.nc-exp) .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-8u-bleed,    body.template-standalone:not(.nc-exp) .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-8u-header,    body.template-standalone:not(.nc-exp) .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-8u-inline {      max-width: 620px;      display: block !important;    }  }  /* 12u Graphics Standalone */  @media all and (min-width: 586px) and (max-width: 665px){    body.template-standalone:not(.nc-exp) .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-12u,    body.template-standalone:not(.nc-exp) .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-12u-wrap,    body.template-standalone:not(.nc-exp) .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-12u-margin,    body.template-standalone:not(.nc-exp) .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-12u-bleed,    body.template-standalone:not(.nc-exp) .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-12u-header,    body.template-standalone:not(.nc-exp) .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-12u-inline {      max-width: 540px;      display: block !important;    }  }  /* 16u Graphics Standalone */  @media all and (min-width: 746px) {    body.template-standalone:not(.nc-exp) .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-16u,    body.template-standalone:not(.nc-exp) .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-16u-wrap,    body.template-standalone:not(.nc-exp) .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-16u-margin,    body.template-standalone:not(.nc-exp) .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-16u-bleed,    body.template-standalone:not(.nc-exp) .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-16u-header,    body.template-standalone:not(.nc-exp) .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-16u-inline {      max-width: 700px;      display: block !important;    }  }  body.at4units .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-4u,  body.at4units .wrap .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-4u-wrap,  body.at4units .margin .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-4u-margin,  body.at4units .bleed .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-4u-bleed,  body.at4units .header .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-4u-header,  body.at4units .inline .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-4u-inline {    max-width: 300px;  }  .wrap .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-8u-wrap,  .wrap .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-12u-wrap,  .wrap .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-16u-wrap,  .margin .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-8u-margin,  .margin .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-12u-margin,  .margin .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-16u-margin {    max-width: 300px;  }  body.at4units .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-4u,  body.at8units .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-8u,  body.at12units .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-12u,  body.at16units .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-16u,  body.at4units .bleed .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-4u-bleed,  body.at8units .bleed .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-8u-bleed,  body.at12units .bleed .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-12u-bleed,  body.at16units .bleed .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-16u-bleed,  body.at4units .header .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-4u-header,  body.at8units .header .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-8u-header,  body.at12units .header .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-12u-header,  body.at16units .header .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-16u-header,  body.at4units .inline .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-4u-inline,  body.at8units .inline .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-8u-inline,  body.at12units .inline .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-12u-inline,  body.at16units .inline .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-16u-inline,  body.at4units .offset .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-4u-offset,  body.at8units .offset .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-8u-offset,  body.at12units .offset .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-12u-offset,  body.at16units .offset .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-16u-offset,  body.at4units .wrap .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-4u,  body.at4units .wrap .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-4u-wrap,  body.at8units .wrap .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-8u-wrap,  body.at12units .wrap .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-12u-wrap,  body.at16units .wrap .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-16u-wrap,  body.at4units .margin .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-4u,  body.at4units .margin .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-4u-margin,  body.at8units .margin .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-8u-margin,  body.at12units .margin .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-12u-margin,  body.at16units .margin .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-16u-margin {    display: block !important;  }  .at12units #wsj-article-wrap[data-articleCentered=&quot;true&quot;] .inline .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-12u,  .at12units #wsj-article-wrap[data-articleCentered=&quot;true&quot;] .offset .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-12u {    display: none !important;  }  .at12units #wsj-article-wrap[data-articleCentered=&quot;true&quot;] .inline .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-16u,  .at12units #wsj-article-wrap[data-articleCentered=&quot;true&quot;] .offset .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-16u {    display: block !important;  }  .at8units #wsj-article-wrap[data-articleCentered=&quot;true&quot;] .inline .ai2html_export,  .at8units #wsj-article-wrap[data-articleCentered=&quot;true&quot;] .offset .ai2html_export {    margin: 0 auto;    max-width: 620px;  }]]&gt;&lt;/style&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot; href=&quot;//asset.wsj.net/wsjnewsgraphics/ai2html/ai2html.min.css&quot;/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;ai2html_export&quot; data-version=&quot;0.9.17&quot; data-date=&quot;06/12/2019&quot; data-uuid=&quot;d7e70d75-64e9-48b7-ae00-bcab24fdbd62&quot;&gt;    &lt;h3 class=&quot;djai2html-headline wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-8u wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-12u wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-16u wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-4u&quot;&gt;Hong Kong From Above &lt;/h3&gt;      &lt;h4 class=&quot;djai2html-leadin wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-8u wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-12u wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-16u wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-4u&quot;&gt;A view of the North side of Hong Kong island, where street protests were held in opposition to a proposed China extradition law.&lt;/h4&gt;    &lt;div class=&quot;ai2html-boards&quot;&gt;      &lt;div id=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513&quot; class=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513artBoard wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-16u ai2html-artboard&quot;&gt;      &lt;style type=&quot;text/css&quot; media=&quot;screen,print&quot;&gt;&lt;![CDATA[        #wsj-ai2html-1560334766513 {          position: relative;          overflow: hidden;                      width: px;                    display: none;        }        .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513aiAbs {          position: absolute;        }        .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513aiImg {          display: block;          width: 100% !important;        }        #wsj-ai2html-1560334766513 p {          font-family: Arial,Helvetica,sans-serif;          font-size: 13px;          line-height: 18px;          margin: 0;        }                  #wsj-ai2html-1560334766513 .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513-aiPstyle-4-0 {            font-family: &quot;Retina Narrow&quot;,Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;            font-size: 13px;            line-height: 13px;                        font-weight: 400;                                      font-style: italic;                                      text-transform: uppercase;                                                  text-shadow: 1px 1px 2px #fff;                                                              text-align: center;                                                            color: #323232;            margin-top: 1px;          }              ]]&gt;&lt;/style&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513-graphic&quot;&gt;                                        &lt;img id=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513ai4-0&quot; class=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513aiImg bg-image&quot; src=&quot;https://si.wsj.net/public/resources/images/B3-EF969_backgr_16U_20190612062011.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513ai4-1&quot; class=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513_textshadow-white wsj-ai2html-1560334766513aiAbs &quot;&gt;                    &lt;p class=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513-aiPstyle-4-0&quot;&gt;BANK OF&lt;/p&gt;                    &lt;p class=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513-aiPstyle-4-0&quot;&gt;cHINA&lt;/p&gt;                  &lt;/div&gt;                &lt;div id=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513ai4-2&quot; class=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513_textshadow-white wsj-ai2html-1560334766513aiAbs &quot;&gt;                    &lt;p class=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513-aiPstyle-4-0&quot;&gt;HONG KONG GOVERNMENT &lt;/p&gt;                    &lt;p class=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513-aiPstyle-4-0&quot;&gt;COMPLEX&lt;/p&gt;                  &lt;/div&gt;                                &lt;div id=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513ai4-4&quot; class=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513_textshadow-white wsj-ai2html-1560334766513aiAbs &quot;&gt;                    &lt;p class=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513-aiPstyle-4-0&quot;&gt;LEGISLATIVE &lt;/p&gt;                    &lt;p class=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513-aiPstyle-4-0&quot;&gt;COUNCIL&lt;/p&gt;                  &lt;/div&gt;                &lt;div id=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513ai4-5&quot; class=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513_textshadow-white wsj-ai2html-1560334766513aiAbs &quot;&gt;                    &lt;p class=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513-aiPstyle-4-0&quot;&gt;PEOPLE’S LIBERATION &lt;/p&gt;                    &lt;p class=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513-aiPstyle-4-0&quot;&gt;ARMY BARRACKS&lt;/p&gt;                  &lt;/div&gt;                &lt;div id=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513ai4-6&quot; class=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513_textshadow-white wsj-ai2html-1560334766513aiAbs &quot;&gt;                    &lt;p class=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513-aiPstyle-4-0&quot;&gt;TAMAR &lt;/p&gt;                    &lt;p class=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513-aiPstyle-4-0&quot;&gt;PARK &lt;/p&gt;                  &lt;/div&gt;                &lt;div id=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513ai4-7&quot; class=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513_textshadow-white wsj-ai2html-1560334766513aiAbs &quot;&gt;                    &lt;p class=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513-aiPstyle-4-0&quot;&gt;VICTORIA HARBOUR&lt;/p&gt;                  &lt;/div&gt;                  &lt;/div&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;      &lt;div id=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513&quot; class=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513artBoard wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-12u ai2html-artboard&quot;&gt;      &lt;style type=&quot;text/css&quot; media=&quot;screen,print&quot;&gt;&lt;![CDATA[        #wsj-ai2html-1560334766513 {          position: relative;          overflow: hidden;                      width: px;                    display: none;        }        .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513aiAbs {          position: absolute;        }        .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513aiImg {          display: block;          width: 100% !important;        }        #wsj-ai2html-1560334766513 p {          font-family: Arial,Helvetica,sans-serif;          font-size: 13px;          line-height: 18px;          margin: 0;        }                  #wsj-ai2html-1560334766513 .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513-aiPstyle-3-0 {            font-family: &quot;Retina Narrow&quot;,Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;            font-size: 13px;            line-height: 13px;                        font-weight: 400;                                      font-style: italic;                                      text-transform: uppercase;                                                  text-shadow: 1px 1px 2px #fff;                                                              text-align: center;                                                            color: #323232;            margin-top: 1px;          }              ]]&gt;&lt;/style&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513-graphic&quot;&gt;                                        &lt;img id=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513ai3-0&quot; class=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513aiImg bg-image&quot; src=&quot;https://si.wsj.net/public/resources/images/B3-EF969_backgr_12U_20190612062011.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513ai3-1&quot; class=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513_textshadow-white_copy wsj-ai2html-1560334766513aiAbs &quot;&gt;                    &lt;p class=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513-aiPstyle-3-0&quot;&gt;BANK OF&lt;/p&gt;                    &lt;p class=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513-aiPstyle-3-0&quot;&gt;cHINA&lt;/p&gt;                  &lt;/div&gt;                &lt;div id=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513ai3-2&quot; class=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513_textshadow-white_copy wsj-ai2html-1560334766513aiAbs &quot;&gt;                    &lt;p class=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513-aiPstyle-3-0&quot;&gt;HONG KONG GOVERNMENT &lt;/p&gt;                    &lt;p class=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513-aiPstyle-3-0&quot;&gt;COMPLEX&lt;/p&gt;                  &lt;/div&gt;                &lt;div id=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513ai3-3&quot; class=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513_textshadow-white_copy wsj-ai2html-1560334766513aiAbs &quot;&gt;                    &lt;p class=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513-aiPstyle-3-0&quot;&gt;LEGISLATIVE &lt;/p&gt;                    &lt;p class=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513-aiPstyle-3-0&quot;&gt;COUNCIL&lt;/p&gt;                  &lt;/div&gt;                &lt;div id=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513ai3-4&quot; class=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513_textshadow-white_copy wsj-ai2html-1560334766513aiAbs &quot;&gt;                    &lt;p class=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513-aiPstyle-3-0&quot;&gt;PEOPLE’S LIBERATION &lt;/p&gt;                    &lt;p class=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513-aiPstyle-3-0&quot;&gt;ARMY BARRACKS&lt;/p&gt;                  &lt;/div&gt;                &lt;div id=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513ai3-5&quot; class=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513_textshadow-white_copy wsj-ai2html-1560334766513aiAbs &quot;&gt;                    &lt;p class=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513-aiPstyle-3-0&quot;&gt;TAMAR &lt;/p&gt;                    &lt;p class=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513-aiPstyle-3-0&quot;&gt;PARK &lt;/p&gt;                  &lt;/div&gt;                &lt;div id=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513ai3-6&quot; class=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513_textshadow-white_copy wsj-ai2html-1560334766513aiAbs &quot;&gt;                    &lt;p class=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513-aiPstyle-3-0&quot;&gt;VICTORIA HARBOUR&lt;/p&gt;                  &lt;/div&gt;                  &lt;/div&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;      &lt;div id=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513&quot; class=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513artBoard wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-8u ai2html-artboard&quot;&gt;      &lt;style type=&quot;text/css&quot; media=&quot;screen,print&quot;&gt;&lt;![CDATA[        #wsj-ai2html-1560334766513 {          position: relative;          overflow: hidden;                      width: px;                    display: none;        }        .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513aiAbs {          position: absolute;        }        .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513aiImg {          display: block;          width: 100% !important;        }        #wsj-ai2html-1560334766513 p {          font-family: Arial,Helvetica,sans-serif;          font-size: 13px;          line-height: 18px;          margin: 0;        }                  #wsj-ai2html-1560334766513 .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513-aiPstyle-2-0 {            font-family: &quot;Retina Narrow&quot;,Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;            font-size: 13px;            line-height: 13px;                        font-weight: 400;                                      font-style: italic;                                      text-transform: uppercase;                                                  text-shadow: 1px 1px 2px #fff;                                                              text-align: center;                                                            color: #323232;            margin-top: 1px;          }              ]]&gt;&lt;/style&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513-graphic&quot;&gt;                                        &lt;img id=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513ai2-0&quot; class=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513aiImg bg-image&quot; src=&quot;https://si.wsj.net/public/resources/images/B3-EF969_backgr_8U_20190612062011.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513ai2-1&quot; class=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513_textshadow-white_copy_2 wsj-ai2html-1560334766513aiAbs &quot;&gt;                    &lt;p class=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513-aiPstyle-2-0&quot;&gt;BANK OF&lt;/p&gt;                    &lt;p class=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513-aiPstyle-2-0&quot;&gt;cHINA&lt;/p&gt;                  &lt;/div&gt;                &lt;div id=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513ai2-2&quot; class=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513_textshadow-white_copy_2 wsj-ai2html-1560334766513aiAbs &quot;&gt;                    &lt;p class=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513-aiPstyle-2-0&quot;&gt;HONG KONG GOVERNMENT &lt;/p&gt;                    &lt;p class=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513-aiPstyle-2-0&quot;&gt;COMPLEX&lt;/p&gt;                  &lt;/div&gt;                                &lt;div id=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513ai2-4&quot; class=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513_textshadow-white_copy_2 wsj-ai2html-1560334766513aiAbs &quot;&gt;                    &lt;p class=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513-aiPstyle-2-0&quot;&gt;LEGISLATIVE &lt;/p&gt;                    &lt;p class=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513-aiPstyle-2-0&quot;&gt;COUNCIL&lt;/p&gt;                  &lt;/div&gt;                &lt;div id=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513ai2-5&quot; class=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513_textshadow-white_copy_2 wsj-ai2html-1560334766513aiAbs &quot;&gt;                    &lt;p class=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513-aiPstyle-2-0&quot;&gt;PEOPLE’S LIBERATION &lt;/p&gt;                    &lt;p class=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513-aiPstyle-2-0&quot;&gt;ARMY BARRACKS&lt;/p&gt;                  &lt;/div&gt;                &lt;div id=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513ai2-6&quot; class=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513_textshadow-white_copy_2 wsj-ai2html-1560334766513aiAbs &quot;&gt;                    &lt;p class=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513-aiPstyle-2-0&quot;&gt;TAMAR &lt;/p&gt;                    &lt;p class=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513-aiPstyle-2-0&quot;&gt;PARK &lt;/p&gt;                  &lt;/div&gt;                &lt;div id=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513ai2-7&quot; class=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513_textshadow-white_copy_2 wsj-ai2html-1560334766513aiAbs &quot;&gt;                    &lt;p class=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513-aiPstyle-2-0&quot;&gt;VICTORIA HARBOUR&lt;/p&gt;                  &lt;/div&gt;                  &lt;/div&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;      &lt;div id=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513&quot; class=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513artBoard wsj-ai2html-1560334766513show-4u ai2html-artboard&quot;&gt;      &lt;style type=&quot;text/css&quot; media=&quot;screen,print&quot;&gt;&lt;![CDATA[        #wsj-ai2html-1560334766513 {          position: relative;          overflow: hidden;                      width: px;                    display: none;        }        .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513aiAbs {          position: absolute;        }        .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513aiImg {          display: block;          width: 100% !important;        }        #wsj-ai2html-1560334766513 p {          font-family: Arial,Helvetica,sans-serif;          font-size: 13px;          line-height: 18px;          margin: 0;        }                  #wsj-ai2html-1560334766513 .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513-aiPstyle-0-0 {            font-family: Retina,Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;            font-size: 13px;            line-height: 16px;                        font-weight: 500;                                                                                                                                                color: #ffffff;            margin-top: 1px;          }                  #wsj-ai2html-1560334766513 .wsj-ai2html-1560334766513-aiPstyle-0-1 {            font-family: Retina,Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;            font-size: 15px;            line-height: 20px;                        font-weight: 500;                                                                          text-shadow: 1px 1px 2px #fff;                                                                                                color: #323232;            margin-top: 1px;          }              ]]&gt;&lt;/style&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513-graphic&quot;&gt;                                        &lt;img id=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513ai0-0&quot; class=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513aiImg bg-image&quot; src=&quot;https://si.wsj.net/public/resources/images/B3-EF969_backgr_4U_20190612062011.jpg&quot;/&gt;                                                                                &lt;div id=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513ai0-6&quot; class=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513_textshadow-white_copy_3 wsj-ai2html-1560334766513aiAbs &quot;&gt;                    &lt;p class=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513-aiPstyle-0-1&quot;&gt;Legislative Council&lt;/p&gt;                  &lt;/div&gt;                                &lt;div id=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513ai0-8&quot; class=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513_textshadow-white_copy_3 wsj-ai2html-1560334766513aiAbs &quot;&gt;                    &lt;p class=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513-aiPstyle-0-1&quot;&gt;Hong Kong Government Complex&lt;/p&gt;                  &lt;/div&gt;                                &lt;div id=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513ai0-10&quot; class=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513_textshadow-white_copy_3 wsj-ai2html-1560334766513aiAbs &quot;&gt;                    &lt;p class=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513-aiPstyle-0-1&quot;&gt;Tamar Park&lt;/p&gt;                  &lt;/div&gt;                                &lt;div id=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513ai0-12&quot; class=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513_textshadow-white_copy_3 wsj-ai2html-1560334766513aiAbs &quot;&gt;                    &lt;p class=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513-aiPstyle-0-1&quot;&gt;People’s Liberation Army Barracks&lt;/p&gt;                  &lt;/div&gt;                                &lt;div id=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513ai0-14&quot; class=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513_textshadow-white_copy_3 wsj-ai2html-1560334766513aiAbs &quot;&gt;                    &lt;p class=&quot;wsj-ai2html-1560334766513-aiPstyle-0-1&quot;&gt;Bank of China&lt;/p&gt;                  &lt;/div&gt;                                  &lt;/div&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      &lt;/div&gt; 




      &lt;p&gt;“Our mission today has finished,” one protester told colleagues, saying they needed to conserve energy and regroup.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;China’s government signaled on Wednesday its continued support for the proposed law, which would allow authorities to send anyone who sets foot in Hong Kong to mainland China for trial for certain alleged offenses. Critics said it would subject every person in the city to the mainland’s more opaque judicial system, leaving them subject to arbitrary detention and torture.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;“As I’ve repeatedly said here, the Chinese central government firmly supports the Hong Kong SAR government in its work to advance the amendment” of extradition legislation, Chinese Foreign Ministry spokesman Geng Shuang said.&lt;/p&gt;






      &lt;div data-layout=&quot;inline&amp;#10;              &quot; data-layout-mobile=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;&amp;#10;        media-object&amp;#10;        type-InsetRichText&amp;#10;          inline&amp;#10;    scope-mobileapps&amp;#10;  article__inset&amp;#10;        article__inset--type-InsetRichText&amp;#10;            article__inset--inline&amp;#10;  &quot;&gt;
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
          &lt;div class=&quot;media-object-rich-text&quot;&gt;
    	

&lt;h4&gt;Photos: Hong Kong Protest Against Extradition Bill Turns Violent&lt;/h4&gt; 
    &lt;/div&gt;

      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      &lt;/div&gt; 






      &lt;div data-layout=&quot;header&amp;#10;              &quot; data-layout-mobile=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;&amp;#10;        media-object&amp;#10;        webui-slideshow-container&amp;#10;  type-InsetWebUISlideshow&amp;#10;          header&amp;#10;    scope-web|mobileapps&amp;#10;  article__inset&amp;#10;        article__inset--type-InsetWebUISlideshow&amp;#10;            article__inset--header&amp;#10;  &quot;&gt;
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
          &lt;style&gt;&lt;![CDATA[
      .webui-slideshow-inset a:link, a:visited {
        color: initial;
      }
    ]]&gt;&lt;/style&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;webui-slideshow-inset&quot; id=&quot;webui_slideshow_inset_SB12720290320763713670604585360380160000678&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;WSJTheme__slideshow_5FmPaFdwN0Jil8Ml6zbI2 &quot;&gt;&lt;hr class=&quot;WSJTheme__slideshow-key-line_2brxkfT7lfg8JgxO__oeLL &quot;/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;WSJTheme__slideshow-desc-box_tg2yFKlqn8XC85iLIpiw_ &quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;WSJTheme__slideshow-caption_1Cxyq4neWj4pjycyRf7kSy &quot;&gt;

Police officers fire a tear gas during a demonstration against a proposed extradition bill in Hong Kong, China June 12, 2019. REUTERS/Athit Perawongmetha Published Credit: Athit Perawongmetha/Reuters&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;WSJTheme__slideshow-credit_1_8b9WabQEcQiw8XsWWEK &quot;&gt;Athit Perawongmetha/Reuters&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;WSJTheme__slideshow-slide-dots_394rI-J8GKAOnGBKUti6Un &quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;WSJTheme__slideshow-slide-dots-dot_38cN1jGZJiqMkz-9xhUX02 &quot;&gt;•&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;WSJTheme__slideshow-slide-dots-dot_38cN1jGZJiqMkz-9xhUX02 &quot;&gt;•&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;WSJTheme__slideshow-slide-dots-dot_38cN1jGZJiqMkz-9xhUX02 &quot;&gt;•&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;WSJTheme__slideshow-slide-dots-dot_38cN1jGZJiqMkz-9xhUX02 &quot;&gt;•&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;WSJTheme__slideshow-slide-dots-dot_38cN1jGZJiqMkz-9xhUX02 &quot;&gt;•&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;hr class=&quot;WSJTheme__slideshow-key-line_2brxkfT7lfg8JgxO__oeLL &quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      &lt;/div&gt; 






       




      &lt;p&gt;Still, the scale of the backlash appears to have caught Beijing by surprise, said Kristin Shi-Kupfer,  director of public-policy research at the Mercator Institute for China Studies think tank in Berlin. &lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;“They seemingly haven’t thought of such broad-scale protests,” she said. “The protests are a huge challenge to Beijing in maintaining their grip on Hong Kong.”&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;The city has a population of 7.3 million compared with the country’s overall 1.4 billion and plays a far less important role in the nation’s economy than when China resumed sovereignty in 1997. But the city has thrived as a semiautonomous region with a Western-style legal system that forms the backbone of its thriving business culture. Its people are accustomed to values such as rule of law and due process, and many are enraged at the prospect of its erosion. &lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;The city has thrived as a financial center linking China with the world and weathered the 2014 protests. Western banks, many of which have a presence in mainland China, have refrained from publicly choosing sides. The U.S. Chamber of Commerce has warned that the law would erode the confidence of U.S. businesses based in the city.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;House Speaker Nancy Pelosi (D., Calif.) offered support for the protesters, saying Tuesday the proposed law imperils U.S.-Hong Kong relations.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;“If it passes, the Congress has no choice but to reassess whether Hong Kong is ‘sufficiently autonomous’ under the ‘one country, two systems’ framework,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;“I hope it all works out for China and for Hong Kong,” President Trump said on Wednesday during a meeting with Polish President Andrzej Duda at the White House. “I’m sure they’ll be able to work it out.” &lt;/p&gt;






      &lt;div data-layout=&quot;wrap&amp;#10;              &quot; data-layout-mobile=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;&amp;#10;        media-object&amp;#10;        type-InsetDynamic&amp;#10;          wrap&amp;#10;    scope-web|mobileapps&amp;#10;  article__inset&amp;#10;        article__inset--type-InsetDynamic&amp;#10;            article__inset--wrap&amp;#10;  &quot;&gt;
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
        &lt;div class=&quot;dynamic-inset-container article__inset__dynamic&quot;&gt;
            
&lt;/div&gt;

      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      &lt;/div&gt; 




      &lt;p&gt;Opponents of the law were angered after the city’s leader, Carrie Lam,  declined to back down on the bill even after Sunday’s mass protests that drew people from many different parts of society. Some said they don’t trust the city’s government and Beijing to prevent such a law from being used unfairly.&lt;/p&gt;




      




      &lt;p&gt;After Ms. Lam said the law was required to avoid Hong Kong becoming a haven for fugitives, the city’s legislaturescheduled a fast-track process to consider and vote on the bill by June 20. Anonymous fliers began circulating around the city and online calling for supporters to surround the Legislative Council building on Wednesday.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;Thousands of protesters heeded the call and after daylight broke, blocked roads and erected barricades. Numbers grew through the day, until phalanxes of police waded in midafternoon, showering tear gas on demonstrators, using pepper spray and firing rubber bullets and beanbag rounds. &lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;“We condemn the excessive use of violence against protesters whose anger is understandable,” said Jeffrey Ngo,  23, from the opposition party Demosisto. “Hong Kong’s current crisis cannot be dealt with physically, only politically.”&lt;/p&gt;






       




      &lt;p&gt;Happening right at the foot of the local headquarters of China’s People’s Liberation Army, the images of thousands of people once again paralyzing city streets are a potential embarrassment for Mr. Xi.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;Mr. Xi will likely see the protests as a challenge to his authority and push the government in Hong Kong harder to pass the legislation, said Steve Tsang,  director of the China Institute at the London-based School of Oriental and African Studies.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;“Neither the government in Hong Kong nor that in China is likely to accept they have made a mistake in introducing these laws,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;Beijing promised to safeguard Hong Kong people’s rights and freedoms until 2047, but in recent years authorities in the city have jailed activists, used the courts to disqualify democratically elected opposition lawmakers, expelled a foreign journalist and banned a political party that advocated Hong Kong independence.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;Ms. Lam condemned Wednesday’s violence.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;“Since the handover, every time an issue between Hong Kong and the mainland has come up it has been used by some to stir division, but violence is not the way to address those views,” she said. “Hong Kong is a free and open society, but there is a bottom line as to how people express their concerns.”&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;The streets at the main protest site remained empty of crowds as the day dawned Thursday in Hong Kong’s business hub. &lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;A handful of tired protesters remained nearby at the city’s cenotaph war memorial, where a hastily attached Hong Kong colonial-era flag fluttered in the light breeze. Some were gathering umbrellas—shields against pepper spray—in anticipation of further conflict. Police officers surrounded the legislative complex but weren’t wearing riot gear. The main site of the action was still strewn with debris. &lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;A lone protester dressed in a white T-shirt and mask had returned to Harcourt Road, picking up hard hats and litter from the previous day. &lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;“I came back this morning to help clean,” she said, giving her name as Cheung and her age as 24. “I don’t know what the situation is.” &lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;At the Admiralty subway station, adjacent to the site of the previous day’s action, trains packed with commuters sped through without stopping.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;Most of those taking part in Wednesday’s protests said they did so spontaneously. Some protesters mounted tram stops nearby, relaying messages and requests for equipment across the heads of the crowd, and on the social media app Telegram.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;Keith, a student in his early 20s running a station distributing supplies at around midday, said that he didn’t believe the protests could prevent the bill from passing, but that he felt compelled to register his dissent.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;p&gt;“We still have to come out here. We have to fight for ourselves,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;






      &lt;div data-layout=&quot;bleed&amp;#10;              &quot; data-layout-mobile=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;&amp;#10;        media-object&amp;#10;        type-InsetMediaIllustration&amp;#10;          bleed&amp;#10;    scope-web|mobileapps&amp;#10;  article__inset&amp;#10;        article__inset--type-InsetMediaIllustration&amp;#10;            article__inset--bleed&amp;#10;  &quot;&gt;
      
      
          
    &lt;div class=&quot;media-object-image enlarge-image renoImageFormat- img-bleed article__inset__image&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/ImageObject&quot;&gt;
    
      
      &lt;div data-mobile-ratio=&quot;66.66666666666666%&quot; data-layout-ratio=&quot;66.66666666666666%&quot; data-subtype=&quot;photo&quot; class=&quot;image-container  responsive-media article__inset__image__image&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img srcset=&quot;https://images.wsj.net/im-81321?width=140&amp;amp;aspect_ratio=1.5 140w,&amp;#10;https://images.wsj.net/im-81321?width=540&amp;amp;aspect_ratio=1.5 540w,&amp;#10;https://images.wsj.net/im-81321?width=620&amp;amp;aspect_ratio=1.5 620w,&amp;#10;https://images.wsj.net/im-81321?width=700&amp;amp;aspect_ratio=1.5 700w,&amp;#10;https://images.wsj.net/im-81321?width=860&amp;amp;aspect_ratio=1.5 860w,&amp;#10;https://images.wsj.net/im-81321?width=1260&amp;amp;aspect_ratio=1.5 1260w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 140px) 100px,&amp;#10;(max-width: 540px) 500px,&amp;#10;(max-width: 620px) 580px,&amp;#10;(max-width: 700px) 660px,&amp;#10;(max-width: 860px) 820px,&amp;#10;1260px&quot; src=&quot;https://images.wsj.net/im-81321?width=620&amp;amp;aspect_ratio=1.5&quot; data-enlarge=&quot;https://images.wsj.net/im-81321?width=1260&amp;amp;aspect_ratio=1.5&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Protesters gather near the Legislative Council in Hong Kong on Wednesday.&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
      &lt;div class=&quot;wsj-article-caption article__inset__image__caption&quot; itemprop=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;
          &lt;span class=&quot;wsj-article-caption-content&quot;&gt;Protesters gather near the Legislative Council in Hong Kong on Wednesday.&lt;/span&gt;
          &lt;span class=&quot;wsj-article-credit article__inset__image__caption__credit&quot; itemprop=&quot;creator&quot;&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;wsj-article-credit-tag&quot;&gt;
              Photo: 
            &lt;/span&gt;
        jerome favre/epa/Shutterstock
          &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      &lt;/div&gt; 




      &lt;p class=&quot;articleTagLine&quot;&gt;—Wenxin Fan, Joyu Wang and Joanne Chiu in Hong Kong and Eva Dou and Chun Han Wong in Beijing contributed to this article. &lt;/p&gt;






      &lt;div data-layout=&quot;inline&amp;#10;              &quot; data-layout-mobile=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;&amp;#10;        media-object&amp;#10;        type-InsetRichText&amp;#10;          inline&amp;#10;    scope-web&amp;#10;  article__inset&amp;#10;        article__inset--type-InsetRichText&amp;#10;            article__inset--inline&amp;#10;  &quot;&gt;
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
          &lt;div class=&quot;media-object-rich-text&quot;&gt;
    	

&lt;h4&gt;Share Your Thoughts&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;em&gt;How should the U.S. respond to the growing tensions between Hong Kong and Beijing? Join the conversation below.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      &lt;/div&gt; 




      &lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Write to &lt;/strong&gt;Natasha Khan at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:natasha.khan@wsj.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;icon &quot;&gt;natasha.khan@wsj.com&lt;/a&gt;, John Lyons at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:john.lyons@wsj.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;icon &quot;&gt;john.lyons@wsj.com&lt;/a&gt; and Mike Bird at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:Mike.Bird@wsj.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;icon &quot;&gt;Mike.Bird@wsj.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;/div&gt;



  &lt;/div&gt;


    &lt;p class=&quot;printheadline&quot;&gt;
      Appeared in the June 13, 2019, print edition as 'Violence Erupts In Hong Kong.'
    &lt;/p&gt;




</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 14:33:56 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>JumpCrisscross</dc:creator>
<og:title>Hong Kong Protests Turn Violent in Standoff Over China’s Control</og:title>
<og:description>A standoff over China’s encroachment on this city’s legal autonomy deepened, with hundreds of police firing tear gas and rubber bullets at protesters, as the financial center’s Beijing-backed government showed no signs of yielding during a second day of widespread demonstrations.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.wsj.com/articles/hong-kong-protest-debate-postponed-on-extradition-bill-as-crowds-swell-in-opposition-11560309637</og:url>
<og:image>https://images.wsj.net/im-81572/social</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.wsj.com/articles/hong-kong-protest-debate-postponed-on-extradition-bill-as-crowds-swell-in-opposition-11560309637</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Green threads explained in 200 lines of Rust</title>
<link>https://cfsamson.gitbook.io/green-threads-explained-in-200-lines-of-rust/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://cfsamson.gitbook.io/green-threads-explained-in-200-lines-of-rust/</guid>
<description>&lt;div data-key=&quot;e40d64eb53d44549b978f7f50545c662&quot; class=&quot;reset-3c756112--blockHint-a7403a60&quot; readability=&quot;8.6301369863014&quot;&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;blockParagraph-544a408c&quot; data-key=&quot;b92148e036a24447af3377d3760cf8aa&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;text-4505230f--TextH400-3033861f--textContentFamily-49a318e1&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-key=&quot;1364f1da202c4617ba8f00679c19c919&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-offset-key=&quot;1364f1da202c4617ba8f00679c19c919:0&quot;&gt;All the code we go through here is&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;link-a079aa82--primary-53a25e66--link-faf6c434&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/cfsamson/example-greenthreads&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; data-key=&quot;827f21f22aca4ea2ac7cb4c0d418891b&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-key=&quot;e242fe777da644ce96ce86077f65e94f&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-offset-key=&quot;e242fe777da644ce96ce86077f65e94f:0&quot;&gt;located in a github repository&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span data-key=&quot;7a524952429e4abba9b918efd2f898a7&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-offset-key=&quot;7a524952429e4abba9b918efd2f898a7:0&quot;&gt;. There are two branches, the&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span data-offset-key=&quot;7a524952429e4abba9b918efd2f898a7:1&quot;&gt;&lt;code spellcheck=&quot;false&quot; class=&quot;code-81e98f88&quot; data-slate-leaf=&quot;true&quot;&gt;main&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span data-offset-key=&quot;7a524952429e4abba9b918efd2f898a7:2&quot;&gt;branch that only contains the code and the&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span data-offset-key=&quot;7a524952429e4abba9b918efd2f898a7:3&quot;&gt;&lt;code spellcheck=&quot;false&quot; class=&quot;code-81e98f88&quot; data-slate-leaf=&quot;true&quot;&gt;commented&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span data-offset-key=&quot;7a524952429e4abba9b918efd2f898a7:4&quot;&gt;branch that contains the code with comments explaining what we do.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;blockParagraph-544a408c&quot; data-key=&quot;f15709aa967a463c9bf057d848edbe03&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;text-4505230f--TextH400-3033861f--textContentFamily-49a318e1&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-key=&quot;7ff5e1440c464e929bc76740c86a66c4&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-offset-key=&quot;7ff5e1440c464e929bc76740c86a66c4:0&quot;&gt;Green threads, userland threads, coroutines, goroutines or fibers, they have many names but for simplicity’s sake I’ll refer to them all as green threads from now on.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;blockParagraph-544a408c&quot; data-key=&quot;e0a8df6da76945f7b72cf2f75a6d136b&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;text-4505230f--TextH400-3033861f--textContentFamily-49a318e1&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-key=&quot;dcd1e35f4e8440d1bb8e2815aacf6748&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-offset-key=&quot;dcd1e35f4e8440d1bb8e2815aacf6748:0&quot;&gt;In this article I want to explore how they work by implementing a very simple example where we create our own green threads in 200 lines of Rust code. We'll be explaining everything along the way so our main focus here is to understand them and learn how they work by using simple, but working example.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div data-key=&quot;16ce84f81cc44189a357486c001366ed&quot; class=&quot;reset-3c756112--blockHint-a7403a60&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;blockParagraph-544a408c&quot; data-key=&quot;dd9cde8cbfaa45a786a78529e576372c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;text-4505230f--TextH400-3033861f--textContentFamily-49a318e1&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-key=&quot;4674257c8d254eef9105f164f75b1562&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-offset-key=&quot;4674257c8d254eef9105f164f75b1562:0&quot;&gt;We will not use any external libraries or helpers and will do everything from scratch so we make sure we really understand what's going on.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;who-is-this-article-for&quot; class=&quot;blockHeading-442b4f12--blockHeading2WithMargin-532d771d&quot; data-key=&quot;cfdb02e1adee458ab9ae93242674a304&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;text-4505230f--HeadingH600-23f228db--textContentFamily-49a318e1&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-key=&quot;5df151bbd2844955ba4375a7e03b68e0&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-offset-key=&quot;5df151bbd2844955ba4375a7e03b68e0:0&quot;&gt;Who is this article for?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;blockParagraph-544a408c&quot; data-key=&quot;beb5c5d882ba4361ae19da17bf30b1a9&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;text-4505230f--TextH400-3033861f--textContentFamily-49a318e1&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-key=&quot;a4b72698663842e0889a496be525fd13&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-offset-key=&quot;a4b72698663842e0889a496be525fd13:0&quot;&gt;We are peeking down the rabbit hole in this article so if that sounds scary, this article probably isn’t for you. Just go back and live happily ever after.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;blockParagraph-544a408c&quot; data-key=&quot;c1b8093b381948ae8b18ea26dc144376&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;text-4505230f--TextH400-3033861f--textContentFamily-49a318e1&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-key=&quot;a395040e8e3642e3890a447838cac91a&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-offset-key=&quot;a395040e8e3642e3890a447838cac91a:0&quot;&gt;If you are the curious kind and want to understand how things work, then read on. Maybe you’ve heard of Go and it’s goroutines, or the equivalent in Ruby or Julia and you know how to use them but want to know how they work - well then read on.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;blockParagraph-544a408c&quot; data-key=&quot;d511ea9e702b4650947063a281b03666&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;text-4505230f--TextH400-3033861f--textContentFamily-49a318e1&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-key=&quot;b7df98dac91c4e1797e5802265002308&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-offset-key=&quot;b7df98dac91c4e1797e5802265002308:0&quot;&gt;In addition, this should be interesting if:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;list-20526648&quot; data-key=&quot;e2c6e3801976432ea4be57dec2356c7c&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;&quot; readability=&quot;-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;div data-key=&quot;2cedd86946c4473ba31f778b880aeaa6&quot; class=&quot;reset-3c756112--listItemContent-756c9114&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;blockParagraph-544a408c--noMargin-acdf7afa&quot; data-key=&quot;b00ef1b95b594fcf9afef6a12b2e75f2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;text-4505230f--TextH400-3033861f--textContentFamily-49a318e1&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-key=&quot;3b6a9b88c74b47dfb42ec09e2c79cd5d&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-offset-key=&quot;3b6a9b88c74b47dfb42ec09e2c79cd5d:0&quot;&gt;You’re new to Rust and want to learn more about its features.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;&quot; readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;div data-key=&quot;80447e535e404e0393832e74048f3892&quot; class=&quot;reset-3c756112--listItemContent-756c9114&quot; readability=&quot;34&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;blockParagraph-544a408c--noMargin-acdf7afa&quot; data-key=&quot;02c8162c0bf24486a5083f902bab8eef&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;text-4505230f--TextH400-3033861f--textContentFamily-49a318e1&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-key=&quot;725e3864dc0e42e58d6051c65a3b992a&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-offset-key=&quot;725e3864dc0e42e58d6051c65a3b992a:0&quot;&gt;You have followed the discussions in the Rust community about async/await, the Pin-API and why we need generators. In this case I try to put all the pieces together in this article.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;&quot; readability=&quot;-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;div data-key=&quot;20c3ce061ef04ac385d6b915bc459907&quot; class=&quot;reset-3c756112--listItemContent-756c9114&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;blockParagraph-544a408c--noMargin-acdf7afa&quot; data-key=&quot;a6e512e86a9d415e85aae5a8573770ff&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;text-4505230f--TextH400-3033861f--textContentFamily-49a318e1&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-key=&quot;df46b4b367794d16b9562c1f38513b96&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-offset-key=&quot;df46b4b367794d16b9562c1f38513b96:0&quot;&gt;If you want to learn the basics of inline assembly in Rust.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;&quot; readability=&quot;-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;div data-key=&quot;adb7553b26024695a1dd2906fc41dec2&quot; class=&quot;reset-3c756112--listItemContent-756c9114&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;blockParagraph-544a408c--noMargin-acdf7afa&quot; data-key=&quot;a36ffc7130f247ca82b583a7420eaf7a&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;text-4505230f--TextH400-3033861f--textContentFamily-49a318e1&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-key=&quot;f48da6cc22cc46ae862e2e3d8454a41f&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-offset-key=&quot;f48da6cc22cc46ae862e2e3d8454a41f:0&quot;&gt;If you’re just curious.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;blockParagraph-544a408c&quot; data-key=&quot;74570e80193046dcb06351518d228a52&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;text-4505230f--TextH400-3033861f--textContentFamily-49a318e1&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-key=&quot;133119c87b1e4527b516da0723cd6a7a&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-offset-key=&quot;133119c87b1e4527b516da0723cd6a7a:0&quot;&gt;Well, join me as we try to figure out everything we need to understand them.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;blockParagraph-544a408c&quot; data-key=&quot;21433fbcbd1343a2bdbb65b319082658&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;text-4505230f--TextH400-3033861f--textContentFamily-49a318e1&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-key=&quot;999aa6a76b404f00908846bd0fe6e383&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-offset-key=&quot;999aa6a76b404f00908846bd0fe6e383:0&quot;&gt;You don’t have to be a Rust programmer to understand this article but it is highly recommended to read some of the basic syntax first. If you want to follow a long or clone the repo and play around with the code you should probably get Rust and learn the basics.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;following-along&quot; class=&quot;blockHeading-442b4f12--blockHeading2WithMargin-532d771d&quot; data-key=&quot;5326bbbb241647dd8f11c38bf0347392&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;text-4505230f--HeadingH600-23f228db--textContentFamily-49a318e1&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-key=&quot;e2bf47e8bca2439cbbd78a786cab29c5&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-offset-key=&quot;e2bf47e8bca2439cbbd78a786cab29c5:0&quot;&gt;Following along&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;blockParagraph-544a408c&quot; data-key=&quot;51fee14064794816932e2c81f2262021&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;text-4505230f--TextH400-3033861f--textContentFamily-49a318e1&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-key=&quot;bedcc9fbfc604c798fb9637e744aeee8&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-offset-key=&quot;bedcc9fbfc604c798fb9637e744aeee8:0&quot;&gt;All the code I provide here is in a single file and has no dependencies which means that you can easily start your own project and follow along if you want to (i suggest you do). You can even run most of the code in the&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;link-a079aa82--primary-53a25e66--link-faf6c434&quot; href=&quot;https://play.rust-lang.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; data-key=&quot;65c7c89201fd49d18c42558ff1e59f9f&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-key=&quot;d23942cb653846e88fdf805a9f4e1af0&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-offset-key=&quot;d23942cb653846e88fdf805a9f4e1af0:0&quot;&gt;Rust playground&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span data-key=&quot;7af31724a51c43218bf83e2ff01fcec9&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-offset-key=&quot;7af31724a51c43218bf83e2ff01fcec9:0&quot;&gt;. Just remember to use the&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span data-offset-key=&quot;7af31724a51c43218bf83e2ff01fcec9:1&quot;&gt;&lt;code spellcheck=&quot;false&quot; class=&quot;code-81e98f88&quot; data-slate-leaf=&quot;true&quot;&gt;nightly&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-offset-key=&quot;7af31724a51c43218bf83e2ff01fcec9:2&quot;&gt;version of the compiler.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;portability-and-issues&quot; class=&quot;blockHeading-442b4f12--blockHeading2WithMargin-532d771d&quot; data-key=&quot;8140809b7973461da1c984f80e273d05&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;text-4505230f--HeadingH600-23f228db--textContentFamily-49a318e1&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-key=&quot;3803d717e5b240658d615f7f9ed0eb19&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-offset-key=&quot;3803d717e5b240658d615f7f9ed0eb19:0&quot;&gt;Portability and issues&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;blockParagraph-544a408c&quot; data-key=&quot;932315a990da47bd8896fd5b0d856397&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;text-4505230f--TextH400-3033861f--textContentFamily-49a318e1&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-key=&quot;5e928aefb4804181b389dbf5c1a4ee1a&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-offset-key=&quot;5e928aefb4804181b389dbf5c1a4ee1a:0&quot;&gt;Currently there is an issue I have with the&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span data-offset-key=&quot;5e928aefb4804181b389dbf5c1a4ee1a:1&quot;&gt;&lt;code spellcheck=&quot;false&quot; class=&quot;code-81e98f88&quot; data-slate-leaf=&quot;true&quot;&gt;asm!&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-offset-key=&quot;5e928aefb4804181b389dbf5c1a4ee1a:2&quot;&gt;macro that doesn't compile in release mode. It seems to be related to the&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span data-offset-key=&quot;5e928aefb4804181b389dbf5c1a4ee1a:3&quot;&gt;&lt;code spellcheck=&quot;false&quot; class=&quot;code-81e98f88&quot; data-slate-leaf=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&quot;=m&quot;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-offset-key=&quot;5e928aefb4804181b389dbf5c1a4ee1a:4&quot;&gt;constraint I use in the inline macro. Even though we could work around this, I don't consider that a big problem since this is only an example.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;blockParagraph-544a408c&quot; data-key=&quot;9763a67552d041e6bf7abffaf374dea2&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;text-4505230f--TextH400-3033861f--textContentFamily-49a318e1&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-key=&quot;deac957adcb946078076962f6dbbe412&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-offset-key=&quot;deac957adcb946078076962f6dbbe412:0&quot;&gt;I've filed an issue about it in the Rust repo, so we'll wait and see if we get a fix for it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;blockParagraph-544a408c&quot; data-key=&quot;16073873bb32464794e50cf43c910e59&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;text-4505230f--TextH400-3033861f--textContentFamily-49a318e1&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-key=&quot;4a5f988fc4b8435e8ce48918e45cf50b&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-offset-key=&quot;4a5f988fc4b8435e8ce48918e45cf50b:0&quot;&gt;I've tested the code on OSX, Linux and Windows.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;docs-internal-guid-12e6c217-7fff-3de7-4bee-4532b47ef574&quot; class=&quot;blockHeading-442b4f12--blockHeading2WithMargin-532d771d&quot; data-key=&quot;ab32e379aa2f49bb90334c2ebc439c46&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;text-4505230f--HeadingH600-23f228db--textContentFamily-49a318e1&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-key=&quot;4079e0c12dbf4165bf5dc0fbbf5e9eb6&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-offset-key=&quot;4079e0c12dbf4165bf5dc0fbbf5e9eb6:0&quot;&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;blockParagraph-544a408c&quot; data-key=&quot;b11eff7db9ff411ba73bd2e8d0492e27&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;text-4505230f--TextH400-3033861f--textContentFamily-49a318e1&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-key=&quot;597a2452cd3c46f0a38f6ee452511242&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-offset-key=&quot;597a2452cd3c46f0a38f6ee452511242:0&quot;&gt;I’m not trying to make a perfect implementation here. I’m cutting corners to get down to the essence and fit it into what was originally intended to be an article but expanded into a small book. This is not the best way of displaying Rusts greatest strengths, its safety guarantees, but it does show an interesting use of Rust and the code is mostly pretty clean and easy to follow.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;blockParagraph-544a408c&quot; data-key=&quot;3c43328903b742e1903a88e5f3f37f28&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;text-4505230f--TextH400-3033861f--textContentFamily-49a318e1&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-key=&quot;73ba0463ff5046b59d49a40bed1a6143&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-offset-key=&quot;73ba0463ff5046b59d49a40bed1a6143:0&quot;&gt;However, if you spot places where I can make the code safer without making it significantly more complex, I welcome you to create an issue in&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;link-a079aa82--primary-53a25e66--link-faf6c434&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/cfsamson/example-greenthreads&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; data-key=&quot;2626b142abad4ab08cb8a0a9954b1e3a&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-key=&quot;4440940933c943208034e6df38ef8874&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-offset-key=&quot;4440940933c943208034e6df38ef8874:0&quot;&gt;the repo&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-key=&quot;9e6b4bd39b884b6f9fca4451e536b853&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-offset-key=&quot;9e6b4bd39b884b6f9fca4451e536b853:0&quot;&gt;or even better, a pull request.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;credits&quot; class=&quot;blockHeading-442b4f12--blockHeading2WithMargin-532d771d&quot; data-key=&quot;35233512430f4da8b986da6f687bbe3b&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;text-4505230f--HeadingH600-23f228db--textContentFamily-49a318e1&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-key=&quot;2e437d5931a64f62b973516be0cb1faa&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-offset-key=&quot;2e437d5931a64f62b973516be0cb1faa:0&quot;&gt;Credits&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;blockParagraph-544a408c&quot; data-key=&quot;8df628678e934e289a66c1a67ef14dd4&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;text-4505230f--TextH400-3033861f--textContentFamily-49a318e1&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-key=&quot;60b6afa8fb474b1081817c24f655d66b&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-offset-key=&quot;60b6afa8fb474b1081817c24f655d66b:0&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-slate-zero-width=&quot;z&quot;&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;link-a079aa82--primary-53a25e66--link-faf6c434&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/mpu&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; data-key=&quot;e1004dfa82bc4c769706b90ba1835d0d&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-key=&quot;2f4961dc2df34560aff650d2c23eaf0f&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-offset-key=&quot;2f4961dc2df34560aff650d2c23eaf0f:0&quot;&gt;Quentin Carbonneaux&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-key=&quot;7fbd176adaa74bf48b3e01d77301d317&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-offset-key=&quot;7fbd176adaa74bf48b3e01d77301d317:0&quot;&gt;wrote an&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;link-a079aa82--primary-53a25e66--link-faf6c434&quot; href=&quot;https://c9x.me/articles/gthreads/intro.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; data-key=&quot;2ea93c47ee7144488c80b228373d54d5&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-key=&quot;8cecf27ffe914c22a0ef5ecbddac178e&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-offset-key=&quot;8cecf27ffe914c22a0ef5ecbddac178e:0&quot;&gt;nice article&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-key=&quot;3e65ab275dd1487c8b44e6220ad0a07a&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-offset-key=&quot;3e65ab275dd1487c8b44e6220ad0a07a:0&quot;&gt;back in 2013 which I used as inspiration for the main code example.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 12:59:50 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>taheris</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://app.gitbook.com/share/space/thumbnail/-LgP18MRzbB2UB0khzEN.png</og:image>
<og:title>Introduction</og:title>
<og:description>This book aims to explain green threads by using a small example where we implement a simple but working program where we use our own green threads to execute code.</og:description>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://cfsamson.gitbook.io/green-threads-explained-in-200-lines-of-rust/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>