<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Amazon Sends 1,700 Alexa Voice Recordings to a Random Person</title>
<link>https://threatpost.com/amazon-1700-alexa-voice-recordings/140201/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://threatpost.com/amazon-1700-alexa-voice-recordings/140201/</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;c-note c-note--dash u-hidden u-block@md&quot; readability=&quot;13.317073170732&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The administrator of your personal data will be Threatpost, Inc., 500 Unicorn Park, Woburn, MA 01801. Detailed information on the processing of personal data can be found in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://threatpost.com/web-privacy-policy/&quot;&gt;privacy policy&lt;/a&gt;. In addition, you will find them in the message confirming the subscription to the newsletter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 17:34:59 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>0xmohit</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://media.threatpost.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/103/2018/12/20101640/Amazon-echo2.jpg</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Amazon Sends 1,700 Alexa Voice Recordings to a Random Person</og:title>
<og:description>The intimate recordings paint a detailed picture of a man's life.</og:description>
<og:url>https://threatpost.com/amazon-1700-alexa-voice-recordings/140201/</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://threatpost.com/amazon-1700-alexa-voice-recordings/140201/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Show HN: Analysis of 2018 Hacker News “Who Is Hiring” Job Posts</title>
<link>https://letstalkalgorithms.com/analysis-of-2018-hacker-news-who-is-hiring-job-posts/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://letstalkalgorithms.com/analysis-of-2018-hacker-news-who-is-hiring-job-posts/</guid>
<description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://letstalkalgorithms.com/content/images/2018/12/Screen-Shot-2018-12-19-at-7.41.56-PM.png&quot; class=&quot;kg-image&quot;/&gt;Image showing all the locations from the Hacker News Who is Hiring Job Posts
&lt;p&gt;If you are an avid Hacker News user, you would know that there's a hiring comment thread during the start of every month called, &lt;code&gt;Who is Hiring&lt;/code&gt;. Hundreds of companies from across the world post job posts as comments to that thread every month hoping to find potential employees.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unlike many other readers, HN users tend to be more technology focussed, so I thought analyzing the job posts would give some insight into how 2018 in software recruiting has been.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's a lot of data, so I decided to focus only on the below parameters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Locations with most Jobs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remote Work - Number of  job posts which allow remote work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visa - Number of job posts which sponsor visa&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Roles - Top roles that are being hired&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Skills - Popular required skill set across all job postings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;data&quot;&gt;Data&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have scraped all the 12 months of job posts(comments on who is hiring threads) in 2018 using the firebase API and a golang hacker news wrapper library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;locations&quot;&gt;Locations&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To find out all the locations in a job post, I used &lt;code&gt;geotext&lt;/code&gt; ,  a python module which gives you a list of places from the text. After aggregating results from all 12 months job posts, I used Google Places API to get latitude and longitude for each city and visualized on a map using &lt;code&gt;AmCharts&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2o18, the top 10 locations with most jobs are below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;  &quot;San Francisco&quot;: 2922
   &quot;New York&quot;: 1746
   &quot;London&quot;: 1236
   &quot;Toronto&quot;: 660
   &quot;Boston&quot;: 558
   &quot;Los Angeles&quot;: 498
   &quot;Berlin&quot;: 474
   &quot;Seattle&quot;: 456
   &quot;Austin&quot;: 324
   &quot;Amsterdam&quot;: 318
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unsurprisingly San Francisco beats most cities by a wide margin and close second is New York. Below are all cities with the number of job posts in that city in 2018 visualized on an interactive map.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;remote-work&quot;&gt;Remote Work&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the evolving phenomena since the last 2-3 years is companies embracing remote work. More companies are offering remote work and are being flexible with partial remote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did a regular expression search in each job post text to see if a job offers remote work or not. The chart below shows the number of job posts that offer remote work. Total number of job posts in each month is usually around 800-1000, so if you are looking for &lt;code&gt;%&lt;/code&gt; a good 12% on average allow remote work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;kg-gallery-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;kg-gallery-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;kg-gallery-image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://letstalkalgorithms.com/content/images/2018/12/remote-jobs-each-month--4-.svg&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;400&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;visa&quot;&gt;Visa&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Silicon Valley and most of the technology companies in the USA rely heavily on foreign workers. With the arbitrary suspension of premium process for H1-B applications, most employees can't easily move and companies can not hire at the same speed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did a regular expression search for the term &lt;code&gt;Visa&lt;/code&gt; and the below chart shows the number of job postings that sponsors visa. As you the jobs which sponsor visa is less than 5%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;kg-gallery-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;kg-gallery-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;kg-gallery-image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://letstalkalgorithms.com/content/images/2018/12/jobs-with-visa-sponsorsh--2--1.svg&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;400&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;roles&quot;&gt;Roles&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While there are more engineering positions than anything else, I did a count of all roles including the level in software engineers and below is the chart that represents number of job posts over the last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;    &quot;Engineering Manager&quot;: 271,
    &quot;Principal Software Engineer&quot;: 25,
    &quot;Product Designer&quot;: 243,
    &quot;Product Manager&quot;: 425,
    &quot;Program Manager&quot;: 35,
    &quot;QA&quot;: 353,
    &quot;Senior Software Engineer&quot;: 818,
    &quot;Software Engineer&quot;: 2975,
    &quot;Staff Software Engineer&quot;: 10
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;kg-gallery-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;kg-gallery-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;kg-gallery-image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://letstalkalgorithms.com/content/images/2018/12/jobs-with-titles--2--1.svg&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;400&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;skills&quot;&gt;Skills&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was really curious to see the popular skills over the last year. I generated the count by using a pre-defined dictionary of skills and below are the counts and a chart that represents the top skills asked for in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edit&lt;/strong&gt;: After posting to HN, I realized some of the skills has false positives during regex search, so until they are updated, please consider these as direction in general, but not as the accurate count. Apologize for the inconsistent data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edit 2: The regex false positive issue is resolved. Fixed it by using word boundaries on regex &lt;code&gt;\\b&amp;lt;word&amp;gt;\\b&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;html, 277
python, 273
.net, 216
react, 211
php, 124
docker, 92
android, 89
c, 80
golang, 79
postgres, 69
ios, 67
javascript , 64
git, 61
ruby, 54
django, 53
kubernetes, 51
angular, 49
rails, 48
java, 40
linux, 39
typescript, 31
rust, 29
shell, 26
swift, 23
scala, 22
react.js, 21
css, 21
julia, 20
vue.js, 20
excel, 16
kotlin, 13
elixir, 13
graphql, 13
spring, 11
sql, 11
reactjs, 10
erlang, 9
perl, 7
lua, 6
mysql, 6
haskell, 5
apache, 4
vuejs, 4
objective-c, 2
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;kg-gallery-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;kg-gallery-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;kg-gallery-image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://letstalkalgorithms.com/content/images/2018/12/skills-in-2018--1-.svg&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;400&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;perks&quot;&gt;Perks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just curiously I checked for number of job posts which offered free lunch over the last year and below is the chart representing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;kg-gallery-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;kg-gallery-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;kg-gallery-image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://letstalkalgorithms.com/content/images/2018/12/jobs-with-free-lunch-1.svg&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;400&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope this helped in giving you some insight into the job posts on Hacker News. I will open source the code used to analyze all this after cleaning up by this weekend, currently it's a combination of Golang, Python, Amcharts, Highcharts to analyze and visualize the hiring data. Follow me on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/venkateshthallam&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; to get notified when the repo is up or check back this post over the weekend for the repo link.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update :&lt;/strong&gt; Added a very initial version of the code &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/2BAP70f&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to help people understand the process/logic i followed for the blog post. Running the code doesn't automatically generates the charts, but hoping to get the repo into that stage in sometime, so it could be reused for other kinds of analytics projects.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 15:02:21 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>vthallam</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Analysis of 2018 Hacker News &quot;Who is Hiring&quot; Job Posts</og:title>
<og:description>If you are an avid Hacker News user, you would know that there's a hiring comment thread during the start of every month called, Who is Hiring. Hundreds of companies from across the world post job posts as comments to that thread every month on the thread hoping to find potential employees.</og:description>
<og:url>http://letstalkalgorithms.com/analysis-of-2018-hacker-news-who-is-hiring-job-posts/</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://letstalkalgorithms.com/analysis-of-2018-hacker-news-who-is-hiring-job-posts/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>We should replace Facebook with personal websites</title>
<link>https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/vbanny/we-should-replace-facebook-with-personal-websites</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/vbanny/we-should-replace-facebook-with-personal-websites</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;As a freshman in high school, in the year of our lord 2002, I made a website called “Jason’s Site.” While a website named after myself and devoted to updates about my own life was unspeakably vain for the time, it was also quite forward looking: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.members.tripod.com/aggro88&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The site&lt;/a&gt; has a news feed, an “about me” page, and an email mailing list for people to receive updates. I intended for it to be funded by reader donations. It had a section for Flash videos and photos, a guestbook, and a “friends” page that was literally a list of my friends. It had an ill-advised but nonetheless prescient “hot or not” section that featured photos of my friends and acquaintances and predated both Facebook and Mark Zuckerberg’s original idea for the social network, called “FaceMash.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I &lt;a href=&quot;https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/wnj5qz/my-10-year-old-geocities-site-was-accused-of-hosting-pornbut-i-saved-it&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;updated the site regularly and obsessively&lt;/a&gt; for about three months, and then never returned to it. The site was embarrassing then and is embarrassing now, but abandoning it was a terrible mistake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I stopped updating my website, I didn’t stop posting online. I just found other places to do it. I made a Xanga, and then a LiveJournal, and then a MySpace. So did all my friends. We posted every day—photos from trips, friend and relationship drama, complaints about teachers, inside jokes. We were conditioned to post because only the weird kids did not post. There were rarely any consequences for posting the intimate details of our lives; the only consequences came from not participating in the online conversation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None of Xanga, LiveJournal, or MySpace managed to figure out how to monetize the stuff we posted in any meaningful sense. There were no targeted advertisements, and none of us ever thought about “personal data” or what could be done with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember the day that the University of Maryland gave incoming freshmen “@umd.edu” email addresses. This was a monumental day not because we were going to be in college soon—it was important because the email address would allow us to create Facebook accounts, since Facebook still required users to verify their profiles with a university email address.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we were first assigned our email addresses (a few weeks before high school graduation), I was in Ms. Brosnan’s genetics class, which had a handful of computers in the back of the classroom. About a dozen people crowded around the computers and started signing up for Facebook. We all did it, one after the other. We began looking for our friends who had already gone to college. And then, we kept posting, just like we had on MySpace. That was 12 years ago, and most of us haven’t stopped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking back, it’s not clear to me why we were all so excited to get a Facebook. We were already all on the same social networks. But someone—a popular kid, probably—decided that we were going to use Facebook, and so we all used Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook gets a lot of credit for “disrupting” social media and for turning MySpace into a worthless piece of garbage, but millions upon millions of teenagers and young adults were already sharing every aspect of their lives on other social networks, and on their own websites. Facebook had the good fortune of being new, slightly different, and exclusive. It was even luckier to come to power shortly before the rise of the smartphone. I guess what I’m saying is that Facebook isn’t really all that much better or more convenient than having your own website, or sending emails or chats. But for some reason, Facebook (and Instagram) are where we post now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s a subtext of the #deleteFacebook movement that has nothing to do with the company’s mishandling of personal data. It’s the idea that people who use Facebook are stupid, or shouldn’t have ever shared so much of their lives. But for people who came of age in the early 2000s, sharing our lives online is second nature, and largely came without consequences. There was no indication that something we’d been conditioned to do would be quickly weaponized against us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook has of course become something much larger than a single website, and has, despite its flaws, &quot;helped connect the world&quot; for better or worse. But Facebook tapped into a trend that was already happening—it didn't invent the idea of letting people put stuff about their lives online, it just monetized it better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I think about my own Facebook use, I think often about that first website I made, and how that site served the exact same purpose then that Facebook does now. My original sin wasn’t making a Facebook account, it was abandoning my own website that I controlled (the original site was hosted on Tripod, but if I had to do it all over again, I'd pay for web hosting.) All these years later, maybe it’s time to update Jason’s Site.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 15:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jbegley</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>We Should Replace Facebook With Personal Websites</og:title>
<og:image>https://video-images.vice.com/articles/5c1aaea91854f30006cb2f1e/lede/1545253629235-shutterstock_1063990172-copy.jpeg?crop=0.7749xw:1xh;0.0391xw,0xh&amp;resize=1200:*</og:image>
<og:url>https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/vbanny/we-should-replace-facebook-with-personal-websites</og:url>
<og:description>Personal websites and email can replace most of what people like about Facebook—namely the urge to post about their lives online.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/vbanny/we-should-replace-facebook-with-personal-websites</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Dear Developer, the Web Isn&amp;#039;t About You</title>
<link>https://www.sonniesedge.co.uk/talks/dear-developer</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.sonniesedge.co.uk/talks/dear-developer</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;We’re back to building sites that are not for everyone - huge, bloated sites, running fragile imperative code on the users local device. We have started to explicitly say &quot;I think you should have this level of tech, processing power, and bandwidth before I think you're eligible to use my site&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why? Because we want to have our fun with technology. Because we don't want to think about &quot;edge case&quot; user needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Edge case&quot; is, to be frank, a phrase that should be banned from all developer conversations (and then tattooed onto the forehead of anyone who continues to use it).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we say &quot;Edge Case&quot; we mean &quot;Stress Case&quot;. In their book, &lt;a href=&quot;https://abookapart.com/products/design-for-real-life&quot;&gt;Design for Real Life&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://meyerweb.com/&quot;&gt;Eric Meyer&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sarawb.com/&quot;&gt;Sara Wachter-Boettcher&lt;/a&gt; point out that what we glibly call an &quot;edge case&quot; is normally an enormously stressful event for a user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It often accompanies high emotions, stress, physical problems, financial problems, etc. When we discount and dismiss the &quot;edge case&quot;, we're actually saying &quot;I don't care about that particular user's stressful situation&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One succinct example I saw recently was an American chap trying to use an airline website while holidaying in SE Asia. His flight had been cancelled and he were trying to rebook. However, due to terrible internet connectivity in his location the site just wasn't loading - it was trying to pull down huge amounts of images and JS that were simply not happening on that connection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot; readability=&quot;5.3670886075949&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/webperf?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#webperf&lt;/a&gt; in Cambodia: Yesterday I tried to book a domestic flight through various booking platforms and airline sites. Gave up after an hour and called a travel agent to book at a premium.&lt;/p&gt;
— Holger Bartel (@foobartel) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/foobartel/status/946299864551276544?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;December 28, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He ended up calling a travel agent via telephone and rebooking. How much of an utter failure is your website if your drive someone off it and into another company's hands?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now imagine if that user had been able to disable Javascript and images and just have the HTML delivered. It wouldn't have been pretty, but it would have &lt;em&gt;worked&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wondered about this, and went to check out the website in question.It turns out that no, you can't. The website is fully JS-driven. If you disable JS then you just get a blank page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the same theme, here's another example. An Angular JS app, failing because of flaky airport wifi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-cards=&quot;hidden&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot; readability=&quot;4.7457627118644&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Your fancy AngularJS apps are all very nice until you're trying to check in for a flight on flaky wifi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://t.co/eTEXHE5XL2&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/eTEXHE5XL2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
— Matt Andrews (@mattpointblank) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mattpointblank/status/595627536748535808?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;May 5, 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are real situations, for real people. And these are only the ones that are reported, because the people in the stress situations are web professionals. How many thousands, millions, of interactions occur every day that no one reports because they're &quot;just&quot; regular users?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 14:05:01 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>colinprince</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.sonniesedge.co.uk/talks/dear-developer</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Slack closes account of an Iranian user living in Canada</title>
<link>https://twitter.com/a_h_a/status/1075510422617219077</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://twitter.com/a_h_a/status/1075510422617219077</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I’m in Canada
No ties to Iran
No teammates in Iran!

If using slack is against US sanctions, the same applies to google, twitter, facebook...

Basically, we should ethnically profile people and stop giving services to certain ethnicities.

Tomorrow, Iranians can’t ride the bus.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 11:50:56 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jwildeboer</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://mobile.twitter.com/a_h_a/status/1075510422617219077</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>VirtualBox 6.0 released</title>
<link>https://www.virtualbox.org/wiki/Changelog-6.0#v0</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.virtualbox.org/wiki/Changelog-6.0#v0</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;This page lists all changes of the VirtualBox 5.2 &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;wiki&quot; href=&quot;https://www.virtualbox.org/wiki/Downloads&quot;&gt;Downloads&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;All branches: &lt;a class=&quot;wiki&quot; href=&quot;https://www.virtualbox.org/wiki/Changelog&quot;&gt;6.0&lt;/a&gt; · &lt;a class=&quot;wiki&quot; href=&quot;https://www.virtualbox.org/wiki/Changelog-5.2&quot;&gt;5.2&lt;/a&gt; · &lt;a class=&quot;wiki&quot; href=&quot;https://www.virtualbox.org/wiki/Changelog-5.1&quot;&gt;5.1&lt;/a&gt; · &lt;a class=&quot;wiki&quot; href=&quot;https://www.virtualbox.org/wiki/Changelog-5.0&quot;&gt;5.0&lt;/a&gt; · &lt;a class=&quot;wiki&quot; href=&quot;https://www.virtualbox.org/wiki/Changelog-4.3&quot;&gt;4.3&lt;/a&gt; · &lt;a class=&quot;wiki&quot; href=&quot;https://www.virtualbox.org/wiki/Changelog-4.2&quot;&gt;4.2&lt;/a&gt; · &lt;a class=&quot;wiki&quot; href=&quot;https://www.virtualbox.org/wiki/Changelog-4.1&quot;&gt;4.1&lt;/a&gt; · &lt;a class=&quot;wiki&quot; href=&quot;https://www.virtualbox.org/wiki/Changelog-4.0&quot;&gt;4.0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;wikianchor&quot; id=&quot;v0&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;strong&gt;VirtualBox 6.0.0&lt;/strong&gt; (released December 18 2018)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a major update. The following major new features were added:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Implemented support for exporting a virtual machine to Oracle Cloud Infrastructure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;User interface: greatly improved HiDPI and scaling support, including better detection and per-machine configuration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Major rework of user interface with simpler and more powerful application and virtual machine set-up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;User interface: a new file manager enabling user to control the guest file system and copy files between host and guest.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Graphics: major update of 3D graphics support for Windows guests, and VMSVGA 3D graphics device emulation on Linux and Solaris guests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added support for surround speaker setups (as used by Windows 10 Build 1809)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added utility vboximg-mount on Apple hosts to access the content of guest disks on the host&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added support for using Hyper-V as the fallback execution core on Windows host, to avoid inability to run VMs at the price of reduced performance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;In addition, the following items were fixed and/or added:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Execution core: fixed single-stepping in certain circumstances (bug &lt;a class=&quot;closed ticket&quot; href=&quot;https://www.virtualbox.org/ticket/17316&quot; title=&quot;defect: Wrong instruction after single-step exception with 'rdtsc' -&amp;gt; fixed in 6.0 (closed: fixed)&quot;&gt;#17316&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;User interface: video and audio recording can now be separately enabled&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Audio/Video recording fixes and improvements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Audio: better support for attaching and detaching remote desktop connections&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Serial port emulation fixes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Serial ports: allow changing the serial port attachment while a machine is running (bug &lt;a class=&quot;closed ticket&quot; href=&quot;https://www.virtualbox.org/ticket/6115&quot; title=&quot;enhancement: Connect/Disconnect Serial ports (uart) on-the-fly via controlvm -&amp;gt; fixed ... (closed: fixed)&quot;&gt;#6115&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Networking: Added a workaround for older guests which do not enable bus mastering for the virtio PCI device&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Networking: fixed wrong RCODE from DNS AAAA query with --natdnshostresolver1 (bug &lt;a class=&quot;closed ticket&quot; href=&quot;https://www.virtualbox.org/ticket/18171&quot; title=&quot;defect: wrong RCODE from DNS AAAA query with --natdnshostresolver1 (with suggested ... (closed: fixed)&quot;&gt;#18171&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;iSCSI: In cases where there is no ambiguity, the LUN of an iSCSI target is automatically determined, for targets with non-zero LUNs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Transparently resize disk images when merging if possible&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VBoxManage: support for DHCP options&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed VNC/RDP (bug 18153)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Guest Control: various new interfaces and features (see SDK documentation)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linux hosts: support Linux 4.20 (thank you Larry Finger)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Solaris: installer fixes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shared folders: performance improvements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Guest Additions: improved shared folder auto-mounting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Windows Guest Additions: fix incorrect tablet co-ordinate handling with recent Windows 10 builds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linux Additions: fix for building vboxvideo on EL 7.6 standard kernel, contributed by Robert Conde (bug &lt;a class=&quot;closed ticket&quot; href=&quot;https://www.virtualbox.org/ticket/18093&quot; title=&quot;defect: Error building the graphics driver module in a RHEL 7.6 guest -&amp;gt; fixed ... (closed: fixed)&quot;&gt;#18093&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linux guests: support Linux 4.20 (thank you Larry Finger)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linux guests: support VMSVGA in the Linux and X11 Additions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MacOS Guest Additions: initial support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OS/2 Guest Additions: initial shared folder support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BIOS fixes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ACPI: Up to four custom ACPI tables can now be configured for a VM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 11:09:47 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>johanhammar</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.virtualbox.org/wiki/Changelog-6.0</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Max Planck Society Discontinues Agreement with Elsevier</title>
<link>https://www.mpdl.mpg.de/en/505</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.mpdl.mpg.de/en/505</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The President and scientific council members of the Max Planck Society (MPS), one of the world’s largest research performing organizations, counting 14,000 scientists who publish 12K new research articles a year—around 1500 of which in Elsevier journals, have mandated the Max Planck Digital Library to discontinue their Elsevier subscription when the current agreement expires on December 31, 2018. With this move the Society joins nearly 200 universities and research institutions in Germany who have already cancelled their individual agreements with Elsevier in the course of 2016 and 2017 and affirmed their support of the national licensing framework &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.projekt-deal.de/about-deal/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; class=&quot;external&quot;&gt;Projekt DEAL&lt;/a&gt;, led by the German Rector’s Conference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In response to the untenably increasing cost of access to scholarly journals and, more importantly, the stifling effect of the antiquated paywall system on the research process, Projekt DEAL was established to negotiate nationwide &lt;a href=&quot;http://esac-initiative.org/guidelines/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; class=&quot;external&quot;&gt;transformative agreements&lt;/a&gt; as a means to transition from the current subscription system to one based on open access publishing models that enable complete and immediate access to the latest research for scholars and citizens alike, free of cost or other barriers. “DEAL is fully in line with the objectives of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://oa2020.org/mission/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; class=&quot;external&quot;&gt;OA2020 Initiative&lt;/a&gt;, which is strongly supported by the Max Planck Society,’ emphasized MPS President Martin Stratmann.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The transformative agreement that the DEAL negotiators propose to the major academic publishers is a “publish and read” model covering open access publication of all scholarly articles by authors affiliated with German institutions and, at the same time, grant reading access for German institutions to the publisher’s entire portfolio of electronic journals still behind paywalls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As no sustainable offer according these fundamental criteria has been forthcoming from the publisher, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.projekt-deal.de/elsevier-news/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; class=&quot;external&quot;&gt;negotiations with Elsevier were suspended last July&lt;/a&gt;. Researchers at the 200 institutions supporting the DEAL negotiations have consequently foregone access to the Elsevier platform and are broadly making use of alternative routes for their research needs. The Max Planck Digital Library has already set in place mechanisms to address the content needs of its researchers when Elsevier shuts off access at the beginning of January.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The system of scholarly publishing today is a relic of the print era, and we want to activate a real paradigm shift in order to finally utilize the opportunities of the digital age”, says Gerard Meijer, director at Max Planck Society’s Fritz Haber Institute and a member of the DEAL negotiation team. In a strong show of support for the DEAL negotiations, 13 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hrk.de/press/press-releases/press-release/meldung/researchers-resign-editorship-of-elsevier-journals-4237/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; class=&quot;external&quot;&gt;prominent Max Planck Society scientists resigned from their positions as editors&lt;/a&gt; and members of the editorial and advisory boards of Elsevier journals in 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Transformative agreements are one of the primary strategies for driving large scale transition of scholarly publishing to open access and are increasingly being adopted by the scores of international supporters of our global Open Access 2020 Initiative”, says Ralf Schimmer, Deputy General Manager of the Max Planck Digital Library. ”As both producers and consumers of the research articles circulated through their journal platforms, we have the leverage to demand a system that meets the needs of our researchers, and by adopting these transformative agreements, we will be able to achieve our Society’s goal of publishing the vast majority of our researchers’ articles open access in a matter of a few short years. We have already accomplished such deals with some of the most relevant publishers to Max Planck researchers, such as Springer Nature, the Royal Society of Chemistry and the Institute of Physics Publishing. Further publishers will follow in 2019.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 10:02:24 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>stargazer-3</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-gb</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.mpdl.mpg.de/en/505</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Alphabet spinoff Malta raises $26M for technology to store power in molten salt</title>
<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-12-19/gates-bezos-among-billionaires-backing-alphabet-energy-spinoff</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-12-19/gates-bezos-among-billionaires-backing-alphabet-energy-spinoff</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-12-19/gates-bezos-among-billionaires-backing-alphabet-energy-spinoff&quot;&gt;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-12-19/gates-bezos-among-billionaires-backing-alphabet-energy-spinoff&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=18721754&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=18721754&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 236&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 128&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 01:27:31 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>lawrenceyan</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bloomberg.com/tosv2.html?vid=&amp;uuid=9174f890-04b3-11e9-828e-114256e555ee&amp;url=L25ld3MvYXJ0aWNsZXMvMjAxOC0xMi0xOS9nYXRlcy1iZXpvcy1hbW9uZy1iaWxsaW9uYWlyZXMtYmFja2luZy1hbHBoYWJldC1lbmVyZ3ktc3Bpbm9mZg==</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>WireGuard for iOS</title>
<link>https://lists.zx2c4.com/pipermail/wireguard/2018-December/003694.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://lists.zx2c4.com/pipermail/wireguard/2018-December/003694.html</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;title&gt;WireGuard for iOS - now in the App Store&lt;/title&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;Index&quot; href=&quot;index.html&quot; /&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;made&quot; href=&quot;mailto:wireguard%40lists.zx2c4.com?Subject=Re%3A%20WireGuard%20for%20iOS%20-%20now%20in%20the%20App%20Store&amp;amp;In-Reply-To=%3CCAHmME9ojT3jdxfiK6kQUn2PBtMyE_t%3Dmf%3Dy9vGcJazVFWnCuew%40mail.gmail.com%3E&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;robots&quot; content=&quot;index,nofollow&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta http-equiv=&quot;Content-Type&quot; content=&quot;text/html; charset=utf-8&quot; /&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;Previous&quot; href=&quot;003693.html&quot; /&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body bgcolor=&quot;#FFFFFF&quot; id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot; readability=&quot;58.150943396226&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jason A. Donenfeld&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:wireguard%40lists.zx2c4.com?Subject=Re%3A%20WireGuard%20for%20iOS%20-%20now%20in%20the%20App%20Store&amp;amp;In-Reply-To=%3CCAHmME9ojT3jdxfiK6kQUn2PBtMyE_t%3Dmf%3Dy9vGcJazVFWnCuew%40mail.gmail.com%3E&quot; title=&quot;WireGuard for iOS - now in the App Store&quot;&gt;Jason at zx2c4.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thu Dec 20 02:04:34 CET 2018&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;pre&gt;
Hi everybody,

Thanks to all of the extremely useful feedback we've received during
the TestFlight of WireGuard for iOS, Roopesh, Eric, and I have now
released a beta into the App Store itself:

&lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/wireguard/id1441195209?ls=1&amp;amp;mt=8&quot;&gt;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/wireguard/id1441195209?ls=1&amp;amp;mt=8&lt;/a&gt;
Depending on your region and Apple's caching semantics, this link
might take some unknown amount of time to begin working.

Apple requested a video of the app running on a physical device during
their review of the app, showing that it works. For the curiosity of
non-iPhone folks, you can see it here:
&lt;a href=&quot;https://data.zx2c4.com/wireguard-ios-app-store-review.mp4&quot;&gt;https://data.zx2c4.com/wireguard-ios-app-store-review.mp4&lt;/a&gt; . It's more
or less the same interface as on Android and is designed to be as
simple and &quot;system-like&quot; as possible, while still exposing all of the
features and flexibility of WireGuard.

Please do keep the feedback coming. At the moment, I'm especially
interested in reports of people transitioning between mobile and WiFi
when using T-Mobile's network within the US. But generally, all bug
reports, complete with the exported log, are very welcome, as we
continue to refine these beta releases.

As before, if you're interested in doing development on this app,
please get in touch with &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.zx2c4.com/mailman/listinfo/wireguard&quot;&gt;team at wireguard.com.&lt;/a&gt; Likewise, we're always
looking for a helping hand with a variety of tasks, including but not
limited to:
- iOS
- macOS
- Android
- Windows
- Web development (wireguard.com could use some love)
- Various kernels
- So forth

Enjoy,
Jason

On Mon, Nov 5, 2018 at 10:27 PM Jason A. Donenfeld &amp;lt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.zx2c4.com/mailman/listinfo/wireguard&quot;&gt;Jason at zx2c4.com&lt;/a&gt;&amp;gt; wrote:
&amp;gt;&lt;em&gt;
&lt;/em&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;em&gt; Hey folks,
&lt;/em&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;em&gt;
&lt;/em&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;em&gt; For the last few weeks, Roopesh and I have been hard at work on the
&lt;/em&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;em&gt; WireGuard for iOS app. Today we're happy to share a
&lt;/em&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;em&gt; likely-buggy-and-broken TestFlight that you can run on your phone:
&lt;/em&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;em&gt; &amp;lt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://testflight.apple.com/join/63I19SDT&quot;&gt;https://testflight.apple.com/join/63I19SDT&lt;/a&gt;&amp;gt;. As usual, use at your
&lt;/em&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;em&gt; own risk, especially since it's alpha quality.
&lt;/em&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;em&gt;
&lt;/em&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;em&gt; Please let us know about any bugs as you find them -- you can send
&lt;/em&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;em&gt; them to me or to &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.zx2c4.com/mailman/listinfo/wireguard&quot;&gt;team at wireguard.com.&lt;/a&gt; Our current TODO list lives here
&lt;/em&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;em&gt; [1], linked via the main project TODO list [2], and if you're an iOS
&lt;/em&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;em&gt; person and want to contribute code, we'd be happy to have you on
&lt;/em&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;em&gt; board.
&lt;/em&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;em&gt;
&lt;/em&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;em&gt; The app costs $3.99 and requires an email address to sign up; we
&lt;/em&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;em&gt; manage all your tunnels for you in the cloud. JUST KIDDING! Like the
&lt;/em&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;em&gt; rest of WireGuard, the iOS app is free and open source [3]. I make
&lt;/em&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;em&gt; this rather tasteless joke, because of the rather surprising
&lt;/em&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;em&gt; quantities of people encouraging me to do the iOS stuff as proprietary
&lt;/em&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;em&gt; paid software, because &quot;apple users will pay&quot; or because &quot;open source
&lt;/em&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;em&gt; is cool, but iphone folks don't care about it so you can get away with
&lt;/em&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;em&gt; charging&quot; or because &quot;none of the other vpn players are doing open
&lt;/em&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;em&gt; source mobile implementations&quot; or even because &quot;apple is more likely
&lt;/em&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;em&gt; to accept paid software into its app store&quot; and so on and so forth.
&lt;/em&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;em&gt; But, as usual, I much prefer for this to be a community project than a
&lt;/em&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;em&gt; closed one, and so like everything else, it's FLOSS.
&lt;/em&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;em&gt;
&lt;/em&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;em&gt; Enjoy! And do let us know about the bugs as you run into them. I'm
&lt;/em&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;em&gt; sure there are plenty.
&lt;/em&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;em&gt;
&lt;/em&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;em&gt; Regards,
&lt;/em&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;em&gt; Jason
&lt;/em&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;em&gt;
&lt;/em&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;em&gt; [1] &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1BnzImOF8CkungFnuRlWhnEpY2OmEHSckat62aZ6LYGY&quot;&gt;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1BnzImOF8CkungFnuRlWhnEpY2OmEHSckat62aZ6LYGY&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/em&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;em&gt; [2] &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wireguard.com/todo/&quot;&gt;https://www.wireguard.com/todo/&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/em&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;em&gt; [3] &lt;a href=&quot;https://git.zx2c4.com/wireguard-ios/&quot;&gt;https://git.zx2c4.com/wireguard-ios/&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.zx2c4.com/mailman/listinfo/wireguard&quot;&gt;More information about the WireGuard mailing list&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 01:05:49 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>bonyt</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://lists.zx2c4.com/pipermail/wireguard/2018-December/003694.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>MagicaVoxel: A free voxel art editor and path tracing renderer</title>
<link>https://ephtracy.github.io/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://ephtracy.github.io/</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://ephtracy.github.io/&quot;&gt;https://ephtracy.github.io/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=18721555&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=18721555&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 281&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 62&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 00:53:14 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Tideflat</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://ephtracy.github.io/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>