<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>SETI spots dozens of new mysterious signals emanating from distant galaxy</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2018/09/10/seti-neural-networks-spot-dozens-of-new-mysterious-signals-emanating-from-distant-galaxy/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2018/09/10/seti-neural-networks-spot-dozens-of-new-mysterious-signals-emanating-from-distant-galaxy/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The perennial optimists at the Search for Extraterrestrial Intelligence, or SETI, have joined the rest of the world in &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.berkeley.edu/2018/09/10/ai-helps-track-down-mysterious-cosmic-radio-bursts/&quot;&gt;deploying AI to help manage huge data sets&lt;/a&gt; — and their efforts almost instantly bore fruit. Seventy-two new “fast radio bursts” from a mysteriously noisy galaxy 3 billion miles away were discovered in previously analyzed data by using a custom machine learning model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be clear, this isn’t Morse code or encrypted instructions to build a teleporter, à la Contact, or at least not that we know of. But these fast radio bursts, or FRBs, are poorly understood and may very well represent, at the very least, some hitherto unobserved cosmic phenomenon. FRB 121102 is the only stellar object known to give off the signals regularly, and so is the target of continued observation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data comes from the Green Bank Telescope in West Virginia (above), which was pointed toward this source of fast and bright (hence the name) bursts for five hours in August of 2017. Believe it or not, that five-hour session yielded 400 &lt;em&gt;terabytes&lt;/em&gt; of transmission data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initial “standard” algorithms identified 21 FRBs, all happening in one hour’s worth of the observations. But Gerry Zhang, a graduate student at UC Berkeley and part of the Breakthrough Listen project, created a convolutional neural network system that would theoretically scour the data set more effectively. Sure enough, the machine learning model picked out &lt;em&gt;72&lt;/em&gt; more FRBs in the same period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_1709207&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;breakout size-full wp-image-1709207&quot; src=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/FRB121102_750.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;750&quot; height=&quot;500&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;A Berkeley GIF visualizing the data of a series of bursts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s quite an improvement, though it’s worth noting that without manual and traditional methods to find an initial set of interesting data, we would have little with which to train such neural networks. They’re complementary tools; one is not necessarily succeeding the other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The paper on the discoveries, co-authored by Cal postdoc Vishal Gajjar, is due to be published in the Astrophysical Journal. Breakthrough Listen is &lt;a href=&quot;https://breakthroughinitiatives.org/about&quot;&gt;one of the initiatives&lt;/a&gt; funded by billionaires Yuri and Julia Milner, of mail.ru and DST fame. The organization &lt;a href=&quot;https://breakthroughinitiatives.org/news/22&quot;&gt;posted its own press release&lt;/a&gt; for the work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new data suggests that the signals are not being received in any kind of pattern we can determine, at least no pattern longer than 10 milliseconds. That may sound discouraging, but it’s just as important to rule things out as it is to find something new.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Gerry’s work is exciting not just because it helps us understand the dynamic behavior of FRBs in more detail, but also because of the promise it shows for using machine learning to detect signals missed by classical algorithms,” explained Berkeley’s Andrew Siemion, who leads the SETI research center there and is principal investigator for Breakthrough Listen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if we’re being imaginative, there’s no reason some hyper-advanced civilization couldn’t cram a bunch of interesting info into such short bursts, or use a pattern we haven’t yet grokked. We don’t know what we don’t know, after all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever the case, SETI and Breakthrough will continue to keep their antennas fastened on FRB 121102. Even if they don’t turn out to be alien SOS signals, it’s good solid science. You can keep up with the Berkeley SETI center’s work &lt;a href=&quot;http://seti.berkeley.edu/&quot;&gt;right here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 18:26:21 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>vfc1</dc:creator>
<og:title>SETI neural networks spot dozens of new mysterious signals emanating from distant galaxy</og:title>
<og:description>The perennial optimists at the Search for Extraterrestrial Intelligence, or SETI, have joined the rest of the world in deploying AI to help manage huge datasets — and their efforts almost instantly bore fruit. 72 new &quot;fast radio bursts&quot; from a mysteriously noisy galaxy 3 billion miles away were dis…</og:description>
<og:image>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/greenbanktelescope.jpg?w=600</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2018/09/10/seti-neural-networks-spot-dozens-of-new-mysterious-signals-emanating-from-distant-galaxy/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2018/09/10/seti-neural-networks-spot-dozens-of-new-mysterious-signals-emanating-from-distant-galaxy/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Google Scientist Resigns Over “Forfeiture of Our Values” in China</title>
<link>https://theintercept.com/2018/09/13/google-china-search-engine-employee-resigns/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://theintercept.com/2018/09/13/google-china-search-engine-employee-resigns/</guid>
<description>&lt;div data-reactid=&quot;187&quot; readability=&quot;123.56960375391&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;A senior Google&lt;/u&gt; research scientist has quit the company in protest over its plan to launch a censored version of its search engine in China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;P1&quot;&gt;Jack Pou&lt;span class=&quot;T7&quot;&gt;l&lt;/span&gt;son worked for Google’s &lt;span class=&quot;T30&quot;&gt;research and machine intelligence&lt;/span&gt; department, where he &lt;span class=&quot;T24&quot;&gt;was focused on improving the accuracy of the company’s search systems.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;P14&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;T8&quot;&gt;In early August, Poulson raised concerns with his managers at Google after The Intercept&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;Internet_20_link&quot; href=&quot;https://theintercept.com/2018/08/01/google-china-search-engine-censorship/&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;T8&quot;&gt;revealed&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;T8&quot;&gt;that the internet giant was secretly developing a Chinese search app for Android devices. The search system, code-named Dragonfly, was designed to remove content that China’s authoritarian government views as sensitive, such as&lt;/span&gt; information about political dissidents, free speech, democracy, human rights, and peaceful protest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;P4&quot;&gt;After entering into discussions with his bosses, Poulson decided in mid-August that he could no longer work for Google. H&lt;span class=&quot;T1&quot;&gt;e tendered his resignation and his last day at the company was August  31.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;P6&quot;&gt;He told The Intercept in an interview that he &lt;span class=&quot;T28&quot;&gt;believes he&lt;/span&gt; is one of about five of the company’s employees to resign over Dragonfly. He felt it was his “ethical responsibility to resign in protest of the forfeiture of our public human rights commitments,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;P23&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;T9&quot;&gt;Poulson, who was previously an assistant professor at Stanford University’s department of mathematics, said he believed that the China plan had violated Google’s artificial intelligence principles, which state that the company will not design or deploy&lt;/span&gt; technologies “whose purpose contravenes widely accepted principles of international law and human rights.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;P26&quot;&gt;He said that he was concerned not just about the censorship itself, but also the ramifications of hosting customer data on the Chinese mainland, where it would be accessible to Chinese security agencies that are well-known for targeting political activists and journalists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;P5&quot;&gt;In &lt;span class=&quot;T2&quot;&gt;his&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;T10&quot;&gt;resignation&lt;/span&gt; lette&lt;span class=&quot;T2&quot;&gt;r,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;T2&quot;&gt;Poulson&lt;/span&gt; told his &lt;span class=&quot;T2&quot;&gt;bosses&lt;/span&gt;: “&lt;span class=&quot;T8&quot;&gt;Due to my conviction that dissent is fundamental to functioning democracies, I am forced to resign in order to avoid contributing to, or profiting from, the erosion of protection for dissidents.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;P7&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;T12&quot;&gt;“I&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;T11&quot;&gt;view our intent to capitulate to censorship and surve&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;T14&quot;&gt;i&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;T11&quot;&gt;llance demands in exchange for access to the&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;T15&quot;&gt;C&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;T11&quot;&gt;hinese&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;T13&quot;&gt;market as a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;T15&quot;&gt;forfeiture&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;T13&quot;&gt;of our values and governmental negotiating position across the globe,” he wrote, adding:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;T3&quot;&gt;“There is an all-too-real possibility that other nations will attempt to leverage our actions in China in order to demand our compliance with their security demands.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;stylized pull-right&quot; data-shortcode-type=&quot;pullquote&quot; data-pull=&quot;right&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;T12&quot;&gt;“&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;T8&quot;&gt;I am forced to resign in order to avoid contributing to, or profiting from, the erosion of protection for dissidents.&lt;span class=&quot;T3&quot;&gt;”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;P18&quot;&gt;In the six weeks since the revelations about Dragonfly, Google has still not publicly addressed concerns about the project, despite facing a &lt;span class=&quot;T25&quot;&gt;major&lt;/span&gt; backlash &lt;span class=&quot;T23&quot;&gt;internally and externally&lt;/span&gt;. &lt;span class=&quot;T22&quot;&gt;Earlier this month,&lt;/span&gt; Google CEO Sundar Pichai refused to appear at a Senate Intelligence Committee hearing, &lt;span class=&quot;T2&quot;&gt;where he would have been asked questions about the China censorship. The company&lt;/span&gt; has ignored dozens of &lt;a href=&quot;https://theintercept.com/2018/08/17/internal-meeting-reveals-how-google-bosses-misled-staff-on-their-china-censorship-plan-here-are-the-questions-they-must-answer/&quot;&gt;questions&lt;/a&gt; from journalists about the plan &lt;span class=&quot;T21&quot;&gt;and it has stonewalled leading human rights groups, who&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;Internet_20_link&quot; href=&quot;https://theintercept.com/2018/08/28/google-china-censorship-plan-human-rights/&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;T21&quot;&gt;say&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;T21&quot;&gt;that the censored search engine&lt;/span&gt; could result in the company “directly contributing to, or [becoming] complicit in, human rights violations.” &lt;span class=&quot;T27&quot;&gt;(Google also did not respond to an inquiry for this story.)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;P8&quot;&gt;Poulson, 32, &lt;span class=&quot;T16&quot;&gt;who began working for Google in May 2016,&lt;/span&gt; told The Intercept that the company’s public silence fueled his sense of frustration. “&lt;span class=&quot;T16&quot;&gt;There are serious worldwide repercussions to this,” he said. “What are Google’s ethical red lines? We already wrote some down, but now we seem to be crossing those. I would really like to see statements about what Google’s commitments are.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;P19&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;T16&quot;&gt;Google launched a censored search engine in China in 2006, but stopped operating the service in the country in 2010, citing Chinese government efforts to limit free speech, block websites, and hack people’s Gmail accounts. At that time, Google co-founder Sergey Brin made clear that he was strongly opposed to the censorship. Brin had spent part of his childhood in the Soviet Union, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.spiegel.de/international/business/google-co-founder-on-pulling-out-of-china-it-was-a-real-step-backward-a-686269.html&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; that he was “&lt;/span&gt;particularly sensitive to the stifling of individual liberties” &lt;span class=&quot;T19&quot;&gt;due to his family’s experiences there.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;T19&quot;&gt;In 2010, after the company pulled its search engine out of China, Brin &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/SB10001424052748704266504575141064259998090&quot;&gt;told&lt;/a&gt; the Wall Street Journal that “with respect to censorship, with respect to surveillance of dissidents” he saw “earmarks of totalitarianism [in China], and I find that personally quite troubling.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;P27&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;T5&quot;&gt;Poulson said that he “very&lt;/span&gt; much agree&lt;span class=&quot;T5&quot;&gt;[s]&lt;/span&gt; with &lt;span class=&quot;T5&quot;&gt;the&lt;/span&gt; case Sergey made in 2010. That’s the company I joined, the one that was making that statement.” &lt;span class=&quot;T18&quot;&gt;If the anti-censorship stance is shifting, he said, then he could no longer “be complicit as a shareholder and citizen of the company.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;P28&quot;&gt;Only a few hundred of Google’s 88,000 employees knew about Dragonfly before it was publicly exposed. Poulson was one of the majority who were kept in the dark. &lt;span class=&quot;T31&quot;&gt;But because he was focused on improving the company’s search systems — specifically in an area called “international query analysis” — it is possible his work could have been integrated into the censored Chinese search engine without his knowledge or consent.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;P9&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;T4&quot;&gt;Once news of Dragonfly spread through Google, there were protests inside the company. More than 1,400 of the internet giant’s employees&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;Internet_20_link&quot; href=&quot;https://theintercept.com/2018/08/16/google-china-crisis-staff-dragonfly/&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;T4&quot;&gt;signed a letter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;T4&quot;&gt;demanding an ombudsman be appointed to assess the&lt;/span&gt; “urgent moral and ethical issues” &lt;span class=&quot;T5&quot;&gt;they said were raised by the  censorship plan. The letter condemned the secrecy surrounding Dragonfly and stated: “&lt;/span&gt;We urgently need more transparency, a seat at the table, and a commitment to clear and open processes: Google employees need to know what we’re building.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div data-reactid=&quot;197&quot; readability=&quot;33.619846261356&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;P10&quot;&gt;Google bosses have &lt;a class=&quot;Internet_20_link&quot; href=&quot;https://theintercept.com/2018/08/03/google-search-engine-china-censorship-backlash/&quot;&gt;tried to contain&lt;/a&gt; the anger by shutting down employee access to documents about the China &lt;span class=&quot;T26&quot;&gt;search engine&lt;/span&gt;. &lt;span class=&quot;T17&quot;&gt;F&lt;/span&gt;ollowing leaks from an all-hands staff meeting &lt;span class=&quot;T17&quot;&gt;last month, sources said, the company has tightened rules so that employees working remotely can no longer view a livestream of the meetings on their own computers — they can only watch them inside a designated room at a Google office overseen by managers.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;P12&quot;&gt;Poulson said he considered staying &lt;span class=&quot;T26&quot;&gt;on&lt;/span&gt; as an employee of Google and trying to raise his protests from within. Some of his colleagues &lt;span class=&quot;T20&quot;&gt;argued&lt;/span&gt; that the decision to launch the Chinese search engine &lt;span class=&quot;T20&quot;&gt;may still be reversed&lt;/span&gt;, and &lt;span class=&quot;T20&quot;&gt;encouraged him&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;T20&quot;&gt;to&lt;/span&gt; wait before &lt;span class=&quot;T20&quot;&gt;making his call on resigning. “But then I have no chance of changing that decision,” he said, “whereas if I resign beforehand, then there’s some chance of impact.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;P11&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;T6&quot;&gt;Between May 2016 and July 2017, Poulson worked out of Google’s Mountain View headquarters, before he relocated to company offices in Toronto. He said he views his former Google colleagues as some of the smartest and most hardworking people he has ever met. But he is surprised&lt;/span&gt; more of the company’s employees have not &lt;span class=&quot;T19&quot;&gt;quit&lt;/span&gt; over &lt;span class=&quot;T19&quot;&gt;Dragonfly&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;P13&quot;&gt;“&lt;span class=&quot;T2&quot;&gt;It’s incredible how little solidarity there is on this,” he said. “It is my understanding that when you have a serious ethical disagreement with an issue, your proper course of action is to resign.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Top photo: Jack Poulson.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 17:18:53 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jessaustin</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://theintercept.com/2018/09/13/google-china-search-engine-employee-resigns/</og:url>
<og:description>The specialist said that the plan to resume the censored search engine project in China could endanger dissidents and encourage online repression elsewhere.</og:description>
<og:image>https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2018/09/jack-poulson-1536850686-e1536850752383.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;q=90&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=1200&amp;h=800</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Senior Google Scientist Resigns Over “Forfeiture of Our Values” in China</og:title>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://theintercept.com/2018/09/13/google-china-search-engine-employee-resigns/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Amazon&amp;#039;s Bezos Launches $2B Fund to Help the Homeless</title>
<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-09-13/amazon-s-bezos-launches-2-billion-fund-to-help-the-homeless</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-09-13/amazon-s-bezos-launches-2-billion-fund-to-help-the-homeless</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;title&gt;Terms of Service Violation&lt;/title&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot; readability=&quot;24&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;container&quot; readability=&quot;9.4285714285714&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/graphics/assets/img/BB-Logo-2line.svg&quot; width=&quot;310&quot;/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your usage has been flagged as a violation of our &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bloomberg.com/tos&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;terms of service&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For inquiries related to this message please &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bloomberg.com/feedback&quot;&gt;contact support&lt;/a&gt;. For sales inquiries, please visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bloomberg.com/professional/request-demo&quot;&gt;http://www.bloomberg.com/professional/request-demo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;If you believe this to be in error, please confirm below that you are not a robot by clicking &quot;I'm not a robot&quot; below.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Please make sure your browser supports JavaScript and cookies and that you are not blocking them from loading. For more information you can review the Terms of Service and Cookie Policy.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;block_uuid&quot;&gt;Block reference ID:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 15:43:35 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>dpflan</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bloomberg.com/tosv2.html?vid=&amp;uuid=5043dfc0-b7b1-11e8-94cf-3dca1476d6dd&amp;url=L25ld3MvYXJ0aWNsZXMvMjAxOC0wOS0xMy9hbWF6b24tcy1iZXpvcy1sYXVuY2hlcy0yLWJpbGxpb24tZnVuZC10by1oZWxwLXRoZS1ob21lbGVzcw==</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Where in the World Is Larry Page?</title>
<link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2018-09-13/larry-page-is-a-no-show-with-google-under-a-harsh-spotlight</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2018-09-13/larry-page-is-a-no-show-with-google-under-a-harsh-spotlight</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;title&gt;Terms of Service Violation&lt;/title&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot; readability=&quot;24&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;container&quot; readability=&quot;9.4285714285714&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/graphics/assets/img/BB-Logo-2line.svg&quot; width=&quot;310&quot;/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your usage has been flagged as a violation of our &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bloomberg.com/tos&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;terms of service&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For inquiries related to this message please &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bloomberg.com/feedback&quot;&gt;contact support&lt;/a&gt;. For sales inquiries, please visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bloomberg.com/professional/request-demo&quot;&gt;http://www.bloomberg.com/professional/request-demo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;If you believe this to be in error, please confirm below that you are not a robot by clicking &quot;I'm not a robot&quot; below.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Please make sure your browser supports JavaScript and cookies and that you are not blocking them from loading. For more information you can review the Terms of Service and Cookie Policy.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;block_uuid&quot;&gt;Block reference ID:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 12:49:20 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>kshatrea</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bloomberg.com/tosv2.html?vid=&amp;uuid=504454f0-b7b1-11e8-a16d-4355ff9ecc10&amp;url=L25ld3MvZmVhdHVyZXMvMjAxOC0wOS0xMy9sYXJyeS1wYWdlLWlzLWEtbm8tc2hvdy13aXRoLWdvb2dsZS11bmRlci1hLWhhcnNoLXNwb3RsaWdodA==</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Using Rust for Game Development [video]</title>
<link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aKLntZcp27M</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aKLntZcp27M</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;eow-description&quot; class=&quot;&quot;&gt;RustConf 2018 - Closing Keynote by Catherine West&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When you’re just starting out in Rust, you start by building small programs. As we all know though, medium and large projects can have very different, unique kinds of problems that smaller projects never encounter. As our projects grow in size, we need to be increasingly concerned about code organization, separation of concerns, implementation hiding, and other techniques to manage growing complexity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most languages have tools and patterns to deal with this, and Rust is no exception. However, the patterns that we learned from other languages, especially in mainstream OO languages, are often unhelpful when applied to Rust, and this can lead to a roadblock when trying to transition to building moderate or large Rust programs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talk will cover a case study of a moderate sized game engine written in Rust and Lua, and show strategies for implementing things in Rust where common implementations in other mainstream languages are a poor fit. I’ll also discuss some examples of problems unique to Rust that ended up with very nice —but sometimes not obvious— solutions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Along the way, I’d also like to discuss working with Rust in game development generally, and what it’s like getting Rust to run on mainstream game consoles.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Slides at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/redirect?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.dropbox.com%2Fs%2Fyphqy57kwe7nsdj%2Frustconf-talk.pdf&amp;amp;v=aKLntZcp27M&amp;amp;event=video_description&amp;amp;redir_token=ivWhbFBfYSOfb6w-SmJd9JQDfsZ8MTUzNjk2OTY4MkAxNTM2ODgzMjgy&quot; class=&quot;yt-uix-sessionlink&quot; data-sessionlink=&quot;itct=CDUQ6TgYACITCMGEzrCYud0CFc3axAod7cgKdij4HUizt6e52fa50Wg&quot; data-url=&quot;/redirect?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.dropbox.com%2Fs%2Fyphqy57kwe7nsdj%2Frustconf-talk.pdf&amp;amp;v=aKLntZcp27M&amp;amp;event=video_description&amp;amp;redir_token=ivWhbFBfYSOfb6w-SmJd9JQDfsZ8MTUzNjk2OTY4MkAxNTM2ODgzMjgy&quot; data-target-new-window=&quot;True&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://www.dropbox.com/s/yphqy57kwe7...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 12:02:46 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>tpush</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aKLntZcp27M</og:url>
<og:title>RustConf 2018 - Closing Keynote - Using Rust For Game Development by Catherine West</og:title>
<og:image>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/aKLntZcp27M/maxresdefault.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>RustConf 2018 - Closing Keynote by Catherine West When you’re just starting out in Rust, you start by building small programs. As we all know though, medium ...</og:description>
<og:type>video.other</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aKLntZcp27M</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>UK’s mass surveillance regime violated human rights law, finds ECHR</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2018/09/13/uks-mass-surveillance-regime-violated-human-rights-law-finds-echr/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2018/09/13/uks-mass-surveillance-regime-violated-human-rights-law-finds-echr/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The complaints in this case were lodged prior to the UK legislating for a new surveillance regime, the 2016 Investigatory Powers Act, so in coming to a judgement the Chamber was considering the oversight regime at the time (and in the case of points 1 and 3 above that’s the Regulation of Investigatory Powers Act 2000).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RIPA has since been superseded by IPA but, as noted above, today’s ruling will likely fuel ongoing human rights challenges to the latter — which the government has already been ordered to amend by other courts on human rights grounds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nor is it the only UK surveillance legislation judged to fall foul on that front. A few years ago UK judges agreed with a similar legal challenge to emergency surveillance legislation that predates IPA — ruling in &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2015/07/17/u-k-emergency-surveillance-law-ruled-unlawful-by-high-court/&quot;&gt;2015&lt;/a&gt; that DRIPA was unlawful under human rights law. A verdict the UK Court of Appeal agreed with, &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/01/30/uk-keeps-up-its-legal-losing-streak-over-mass-surveillance/&quot;&gt;earlier this year&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also in 2015 the intelligence agencies’ own oversight court, the IPT, also found &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2015/06/23/u-k-spy-oversight-court-rules-gchq-acted-unlawfully-again/&quot;&gt;multiple&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2015/02/06/ipt-nsa-gchq-ruling/&quot;&gt;violations&lt;/a&gt; following challenges to aspects of its historical surveillance operations, after they have been made public by the Snowden revelations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such judgements did not stop the government &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2016/11/17/uk-parliament-rubberstamps-mass-surveillance-law/&quot;&gt;pushing on with the IPA&lt;/a&gt;, though — and it went on to cement bulk collection at the core of its surveillance modus operandi at the end of 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among the most &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2016/11/29/yes-the-uk-now-has-a-law-to-log-web-users-browsing-behavior-hack-devices-and-limit-encryption/&quot;&gt;controversial elements of the IPA&lt;/a&gt; is a requirement that communications service providers collect and retain logs on the web activity of the digital services accessed by all users for 12 months; state power &lt;a href=&quot;https://beta.techcrunch.com/2016/07/15/uk-surveillance-bill-includes-powers-to-limit-end-to-end-encryption/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;to require a company to remove encryption&lt;/a&gt;, or limit the rollout of end-to-end encryption on a future service; and&lt;span&gt; state powers to hack devices, networks and services, including &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://beta.techcrunch.com/2016/08/08/uk-faces-human-rights-challenge-to-states-bulk-hacking-abroad/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;bulk hacking&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt; on foreign soil. It also allows the security agencies to maintain &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://beta.techcrunch.com/2015/03/12/isc-report-privacy-and-security-report/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;large databases of personal information on U.K. citizens&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, including individuals suspected of no crime.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the safeguards front the government legislated for what it claimed was a “double lock” authorization process for interception warrants — which loops in the judiciary to signing off intercept warrants for the first time in the U.K., along with senior ministers. However this does not regulate the collection or accessing of web activity data that’s blanket-retained on all users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/04/27/uk-mass-surveillance-regime-dealt-another-blow-in-court/&quot;&gt;April&lt;/a&gt; this shiny new surveillance regime was also dealt a blow in UK courts — with judges ordering the government to amend the legislation to narrow how and why retained metadata could be accessed, giving ministers a deadline of November 1 to make the necessary changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In that case the judges also did not rule against bulk collection in general — declining to find that the state’s current data retention regime is unlawful on the grounds that it constituted “general and indiscriminate” retention of data. (For its part the government has always argued its bulk collection activities do not constitute blanket retention.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And today’s ECHR ruling further focuses attention on the safeguards placed &lt;em&gt;around&lt;/em&gt; bulk collection programs — having found the UK regime lacked sufficient monitoring to be lawful (but not that bulk collection itself is unlawful by default).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Opponents of the current surveillance regime will be busily parsing the ruling to find fresh fronts to attack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed breakout&quot; readability=&quot;7.6932203389831&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-width=&quot;550&quot; data-dnt=&quot;true&quot; readability=&quot;9.0508474576271&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;The battle moves on now to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/libertyhq?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@libertyhq&lt;/a&gt;’s litigation challenging the current Snoopers Charter – the Investigatory Powers Act. Many of the legal flaws slammed in today’s decision are baked into that law. The wind is in our sails today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Corey Stoughton (@CoreyStoughton) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/CoreyStoughton/status/1040170939835658241?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;September 13, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not the first time the ECHR has looked at bulk interception. Most recently, in June 2018, it deemed Swedish legislation and practice in the field of signals intelligence did not violate EU human rights law. Among its reasoning was that it found the Swedish system to have provided “adequate and sufficient guarantees against arbitrariness and the risk of abuse”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However it said the Big Brother Watch and Others vs United Kingdom case being ruled upon today is the first case in which it specifically considered the extent of the interference with a person’s private life that could result from the interception and examination of communications data (as opposed to content).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.echr.coe.int/Documents/Press_Q_A_Brother_Watch_ENG.pdf&quot;&gt;Q&amp;amp;A&lt;/a&gt; about today’s judgement, the court notes that it “expressly recognised” the severity of threats facing states, and also how advancements in technology have “made it easier for terrorists and criminals to evade detection on the Internet”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It therefore held that States should enjoy a broad discretion in choosing how best to protect national security. Consequently, a State may operate a bulk interception regime if it considers that it is necessary in the interests of national security. That being said, the Court could not ignore the fact that surveillance regimes have the potential to be abused, with serious consequences for individual privacy. In order to minimise this risk, the Court has previously identified six minimum safeguards which all interception regimes must have,” it writes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The safeguards are that the national law must clearly indicate: the nature of offences which may give rise to an interception order; a definition of the categories of people liable to have their communications intercepted; a limit on the duration of interception; the procedure to be followed for examining, using and storing the data obtained; the precautions to be taken when communicating the data to other parties; and the circumstances in which intercepted data may or must be erased or destroyed.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Additional elements the court says it considered in an earlier surveillance case, Roman Zakharov v. Russia, also to determine whether legislation breached Article 8, included “arrangements for supervising the implementation of secret surveillance measures, any notification mechanisms and the remedies provided for by national law”.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Commenting on today’s ruling in a statement, Megan Goulding, a lawyer for Liberty, said: “This is a major victory for the rights and freedom of people in the UK. It shows that there is — and should be — a limit to the extent that states can spy on their citizens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Police and intelligence agencies need covert surveillance powers to tackle the threats we face today — but the court has ruled that those threats do not justify spying on every citizen without adequate protections. Our government has built a surveillance regime more extreme than that of any other democratic nation, abandoning the very rights and freedoms terrorists want to attack. It can and must give us an effective, targeted system that protects our safety, data security and fundamental rights.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Liberty spokeswoman also told us it will continue its challenge to IPA in the UK High Court, adding: “We continue to believe that mass surveillance can never be compliant in a free, rights-respecting democracy.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also commenting in a statement, Silkie Carlo, director of Big Brother Watch, said: “This landmark judgment confirming that the UK’s mass spying breached fundamental rights vindicates Mr Snowden’s courageous whistleblowing and the tireless work of Big Brother Watch and others in our pursuit for justice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Under the guise of counter-terrorism, the UK has adopted the most authoritarian surveillance regime of any Western state, corroding democracy itself and the rights of the British public. This judgment is a vital step towards protecting millions of law-abiding citizens from unjustified intrusion. However, since the new Investigatory Powers Act arguably poses an ever greater threat to civil liberties, our work is far from over.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A spokesperson for &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://crunchbase.com/organization/privacy-international&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;privacy-international&quot;&gt;Privacy International&lt;/a&gt; told us it’s considering taking the case to the ECHR’s Grand Chamber.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also commenting in a supporting statement, Antonia Byatt, director of English PEN, added: “This judgment confirms that the British government’s surveillance practices have violated not only our right to privacy, but our right to freedom of expression too. Excessive surveillance discourages whistle-blowing and discourages investigative journalism. The government must now take action to guarantee our freedom to write and to read freely online.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve reached out to the Home Office for comment from the UK government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On intelligence sharing between governments, which the court had not previously considered, the judges found that &lt;span&gt;the procedure for requesting either the interception or the conveyance of intercept material from foreign intelligence agencies to have been set out with “sufficient clarity in the domestic law and relevant code of practice”, noting: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;“In particular, material from foreign agencies could only be searched if all the requirements for searching material obtained by the UK security services were fulfilled.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;It also found “no evidence of any significant shortcomings in the application and operation of the regime, or indeed evidence of any abuse” — hence finding the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;intelligence sharing regime did not violate Article 8.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the portion of the challenge concerning complaints that UK intelligence agencies’ oversight court, the IPT, &lt;span&gt;lacked independence and impartiality, the court disagreed — finding that the tribunal had “extensive power to consider complaints concerning wrongful interference with communications, and those extensive powers had been employed in the applicants’ case to ensure the fairness of the proceedings”.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;“Most notably, the IPT had access to open and closed material and it had appointed Counsel to the Tribunal to make submissions on behalf of the applicants in the closed proceedings,” it also writes.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, it said it accepted the government’s argument that in order to &lt;span&gt;ensure the efficacy of the secret surveillance regime restrictions on the applicants’ procedural rights had been “both necessary and proportionate and had not impaired the essence of their Article 6 rights”.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 11:40:53 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>sahin-boydas</dc:creator>
<og:title>UK’s mass surveillance regime violated human rights law, finds ECHR</og:title>
<og:description>In another blow to the UK government’s record on bulk data handling for intelligence purposes the European Court of Human Rights (ECHR) has ruled that state surveillance practices violated human rights law. Arguments against the UK intelligence agencies’ bulk collection and data sharing…</og:description>
<og:image>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/3029613413_145219499e_b.jpg?w=491</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2018/09/13/uks-mass-surveillance-regime-violated-human-rights-law-finds-echr/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2018/09/13/uks-mass-surveillance-regime-violated-human-rights-law-finds-echr/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Yarn Plug&amp;#039;n&amp;#039;Play: Getting rid of node_modules</title>
<link>https://github.com/yarnpkg/rfcs/pull/101</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/yarnpkg/rfcs/pull/101</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TL;DR:&lt;/strong&gt; Plug 'N Play is a good idea. &lt;code&gt;.pnp.js&lt;/code&gt; is a bad idea. &lt;code&gt;.pnp.json&lt;/code&gt; would be a better idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To preface this, I think Plug 'N Play is a great idea. My concerns come from the dependency analysis side. My day job is building analysis tools at &lt;a href=&quot;https://fossa.io&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;FOSSA&lt;/a&gt;, and I've worked with a lot of package managers while building the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/fossas/fossa-cli&quot;&gt;FOSSA CLI&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;code&gt;.pnp.js&lt;/code&gt; is much harder to analyse than &lt;code&gt;node_modules&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There should be a method to access the Plug 'n Play API in a language-agnostic way &lt;strong&gt;without requiring a Node.JS runtime&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At FOSSA, we do dependency analysis in a variety of environments. We need to provide results reliably across these environments, including environments where Node.JS is not available. This use case is surprisingly common for us:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;A project-specific CI image with Node.JS does the actual &lt;code&gt;npm install&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;npm test&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An organisation-wide CI image runs &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/fossas/fossa-cli&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;fossa-cli&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to do dependency analysis. This image &lt;strong&gt;does not have Node.JS&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;Often, we need to integrate with the organisation-wide CI image due to internal political or resourcing constraints that are out of our control. This is often the only feasible way to integrate across thousands of projects in an organisation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the current &lt;code&gt;node_modules&lt;/code&gt; scheme, this is easy: we emulate Node's behaviour by searching for &lt;code&gt;node_modules&lt;/code&gt; folders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The proposal for Plug 'n Play provides an executable JavaScript file as an API. This is hard for us to handle when we don't have a JavaScript interpreter available. To handle this, we have two options:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Package and ship a JS interpreter with the dependency analysis tool (please don't make me write this code).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Convince the organisation to add Node.JS to their organisation-wide CI image (this is very hard, and the build/release/CI/devops teams at these organisations will rightly push back that this adds too much complexity and attack surface to their images).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;The proposal claims that generating an executable script as an API provides better encapsulation than using a file format while still being easily consumable by other languages (by executing the script and reading its JSON output). I disagree on both points:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;If the script provides machine-parseable output, its output format will be frozen in the same way that any file format would be constrained. Conversely, &lt;code&gt;yarn&lt;/code&gt; could change its internal PNP representation by creating a new file and translating its format into older formats, or by reserving fields in the PNP file for future usage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Invoking the executable script requires Node.JS. As above, this is not always feasible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;code&gt;.pnp.js&lt;/code&gt; is a significant security risk for a small gain&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Providing an executable package manifest (even a tool-generated one) is much harder to secure in practice. A static manifest file's parser is a relatively small amount of code to secure (and existing formats already have battle-tested parsers). Conversely, an executable file manifest is very difficult to both analyse and secure:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;How do you know that the generated code is not malicious?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do you know that the generated code behaves correctly across all the environments it will run in?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How can you guarantee that any &lt;code&gt;.pnp.js&lt;/code&gt; file that is generated will be secure?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do we prevent tampering and phishing attacks? (I can easily imagine a phishing attack targeting beginners, telling them to execute &lt;code&gt;node .pnp.js&lt;/code&gt; in a maliciously crafted project and bypassing any integrity checks that &lt;code&gt;yarn&lt;/code&gt; itself might have in place.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are solutions to all of these security problems, but my point is that the attack surface and risk is much larger than that of a static manifest file for relatively little gain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Instead, &lt;code&gt;yarn&lt;/code&gt; should use a well-documented manifest file&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ideally, the public API would be truly language-agnostic. For us, a best case scenario is a well-documented manifest file format that is readily parseable (e.g. JSON, YAML, TOML). This solves all of these issues:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;A manifest file does not require an interpreter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A manifest file is a much smaller security risk.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 11:19:30 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Couto</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars3.githubusercontent.com/u/1037931?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>Yarn Plug'n'Play: Getting rid of node_modules by arcanis · Pull Request #101 · yarnpkg/rfcs</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/yarnpkg/rfcs/pull/101</og:url>
<og:description>Note: This PR&amp;#39;s discussions should be focused on the high-level design. [A separate PR] (yarnpkg/yarn#6382) has been opened on the code repository to discuss the implementation details. A pdf...</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/yarnpkg/rfcs/pull/101</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ending PHP Support, and the Future of Hack</title>
<link>https://hhvm.com/blog/2018/09/12/end-of-php-support-future-of-hack.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://hhvm.com/blog/2018/09/12/end-of-php-support-future-of-hack.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;HHVM v3.30 will be the last release series where HHVM aims to support PHP. The key dates are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;2018-12-03: branch cut: expect PHP code to stop working with master and nightly builds after this date&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2018-12-17: expected release date for v3.30.0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2019-01-28: expected release date for v4.0.0, without PHP support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2019-11-19: expected end of support for v3.30&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, we recommend that projects either migrate entirely to the Hack language, or entirely to PHP7 and the PHP runtime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We expect support for real-world PHP code to break rapidly: for example, we are likely to replace reference parameters (&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;$foo&lt;/code&gt;) to builtins with &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;inout&lt;/code&gt; parameters, make &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;INT64_MAX + 1 === INT64_MIN&lt;/code&gt; (instead of a float), among other changes. In the short term, we expect it to be fairly straightforward to migrate code to deal with these changes, but this will require that any dependencies written in PHP are either forked and migrated to Hack, or migrated away from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re extremely grateful to the users and developers of PHP, and are glad to have been part of those communities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are proud of Hack, but there are still many areas where we want to make major improvements to the language; during the next 2-3 years, we will be working towards making Hack a language that builds on the best parts of its’ heritage to produce:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;a consistent, statically typed language&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the development speed and ease-of-use that’s traditionally associated with dynamically typed languages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;During these 2-3 years, aggressive growth of our user base is not a primary goal: we want most people’s first exposure to Hack to be the improved language that we are working towards. However, we will be increasing our investment in Hack/HHVM open source, to continue to support our existing users, and aim to build a community ready to support growth in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we expect the language to evolve rapidly, we &lt;strong&gt;strongly&lt;/strong&gt; recommend using the regular releases instead of the LTS releases for large projects; while this does mean you need to upgrade more often, both us and our users have found that it is generally easier to catch up on 2 months worth of changes 3 times as often than 6 months of changes in one go. We will also be re-evaluating the length of our release cycle; one possibility is that we will move to releases every 4 weeks, with these releases being supported for 6-8 weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this time period, most of Facebook’s Hack libraries and tools on GitHub will only target the latest release, not LTS versions; branches and fixes will be made as-needed, but these branches will be community supported, except for security issues reported via &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/whitehat&quot;&gt;Facebook’s Whitehat Program&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The priorities of the Hack/HHVM open source team are to support our existing users, and to reduce the pain of the removal of PHP support. This will involve creating additional projects, and polishing several existing projects to reach a state suitable for v1.x.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, plans include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/hhvm/hh-apidoc&quot;&gt;hh-apidoc&lt;/a&gt;: improve ease of use, integrate with existing projects, improve readability and formatting of produced documents&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/hhvm/hacktest&quot;&gt;hacktest&lt;/a&gt;: improve ease of use, documentation, and use as a replacement for PHPUnit in all our existing projects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/hhvm/hack-router&quot;&gt;hack-router&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/hhvm/hack-router-codegen&quot;&gt;hack-router-codegen&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/facebookexperimental/hack-http-request-response-interfaces/&quot;&gt;remove the dependency on PSR-7&lt;/a&gt;, revisit the API design for current best practices, improve documentation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;we are investigating migrating away from Composer and Packagist; it currently seems likely that this is going to be a set of best practices or extensions to &lt;a href=&quot;https://yarnpkg.com/&quot;&gt;Yarn&lt;/a&gt;, using the NPM repository, with the goal of using a single package manager for both the JS and Hack parts of web-based projects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;We hope to help the community build what is needed; please get in contact via &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/groups/hhvm.general/&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/hacklang&quot;&gt;Reddit&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hacklang/&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, or in #hhvm on irc.freenode.net.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2019, we expect this work to continue and expand in scope, and to provide more automated migrations to update code to deal with language changes.&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 01:26:28 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>dcgudeman</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://hhvm.com/blog/2018/09/12/end-of-php-support-future-of-hack.html</og:url>
<og:title>Ending PHP Support, and The Future Of Hack</og:title>
<og:image>http://hhvm.com/static/og_image.png</og:image>
<og:description>Ending Support for PHP</og:description>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://hhvm.com/blog/2018/09/12/end-of-php-support-future-of-hack.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Manhattan DA&amp;#039;s office drops more than 3,000 open marijuana cases</title>
<link>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-new-york-marijuana/manhattan-das-office-drops-more-than-3000-open-marijuana-cases-idUSKCN1LS2ID</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.reuters.com/article/us-new-york-marijuana/manhattan-das-office-drops-more-than-3000-open-marijuana-cases-idUSKCN1LS2ID</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;NEW YORK (Reuters) - Manhattan District Attorney Cyrus Vance on Wednesday dropped more than 3,000 open marijuana smoking and possession cases dating back to 1978, saying the action would serve justice and address racial disparities in the prosecution of marijuana offenses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;PrimaryAsset_container&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Image_container&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot; readability=&quot;13&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;LazyImage_container LazyImage_dark&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s4.reutersmedia.net/resources/r/?m=02&amp;amp;d=20180912&amp;amp;t=2&amp;amp;i=1303619353&amp;amp;r=LYNXNPEE8B1PY&amp;amp;w=20&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Manhattan District Attorney Cyrus R. Vance Jr. speaks at a news conference about dismissing some 3,000 marijunana smoking and possession cases in New York City, U.S., September 12, 2018. REUTERS/Jeenah Moon&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vance moved to vacate 3,042 outstanding warrants and dismiss the underlying charges before New York City Criminal Court Judge Kevin McGrath. The judge said the cases must be sealed within 90 days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The district attorney’s decision applies to misdemeanor and violation cases in which a warrant was issued because the defendant failed to appear in court. It does not apply to any cases where a defendant was convicted, or to more serious charges like selling marijuana.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Slideshow_container Slideshow_small Slideshow_standard&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Slideshow_preview-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;LazyImage_container LazyImage_dark&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s1.reutersmedia.net/resources/r/?m=02&amp;amp;d=20180912&amp;amp;t=2&amp;amp;i=1303619356&amp;amp;r=LYNXNPEE8B1Q1&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

Slideshow &lt;span class=&quot;Slideshow_count&quot;&gt;(5 Images)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“By vacating these warrants, we are preventing unnecessary future interactions with the criminal justice system,” Vance said in court.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We made the decision that it is really in the interest of justice,” Vance said at a press conference in court after making his motion. He added that dropping the charges would remove a burden from his office and the court system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We have to actually look at what resources we have, what resources the court has,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vance announced earlier this year that his office would no longer prosecute marijuana smoking and possession cases. The decision was part of a nationwide trend among state and local governments to ease enforcement or legalize the drug.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marijuana remains illegal at the federal level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Attribution_container&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Attribution_attribution&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Attribution_content&quot;&gt;Reporting By Brendan Pierson in New York; Editing by Steve Orlofsky&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;StandardArticleBody_trustBadgeContainer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;StandardArticleBody_trustBadgeTitle&quot;&gt;Our Standards:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;trustBadgeUrl&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thomsonreuters.com/en/about-us/trust-principles.html&quot;&gt;The Thomson Reuters Trust Principles.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 23:27:52 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>DoreenMichele</dc:creator>
<og:title>Manhattan DA's office drops more than 3,000 open marijuana cases</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-new-york-marijuana/manhattan-das-office-drops-more-than-3000-open-marijuana-cases-idUSKCN1LS2ID</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>Manhattan District Attorney Cyrus Vance on Wednesday dropped more than 3,000 ope...</og:description>
<og:image>https://s4.reutersmedia.net/resources/r/?m=02&amp;d=20180912&amp;t=2&amp;i=1303619353&amp;w=1200&amp;r=LYNXNPEE8B1PY</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-new-york-marijuana/manhattan-das-office-drops-more-than-3000-open-marijuana-cases-idUSKCN1LS2ID</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Google’s first all-hands after 2016 election [video]</title>
<link>https://www.breitbart.com/tech/2018/09/12/leaked-video-google-leaderships-dismayed-reaction-to-trump-election/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.breitbart.com/tech/2018/09/12/leaked-video-google-leaderships-dismayed-reaction-to-trump-election/</guid>
<description>&lt;h2&gt;A video recorded by Google shortly after the 2016 presidential election reveals an atmosphere of panic and dismay amongst the tech giant’s leadership, coupled with a determination to thwart both the Trump agenda and the broader populist movement emerging around the globe.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The video is a full recording of Google’s first all-hands meeting following the 2016 election (these weekly meetings are known inside the company as “TGIF” or “Thank God It’s Friday” meetings). Sent to Breitbart News by an anonymous source, it features co-founders Larry Page and Sergey Brin, VPs Kent Walker and Eileen Naughton, CFO Ruth Porat, and CEO Sundar Pichai. It can be watched in full above. It can and should be watched in full above in order to get the full context of the meeting and the statements made.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;It was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.breitbart.com/big-government/2018/09/10/silent-donation-corporate-emails-reveal-google-executives-efforts-to-swing-election-to-hillary-clinton-with-latino-outreach-campaign/&quot;&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt; earlier this week that Google tried to boost turnout among the Latino population to help Hillary Clinton, only to be dismayed as the usually solid Democratic voting bloc switched to the GOP in record numbers. This video shows a similar level of dismay among Google’s most high-profile figures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These individuals, who preside over a company with unrivaled influence over the flow of information, can be seen disparaging the motivations of Trump voters and plotting ways to use their vast resources to thwart the Trump agenda.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Co-founder Sergey Brin can be heard comparing Trump supporters to fascists and extremists. Brin argues that like other extremists, Trump voters were motivated by “boredom,” which he says in the past led to fascism and communism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Google co-founder then asks his company to consider what it can do to ensure a “better quality of governance and decision-making.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VP for Global Affairs Kent Walker argues that supporters of populist causes like the Trump campaign are motivated by “fear, xenophobia, hatred, and a desire for answers that may or may not be there.”&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Later, Walker says that Google should fight to ensure the populist movement – not just in the U.S. but around the world – is merely a “blip” and a “hiccup” in a historical arc that “bends toward progress.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CEO Sundar Pichai states that the company will develop machine learning and A.I. to combat what an employee described as “misinformation” shared by “low-information voters.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key moments from the video can be found at the following timestamps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;(00:00:00 – 00:01:12) Google co-founder Sergey Brin states that the weekly meeting is “probably not the most joyous we’ve had” and that “most people here are pretty upset and pretty sad.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(00:00:24) Brin contrasts the disappointment of Trump’s election with his excitement at the legalization of cannabis in California, triggering laughs and applause from the audience of Google employees.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(00:01:12) Returning to seriousness, Brin says he is “deeply offen[ded]” by the election of Trump, and that the election “conflicts with many of [Google’s] values.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(00:09:10) Trying to explain the motivations of Trump supporters, Senior VP for Global Affairs, Kent Walker concludes: “fear, not just in the United States, but around the world is fueling concerns, xenophobia, hatred, and a desire for answers that may or may not be there.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(00:09:35) Walker goes on to describe the Trump phenomenon as a sign of “tribalism that’s self-destructive [in] the long-term.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(00:09:55) Striking an optimistic tone, Walker assures Google employees that despite the election, “history is on our side” and that the “moral arc of history bends towards progress.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(00:10:45) Walker approvingly quotes former Italian Prime Minister Matteo Renzi’s comparison between “the world of the wall” with its “isolation and defensiveness” and the “world of the square, the piazza, the marketplace, where people come together into a community and enrich each other’s lives.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(00:13:10) CFO Ruth Porat appears to break down in tears when discussing the election result.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(00:15:20) Porat promises that Google will “use the great strength and resources and reach we have to continue to advance really important values.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(00:16:50) Stating “we all need a hug,” she then instructs the audience of Google employees to hug the person closest to them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(00:20:24) Eileen Naughton, VP of People Operations, promises that Google’s policy team in DC is “all over” the immigration issue and that the company will “keep a close watch on it.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(00:21:26) Naughton jokes about Google employees asking, ‘Can I move to Canada?’ after the election. She goes on to seriously discuss the options available to Google employees who wish to leave the country.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(00:23:12) Naughton does acknowledge “diversity of opinion and political persuasion” and notes that she has heard from conservative Google employees who say they “haven’t felt entirely comfortable revealing who [they] are.” and urged “tolerance.” (Several months later, the company would fire James Damore allegedly for disagreeing with progressive narratives.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(00:27:00) Responding to a question about “filter bubbles,” Sundar Pichai promises to work towards “correcting” Google’s role in them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(00:27:30) Sergey Brin praises an audience member’s suggestion of increasing matched Google employee donations to progressive groups.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(00:34:40) Brin compares Trump voters to “extremists,” arguing for a correlation between the economic background of Trump supporters and the kinds of voters who back extremist movements. Brin says that “voting is not a rational act” and that not all of Trump’s support can be attributed to “income disparity.” He suggests that Trump voters might have been motivated by boredom rather than legitimate concerns.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(00:49:10) An employee asks if Google is willing to “invest in grassroots, hyper-local efforts to bring tools and services and understanding of Google products and knowledge” so that people can “make informed decisions that are best for themselves.” Pichai’s response: Google will ensure its “educational products” reach “segments of the population [they] are not [currently] fully reaching.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(00:54:33) An employee asks what Google is going to do about “misinformation” and “fake news” shared by “low-information voters.” Pichai responds by stating that “investments in machine learning and AI” are a “big opportunity” to fix the problem.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(00:56:12) Responding to an audience member, Walker says Google must ensure the rise of populism doesn’t turn into “a world war or something catastrophic … and instead is a blip, a hiccup.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(00:58:22) Brin compares Trump voters to supporters of fascism and communism, linking the former movement to “boredom,” which Brin previously linked to Trump voters. “It sort of sneaks up sometimes, really bad things” says Brin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(01:01:15) A Google employee states: “speaking to white men, there’s an opportunity for you right now to understand your privilege” and urges employees to “go through the bias-busting training, read about privilege, read about the real history of oppression in our country.” He urges employees to “discuss the issues you are passionate about during Thanksgiving dinner and don’t back down and laugh it off when you hear the voice of oppression speak through metaphors.” Every executive on stage – the CEO, CFO, two VPs and the two Co-founders – applaud the employee.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(01:01:57) An audience member asks if the executives see “anything positive from this election result.” The audience of Google employees, and the executives on stage, burst into laughter. “Boy, that’s a really tough one right now” says Brin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update —&lt;/strong&gt; After Breitbart News published this article, a Google spokesperson replied to a request for comment with the following statement:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;gmail-docs-internal-guid-f386b419-7fff-b420-b3b6-04227e966676&quot;&gt;“At a regularly scheduled all hands meeting, some Google employees and executives expressed their own personal views in the aftermath of a long and divisive election season. For over 20 years, everyone at Google has been able to freely express their opinions at these meetings. Nothing was said at that meeting, or any other meeting, to suggest that any political bias ever influences the way we build or operate our products. To the contrary, our products are built for everyone, and we design them with extraordinary care to be a trustworthy source of information for everyone, without regard to political viewpoint.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Allum Bokhari is the senior technology correspondent at Breitbart News. You can follow him &lt;a class=&quot;x5l&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/LibertarianBlue&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&quot;x5l&quot; href=&quot;https://gab.ai/ab&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Gab.ai&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class=&quot;x5l&quot; href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/profile.php?id=100009540769414&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;add him on Facebook.&lt;/a&gt; Email tips and suggestions to &lt;a class=&quot;x5l&quot; href=&quot;mailto:allumbokhari@protonmail.com&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;allumbokhari@protonmail.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 23:11:53 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Domenic_S</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>LEAKED VIDEO: Google Leadership's Dismayed Reaction to Trump Election | Breitbart</og:title>
<og:description>Leaked footage shows Google's leadership team - including its CEO and Co-founders - reaction to the election of Donald Trump. | Tech</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.breitbart.com/tech/2018/09/12/leaked-video-google-leaderships-dismayed-reaction-to-trump-election/</og:url>
<og:image>https://media.breitbart.com/media/2018/09/non-clapping-pic-no-g.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.breitbart.com/tech/2018/09/12/leaked-video-google-leaderships-dismayed-reaction-to-trump-election/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>