<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>China to take over Kenya’s main port over unpaid huge Chinese Loan</title>
<link>https://www.africanstand.com/news/africa/east-africa/china-to-take-over-kenyas-main-port-over-unpaid-huge-chinese-loan/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.africanstand.com/news/africa/east-africa/china-to-take-over-kenyas-main-port-over-unpaid-huge-chinese-loan/</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.africanstand.com/news/africa/east-africa/china-to-take-over-kenyas-main-port-over-unpaid-huge-chinese-loan/&quot;&gt;https://www.africanstand.com/news/africa/east-africa/china-to-take-over-kenyas-main-port-over-unpaid-huge-chinese-loan/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=18762144&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=18762144&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 228&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 115&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 26 Dec 2018 13:59:44 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>tartoran</dc:creator>
<dc:identifier>https://www.africanstand.com/news/africa/east-africa/china-to-take-over-kenyas-main-port-over-unpaid-huge-chinese-loan/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>New Office Hours Aim for Well Rested, More Productive Workers</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/12/24/well/mind/work-schedule-hours-sleep-productivity-chronotype-night-owls.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2018/12/24/well/mind/work-schedule-hours-sleep-productivity-chronotype-night-owls.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;css-u5vfum StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;A few years ago, scientists conducted a &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/25772446&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;real-world experiment at a ThyssenKrupp steel factory&lt;/a&gt; in Germany. They assigned the day shift to early risers and the late shift to night owls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Soon the steel workers, many of whom had been skeptical at the outset, were getting an extra hour of sleep on work nights. By simply aligning work schedules with people’s internal clocks, the researchers had helped people get more and better rest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“They got 16 percent more sleep, almost a full night’s length over the course of the week,” said Till Roenneberg, a chronobiologist at Ludwig-Maximilian University in Munich, who headed the study. “That is enormous.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;In recent years, American educators have been paying increased attention to their students’ sleep needs, with &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/09/07/us/california-school-start-times.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;growing debate about delaying school start times&lt;/a&gt;. Now a number of businesses are following suit, encouraging their employees to work when their bodies are most awake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-1m2ozyi&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;css-u5vfum StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“It’s a huge financial burden not to sleep properly,” Dr. Roenneberg said. “The estimates go toward 1 percent of gross national product,” both in the United States and Germany.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Emerging science reveals that each of us has an optimal time to fall asleep and wake up, a personalized biological rhythm known as a “chronotype.” When you don’t sleep at the time your body wants to sleep — your so-called biological night — you don’t sleep as well or as long, setting the stage not only for fatigue, poor work performance and errors but also health problems ranging from heart disease and obesity to anxiety and depression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;A full 80 percent of people have work schedules that clash with their internal clocks, said Céline Vetter, an assistant professor at the University of Colorado at Boulder and director of the university’s circadian and sleep epidemiology lab. “The problem is huge,” Dr. Vetter said. “If we consider your individual chronotype and your work hours, the chances are very high that there’s quite a bit of misalignment.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Put it this way: If you rely on an alarm clock to wake up, you’re out of sync with your own biology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Studies on workers in the call center of a &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;http://www.producao.ufrgs.br/arquivos/publicacoes/59_art01.pdf&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;mobile phone company&lt;/a&gt;, a &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://content.iospress.com/articles/work/wor0371&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;packaging manufacturer&lt;/a&gt; and an &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;http://www.producao.ufrgs.br/arquivos/publicacoes/68_art10.pdf&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;oil transportation company&lt;/a&gt; show that these employees are more stressed and may experience more work-related discomfort and pain. It’s the mismatch — not the hours themselves — that matters. &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;http://care.diabetesjournals.org/content/38/9/1707&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;A 2015 Harvard Medical School study&lt;/a&gt; found that for night owls, working during the day increases diabetes risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-1m2ozyi&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-u5vfum StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Among the companies seeking to remedy the problem is Southwest Airlines, which allows pilots to choose between morning and evening flight schedules. The United States Navy recently traded an 18-hour submarine shift schedule for a 24-hour one that more closely matches sailors’ biological rhythms. And at some pharmaceutical, software and financial companies, managers expect employees to come to the office for only a few hours in the middle of the day — or to work off site entirely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“I think circadian rhythms will be a huge issue for human resources in the future,” said Camilla Kring, a Danish consultant who has helped employees at AbbVie, Roche, Medtronic and other companies learn to respect their natural sleep cycles. “It really makes sense to think about when people have the most energy and when they’re peaking mentally.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Worker fatigue has played a role in many workplace accidents, most famously the Challenger space shuttle explosion and the Exxon Valdez oil spill, but no doubt countless more on the commute to and from work. The National Highway Traffic Safety Administration estimates that drowsy drivers cause 16.5 percent of fatal crashes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;A &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nsc.org/work-safety/safety-topics/fatigue/survey-report&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;survey released last year by the National Safety Council&lt;/a&gt; found that 97 percent of workers have at least one risk factor for fatigue, with 27 percent reporting having unintentionally fallen asleep on the job in the previous month and 16 percent that they had experienced at least one safety incident because of fatigue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“We have a 24/7 society, so we knew fatigue was definitely affecting part of our work force,” said Emily Whitcomb, senior program manager of the council’s fatigue initiative. “But we did not anticipate that fatigue was going to be affecting almost 100 percent of our work force.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Sleep deprivation may even lead to ethical breaches at work. In a &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0956797614541989&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;2014 experiment&lt;/a&gt;, Christopher Barnes of the University of Washington and colleagues asked 142 people with extreme chronotypes to show up at their laboratory either at 7 a.m. or at midnight for a dice-rolling game that offered a $500 prize. Reporting was on the honor system. Morning people lied 18 percent more when they did the task at midnight than when they did it in the morning, whereas night owls lied 16 percent more when doing the task at 7 a.m.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Dr. Roenneberg has collected data from 300,000 people and found that chronotypes plot as a bell-shaped curve, with a few individuals at each extreme and most falling somewhere in the middle. According to Dr. Roenneberg’s research, the most frequent chronotype — held by about 13 percent of the population — sleeps from around midnight to 8 a.m. Thirty-one percent of people have an earlier natural bedtime, and 56 percent have a later one. That means for at least 69 percent of the population, getting to the office by 8 or 9 a.m. requires waking up before their body is ready.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-1m2ozyi&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-u5vfum StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Not all experts acknowledge such fine-grained distinctions, instead grouping people into morning, evening and “intermediate” types. Regardless, while true “larks” and “owls” &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/08/25/style/sleep-problem-late-night.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;tend to dominate the conversation&lt;/a&gt;, they make up a small percentage of the population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;To determine your chronotype, imagine that you have two weeks of vacation to spend as you like, with no evening or morning commitments and no pets or children to wake you. Chronotypes reflect habits as well as biology, so you would also need to eliminate caffeine and avoid artificial light at night, which pushes a person’s chronotype later. At what time would you tend to fall asleep and wake up? Don’t be surprised if you’re unsure. After years spent accommodating work, family and social commitments at the expense of sleep, “a lot of people don’t know what rhythm they have,” Ms. Kring said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;css-11q3cgf ewiwup50&quot;/&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Chronotypes shift in a predictable way over the course of a lifetime. Between the ages of 12 and 21, everyone’s natural sleep schedule gets about 2 1/2 hours later — which is why adolescents have so much trouble waking up for school. After that, chronotype creeps in the other direction, which is why older people typically find themselves waking earlier than they used to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;But chronotype determines more than when you sleep and wake. It orchestrates predictable peaks and troughs of energy over the course of the 24-hour day. The so-called “window of circadian low” — the hours when the body is least adapted for wakefulness — typically occurs between 2 a.m. and 6 a.m. There’s another, smaller dip 12 hours later, in the midafternoon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;There are also two high points, when thinking is sharp and reaction times quick. One occurs within an hour or two after waking, and the other after the daytime dip. This cycle is shifted earlier in a morning person and later in an evening or night person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;At the Denmark offices of the pharmaceutical company AbbVie, employees design work schedules that take advantage of their biological strengths. A nine-hour training program helps them identify when they are ripe for creative or challenging projects, typically mornings for early risers and afternoons for late risers. Lower-energy periods are meant for more mundane tasks, like handling emails or doing administrative chores. Workers save commuting time by avoiding rush hour traffic, and can better mesh their personal and professional lives — for example, by getting their children from school in the afternoon, then working from home in the evening after the kids are in bed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Employee satisfaction with work-life balance has risen from 39 percent 10 years ago, when the program launched, to nearly 100 percent today, according to company surveys. Last year the Denmark division of Great Place to Work, a global organization that ranks companies based on employee satisfaction, named AbbVie the top middle-size company in the country. “The flexibility actually empowers people to deliver the best possible results,” said Christina Jeppesen, the company’s general manager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-1m2ozyi&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-u5vfum StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;A 2018 survey by the Society for Human Resource Management, which represents 300,000 H.R. professionals in more than 165 countries, found that 57 percent of its members offer flexible hours, 5 percent more than in 2014. “Managers who give it a try often find that employees’ morale, engagement and productivity all go up, because they are working at a time that works best for them, and able to get the most work done,” said Lisa Horn, the group’s vice president of congressional affairs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Some companies restrict meetings to “core hours,” between, say, 10 a.m. and 3 p.m., to accommodate various schedules. Others build flextime into the workweek. At Phase 2, a software development firm in Oklahoma City, each week ends with “productivity Friday,” when employees are expected to work remotely in a place of their choice — whether that be from home, a coffee shop or at a weekend house at the lake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Stefan Volk, a senior lecturer at the University of Sydney Business School, has suggested that businesses can leverage chronotypes to maximize team success. For example, members of a surgery team should have similar chronotypes because they need to be in top form simultaneously. But at a nuclear power plant, workers should have different energy peaks, so that someone is always on the alert.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;But while lots of corporations promise flexibility, veering from the traditional 9 to 5 work hours requires a cultural shift. A &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/record/2014-23623-001&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;2014 study led by Dr. Barnes&lt;/a&gt; found that many managers have an ingrained prejudice in favor of early birds, whom they perceived as more conscientious simply because they arrived at work early, a view that could dissuade some workers from using flextime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;But sticking to traditional hours can be counterproductive, leading to “presenteeism” — employees showing up and being only minimally functional. “Companies are wasting the potential of their people,” Dr. Volk said. “You have someone sitting there from 7 til 9 a.m. sipping coffee, being completely unproductive, and then you send them home at 4 when they actually start getting productive.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;For many office workers, the answer may be as simple as delaying work start times an hour or two — say until 9:30 or 10 a.m. Since many people are in the middle of the chronotype continuum and wake naturally around 8 or 9 a.m., such a modest shift could provide widespread relief. “We’re talking about one hour,” Ms. Kring said, “not a revolution.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-1m2ozyi&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 26 Dec 2018 00:19:54 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>acjohnson55</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/12/24/well/mind/work-schedule-hours-sleep-productivity-chronotype-night-owls.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>New Office Hours Aim for Well Rested, More Productive Workers</og:title>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/12/25/science/25CHRONOGRAPH-GIF/25CHRONOGRAPH-GIF-facebookJumbo.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>A growing number of businesses are encouraging their employees to work when their bodies are most awake.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/12/24/well/mind/work-schedule-hours-sleep-productivity-chronotype-night-owls.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Machine learning has become alchemy (2017) [video]</title>
<link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=x7psGHgatGM</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=x7psGHgatGM</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=x7psGHgatGM&quot;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=x7psGHgatGM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=18759241&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=18759241&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 221&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 105&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 25 Dec 2018 21:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>henning</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=x7psGHgatGM</og:url>
<og:title>NIPS 2017 Test of Time Award &quot;Machine learning has become alchemy.” | Ali Rahimi, Google</og:title>
<og:image>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/x7psGHgatGM/maxresdefault.jpg</og:image>
<og:description> </og:description>
<og:type>video.other</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=x7psGHgatGM</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>My video with 47M views was stolen on YouTube [video]</title>
<link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=z4AeoAWGJBw</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=z4AeoAWGJBw</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=z4AeoAWGJBw&quot;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=z4AeoAWGJBw&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=18758758&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=18758758&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 231&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 82&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 25 Dec 2018 19:08:16 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Michie</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=z4AeoAWGJBw</og:url>
<og:title>How my video with 47 million views was stolen on YouTube</og:title>
<og:image>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/z4AeoAWGJBw/maxresdefault.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>PLEASE SIGN THE PETITION: https://goo.gl/Jo85kU #FixYouTubeCopyright Twitter: http://twitter.com/ThisIsTheFatRat Facebook: http://www.facebook.com/thisisthef...</og:description>
<og:type>video.other</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=z4AeoAWGJBw</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Human blood cells can be directly reprogrammed into neural stem cells</title>
<link>https://www.dkfz.de/en/presse/pressemitteilungen/2018/dkfz-pm-18-71-Human-blood-cells-can-be-directly-reprogrammed-into-neural-stem-cells.php</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.dkfz.de/en/presse/pressemitteilungen/2018/dkfz-pm-18-71-Human-blood-cells-can-be-directly-reprogrammed-into-neural-stem-cells.php</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Stem cells are considered to be the all-rounders of our tissues: they can multiply indefinitely and then - if they are pluripotent embryonic stem cells - generate all conceivable cell types. In 2006, the Japanese scientist Shinya Yamanaka recognized that such cells could also be produced in the laboratory - from mature body cells. Four genetic factors alone are sufficient to reverse the course of development and produce so-called induced pluripotent stem cells (iPS) that have identical properties to embryonic stem cells. Yamanaka was awarded the Nobel Prize for Medicine in 2012 for this discovery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;This was a major breakthrough for stem cell research,&quot; said Andreas Trumpp, German Cancer Research Center (DKFZ) and Director of HI-STEM in Heidelberg. &quot;This applies in particular to for research in Germany, where the generation of human embryonic stem cells is not permitted. Stem cells have enormous potential both for basic research and for the development of regenerative therapies that aim to restore diseased tissue in patients. However, reprogramming is also associated with problems: For example, pluripotent cells can form germ line tumors, so-called teratomas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another possibility is not to completely turn back the course of development. For the first time, Trumpp's team has succeeded in reprogramming mature human cells in such a way that a defined type of induced neural stem cells is produced that can multiply almost indefinitely. &quot;We used four genetic factors like Yamanaka, but different ones for our reprogramming,&quot; explains Marc Christian Thier, first author of the study. &quot;We assumed that our factors would allow reprogramming to an early stage of development of the nervous system.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the past, other research groups also reprogrammed connective tissue cells into mature nerve cells or neural precursor cells. However, these artificially produced nerve cells often could not be expanded and could therefore hardly be used for therapeutic purposes. &quot;Often, it was a heterogeneous mixture of different cell types that might not exist in the body under physiological conditions,&quot; said Andreas Trumpp explaining the problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Together with stem cell researcher Frank Edenhofer from the University of Innsbruck and neuroscientist Hannah Monyer from DKFZ and the Heidelberg University Hospital, Trumpp and his team have succeeded in reprogramming different human cells: connective tissue cells of the skin or pancreas as well as peripheral blood cells. &quot;The origin of the cells had no influence on the properties of the stem cells,&quot; said Thier. In particular, the possibility of extracting neural stem cells from the blood of patients without invasive intervention is a decisive advantage for future therapeutic approaches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is special about the reprogrammed cells of the Heidelberg researchers is that they are a homogeneous cell type that resembles a stage of neural stem cells that occurs during the embryonic development of the nervous system. &quot;Corresponding cells exist in mice and probably also in humans during early embryonic brain development,&quot; said Thier. &quot;We have described here a new neural stem cell type in the mammalian embryo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These so called &quot;induced Neural Plate Border Stem Cells&quot; (iNBSCs) have a broad development potential. The iNBSCs of the Heidelberg scientists are expandable and multipotent and can develop in two different directions. On the one hand, they can take the path of development to mature nerve cells and their supplier cells, the glial cells, i.e. become cells of the central nervous system. On the other hand, they can also develop into cells of the neural crest, from which different cell types emerge, for example peripheral sensitive nerve cells or cartilage and bones of the skull.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The iNBSCs thus form an ideal basis for generating a broad range of different cell types for an individual patient. &quot;These cells have the same genetic material as the donor and are therefore presumably recognized as &quot;self&quot; by the immune system and are not rejected,&quot; explains Thier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CRISPR/Cas9 gene scissors can be used to modify the iNBSC or repair genetic defects, as the scientists have shown in their experiments. &quot;They are therefore of interesting both for basic research and the search for new active substances and for the development of regenerative therapies, for example in patients with diseases of the nervous system. However until we can use them in patients, a lot of research work will still be necessary,&quot; emphasizes Trumpp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*The Heidelberg Institute for Stem Cell Research and Experimental Medicine (HI-STEM) gGmbH was founded in 2008 as a public-private partnership between the DKFZ and the Dietmar Hopp Foundation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marc Christian Thier, Oliver Hommerding, Jasper Panten, Roberta Pinna, Diego García-González, Thomas Berger, Philipp Wörsdörfer, Yassen Assenov, Roberta Scognamiglio, Adriana Przybylla, Paul Kaschutnig, Lisa Becker, Michael D. Milsom, Anna Jauch, Jochen Utikal, Carl Herrmann, Hannah Monyer, Frank Edenhofer and Andreas Trumpp. Cell Stem Cell (2018), DOI: 10.1016/j.stem.2018.11.015&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 25 Dec 2018 19:03:11 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>myinnerbanjo</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.dkfz.de/en/presse/pressemitteilungen/2018/dkfz-pm-18-71-Human-blood-cells-can-be-directly-reprogrammed-into-neural-stem-cells.php</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Emacs Fireplace</title>
<link>https://github.com/johanvts/emacs-fireplace</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/johanvts/emacs-fireplace</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;Box-header px-2 clearfix&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;Box-title pr-3&quot;&gt;README.rst&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Box-body p-6&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;markdown-body entry-content&quot; itemprop=&quot;text&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://travis-ci.org/johanvts/emacs-fireplace&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/af12fd9c0ac0d8e026c02441341c3145f4c840ee/68747470733a2f2f6170692e7472617669732d63692e6f72672f6a6f68616e7674732f656d6163732d66697265706c6163652e737667&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://api.travis-ci.org/johanvts/emacs-fireplace.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://coveralls.io/r/johanvts/emacs-fireplace&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/82111326ce80db3d38693b0591209f69d1057d0e/68747470733a2f2f636f766572616c6c732e696f2f7265706f732f6a6f68616e7674732f656d6163732d66697265706c6163652f62616467652e737667&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://coveralls.io/repos/johanvts/emacs-fireplace/badge.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://melpa.org/#/fireplace&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/20cae8fdbe1c7058e3c70ef8007741febaa9fd8b/687474703a2f2f6d656c70612e6f72672f7061636b616765732f66697265706c6163652d62616467652e737667&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;http://melpa.org/packages/fireplace-badge.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://stable.melpa.org/#/fireplace&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/fb40631fcb8d8afe9ece6934adced95a851012b0/687474703a2f2f737461626c652e6d656c70612e6f72672f7061636b616765732f66697265706c6163652d62616467652e737667&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;http://stable.melpa.org/packages/fireplace-badge.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/johanvts/emacs-fireplace/tags&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/97a524b5c2c3e660a538b87de9223b3f677a79f6/68747470733a2f2f696d672e736869656c64732e696f2f6769746875622f7461672f6a6f68616e7674732f656d6163732d66697265706c6163652e737667&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/tag/johanvts/emacs-fireplace.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gnu.org/licenses/gpl-3.0.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/3ff3f8b43676ebcaa5049d1e12537434b9359e35/687474703a2f2f696d672e736869656c64732e696f2f3a6c6963656e73652d67706c332d626c75652e737667&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;http://img.shields.io/:license-gpl3-blue.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/fb294d4545fdc5558777cffe6d21777748fec615/68747470733a2f2f7261772e6769746875622e636f6d2f6a6f68616e7674732f656d6163732d66697265706c6163652f6d61737465722f696d672f66697265706c6163652e676966&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;https://raw.github.com/johanvts/emacs-fireplace/master/img/fireplace.gif&quot; src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/fb294d4545fdc5558777cffe6d21777748fec615/68747470733a2f2f7261772e6769746875622e636f6d2f6a6f68616e7674732f656d6163732d66697265706c6163652f6d61737465722f696d672f66697265706c6163652e676966&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://raw.github.com/johanvts/emacs-fireplace/master/img/fireplace.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A cozy fireplace for emacs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Usage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After you installed the fireplace package from &lt;a href=&quot;http://melpa.org/#/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;melpa&lt;/a&gt; you can start the fire using &lt;code&gt;M-x fireplace&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fireplace will try to fill the current window with a new buffer. To put the fire out use &lt;code&gt;M-x fireplace-off&lt;/code&gt; or hotkey &lt;code&gt;q&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead valign=&quot;bottom&quot;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;Key bind&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Function&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;C-+&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Move fire up&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;C--&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Move fire down&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;C-*&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Toggle smoke&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;q&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Turn off fire&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;Use &lt;code&gt;M-x customize-group RET fireplace RET&lt;/code&gt; to view and change the user defined variables and read their documentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Configuration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can tweak the setting of &lt;code&gt;fireplace&lt;/code&gt; the way you please with the &lt;code&gt;customize-group&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;fireplace&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;fireplace-faces&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among the options, the name of the buffer, the frequency of refresh, the smoke char, or the faces used in the fireplace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Manual Installation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you don't want to use melpa to install this package, follow these steps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Download &lt;code&gt;fireplace.el&lt;/code&gt; and place it somewhere in your &lt;code&gt;.emacs.d&lt;/code&gt; directory, say in &lt;code&gt;.emacs.d/fireplace/&lt;/code&gt;. Compile the file using &lt;code&gt;M-x byte-compile-file&lt;/code&gt;. Put &lt;code&gt;(load &quot;~/.emacs.d/fireplace/fireplace&quot;)&lt;/code&gt; in your init file (&lt;code&gt;.emacs&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that there is a significant performance difference between the compiled and non-compiled fireplace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Acknowledgment&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A big thanks to Dan Torop for his &lt;a href=&quot;http://dantorop.info/project/emacs-animation/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;emacs animation guide&lt;/a&gt; and Vasilij Schneidermann for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/wasamasa/xbm-life&quot;&gt;xbm-life&lt;/a&gt; package. The code relies heavily on these two sources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Contribution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please feel free to do whatever you want with this code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ideas and pull requests are very welcome. I can be reached through &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:johanvts@gmail.com&quot;&gt;johanvts@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt; or on twitter @johanvts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;To-Do&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Better status bar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 25 Dec 2018 18:23:23 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>clircle</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars2.githubusercontent.com/u/1846239?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>johanvts/emacs-fireplace</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/johanvts/emacs-fireplace</og:url>
<og:description>A cozy fireplace for emacs. Contribute to johanvts/emacs-fireplace development by creating an account on GitHub.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/johanvts/emacs-fireplace</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>T * sin (t) ≈ Christmas tree</title>
<link>https://github.com/anvaka/atree</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/anvaka/atree</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;Box-body p-6&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;markdown-body entry-content&quot; itemprop=&quot;text&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found animated Christmas tree on reddit:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/1ef821cdc5a42e5a04bfb71b0c830f7f4a6572d3/687474703a2f2f692e696d6775722e636f6d2f46793453316a522e676966&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/1ef821cdc5a42e5a04bfb71b0c830f7f4a6572d3/687474703a2f2f692e696d6775722e636f6d2f46793453316a522e676966&quot; alt=&quot;reddit tree&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/Fy4S1jR.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Was curious to make it in js. Current results are here: &lt;a href=&quot;http://anvaka.github.io/atree/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Happy new 2018!&lt;/a&gt;. Wish you all great successes and joy, doing what you love!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How it's built?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tree is built of two spirals. These &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/anvaka/atree/blob/2937249242a0204929aca45cdb8b937cfb5af3e5/index.js#L86-L97&quot;&gt;11 lines of code&lt;/a&gt; render one line on spiral. It includes 3d projection and background shadow. &lt;em&gt;Almost&lt;/em&gt; the same as this &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:ComplexSinInATimeAxe.gif&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;wiki image&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/99bc360506276759bf0e0e8ecf2d429990974189/687474703a2f2f75706c6f61642e77696b696d656469612e6f72672f77696b6970656469612f636f6d6d6f6e732f612f61352f436f6d706c657853696e496e4154696d654178652e676966&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/99bc360506276759bf0e0e8ecf2d429990974189/687474703a2f2f75706c6f61642e77696b696d656469612e6f72672f77696b6970656469612f636f6d6d6f6e732f612f61352f436f6d706c657853696e496e4154696d654178652e676966&quot; alt=&quot;spiral&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/a/a5/ComplexSinInATimeAxe.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;It's almost perfect now&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EDIT:&lt;/strong&gt; Thank you reddit. With your help we made it almost perfect. You are awesome!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Huge appreciation goes to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/CensoredUsername&quot;&gt;@CensoredUsername&lt;/a&gt; who made &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/programming/comments/1tswai/t_sin_t_christmas_tree/cebhvu9&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;significant improvement&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Yazuak&quot;&gt;@Yazuak&lt;/a&gt; first gave and implemented &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/programming/comments/1tswai/t_sin_t_christmas_tree/cebajpt&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;idea&lt;/a&gt; of how to manage even distribution of points along the curves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vitaliy Kaurov implemented the same tree in Wolfram language... in just &lt;a href=&quot;http://community.wolfram.com/groups/-/m/t/175891&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;15 lines of code&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/davidlibrera&quot;&gt;David Librera&lt;/a&gt; rewrote this in CoffeScript. Checkout &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/davidlibrera/atree/tree/master/js/coffee&quot;&gt;his repository&lt;/a&gt; for nice OO design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what's left? Just small changes which could make this tree perfect:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Shadows are not accurate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I think code is more complex than it should be (subjectively).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MIT&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 25 Dec 2018 17:44:51 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>adamnemecek</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars2.githubusercontent.com/u/225407?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>anvaka/atree</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/anvaka/atree</og:url>
<og:description>Just a simple christmas tree, based on redit story - anvaka/atree</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/anvaka/atree</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Teach Yourself Logic: A Study Guide [pdf]</title>
<link>https://www.logicmatters.net/resources/pdfs/TeachYourselfLogic2017.pdf</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.logicmatters.net/resources/pdfs/TeachYourselfLogic2017.pdf</guid>
<description>&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.logicmatters.net/resources/pdfs/TeachYourselfLogic2017.pdf&quot;&gt;Download PDF&lt;/a&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 25 Dec 2018 16:40:07 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>furcyd</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars2.githubusercontent.com/u/225407?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>anvaka/atree</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/anvaka/atree</og:url>
<og:description>Just a simple christmas tree, based on redit story - anvaka/atree</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.logicmatters.net/resources/pdfs/TeachYourselfLogic2017.pdf</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>China Cracks Down on Churches</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/12/25/world/asia/china-christmas-church-crackdown.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2018/12/25/world/asia/china-christmas-church-crackdown.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;css-u5vfum StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;CHENGDU, China — For months, Gu Baoluo had been looking forward to a boisterous Christmas celebration at one of China’s best-known Protestant churches. He loved decorating trees, singing songs like “Silent Night” and watching the annual Christmas pageant recounting the birth of Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;But in early December, the police &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/12/13/world/asia/china-religion-crackdown.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;shut down&lt;/a&gt; Mr. Gu’s usual place of worship, the Early Rain Covenant Church in the southwest city of Chengdu, as part of what activists say is the most severe crackdown on Christianity in more than a decade. The police confiscated Bibles, shuttered a school and seminary run by the well-known church and detained Early Rain’s outspoken pastor on charges of “inciting subversion,” punishable in serious cases by at least five years in prison.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;On Christmas Eve, Mr. Gu, 31, a rice seller, went to the only safe place to worship that he knew: a friend’s home, where he recited hymns and prayed for the two dozen Early Rain members that are in detention. Fearing that he and his friends might be arrested, Mr. Gu used encrypted chat apps to share information about surveillance and harassment by the police.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“We will not forfeit our faith because of suppression by the authorities,” Mr. Gu said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;As millions around the world gathered to celebrate Christmas, China is capping a year in which the government of President Xi Jinping has led an unrelenting campaign against unofficial churches in China, which by some estimates serve as many as 30 million people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-1m2ozyi&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;css-u5vfum StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Mr. Xi, apparently concerned that independent worship might pose a threat to the ruling Communist Party’s dominance over daily life in China, has sought to bring Christianity more firmly under the party’s control. The government this year &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/04/05/world/asia/china-bans-bible-sales.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;banned online sales of the Bible&lt;/a&gt;, burned crosses, &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/01/12/world/asia/china-church-dynamite.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;demolished churches&lt;/a&gt; and forced at least a half-dozen places of worship to close.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The campaign comes as Mr. Xi, the most powerful Chinese leader since Mao Zedong, has worked to more aggressively &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/09/24/world/asia/china-vatican-agreement-appoint-catholic-bishops.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;control religion&lt;/a&gt; across China, including the &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/09/08/world/asia/china-uighur-muslim-detention-camp.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;detention of thousands of Muslims&lt;/a&gt; in the western region of Xinjiang.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-1m2ozyi&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-13nfagi&quot;&gt;
&lt;section id=&quot;chinamap&quot; data-id=&quot;100000006279465&quot; class=&quot;interactive-embedded interactive-size-scoop css-16sx513 e10adaur1&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;interactive-graphic css-17ih8de e10adaur0&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-1226-for-webCHINAmap-box&quot; class=&quot;ai2html ai2html-box-v5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;g-1226-for-webCHINAmap-1_8_x_2&quot; class=&quot;g-artboard&quot; data-aspect-ratio=&quot;0.9&quot; data-min-width=&quot;300&quot;&gt;&lt;img id=&quot;g-1226-for-webCHINAmap-1_8_x_2-img&quot; class=&quot;g-aiImg g-aiAbs&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/newsgraphics/2018/12/25/chinamap/2906eca5f75baa8edc34e8d01ec5e8c6d8088095/1226-for-webCHINAmap-1_8_x_2.png&quot; src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhCgAKAIAAAB8fHwAAACH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAAKAAoAAAIIhI+py+0PYysAOw==&quot;/&gt;










&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;footer class=&quot;css-irejme interactive-footer custom-footer&quot;&gt;&lt;p data-testid=&quot;credit&quot; class=&quot;css-1ct2c9h interactive-credit custom-credit&quot;&gt;By The New York Times&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/footer&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-wrapper&quot; class=&quot;css-79elbk ehw59r11&quot;&gt;

&lt;div data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-children&quot; class=&quot;css-1a48zt4 ehw59r111&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1xdhyk6 e1vv25i80&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1afaoz0&quot;&gt;Image&lt;/span&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;css-1m50asq&quot; src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/12/26/world/26china-2/merlin_142082223_30b62be3-a1c4-43b2-86ba-75003c3b9126-articleLarge.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;auto=webp&amp;amp;disable=upscale&quot; srcset=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/12/26/world/26china-2/merlin_142082223_30b62be3-a1c4-43b2-86ba-75003c3b9126-articleLarge.jpg?quality=90&amp;amp;auto=webp 600w,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/12/26/world/26china-2/merlin_142082223_30b62be3-a1c4-43b2-86ba-75003c3b9126-jumbo.jpg?quality=90&amp;amp;auto=webp 1024w,https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/12/26/world/26china-2/merlin_142082223_30b62be3-a1c4-43b2-86ba-75003c3b9126-superJumbo.jpg?quality=90&amp;amp;auto=webp 2048w&quot; sizes=&quot;((min-width: 600px) and (max-width: 1004px)) 84vw, (min-width: 1005px) 60vw, 100vw&quot; itemprop=&quot;url&quot; itemid=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/12/26/world/26china-2/merlin_142082223_30b62be3-a1c4-43b2-86ba-75003c3b9126-articleLarge.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;auto=webp&amp;amp;disable=upscale&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;css-8i9d0s e1olku6u0&quot;&gt;The Chinese authorities shuttered a church near the city of Nanyang in central China earlier this year as part of a broad campaign against independent churches.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot; class=&quot;css-vuqh7u e18m0s9i0&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1afaoz0&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Ng Han Guan/Associated Press&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-u5vfum StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Renee Xia, international director for China Human Rights Defenders, an advocacy group, described the effort as targeting the “heart of the underground Christian resistance.” The government has focused its campaign on unofficial Christian churches that promote ideas like social justice or have been critical of the party’s grip on society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“The message,” Ms. Xia said, “is that Xi can’t be messed with.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The crackdown escalated in the weeks leading up to Christmas. The police this month shut down the 40-year-old Rongguili Church in the southern Chinese city of Guangzhou, which attracted thousands of worshipers. And in September, the authorities in Beijing ordered the closing of the 1,500-member Zion Church, one of the largest unofficial churches in the capital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The government requires religious groups to register, though many still worship in unofficial churches, sometimes called underground or house churches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-1m2ozyi&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-u5vfum StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Many in the party believe Christianity, which by some estimates is China’s fastest-growing religion, promotes Western values and ideals like human rights that conflict with the aims of China’s authoritarian government and Mr. Xi’s embrace of traditional Chinese culture and Confucian teachings that emphasize obedience and order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;But the government’s heavy-handed efforts to obliterate several high-profile churches have been met with resistance among Christians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;On Christmas Eve, the authorities posted a sign at Early Rain’s former headquarters saying its 23rd-floor sanctuary had been converted into office space for the local government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Li Shuangde, a teacher in Chengdu who has been part of Early Rain since 2011, said that church members had been asked by the authorities to sign letters stating that they no longer believe in Christianity. He said Early Rain had no choice but continue to exist in secret. “We have moved underground,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-1m2ozyi&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-wrapper&quot; class=&quot;css-79elbk ehw59r11&quot;&gt;

&lt;div data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-children&quot; class=&quot;css-1a48zt4 ehw59r111&quot;&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;css-8i9d0s e1olku6u0&quot;&gt;Police officers in Beijing keeping watch in September outside Zion Church, which was ordered by the authorities to close. The 1,500-member church was one of the largest unofficial churches in the capital.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot; class=&quot;css-vuqh7u e18m0s9i0&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1afaoz0&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Andy Wong/Associated Press&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-u5vfum StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Members have continued to hold Sunday services, sometimes on the banks of a river near the church’s former headquarters in a downtown high-rise. They have called for the release of detained leaders, including Wang Yi, the pastor of Early Rain, and his wife, Jiang Rong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Mr. Wang, in a &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://chinachange.org/2018/12/24/my-declaration-the-faith-of-disobedience/&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;prewritten message&lt;/a&gt; released after his detention, spoke about the importance of disobedience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“The Communist regime’s persecution of the church is an extremely vicious crime,” he wrote. “As a pastor of the Christian church, I must strictly and publicly condemn such crimes.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-1m2ozyi&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-u5vfum StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Mr. Wang had been scheduled to deliver a Christmas Eve sermon at Early Rain titled “The God Who Bestows Peace.” Instead, hundreds of Early Rain members on Monday scattered across Chengdu for services inside the homes of friends and relatives or at welcoming churches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;At Chengdu Xishuipang Reformed Church, a Protestant church with close ties to Early Rain, more than 100 people gathered inside a worship hall on the 16th floor of an apartment building.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;A children’s choir sang “Silent Night,” and a small Christmas tree, decorated with snowflakes, was on display near the lectern.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The anxieties brought on by the recent arrests hung over the ceremony.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“If you see the police, national security or community workers, greet them with gentleness,” Wen Hongbin, an elder at Xishuipang, told the congregation. “If they try to grab the microphone, I ask the brothers sitting in the front row to please stop them.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-1m2ozyi&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-wrapper&quot; class=&quot;css-79elbk ehw59r11&quot;&gt;

&lt;div data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-children&quot; class=&quot;css-1a48zt4 ehw59r111&quot;&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;css-8i9d0s e1olku6u0&quot;&gt;An entrance to Zion Church, an independent Protestant congregation in Beijing, has been sealed by order of the police since September.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot; class=&quot;css-vuqh7u e18m0s9i0&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1afaoz0&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Andy Wong/Associated Press&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-u5vfum StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;While he did not explicitly mention Early Rain, Mr. Wen asked those in attendance to remember “those who are criminally detained.” Then he began a sermon about the meaning of Christmas and the sacrifice made by Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Since Mr. Xi rose to power in 2012, the authorities have led a sustained campaign against unregistered churches. In one province, more than 1,500 crosses &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2016/05/22/world/asia/china-christians-zhejiang.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;were removed from churches&lt;/a&gt; from 2014 to 2016, according to advocacy groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;This year, some Chinese cities have &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/12/19/world/asia/china-christmas-display-ban.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;banned Christmas displays&lt;/a&gt;. But the government also allows some degree of celebration, in part to stimulate the economy. Here in Chengdu, the capital of Sichuan Province, Christmas trees stand side by side on city streets with propaganda posters, and music from “The Nutcracker” plays in the background at malls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-1m2ozyi&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-u5vfum StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Officials in the United States have denounced the Chinese government’s efforts to limit the spread of Christianity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“China’s Christians and other faith communities are under siege and treated as enemies of the state for daring to worship and peacefully live out their faith,” Senator Marco Rubio of Florida and Representative Chris Smith of New Jersey said in a joint statement condemning the recent detentions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;But China’s growing influence in world affairs has shielded it from some criticism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;One notably silent voice: the Vatican, which in September &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/09/22/world/asia/china-vatican-bishops.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;reached a provisional deal&lt;/a&gt; with the Chinese government to end a decades-old power struggle over the right to appoint bishops in China. The Vatican said it &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;http://www.globaltimes.cn/content/1132032.shtml&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;sent a delegation of leaders&lt;/a&gt; to China this month to work out details of the agreement, but declined to comment on the crackdown on Christian churches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Despite Mr. Xi’s efforts to expand the officially atheist party’s control of worship, religious life in China is flourishing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-1m2ozyi&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-wrapper&quot; class=&quot;css-79elbk ehw59r11&quot;&gt;

&lt;div data-testid=&quot;photoviewer-children&quot; class=&quot;css-1a48zt4 ehw59r111&quot;&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;css-8i9d0s e1olku6u0&quot;&gt;Members of the Early Rain church have continued to hold Sunday services, sometimes on the banks of a river near the church’s former headquarters.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;copyrightHolder&quot; class=&quot;css-vuqh7u e18m0s9i0&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;css-1ly73wi e1afaoz0&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;The New York Times&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-u5vfum StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;While official figures are imprecise, experts believe there are about 60 million Christians in China, with roughly half worshiping at state-sanctioned churches and half at unofficial churches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Independent churches like Early Rain, with more than 500 members, have attracted large followings in recent years, especially among white-collar workers seeking an escape from rampant materialism at the center of modern Chinese life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;While sermons at state-sanctioned churches are often tightly scripted, independent churches boom with searing indictments of corrupt officials and rousing calls to protect the rights of the poor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-1m2ozyi&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-u5vfum StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-4w7y5l&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Early Rain, which Mr. Wang founded in 2008, was among the most daring. Mr. Wang called Mr. Xi a sinner, held prayer sessions each year to mark the brutal crackdown on pro-democracy demonstrations around Tiananmen Square in Beijing in 1989, and organized a fund to support relatives of political prisoners in China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Mr. Gu, the rice seller, began attending services two years ago after finding videos of Mr. Wang’s fiery sermons online. He felt Mr. Wang’s concern for the poor was in line with his own view that the government was abusing workers and violating human rights by destroying their homes to make way for expensive developments. Mr. Gu was baptized last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“I saw injustices in society,” Mr. Gu said. “I saw that the government’s promotion of China as a just country that enforces laws in a civilized manner was all a lie.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Worried for his own safety, Mr. Gu recently closed his business, hoping to avoid government scrutiny. He said he has grown fearful as he has watched the police arrest his friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Mr. Gu has turned to the Bible in recent days for support. Sometimes, he recites a verse from the Book of Proverbs: “The path of the righteous is like the morning sun, shining ever brighter till the full light of day.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-1m2ozyi&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 25 Dec 2018 16:22:24 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>traderjane</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/12/25/world/asia/china-christmas-church-crackdown.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>As China Cracks Down on Churches, Christians Declare ‘We Will Not Forfeit Our Faith’</og:title>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/12/26/world/26china-5/26china-5-facebookJumbo.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>China this year banned online sales of the Bible, burned crosses, demolished churches and forced at least a half-dozen places of worship to close.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/12/25/world/asia/china-christmas-church-crackdown.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Mental Models I Find Repeatedly Useful (2016)</title>
<link>https://medium.com/@yegg/mental-models-i-find-repeatedly-useful-936f1cc405d</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://medium.com/@yegg/mental-models-i-find-repeatedly-useful-936f1cc405d</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;section-inner sectionLayout--insetColumn&quot; readability=&quot;48.581383773021&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;aspectRatioPlaceholder is-locked&quot;&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;graf-image&quot; data-image-id=&quot;1*C1DE6dVyfkEdFIvmFZC_4Q.jpeg&quot; data-width=&quot;1666&quot; data-height=&quot;1666&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; data-action-value=&quot;1*C1DE6dVyfkEdFIvmFZC_4Q.jpeg&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*C1DE6dVyfkEdFIvmFZC_4Q.jpeg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;uiScale uiScale-ui--regular uiScale-caption--regular u-flexCenter u-marginVertical24 u-fontSize15 js-postMetaLockup&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;u-flex0&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;link u-baseColor--link avatar&quot; href=&quot;https://medium.com/@yegg?source=post_header_lockup&quot; data-action=&quot;show-user-card&quot; data-action-source=&quot;post_header_lockup&quot; data-action-value=&quot;e1a76f1f570&quot; data-action-type=&quot;hover&quot; data-user-id=&quot;e1a76f1f570&quot; dir=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/fit/c/100/100/1*4idmo7xd7H02knpQ7BGCRw.jpeg&quot; class=&quot;avatar-image u-size50x50&quot; alt=&quot;Go to the profile of Gabriel Weinberg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;u-flex1 u-paddingLeft15 u-overflowHidden&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;time datetime=&quot;2016-07-06T00:42:46.920Z&quot;&gt;Jul 5, 2016&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;2fdf&quot; id=&quot;2fdf&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--h3&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;Update: Since this post came out, I co-authored a book about it called&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2PqmeZD&quot; data-href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2PqmeZD&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;Super Thinking&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;. Get notified about book updates&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://upscri.be/6b02a1&quot; data-href=&quot;https://upscri.be/6b02a1&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;here&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;markup--em markup--p-em&quot;&gt;(currently scheduled to come out in May, 2019).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;7c0e&quot; id=&quot;7c0e&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Around 2003 I came across &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Charlie_Munger&quot; data-href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Charlie_Munger&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Charlie Munger’s&lt;/a&gt; 1995 speech, &lt;a href=&quot;http://web.archive.org/web/20151004200748/http://law.indiana.edu/instruction/profession/doc/16_1.pdf&quot; data-href=&quot;http://web.archive.org/web/20151004200748/http://law.indiana.edu/instruction/profession/doc/16_1.pdf&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Psychology of Human Misjudgment&lt;/a&gt;, which introduced me to how behavioral economics can be applied in business and investing. More profoundly, though, it opened my mind to the power of seeking out and applying mental models across a wide array of disciplines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;7550&quot; id=&quot;7550&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;A mental model is just a concept you can use to help try to explain things (e.g. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hanlon%27s_razor&quot; data-href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hanlon%27s_razor&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Hanlon’s Razor&lt;/a&gt; — “never attribute to malice that which is adequately explained by carelessness.”). There are tens of thousands of mental models, and every discipline has their own set that you can learn through coursework, mentorship, or first-hand experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;4ce5&quot; id=&quot;4ce5&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;There is a much smaller set of concepts, however, that come up repeatedly in day-to-day decision making, problem solving, and truth seeking. As &lt;a href=&quot;https://25iq.com/2015/08/22/a-dozen-things-ive-learned-from-charlie-munger-about-mental-models-and-worldly-wisdom/&quot; data-href=&quot;https://25iq.com/2015/08/22/a-dozen-things-ive-learned-from-charlie-munger-about-mental-models-and-worldly-wisdom/&quot; class=&quot;markup--anchor markup--p-anchor&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Munger says&lt;/a&gt;, “80 or 90 important models will carry about 90% of the freight in making you a worldly‑wise person.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;a273&quot; id=&quot;a273&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;This post is my attempt to enumerate the mental models that are repeatedly useful to me. This set is clearly biased from my own experience and surely incomplete. I hope to continue to revise it as I remember and learn more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;4a73&quot; id=&quot;4a73&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;How-to Use This List&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;11b8&quot; id=&quot;11b8&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;I find mental models are useful to try to make sense of things and to help generate ideas. To actually be useful, however, you have to apply them in the right context at the right time. And for that to happen naturally, you have to know them well and practice using them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p name=&quot;48b3&quot; id=&quot;48b3&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Therefore, here are two suggestions for using this list:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;postList&quot;&gt;&lt;li name=&quot;ae90&quot; id=&quot;ae90&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--p&quot;&gt;For mental models you don’t know or don’t know well, you can use this list as a jumping off point to study them. I’ve provided links (mainly to Wikipedia) to start that process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;7c51&quot; id=&quot;7c51&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;When you have a particular problem in front of you, you can go down this list, and see if any of the models could possibly apply.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p name=&quot;8e62&quot; id=&quot;8e62&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--p graf-after--li&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;markup--strong markup--p-strong&quot;&gt;Notes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;postList&quot;&gt;&lt;li name=&quot;3743&quot; id=&quot;3743&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--p&quot;&gt;Most of the mental models on this list are here because they are useful outside of their specific discipline. For example, use of the mental model “peak oil” isn’t restricted to an energy context. Most references to “peak x” are an invocation of this model. Similarly, inflation as a concept applies outside of economics, e.g. grade inflation and expectations inflation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;d553&quot; id=&quot;d553&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;I roughly grouped the mental models by discipline, but as noted, this grouping is not to be taken as an assertion that they only apply within that dicipline. The best ideas often arise when going cross-dicipline.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;25e4&quot; id=&quot;25e4&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;I realize my definition of mental model differs from some others, with mine being more broadly defined as any concept that helps explain, analyze, or navigate the world. I prefer this broader definition because it allows me to assemble a more wide-ranging list of useful concepts that may not be mental models under other definitions, but I nevertheless find on relatively equal footing in terms of usefulness in the real world.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;dcf9&quot; id=&quot;dcf9&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;The numbers next to each mental model reflect the frequency with which they come up:&lt;br/&gt;(1) — Frequently (63 models)&lt;br/&gt;(2) — Occasionally (43 models)&lt;br/&gt;(3) — Rarely, though still repeatedly (83 models)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;847f&quot; id=&quot;847f&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;If studying new models, I’d start with the lower numbers first. The quotes next to each concept are meant to be a basic definition to remind you what it is, and not a teaching tool. Follow the link to learn more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;4f1f&quot; id=&quot;4f1f&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li&quot;&gt;I am not endorsing any of these concepts as normatively good; I’m just saying they have repeatedly helped me explain and navigate the world.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li name=&quot;7d13&quot; id=&quot;7d13&quot; class=&quot;graf graf--li graf-after--li graf--trailing&quot;&gt;I wish I had learned many of these years earlier. In fact, the proximate cause for posting this was so I could more effectively answer the question I frequently get from people I work with: “what should I learn next?” If you’re trying to be generally effective, my best advice is to start with the things on this list.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 25 Dec 2018 16:16:10 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>febin</dc:creator>
<og:title>Mental Models I Find Repeatedly Useful – Gabriel Weinberg – Medium</og:title>
<og:url>https://medium.com/@yegg/mental-models-i-find-repeatedly-useful-936f1cc405d</og:url>
<og:image>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*C1DE6dVyfkEdFIvmFZC_4Q.jpeg</og:image>
<og:description>Update: Since this post came out, I co-authored a book about it called Super Thinking. Get notified about book updates here (currently…</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://medium.com/@yegg/mental-models-i-find-repeatedly-useful-936f1cc405d</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>