<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Trump administration announces overhaul of H1B visa program requiring higher pay</title>
<link>https://www.wsj.com/articles/trump-administration-announces-overhaul-of-h-1b-visa-program-11602017434</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.wsj.com/articles/trump-administration-announces-overhaul-of-h-1b-visa-program-11602017434</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;is-lead-inset&quot;&gt;
&lt;div data-layout=&quot;header&quot; data-layout-mobile=&quot;&quot; class=&quot; media-object type-InsetMediaIllustration header article__inset article__inset--type-InsetMediaIllustration article__inset--header article__inset--lead&quot;&gt;
&lt;div data-mobile-ratio=&quot;66.66666666666666%&quot; data-layout-ratio=&quot;66.66666666666666%&quot; data-subtype=&quot;photo&quot; class=&quot;image-container responsive-media article__inset__image__image&quot;&gt;&lt;img srcset=&quot;https://images.wsj.net/im-241285?width=140&amp;amp;size=1.5 140w, https://images.wsj.net/im-241285?width=540&amp;amp;size=1.5 540w, https://images.wsj.net/im-241285?width=620&amp;amp;size=1.5 620w, https://images.wsj.net/im-241285?width=700&amp;amp;size=1.5 700w, https://images.wsj.net/im-241285?width=860&amp;amp;size=1.5 860w, https://images.wsj.net/im-241285?width=1260&amp;amp;size=1.5 1260w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 140px) 100px, (max-width: 540px) 500px, (max-width: 620px) 580px, (max-width: 700px) 660px, (max-width: 860px) 820px, 1260px&quot; src=&quot;https://images.wsj.net/im-241285?width=620&amp;amp;size=1.5&quot; data-enlarge=&quot;https://images.wsj.net/im-241285?width=1260&amp;amp;size=1.5&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Trump administration announced an overhaul of a visa program for high-skilled foreign workers.&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;wsj-article-caption-content&quot;&gt;The Trump administration announced an overhaul of a visa program for high-skilled foreign workers.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;wsj-article-credit article__inset__image__caption__credit&quot; itemprop=&quot;creator&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;wsj-article-credit-tag&quot;&gt;Photo:&lt;/span&gt; michael reynolds/EPA/Shutterstock&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;clearfix byline-wrap&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;byline article__byline&quot;&gt;By
&lt;div class=&quot;author-container&quot;&gt;&lt;button class=&quot;author-button&quot;&gt;Michelle Hackman&lt;/button&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;author-dropdown&quot;&gt;&lt;button aria-label=&quot;Close&quot; class=&quot;mobile-modal-close&quot;&gt;Close&lt;/button&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;mobile-modal-author-name&quot;&gt;Michelle Hackman&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;time class=&quot;timestamp article__timestamp flexbox__flex--1&quot;&gt;Updated Oct. 6, 2020 8:46 pm ET&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;article-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WASHINGTON—The Trump administration announced an overhaul of the H-1B visa program for high-skilled foreign workers that will require employers to pay H-1B workers significantly higher wages, narrow the types of degrees that could qualify an applicant and shorten the length of visas for certain contract workers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The changes, introduced by the Departments of Labor and Homeland Security on Tuesday, will likely make it tougher to qualify for one of the coveted visas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paywall&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ken Cuccinelli, the No. 2 official at DHS, said on a news conference call Tuesday that he expects about one-third of H-1B visa applications would be rejected under the new set of rules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div data-layout=&quot;wrap&quot; data-layout-mobile=&quot;&quot; class=&quot; media-object type-InsetRichText wrap scope-web|mobileapps article__inset article__inset--type-InsetRichText article__inset--wrap&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;media-object-rich-text&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;More on H-1B visas&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mr. Cuccinelli and Patrick Pizzella, the deputy secretary of labor, said the changes were necessary to protect American workers, whom the administration believes are being undercut by foreign workers on H-1B visas who are paid lower wages to perform similar jobs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“America’s immigration laws should put American workers first,” Mr. Pizzella said, pointing to what he described as insufficiently stringent wage requirements on foreign workers in the H-1B visa program. “The result is U.S. workers are being ousted from good-paying, middle-class jobs and being replaced by foreign workers,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The policy changes have been expected &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/indian-workers-in-u-s-fear-trump-h-1b-visa-crackdown-1488191404&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;icon none&quot;&gt;since 2017&lt;/a&gt;, when the administration first announced intentions to revamp the H-1B visa program. Even before these formal changes were announced, however, the Trump administration &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/approval-rate-declines-for-h-1b-visas-11550926800&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;icon none&quot;&gt;tightened issuance of H-1B visas&lt;/a&gt;, rejecting 15.1% of applications in 2019 compared with 6.1% in 2016, according to figures from U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Business groups and immigrant advocates criticized the overhaul, saying the Trump administration was attempting to solve a problem that doesn’t exist on a broad scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A federal judge in San Francisco last week &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/judge-partially-blocks-trump-administration-from-enforcing-visa-ban-11601593554&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;icon none&quot;&gt;blocked the Trump administration&lt;/a&gt; from enforcing its ban against many of the biggest U.S. companies bringing in foreign workers under H-1B and other visas. TechNet, one of four business and trade organizations that brought the suit, said Tuesday’s announcement flouted the court’s ruling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Changing the requirements around H-1B and other work visas will only hurt American companies that depend on high-skilled workers who fill critical positions while we work to grow our domestic [science, technology, engineering and math] pipeline,” said Linda Moore, TechNet’s president and chief executive officer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jon Baselice, executive director of immigration policy at the U.S. Chamber of Commerce, another one of the plaintiffs in the suit, said, “We’re still evaluating these proposals, but both of these rules have the potential to inflict serious harm upon many American companies.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Labor Department’s wage-scale revision would significantly increase the required wages employers must pay their workers on H-1B visas. The requirements, which are set to take effect Thursday, are based on surveys of the range of salaries paid in particular professions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under the new rule, the required wage level for entry-level workers would rise to the 45th percentile of their profession’s distribution, from the current requirement of the 17th percentile. The requirement for the highest-skilled workers would rise to the 95th percentile, from the 67th percentile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because those required wage increases take effect this week, existing H-1B holders looking to renew their visas might not qualify unless their employers raise their salaries accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Department of Homeland Security’s rule would narrow who qualifies for H-1B visas based on their specific education. Currently, foreigners with a college degree or the equivalent amount of experience can apply to work in what is known as a specialty occupation. Under the changes, an applicant must have a college degree in the specific field in which he or she is looking to work. A software developer, for example, wouldn’t be awarded an H-1B visa if that person has a degree in electrical engineering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That requirement could make it tough for technology companies to hire in emerging fields like artificial intelligence or bioinformatics, which combines biological data, computer science and mathematics. Experts in such fields may have studied other subjects, or degrees in some subjects may not have existed until recently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only exception to this rule is for fashion models, who aren’t required to have college degrees. First lady Melania Trump, who worked as a fashion model when she first moved to the U.S. from Slovenia in 1996, was an H-1B visa recipient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new rules also aim to curb business arrangements under which an H-1B worker hired by one company works primarily at a second company. Those arrangements would receive more scrutiny in the application process, and these workers would receive visas that are valid for only one year instead of three, as are most H-1B visas. That would increase costs for employers, who would need to file new applications for their workers annually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The changes target information-technology companies that rely on H-1B workers, mostly from India, whom they outsource to companies to work as on-site IT staff. Critics of the H-1B program take issue with these deals, pointing to companies that lay off internal IT staffs in favor of cheaper outside workers. The arrangement is common in several industries including human resources and consulting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new policies were issued as interim final rules, meaning they will take effect without first undergoing a public-comment and review process that is customary for such rules. The administration also waived its typical regulatory review process before issuing to the rule in order to be able to publish it faster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Administration officials said both measures were necessary to speed the policy changes in the midst of the continuing economic fallout from the coronavirus pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similar policy changes that bypass the customary regulatory process have been met with legal challenges, and in some cases have been overturned by courts. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/trumps-daca-setback-puts-immigration-judicial-picks-in-2020-spotlight-11592520950&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;icon none&quot;&gt;The Supreme Court ruled in June&lt;/a&gt; that the Trump administration improperly ended the Deferred Action for Childhood Arrivals program for immigrants who have lived in the U.S. illegally since childhood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The government issues about 85,000 H-1B visas each year, though it receives many more applications than it can accept.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if the rejection rate rises, the number of workers on visas is likely to remain roughly stable, said Theresa Brown, director of cross-border policy at the Bipartisan Policy Center, a Washington-based think tank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“If you’re saying you’re doing this because lots of people are unemployed, I don’t see anything in here that says there will actually be fewer H-1B workers,” Ms. Brown said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rule’s economic analysis states that, wage increases aside, the other changes DHS is requiring will cost employers about $4.3 billion over a decade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Instead of pursuing targeted policies that would root out real fraud by unscrupulous employers, they are demonizing half a million employees and presenting no compelling evidence that they actually depress wages,” said Doug Rand, who advised the Obama administration on immigration policy and co-founded a company that helps people apply for green cards. He said the accelerated pace was part of Mr. Trump’s re-election strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Democratic presidential nominee Joe Biden’s immigration platform says he supports moves such as raising the required wages for H-1B workers. His campaign didn’t respond to a question about whether the former vice president would keep the Trump administration’s changes in place. The next Congress could vote to reverse the changes under a law called the Congressional Review Act.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Write to&lt;/strong&gt; Michelle Hackman at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:Michelle.Hackman@wsj.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;icon&quot;&gt;Michelle.Hackman@wsj.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Copyright ©2020 Dow Jones &amp;amp; Company, Inc. All Rights Reserved. 87990cbe856818d5eddac44c7b1cdeb8&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;printheadline&quot;&gt;Appeared in the October 7, 2020, print edition as 'U.S. Imposes New Curbs on H-1B Visas.'&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 21:13:54 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>grej</dc:creator>
<og:title>Trump Administration Announces Overhaul of H-1B Visa Program</og:title>
<og:description>The changes will require employers to pay high-skilled foreign workers significantly higher wages, narrow the types of degrees that could qualify an applicant, and shorten the length of visas for certain contract workers.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.wsj.com/articles/trump-administration-announces-overhaul-of-h-1b-visa-program-11602017434</og:url>
<og:image>https://images.wsj.net/im-241285/social</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.wsj.com/articles/trump-administration-announces-overhaul-of-h-1b-visa-program-11602017434</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Eddie Van Halen has died</title>
<link>https://www.npr.org/2020/10/06/834995224/eddie-van-halen-guitar-hero-dies-at-65</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.npr.org/2020/10/06/834995224/eddie-van-halen-guitar-hero-dies-at-65</guid>
<description>&lt;div id=&quot;res920850248&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap image large&quot; readability=&quot;4.7441860465116&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;imagewrap&quot; data-crop-type=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2020/10/06/gettyimages-74299482_wide-5ac106c73086aa63c495089c35f4811d0bb1ce5b-s1100-c15.jpg&quot; data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2020/10/06/gettyimages-74299482_wide-5ac106c73086aa63c495089c35f4811d0bb1ce5b-s1100.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img lazyOnLoad&quot; alt=&quot;Eddie Van Halen.&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;credit-caption&quot;&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Michael Ochs Archive/Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;enlarge_measure&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img_wrap&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2020/10/06/gettyimages-74299482_wide-5ac106c73086aa63c495089c35f4811d0bb1ce5b-s1200.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Eddie Van Halen.&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;enlarge_html&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;credit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Image credit&quot;&gt;Michael Ochs Archive/Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eddie Van Halen, the guitarist and songwriter who helped give the rock band Van Halen its name and sound, died Tuesday after a battle with cancer. He was 65.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His death was announced by his son, Wolf Van Halen, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/WolfVanHalen/status/1313561314598350848&quot;&gt;on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;I can't believe I'm having to write this,&quot; the statement said, &quot;but my father, Edward Lodewijk Van Halen, has lost his long and arduous battle with cancer this morning. He was the best father I could ever ask for. Every moment I've shared with him on and off stage was a gift.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a band known for its instability — due in part to a rotating cast of lead singers that most notably includes David Lee Roth and Sammy Hagar — Eddie Van Halen and his brother, Alex, remained constants, appearing on 12 studio albums that reached across five decades and sold tens of millions of copies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No matter the singer, Eddie Van Halen's high-flying guitar sound — heavy on tapping, with both hands on the neck of the instrument — was deeply influential, but also hard to imitate. He grew up obsessed with Eric Clapton, only to himself become a lodestar for generations of guitarists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id=&quot;ad-backstage-wrap&quot; aria-label=&quot;advertisement&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 1972, with Alex on drums, Eddie Van Halen formed the band that would become Van Halen. By 1974, it had the lineup that would make it one of the biggest groups in rock history: the two Dutch-born brothers, plus bassist Michael Anthony and singer David Lee Roth. From there, Eddie Van Halen stood at the center of an era-spanning — but unmistakably volatile — rock-and-roll juggernaut.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;res920911980&quot; class=&quot;bucketwrap internallink insettwocolumn inset2col&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bucket img&quot;&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;featuredStackSquareImage146880432&quot; href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/sections/therecord/2012/02/14/146880432/the-truth-about-van-halen-and-those-brown-m-ms&quot; data-metrics=&quot;{&amp;quot;category&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Story to Story&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;action&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Click Internal Link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;label&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https:\/\/www.npr.org\/sections\/therecord\/2012\/02\/14\/146880432\/the-truth-about-van-halen-and-those-brown-m-ms&amp;quot;}&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2012/02/14/brown_mms_sq-fc51dd86df5ab63612079dc05c869e46722ac1eb-s100-c15.jpg&quot; data-original=&quot;https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2012/02/14/brown_mms_sq-fc51dd86df5ab63612079dc05c869e46722ac1eb-s100.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img lazyOnLoad&quot; alt=&quot;The Truth About Van Halen And Those Brown M&amp;amp;Ms&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout the late 1970s and early '80s, Van Halen became increasingly successful. Early hits such as 1979's &quot;Dance the Night Away&quot; eventually gave way to the bestselling &lt;em&gt;1984&lt;/em&gt; — the band's sixth album — which spawned the chart-topping &quot;Jump,&quot; as well as flamboyant hits like &quot;Panama&quot; and &quot;Hot for Teacher.&quot; Peaking at No. 2 on the &lt;em&gt;Billboard&lt;/em&gt; albums chart, &lt;em&gt;1984&lt;/em&gt; was held back only by Michael Jackson's &lt;em&gt;Thriller&lt;/em&gt;, whose iconic &quot;Beat It&quot; just happened to feature a guitar solo from Eddie Van Halen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But &lt;em&gt;1984&lt;/em&gt;'s success only intensified tensions between the Van Halen brothers and David Lee Roth, who left the band in 1985 for a solo career that capitalized on his cheerful, outsize persona. The remaining members of Van Halen regrouped around former Montrose frontman Sammy Hagar, who helped the group top the charts with its next four albums: &lt;em&gt;5150&lt;/em&gt; (1986), &lt;em&gt;OU812&lt;/em&gt; (1988), &lt;em&gt;For Unlawful Carnal Knowledge&lt;/em&gt; (1991) and &lt;em&gt;Balance&lt;/em&gt; (1995).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From there, the band's output slowed. Hagar left Van Halen in 1996, citing creative differences, which led Roth to rejoin briefly — only to give way to former Extreme frontman Gary Cherone, whose one album with Van Halen (1998's &lt;em&gt;Van Halen III&lt;/em&gt;) was a critical and commercial disappointment. Hagar and Roth both rejoined the group at various points since 2003, with the latter presiding over Van Halen's final album, 2012's &lt;em&gt;A Different Kind of Truth&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long known for his reclusiveness, Eddie Van Halen battled an assortment of health issues in recent decades, including hip-replacement surgery in 1999, a bout with tongue cancer in the early 2000s, a history of drug and alcohol abuse that led him to enter a rehabilitation facility in 2007 and surgery for diverticulitis in 2012.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though the guitarist often had contentious relationships with bandmates — particularly Roth and Hagar, each of whom criticized him heavily in books and interviews — Eddie Van Halen remained extremely close with family. In addition to a lifelong working relationship with his brother, Alex, he tirelessly championed his son, Wolf, who joined Van Halen as bassist after the departure of Michael Anthony in 2006.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Van Halen was inducted into the Rock &amp;amp; Roll Hall of Fame in 2007.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 20:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>psim1</dc:creator>
<og:title>Eddie Van Halen, Guitar Hero, Dies At 65</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.npr.org/2020/10/06/834995224/eddie-van-halen-guitar-hero-dies-at-65</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>The namesake of rock band Van Halen dazzled a generation of guitar fans with his flashy solos and trademark finger tapping.</og:description>
<og:image>https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2020/10/06/gettyimages-74299482_wide-5ac106c73086aa63c495089c35f4811d0bb1ce5b.jpg?s=1400</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.npr.org/2020/10/06/834995224/eddie-van-halen-guitar-hero-dies-at-65</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>How I remember what I learn</title>
<link>https://vasilishynkarenka.com/learning/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://vasilishynkarenka.com/learning/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“I don’t remember a damn thing.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book I held my hands was full of highlights. It seemed like I’ve got all colors of the rainbow on a page. Apparently, this didn’t help. When I tried recalling ideas from the book, I didn’t hear a thing. Just. Silence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Terrified, I started questioning how much I &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; know. If I forget everything I read, I can’t apply my knowledge to the problem at hand. I can’t transfer it. And without transfer, knowledge is very much like music for deaf ears.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I quickly did the math. I was planning to invest in learning a few hours a day for the next ~75 years of my life. Staring at the number of potentially wasted hours, I knew exactly what I had to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the past six months, I’ve devoured dozens of books, research papers, and studies on how people learn. As a result, I’ve designed a learning process that works for me. It’s not perfect, but an order of magnitude better than what I had before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this work, I outline my workflow so that you can try it out. It applies to any subject or discipline, from programming to economics. If you stumble upon something where it doesn’t work, let me know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Make it time-based, take regular breaks, and learn what you’re curious about.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most important thing is that my learning is time-based, not goal-based. Setting learning goals such as “read X pages today” is a way to fail because you set up the wrong incentives. When you plan to read X pages by lunch, you can’t help but begin optimizing for the goal, which leads to focusing on speed instead of understanding. And when you don’t have those “aha” moments, it is hard to remember what you learn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s also important to not overload yourself and take breaks. I do 3h learning sessions every day split into 30 min intervals with 5 min breaks. Breaks help to fall back into the diffuse mode of thinking and get access to a broader set of neural networks in my head. They also warm up my body, and I feel better after moving around for a few minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for material, I learn what I’m interested in. First, because life is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.paulgraham.com/vb.html&quot;&gt;too short&lt;/a&gt; to do things that you don’t love. Second, I’ve found that studying stuff I genuinely like awakens my curiosity. And curiosity is essential to develop mastery because mastery is about depth and breadth of knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, if you’re learning JavaScript and you’re curious about it, you’ll go and figure out how JS runtime environment works in Chrome even though the tutorial doesn’t cover it. Just because you’re interested. But if you’re not curious, then you’ll just memorize the tutorial, and your knowledge will be shallow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-my-learning-session-works&quot;&gt;How my learning session works&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clean up working memory, apply metacognition, and &quot;siege&quot; the thing with questions to improve understanding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I learn, I always have two devices on my desk. I have my laptop with the study material (ie, a book, a video, an article) on the right, and I have my iPad with a text editor open on the left.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is how my current setup looks like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://vasilishynkarenka.com/content/images/2020/09/IMG_2658.jpg&quot; class=&quot;kg-image&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;https://vasilishynkarenka.com/content/images/size/w600/2020/09/IMG_2658.jpg 600w, https://vasilishynkarenka.com/content/images/size/w1000/2020/09/IMG_2658.jpg 1000w, https://vasilishynkarenka.com/content/images/size/w1600/2020/09/IMG_2658.jpg 1600w, https://vasilishynkarenka.com/content/images/size/w2400/2020/09/IMG_2658.jpg 2400w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 720px) 720px&quot;/&gt;Morning learning session.
&lt;p&gt;When I begin learning, I set a timer for 30 minutes and create three files in Drafts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;A file with a timestamp where my random thoughts go.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A file with a timestamp where I think about the subject.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A file with questions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The first file is a mind dump.&lt;/strong&gt; When I start learning, I immediately begin thinking about things. It’s almost as if my brain wakes up and starts throwing ideas, tasks, and memories at me. I suspect this comes from the associative memory because I present myself with many triggers when I’m learning; words and sentences that bear special meaning to me and invoke these ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But here’s the problem. If I don’t write thoughts down, I can’t focus. My working memory is overloaded with todos, ideas, and emotions. You’ve probably experienced this for yourself – your mind is running too fast, and you can’t really concentrate on what you’re learning. Having this “dump” file is immensely useful to a) free up my working memory to focus on my learning instead of thinking about these things, and b) store these thoughts somewhere safe to go back to them later and take action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The second file is where I write about what I’m learning.&lt;/strong&gt; Folks in the kitchen call it metacognition, which means thinking about thinking. Metacognition is the single best trick I’ve found to improve understanding, and I will write more about it in the future. Whenever I don’t understand something or see that my understanding is shallow, I begin writing in the first person. It looks like this: “So Peter explains that there are four characteristics of a monopoly, but I don’t really understand why branding is one of them; why so?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s also important to note that I don’t write in a usual sentence-paragraph manner. Instead, I write every thought on a new line. I don’t even put dots at the end of the sentences. This helps me to focus on understanding instead of nitty-gritty styling and typos. The “enter” key on a keyboard serves as the “end of thought” symbol and helps formulate ideas more clearly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another important idea is that my editor is plain text. I’ve found it incredibly liberating to operate in a plain text environment where you don’t have incentives to color, underline, bold, italicize, or do some other weird things with the text you’re writing. Instead of choosing the right font for my heading, I can focus on meaning instead. Also, my plain text app is way faster than all feature-rich text editors, and I’ve found it essential for a thought input environment to be fast. Otherwise, I can't think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s a fragment from my learning of React yesterday:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://vasilishynkarenka.com/content/images/2020/09/IMG_D7F6BD12F133-1.jpeg&quot; class=&quot;kg-image&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;https://vasilishynkarenka.com/content/images/size/w600/2020/09/IMG_D7F6BD12F133-1.jpeg 600w, https://vasilishynkarenka.com/content/images/size/w1000/2020/09/IMG_D7F6BD12F133-1.jpeg 1000w, https://vasilishynkarenka.com/content/images/size/w1600/2020/09/IMG_D7F6BD12F133-1.jpeg 1600w, https://vasilishynkarenka.com/content/images/size/w2400/2020/09/IMG_D7F6BD12F133-1.jpeg 2400w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 720px) 720px&quot;/&gt;Metacognition notes from studying React.js.
&lt;p&gt;You’re probably thinking that it’s quite a bit of writing. It is. For an hour-long learning session, I usually do about 500-1000 words in this file. But it’s worth every character, and here’s why:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;When I apply metacognition, I understand things &lt;em&gt;way&lt;/em&gt; better than when I don’t. I’ve tested many different learning modes and found metacognition to perform at least 2x better based on my later ability to recall and transfer knowledge. Also, there’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://academicpublishingplatforms.com/downloads/pdfs/ati/volume18/201607070302_09_ATI_Vol11_Issue2_2015_Todorova_and_Karamanska_Study_motivation_satisfaction_students_e-learning_pp.82-89.pdf&quot;&gt;some&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.csun.edu/science/ref/reasoning/how-students-learn/1.html&quot;&gt;research&lt;/a&gt; on metacognition as well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Having a file with my thinking about the subject keeps my working memory clean. I don’t feel overloaded as I usually feel after reading many articles at one go. You’ve probably experienced this yourself; your brain is almost melting after an hour of scrolling through the web. That’s because you present yourself with too much information without really making sense of it. After a few months of applying metacognitive practices, I realized that I can’t go back. It just feels so strange to experience that cognitive load again.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Metacognition improves remembering through elaboration and interleaving. When I’m writing my thoughts in the file, I can’t help but begin connecting them with other ideas on that topic because of associative memory. And interleaving leads to mastery.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(Speculation) Training metacognition improves my ability to transform vague notions and thoughts that I have during the day into specific words that I can write down for later analysis. This one is particularly interesting to me, but there’s no evidence besides my own experiments. And I might be biased because I’ve come up with this method.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Moreover, I type 2-3x faster than most people because I use &lt;a href=&quot;https://barehands.substack.com/p/how-to-type-3x-faster&quot;&gt;shortcuts&lt;/a&gt;. So it’s not that bad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The third file is questions.&lt;/strong&gt; Whenever I stumble upon something that I don’t understand, I try to break it down into a set of simple questions. Each question in the group takes on a small part of the problem. If the concept is particularly challenging, I try to “siege” it with questions from many many different angles and break it down even further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I’m beginning a new session, I always start from the previous one’s questions file. I only look at questions and answer them before I’m beginning new learning. This doesn’t sound like very much fun, but it’s actually pretty interesting to explain stuff to yourself if you do it out loud. Answering questions improves my understanding and helps to connect ideas together. And yes, answering questions counts as learning – probably the most efficient learning you could be doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I'm not going into much detail on questions because Michael Nielsen has done a phenomenal job describing it &lt;a href=&quot;http://augmentingcognition.com/ltm.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-happens-after-the-session&quot;&gt;What happens after the session&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write a dense summary, provoke elaboration, interleaving, and transfer, and choose what to never forget.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the session is done, and my three files are full of information, I begin the recap process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First, I write a three to five sentence-long summary of what I’ve just studied.&lt;/strong&gt; Here I try to distill the material’s core idea and compress the whole thing into a maximally dense chunk. When I’m summarizing, my laptop is closed. Not looking at the text helps to “compress” the idea to its core and make a small “hook” to my memory to later see what the whole book was about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s how my summary note looks like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://vasilishynkarenka.com/content/images/2020/09/IMG_9771D059CFD1-1.jpeg&quot; class=&quot;kg-image&quot; alt=&quot;Recap of studying React.js.&quot; srcset=&quot;https://vasilishynkarenka.com/content/images/size/w600/2020/09/IMG_9771D059CFD1-1.jpeg 600w, https://vasilishynkarenka.com/content/images/size/w1000/2020/09/IMG_9771D059CFD1-1.jpeg 1000w, https://vasilishynkarenka.com/content/images/size/w1600/2020/09/IMG_9771D059CFD1-1.jpeg 1600w, https://vasilishynkarenka.com/content/images/size/w2400/2020/09/IMG_9771D059CFD1-1.jpeg 2400w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 720px) 720px&quot;/&gt;Recap of studying React.js.
&lt;p&gt;Very often, what I’m writing in the summary section is not what the text was about, but what it means to me. In other words, if both of us read this text and wrote a summary of it, mine would be very different than yours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After I’m done with the summary, I write down the answers to three questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;What are the key ideas?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How can I apply this knowledge that I learned?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do these ideas relate to what I already know?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The first question speaks for itself.&lt;/strong&gt; I try to remember what I just read and write down as many ideas as I can bring back. When I began applying the metacognition trick that I mentioned earlier, I noticed a 3x increase in the number of concepts I could recall. And as I speculate that long-term memory recall is influenced by initial interleaving and recall, this might actually help to improve your long-term memory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The second question is about transfer.&lt;/strong&gt; The sole purpose of learning is to apply the knowledge that we learn. Without application, knowledge is useless. But to use my knowledge, I must remember it exactly when I need it. The transfer question helps to discover how to apply the knowledge I’ve just learned. Usually, it also uncovers some todos that I add to my inbox. For example, I was recently learning about monopolies, and the answer to this question was, “I can think what characteristics of a monopoly our idea has.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The third question is a fallback for interleaving.&lt;/strong&gt; It helps to proactively think about how this piece of knowledge that I just consumed connects to the broader picture of what I already know. The trick here is that when you answer this question, you not only make connections but improve your long-term memory because you recall that other thing that you connect the freshly learned knowledge to. And as creativity is just connecting things, having a habit of proactively making these connections helps think new thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, I take my file with questions and plug it into the &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.ankiweb.net/&quot;&gt;Anki app&lt;/a&gt;. Anki is a spaced repetition system that I use for remembering things. It’s dead simple; you add flashcards and then test yourself. If you remember, it pushes the next test time further into the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most exciting idea here is that using Anki changed my relationship with memory. I don’t fear forgetting anymore because I know that I will remember forever &lt;em&gt;everything&lt;/em&gt; I add to Anki. It feels like a superpower. What’s more interesting, having this superpower provokes an unusual question, “What do I want to never forget?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can read more about Anki&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://augmentingcognition.com/ltm.html&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;here&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-to-do-between-learning-sessions&quot;&gt;What to do between learning sessions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Talk to friends about what you learn, apply spaced repetition to prevent forgetting, and build the daily recall habit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;talking-to-friends&quot;&gt;Talking to friends&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whenever I learn some new cool thing, I feel an urge to explain it to my friends. This helps to quickly realize if I really know it or I just know the words. Sometimes I just message them, and sometimes I talk to them about an idea in a conversation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;spaced-repetition&quot;&gt;Spaced repetition&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another trick I use to learn better is testing. Many people have this mistaken image of testing as something unpleasant. Like something you had to do at school. In reality, testing is very useful and fun, especially if done right. In some way, I'm actually learning through testing; I ask questions about what I'm reading even before I've read the answer and try to guess what the answer would be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Between sessions, I use Anki whenever I have a minute to test myself. For example, yesterday, I did a few Anki questions when standing in line for groceries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also suspect that I'm utilizing a lot of spaced repetition during the workday because I always have my iPad with Drafts opened on the left, and apply a lot of metacognition. But that's a hypothesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you're interested in learning more about spaced repetition, check out&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://augmentingcognition.com/ltm.html&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Michael's work on long-term memory&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gwern.net/Spaced-repetition&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Gwern's post about spaced repetition&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;daily-active-recall&quot;&gt;Daily active recall&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One more habit that I’ve found extremely useful is the daily recall. It’s the first thing I do every morning after I wake up and the last thing before I go to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s how it works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the evening, I open a new file in Drafts and ask myself: “What do I remember from today?” In the first thirty seconds, it seems unbearably hard to recall even a few ideas. The mind is gone. But after a few minutes, I begin bringing back more and more. After a few months of deliberate practice, I can recall about 90-95% of ideas that I discover during the day, whether that’s how something in JS works, characteristics of a monopoly business, or why mixed practice improves remembering. And I have audacious speculation that doing this recall process twice a day actually trains my mental machinery to perceive and remember ideas better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re asking yourself, “why to bother so much?” here’s why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So much of what we call creativity and intelligence is just &lt;a href=&quot;http://augmentingcognition.com/&quot;&gt;memory&lt;/a&gt;. If you think you can look it up on Google, you’re wrong. The thought process is &lt;em&gt;way&lt;/em&gt; faster than looking stuff up, and when you’re thinking about something or solving an important problem, you have to have your toolkit ready. Also, the most interesting ideas come when you’re not at your desk but showering, glazing over stars or wandering around in the city center. When you can’t Google. And this tiny 10-minute habit of recalling ideas is totally worth it if you think of the implications on a fifty-year timeframe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apply mixed practice and develop mastery by pattern-matching to complex environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to practice, I mix it up. Mixed practice means putting exercises at the end of the book, not at the end of the chapter. When we apply blocked practice (i.e., a chapter about subject X and exercises after the chapter about the same subject X), we trick ourselves into using way less cognitive power than if the problems are mixed. And the results are fascinating – medical students who had examples mixed up &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/cwaWHeyK_aM?t=2162&quot;&gt;outperformed their classmates&lt;/a&gt; by 50%. Just to be clear on that, not some 5 or 10 percent improvement. 50%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;example-mixed-practice-in-learning-how-to-code&quot;&gt;Example: mixed practice in learning how to code&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, most coding schools and platforms haven’t bothered to look up cognitive science much. They all commit the same mimetic mistake of putting the subject on the left and exercises on the right. And this is even worse than blocked practice. When you do blocked practice, some forgetting occurs, and you recall things from the short-term memory. But on most coding sites, you just retype stuff from the left to the tiny window on the right. Monkey see monkey do. And it takes tremendous willpower to &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; do that when the example is on the left!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other words, if you’re going through a gangster neighborhood with a giant pile of cash in your hands, the dumbfuck is probably you, not the gangsters who’ll gladly kick your ass and take the money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I try to apply mixed practice by interleaving different ideas or ways of solving the problem. For example, if the task is to write a simple JS array sort of numbers, the expected solution is, well, to just write the sort. Instead, I create a function that takes in an array and returns a sorted one. Then I go ahead and make another one with, say, descended sort. I create an array of arrays and write a function that sorts all nested arrays. I apply all ways of sorting that I remember. Or I define a new array with words and letters and do alphabet sort. You got the idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, it takes time. But I believe this is the time that matters most, not watching tutorials. At the end of the day, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.researchgate.net/publication/49401082_Expert_and_novice_problem_solving_strategies_in_chess_Sixty_years_of_citing_de_Groot_1946&quot;&gt;mastery is about pattern-matching&lt;/a&gt; that changes your perception to include things that had to be reasoned about before, so if you just keep practicing for decades, you’ll master anything you want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To identify the best learning material, skim through one Amazon book sample every day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How you learn matters. But another thing that matters is the source of knowledge, the artifact, that you learn from. And as I believe most people screw it up badly, I want to explain my approach here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea is dead simple: if you want to find better learning material, what you have to do is, well, sample a ton of stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can’t trust the NYT bestsellers for two reasons. First, if they’re bestsellers, this means everybody reads them. And if you read what everybody reads, you will think what everybody thinks. Second, because the value of books is subjective. The same text can mean the world to me and nothing to you, and vice versa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s why I’ve built a habit of reading one book a day. Here’s what I do:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;I go to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/&quot;&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and find a bunch of books I’m interested in. Usually, the books come from recommendations of thoughtful people who I trust. It’s usually a sufficient criteria to give a book a try. If many respectful people recommend a book, then it’s unlikely to be complete crap.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I download samples for all these books. I believe book samples are the single most underrated thing in the world. They’re free and available for literally every book out there. Another thing I do is downloading books from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gutenberg.org/&quot;&gt;Project Gutenberg&lt;/a&gt;; they’ve got a phenomenal free library of almost all old books worth reading.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have a folder in my Kindle app called “Want to Read.” All book samples that I download go into this folder.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At 3 pm every day, I take an hour-long break from work. I go to Costa coffee, which is about a 10m walk away from where I live, and get myself a black Americano. I don’t take an iPad with me, only my phone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I open the first book sample from the Want to Read folder and begin reading. In my Drafts app on my phone, I create a new note with the book’s name that I’m reviewing. I usually start from the book description to understand what it’s about, and write down a couple sentences, trying to guess what’s coming up. Then I go straight to the table of contents and see if anything catches my attention there. If something does, then I jump ahead and begin reading the thing. If not, I start glancing through the book. I don’t speed read but glance at the first sentence of the paragraph and then skim through the rest of it. You might be wondering that when I’m reading like that, I don’t understand much. You’re right. But the purpose of this “picture walk” reading is different; it’s to catch my curiosity. And curiosity is different from understanding because it’s either happens or not. It’s like you’re seeing a pretty girl; you don’t really sit and reason, “well, do I really like her?”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It takes me about 10-15 minutes to understand if the book worth reading in its entirety. Note that it’s tempting to list all books as “worth” reading. Don’t do that. If you’re &lt;a href=&quot;https://sive.rs/hellyeah&quot;&gt;not sure&lt;/a&gt;, delete the sample. As with girls, there will always be another one tomorrow and you will know when it’s &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; interesting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the book is worth reading, I go ahead and buy it right now. If I’m not sure, then I delete it from the sample folder and forget about it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Repeat the same process daily.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;By taking just 10 minutes a day to quickly scroll through the book instead of my Twitter feed, I end up having 365 books scrolled in a year. From these 365, about two end up being life-changing, ten – deeply interesting, and ten – sort of interesting. Everything else is noise. 94%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, do the math. If I didn’t have this discovery routine and aimed to read books from cover to cover, I’d randomly sample about twenty books from 365 with meager chances of all of them being good. And I was doing that &lt;em&gt;for years&lt;/em&gt;. So don’t repeat my mistake and invest 5-10 minutes a day to discover what you learn from, because learning is like eating. You become what you consume.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing you might have noticed is that the habit is tied up to a specific behavior. That’s the best thing you could do when building a new one because that’s how you guarantee you won’t forget it. You wouldn’t believe me if I said how many times I wanted to do something but simply forgot about it. Don’t rely on your shallow memory and tie your habit to some activity you’re going to do anyway. Taking a shower, eating a meal, brushing your teeth – all are good examples because they’re the things you have to do no matter what.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, you can set up a reward after you do the habit. For example, get yourself some coffee or go for a walk. For some reason, we don’t forget about our rewards as often as our habits, so by having a reward after you create even more opportunities for yourself to remember about doing the thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you’re interested in reading up on habits, here’s&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Atomic-Habits-Proven-Build-Break-ebook/dp/B07D23CFGR&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;a good book&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;to start with.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To develop the learning habit, make it time-based, start really small, and do it every day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I started building my learning habit, I began at ten minutes a day. This doesn't seem like much, but that's precisely the point. If you hook it up to some must-do habit like taking a shower after work, then it won't seem like a big deal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What's even more interesting, when I artificially lowered the time that I had to put in a newly born habit, I &lt;em&gt;wanted it more&lt;/em&gt; because of the scarcity effect. My brain was like: &quot;Well, we will only be learning for ten minutes. But I want to learn things because I want to be smart. So I better make the most out of these 10 minutes and not fuck around because otherwise, I won't have an opportunity to learn today.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But never postpone. If you fail to perform the habit in the morning, don't make up for it by cramming it into the evening. Because if you do, you set up a good excuse for your mind to trick you into snoozing more and more. It will begin seeming like it's better to postpone because &quot;hey, we can always do it later!&quot; Never snooze.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;One trick I’ve found extremely useful is deleting &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; potential sources of distraction from the device I use to learn. I went ahead and killed all messaging apps, all social networks, all email apps, and everything else that could be a potential source of distraction from my iPad. This made my life so much easier, and I’m still wondering why I hadn’t done this earlier.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Another trick is environment design. When I begin learning, I leave my phone in a different room. That way, I’m not tempted to use it just because it gets into my perception. This trick saved me a ton of time and energy, so I welcome you to try it out as well. As you may have guessed correctly, this extends way beyond learning; I apply the same approach to my work. When I sit down to write, I leave all potential distractions (including my wife) in a different room. Immensely helpful.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Metacognition works not just for learning. When I’m writing code or designing a process, I find it incredibly liberating to have a place for explaining what I &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; want to do here instead of just bashing the keyboard.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When I'm facing an idea that I don't understand, I draw things. Sketching takes full advantage of &lt;a href=&quot;https://vasilishynkarenka.com/meeting-notes/&quot;&gt;spatial cognition&lt;/a&gt; and helps to break down the most challenging concepts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When I built a process for learning something new, I stopped being afraid. I know it’s only a matter of time until I master the thing, and this encourages me to take on ambitious projects that I’d not dare to think of before.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;does-this-apply-to-reading-articles-or-watching-videos&quot;&gt;Does this apply to reading articles or watching videos?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The learning process applies to everything that you learn. If you read an article to understand it and use the knowledge from it later, yes. If it’s a fiction story or a newspaper article, then it’s probably overkill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-long-does-it-take-to-master-the-process&quot;&gt;How long does it take to master the process?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Less longer than you think to apply and begin getting benefits, and way longer to master. I’m still learning!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;does-the-process-apply-to-learning-how-to-code&quot;&gt;Does the process apply to learning how to code?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course! This process was designed to figure out how to teach me to code. A big deal of intelligence is just knowledge, and knowledge comes from changes in long-term memory. If you’re learning how to code, ping me at &lt;a&gt;vasilishynkarenka@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;, and I’ll share additional tips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;can-i-use-this-process-if-i-don-t-have-a-second-device-read-from-my-phone-or-use-physical-books&quot;&gt;Can I use this process if I don’t have a second device, read from my phone, or use physical books?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes. I’ve experimented with a single device study mode and found it to be quite productive. It’s less superior than the double-device process in terms of metacognition but better in terms of focus. If you minimize your kindle app on the phone and open the notes app, you have to bring those things back from your mind instead of reciting them from the book. In other words, this mode has better incentives for immediate recall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the most interesting works I’ve found in the past six months in no specific order:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 18:06:43 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>flreln</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>How to remember what you learn</og:title>
<og:description>Make it time-based, apply metacognition &amp; active recall, and learn what you’re curious about.</og:description>
<og:url>https://vasilishynkarenka.com/learning/</og:url>
<og:image>https://vasilishynkarenka.com/content/images/2020/09/IMG_1517.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://vasilishynkarenka.com/learning/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>US Insulin prices 8 times higher than in other nations</title>
<link>https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2020-10/rc-uip100620.php</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2020-10/rc-uip100620.php</guid>
<description>&lt;div readability=&quot;114.41671115857&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Insulin prices are more than eight times higher in the United States than in 32 high-income comparison nations combined, according to a new RAND Corporation study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The study compared how much different types of insulin sold in the U.S. would cost if bought at prices in other countries. The average price per unit across all types of insulin in the U.S. was $98.70. Other countries would have paid a fraction as much for the same insulins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;U.S. prices were higher than each of the 32 comparison countries individually, ranging from 3.8 times higher than those in Chile to 27.7 times those in Turkey. U.S. prices were 6.3 times higher than those in Canada, 5.9 times higher than those in Japan and 8.9 times higher than those in the United Kingdom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The study used manufacturer prices for the analysis. The final, net prices paid for insulins are likely to be significantly lower than manufacturer prices in the U.S. because rebates and other discounts often drive down the price paid by individuals in the U.S.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But even if such rebates and discounts drive down prices by as much as 50%, the prices paid by U.S. consumer are likely to be four times the average paid in other high-income nations, according to the study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;This analysis provides the best available evidence about how much more expensive insulin is in the U.S. than in other nations around the world,&quot; said Andrew Mulcahy, the study's lead author and a senior policy researcher at RAND, a nonprofit research organization. &quot;Prices in the U.S. are always much higher than other nations, even if you assume steep discounts to manufacturer prices in the United States.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Insulin list prices in the United States have increased dramatically over the past decade. For example, one federal analysis found that the average U.S. wholesale-acquisition price for rapid-acting, long-acting, and short-acting insulin increased by 15% to 17% per year from 2012 to 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another study found that among adults with employer-sponsored health insurance, annual insulin spending per person doubled between 2012 and 2016, increasing from $1,432 to $2,853 even after accounting for a 50% rebate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Insulin is a drug most commonly used to control blood sugar levels in people who have insulin-dependent diabetes. The drug is sold in many different forms, with different chemical properties and different duration of effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RAND researchers compiled their estimates of international insulin prices by examining industry-standard IQVIA MIDAS data on insulin sales and volume for 2018, comparing the U.S. to 32 nations that belong to the Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the ratio of U.S. prices to other-country prices varied depending on the comparison country and insulin category, U.S. prices were always higher and often 5 to 10 times higher than those in other countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The study found that U.S. prices were relatively higher for analog versus human insulins and for rapid-acting rather than short or long-acting insulins. U.S. prices were even higher when researchers compared prices pooling similar insulin products together, suggesting that the United States uses a more-expensive mix of insulin products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The study was sponsored by the Office of the Assistant Secretary for Planning and Evaluation in the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The report, &quot;Comparing Insulin Prices in the United States to Other Countries: Results from a Price Index Analysis,&quot; is available on the website of the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services and on &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.rand.org&quot;&gt;http://www.&lt;wbr/&gt;rand.&lt;wbr/&gt;org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other authors of the report are Daniel Schwam and Nate Edenfield.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RAND Health Care promotes healthier societies by improving health care systems in the United States and other countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;###&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;34&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclaimer:&lt;/strong&gt; AAAS and EurekAlert! are not responsible for the accuracy of news releases posted to EurekAlert! by contributing institutions or for the use of any information through the EurekAlert system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 18:04:32 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>rustoo</dc:creator>
<og:title>US Insulin prices 8 times higher than in other nations</og:title>
<og:description>Insulin list prices in the United States have increased dramatically over the past decade, with per person insulin spending doubling between 2012 and 2016. A new study finds that U.S. insulin prices are dramatically higher than elsewhere in the world, averaging eight times the cost in other high-income nations.</og:description>
<og:url>https://eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2020-10/rc-uip100620.php</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.eurekalert.org/socialshare/EurekAlert-bluebg_Twitter_1200x675.jpg</og:image>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2020-10/rc-uip100620.php</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Q3 Linux touchpad update: Multitouch gesture test packages now ready</title>
<link>https://bill.harding.blog/2020/10/06/q3-linux-touchpad-like-macbook-update-multitouch-gesture-test-packages-are-ready/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://bill.harding.blog/2020/10/06/q3-linux-touchpad-like-macbook-update-multitouch-gesture-test-packages-are-ready/</guid>
<description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;reply-title&quot; class=&quot;comment-reply-title&quot;&gt;Leave a Reply &lt;small/&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;form action=&quot;https://bill.harding.blog/wp-comments-post.php&quot; method=&quot;post&quot; id=&quot;commentform&quot; class=&quot;comment-form&quot; novalidate=&quot;&quot; readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;comment-notes&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;email-notes&quot;&gt;Your email address will not be published.&lt;/span&gt; Required fields are marked &lt;span class=&quot;required&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;comment-form-comment&quot;&gt;&lt;label for=&quot;comment&quot;&gt;Comment&lt;/label&gt; &lt;textarea id=&quot;comment&quot; name=&quot;comment&quot; cols=&quot;45&quot; rows=&quot;8&quot; maxlength=&quot;65525&quot; required=&quot;required&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;comment-form-author&quot;&gt;&lt;label for=&quot;author&quot;&gt;Name &lt;span class=&quot;required&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/label&gt; &lt;input id=&quot;author&quot; name=&quot;author&quot; type=&quot;text&quot; value=&quot;&quot; size=&quot;30&quot; maxlength=&quot;245&quot; required=&quot;required&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;comment-form-email&quot;&gt;&lt;label for=&quot;email&quot;&gt;Email &lt;span class=&quot;required&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/label&gt; &lt;input id=&quot;email&quot; name=&quot;email&quot; type=&quot;email&quot; value=&quot;&quot; size=&quot;30&quot; maxlength=&quot;100&quot; aria-describedby=&quot;email-notes&quot; required=&quot;required&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;comment-form-url&quot;&gt;&lt;label for=&quot;url&quot;&gt;Website&lt;/label&gt; &lt;input id=&quot;url&quot; name=&quot;url&quot; type=&quot;url&quot; value=&quot;&quot; size=&quot;30&quot; maxlength=&quot;200&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;comment-form-cookies-consent&quot;&gt;&lt;input id=&quot;wp-comment-cookies-consent&quot; name=&quot;wp-comment-cookies-consent&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot; value=&quot;yes&quot;/&gt;&lt;label for=&quot;wp-comment-cookies-consent&quot;&gt;Save my name, email, and website in this browser for the next time I comment.&lt;/label&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- Anti-spam plugin wordpress.org/plugins/anti-spam/ --&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wantispam-required-fields&quot;&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;hidden&quot; name=&quot;wantispam_t&quot; class=&quot;wantispam-control wantispam-control-t&quot; value=&quot;1602032072&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;#13;
					&lt;label&gt;Current ye@r &lt;span class=&quot;required&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/label&gt;&amp;#13;
					&lt;input type=&quot;hidden&quot; name=&quot;wantispam_a&quot; class=&quot;wantispam-control wantispam-control-a&quot; value=&quot;2020&quot;/&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;text&quot; name=&quot;wantispam_q&quot; class=&quot;wantispam-control wantispam-control-q&quot; value=&quot;6.5.4&quot; autocomplete=&quot;off&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#13;
					&lt;label&gt;Leave this field empty&lt;/label&gt;&amp;#13;
					&lt;input type=&quot;text&quot; name=&quot;wantispam_e_email_url_website&quot; class=&quot;wantispam-control wantispam-control-e&quot; value=&quot;&quot; autocomplete=&quot;off&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!--\End Anti-spam plugin --&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;hidden&quot; id=&quot;ct_checkjs_beed13602b9b0e6ecb5b568ff5058f07&quot; name=&quot;ct_checkjs&quot; value=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/form&gt;	</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 17:54:41 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>wbharding</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://bill.harding.blog/2020/10/06/q3-linux-touchpad-like-macbook-update-multitouch-gesture-test-packages-are-ready/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Time for a WTF MySQL Moment</title>
<link>https://gbl08ma.com/time-for-a-wtf-mysql-moment/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://gbl08ma.com/time-for-a-wtf-mysql-moment/</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;post-meta&quot;&gt;October 4, 2020 / gbl08ma / 0 Comments&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many people have been experiencing strange time perception phenomenon throughout 2020, but certain database management systems have been into time shenanigans for way longer. This came to my attention when a friend received the following exception in one of his projects (his popular Discord bot, &lt;a href=&quot;https://accord.abcric.net/&quot;&gt;Accord&lt;/a&gt;), coming from the MySQL connector being used with EF Core:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
MySqlException: Incorrect TIME value: '960:00:00.000000'
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not being too experienced with MySQL, as I prefer PostgreSQL for reasons that will soon become self-evident, for a brief moment I assumed the incorrection in this value was the hundreds of hours, as one could reasonably assume that maybe TIME values were capped at 24 hours, or that a different syntax was needed for values spanning multiple days, and that one would need to use, say, “40:00:00:00” to represent 40 days. But reality turned out to be more complex and harder to explain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With checking the documentation being the most natural next step, the MySQL documentation goes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MySQL retrieves and displays &lt;code class=&quot;literal&quot;&gt;TIME&lt;/code&gt; values in &lt;em class=&quot;replaceable&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;'hh:mm:ss'&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/em&gt; format (or &lt;em class=&quot;replaceable&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;'hhh:mm:ss'&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/em&gt; format for large hours values).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far so good, our problematic TIME value respects this format, but the fact that &lt;code&gt;hh&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;hhh&lt;/code&gt; are explicitly pointed out is already suspect (what about values with over 999 hours?). The next sentence in the documentation explains why, and left me with even more questions of the WTF kind:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;literal&quot;&gt;TIME&lt;/code&gt; values may range from &lt;code class=&quot;literal&quot;&gt;'-838:59:59'&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code class=&quot;literal&quot;&gt;'838:59:59'&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oooh Kaaay… that’s an oddly specific range, but I’m sure there has to be a technical reason for it. 839 hours is 34.958(3) days, and the whole range spans exactly 6040798 seconds. The documentation also mentions the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MySQL recognizes &lt;code class=&quot;literal&quot;&gt;TIME&lt;/code&gt; values in several formats, some of which can include a trailing fractional seconds part in up to microseconds (6 digits) precision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, it also makes sense to point out that the whole interval spans &lt;span id=&quot;display&quot; class=&quot;tile__display__main&quot;&gt;6 040 798&lt;/span&gt; 000 000 microseconds, but again, these seem like oddly specific numbers. They are not near any power of two, the latter being between 2&lt;sup&gt;42&lt;/sup&gt; and 2&lt;sup&gt;43&lt;/sup&gt;, so MySQL must be using some awkward internal representation format. But before we dive into that, let me just point out how bad this type is. It is the closest MySQL has to a time interval type, and yet it can’t deal with intervals that are just a bit over a month long. How much is that “bit”? Not even a nice, rounded number of days, it seems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make matters worse, it appears that the most popular EF Core MySQL provider maps .NET’s &lt;code&gt;TimeSpan&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;TIME&lt;/code&gt; by default, despite the fact that &lt;code&gt;TimeSpan&lt;/code&gt; can contain intervals in the dozens of millennia (it uses a 64 bit integer and has 10&lt;sup&gt;-8&lt;/sup&gt; s precision) compared to TIME’s measly “a bit over two months”. This is an &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/PomeloFoundation/Pomelo.EntityFrameworkCore.MySql/issues/1046&quot;&gt;issue other people have run into&lt;/a&gt;, and the discussion in that issue includes a “This mimics the behavior of SQL Server” remark, which made me go check and, sure enough, SQL Server’s &lt;code&gt;time&lt;/code&gt; is meant to encode a time of day and has a range of 00:00:00.0000000 through 23:59:59.9999999, something which overall makes more sense to me than MySQL’s odd TIME range.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So let’s go back to MySQL. What is the reasoning behind such an &lt;em&gt;interesting&lt;/em&gt; range? The &lt;a href=&quot;https://dev.mysql.com/doc/internals/en/date-and-time-data-type-representation.html&quot;&gt;MySQL Internals Manual&lt;/a&gt; says that the storage for the TIME type has changed with version 5.6.4, having gained support for fractional seconds in this version. It uses 3 bytes for the non-fractional type. Now, had they just used these 3 bytes to encode a number of seconds, they would have been able to support intervals spanning over 2330 hours, which would already be a considerable improvement over the current 838 hours maximum, even if still a bit useless when it comes to mapping a &lt;code&gt;TimeSpan&lt;/code&gt; to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This means their encoding must be wasting bits, probably so it is easier to work with… not sure in what circumstances exactly, but maybe it makes more sense if your database management system (and/or your conception of what the users will do with it) just loves strings, and you really want to speed up the hh:mm:ss representation. So, behold:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
1 bit sign (1= non-negative, 0= negative)
1 bit unused (reserved for future extensions)
10 bits hour (0-838)
6 bits minute (0-59) 
6 bits second (0-59) 
---------------------
24 bits = 3 bytes
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This explains everything, right? Well, look closely. 10 bits for the hour… and a range of 0 to 838. I kindly remind you that 2&lt;sup&gt;10&lt;/sup&gt; is 1024, not 838. The plot thickens. I’m not the first person to wonder about this, of course, &lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/39259910/why-is-mysqls-maximum-time-limit-8385959&quot;&gt;this was asked on StackOverflow before&lt;/a&gt;. The accepted answer in that question explains everything, but &lt;em&gt;it almost didn’t&lt;/em&gt;, as it initially dismisses the odd choice of 838 as “backward compatibility with applications that were written a while ago”, and only later it is explained that this choice had to do with compatibility with MySQL version… 3, from the times when, you know, Windows 98 was a fresh operating system and Linux wasn’t 10 years old yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In MySQL 3, the TIME type used 3 bytes as well, but they were used differently. One of the bits was used for the sign as well, but the remaining 23 bits were an integer value produced like this: Hours × 10000 + Minutes × 100 + Seconds; in other words, the two least significant decimal digits of the number contained the seconds, the next two contained the minutes, and the remaining ones contained the hours. 2&lt;sup&gt;23&lt;/sup&gt; is 83888608, i.e. 838:86:08, therefore, the maximum valid time in this format is 838:59:59. This format is even less wieldy than the current one, requiring multiplication and division to do basically anything with it, except string formatting and parsing – once again showing that MySQL places too much value on string IO and not so much on having types that are convenient for internal operations and non-string-based protocols.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MySQL developers had ample opportunities to fix this type, or at the very least introduce an alternative one that is free of this reduced range. They changed this type twice from MySQL 3 until now, but decided to retain the range every time, supposedly for compatibility reasons. I am struggling to imagine the circumstances where increasing the value range for a type can break compatibility with an application – do types in MySQL have defined overflow behaviors? Is any sane person writing applications where they are relying on a database type’s intrinsic limits for validation? If yes, who looked at this awkward 838 hours range and thought of it as an appropriate limitation to carry unchanged into their application’s data model? At this point, I don’t even want to know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite having changed twice throughout MySQL’s lifetime, the TIME type is still quite an awkward and limited one. That unused, “reserved for future extensions” bit is, in my opinion, really the &lt;em&gt;pièce de résistance&lt;/em&gt; here. Here’s hoping that one day it will be used to signify a “legacy” TIME value and that, by then, MySQL and/or MariaDB will have support for a proper type like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.postgresql.org/docs/current/datatype-datetime.html&quot;&gt;PostgreSQL’s INTERVAL&lt;/a&gt;, which has a range of +/- 178000000 years and a very reasonable microsecond precision.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 15:23:54 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>gbl08ma</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>TIME for a WTF MySQL moment</og:title>
<og:url>https://gbl08ma.com/time-for-a-wtf-mysql-moment/</og:url>
<og:description>Many people have been experiencing strange time perception phenomenon throughout 2020, but certain database management systems have been into time shenanigans for way longer. This came to my attent…</og:description>
<og:image>https://gbl08ma.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/cropped-avatar-hdpi.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://gbl08ma.com/time-for-a-wtf-mysql-moment/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>DigitalOcean App Platform</title>
<link>https://pages.news.digitalocean.com/Y0V490bXc00o40036IE0WDo</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://pages.news.digitalocean.com/Y0V490bXc00o40036IE0WDo</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.news.digitalocean.com/Y0V490bXc00o40036IE0WDo&quot;&gt;https://pages.news.digitalocean.com/Y0V490bXc00o40036IE0WDo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24698334&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24698334&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 408&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 216&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 14:59:17 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>digianarchist</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://pages.news.digitalocean.com/Y0V490bXc00o40036IE0WDo</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Elixir 1.11</title>
<link>https://elixir-lang.org/blog/2020/10/06/elixir-v1-11-0-released/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://elixir-lang.org/blog/2020/10/06/elixir-v1-11-0-released/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Over the last releases, the Elixir team has been focusing on the compiler, both in terms of catching more mistakes at compilation time and making it faster. Elixir v1.11 has made excellent progress on both fronts. This release also includes many other goodies, such as tighter Erlang integration, support for more guard expressions, built-in datetime formatting, and other calendar enhancements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this period, we have also started &lt;a href=&quot;https://elixir-lang.org/blog/categories.html#Cases&quot;&gt;publishing a series of production cases&lt;/a&gt; on our website, featuring Elixir’s usage at &lt;a href=&quot;https://elixir-lang.org/blog/2020/06/23/growing-with-elixir-at-brex/&quot;&gt;Brex&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://elixir-lang.org/blog/2020/08/20/embedded-elixir-at-farmbot/&quot;&gt;Farmbot&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://elixir-lang.org/blog/2020/09/24/paas-with-elixir-at-Heroku/&quot;&gt;Heroku&lt;/a&gt;, with many more cases coming soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now, let’s focus on what’s new in Elixir v1.11.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;tighter-erlang-integration&quot;&gt;Tighter Erlang integration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the footsteps of v1.10, we have further integrated with Erlang’s new logger by adding four new log levels: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;notice&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;critical&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;alert&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;emergency&lt;/code&gt;, matching all log levels found in the Syslog standard. The &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Logger&lt;/code&gt; module now supports structured logging by passing maps and keyword lists to its various functions. It is also possible to specify the log level per module, via the &lt;a href=&quot;https://hexdocs.pm/logger/Logger.html#put_module_level/2&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Logger.put_module_level/2&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; function. Log levels per application will be added in future releases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IEx also has been improved to show the documentation for Erlang modules directly from your Elixir terminal. For example, here is a clip of me accessing the documentation for &lt;a href=&quot;https://elixir-lang.org/blog/2020/10/06/elixir-v1-11-0-released/erlang.org/doc/man/gen_server.html&quot;&gt;Erlang’s gen_server module&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://asciinema.org/a/iAOk0yaZtQDsuJqn2sXa1FRQW&quot;&gt;See the example in asciinema&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This works with Erlang/OTP 23+ and requires Erlang modules to have been compiled with documentation chunks. A huge thank you to the Erlang/OTP team and the Documentation Working Group of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://erlef.org/&quot;&gt;Erlang Ecosystem Foundation&lt;/a&gt; for making this possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;compiler-checks-application-boundaries&quot;&gt;Compiler checks: application boundaries&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elixir v1.11 builds on top of the recently added compilation tracers to track application boundaries. From this release, Elixir will warn if you invoke a function from an existing module but this module does not belong to any of your listed dependencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These two conditions may seem contradictory. After all, if a module is available, it must have come from a dependency. This is not true in two scenarios:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Modules from Elixir and Erlang/OTP are always available - even if their applications are not explicitly listed as a dependency&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an umbrella project, because all child applications are compiled within the same VM, you may have a module from a sibling project available, even if you don’t depend on said sibling&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;This new compiler check makes sure that all modules that you invoke are listed as part of your dependencies, emitting a warning like below otherwise:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-text highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;:ssl.connect/2 defined in application :ssl is used by the current
application but the current application does not directly depend
on :ssl. To fix this, you must do one of:

  1. If :ssl is part of Erlang/Elixir, you must include it under
     :extra_applications inside &quot;def application&quot; in your mix.exs

  2. If :ssl is a dependency, make sure it is listed under &quot;def deps&quot;
     in your mix.exs

  3. In case you don't want to add a requirement to :ssl, you may
     optionally skip this warning by adding [xref: [exclude: :ssl]
     to your &quot;def project&quot; in mix.exs
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This comes with extra benefits in umbrella projects, as it requires child applications to explicitly list their dependencies, completely rejecting cyclic dependencies between siblings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;compiler-checks-data-constructors&quot;&gt;Compiler checks: data constructors&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Elixir v1.11, the compiler also tracks structs and maps fields across a function body. For example, imagine you wanted to write this code:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-elixir highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;drive?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(%&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;User&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;age:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;age&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}),&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;age&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;18&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If there is either a typo on the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;:age&lt;/code&gt; field or the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;:age&lt;/code&gt; field was not yet defined, the compiler will fail accordingly. However, if you wrote this code:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-elixir highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;drive?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(%&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;User&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{}&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;user&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;),&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;user&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;age&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;18&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The compiler would not catch the missing field and an error would only be raised at runtime. With v1.11, Elixir will track the usage of all maps and struct fields within the same function, emitting warnings for cases like above:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-text highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;warning: undefined field `age` in expression:

    # example.exs:7
    user.age

expected one of the following fields: name, address

where &quot;user&quot; was given the type %User{} in:

    # example.exs:7
    %User{} = user

Conflict found at
  example.exs:7: Check.drive?/1
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The compiler also checks binary constructors. Consider you have to send a string over the wire with length-based encoding, where the string is prefixed by its length, up to 4MBs. Your initial attempt may be this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-elixir highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;run_length&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;string&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;when&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;is_binary&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;string&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;byte_size&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;string&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)::&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;32&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;string&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the code above has a bug. Each segment given between &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; must be an integer, unless specified otherwise. With Elixir v1.11, the compiler will let you know so:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-text highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;warning: incompatible types:

    binary() !~ integer()

in expression:

    &amp;lt;&amp;lt;byte_size(string)::integer()-size(32), string&amp;gt;&amp;gt;

where &quot;string&quot; was given the type integer() in:

    # foo.exs:4
    &amp;lt;&amp;lt;byte_size(string)::integer()-size(32), string&amp;gt;&amp;gt;

where &quot;string&quot; was given the type binary() in:

    # foo.exs:3
    is_binary(string)

HINT: all expressions given to binaries are assumed to be of type integer()
unless said otherwise. For example, &amp;lt;&amp;lt;expr&amp;gt;&amp;gt; assumes &quot;expr&quot; is an integer.
Pass a modifier, such as &amp;lt;&amp;lt;expr::float&amp;gt;&amp;gt; or &amp;lt;&amp;lt;expr::binary&amp;gt;&amp;gt;, to change the
default behaviour.

Conflict found at
  foo.exs:4: Check.run_length/1
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which can be fixed by adding &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;::binary&lt;/code&gt; to the second component:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;def run_length(string) when is_binary(string) do
  &amp;lt;&amp;lt;byte_size(string)::32, string::binary&amp;gt;&amp;gt;
end
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While some of those warnings could be automatically fixed by the compiler, future versions will also perform those checks across functions and potentially across modules, where automatic fixes wouldn’t be desired (nor possible).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;compilation-time-improvements&quot;&gt;Compilation time improvements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elixir v1.11 features many improvements to how the compiler tracks file dependencies, such that touching one file causes less files to be recompiled. In previous versions, Elixir tracked three types of dependencies:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;compile time dependencies - if A depends on B at compile time, such as by using a macro, whenever B changes, A is recompiled&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;struct dependencies - if A depends on B’s struct, whenever B’s struct definition changed, A is recompiled&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;runtime dependencies - if A depends on B at runtime, A is never recompiled&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, because dependencies are transitive, if A depends on B at compile time and B depends on C at runtime, A would depend on C at compile time. Therefore, it is very important to reduce the amount of compile time dependencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elixir v1.11 replaces “struct dependencies” by “exports dependencies”. In other words, if A depends on B, whenever B public’s interface changes, A is recompiled. B’s public interface is made by its struct definition and all of its public functions and macros.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This change allows us to mark &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;import&lt;/code&gt;s and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;require&lt;/code&gt;s as “exports dependencies” instead of “compile time” dependencies. This simplifies the dependency graph considerably. For example, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/hexpm/hexpm&quot;&gt;in the Hex.pm project&lt;/a&gt;, changing the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;user.ex&lt;/code&gt; file in Elixir v1.10 would emit this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-text highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;$ touch lib/hexpm/accounts/user.ex &amp;amp;&amp;amp; mix compile
Compiling 90 files (.ex)
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Elixir v1.11, we now get:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-text highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;$ touch lib/hexpm/accounts/user.ex &amp;amp;&amp;amp; mix compile
Compiling 16 files (.ex)
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make things even better, Elixir v1.11 also introduces a more granular tracking for umbrella projects (and path dependencies in general). In previous versions, a module from a sibling application would always be treated as a compile time dependency. This often meant that changing an application would cause many modules in sibling applications to recompile. Elixir v1.11 will tag modules from dependencies as exports whenever possible, yielding dramatic improvements in those cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To round up the list of compiler enhancements, the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;--profile=time&lt;/code&gt; option added in Elixir v1.10 now also includes the time to compile each individual file. For example, in the Plug project, one can now get:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-text highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;[profile] lib/plug/conn.ex compiled in 935ms
[profile] lib/plug/ssl.ex compiled in 147ms (plus 744ms waiting)
[profile] lib/plug/static.ex compiled in 238ms (plus 654ms waiting)
[profile] lib/plug/csrf_protection.ex compiled in 237ms (plus 790ms waiting)
[profile] lib/plug/debugger.ex compiled in 719ms (plus 947ms waiting)
[profile] Finished compilation cycle of 60 modules in 1802ms
[profile] Finished group pass check of 60 modules in 75ms
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While implementing those features, we have also made the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;--long-compilation-threshold&lt;/code&gt; flag more precise. In previous versions, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;--long-compilation-threshold&lt;/code&gt; would consider both the time a file spent to compile and the time spent waiting on other files. In Elixir v1.11, it considers only the compilation time. This means less false positives and you can now effectively get all files that take longer than 2s to compile, in execution time, by passing &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;--long-compilation-threshold 2&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;configruntimeexs-and-mix-appconfig&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;config/runtime.exs&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;mix app.config&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elixir v1.9 introduced a new configuration file called &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;config/releases.exs&lt;/code&gt;. However, this new configuration file was executed only during releases. For those not familiar with releases, a release is a self-contained artifact with the Erlang VM, Elixir and your application, ready to run in production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This new configuration file was considered a very useful addition to releases. Therefore, we are also introducing &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;config/runtime.exs&lt;/code&gt;, which is executed after the code compilation on all environments (dev, test, and prod) - for both Mix and releases. Our goal is to provide a better runtime configuration experience to developers, in contrast to our current configuration system which has been mostly compile-time centric.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;config/runtime.exs&lt;/code&gt; works the same as any other configuration file in Elixir. However, given &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;config/runtime.exs&lt;/code&gt; is meant to run in production systems, where our &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Mix&lt;/code&gt; build tool is not available, developers must not use &lt;a href=&quot;https://hexdocs.pm/mix/Mix.html#env/0&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Mix.env()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://hexdocs.pm/mix/Mix.html#target/0&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Mix.target()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;config/runtime.exs&lt;/code&gt;. Instead, they must use the new &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;config_env()&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;config_target()&lt;/code&gt;, which have been added to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://hexdocs.pm/elixir/Config.html&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Config&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; module.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;config/releases.exs&lt;/code&gt; will continue to be supported, developers can migrate to &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;config/runtime.exs&lt;/code&gt; without loss of functionality. For example, a &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;config/releases.exs&lt;/code&gt; file such as this one&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-elixir highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;# config/releases.exs&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;kn&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;Config&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;config&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;:foo&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;...&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;config&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;:bar&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;...&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;could run as is as &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;config/runtime.exs&lt;/code&gt;. However, given &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;config/runtime.exs&lt;/code&gt; runs in all environments, you may want to restrict part of your configuration to the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;:prod&lt;/code&gt; environment:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-elixir highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;# config/runtime.exs&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;kn&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;Config&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;config_env&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;:prod&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;config&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;:foo&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;...&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;config&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;:bar&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;...&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If both files are available, releases will pick the now preferred &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;config/runtime.exs&lt;/code&gt; instead of &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;config/releases.exs&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To wrap it all up, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Mix&lt;/code&gt; also includes a new task called &lt;a href=&quot;https://hexdocs.pm/mix/Mix.Tasks.App.Config.html&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;mix app.config&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. This task loads all applications and configures them, without starting them. Whenever you write your own Mix tasks, you will typically want to invoke either &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;mix app.start&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;mix app.config&lt;/code&gt; before running your own code. Which one is better depends if you want your applications running or only configured.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;other-improvements&quot;&gt;Other improvements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elixir v1.11 adds the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;is_struct/2&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;is_exception/1&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;is_exception/2&lt;/code&gt; guards. It also adds support for the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;map.field&lt;/code&gt; syntax in guards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Calendar module ships with a new &lt;a href=&quot;https://hexdocs.pm/elixir/Calendar.html#strftime/3&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Calendar.strftime/3&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; function, which provides datetime formatting based on the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;strftime&lt;/code&gt; format. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://hexdocs.pm/elixir/Date.html&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Date&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; module got new functions for working with weeks and months, such as &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Date.beginning_of_month/1&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Date.end_of_week/2&lt;/code&gt;. Finally, all calendar types got conversion functions from and to gregorian timestamps, such as &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Date.from_gregorian_days/2&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;NaiveDateTime.to_gregorian_seconds/1&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, to bring visibility to the compiler tracking improvements described in previous sections, we have also added new features to &lt;a href=&quot;https://hexdocs.pm/mix/Mix.Tasks.Xref.html&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;mix xref&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;mix xref&lt;/code&gt; is a task that describes cross-references between files in your projects and can be helpful to diagnose large compilation cycles in projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a complete list of all changes, see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/elixir-lang/elixir/releases/tag/v1.11.0&quot;&gt;full release notes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check &lt;a href=&quot;https://elixir-lang.org/install.html&quot;&gt;the Install section&lt;/a&gt; to get Elixir installed and read our &lt;a href=&quot;http://elixir-lang.org/getting-started/introduction.html&quot;&gt;Getting Started guide&lt;/a&gt; to learn more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have fun!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 14:38:04 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>nifoc</dc:creator>
<og:title>Elixir v1.11 released</og:title>
<og:description>Elixir v1.11 is out with improvements to the compiler and tighter integration with Erlang/OTP</og:description>
<og:url>https://elixir-lang.org/blog/2020/10/06/elixir-v1-11-0-released/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://elixir-lang.org/blog/2020/10/06/elixir-v1-11-0-released/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>U.S. House&amp;#039;s antitrust report hints at break-up of big tech firms: lawmaker</title>
<link>http://reuters.com/article/us-usa-tech-antitrust/u-s-houses-antitrust-report-hints-at-break-up-of-big-tech-firms-lawmaker-idUSKBN26R0EK</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://reuters.com/article/us-usa-tech-antitrust/u-s-houses-antitrust-report-hints-at-break-up-of-big-tech-firms-lawmaker-idUSKBN26R0EK</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;ArticleBody-byline-container-3H6dy&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Byline-byline-1sVmo ArticleBody-byline-10B7D&quot;&gt;By &lt;a class=&quot;TextLabel__text-label___3oCVw TextLabel__black-to-orange___23uc0 TextLabel__serif___3lOpX Byline-author-2BSir&quot; href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/journalists/diane-bartz&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Diane Bartz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ArticleBody-read-time-and-social-2VOIr&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;TextLabel__text-label___3oCVw TextLabel__gray___1V4fk TextLabel__small-all-caps-spaced-out___3O9H4 ReadTime-read-time-1s3CG ArticleBody-read-time-29pGN&quot;&gt;3 Min Read&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;WASHINGTON (Reuters) - The U.S. House of Representatives antitrust report on Big Tech firms contains a “thinly veiled call to break up” the companies, Republican Congressman Ken Buck said in a draft response seen by Reuters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FILE PHOTO: The logos of Amazon, Apple, Facebook and Google in a combination photo from Reuters files./File Photo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;The House antitrust subcommittee is expected to publish its report this week on Amazon.com Inc, Apple Inc, Facebook Inc and Google owner Alphabet Inc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;A Buck representative confirmed to Reuters the authenticity of the draft response, which was first reported by Politico.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;In the draft, Buck said he shared Democratic concerns about the power of Big Tech firms, with their penchant for “killer acquisitions” to eliminate rivals and self-preferencing in guiding customers to their other products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;However, he objected to a plan to require them to delineate a clear “single line of business”. Social media platform Facebook also owns Instagram and WhatsApp, search engine provider Google’s businesses include YouTube and Android, and e-commerce leader Amazon operates a massive cloud computing unit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;“This proposal is a thinly veiled call to break up Big Tech firms. We do not agree with the majority’s approach,” Buck wrote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;It is not yet known how many Republicans will support the report, which is being led by Democratic Chairman David Cicilline. Reports and recommendations with bipartisan support usually have a bigger impact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;“The report offers a chilling look into how Apple, Amazon, Google and Facebook have used their power to control how we see and understand the world,” Buck wrote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;He agreed with some of the report’s recommendations, such as making it easier for the Justice Department and Federal Trade Commission to stop mergers by lowering their burden of proof, and allowing consumers to take control of their data through data portability and interoperability between platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;“These potential changes need not be dramatic to be effective,” Buck wrote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;Buck also said he was displeased that the report failed to address conservative allegations that some platforms have tried to stifle conservative voices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;4.8943089430894&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Attribution-attribution-Y5JpY&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reporting by Diane Bartz in Washington; Editing by Christopher Cushing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 14:17:42 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>cblconfederate</dc:creator>
<og:title>U.S. House's antitrust report hints at break-up of Big Tech firms: lawmaker</og:title>
<og:description>The U.S. House of Representatives antitrust report on Big Tech firms contains a &quot;thinly veiled call to break up&quot; the companies, Republican Congressman Ken Buck said in a draft response seen by Reuters.</og:description>
<og:image>https://static.reuters.com/resources/r/?m=02&amp;d=20201006&amp;t=2&amp;i=1536313145&amp;r=LYNXMPEG9506S&amp;w=800</og:image>
<og:url>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-usa-tech-antitrust-idUSKBN26R0EK</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-usa-tech-antitrust/u-s-houses-antitrust-report-hints-at-break-up-of-big-tech-firms-lawmaker-idUSKBN26R0EK</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>DDR5 Is Coming: First 64GB DDR5-4800 Modules from SK Hynix</title>
<link>https://www.anandtech.com/show/16142/ddr5-is-coming-first-64gb-ddr5-4800-modules-from-sk-hynix</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.anandtech.com/show/16142/ddr5-is-coming-first-64gb-ddr5-4800-modules-from-sk-hynix</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Discussion of the next generation of DDR memory has been aflutter in recent months as manufacturers have been showcasing a wide variety of test vehicles ahead of a full product launch. Platforms that plan to use DDR5 are also fast approaching, with an expected debut on the enterprise side before slowly trickling down to consumer. As with all these things, development comes in stages: memory controllers, interfaces, electrical equivalent testing IP, and modules. It’s that final stage that SK Hynix is launching today, or at least the chips that go into these modules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DDR5 is the next stage of platform memory for use in the majority of major compute platforms. The specification (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.anandtech.com/show/15912/ddr5-specification-released-setting-the-stage-for-ddr56400-and-beyond&quot;&gt;as released in July 2020&lt;/a&gt;) brings the main voltage down from 1.2 V to 1.1 V, increases the maximum silicon die density by a factor 4, doubles the maximum data rate, doubles the burst length, and doubles the number of bank groups. Simply put, the JEDEC DDR specifications allows for a 128 GB unbuffered module running at DDR5-6400. RDIMMs and LRDIMMs should be able to go much higher, power permitting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table align=&quot;center&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;680&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;tgrey&quot;&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; colspan=&quot;7&quot;&gt;JEDEC DDR Generations&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;tlblue&quot;&gt;&lt;td width=&quot;200&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; width=&quot;225&quot;&gt;DDR5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; width=&quot;225&quot;&gt;DDR4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; width=&quot;225&quot;&gt;DDR3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; width=&quot;225&quot;&gt;LPDDR5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tlgrey&quot;&gt;Max Die Density&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;64 Gbit&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;16 Gbit&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;4 Gbit&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;32 Gbit&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tlgrey&quot;&gt;Max UDIMM Size&lt;br/&gt;(DSDR)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;128 GB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;32 GB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;8 GB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;N/A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tlgrey&quot;&gt;Max Data Rate&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;6.4 Gbps&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;3.2 Gbps&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;1.6 Gbps&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;6.4Gbps&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tlgrey&quot;&gt;Channels per Module&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tlgrey&quot;&gt;Total Width&lt;br/&gt;(Non-ECC)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;64-bits&lt;br/&gt;(2x32-bit)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;64-bits&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;64-bits&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;16-bits&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tlgrey&quot;&gt;Banks&lt;br/&gt;(Per Group)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;16&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tlgrey&quot;&gt;Bank Groups&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;8/4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;4/2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tlgrey&quot;&gt;Burst Length&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;BL16&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;BL8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;BL8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;BL16&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tlgrey&quot;&gt;Voltage (Vdd)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;1.1v&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;1.2v&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;1.5v&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;1.05v&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tlgrey&quot;&gt;Vddq&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;1.1v&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;1.2v&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;1.5v&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.5v&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are four angles in the world of DDR that everyone involved in the specification wants to iterate on. Capacity is the obvious one, but also memory bandwidth plays a key role in performance scaling of common multi-core workloads in the large core-count servers we are seeing. The other two are power (an obvious goal), and the other is latency, another key metric for performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With DDR5, one of the major changes to help drive this is the way the memory is seen by the system. Rather than being a single 64-bit data channel per module, DDR5 is seen as two 32-bit data channels per module (or 40 bits in ECC). The burst length has doubled, meaning that each 32-bit channel will still deliver 64 bytes per operation, but can do so in a more interleaved fashion. That means the standard ‘two 64-bit channel DDR4’ system will morph into a ‘quad 32-bit channel DDR5’ arrangement, although each memory stick provides a total of 64-bits but in a more controllable way. This also makes doubling the data rate, a key element in increasing peak bandwidth, easier, as well as a finer-grained bank refresh feature, which allows for asynchronous operations on the memory while it is in use, reducing latency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Voltage regulation is also being moved from the motherboard to the memory module, allowing the module to regulate its own needs. We already saw DDR4 adopt a per-chip Vdroop control, but this takes the whole idea a stage further for tighter power control and management. It also puts power management in the hands of the module vendor rather than the motherboard manufacturer, allowing the module manufacturer to size up what is required for faster memory – it will be interesting to see how different firmware cope with non-JEDEC standard gaming memory that will undoubtedly go above specification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://images.anandtech.com/doci/16142/SK_hynix_develops_1Ynm_DDR5_DRAM_12.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://images.anandtech.com/doci/16142/SK_hynix_develops_1Ynm_DDR5_DRAM_12_575px.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SK Hynix’s announcement today is that they are ready to start shipping DDR5 ECC memory to module manufacturers – specifically 16 gigabit dies built on its 1Ynm process that support DDR5-4800 to DDR5-5600 at 1.1 volts. With the right packaging technology (such as 3D TSV), SK Hynix says that partners can build 256 GB LRDIMMs. Additional binning of the chips for better-than-JEDEC speeds will have to be done by the module manufacturers themselves. SK Hynix also appears to have its own modules, specifically 32GB and 64GB RDIMMs at DDR5-4800, and has previously promised to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.anandtech.com/show/15699/sk-hynix-ddr5-8400&quot;&gt;offer memory up to DDR5-8400&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SK Hynix has not provided information of the sub-timings of these modules. The JEDEC specification defines three different modes for DDR5-4800:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;DDR5-4800A: 34-34-34&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DDR5-4800B: 40-40-40&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DDR5-4800C: 42-42-42&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is unclear which one of these that SK Hynix is using. The module says '4800E', however that appears to just be part of the module naming, as the JEDEC specification doesn't go beyond a CL value of 42 for DDR5-4800.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For bandwidth, other memory manufacturers have quoted that for the theoretical 38.4 GB/s that each module of DDR5-4800 can bring, they are already seeing effective numbers in the 32 GB/s range. This is above the effective 20-25 GB/s per channel that we are seeing on DDR4-3200 today. Other memory manufacturers &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.anandtech.com/show/15325/ces-2020-micron-begins-to-sample-ddr5-rdimms-with-server-makers&quot;&gt;have already announced&lt;/a&gt; that they are sampling DDR5 with customers since the beginning of the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of the announcement, it was interesting to see Intel as one of the lead partners for these modules. Intel has committed to enabling DDR5 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.anandtech.com/show/15120/intels-2021-exascale-vision-in-aurora-two-sapphire-rapids-cpus-with-six-ponte-vecchio-gpus&quot;&gt;on its Sapphire Rapids Xeon processor platform&lt;/a&gt;, due for initial launch in late 2021/2022. AMD was not mentioned with the announcement, and neither were any Arm partners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SK Hynix quotes that DDR5 is expected to be 10% of the global market in 2021, increasing to 43% in 2024. The intersection point for consumer platforms is somewhat blurred at this point, as we’re probably only half-way through (or less than half) of the DDR4 cycle. Traditionally we expect a cost interception between old and new technology when they are equal in market share, however the additional costs in voltage regulation that DDR5 requires is likely to drive up module costs – scaling from standard power delivery on JEDEC modules up to a beefier solution on the overclocked modules. It should however make motherboards cheaper in that regard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.skhynix.com/sk-hynix-launches-worlds-first-ddr5-dram/&quot;&gt;SK hynix&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Related Reading&lt;/h3&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 12:50:58 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ryansmccoy</dc:creator>
<og:title>DDR5 is Coming: First 64GB DDR5-4800 Modules from SK Hynix</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.anandtech.com/show/16142/ddr5-is-coming-first-64gb-ddr5-4800-modules-from-sk-hynix</og:url>
<og:image>https://images.anandtech.com/doci/16142/IMGP7929_678x452.jpg</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.anandtech.com/show/16142/ddr5-is-coming-first-64gb-ddr5-4800-modules-from-sk-hynix</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>