<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Go master Lee Se-dol says he quits, unable to win over AI Go players</title>
<link>https://en.yna.co.kr/view/AEN20191127004800315</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://en.yna.co.kr/view/AEN20191127004800315</guid>
<description>&lt;div readability=&quot;34&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;inner&quot; readability=&quot;13&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SEOUL, Nov. 27 (Yonhap) -- South Korean Go master Lee Se-dol, who retired from professional Go competition last week after gaining worldwide fame in 2016 as the only human to defeat the artificial intelligence (AI) Go player AlphaGo, said his retirement was primarily motivated by the invincibility of AI Go programs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;32.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;inner&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;With the debut of AI in Go games, I've realized that I'm not at the top even if I become the number one through frantic efforts,&quot; said Lee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;32.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;inner&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Even if I become the number one, there is an entity that cannot be defeated,&quot; he said in an interview with Yonhap News Agency in Seoul on Monday.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;33&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;inner&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AlphaGo, built by Google's DeepMind Technologies, won four of its five matches against Lee in March 2016, but Lee's sole win in Game 4 remains the only time a human has beaten the AI player.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;32.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;inner&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reflecting on the historic Game 4 on March 13, 2016, Lee attributed his win to a bug in the AlphaGo program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;33&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;inner&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the game, Lee's unexpected move at white 78 developed a white wedge between blacks at the center. The apparently embarrassed AlphaGo responded poorly on move 79, suddenly turning the game in Lee's favor. AlphaGo then declared its surrender by displaying a &quot;resign&quot; message on the computer screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;inner&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lee's white 78 is still praised as a &quot;brilliant, divine&quot; move that offered a ray of hope to humans frustrated by AIs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;31&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;inner&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Lee said he managed to win Game 4 due to AlphaGo's buggy response to his &quot;tricky&quot; moves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;33.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;inner&quot; readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;My white 78 was not a move that should be countered straightforwardly. Such a bug still occurs in Fine Art (a Chinese Go-playing computer program). Fine Art can hardly be defeated even after accepting two stone handicaps against humans. But when it loses, it loses in a strange way. It's due to a bug,&quot; Lee said.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;31&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;inner&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lee said he felt frustrated after losing the first three games to AlphaGo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;33&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;inner&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;I rarely read comments on internet news about me. But I got curious about how badly people were speaking of me after my three straight losses to AlphaGo. Unexpectedly, few people criticized me,&quot; Lee said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;inner&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Frankly, I had sensed kind of a defeat even before the start of the matches against AlphaGo. People from Google's DeepMind Technologies looked very confident from the beginning.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;33&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;inner&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go, known as &quot;baduk&quot; in Korea, originated in China more than 2,500 years ago. It involves two players alternately placing black and white stones on a checkerboard-like grid of 19 lines by 19 lines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;34.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;inner&quot; readability=&quot;14&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 36-year-old, who scored 18 victories in international competitions and 32 victories in domestic events, submitted his letter of retirement to the Korea Baduk Association (KBA), which oversees Go professionals in South Korea, on Nov. 19, terminating his legendary 24-year career.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;inner&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lee didn't deny that his retirement decision was also influenced by a conflict with the KBA over the use of membership fees. He actually quit the KBA in May 2016 and is now suing the association for the return of his membership fee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;31.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;inner&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lee had once considered playing in professional Go leagues in China or Japan but gave up the idea due to problems relating to his nationality among other things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;inner&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ironically, Lee plans to face off against another AI Go player next month to commemorate his retirement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;32.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;inner&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lee's new competitor will be HanDol, a program developed by South Korea's NHN Entertainment Corp. Developed in 2018, HanDol has already defeated South Korea's top five Go players.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;inner&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first match, Lee will be given an advantage of two stones. His advantage in subsequent games will be determined by the result of the first match.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;34&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;inner&quot; readability=&quot;13&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Even with a two-stone advantage, I feel like I will lose the first game to HanDol. These days, I don't follow Go news. I wanted to play comfortably against HanDol as I have already retired, though I will do my best,&quot; he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;32.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;inner&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some media commentators have speculated that Lee may enter politics after quitting his Go career, noting he made a public speech in support of President Moon Jae-in during his election campaign in May 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;33&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;inner&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When asked if he has political ambitions, however, Lee denied it flatly, saying he is not suitable for politics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;33&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;inner&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Membership of the National Assembly is not one of high status but a post that serves the people. I'm not suitable for the post. I'm also too young to do the job and have something else to do,&quot; he said, asserting his only dream for now is to rest and spend time with his family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 16:50:39 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>partingshots</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://en.yna.co.kr/view/AEN20191127004800315</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>(Yonhap Interview) Go master Lee says he quits unable to win over AI Go players | Yonhap News Agency</og:title>
<og:description>SEOUL, Nov. 27 (Yonhap) -- South Korean Go master Lee Se-dol, who retired from professiona...</og:description>
<og:image>https://img9.yna.co.kr/etc/inner/EN/2019/11/27/AEN20191127004800315_01_i_P4.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://en.yna.co.kr/view/AEN20191127004800315</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ubuntu 19.10: It’s fast</title>
<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=1623735</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://arstechnica.com/?p=1623735</guid>
<description>&lt;aside id=&quot;social-left&quot; class=&quot;social-left&quot; aria-label=&quot;Read the comments or share this article&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;comment-count-before&quot;&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;69 posters participating&quot; class=&quot;comment-count icon-comment-bubble-down&quot; href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2019/11/ubuntu-19-10-quite-simply-the-best-ubuntu-canonical-has-ever-released/?comments=1&quot;&gt;reader comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;a title=&quot;69 posters participating&quot; class=&quot;comment-count icon-comment-bubble-down&quot; href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2019/11/ubuntu-19-10-quite-simply-the-best-ubuntu-canonical-has-ever-released/?comments=1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;comment-count-number&quot;&gt;116&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;visually-hidden&quot;&gt;with 69 posters participating&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;share-links&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Share this story&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;Leaves are turning. Temperatures have dipped. These are sure signs—if you live in the Northern Hemisphere, at least—that Canonical's Autumn release is upon us. Things are a bit different in 2019, however. Not only is Ubuntu 19.10 nicknamed Eoan Ermine (no, I don't know how you pronounce it either), but it's the best non-LTS Ubuntu release Canonical has ever put out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I should qualify that statement somewhat, because really, as the newest version, it had damn well better be the best Ubuntu ever. But there's more than recency bias behind the sentiment. I've been reviewing Ubuntu for 10 years now, and I was using and interacting with this distro in some form or another for another three or four years before that. After spending recent weeks with Ubuntu 19.10, I can say confidently it is quite simply the best Ubuntu Canonical has ever released.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first reason I like 19.10 so much is that it feels insanely fast. Everyday tasks like opening applications, dragging windows, activating the search interface, and even just moving the cursor around are all noticeably faster than in &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2019/05/ubuntu-19-04-review-the-disco-dingo-aims-its-nose-at-the-cloud-and-developers/&quot;&gt;19.04&lt;/a&gt;. The speed boost is immediately noticeable from the minute you pop in the live CD, and it's even faster once you have 19.10 installed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I happened to be testing a top-of-the-line MacBook around the time I first installed the 19.10 beta on my aging Lenovo x240, and it instantly made the Mac feel like a sloth. Ubuntu 19.10 ran circles around the Mac even on much, much less powerful hardware, and nothing says success during testing like software that makes old hardware feel newer. Even if that were all you got out of Ubuntu 19.10, I'd call it a win.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But as is typical of Ubuntu's October release, a number of new features that are not quite ready for prime time yet show considerable promise—those features include support for the ZFS file system. While still clearly labelled &quot;experimental&quot; (in all caps even), I have not had problems running 19.10 on a root partition formatted with ZFS. That's not to say that you should go try it—it is EXPERIMENTAL, after all—but it appears that what's really lacking are tools for managing and working with ZFS. Using ZFS enables some powerful backup and replication possibilities, but the tools for working with ZFS in Ubuntu remain somewhat limited for now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But talk of the extra features can wait. Ubuntu 19.10 is so fast, it's worth digging deeper into the speed improvements and what's going on under the hood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/ubuntu1910-desktop-1.jpg&quot; class=&quot;enlarge&quot; data-height=&quot;1080&quot; data-width=&quot;1920&quot; alt=&quot;The default GNOME desktop in Ubuntu 19.10.&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/ubuntu1910-desktop-1-640x360.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; srcset=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/ubuntu1910-desktop-1-1280x720.jpg 2x&quot; alt=&quot;The default GNOME desktop in Ubuntu 19.10.&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-text&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/ubuntu1910-desktop-1.jpg&quot; class=&quot;enlarge-link&quot; data-height=&quot;1080&quot; data-width=&quot;1920&quot;&gt;Enlarge&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;sep&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; The default GNOME desktop in Ubuntu 19.10.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;caption-credit&quot;&gt;Canonical / Linux&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Like GNOME, but fast&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most improvements in 19.10 can be attributed to the latest release of GNOME 3.34, the default desktop for Ubuntu. However, GNOME 3.34 is faster largely because of work Canonical engineers put in. (As an aside, I think the current state of GNOME and the work Canonical has done to make it better are the best argument around for why Canonical made the right call when it shut down Unity.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you'd like to understand the finer details of what Canonical did to improve GNOME and how it did it, there's a post over on the Ubuntu Discourse board that &lt;a href=&quot;https://discourse.ubuntu.com/t/boosting-the-real-time-performance-of-gnome-shell-3-34-in-ubuntu-19-10/13095&quot;&gt;goes into considerable detail&lt;/a&gt;. The biggest takeaway is that Canonical's engineers looked not for the typical &quot;hot spots,&quot; places RAM or CPU usage spiked, but what it calls &quot;cold spots.&quot; It wanted to find places where GNOME &quot;was idle instead of updating the screen smoothly.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Canonical developers identified a bunch of places where this was happening. The three that jumped out at me are improvements to how Mutter refreshes, changes that transferred some work from the GPU &lt;em&gt;back&lt;/em&gt; to the CPU, and a fix to frame lagging in Xorg. The latter is interesting because one of the things that I noticed in this release is that GNOME under Wayland did not feel dramatically faster than under Xorg the way it did for me in 19.04. I quickly lost my Wayland envy with the speed improvements in this release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Canonical's write-up of the work done to improve GNOME is also interesting for the long list of what didn't work and how wrong some of the developers' initial assumptions were—especially regarding GNOME's use of JavaScript. It turns out JavaScript had next to no effect on performance. So sorry JavaScript haters, but &quot;assuming that JavaScript is slower than everything else written in C&quot; is evidently a bad assumption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Canonical is not done improving GNOME. The project's goal for the next release is better performance on faster, modern hardware. Then in 20.10, it wants to improve performance on older, slower machines. As Canonical's Daniel Van Vugt puts it, &quot;the future of Gnome Shell is bright and worth getting excited about.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But let's not get too far ahead of ourselves, because even the present is pretty bright. As primarily an i3 user, I still find GNOME Shell overkill, but in 19.10 it's fast enough that I no longer rush to uninstall it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Listing image by Canonical / Linux&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 16:41:48 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>feross</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2019/11/ubuntu-19-10-quite-simply-the-best-ubuntu-canonical-has-ever-released/</og:url>
<og:title>Ubuntu 19.10: It’s fast, like “make old hardware feel new” fast</og:title>
<og:image>https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/ubuntu1910-desktop-1-760x380.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>There's even support for the ZFS filesystem (though it's &quot;EXPERIMENTAL&quot;).</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2019/11/ubuntu-19-10-quite-simply-the-best-ubuntu-canonical-has-ever-released/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>RoughViz: JS library for creating sketchy/hand-drawn style charts in the browser</title>
<link>https://github.com/jwilber/roughViz</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/jwilber/roughViz</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;Box-body&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;markdown-body entry-content p-5&quot; itemprop=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jwilber/random_data/master/roughViz_Title.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jwilber/random_data/master/roughViz_Title.png&quot; width=&quot;350&quot; alt=&quot;roughViz.js&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://badge.fury.io/js/rough-viz&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/ca0be361f0b4455d8a4cbea43ad150c7414aee72/68747470733a2f2f62616467652e667572792e696f2f6a732f726f7567682d76697a2e737667&quot; alt=&quot;npm version&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://badge.fury.io/js/rough-viz.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/e8d3822a73eef62b6bd00f9ed214aa7737ba2ff6/68747470733a2f2f696d672e736869656c64732e696f2f62756e646c6570686f6269612f6d696e2f726f7567682d76697a2f312e302e35&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/e8d3822a73eef62b6bd00f9ed214aa7737ba2ff6/68747470733a2f2f696d672e736869656c64732e696f2f62756e646c6570686f6269612f6d696e2f726f7567682d76697a2f312e302e35&quot; alt=&quot;npm bundle size (version)&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/bundlephobia/min/rough-viz/1.0.5&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;roughViz.js&lt;/strong&gt; is a reusable JavaScript library for creating sketchy/hand-drawn styled charts in the browser, based on D3v5, roughjs, and handy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jwilber/random_data/master/roughViz.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jwilber/random_data/master/roughViz.gif&quot; alt=&quot;roughViz.js&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Why?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use these charts where the communication goal is to show intent or generality, and not absolute precision. Or just because they're fun and look weird.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Features&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chart Types&lt;/strong&gt; (more to come!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apply the features of &lt;code&gt;roughjs&lt;/code&gt; to each chart:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;roughness&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jwilber/random_data/master/roughViz_roughnessbars.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jwilber/random_data/master/roughViz_roughnessbars.png&quot; alt=&quot;roughness examples&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong id=&quot;user-content-fillstyle&quot;&gt;fillStyle&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jwilber/random_data/master/rough_fillStyles.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jwilber/random_data/master/rough_fillStyles.png&quot; alt=&quot;fillStyle examples&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;fillWeight&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jwilber/random_data/master/roughViz_fillweight.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jwilber/random_data/master/roughViz_fillweight.png&quot; alt=&quot;fillStyle examples&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As well as additional chart-specific options (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jwilber/roughViz#API&quot;&gt;see API below&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Installation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Via CDN (expose the &lt;code&gt;roughViz&lt;/code&gt; global in &lt;code&gt;html&lt;/code&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-text-html-basic&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&amp;lt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-ent&quot;&gt;script&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-e&quot;&gt;src&lt;/span&gt;=&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;https://unpkg.com/rough-viz@1.0.5&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/&lt;span class=&quot;pl-ent&quot;&gt;script&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Via &lt;code&gt;npm&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
npm install rough-viz
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Want to use with &lt;code&gt;React&lt;/code&gt;? &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Chris927/react-roughviz&quot;&gt;There's a wrapper!&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
npm install react-roughviz
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Want to use it with &lt;code&gt;Python&lt;/code&gt;? &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/hannansatopay/roughviz&quot;&gt;There's a wrapper!&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
pip install roughviz
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;How to use&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create some container elements, one for each chart:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-text-html-basic&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;!--&lt;/span&gt;you can name each id whatever you want &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;--&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&amp;lt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-ent&quot;&gt;div&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-e&quot;&gt;id&lt;/span&gt;=&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;viz0&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/&lt;span class=&quot;pl-ent&quot;&gt;div&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-ent&quot;&gt;div&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-e&quot;&gt;id&lt;/span&gt;=&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;viz1&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/&lt;span class=&quot;pl-ent&quot;&gt;div&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the javascript, just create charts, referencing the desired container:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-js&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;//&lt;/span&gt; create donut chart from csv file, using default options&lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;roughViz.Bar&lt;/span&gt;({
    element&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;#vis0&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;//&lt;/span&gt; container selection&lt;/span&gt;
    data&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jwilber/random_data/master/flavors.csv&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;,
    labels&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;flavor&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;,
    values&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;price&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
});

&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;//&lt;/span&gt; create Donut chart using defined data &amp;amp; customize plot options&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;roughViz.Donut&lt;/span&gt;(
  {
    element&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;#vis1&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;,
    data&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; {
      labels&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; [&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;North&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;South&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;East&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;West&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;],
      values&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; [&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;8&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;]
    },
    title&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;Regions&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;,
    width&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;window&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;innerWidth&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;,
    roughness&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;8&lt;/span&gt;,
    colors&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; [&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;red&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;orange&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;blue&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;skyblue&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;],
    stroke&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;black&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;,
    strokeWidth&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;,
    fillStyle&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;cross-hatch&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;,
    fillWeight&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;3.5&lt;/span&gt;,
  }
);
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;user-content-api&quot;&gt;API&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;code id=&quot;user-content-bar&quot;&gt;roughViz.Bar&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Required&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;element&lt;/code&gt; [string]: Id or class of container element.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;data&lt;/code&gt;: Data with which to construct chart. Can be either an object or string.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;If object: must contain &lt;code&gt;labels&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;values&lt;/code&gt; keys:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-js&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;roughViz.Bar&lt;/span&gt;({
   element&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;.viz&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;,
   data&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; {labels&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; [&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;a&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;b&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;], values&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; [&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;20&lt;/span&gt;]}
 })
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;If string: must be a path/url to a &lt;code&gt;csv&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;tsv&lt;/code&gt;, and you must also specify the &lt;code&gt;labels&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;values&lt;/code&gt; as separate attributes that represent columns in said file:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-js&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;roughViz.Bar&lt;/span&gt;({
  element&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;#viz0&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;,
  data&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;stringToDataUrl.csv&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;,
  labels&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;nameOfLabelsColumn&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;,
  values&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;nameOfValuesColumn&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;,
})
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Optional&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;axisFontSize&lt;/code&gt; [string]: Font-size for axes' labels. Default: &lt;code&gt;'1rem'&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;axisRoughness&lt;/code&gt; [number]: Roughness for x &amp;amp; y axes. Default: &lt;code&gt;0.5&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;axisStrokeWidth&lt;/code&gt; [number]: Stroke-width for x &amp;amp; y axes. Default: &lt;code&gt;0.5&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;bowing&lt;/code&gt; [number]: Chart bowing. Default: &lt;code&gt;0&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;color&lt;/code&gt; [string]: Color for each bar. Default: &lt;code&gt;'skyblue'&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;fillStyle&lt;/code&gt; [string]: Bar fill-style. Should be one of &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jwilber/roughViz#fillStyle&quot;&gt;fillStyles&lt;/a&gt; shown above.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;fillWeight&lt;/code&gt; [number]: Weight of inner paths' color. Default: &lt;code&gt;0.5&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;font&lt;/code&gt;: Font-family to use. You can use &lt;code&gt;0&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;gaegu&lt;/code&gt; to use &lt;code&gt;Gaegu&lt;/code&gt;, or &lt;code&gt;1&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;indie flower&lt;/code&gt; to use &lt;code&gt;Indie Flower&lt;/code&gt;. Or feed it something else. Default: &lt;code&gt;Gaegu&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;highlight&lt;/code&gt; [string]: Color for each bar on hover. Default: &lt;code&gt;'coral'&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;innerStrokeWidth&lt;/code&gt; [number]: Stroke-width for paths inside bars. Default: &lt;code&gt;1&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;interactive&lt;/code&gt; [boolean]: Whether or not chart is interactive. Default: &lt;code&gt;true&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;labelFontSize&lt;/code&gt; [string]: Font-size for axes' labels. Default: &lt;code&gt;'1rem'&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;margin&lt;/code&gt; [object]: Margin object. Default: &lt;code&gt;{top: 50, right: 20, bottom: 70, left: 100}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;padding&lt;/code&gt; [number]: Padding between bars. Default: &lt;code&gt;0.1&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;roughness&lt;/code&gt; [number]: Roughness level of chart. Default: &lt;code&gt;1&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;simplification&lt;/code&gt; [number]: Chart simplification. Default &lt;code&gt;0.2&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;stroke&lt;/code&gt; [string]: Color of bars' stroke. Default: &lt;code&gt;black&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;strokeWidth&lt;/code&gt; [number]: Size of bars' stroke. Default: &lt;code&gt;1&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;title&lt;/code&gt; [string]: Chart title. Optional.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;titleFontSize&lt;/code&gt; [string]: Font-size for chart title. Default: &lt;code&gt;'1rem'&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;tooltipFontSize&lt;/code&gt; [string]: Font-size for tooltip. Default: &lt;code&gt;'0.95rem'&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;xLabel&lt;/code&gt; [string]: Label for x-axis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;yLabel&lt;/code&gt; [string]: Label for y-axis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;code id=&quot;user-content-barh&quot;&gt;roughViz.BarH&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Required&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;element&lt;/code&gt; [string]: Id or class of container element.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;data&lt;/code&gt;: Data with which to construct chart. Can be either an object or string.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;If object: must contain &lt;code&gt;labels&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;values&lt;/code&gt; keys:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-js&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;roughViz.BarH&lt;/span&gt;({
   element&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;.viz&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;,
   data&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; {labels&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; [&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;a&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;b&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;], values&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; [&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;20&lt;/span&gt;]}
 })
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;If string: must be a path/url to a &lt;code&gt;csv&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;tsv&lt;/code&gt;, and you must also specify the &lt;code&gt;labels&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;values&lt;/code&gt; as separate attributes that represent columns in said file:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-js&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;roughViz.BarH&lt;/span&gt;({
  element&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;#viz0&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;,
  data&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;stringToDataUrl.csv&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;,
  labels&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;nameOfLabelsColumn&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;,
  values&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;nameOfValuesColumn&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;,
})
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Optional&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;axisFontSize&lt;/code&gt; [string]: Font-size for axes' labels. Default: &lt;code&gt;'1rem'&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;axisRoughness&lt;/code&gt; [number]: Roughness for x &amp;amp; y axes. Default: &lt;code&gt;0.5&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;axisStrokeWidth&lt;/code&gt; [number]: Stroke-width for x &amp;amp; y axes. Default: &lt;code&gt;0.5&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;bowing&lt;/code&gt; [number]: Chart bowing. Default: &lt;code&gt;0&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;color&lt;/code&gt; [string]: Color for each bar. Default: &lt;code&gt;'skyblue'&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;fillStyle&lt;/code&gt; [string]: Bar fill-style. Should be one of &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jwilber/roughViz#fillStyle&quot;&gt;fillStyles&lt;/a&gt; shown above.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;fillWeight&lt;/code&gt; [number]: Weight of inner paths' color. Default: &lt;code&gt;0.5&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;font&lt;/code&gt;: Font-family to use. You can use &lt;code&gt;0&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;gaegu&lt;/code&gt; to use &lt;code&gt;Gaegu&lt;/code&gt;, or &lt;code&gt;1&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;indie flower&lt;/code&gt; to use &lt;code&gt;Indie Flower&lt;/code&gt;. Or feed it something else. Default: &lt;code&gt;Gaegu&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;highlight&lt;/code&gt; [string]: Color for each bar on hover. Default: &lt;code&gt;'coral'&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;innerStrokeWidth&lt;/code&gt; [number]: Stroke-width for paths inside bars. Default: &lt;code&gt;1&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;interactive&lt;/code&gt; [boolean]: Whether or not chart is interactive. Default: &lt;code&gt;true&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;labelFontSize&lt;/code&gt; [string]: Font-size for axes' labels. Default: &lt;code&gt;'1rem'&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;margin&lt;/code&gt; [object]: Margin object. Default: &lt;code&gt;{top: 50, right: 20, bottom: 70, left: 100}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;padding&lt;/code&gt; [number]: Padding between bars. Default: &lt;code&gt;0.1&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;roughness&lt;/code&gt; [number]: Roughness level of chart. Default: &lt;code&gt;1&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;simplification&lt;/code&gt; [number]: Chart simplification. Default &lt;code&gt;0.2&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;stroke&lt;/code&gt; [string]: Color of bars' stroke. Default: &lt;code&gt;black&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;strokeWidth&lt;/code&gt; [number]: Size of bars' stroke. Default: &lt;code&gt;1&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;title&lt;/code&gt; [string]: Chart title. Optional.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;titleFontSize&lt;/code&gt; [string]: Font-size for chart title. Default: &lt;code&gt;'1rem'&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;tooltipFontSize&lt;/code&gt; [string]: Font-size for tooltip. Default: &lt;code&gt;'0.95rem'&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;xLabel&lt;/code&gt; [string]: Label for x-axis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;yLabel&lt;/code&gt; [string]: Label for y-axis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;code id=&quot;user-content-donut&quot;&gt;roughViz.Donut&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Required&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;element&lt;/code&gt; [string]: Id or class of container element.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;data&lt;/code&gt;: Data with which to construct chart. Can be either an object or string.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;If object: must contain &lt;code&gt;labels&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;values&lt;/code&gt; keys:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-js&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;roughViz.Donut&lt;/span&gt;({
   element&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;.viz&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;,
   data&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; {labels&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; [&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;a&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;b&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;], values&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; [&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;20&lt;/span&gt;]}
 })
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;If string: must be a path/url to a &lt;code&gt;csv&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;json&lt;/code&gt;, or &lt;code&gt;tsv&lt;/code&gt;, and you must also specify the &lt;code&gt;labels&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;values&lt;/code&gt; as separate attributes that represent columns in said file:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-js&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;roughViz.Donut&lt;/span&gt;({
  element&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;#viz0&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;,
  data&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;stringToDataUrl.csv&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;,
  labels&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;nameOfLabelsColumn&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;,
  values&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;nameOfValuesColumn&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;,
})
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Optional&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;bowing&lt;/code&gt; [number]: Chart bowing. Default: &lt;code&gt;0&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;colors&lt;/code&gt; [array]: Array of colors for each arc. Default: &lt;code&gt;['coral', 'skyblue', '#66c2a5', 'tan', '#8da0cb', '#e78ac3', '#a6d854', '#ffd92f', 'tan', 'orange']&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;fillStyle&lt;/code&gt; [string]: Bar fill-style. Should be one of &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jwilber/roughViz#fillStyle&quot;&gt;fillStyles&lt;/a&gt; shown above.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;fillWeight&lt;/code&gt; [number]: Weight of inner paths' color. Default: &lt;code&gt;0.85&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;font&lt;/code&gt;: Font-family to use. You can use &lt;code&gt;0&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;gaegu&lt;/code&gt; to use &lt;code&gt;Gaegu&lt;/code&gt;, or &lt;code&gt;1&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;indie flower&lt;/code&gt; to use &lt;code&gt;Indie Flower&lt;/code&gt;. Or feed it something else. Default: &lt;code&gt;Gaegu&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;highlight&lt;/code&gt; [string]: Color for each arc on hover. Default: &lt;code&gt;'coral'&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;innerStrokeWidth&lt;/code&gt; [number]: Stroke-width for paths inside arcs. Default: &lt;code&gt;0.75&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;interactive&lt;/code&gt; [boolean]: Whether or not chart is interactive. Default: &lt;code&gt;true&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;legend&lt;/code&gt; [boolean]: Whether or not to add legend. Default: &lt;code&gt;'true'&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;legendPosition&lt;/code&gt; [string]: Position of legend. Should be either &lt;code&gt;'left'&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;'right'&lt;/code&gt;. Default: &lt;code&gt;'right'&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;margin&lt;/code&gt; [object]: Margin object. Default: &lt;code&gt;{top: 50, right: 20, bottom: 70, left: 100}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;padding&lt;/code&gt; [number]: Padding between bars. Default: &lt;code&gt;0.1&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;roughness&lt;/code&gt; [number]: Roughness level of chart. Default: &lt;code&gt;1&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;simplification&lt;/code&gt; [number]: Chart simplification. Default &lt;code&gt;0.2&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;strokeWidth&lt;/code&gt; [number]: Size of bars' stroke. Default: &lt;code&gt;1&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;title&lt;/code&gt; [string]: Chart title. Optional.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;titleFontSize&lt;/code&gt; [string]: Font-size for chart title. Default: &lt;code&gt;'1rem'&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;tooltipFontSize&lt;/code&gt; [string]: Font-size for tooltip. Default: &lt;code&gt;'0.95rem'&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;code id=&quot;user-content-line&quot;&gt;roughViz.Line&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Required&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;element&lt;/code&gt; [string]: Id or class of container element.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;data&lt;/code&gt;: Must be a path/url to a &lt;code&gt;csv&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;tsv&lt;/code&gt;, and you must also specify the each &lt;code&gt;y&lt;/code&gt; as separate attributes that represent columns in said file. Each attribute prefaced with &lt;code&gt;y&lt;/code&gt; (except &lt;code&gt;yLabel&lt;/code&gt;) will receive its own line:
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-js&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;roughViz.Line&lt;/span&gt;({
  element&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;#viz0&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;,
  data&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jwilber/random_data/master/profits.csv&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;,
  y1&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;revenue&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;,
  y2&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;cost&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;,
  y3&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;profit&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
})
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Optional&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;axisFontSize&lt;/code&gt; [string]: Font-size for axes' labels. Default: &lt;code&gt;'1rem'&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;axisRoughness&lt;/code&gt; [number]: Roughness for x &amp;amp; y axes. Default: &lt;code&gt;0.5&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;axisStrokeWidth&lt;/code&gt; [number]: Stroke-width for x &amp;amp; y axes. Default: &lt;code&gt;0.5&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;bowing&lt;/code&gt; [number]: Chart bowing. Default: &lt;code&gt;0&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;circle&lt;/code&gt; [boolean]: Whether or not to add circles to chart. Default: &lt;code&gt;true&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;circleRadius&lt;/code&gt; [number]: Radius of circles. Default: &lt;code&gt;10&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;circleRoughness&lt;/code&gt; [number]: Roughness of circles. Default: &lt;code&gt;2&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;colors&lt;/code&gt; [array or string]: Array of colors for each arc. Default: &lt;code&gt;['coral', 'skyblue', '#66c2a5', 'tan', '#8da0cb', '#e78ac3', '#a6d854', '#ffd92f', 'tan', 'orange']&lt;/code&gt;. If string (e.g. &lt;code&gt;'blue'&lt;/code&gt;), all circles will take that color.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;fillStyle&lt;/code&gt; [string]: Bar fill-style. Should be one of &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jwilber/roughViz#fillStyle&quot;&gt;fillStyles&lt;/a&gt; shown above.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;fillWeight&lt;/code&gt; [number]: Weight of inner paths' color. Default: &lt;code&gt;0.5&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;font&lt;/code&gt;: Font-family to use. You can use &lt;code&gt;0&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;gaegu&lt;/code&gt; to use &lt;code&gt;Gaegu&lt;/code&gt;, or &lt;code&gt;1&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;indie flower&lt;/code&gt; to use &lt;code&gt;Indie Flower&lt;/code&gt;. Or feed it something else. Default: &lt;code&gt;Gaegu&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;interactive&lt;/code&gt; [boolean]: Whether or not chart is interactive. Default: &lt;code&gt;true&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;labelFontSize&lt;/code&gt; [string]: Font-size for axes' labels. Default: &lt;code&gt;'1rem'&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;legend&lt;/code&gt; [boolean]: Whether or not to add legend. Default: &lt;code&gt;true&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;legendPosition&lt;/code&gt; [string]: Position of legend. Should be either &lt;code&gt;'left'&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;'right'&lt;/code&gt;. Default: &lt;code&gt;'right'&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;margin&lt;/code&gt; [object]: Margin object. Default: &lt;code&gt;{top: 50, right: 20, bottom: 70, left: 100}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;roughness&lt;/code&gt; [number]: Roughness level of chart. Default: &lt;code&gt;1&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;simplification&lt;/code&gt; [number]: Chart simplification. Default &lt;code&gt;0.2&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;stroke&lt;/code&gt; [string]: Color of lines' stroke. Default: &lt;code&gt;this.colors&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;strokeWidth&lt;/code&gt; [number]: Size of lines' stroke. Default: &lt;code&gt;1&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;title&lt;/code&gt; [string]: Chart title. Optional.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;titleFontSize&lt;/code&gt; [string]: Font-size for chart title. Default: &lt;code&gt;'0.95rem'&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;tooltipFontSize&lt;/code&gt; [string]: Font-size for tooltip. Default: &lt;code&gt;'0.95rem'&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;xLabel&lt;/code&gt; [string]: Label for x-axis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;yLabel&lt;/code&gt; [string]: Label for y-axis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;code id=&quot;user-content-pie&quot;&gt;roughViz.Pie&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Required&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;element&lt;/code&gt; [string]: Id or class of container element.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;data&lt;/code&gt;: Data with which to construct chart. Can be either an object or string.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;If object: must contain &lt;code&gt;labels&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;values&lt;/code&gt; keys:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-js&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;roughViz.Pie&lt;/span&gt;({
   element&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;.viz&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;,
   data&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; {labels&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; [&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;a&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;b&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;], values&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; [&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;20&lt;/span&gt;]}
 })
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;If string: must be a path/url to a &lt;code&gt;csv&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;json&lt;/code&gt;, or &lt;code&gt;tsv&lt;/code&gt;, and you must also specify the &lt;code&gt;labels&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;values&lt;/code&gt; as separate attributes that represent columns in said file:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-js&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;roughViz.Pie&lt;/span&gt;({
  element&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;#viz0&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;,
  data&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;stringToDataUrl.csv&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;,
  labels&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;nameOfLabelsColumn&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;,
  values&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;nameOfValuesColumn&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;,
})
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Optional&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;bowing&lt;/code&gt; [number]: Chart bowing. Default: &lt;code&gt;0&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;colors&lt;/code&gt; [array]: Array of colors for each arc. Default: &lt;code&gt;['coral', 'skyblue', '#66c2a5', 'tan', '#8da0cb', '#e78ac3', '#a6d854', '#ffd92f', 'tan', 'orange']&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;fillStyle&lt;/code&gt; [string]: Bar fill-style. Should be one of &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jwilber/roughViz#fillStyle&quot;&gt;fillStyles&lt;/a&gt; shown above.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;fillWeight&lt;/code&gt; [number]: Weight of inner paths' color. Default: &lt;code&gt;0.85&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;font&lt;/code&gt;: Font-family to use. You can use &lt;code&gt;0&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;gaegu&lt;/code&gt; to use &lt;code&gt;Gaegu&lt;/code&gt;, or &lt;code&gt;1&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;indie flower&lt;/code&gt; to use &lt;code&gt;Indie Flower&lt;/code&gt;. Or feed it something else. Default: &lt;code&gt;Gaegu&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;highlight&lt;/code&gt; [string]: Color for each arc on hover. Default: &lt;code&gt;'coral'&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;innerStrokeWidth&lt;/code&gt; [number]: Stroke-width for paths inside arcs. Default: &lt;code&gt;0.75&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;interactive&lt;/code&gt; [boolean]: Whether or not chart is interactive. Default: &lt;code&gt;true&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;legend&lt;/code&gt; [boolean]: Whether or not to add legend. Default: &lt;code&gt;true&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;legendPosition&lt;/code&gt; [string]: Position of legend. Should be either &lt;code&gt;'left'&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;'right'&lt;/code&gt;. Default: &lt;code&gt;'right'&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;margin&lt;/code&gt; [object]: Margin object. Default: &lt;code&gt;{top: 50, right: 20, bottom: 70, left: 100}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;padding&lt;/code&gt; [number]: Padding between bars. Default: &lt;code&gt;0.1&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;roughness&lt;/code&gt; [number]: Roughness level of chart. Default: &lt;code&gt;1&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;simplification&lt;/code&gt; [number]: Chart simplification. Default &lt;code&gt;0.2&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;strokeWidth&lt;/code&gt; [number]: Size of bars' stroke. Default: &lt;code&gt;1&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;title&lt;/code&gt; [string]: Chart title. Optional.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;titleFontSize&lt;/code&gt; [string]: Font-size for chart title. Default: &lt;code&gt;'1rem'&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;tooltipFontSize&lt;/code&gt; [string]: Font-size for tooltip. Default: &lt;code&gt;'0.95rem'&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;code id=&quot;user-content-scatter&quot;&gt;roughViz.Scatter&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Required&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;element&lt;/code&gt; [string]: Id or class of container element.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;data&lt;/code&gt;: Data with which to construct chart. Can be either an object or string.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;If object: must contain &lt;code&gt;x&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;y&lt;/code&gt; keys:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-js&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;roughViz.Scatter&lt;/span&gt;({
   element&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;.viz&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;,
   data&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; {x&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; [&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;35&lt;/span&gt;], y&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; [&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;20&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;8&lt;/span&gt;]}
 })
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;If string: must be a path/url to a &lt;code&gt;csv&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;tsv&lt;/code&gt;, and you must also specify the &lt;code&gt;x&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;y&lt;/code&gt; as separate attributes that represent columns in said file:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-js&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;roughViz.Scatter&lt;/span&gt;({
  element&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;#viz0&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;,
  data&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;stringToDataUrl.csv&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;,
  x&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;nameOfLabelsColumn&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;,
  y&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;nameOfValuesColumn&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;,
})
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Optional&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;axisFontSize&lt;/code&gt; [string]: Font-size for axes' labels. Default: &lt;code&gt;'1rem'&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;axisRoughness&lt;/code&gt; [number]: Roughness for x &amp;amp; y axes. Default: &lt;code&gt;0.5&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;axisStrokeWidth&lt;/code&gt; [number]: Stroke-width for x &amp;amp; y axes. Default: &lt;code&gt;0.5&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;bowing&lt;/code&gt; [number]: Chart bowing. Default: &lt;code&gt;0&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;colors&lt;/code&gt; [array or string]: Array of colors for each arc. Default: &lt;code&gt;['coral', 'skyblue', '#66c2a5', 'tan', '#8da0cb', '#e78ac3', '#a6d854', '#ffd92f', 'tan', 'orange']&lt;/code&gt;. If string (e.g. &lt;code&gt;'blue'&lt;/code&gt;), all circles will take that color.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;colorVar&lt;/code&gt; [string]: If input data is &lt;code&gt;csv&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;tsv&lt;/code&gt;, this should be an ordinal column with which to color points by. &lt;code&gt;curbZero&lt;/code&gt; [boolean]: Whether or not to force (x, y) axes to (0, 0). Default: &lt;code&gt;false&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;fillStyle&lt;/code&gt; [string]: Bar fill-style. Should be one of &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jwilber/roughViz#fillStyle&quot;&gt;fillStyles&lt;/a&gt; shown above.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;fillWeight&lt;/code&gt; [number]: Weight of inner paths' color. Default: &lt;code&gt;0.5&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;font&lt;/code&gt;: Font-family to use. You can use &lt;code&gt;0&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;gaegu&lt;/code&gt; to use &lt;code&gt;Gaegu&lt;/code&gt;, or &lt;code&gt;1&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;indie flower&lt;/code&gt; to use &lt;code&gt;Indie Flower&lt;/code&gt;. Or feed it something else. Default: &lt;code&gt;Gaegu&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;highlight&lt;/code&gt; [string]: Color for each bar on hover. Default: &lt;code&gt;'coral'&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;highlightLabel&lt;/code&gt; [string]: If input data is &lt;code&gt;csv&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;tsv&lt;/code&gt;, this should be a column representing what value to display on hover. Otherwise, &lt;code&gt;(x, y)&lt;/code&gt; values will be shown on hover.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;innerStrokeWidth&lt;/code&gt; [number]: Stroke-width for paths inside circles. Default: &lt;code&gt;1&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;interactive&lt;/code&gt; [boolean]: Whether or not chart is interactive. Default: &lt;code&gt;true&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;labelFontSize&lt;/code&gt; [string]: Font-size for axes' labels. Default: &lt;code&gt;'1rem'&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;margin&lt;/code&gt; [object]: Margin object. Default: &lt;code&gt;{top: 50, right: 20, bottom: 70, left: 100}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;radius&lt;/code&gt; [number]: Circle radius. Default: &lt;code&gt;8&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;roughness&lt;/code&gt; [number]: Roughness level of chart. Default: &lt;code&gt;1&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;simplification&lt;/code&gt; [number]: Chart simplification. Default &lt;code&gt;0.2&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;stroke&lt;/code&gt; [string]: Color of circles' stroke. Default: &lt;code&gt;black&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;strokeWidth&lt;/code&gt; [number]: Size of circles' stroke. Default: &lt;code&gt;1&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;title&lt;/code&gt; [string]: Chart title. Optional.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;titleFontSize&lt;/code&gt; [string]: Font-size for chart title. Default: &lt;code&gt;'0.95rem'&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;tooltipFontSize&lt;/code&gt; [string]: Font-size for tooltip. Default: &lt;code&gt;'0.95rem'&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;xLabel&lt;/code&gt; [string]: Label for x-axis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;yLabel&lt;/code&gt; [string]: Label for y-axis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;code id=&quot;user-content-stackedbar&quot;&gt;roughViz.StackedBar&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Required&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;element&lt;/code&gt; [string]: Id or class of container element.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;data&lt;/code&gt;: Data with which to construct chart. Should be an object.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;labels&lt;/code&gt;: String name of label key in &lt;code&gt;data&lt;/code&gt; object.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-js&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;roughViz.StackedBar&lt;/span&gt;({
   element&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;#vis0&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;,
   data&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; [
       {month&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;Jan&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;A&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;20&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;B&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;},
       {month&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;Feb&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;A&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;25&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;B&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;},    
   ],
   labels&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;month&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;,
 })
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Optional&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;axisFontSize&lt;/code&gt; [string]: Font-size for axes' labels. Default: &lt;code&gt;'1rem'&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;axisRoughness&lt;/code&gt; [number]: Roughness for x &amp;amp; y axes. Default: &lt;code&gt;0.5&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;axisStrokeWidth&lt;/code&gt; [number]: Stroke-width for x &amp;amp; y axes. Default: &lt;code&gt;0.5&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;bowing&lt;/code&gt; [number]: Chart bowing. Default: &lt;code&gt;0&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;colors&lt;/code&gt; [string]: Array of colors for each bar grouping.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;fillStyle&lt;/code&gt; [string]: Bar fill-style. Should be one of &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jwilber/roughViz#fillStyle&quot;&gt;fillStyles&lt;/a&gt; shown above.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;fillWeight&lt;/code&gt; [number]: Weight of inner paths' color. Default: &lt;code&gt;0.5&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;font&lt;/code&gt;: Font-family to use. You can use &lt;code&gt;0&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;gaegu&lt;/code&gt; to use &lt;code&gt;Gaegu&lt;/code&gt;, or &lt;code&gt;1&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;indie flower&lt;/code&gt; to use &lt;code&gt;Indie Flower&lt;/code&gt;. Or feed it something else. Default: &lt;code&gt;Gaegu&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;highlight&lt;/code&gt; [string]: Color for each bar on hover. Default: &lt;code&gt;'coral'&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;innerStrokeWidth&lt;/code&gt; [number]: Stroke-width for paths inside bars. Default: &lt;code&gt;1&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;interactive&lt;/code&gt; [boolean]: Whether or not chart is interactive. Default: &lt;code&gt;true&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;labelFontSize&lt;/code&gt; [string]: Font-size for axes' labels. Default: &lt;code&gt;'1rem'&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;margin&lt;/code&gt; [object]: Margin object. Default: &lt;code&gt;{top: 50, right: 20, bottom: 70, left: 100}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;padding&lt;/code&gt; [number]: Padding between bars. Default: &lt;code&gt;0.1&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;roughness&lt;/code&gt; [number]: Roughness level of chart. Default: &lt;code&gt;1&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;simplification&lt;/code&gt; [number]: Chart simplification. Default &lt;code&gt;0.2&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;stroke&lt;/code&gt; [string]: Color of bars' stroke. Default: &lt;code&gt;black&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;strokeWidth&lt;/code&gt; [number]: Size of bars' stroke. Default: &lt;code&gt;1&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;title&lt;/code&gt; [string]: Chart title. Optional.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;titleFontSize&lt;/code&gt; [string]: Font-size for chart title. Default: &lt;code&gt;'1rem'&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;tooltipFontSize&lt;/code&gt; [string]: Font-size for tooltip. Default: &lt;code&gt;'0.95rem'&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;xLabel&lt;/code&gt; [string]: Label for x-axis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;yLabel&lt;/code&gt; [string]: Label for y-axis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Contributors&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Acknowledgements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This library wouldn't be possible without the following people:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;License&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MIT License&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Copyright (c) 2019 Jared Wilber&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a copy of this software and associated documentation files (the &quot;Software&quot;), to deal in the Software without restriction, including without limitation the rights to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense, and/or sell copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the Software is furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The above copyright notice and this permission notice shall be included in all copies or substantial portions of the Software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;THE SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED &quot;AS IS&quot;, WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND NONINFRINGEMENT. IN NO EVENT SHALL THE AUTHORS OR COPYRIGHT HOLDERS BE LIABLE FOR ANY CLAIM, DAMAGES OR OTHER LIABILITY, WHETHER IN AN ACTION OF CONTRACT, TORT OR OTHERWISE, ARISING FROM, OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE SOFTWARE OR THE USE OR OTHER DEALINGS IN THE SOFTWARE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 16:02:56 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>feross</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars0.githubusercontent.com/u/8595819?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>jwilber/roughViz</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/jwilber/roughViz</og:url>
<og:description>Reusable JavaScript library for creating sketchy/hand-drawn styled charts in the browser. - jwilber/roughViz</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/jwilber/roughViz</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Apple changes Crimea map when viewed from Russia</title>
<link>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-50573069</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-50573069</guid>
<description>&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape no-caption full-width lead&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                &lt;img class=&quot;js-image-replace&quot; alt=&quot;Apple iPhone&quot; src=&quot;https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/320/cpsprodpb/816B/production/_109913133_mediaitem109913129.jpg&quot; width=&quot;976&quot; height=&quot;549&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image copyright&lt;/span&gt;
                 &lt;span class=&quot;story-image-copyright&quot;&gt;Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
        &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;story-body__introduction&quot;&gt;Apple has complied with Russian demands to show the annexed Crimean peninsula as part of Russian territory on its apps.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Russian forces annexed Crimea from Ukraine in March 2014, drawing international condemnation. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The region, which has a Russian-speaking majority, is now shown as Russian territory on Apple Maps and its Weather app, when viewed from Russia.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But the apps do not show it as part of any country when viewed elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape has-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
                 &lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image copyright&lt;/span&gt;
                 &lt;span class=&quot;story-image-copyright&quot;&gt;APPLE WEATHER&lt;/span&gt;
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
            &lt;figcaption class=&quot;media-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image caption&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;media-caption__text&quot;&gt;
                    The Apple Weather app now lists Crimea as part of Russia
                &lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape has-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
                 &lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image copyright&lt;/span&gt;
                 &lt;span class=&quot;story-image-copyright&quot;&gt;Apple Maps&lt;/span&gt;
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
            &lt;figcaption class=&quot;media-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image caption&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;media-caption__text&quot;&gt;
                    Apple Maps does not show a border between Crimea and Russia
                &lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;The State Duma, the Russian parliament's lower house, said in a statement: &quot;Crimea and Sevastopol now appear on Apple devices as Russian territory.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Russia treats the naval port city of Sevastopol as a separate region.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The BBC tested several iPhones in Moscow and it appears the change affects devices set up to use the Russian edition of Apple's App Store. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Apple had been in talks with Russia for several months over what the &lt;a href=&quot;http://duma.gov.ru/en/news/47107/&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link-external&quot;&gt;State Duma described as &quot;inaccuracy&quot;&lt;/a&gt; in the way Crimea was labelled.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The tech giant originally suggested it could show Crimea as undefined territory - part of neither Russia nor Ukraine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But Vasily Piskaryov, chairman of the Duma security and anti-corruption committee, said Apple had complied with the Russian constitution.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He said representatives of the company were reminded that labelling Crimea as part of Ukrainian territory was a criminal offence under Russian law, according to Interfax news agency.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;There is no going back,&quot; Mr Piskaryov said. &quot;Today, with Apple, the situation is closed - we have received everything we wanted.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He said Russia was always open to &quot;dialogue and constructive co-operation with foreign companies&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Apple has not yet commented on the decision.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Google, which also produces a popular Maps app, does not show Crimea as belonging to either Russia or Ukraine on its maps.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, it uses the Russian spelling of Crimean place names, rather than the Ukrainian spelling, on its maps in Russia.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most of the international community, including the EU and the US, does not recognise the annexation of Crimea to Russia. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The loss of Crimea is a deep wound for Ukrainians. Shortly after the peninsula was annexed in early 2014, a separate conflict broke out in the eastern Donetsk and Luhansk regions when separatists moved against the Ukrainian state. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ukraine and the West accuse Russia of sending its troops to the region and arming the separatists.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Moscow denies this but says that Russian volunteers are helping the rebels. More than 13,000 people have been killed in the conflict. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The BBC does not show Crimea as part of Russia on its maps, but shows a dotted line to mark disputed territory.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape no-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
        &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;story-body__crosshead&quot;&gt;You might also be interested in:&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul class=&quot;story-body__unordered-list&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-50507849&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link&quot;&gt;Russia bans sale of gadgets without Russian-made software&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-50259597&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link&quot;&gt;Russia introduces new internet controls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-with-caption&quot; readability=&quot;-24&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;player-with-placeholder&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img class=&quot;media-placeholder player-with-placeholder__image narrative-video-placeholder&quot; src=&quot;https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/images/ic/720x405/p077b9cz.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Media playback is unsupported on your device&lt;/p&gt;
      
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;figcaption class=&quot;media-with-caption__caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Media caption&lt;/span&gt;How Russia wants to control the internet&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 15:28:55 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mzs</dc:creator>
<og:title>Apple changes Crimea map to meet Russian demands</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>Apple Maps now shows Crimea - annexed from Ukraine in 2014 - as part of Russia, when viewed there.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-50573069</og:url>
<og:image>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/816B/production/_109913133_mediaitem109913129.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-GB</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-50573069</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Apocalyptic Claims About Climate Change Are Wrong</title>
<link>https://www.forbes.com/sites/michaelshellenberger/2019/11/25/why-everything-they-say-about-climate-change-is-wrong/#4dd5de4912d6</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.forbes.com/sites/michaelshellenberger/2019/11/25/why-everything-they-say-about-climate-change-is-wrong/#4dd5de4912d6</guid>
<description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://specials-images.forbesimg.com/imageserve/5ddb40bc2c886a0007ecfb87/960x0.jpg?fit=scale&quot; alt=&quot;Bill McKibben, Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez, Greta Thunberg, and Zion Lights of Extinction Rebellion&quot; data-height=&quot;234&quot; data-width=&quot;842&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;color-body light-text&quot;&gt;Climate scientists are speaking out against grossly exaggerated claims about global warming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;small&gt;Getty&lt;/small&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;speakable-paragraph&quot;&gt;Environmental journalists and advocates have in recent weeks made a number of apocalyptic predictions about the impact of climate change. Bill McKibben &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/billmckibben/status/1198375629638586373?s=20&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;color-link&quot;&gt;suggested&lt;/a&gt; climate-driven fires in Australia had made koalas “functionally extinct.” Extinction Rebellion &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZMtVCm5V7X4&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;color-link&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; “Billions will die” and “Life on Earth is dying.” &lt;em&gt;Vice&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/8xwygg/the-collapse-of-civilization-may-have-already-begun&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;color-link&quot;&gt;claimed&lt;/a&gt; the “collapse of civilization may have already begun.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Few have underscored the threat more than student climate activist Greta Thunberg and Green New Deal sponsor Rep. Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez. The latter &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usatoday.com/story/news/politics/onpolitics/2019/01/22/ocasio-cortez-climate-change-alarm/2642481002/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;color-link&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt;, “The world is going to end in 12 years if we don't address climate change.” &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/One-Too-Small-Make-Difference/dp/0141991747&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;color-link&quot;&gt;Says&lt;/a&gt; Thunberg in her new book, “Around 2030 we will be in a position to set off an irreversible chain reaction beyond human control that will lead to the end of our civilization as we know it.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, scientists themselves make apocalyptic claims. “It’s difficult to see how we could accommodate a billion people or even half of that,” if Earth warms four degrees, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2019/may/18/climate-crisis-heat-is-on-global-heating-four-degrees-2100-change-way-we-live&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;color-link&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; one earlier this year. “The potential for multi-breadbasket failure is increasing,” &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/08/08/climate/climate-change-food-supply.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;color-link&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; another. If sea levels rise as much as the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change predicts, another scientist &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/science/archive/2019/09/ipcc-sea-level-rise-report/598765/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;color-link&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt;, “It will be an unmanageable problem.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apocalyptic statements like these have real-world impacts. In September, a group of British psychologists &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/article/us-britain-climate-children/children-suffering-eco-anxiety-over-climate-change-say-psychologists-idUSKBN1W42CF&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;color-link&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; children are increasingly suffering from anxiety from the frightening discourse around climate change. In October, an activist with Extinction Rebellion (”XR”) — an environmental group founded in 2018 to commit civil disobedience to draw awareness to the threat its founders and supporters say climate change poses to human existence — and a videographer, were &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kHOr2WH7V1k&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;color-link&quot;&gt;kicked and beaten&lt;/a&gt; in a London Tube station by angry commuters. And last week, an XR co-founder &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.independent.co.uk/news/world/europe/extinction-rebellion-founder-roger-hallam-holocaust-genocide-nazis-a9211781.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;color-link&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; a genocide like the Holocaust was “happening again, on a far greater scale, and in plain sight” from climate change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Climate change is an issue I care passionately about and have dedicated a significant portion of my life to addressing. I have been &lt;a href=&quot;http://environmentalprogress.org/founder-president&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;color-link&quot;&gt;politically active&lt;/a&gt; on the issue for over 20 years and have researched and written about it for 17 years. Over the last four years, my organization, Environmental Progress, has worked with some of the world’s leading climate scientists to &lt;a href=&quot;http://environmentalprogress.org/mission&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;color-link&quot;&gt;prevent&lt;/a&gt; carbon emissions from rising. So far, we’ve helped prevent emissions increasing the equivalent of adding 24 million cars to the road. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also care about getting the facts and science right and have in recent months corrected inaccurate and apocalyptic news media coverage of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/michaelshellenberger/2019/08/26/why-everything-they-say-about-the-amazon-including-that-its-the-lungs-of-the-world-is-wrong/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;color-link&quot;&gt;fires in the Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/michaelshellenberger/2019/11/04/why-everything-they-say-about-california-fires--including-that-climate-matters-most--is-wrong/#d8b37c4cb66f&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;color-link&quot;&gt;fires in California&lt;/a&gt;, both of which have been improperly presented as resulting primarily from climate change. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Journalists and activists alike have an obligation to describe environmental problems honestly and accurately, even if they fear doing so will reduce their news value or salience with the public. There is good evidence that the catastrophist framing of climate change is self-defeating because it alienates and &lt;a href=&quot;https://oxfordre.com/climatescience/view/10.1093/acrefore/9780190228620.001.0001/acrefore-9780190228620-e-306?rskey=8FqRAO&amp;amp;result=1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;color-link&quot;&gt;polarizes&lt;/a&gt; many people. And exaggerating climate change risks distracting us from other important issues including ones we might have more near-term control over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel the need to say this up-front because I want the issues I’m about to raise to be taken seriously and not dismissed by those who label as “climate deniers” or “climate delayers” anyone who pushes back against exaggeration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that out of the way, let’s look whether the science supports what’s being said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, no credible scientific body has ever said climate change threatens the collapse of civilization much less the extinction of the human species. “‘Our children are going to die in the next 10 to 20 years.’ What’s the scientific basis for these claims?” BBC’s Andrew Neil &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?time_continue=7&amp;amp;v=pO1TTcETyuU&amp;amp;feature=emb_logo&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;color-link&quot;&gt;asked&lt;/a&gt; a visibly uncomfortable XR spokesperson last month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“These claims have been disputed, admittedly,” she said. “There are some scientists who are agreeing and some who are saying it’s not true. But the overall issue is that these deaths are going to happen.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“But most scientists don’t agree with this,” said Neil. “I looked through IPCC reports and see no reference to billions of people going to die, or children in 20 years. &lt;em&gt;How&lt;/em&gt; would they die?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Mass migration around the world already taking place due to prolonged drought in countries, particularly in South Asia. There are wildfires in Indonesia, the Amazon rainforest, Siberia, the Arctic,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But in saying so, the XR spokesperson had grossly misrepresented the science. “There is robust evidence of disasters displacing people worldwide,” &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ipcc.ch/site/assets/uploads/2018/02/WG1AR5_Chapter13_FINAL.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;color-link&quot;&gt;notes&lt;/a&gt; IPCC, “but limited evidence that climate change or sea-level rise is the direct cause” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What about “mass migration”? “The majority of resultant population movements tend to occur &lt;em&gt;within&lt;/em&gt; the borders of affected countries,&quot; says IPCC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not like climate doesn’t matter. It’s that climate change is outweighed by other factors. Earlier this year, researchers &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/31189956&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;color-link&quot;&gt;found&lt;/a&gt; that climate “has affected organized armed conflict within countries. However, other drivers, such as low socioeconomic development and low capabilities of the state, are judged to be substantially more influential.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last January, after climate scientists criticized Rep. Ocasio-Cortez for saying the world would end in 12 years, her spokesperson &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.axios.com/climate-change-scientists-comment-ocasio-cortez-12-year-deadline-c4ba1f99-bc76-42ac-8b93-e4eaa926938d.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;color-link&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; &quot;We can quibble about the phraseology, whether it's existential or cataclysmic.” He added, “We're seeing lots of [climate change-related] problems that are already impacting lives.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That last part may be true, but it’s also true that economic development has made us less vulnerable, which is why there was a 99.7% &lt;a href=&quot;https://ourworldindata.org/natural-disasters&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;color-link&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;decline&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in the death toll from natural disasters since its peak in 1931. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1931, 3.7 million people died from natural disasters. In 2018, just 11,000 did.  And that decline &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nasa.gov/topics/earth/features/upsDownsGlobalWarming.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;color-link&quot;&gt;occurred&lt;/a&gt; over a period when the global population &lt;em&gt;quadrupled&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What about sea level rise? IPCC estimates sea level could rise two feet (0.6 meters) by 2100. Does that sound apocalyptic or even “unmanageable”?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider that one-third of the Netherlands is below sea level, and some areas &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.researchgate.net/publication/283417310_First_National_Report_on_Forest_Genetic_Resources_for_Food_and_AgricultureThe_Netherlands_country_report_for_the_FAO_first_state_of_the_world's_forest_genetic_resources_for_food_and_agriculture_Minist&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;color-link&quot;&gt;are&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;seven&lt;/em&gt; meters below sea level. You might object that Netherlands is rich while Bangladesh is poor. But the Netherlands adapted to living below sea level &lt;em&gt;400 years ago.&lt;/em&gt; Technology has improved a bit since then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What about claims of crop failure, famine, and mass death? That’s science fiction, not science. Humans today produce enough food for 10 billion people, or 25% more than we need, and scientific bodies predict increases in that share, not declines. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The United Nations Food and Agriculture Organization (FAO) &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/3/I8429EN/i8429en.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;color-link&quot;&gt;forecasts&lt;/a&gt; crop yields increasing 30% by 2050. And the poorest parts of the world, like sub-Saharan Africa, are expected to see increases of 80 to 90%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nobody is suggesting climate change won’t negatively impact crop yields. It could. But such declines should be put in perspective. Wheat yields increased 100 to 300% around the world since the 1960s, while a study of 30 models &lt;a href=&quot;http://eprints.whiterose.ac.uk/85540/1/Main_Asseng_2014-9-22.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;color-link&quot;&gt;found&lt;/a&gt; that yields would decline by 6% for every one degree Celsius increase in temperature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rates of future yield growth depend far more on whether poor nations get access to tractors, irrigation, and fertilizer than on climate change, says FAO.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of this helps explain why IPCC anticipates climate change will have a modest impact on economic growth. By 2100, IPCC projects the global economy will be 300 to 500% larger than it is today. Both &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ipcc.ch/site/assets/uploads/2018/05/SYR_AR5_FINAL_full_wcover.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;color-link&quot;&gt;IPCC&lt;/a&gt; and the Nobel-winning Yale economist, William Nordhaus, &lt;a href=&quot;https://data.nber.org/reporter/2017number3/nordhaus.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;color-link&quot;&gt;predict&lt;/a&gt; that warming of 2.5°C and 4°C would reduce gross domestic product (GDP) by 2% and 5% over that same period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does this mean we shouldn’t worry about climate change? Not at all. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the reasons I work on climate change is because I worry about the impact it could have on endangered species. Climate change &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.un.org/sustainabledevelopment/blog/2019/05/nature-decline-unprecedented-report/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;color-link&quot;&gt;may&lt;/a&gt; threaten one million species globally and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0006320717311539?via%3Dihub&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;color-link&quot;&gt;half&lt;/a&gt; of all mammals, reptiles, and amphibians in diverse places like the Albertine Rift in central Africa, home to the endangered mountain gorilla.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it’s not the case that “we’re putting our own survival in danger” through extinctions, as Elizabeth Kolbert &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2014/02/16/books/review/the-sixth-extinction-by-elizabeth-kolbert.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;color-link&quot;&gt;claimed&lt;/a&gt; in her book, &lt;em&gt;Sixth Extinction&lt;/em&gt;. As tragic as animal extinctions are, they do not threaten human civilization. If we want to save endangered species, we need to do so because we care about wildlife for spiritual, ethical, or aesthetic reasons, not survival ones.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And exaggerating the risk, and suggesting climate change is more important than things like habitat destruction, are counterproductive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, Australia’s fires are not driving koalas extinct, as Bill McKibben suggested. The main scientific body that tracks the species, the International Union for the Conservation of Nature, or IUCN, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.iucnredlist.org/species/16892/21960344#threats&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;color-link&quot;&gt;labels&lt;/a&gt; the koala “vulnerable,” which is one level less threatened than “endangered,” two levels less than “critically endangered,” and three less than “extinct” in the wild. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Should we worry about koalas? Absolutely! They are amazing animals and their numbers have declined to around 300,000. But they face far bigger &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.iucnredlist.org/species/16892/21960344#threats&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;color-link&quot;&gt;threats&lt;/a&gt; such as the destruction of habitat, disease, bushfires, and invasive species. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think of it this way. The climate could change dramatically — and we could still save koalas. Conversely, the climate could change only modestly — and koalas could still go extinct. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The monomaniacal focus on climate distracts our attention from other threats to koalas and opportunities for protecting them, like protecting and expanding their habitat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for fire, one of Australia’s leading scientists on the issue &lt;a href=&quot;https://theconversation.com/climate-change-and-bushfires-youre-missing-the-point-19649&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;color-link&quot;&gt;says&lt;/a&gt;, “Bushfire losses can be explained by the increasing exposure of dwellings to fire-prone bushlands. No other influences need be invoked. So even if climate change had played some small role in modulating recent bushfires, and we cannot rule this out, any such effects on risk to property are clearly swamped by the changes in exposure.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nor are the fires solely due to drought, which is common in Australia, and exceptional this year. “Climate change is playing its role here,” &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.abc.net.au/news/2019-09-10/more-than-climate-change-driving-queensland-fires/11493950&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;color-link&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; Richard Thornton of the Bushfire and Natural Hazards Cooperative Research Centre in Australia, “but it's not the cause of these fires.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same is true for fires in the United States. In 2017, scientists modeled 37 different regions and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pnas.org/content/pnas/114/52/13750.full.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;color-link&quot;&gt;found&lt;/a&gt; “humans may not only influence fire regimes but their presence can actually override, or swamp out, the effects of climate.” Of the 10 variables that influence fire, “none were as significant… as the anthropogenic variables,” such as building homes near, and managing fires and wood fuel growth within, forests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Climate scientists are starting to push back against exaggerations by activists, journalists, and other scientists. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“While many species are threatened with extinction,” &lt;a href=&quot;https://physicsworld.com/a/climate-scientist-or-climate-activist-wheres-the-line/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;color-link&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; Stanford’s Ken Caldeira, “climate change does not threaten human extinction... I would not like to see us motivating people to do the right thing by making them believe something that is false.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I asked the Australian climate scientist Tom Wigley what he thought of the claim that climate change threatens civilization. “It really does bother me because it’s wrong,” he said. “All these young people have been misinformed. And partly it’s Greta Thunberg’s fault. Not deliberately. But she’s wrong.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But don’t scientists and activists need to exaggerate in order to get the public’s attention?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I’m reminded of what [late Stanford University climate scientist] Steve Schneider used to say,” Wigley replied. “He used to say that as a scientist, we shouldn’t really be concerned about the way we slant things in communicating with people out on the street who might need a little push in a certain direction to realize that this is a serious problem. Steve didn’t have any qualms about speaking in that biased way. I don’t quite agree with that.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wigley started working on climate science full-time in 1975 and created one of the first climate models (MAGICC) in 1987. It remains one of the main climate models in use today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“When I talk to the general public,” he said, “I point out some of the things that might make projections of warming less &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; the things that might make them more. I always try to present both sides.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part of what bothers me about the apocalyptic rhetoric by climate activists is that it is often accompanied by demands that poor nations be denied the cheap sources of energy they need to develop. I have found that many scientists share my concerns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“If you want to minimize carbon dioxide in the atmosphere in 2070  you might want to accelerate the burning of coal in India today,” MIT climate scientist Kerry Emanuel said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It doesn’t sound like it makes sense. Coal is terrible for carbon. But it’s by burning a lot of coal that they make themselves wealthier, and by making themselves wealthier they have fewer children, and you don’t have as many people burning carbon, you might be better off in 2070.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emanuel and Wigley say the extreme rhetoric is making political agreement on climate change harder. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You’ve got to come up with some kind of middle ground where you do reasonable things to mitigate the risk and try at the same time to lift people out of poverty and make them more resilient,” said Emanuel. “We shouldn’t be forced to choose between lifting people out of poverty and doing something for the climate.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happily, there is a plenty of middle ground between climate apocalypse and climate denial.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 15:23:59 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>hsnewman</dc:creator>
<og:title>Why Apocalyptic Claims About Climate Change Are Wrong</og:title>
<og:image>https://thumbor.forbes.com/thumbor/600x315/https%3A%2F%2Fspecials-images.forbesimg.com%2Fimageserve%2F5ddb40bc2c886a0007ecfb87%2F960x0.jpg%3FcropX1%3D195%26cropX2%3D612%26cropY1%3D0%26cropY2%3D233</og:image>
<og:url>https://www.forbes.com/sites/michaelshellenberger/2019/11/25/why-everything-they-say-about-climate-change-is-wrong/</og:url>
<og:description>Climate change is real but it's not the end of the world. And increasingly extreme statements by activists undermine environmental progress, say climate scientists.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.forbes.com/sites/michaelshellenberger/2019/11/25/why-everything-they-say-about-climate-change-is-wrong/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Show HN: I made an open-source anonymous email forwarding service</title>
<link>https://anonaddy.com/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://anonaddy.com/</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;meta charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;viewport&quot; content=&quot;width=device-width, initial-scale=1, shrink-to-fit=no&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta http-equiv=&quot;x-ua-compatible&quot; content=&quot;ie=edge&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;author&quot; content=&quot;AnonAddy&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;description&quot; content=&quot;Create unlimited aliases for free. Protect your email from spam using disposable addresses. Encrypt forwarded emails with PGP encryption using this service.&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:title&quot; content=&quot;Free, Open-source Anonymous Email Forwarding | AnonAddy&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:url&quot; content=&quot;https://anonaddy.com/&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:description&quot; content=&quot;Create unlimited aliases for free. Protect your email from spam using disposable addresses. Encrypt forwarded emails with PGP encryption using this service.&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:image&quot; content=&quot;https://anonaddy.com/og-image.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:type&quot; content=&quot;website&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;twitter:card&quot; content=&quot;summary&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;twitter:site&quot; content=&quot;@AnonAddy&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;twitter:title&quot; content=&quot;Free, Open-source Anonymous Email Forwarding | AnonAddy&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;twitter:description&quot; content=&quot;Create unlimited aliases for free. Protect your email from spam using disposable addresses. Encrypt forwarded emails with PGP encryption using this service.&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;twitter:image&quot; content=&quot;https://anonaddy.com/og-image.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;msapplication-TileColor&quot; content=&quot;#da532c&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;theme-color&quot; content=&quot;#19216C&quot;/&gt;&lt;title&gt;Free, Open-source Anonymous Email Forwarding - AnonAddy&lt;/title&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;home&quot; href=&quot;https://anonaddy.com&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;apple-touch-icon&quot; sizes=&quot;180x180&quot; href=&quot;/apple-touch-icon.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;icon&quot; type=&quot;image/png&quot; sizes=&quot;32x32&quot; href=&quot;/favicon-32x32.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;icon&quot; type=&quot;image/png&quot; sizes=&quot;16x16&quot; href=&quot;/favicon-16x16.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;manifest&quot; href=&quot;/site.webmanifest&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;mask-icon&quot; href=&quot;/safari-pinned-tab.svg&quot; color=&quot;#5BBAD5&quot;/&gt;&lt;link href=&quot;/blog/feed.atom&quot; type=&quot;application/atom+xml&quot; rel=&quot;alternate&quot; title=&quot;AnonAddy Atom Feed&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; href=&quot;/assets/build/css/main.css?id=69a2ca437d1b972c59b7&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot;/&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body class=&quot;gradient text-white leading-normal font-sans&quot; id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot; readability=&quot;49.075251601098&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bg-indigo-900&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;container mx-auto px-5 py-4 md:py-0 flex justify-center items-center md:h-16&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sale Alert! Until Friday get 50% off your first year with coupon code - &lt;span class=&quot;block md:inline-block font-semibold&quot;&gt;BLACKFRIDAY50&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;header class=&quot;flex items-center gradient lg:h-20 py-4&quot; role=&quot;banner&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;container flex items-center max-w-8xl mx-auto px-4 lg:px-8&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;flex items-center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://anonaddy.com/&quot; title=&quot;AnonAddy home&quot; class=&quot;inline-flex items-center&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;h-8 mr-3&quot; src=&quot;https://anonaddy.com/assets/img/logo.svg&quot; alt=&quot;AnonAddy logo&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/header&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;label for=&quot;menu-handle&quot; class=&quot;hidden&quot;&gt;Menu&lt;/label&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;section class=&quot;bg-white border-b border-grey-100 py-8&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;container max-w-5xl mx-auto m-8&quot;&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;flex flex-wrap&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;w-full sm:w-1/2 p-6&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;text-3xl text-grey-800 font-bold leading-none mb-3&quot;&gt;1. Register Your Username&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-grey-600 mb-4&quot;&gt;Let's say your username is &lt;strong&gt;johndoe&lt;/strong&gt;. You can now use *@johndoe.anonaddy.com (or .me) as your email. Where * denotes any valid local part for an email address.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-grey-600&quot;&gt;If you would like to remain anonymous choose a username that is not linked to your real name or identify and that you haven't used anywhere else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;w-full sm:w-1/2 p-6&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;w-full sm:h-64 mx-auto&quot; src=&quot;https://anonaddy.com/assets/img/register.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Register&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;flex flex-wrap flex-col-reverse sm:flex-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;w-full sm:w-1/2 p-6 mt-6&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;w-full sm:h-64 mx-auto&quot; src=&quot;https://anonaddy.com/assets/img/email_aliases.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Email Aliases&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;w-full sm:w-1/2 p-6 mt-6&quot; readability=&quot;10.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;align-middle&quot; readability=&quot;16&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;text-3xl text-grey-800 font-bold leading-none mb-3&quot;&gt;2. Create Aliases On The Fly&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-grey-600 mb-4&quot;&gt;Next time you are signing up to a website or newsletter, simply make up a new alias and enter that instead of your real email address.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-grey-600 mb-4&quot;&gt;For example, if you are on vuejs.org and you want to sign up to their newsletter you could simply enter &lt;strong&gt;vuejs@johndoe.anonaddy.com&lt;/strong&gt; (or .me).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-grey-600 mb-4&quot;&gt;We'll automatically create the alias in your dashboard as soon as it receives its first email. You can reply to emails anonymously too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;flex flex-wrap&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;w-full sm:w-1/2 p-6&quot; readability=&quot;13&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;text-3xl text-grey-800 font-bold leading-none mb-3&quot;&gt;3. Manage Aliases&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-grey-600 mb-4&quot;&gt;Let's say a spammer gets hold of one of your aliases and starts sending unsolicited email to it. You can simply toggle a switch in your dashboard and deactivate that alias.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-grey-600 mb-4&quot;&gt;Our system will then silently &lt;strong&gt;discard&lt;/strong&gt; any further emails and you won't be forwarded anything else for that alias.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-grey-600 mb-4&quot;&gt;You can also delete the alias. Then our system will &lt;strong&gt;reject&lt;/strong&gt; any emails and respond with an error.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;w-full sm:w-1/2 p-6&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;w-full sm:h-64 mx-auto&quot; src=&quot;https://anonaddy.com/assets/img/dashboard.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Manage Aliases&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section class=&quot;bg-white border-b border-grey-100 py-8&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;container max-w-5xl mx-auto m-8&quot;&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;flex flex-wrap flex-col-reverse sm:flex-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;w-full sm:w-1/2 p-6 mt-6&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;w-full sm:h-64 mx-auto&quot; src=&quot;https://anonaddy.com/assets/img/browsers.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Browser Extension&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;w-full sm:w-1/2 p-6 mt-6&quot; readability=&quot;7.7359550561798&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;align-middle&quot; readability=&quot;10.921348314607&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;text-3xl text-grey-800 font-bold leading-none mb-3&quot;&gt;Browser Extension&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-grey-600 mb-4&quot;&gt;Generate UUID aliases in a couple of clicks straight from your browser using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/anonaddy/browser-extension&quot; class=&quot;text-indigo-700&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;open-source&lt;/a&gt; browser extension.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-grey-600 b-4&quot;&gt;The extension is available for download on &lt;a href=&quot;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-GB/firefox/addon/anonaddy/&quot; class=&quot;text-indigo-700&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Firefox&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/anonaddy/iadbdpnoknmbdeolbapdackdcogdmjpe&quot; class=&quot;text-indigo-700&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Chrome&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-grey-600 mb-4&quot;&gt;Also available on other chromium based browsers such as Brave and Vivaldi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;flex flex-wrap&quot; readability=&quot;9.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;w-full sm:w-1/2 p-6&quot; readability=&quot;14&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;text-3xl text-grey-800 font-bold leading-none mb-3&quot;&gt;GPG/OpenPGP Encryption&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-grey-600 mb-4&quot;&gt;Bring your own GPG/OpenPGP public keys and add them per recipient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-grey-600&quot;&gt;You can then easily toggle encryption on and off. With encryption on, all forwarded messages will be encrypted with your public key. Only you will be able to decrypt them with the corresponding private key.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-grey-600&quot;&gt;This is great if you are using Gmail or Outlook and wish to prevent any inbox snooping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;w-full sm:w-1/2 p-6&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;w-full sm:h-64 mx-auto&quot; src=&quot;https://anonaddy.com/assets/img/fingerprint.svg&quot; alt=&quot;GPG/OpenPGP Encryption&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;flex flex-wrap flex-col-reverse sm:flex-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;w-full sm:w-1/2 p-6 mt-6&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;w-full sm:h-64 mx-auto&quot; src=&quot;https://anonaddy.com/assets/img/domains.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Custom Domains&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;w-full sm:w-1/2 p-6 mt-6&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;align-middle&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;text-3xl text-grey-800 font-bold leading-none mb-3&quot;&gt;Custom Domains&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-grey-600 mb-4&quot;&gt;If you have your own domain you can add it and use it as a catch-all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-grey-600 b-4&quot;&gt;You'll be able to use it exactly like your username subdomain aliases e.g. &lt;strong&gt;alias@example.com&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-grey-600 mb-4&quot;&gt;You can then manage your aliases and deactivate/delete any that start receiving spam!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;flex flex-wrap&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;w-full sm:w-1/2 p-6&quot; readability=&quot;13&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;text-3xl text-grey-800 font-bold leading-none mb-3&quot;&gt;Generate UUID Aliases&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-grey-600 mb-4&quot;&gt;If you don't like the fact that all your aliases contain your username then you can generate unique aliases from your dashboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-grey-600 mb-4&quot;&gt;The generated aliases will look something like this &lt;strong&gt;94960540-f914-42e0-9c50-6faa7a385384@anonaddy.me&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-grey-600 mb-4&quot;&gt;This prevents anyone linking ownership of the alias to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;w-full sm:w-1/2 p-6&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;w-full sm:h-64 mx-auto&quot; src=&quot;https://anonaddy.com/assets/img/anonymous.svg&quot; alt=&quot;UUID Aliases&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;flex flex-wrap flex-col-reverse sm:flex-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;w-full sm:w-1/2 p-6 mt-6&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;w-full sm:h-64 mx-auto&quot; src=&quot;https://anonaddy.com/assets/img/recipients.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Multiple Recipients&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;w-full sm:w-1/2 p-6 mt-6&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;align-middle&quot; readability=&quot;13&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;text-3xl text-grey-800 font-bold leading-none mb-3&quot;&gt;Multiple Recipients Per Alias&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-grey-600 mb-4&quot;&gt;If you'd like an alias to go to more than one recipient you can easily add multiple recipients from your dashboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-grey-600 mb-4&quot;&gt;You can even add recipients to an alias as it is created by doing &lt;strong&gt;alias+2.3.4@user.anonaddy.com&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-grey-600 mb-4&quot;&gt;Where 2,3 and 4 are the keys for existing recipients in your account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;flex flex-wrap&quot; readability=&quot;9.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;w-full sm:w-1/2 p-6&quot; readability=&quot;14&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;text-3xl text-grey-800 font-bold leading-none mb-3&quot;&gt;Add Additional Usernames&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-grey-600 mb-4&quot;&gt;You can add additional usernames to your account and use them exactly like the one you signed up with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-grey-600 mb-4&quot;&gt;So if you signed up as johndoe you can add johnsmith as an additional username and then use &lt;strong&gt;anyalias@johnsmith.anonaddy.com&lt;/strong&gt; too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-grey-600 mb-4&quot;&gt;This can be used to compartmentalise your aliases. You could have a username for work emails a different one for personal emails etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;w-full sm:w-1/2 p-6&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;w-full sm:h-64 mx-auto&quot; src=&quot;https://anonaddy.com/assets/img/usernames.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Additional Usernames&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;flex flex-wrap flex-col-reverse sm:flex-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;w-full sm:w-1/2 p-6 mt-6&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;w-full sm:h-64 mx-auto&quot; src=&quot;https://anonaddy.com/assets/img/api.svg&quot; alt=&quot;API&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;w-full sm:w-1/2 p-6 mt-6&quot; readability=&quot;7.2&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;align-middle&quot; readability=&quot;9.9&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;text-3xl text-grey-800 font-bold leading-none mb-3&quot;&gt;API Access&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-grey-600 mb-4&quot;&gt;Manage your aliases, recipients, domains and additional usernames using the AnonAddy API.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-grey-600 mb-4&quot;&gt;In order to use the API you first need to generate an API access token in your account settings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-grey-600 mb-4&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://app.anonaddy.com/docs/&quot; class=&quot;text-indigo-700&quot;&gt;View API documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section id=&quot;pricing&quot; class=&quot;bg-grey-50 py-8&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;container mx-auto px-2 pt-4 pb-12 text-grey-800&quot;&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;flex flex-col md:flex-row justify-center pt-12 my-12 sm:my-4&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;flex flex-col w-5/6 lg:w-1/4 mx-auto lg:mx-0 rounded-none lg:rounded-l-lg bg-white mt-4&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;flex-1 bg-white text-grey-600 rounded-t rounded-b-none overflow-hidden shadow&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Free&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;px-8 pt-8 text-base my-0 flex justify-center&quot; readability=&quot;31&quot;&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unlimited&lt;/strong&gt; Standard Aliases&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;20&lt;/strong&gt; UUID Aliases&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2&lt;/strong&gt; Recipients&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Public Key &lt;strong&gt;Per Recipient&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;API&lt;/strong&gt; Access&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10MB&lt;/strong&gt; Monthly Bandwidth&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;flex flex-col w-5/6 lg:w-1/3 mx-auto lg:mx-0 rounded-lg bg-white mt-4 md:-mt-6 shadow-lg z-10&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;flex-1 bg-white rounded-t rounded-b-none overflow-hidden shadow&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lite&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;px-8 pt-8 text-base my-0 flex justify-center&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Everything&lt;/strong&gt; in Free&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;50&lt;/strong&gt; UUID Aliases&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1&lt;/strong&gt; Custom Domain&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1&lt;/strong&gt; Additional Username&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5&lt;/strong&gt; Recipients&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;20 daily&lt;/strong&gt; Anonymous Replies&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Access to &lt;strong&gt;Paid Plan Settings&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Additional&lt;/strong&gt; Alias Domain&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Priority&lt;/strong&gt; Email Queue&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;50MB&lt;/strong&gt; Monthly Bandwidth&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;flex-none mt-auto bg-white rounded-b rounded-t-none overflow-hidden shadow p-4&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;text-base text-grey-500 font-normal&quot;&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;1 &lt;span class=&quot;text-base text-grey-500 font-normal&quot;&gt;/ month&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;text-sm text-grey-500 mb-0 w-full text-center&quot;&gt;Billed Yearly&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;flex flex-col w-5/6 lg:w-1/4 mx-auto lg:mx-0 rounded-none lg:rounded-l-lg bg-white mt-4&quot; readability=&quot;6.1578947368421&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;flex-1 bg-white rounded-t rounded-b-none overflow-hidden shadow&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pro&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;px-8 pt-8 text-base my-0 flex justify-center&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Everything&lt;/strong&gt; in Free&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unlimited&lt;/strong&gt; UUID Aliases&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5&lt;/strong&gt; Custom Domains&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3&lt;/strong&gt; Additional Usernames&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;20&lt;/strong&gt; Recipients&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;100 daily&lt;/strong&gt; Anonymous Replies&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Access to &lt;strong&gt;Paid Plan Settings&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Additional&lt;/strong&gt; Alias Domain&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Priority&lt;/strong&gt; Email Queue&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;500MB&lt;/strong&gt; Monthly Bandwidth&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;flex-none mt-auto bg-white rounded-b rounded-t-none overflow-hidden shadow p-4&quot; readability=&quot;5.9661016949153&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;text-base text-grey-500 font-normal&quot;&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;3 &lt;span class=&quot;text-base text-grey-500 font-normal&quot;&gt;/ month&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;text-sm text-grey-500 mb-0 w-full text-center&quot;&gt;Billed Yearly, $4 Billed Monthly&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section class=&quot;container flex flex-col items-center py-6&quot; readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;my-3 text-sm&quot;&gt;Get notified about new features!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/section&gt;&lt;footer class=&quot;gradient&quot; role=&quot;contentinfo&quot;&gt;
&lt;/footer&gt;&lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 14:33:20 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>willbrowning</dc:creator>
<og:title>Free, Open-source Anonymous Email Forwarding | AnonAddy</og:title>
<og:url>https://anonaddy.com/</og:url>
<og:description>Create unlimited aliases for free. Protect your email from spam using disposable addresses. Encrypt forwarded emails with PGP encryption using this service.</og:description>
<og:image>https://anonaddy.com/og-image.png</og:image>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://anonaddy.com/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Off-Grid Cyberdeck: Raspberry Pi Recovery Kit</title>
<link>https://back7.co/home/raspberry-pi-recovery-kit</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://back7.co/home/raspberry-pi-recovery-kit</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt; The concept often feels like something out of a science fiction movie or a doomsday prepper’s handbook- and while this device can work in both scenarios, it’s also about understanding resiliency for your projects and being a good steward of the systems in place today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;I’ve been posting the progress of this project on Instagram, Twitter, and Facebook all month, and this is my full build log of the project. You’ll find the parts list at the bottom of this article. They are affiliate links that help me make more cool stuff, and by using them you don’t pay any more than usual- so thank you for supporting my projects, even just a little bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;I posted about a month ago on my retrospective from four years ago when I made the Raspberry Pi Field Unit, which was generously shared on Hackaday then, and I posted a follow-up on Reddit several weeks back. There’s a few common issues that I came across:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul data-rte-list=&quot;default&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;There was no keyboard!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;The solution isn’t truly waterproof&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Numerous holes in the case would make ingress of water or moisture even more common&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;My wiring on the original project was a mess&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;The display took up too much room and was too hard to mount&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;The project was too hard to maintain or fix&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Several connectors were very fragile&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Material choices for the internal structure were not good- I picked plastics that were too brittle, and the overall structure was poor&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;No EM shielding from the preppers in the audience&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;I could go on and on, but those are the key points. I’ll address each of these below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;No keyboard&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;In 2014 I wasn’t aware of any reduced footprint keyboards, and I did look. Even looking today there wasn’t any that fit common search terms, but as a lurker in /r/mechanicalkeyboards I did find out and had already bought a Plaid keyboard kit. As luck turns out, it was a perfect fit. It’s my first orthagonal keyboard, but it matches the cyberdeck feel of the project. I’m using DSA Beyond keycaps and Cherry MX Silent switches, all hand-soldered. More pics are here, but here’s a shot below:&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 12:50:39 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>gbrown_</dc:creator>
<og:title>Off-Grid Cyberdeck! The Raspberry Pi Recovery Kit — BACK7.CO</og:title>
<og:url>https://back7.co/home/raspberry-pi-recovery-kit</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>Building Internet-connected things seems obvious today, but what about when there’s no Internet? &amp;nbsp;The concept often feels like something out of a science fiction movie or a doomsday prepper’s handbook- and while this device can work in both scenarios, it’s also about understanding resilien</og:description>
<og:image>http://static1.squarespace.com/static/5caa4adb92441be122fcead4/5d7a9da8eb857f5277e8f2d6/5d7a9da8eb857f5277e8f353/1573103301595/JAY01431.jpg?format=1500w</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://back7.co/home/raspberry-pi-recovery-kit</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Lessons learned building an ML trading system</title>
<link>https://www.tradientblog.com/2019/11/lessons-learned-building-an-ml-trading-system-that-turned-5k-into-200k/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.tradientblog.com/2019/11/lessons-learned-building-an-ml-trading-system-that-turned-5k-into-200k/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;One of my recent side projects was building an automated trading system for the crypto markets. To be fair, I probably spent more time on this than on my full-time job, so calling it a side project may not be completely accurate. The internet is full of people ready to teach you about trading. Most are trying to sell you something, and many are mistaking random chance for skill. Coming from a technical background in scientific research and software engineering, I tried to ignore anything with little scientific validity, like technical analysis, or anything that looked like marketing BS. After a lot of iterations, I managed to build and deploy a system that turned my &lt;code&gt;$5k&lt;/code&gt; investment into around &lt;code&gt;$200k&lt;/code&gt; of pre-tax profit over a 12-month period while staying largely market neutral, i.e. not relying on ups or downs. The best run was a &lt;strong&gt;4-month period without a single losing day&lt;/strong&gt;. I did have losses on shorter time scales, but very rarely on a daily level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this post I want share some of the problems encountered and lessons learned. I will try to strike a balance between providing useful information while not revealing specific implementation details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;can-we-predict-the-market&quot;&gt;Can we predict the market?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A common misconception is that the market cannot be predicted and that hedge fund managers are no better than dart-throwing monkeys. Many academic &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cass.city.ac.uk/faculties-and-research/research/cass-knowledge/2013/april/monkeys-vs-fund-managers-an-evaluation-of-alternative-equity-indices&quot;&gt;research papers&lt;/a&gt; back up this claim with data. This is an overly simplistic view. Just because some markets cannot be predicted under some experimental settings, such as equities traded on a daily basis, this does not mean no market can be predicted in any setting. Let us try to get an intuitive understanding of what it means to predict the market. To do so, we have to understand the market participants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Retail investors&lt;/strong&gt;: The average person. He or she may be buying BTC because a friend recommended it, or selling mined BTC to get some cash. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Institutional Investors&lt;/strong&gt;: Organizations or high net-worth individuals who trade large quantities. They can be responsible for big market movements.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Professional Human Traders&lt;/strong&gt;: These people are actively trying to beat the market. They may make trades based on news, some combination of technical analysis indicators, or gut feeling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Algorithms:&lt;/strong&gt; Trading algorithms receive market data, make decisions, and place orders automatically.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;To anyone looking at the data, retail and institutional investor activity looks random. A Bitcoin miner may be cashing out, or someone may be buying up a large quantity of BTC because due to insider information. There is no way we could ever predict such market activity. For our purposes, it is just random noise. Sometimes we will be lucky and be on right side of the market when such random activity moves the price, and sometimes we end up on the wrong side. Over a big enough time period this should come out to net zero.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Professional human traders and algorithms are more interesting to us. They are essentially the same as both of of them follow a set of rules to make decisions. As a result of that, they leave patterns in the data. If we knew their rules, it would be trivial to come up with a exploitative strategy to make money. For example, if we knew that some algorithm buy X amount when a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.investopedia.com/terms/m/macd.asp&quot;&gt;MACD&lt;/a&gt; signal, a type of nonsense but widely-used technical analysis indicator, reaches its threshold, we just need to slightly modify the parameters to buy before the algorithm does, and then sell after the algorithm drove up the price with its buy. Of course this is an overly simplified example. Most algorithms are more complicated, such ML-based models, and we are ignoring liquidity, latency, fees, and other aspects. The point is that any market participant making consistent rule-based decisions can be exploited if we know how.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An important aspect of the above is &lt;strong&gt;time scale&lt;/strong&gt;. Looking at daily prices, market activity looks more random than if we looked at the data on a per-second scale. The reason for that is quite intuitive. Over longer time scales, such as days and weeks, market activity is a result of complex interactions between political news, legal rulings, public sentiment, social hype, business decisions, and so on. Large random trades by institutional investors can also have a big impact, but they don't happen very often. These are not things that can be modeled or exploited by algorithms. We don't have data for &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Black_swan_theory&quot;&gt;black-swan events&lt;/a&gt;, making it impossible to model and predict them algorithmically. However, if we zoom into the market activity for a single hour, minute, or second, we can often see patterns. These patterns are a result of algorithmic rule-based trading. Our goal is exploiting such patterns to make a profit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other words, instead of thinking of beating the market, let's think of making a profit as exploiting a large-enough population of other market participants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;whats-your-edge&quot;&gt;What's your edge?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Buy and sell transactions happen between two or more market participants and in order for us to make a profit, someone else must make a loss. What makes us better than all the other traders who are also trying to be profitable? In trading, a competitive advantage is called an &lt;strong&gt;edge&lt;/strong&gt; and may come from various places:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Latency:&lt;/strong&gt; We have a faster connection to the exchange than others. This means we can observe new data faster and submit orders before others. In the financial markets, institutions spend millions of dollars to minimize latency to exchanges.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Infrastructure:&lt;/strong&gt; Our infrastructure may be more fault-tolerant, higher performance, or handle edge cases betters than the competition.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data:&lt;/strong&gt; We may have better data than others, where &lt;em&gt;better&lt;/em&gt; can mean many things. Our data may be collected more reliably with fewer outages, come from a different API, or cleaned and post-processed more carefully. &lt;a href=&quot;https://ethz.ch/content/dam/ethz/special-interest/mtec/chair-of-entrepreneurial-risks-dam/documents/dissertation/master%20thesis/thesis_schroeter.pdf&quot;&gt;Reconstructing the Limit-Order Book&lt;/a&gt; from raw real-time API data can be an error-prone process due to noisy, delayed, or duplicate data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Model:&lt;/strong&gt; We may be able to build a better predictive model based on patterns in the data. Perhaps we use some fancy new Deep Learning techniques, have a better optimization function (more on that below), better features, or a different training algorithm.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Market Access:&lt;/strong&gt; We may have access to a market not everyone can trade in. For example, certain exchanges in South Korea require you to be a citizen to get access. Many international exchanges don't accept U.S. citizens as customers to avoid dealing with the IRS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A common mistake is to focus on the model because it's sexy.&lt;/strong&gt; I have talked to many people who tried to build a profitable trading system using a fancy (and now commoditized) Deep Learning and/or Reinforcement Learning algorithm. Most of them fail. They believe their edge comes from the model and neglect the other ingredients. They don't optimize server placement, use open source software to place orders and collect data, and use easily accessible public datasets for training. Their model may in fact give them a small edge, but it's not big enough to make up for all the other mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's hard to pin down where my own edge comes from. It's likely a combination of all the above. I do have some fancy Machine Learning models, but the biggest edge probably comes from the effort put into building the infrastructure. Almost any trading-related open source software is suboptimal. It's useful to play around with for learning purposes, but not suited for serious production usage. I started out with using open source components, but after many iterations I ended up building custom components for everything, including real-time data collection and cleaning, backtesting and simulation, order management and normalization, monitoring, and live trading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;picking-a-market&quot;&gt;Picking a market&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A market is an asset traded on a specific exchange. For example, one market is &lt;code&gt;BTC/USDT&lt;/code&gt; traded on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.binance.com&quot;&gt;Binance&lt;/a&gt;. Another one is &lt;code&gt;BTC/USD&lt;/code&gt; traded on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coinbase.com/&quot;&gt;Coinbase&lt;/a&gt;. There exist hundreds of different &lt;a href=&quot;https://coinmarketcap.com/rankings/exchanges/&quot;&gt;cryptocurrency exchanges&lt;/a&gt;, each trading dozens of assets. How do we choose where to trade? The ideal market has high liquidity, low trading fees, fast and reliable APIs, and good security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's talk about market liquidity. Whole books have been written on defining and measuring liquidity, but it can be roughly understood as the volume we can trade without significantly affecting the market price. Liquid markets have a small &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.investopedia.com/terms/b/bid-askspread.asp&quot;&gt;spread&lt;/a&gt; and little &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.investopedia.com/terms/s/slippage.asp&quot;&gt;slippage&lt;/a&gt;. They offer low trading costs while allowing us to trade large volumes. An easy-to-measure proxy metric for liquidity is trade volume. Markets with high trade volume often, but not always, have high liquidity. Because it is such a commonly used metric to make decisions, many cryptocurrency exchanges use &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/crypto-integrity/fake-volumes-in-cryptocurrency-markets-february-report-fec9329f1f98&quot;&gt;fake volumes&lt;/a&gt; to make themselves look better than they are. Unfortunately, there is no public ranking of exchanges that's reliable, even though attempts such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://cer.live/&quot;&gt;cer.live&lt;/a&gt; exist. A common mistake is to rely on sites such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://coinmarketcap.com/rankings/exchanges/&quot;&gt;CMC's exchange ranking&lt;/a&gt;, which is useless and driven by exchanges paying advertising fees to get listed. In the end, any publicly available ranking is prone to being gamed by the exchanges, either by outright paying money to the maintainers, or by manipulating their data. Whenever an exchange ranking becomes popular, it's probably only a matter of time before the exchanges, many of which are swimming in cash, are offering enough to the owners to get listed. On top of that, exchange ranking sites don't care how accurate their data is. They are not trading based on their data, they are marketing machines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The only reliable way to evaluate markets is to collect and analyze data yourself.&lt;/strong&gt; What does the order book like like? Do trades look real or fake? What are the spread and slippage distributions? While some exchanges are blatant in their use of algorithms to fake trade data, others employ more sophisticated techniques to make their data look real. In such cases, we won't find out that we are dealing with fake data until we actually start trading on the exchange ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;understanding-trading-costs&quot;&gt;Understanding trading costs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be profitable, our trades must be &lt;em&gt;good enough&lt;/em&gt; to offset all trading costs. Exchange trading fees are obvious to most people, but costs such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.investopedia.com/terms/s/slippage.asp&quot;&gt;slippages&lt;/a&gt; tend to be neglected despite being crucial. Let's say we buy a quantity &lt;code&gt;qty&lt;/code&gt; of BTC and sell it again after some time period. Here is what we would pay in pure trading costs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;trade_cost(qty) = (2 * qty * exchange_fee) + (qty * spread) + slippage_buy(qty) + slippage_sell(qty)
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;(2 * qty * exchange_fee)&lt;/code&gt; is the exchange fee. For example, an exchange may charge 0.01% trading fees on each trade. Since we are buying and selling we're making two trades and paying the fee twice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;(qty * spread)&lt;/code&gt; is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bid%E2%80%93ask_spread&quot;&gt;bid-ask spread&lt;/a&gt; we are paying for buying at the ask and selling at the bid. Even if the market does not move at all, we are still buying at a slightly higher price than we are selling at. The spread changes over time, and incorporating it into our trading decisions is crucial. If we are trading &lt;code&gt;BTC/USDT&lt;/code&gt; on Binance, the spread distribution over single day may look something like this, ranging from less than $1 most of the time up to $5+ dollars at illiquid times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.tradientblog.com/img/spread_dist_binance_btc_usdt.png&quot; alt=&quot;Binance spread distribution&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;slippage_buy(qty)&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;slippage_sell(qty)&lt;/code&gt; are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.investopedia.com/terms/s/slippage.asp&quot;&gt;price slippages&lt;/a&gt; as a result of insufficient market liquidity. The larger the quantity we are trading, the more slippage cost we are paying because full quantity cannot be filled at the best price. For &lt;code&gt;BTC/USDT&lt;/code&gt; on Binance, the slippage distribution looks something like shown below. Each row corresponds to a specific trade size, ranging from &lt;code&gt;0.1&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;2.0&lt;/code&gt; BTC, and the x-axis shows the cost as &lt;code&gt;% of price paid&lt;/code&gt;. Trading during times of low liquidity means that slippage costs can easily dominate exchange fees or spreads, as we can see from the extremes of the distribution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.tradientblog.com/img/binance_slippage_distribution.png&quot; alt=&quot;Binance slippage cost distribution&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How much do these costs matter? It depends. If we are trading once a day and betting on large market movements we can ignore most of these costs. 0.5% trading fees are bearable when we are betting on 10%+ price movements. The shorter the time scales we are trading on, the more crucial these costs become. The market does not make large movements within a few seconds and our trades can easily be dominated by trading costs, wiping out any profit. The other important factor is the quantity we are trading. Larger quantities mean more profit, but also more fees. Exchange fees and spread may scale linearly with quantity, but the slippage does not and can lead to bad surprises. Using book-crossing limit orders instead of market orders is one way to protect oneself against large slippage costs, but requires additional infrastructure to manage partial order fills and cancellations. Again, the shorter the time scale we are trading on, the lower the quantity we can profitably trade without getting wiped out by trading costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;time-scale&quot;&gt;Time scale&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do we decide if we should trade based on high frequency data or make a single trade per day? To understand to tradeoffs, let's look at the extremes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On short time scales, such as milliseconds, large market movements don't occur. Each of our trades can result in only tiny profit only, but we can make a lot of them. And as discussed above, high trading costs are likely going to destroy us. Even if we could perfectly predict the market on a millisecond-scale, such a model would not be useful. Sending an HTTP request to the exchange and waiting for it to be processed by the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Order_matching_system&quot;&gt;exchange matching engine&lt;/a&gt; typically takes tens to hundreds of milliseconds. By the time our order is processed, the market has changed significantly and our prediction is outdated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other extreme would be trading based on something closer to daily prices. Market movements from one day to the next are large enough for us to completely ignore trading costs. Latencies don't matter either. However, such long-term market movements are probably driven by complex real-world interactions such as news and social behavior or other random events like institutional investor activity. If we are relying on pure pattern matching (Machine Learning), we can't hope to make good predictions on such time scales. We also don't have much data. A few hundred examples are not enough data to train any modern algorithms. We also can't reliably test and evaluate our algorithms. With so much noise in the data, testing on a few hundred data points is like throwing darts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This means we need to find a balance between significantly large returns to cover the trading costs, big enough datasets, and the ability to recognize patterns in the data. Short time scales tend to have more patterns and examples, but we need to be careful about trading costs and latencies, which in turn depend on market liquidity and exchange APIs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An alternative to using a intervals based on a natural clock (seconds) is to use intervals based on &lt;a href=&quot;https://quant.stackexchange.com/questions/43534/volume-or-dollar-bars-vs-volatility-normalized-and-demeaned-financial-time-seri&quot;&gt;some other measure, such as trade volume&lt;/a&gt;. For example, instead of defining a tick as &lt;code&gt;1 second&lt;/code&gt;, we could define it as &lt;code&gt;1.0 BTC traded&lt;/code&gt;, which could happen within one second or one minute, depending on how busy the market is. The intuition here is that we want to act more frequently during high-activity periods (high volume traded) and less frequently during low-activity periods (low volume traded). Aggregating data based on volume also results in more normalized data distributions of features and labels, which is helpful for training ML algorithms. Such approaches come with their own drawbacks. For example, when acting based on volume traded we may be too late already. Acting after volume spike means that the market has moved already. Ideally we want to place an order before the other market participants, i.e. before the trade volume picks up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In the end, time scale, and how to define time, is hyperparameter that must be optimized on a per-market basis.&lt;/strong&gt; A highly liquid market with low fees and low API latencies allows us to trade profitably on much shorter time scales than a less liquid market with higher fees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;optimization-function&quot;&gt;Optimization function&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To train a Machine Learning model on market data we need to pick an optimization metric. An obvious choice would be to train a regression model on raw prices. The problem with prices is that they are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.investopedia.com/articles/trading/07/stationary.asp&quot;&gt;nonstationary&lt;/a&gt;. The vast majority of modern Machine Learning techniques require, or work best with, stationary data and assume that the data distribution does not change over time, both within the training set, and across training, validation and test sets. That's why in finance we typically model &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rate_of_return&quot;&gt;returns&lt;/a&gt; instead of prices, where the return &lt;code&gt;r(t)&lt;/code&gt; at time &lt;code&gt;t&lt;/code&gt; is defined as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;r(t) = (p(t) / p(t-1)) - 1
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's is simply the percentage the price has moved. A return greater than 0 means the price moved up, and a return less than 0 means the price went down. You can define the timescale &lt;code&gt;t&lt;/code&gt; however you like, as discussed in the previous section. You may calculate minutely returns, daily returns, or returns based on a volume clock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An even better metric are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.portfolioprobe.com/2010/10/04/a-tale-of-two-returns/&quot;&gt;log-returns&lt;/a&gt;. They measure the same thing, but are closer to normally distributed and have a few convenient statistical properties useful for training ML algorithms:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;logr(t) = log(p(t)) - log(p(t-1))
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Training a regression model on log-returns on some fixed time scale is one optimization function we could pick. It's a pretty standard one. But there are many other possibilities. For example, in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Advances-Financial-Machine-Learning-Marcos/dp/1119482089&quot;&gt;Advances in Financial Machine Learning&lt;/a&gt;, the author discusses how to pick sensible thresholds and transform the data to convert the regression into a classification problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is one aspect of the above formula that we conveniently glanced over. It's the price &lt;code&gt;p(t)&lt;/code&gt;. In practice, there are several ways we could define &lt;code&gt;p(t)&lt;/code&gt;. When we see a single price for an asset such as BTC, it typically refers to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mid_price&quot;&gt;midprice&lt;/a&gt;. However, the midprice is a synthetic quantity, not a price we can actually trade at. When buying, we are paying more than the midprice. When selling, we are getting less than midprice. As discussed earlier, we also pay slippage costs as a function of order quantity. Thus, the price is really a function of time, side (buy or sell) and the order quantity, &lt;code&gt;p(t, s, q)&lt;/code&gt;. The above formula should really be something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;logr(t, quantity) = log(p(t, BUY, quantity)) - log(p(t-1, SELL, quantity))
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are other definitions of price we could use for modeling purposes, such as the &lt;a href=&quot;https://wwwf.imperial.ac.uk/~ajacquie/Gatheral60/Slides/Gatheral60%20-%20Stoikov.pdf&quot;&gt;microprice&lt;/a&gt;. How much does picking an accurate representation of price matter? Again, it depends on time scale and market liquidity. Modeling returns based on midprice may be good enough in very liquid markets with low slippage costs, but completely useless in illiquid ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;training-vs-backtesting-vs-live-trading&quot;&gt;Training vs. Backtesting vs. Live Trading&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The typical workflow for building a trading algorithm looks something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;Data collection
-&amp;gt; Data preprocessing and cleaning
-&amp;gt; Feature construction
-&amp;gt; Model training
-&amp;gt; Backtesting
-&amp;gt; Live trading
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What we optimize for during model training, such the accurate prediction of log-returns, is only a proxy metric for what we truly are about, which is Profit or Loss (PnL).&lt;/strong&gt; That's why &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.investopedia.com/articles/trading/05/030205.asp&quot;&gt;backtesting&lt;/a&gt; is crucial. In the context of automated trading, backtesting refers to running a full-fledged simulation of the market using a trained model and a historical data stream. &lt;a href=&quot;https://quantpedia.com/links-tools/&quot;&gt;Commercially available backtesting software&lt;/a&gt; can be quite expensive, especially if geared towards high-frequency trading. At the very least, such backtesting software can simulate latencies, non-standard order types, exchange commission structures and slippages. It may also automatically optimize hyperparameters and output charts and statistics to evaluate the model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But no matter how good the backtesting software, it is still fundamentally different from a live environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th/&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Training&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Backtesting&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Live&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Metric&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Proxy Metric&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;PnL&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;PnL&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Slippage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Predictable&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Unpredictable&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Latencies&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fixed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Highly variable&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Market Impact&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;No&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;No&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data Distribution&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Estimated&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Estimated&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Real&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;API Issues&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;No&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;No&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;While backtesters may simulate latencies, the real world is significantly more unpredictable. Latencies in the real world may be stable during low-activity periods and spike during high-activity periods. They can also have a seasonality to them. The same is true for APIs. In simulation everything works perfectly, but in the real world we run into API issues, request throttling, and random order rejections during busy periods. And usually it's those busy periods when our actions matter the most. In the real world we also have market impact - we influence other market participants. We can't simulate this. Backtesting is also fundamentally limited by the data we have. The historical data we obtain from exchange APIs is often noisy and incomplete - there is no guarantee it truly reflects the current state of the exchange.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Backtesting thus serves mostly as a filter, or an optimistic estimate. If our model does not perform well in backtesting, there is little chance it would do well in a live scenario. But a model performing well in a controlled backtest is not guaranteed to do well in the real world. Unless you are careful, backtesting is also prone to overfitting and can yield spurious results. Live trading will punish you for this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is one reason why many academics papers on trading are not very useful in practice. They final step in finance research is often backtesting on historical data. If the model does well, the researchers declare success, conveniently ignoring the fact that their model would probably never be profitable in a production environment. Academic researchers don't have access to live trading infrastructure to test their models. If they did, and their new algorithm performed well in the real-world, they certainly would not publish a paper about it and give away their edge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Training (supervised) Machine Learning models for trading is hard. In many other ML use case, train-test performance directly correlates with live performance. For example, if we train a recommendation system with proper train/validation/test splits and the data distribution does not change significantly over time, we can be pretty sure that a model performing well on the test set also does so in production. In trading, our training, backtesting, and live environments are so different that we can't make any guarantees. We can only hope that a trained model, which uses some kind of proxy metric, does well in backtesting. And then we need to hope again that the model still does well in a live environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;other-challenges&quot;&gt;Other challenges&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post is already longer than I wanted it to be, but there are still many challenges we have not touched upon. Upcoming blog posts may go into more detail on some of these:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Non-IID noisy data:&lt;/strong&gt; Market data is not &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Independent_and_identically_distributed_random_variables&quot;&gt;independent and identically distributed&lt;/a&gt;, making it more challenging to train accurate ML models. There is also large amount of noise. There may be patterns in market activity, but they are hidden within a lot of random activity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Order book reconstruction&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;https://ethz.ch/content/dam/ethz/special-interest/mtec/chair-of-entrepreneurial-risks-dam/documents/dissertation/master%20thesis/thesis_schroeter.pdf&quot;&gt;Order book reconstruction&lt;/a&gt; is a common bottleneck in trading and backtesting infrastructure. How can we do this efficiently? Exchange APIs are often unreliable and have jitter, how can we deal with this?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Minimizing latencies:&lt;/strong&gt; What are some of the tricks to minimize end-to-end latency between receiving data and sending orders to the exchanges?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feature construction:&lt;/strong&gt; Which features are the most useful for our ML algorithms to model the data, and how can we efficiently construct them in real-time?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Order Management:&lt;/strong&gt; With spotty and unreliable exchange APIs we must manage orders ourselves. What does a typical order management system look like?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fault Tolerance:&lt;/strong&gt; What happens when things go wrong in a live setting and how can we recover?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;thoughts-on-arbitrage-and-market-making-strategies&quot;&gt;Thoughts on Arbitrage and Market Making strategies&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this post we discussed one specific type of trading strategy, a liquidity-taking strategy that tries to profit from price movements. Two other common types of trading strategies are arbitrage and market making. Without going into too much detail, I want to share some thoughts on their viability in the current crypto markets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arbitrage, taking advantage of price difference between exchanges, is perhaps the most popular trading strategy in the crypto markets. Most exchanges trade the same assets, so arbitrage makes sense. It is intuitive, easy to understand, and easy to implement. A quick Google search will flood you with crypto arbitrage bots, SaaS services, tutorials, books, and gurus ready to explain how to make a quick buck. That alone should make you skeptical. There is nothing wrong with arbitrage in general, but you must ask yourself: What is your edge? The barrier of entry is so low and thousands of people, and some very sophisticated trading companies, are doing the same thing. From what I've seen, &lt;strong&gt;informative prices are often mistaken for arbitrage opportunities&lt;/strong&gt;. When the BTC price on exchange A is lower than on exchange B, it's likely a reflection of risk, not an arbitrage opportunity. Exchange A may be less secure than exchange B, less regulated, or less reputable. The lower price then reflects the risk you are taking for storing money on that exchange. For international arbitrage, price differences often reflect the volatility of a country's fiat currency, or the regulations and limitations around cashing out and moving large amounts of fiat out of the country. These are not arbitrage opportunities. These are informative prices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/High-frequency_trading#Market_making&quot;&gt;Market Making&lt;/a&gt; is the opposite of a liquidity-taking strategy. Instead of taking liquidity, betting on market movements, and paying the spread, we can provide liquidity, protect against market movements, and profit from the spread. In the financial markets, professional market making firms are some of the most profitable operations in existence. Market Making in the crypto markets is a viable strategy, but can be difficult to pull off if you don't have professional Market Making experience. Due to the accumulation of inventory it can be risky, and unreliable exchange APIs, high latencies, and jitter are less forgivable in a market making scenario than they are in a liquidity-taking strategy. Market making also requires significantly more complex infrastructure for inventory and risk management. The competition here is also stiff. Many professional market making firms from the financial markets have moved into crypto. On the bright side, many exchanges are actively trying to recruit market makers with favorable fee structures and commissions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;resources&quot;&gt;Resources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trading industry is one of the most secretive industries I've ever been involved in. Most of what you find online is noise, or gurus trying to sell something. Most successful traders I've talked to have worked for a professional trading company, and that's where they learned the ropes. They have no incentive to share any of their knowledge online, and sharing has never been part of the culture in finance. As a result, the whole field can seem complex and overwhelming to newcomers. The best way to learn is probably by doing. Unlike in the financial markets, where trading infrastructure and high-frequency data can cost millions of dollars, trading in th crypto markets is available to anyone and can be used as learning environment. Nevertheless, here are a few resources I found helpful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Advances-Financial-Machine-Learning-Marcos/dp/1119482089&quot;&gt;Advances in Financial Machine Learning&lt;/a&gt; - A no-nonsense book that covers the application of Machine Learning techniques in the financial markets. It is more on the academic side and some of it is not very practical. While I don't agree with everything in this book, it's an excellent introduction to various challenges and pitfalls you encounter when building trading systems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Introduction-High-Frequency-Finance-Ramazan-Gen%C3%A7ay/dp/0122796713&quot;&gt;An Introduction to High-Frequency Finance&lt;/a&gt; - Covers a lot of common terminology and methods used in automated trading. Can be quite academic and hard to digest at times, but worth a read.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Fooled-Randomness-Hidden-Markets-Incerto-ebook/dp/B001FA0W5W&quot;&gt;Fooled by Randomness: The Hidden Role of Chance in Life and in the Markets&lt;/a&gt; - Not about the technical aspects of trading, but written by an options trader, it teaches you how to think about random chance, both in the markets and in life.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/list/q-fin/recent&quot;&gt;arXiv q-fin&lt;/a&gt; - Reading recent research papers is a great way to come up with new ideas or learn how to think about a problem. Read them because they are interesting and educational, but don't pay too much attention to the results. As mentioned earlier, academics have little incentive to publish something that works in practice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;closing-thoughts&quot;&gt;Closing Thoughts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope that I was able to give some insight into problems that may come up when building automated trading systems. You may be disappointed that this post was more focused on problems than solutions. But that's for a reason. There are no universal solutions to complex problems that work in all cases. What's important is to fully understand the facets of a problem, and then make the reasonable decision specific to your context.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my first post, so I am not sure where to go from here. I would love to hear your feedback in the comments.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 11:34:21 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>traK6Dcm</dc:creator>
<og:title>Lessons learned building an ML trading system that turned $5k into $200k</og:title>
<og:description>One of my recent side projects was building an automated trading system for the crypto markets. To be fair, I probably spent more time on this than on my full-time job, so calling it a side project may not be completely accurate. The internet is full of people ready to teach you about trading. Most are trying to sell you something, and many are mistaking random chance for skill. Coming from a technical background in scientific research and software engineering, I tried to ignore anything with little scientific validity, like technical analysis, or anything that looked like marketing BS.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>/2019/11/lessons-learned-building-an-ml-trading-system-that-turned-5k-into-200k/</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.tradientblog.com/2019/11/lessons-learned-building-an-ml-trading-system-that-turned-5k-into-200k/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Everything I know about Kubernetes I learned from a cluster of Raspberry Pis</title>
<link>https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2019/everything-i-know-about-kubernetes-i-learned-cluster-raspberry-pis</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2019/everything-i-know-about-kubernetes-i-learned-cluster-raspberry-pis</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I realized I haven't posted about my DrupalCon Seattle 2019 session titled &lt;a href=&quot;https://events.drupal.org/seattle2019/sessions/everything-i-know-about-kubernetes-i-learned-cluster-raspberry-pis&quot;&gt;Everything I know about Kubernetes I learned from a cluster of Raspberry Pis&lt;/a&gt;, so I thought I'd remedy that. First, here's a video of the recorded session:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/yLzO88h40uw&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.jeffgeerling.com/sites/jeffgeerling.com/files/images/pi-dramble-original.jpeg&quot; width=&quot;390&quot; height=&quot;589&quot; alt=&quot;The original Raspberry Pi Dramble Cluster&quot; class=&quot;insert-image&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;The original Pi Dramble 6-node cluster, running the LAMP stack.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started running the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pidramble.com&quot;&gt;Raspberry Pi Dramble&lt;/a&gt; in 2014, after I realized I could automate the setup of everything in a LAMP stack on a set of Raspberry Pi 2s using Ansible (one Pi for an HTTP load balancer/reverse proxy, two for PHP app backends, and two for MySQL redundancy. Kubernetes was the logical next step, so I moved things towards Kubernetes in 2017, but running Kubernetes was a lesson in pain due to the Pi's limited memory (1 GB maximum) at the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the Raspberry Pi 4 came around, I acquired some 2 GB models as quickly as I could, and redeployed onto them. Gone were the restrictions that were causing Kubernetes' API to be flaky with the older Pis, and now the Pi 4 cluster is extremely reliable. Early on, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2019/raspberry-pi-4-needs-fan-heres-why-and-how-you-can-add-one&quot;&gt;cooling was an issue&lt;/a&gt;, but the recent firmware update has made that less problematic. I now power the cluster using the official PoE HAT, which means I only have one plug for each Pi, and everything fits nicely into a small travel case (if I want to bring the cluster with me anywhere).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.jeffgeerling.com/sites/jeffgeerling.com/files/images/pi-dramble-4-k8s-edition.jpeg&quot; width=&quot;650&quot; height=&quot;432&quot; alt=&quot;Raspberry Pi Dramble 4 Kubernetes edition cluster&quot; class=&quot;insert-image&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;The current Pi Dramble, running Kubernetes and sporting &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.blinkstick.com/products/blinkstick-nano&quot;&gt;BlinkStick Nanos&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I even got it all to run off a 10,000 mAh battery pack with a bunch of USB splitters... but it did not stay powered long, and kept giving low power warnings—so I'll have to consider other options for a highly-mobile four-node Kubernetes bare-metal cluster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've continually updated the cluster so it is tested in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/geerlingguy/raspberry-pi-dramble/tree/master/testing/docker&quot;&gt;Docker-based Kubernetes environment&lt;/a&gt;, a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/geerlingguy/raspberry-pi-dramble/tree/master/testing/vagrant&quot;&gt;Vagrant-based Kubernetes local development environment&lt;/a&gt;, and of course, the Pi environment. The latter environment causes much consternation, as many common container images are not maintained in an &lt;code&gt;armv6&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;linux/arm&lt;/code&gt; format, which is required when running on the 32-bit ARM OS the Pi uses, Raspbian. But the Pi Dramble abides, and it quietly goes on, serving up traffic for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pidramble.com&quot;&gt;https://www.pidramble.com&lt;/a&gt; through the years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The official &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pidramble.com/wiki&quot;&gt;Pi Dramble Wiki&lt;/a&gt; has all the instructions for building your own Pi Kubernetes cluster, with links to buy all the parts I have, along with every step to get it running using open source Ansible roles to install Kubernetes and Docker for ARM, then configure a new four-node cluster.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 10:30:25 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>alexellisuk</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2019/everything-i-know-about-kubernetes-i-learned-cluster-raspberry-pis</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Russian whistleblower was assassinated after uncovering $200B scandal (2018)</title>
<link>https://www.thedailybeast.com/russian-whistleblower-assassinated-after-uncovering-dollar200-billion-dirty-money-scandal</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.thedailybeast.com/russian-whistleblower-assassinated-after-uncovering-dollar200-billion-dirty-money-scandal</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;LONDON—A crusading Russian official traveled to Estonia in the summer of 2006 to warn the authorities that an unprecedented money-laundering scheme had been established in the tiny Baltic financial sector. The scam he had uncovered would go on to become the biggest dirty-money operation in history: the $200 billion Danske Bank scandal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three months after Andrei Kozlov, the first deputy chairman of the Russian Central Bank, tried to raise the alarm, he was dead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crooked beneficiaries of the illicit multibillion-dollar scheme to transfer money out of Russia &lt;a class=&quot;TrackingLink LinkWrapper&quot; href=&quot;https://www.thedailybeast.com/report-putins-family-used-estonian-bank-to-launder-money&quot;&gt;included a member of Vladmir Putin’s family&lt;/a&gt; and agents from the KGB’s successor, the FSB, &lt;a class=&quot;LinkWrapper LinkWrapper--external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.occrp.org/en/projects/28-ccwatch/cc-watch-indepth/7698-report-russia-laundered-billions-via-danske-bank-estonia&quot;&gt;according to a leaked report drawn up by a bank insider&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to a diplomatic cable seen by The Daily Beast, U.S. officials briefly investigated Kozlov’s trip to try to shut down the money-laundering superhighway through Tallinn soon after his death, but the scale and importance of the dirty-money route was unknown at the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kozlov becomes the third dead Russian who can be linked to the Danske scandal after Alexander Perepilichnyy, whose company used the bank’s Estonia branch, died in suspicious circumstances in Britain, and Sergei Magnitsky, a Russian lawyer who was investigating the theft of $230 million when he died in Russian custody. It is claimed that the vast majority of the proceeds of that theft were laundered through Danske Bank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;Fancylinks&quot; data-nosnippet=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Sept. 13, 2006, Kozlov, who was 41, took part in a friendly soccer match between bankers and financial regulators at the Spartak Moscow sports complex in northeast Moscow. After the game, the young central banker walked back out to a car park, where a driver was waiting. His high-profile role had already earned him enough money and status for his own chauffeur; his zeal to clean up Russia’s financial sector had earned him a stellar reputation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Kozlov, who had a neat beard and broad face, reached his car at around 8:45 p.m., three strangers approached. They fired a volley of shots that struck Kozlov and his driver.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alexander Semyonov, the 54-year-old chauffeur, died right there outside the sports arena. Kozlov, who was hit in the head, chest, and stomach, made it as far as the operating table at Moscow’s Hospital No. 33, but he did not regain consciousness and was never able to tell his story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;PullQuote&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;PullQuote__quote&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Up to that time, it was the most high-profile killing in Russia since Putin had become president six years earlier.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He died at 5:30 a.m. the following morning, leaving his wife, Yekaterina, and three children.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Up to that time, it was the most high-profile killing in Russia since Putin had become president six years earlier. Anna Politkovskaya, the investigative journalist and arch-critic of the Kremlin, was to be murdered a month later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within hours of Kozlov’s death, Russian officials were publicly speculating that he was most likely murdered in retaliation for revoking the licenses of a number of small banks. “It’s quite possible that the gangsters linked to them might have put out a contract on him,” &lt;a class=&quot;LinkWrapper LinkWrapper--external&quot; href=&quot;http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/world/europe/5345236.stm&quot;&gt;said Boris Gryzlov&lt;/a&gt;, the chairman of Putin’s United Russia Party, the day he died.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This somewhat outlandish theory quickly “proved” exactly right; the Russian authorities found the operator of just such an institution and accused him of ordering the murder. Alexei Frenkel, whose VIP Bank had been shut down by the Russian Central Bank, was arrested for hiring three Ukrainian hitmen to gun down Kozlov.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As guards led Frenkel away from his first court appearance, &lt;a class=&quot;LinkWrapper LinkWrapper--external&quot; href=&quot;https://reuters.screenocean.com/record/318896&quot;&gt;Reuters reported&lt;/a&gt; that the private banker, who was 34 at the time, managed to shout out to a group of journalists in the corridor: “I am not guilty!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite his protestations of innocence, which continue to this day, Frenkel was soon convicted and sentenced to 19 years in prison for an outrageous plot to shut down one of Russia’s most prominent anti-corruption officials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can now say that Kozlov had far more dangerous enemies at the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In June 2006, the central banker went to Estonia personally to warn the local authorities that billions of rubles were being transferred illegally into dollars and euros in the West via an Estonian outpost of Sampo Bank. Sampo, an institution based in Finland, was subsumed by Denmark’s largest bank, Danske, later that year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When he got to Tallinn, Kozlov told Andres Palumaa, the head of anti-money-laundering at Estonia’s Financial Supervision Authority (FSA), that the proceeds from tax evasion and money-laundering in Russia were being passed through the financial system that he oversaw. Kozlov demanded the closure of several specific accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The unusual visit was first reported by the Estonian investigative newspaper &lt;em&gt;Eesti Ekspress&lt;/em&gt; a month after Kozlov was killed. His trip over the border to Estonia never became a global news story because the significance of the crime Kozlov had been trying to expose was still an extraordinary secret.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It would be another 12 years before Danske Bank admitted that $234 billion in non-resident money had flowed from Russia and former Soviet republics through Danske’s tiny operation in Estonia. According to &lt;a class=&quot;LinkWrapper LinkWrapper--external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.berlingske.dk/virksomheder/whistleblower-alert-putin-family-and-russian-intelligence-used-danske-bank-to&quot;&gt;a whistleblower's claims leaked to Danish newspaper &lt;em href=&quot;undefined&quot;&gt;Berlingske&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, it was discovered that some of the suspicious accounts were operated by “the Putin family and FSB.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One organization that did follow up on that article in the Estonian press was the U.S. Embassy in Tallinn. According to &lt;a class=&quot;LinkWrapper LinkWrapper--external&quot; href=&quot;https://search.wikileaks.org/plusd/cables/06TALLINN1009_a.html&quot;&gt;a telegram that remained buried until now in the cache of 250,000 diplomatic cables leaked by WikiLeaks&lt;/a&gt; in 2010, U.S. officials went to interview Palumaa soon after the story appeared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Estonian regulator downplayed Kozlov’s warning, according to the cable sent from the embassy in Tallinn to the U.S. embassy in Moscow and back to the State Department in D.C. He conceded there could have been some legal issues with the accounts, but said he had seen no evidence of wrongdoing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Palumaa said that after Kozlov’s warning, the FSA followed up with their Russian counterparts in Moscow, but the Russians said that they had no information to substantiate Kozlov’s accusations,” the cable reads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other words, soon after their meeting in June, Palumaa flagged up Kozlov’s anti-corruption operation to the authorities back in Moscow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Russian officials may have already have been aware of his attempts to shut down the gross corruption of his political superiors. Either way, &lt;a class=&quot;LinkWrapper LinkWrapper--external&quot; href=&quot;http://old.themoscowtimes.com/sitemap/free/2006/10/article/3-suspects-arrested-in-kozlov-killing/201636.html&quot;&gt;according to leading Russian newspaper &lt;em&gt;Kommersant&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the Ukrainian contract killers had begun to track Kozlov by July.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;PullQuote&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;PullQuote__quote&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The Ukrainian contract killers had begun to track Kozlov by July.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Estonian branch of Sampo bank, which was bought by Danske, was alleged to be a central nexus in a host of criminal enterprises run out of Russia. As the Danish bank’s own internal inquiry found last month (&lt;a class=&quot;LinkWrapper LinkWrapper--external&quot; href=&quot;https://danskebank.com/-/media/danske-bank-com/file-cloud/2018/9/report-on-the-non-resident-portfolio-at-danske-banks-estonian-branch-.-la=en.pdf&quot;&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;), more than $200 billion in foreign money was allowed to race through its accounts in the years after Kozlov raised the alarm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a lot of well-connected Russians, removing the potential obstacle of Kozlov has proved to be extremely lucrative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Danske’s internal report, written by the Danish law firm Bruun &amp;amp; Hjejle and published in September, did not examine the status of all of the $234 billion identified, but concluded that &lt;a class=&quot;LinkWrapper LinkWrapper--external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-09-19/danske-bank-ceo-to-step-down-for-role-in-laundering-scandal&quot;&gt;“a large part” of it may need to be considered suspicious&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The law firm also identified three major international scandals tied to Danske’s accounts in Estonia. It found almost 200 accounts linked to the &lt;a class=&quot;LinkWrapper LinkWrapper--external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.occrp.org/en/laundromat/the-russian-laundromat-exposed/&quot;&gt;“Russian Laundromat”&lt;/a&gt; exposed by the Organized Crime and Corruption Reporting Project (OCCRP), which uncovered a complex laundering system used to funnel approximately $20 billion out of Russia illegally. An additional 75 accounts were linked to the similar &lt;a class=&quot;LinkWrapper LinkWrapper--external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.occrp.org/en/azerbaijanilaundromat/&quot;&gt;“Azerbaijani Laundromat.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third scandal tied to Danske in the report is the $230 million fraud uncovered by Sergei Magnitsky. In 2008, the tax lawyer was detained, beaten, and left to die in a Russian jail cell after uncovering evidence that Russian officials had been involved in stealing Russian public funds in a scam that victimized Hermitage Capital Management, an investment fund founded by Bill Browder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;PullQuote&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;PullQuote__quote&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It may take years to disentangle all of the suspicious accounts.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Browder has since campaigned for the introduction of a series of anti-corruption laws, which have been enacted all over the world. The U.S. laws passed in Sergei Magnitsky’s name have so far been used to sanction 74 individuals accused of corruption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of the $230 million obtained fraudulently, Browder estimates that more than $200 million passed through the Danske bank in Estonia. He first reported suspected money laundering at the bank to the Estonian authorities in 2012. In July this year, &lt;a class=&quot;LinkWrapper LinkWrapper--external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.ft.com/content/f5df1236-85e5-11e8-96dd-fa565ec55929&quot;&gt;Browder sent a 22-page complaint to the Danish public prosecutor&lt;/a&gt; detailing 190 suspicious accounts linked to the Russian fraud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Danske announced last week that the U.S. authorities had opened an investigation into the bank to run alongside similar probes launched in Britain, France, Denmark, and Estonia. It may take years to disentangle all of the suspicious accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One controversial figure allegedly linked to money-laundering through the bank was Perepilichnyy, whose company IC Financial Bridge was a client of Danske’s Estonian branch, &lt;a class=&quot;LinkWrapper LinkWrapper--external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.ft.com/content/f13ae77a-c7f1-11e8-ba8f-ee390057b8c9&quot;&gt;according to the &lt;em&gt;Financial Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The Russian businessman turned whistleblower &lt;a class=&quot;TrackingLink LinkWrapper&quot; href=&quot;https://www.thedailybeast.com/killer-flower-found-in-dead-russian-whistleblowers-stomach&quot;&gt;died suddenly near his home&lt;/a&gt; in the suburbs outside London; he had been due to testify in Switzerland as part of a case alleging endemic corruption in Russia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His is one of a number of suspicious deaths linked to Russia in Britain that are set to be re-examined by the authorities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Russia, officials are in no rush to re-open the murder of Andrei Kozlov.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Five years after his murder conviction, &lt;a class=&quot;LinkWrapper LinkWrapper--external&quot; href=&quot;http://www.rapsinews.com/judicial_news/20121120/265438038.html&quot;&gt;Alexei Frenkel saw his latest appeal turned down in 2012&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doubts that Frenkel, a young financier, would have ordered the hit on a senior Russian official emerged as soon as he was publicly accused of the killing by &lt;a class=&quot;TrackingLink LinkWrapper&quot; href=&quot;https://www.thedailybeast.com/was-yury-chaika-a-putin-loyalist-accused-of-corruption-behind-the-don-jr-meeting&quot;&gt;Putin’s close confidant Yury Chaika&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chaika, whose son has been hit with sanctions by the U.S. under the Global Magnitsky Act, is Russia’s prosecutor general. After Kozlov’s death, he said he would &lt;a class=&quot;LinkWrapper LinkWrapper--external&quot; href=&quot;https://sputniknews.com/russia/2006091453862983/&quot;&gt;take the case under his personal control&lt;/a&gt;. Chaika is a hugely influential man in Moscow; he is also the alleged source of both &lt;a class=&quot;TrackingLink LinkWrapper&quot; href=&quot;https://www.thedailybeast.com/if-team-trump-knew-kremlin-had-clinton-dirt-theyve-been-lying-about-russian-hacking&quot;&gt;the supposed Hillary Clinton kompromat offered to Donald Trump Jr&lt;/a&gt;. at the Trump Tower meeting and the &lt;a class=&quot;TrackingLink LinkWrapper&quot; href=&quot;https://www.thedailybeast.com/gop-lawmaker-got-direction-from-moscow-took-it-back-to-dc&quot;&gt;propaganda handed to controversial Rep. Dana Rohrabacher&lt;/a&gt; (R-CA).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Frenkel was arrested, &lt;a class=&quot;LinkWrapper LinkWrapper--external&quot; href=&quot;https://wikileaks.org/plusd/cables/07MOSCOW103_a.html&quot;&gt;a diplomatic cable from the U.S. Embassy&lt;/a&gt; said the reaction in Moscow was mixed. Some were impressed that the prosecutor general’s office had shown a determination never previously glimpsed. “This is the first time that authorities went after not just the ones who committed the crime, but the ones who ordered it and paid for it,” a source said. “It is also the first time that a Russian, not a Ukrainian or a Georgian, was found responsible.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other sources expressed “disbelief that Frenkel could have orchestrated the murder.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Austrian government would also come to doubt the official account of Kozlov’s demise. Similar to his work in Estonia, Kozlov had been in touch with Austrian financial regulators to warn them of illicit sources of money coming out of Russia. A few weeks before his death, he had ordered the closure of a small Russian bank engaged in suspicious activity linked to the Austrian banking sector.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;PullQuote&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;PullQuote__quote&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;““There is no need to end your life with an article — someone might simply wait for you at the entrance to your apartment building, and they will not find a killer afterward.””&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— A warning to investigative journalist Natalia Morar&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In April 2007, seven months after Kozlov was shot dead and long after Frenkel was placed behind bars, the Austrian interior ministry made public a report of its own investigation into Kozlov’s death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They said they had passed their findings to the Russian prosecutor general’s office but had received no response, &lt;a class=&quot;LinkWrapper LinkWrapper--external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2007/06/14/opinion/14iht-moscow.4.6144376.html&quot;&gt;according to a report in &lt;em&gt;The&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The Austrians confirmed they had been working closely with Kozlov about shutting down these money-laundering pipelines out of Russia, and concluded that they could not rule out “official corruption” as the motive for his murder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An investigative reporter for Russia’s opposition &lt;em&gt;New Times&lt;/em&gt; newspaper also wrote that Kozlov may have been &lt;a class=&quot;LinkWrapper LinkWrapper--external&quot; href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20071010062433/http://www.newtimes.ru:80/magazine/issue_15/issue_2.htm&quot;&gt;killed for delving into money-laundering issues&lt;/a&gt; that may have upset powerful people in Russiam rather than interfering in the work of a small independent bank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The &lt;em&gt;New Times&lt;/em&gt; interviewees at the Interior Ministry, in the State Duma, and in the banking community are convinced that ‘Frenkel has nothing to do with murder,’” wrote Natalia Morar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Morar’s sources even suggested that Frenkel could have been framed because he knew too much about the very same black-money trails that Kozlov was investigating. Either way, she reported that Kozlov was heading up an investigation into “the possibility of money-laundering through foreign banks by a number of Russian commercial organizations, and also by individuals” when he was killed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soon after her story was published, Morar, a Moldovan citizen, was denied entry to Russia. &lt;a class=&quot;LinkWrapper LinkWrapper--external&quot; href=&quot;https://archive.is/20120918023915/http://www.theinvestigativefund.org/investigations/international/1230/moscow%E2%80%99s_new_rules/&quot;&gt;She said sources close to the FSB had warned her to quit&lt;/a&gt;: “There is no need to end your life with an article—someone might simply wait for you at the entrance to your apartment building, and they will not find a killer afterward.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;a class=&quot;LinkWrapper LinkWrapper--external&quot; href=&quot;https://books.google.co.uk/books?id=QRtVDgAAQBAJ&amp;amp;pg=PA130#v=onepage&amp;amp;q&amp;amp;f=false&quot;&gt;Amy Knight’s book &lt;em&gt;Orders to Kill&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;/a&gt; Kozlov feared that there may be agents in the FSB who wanted to stop him, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite that specter hanging over him, when Kozlov went to Estonia to try and shut down the Sampo/Danske bank route to the West, nobody—not even Kozlov himself—realized that he was stumbling into what would become the single biggest money-laundering scheme used to clean up the ill-gotten gains of Russia’s most powerful men.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 09:56:06 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>krn</dc:creator>
<og:title>Russian Murdered After Revealing $200 Billion Dirty-Money Scam</og:title>
<og:description>Andrei Kozlov was gunned down in 2006, weeks after trying to shutter the world’s biggest money-laundering scam—one reportedly used by Putin’s family and the FSB.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.thedailybeast.com/russian-whistleblower-assassinated-after-uncovering-dollar200-billion-dirty-money-scandal</og:url>
<og:image>https://img.thedailybeast.com/image/upload/c_crop,d_placeholder_euli9k,h_1440,w_2560,x_0,y_0/dpr_2.0/c_limit,w_740/fl_lossy,q_auto/v1539122708/181009-hines-russian-murder-hero_ldsjun</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.thedailybeast.com/russian-whistleblower-assassinated-after-uncovering-dollar200-billion-dirty-money-scandal</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>