<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Facebook Expects to Be Fined Up to $5B by FTC Over Privacy Issues</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/04/24/technology/facebook-ftc-fine-earnings.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2019/04/24/technology/facebook-ftc-fine-earnings.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;SAN FRANCISCO — Facebook said on Wednesday that it &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://investor.fb.com/investor-news/press-release-details/2019/Facebook-Reports-First-Quarter-2019-Results/default.aspx&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;expected to be fined&lt;/a&gt; up to $5 billion by the Federal Trade Commission for privacy violations. The penalty would be a record by the agency against a technology company and a sign that the United States was willing to punish big tech companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The social network disclosed the amount in its quarterly financial results, saying it estimated a one-time charge of $3 billion to $5 billion in connection with an “ongoing inquiry” by the F.T.C. Facebook added that “the matter remains unresolved, and there can be no assurance as to the timing or the terms of any final outcome.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Facebook has been &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/02/14/technology/facebook-ftc-settlement.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;in negotiations&lt;/a&gt; with the regulator for months over a financial penalty for claims that the company violated a 2011 privacy consent decree. That year, the social network promised a series of measures to protect its users’ privacy after an investigation found that its handling of data had harmed consumers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The F.T.C. opened a new investigation last year after Facebook came under fire again. This time, the company was accused of not protecting its users’ data from being harvested without their consent by &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/03/17/us/politics/cambridge-analytica-trump-campaign.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Cambridge Analytica&lt;/a&gt;, a British political consulting firm that was building voter profiles for the Trump campaign. Facebook also &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/09/28/technology/facebook-hack-data-breach.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;suffered a data breach&lt;/a&gt; that exposed the personal information of nearly 50 million users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Levying a sizable fine on Facebook would go against the reputation of the United States of not restraining the power of big tech companies. For years, American regulators have faced criticism that they allowed Silicon Valley firms to grow unchecked, even as their European counterparts aggressively brought actions against tech companies — including &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/07/18/technology/google-eu-android-fine.html?action=click&amp;amp;module=inline&amp;amp;pgtype=Homepage&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;fining Google a record $5.1 billion&lt;/a&gt; last year for abusing its power in the mobile phone market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;For the Trump administration, penalizing Facebook would be a defining action. Although President Trump has rolled back scores of business regulations, he and others in Washington — including Democrats — have coalesced around calling for greater scrutiny and enforcement of tech companies. Senator Elizabeth Warren, Democrat of Massachusetts and presidential candidate, has &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/03/08/us/politics/elizabeth-warren-amazon.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;called for the breakup&lt;/a&gt; of Amazon, Google and Facebook. And Mr. Trump has sounded alarms over the dominance of the firms and their control over speech and the distribution of information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;It would also be a milestone for the F.T.C., whose biggest fine for a tech company was $22 million against Google in 2012 for misrepresenting how it used some online tracking tools. The agency, which is charged with overseeing deceptive and unfair business practices, is riding a wave of anti-tech sentiment as questions about how tech companies have contributed to misinformation, election meddling and data privacy problems have stacked up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“The F.T.C. is really limited in what they can actually do in enforcing a consent decree, but in the case of Facebook, they had public pressure on their side,” said Justin Brookman, a former official for the regulator who is now a director of privacy at Consumers Union, nonprofit consumer advocacy group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;But some lawmakers said a fine would not suffice in punishing Facebook. Representative David Cicilline, Democrat of Rhode Island, said that “a fine in the low billions of dollars would amount to a slap on the wrist for Facebook” and that Congress needed to act.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“Facebook must be held accountable — not just by fines — but also far reaching reforms in management, privacy practices and culture,” Senator Richard Blumenthal, Democrat of Connecticut, added in a tweet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The F.T.C. declined to comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Officials at the agency have not reached a final decision on Facebook, said two people with knowledge of the situation, who were not authorized to speak publicly. In recent weeks, the agency’s chairman, Joseph Simons, sent strict orders to all commission offices and staff in the consumer protection, enforcement and privacy bureaus to not discuss the Facebook case, two people said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;But Facebook’s estimate of a fine signaled that a settlement with the F.T.C. was near. The Securities and Exchange Commission typically requires that a company notify investors of any significant financial hits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;For Facebook, a $5 billion fine would amount to a fraction of its $56 billion in annual revenue. Any resolution would also alleviate some of the regulatory pressure that has been intensifying against the company over the past two and a half years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“This would be a joke of a fine — a two-weeks-of-revenue, parking-ticket-level penalty for destroying democracy,” said Matt Stoller, a fellow at the Open Markets Institute, a think tank that is a vocal critic of the power of tech companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;More meaningful to Facebook would be any regulatory mandates that curbed its ability to share data with business partners or required it to take more measures to inform consumers when and how it collected data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“Those will have the most lasting impact on consumers’ privacy,” said Ashkan Soltani, a former chief technology officer for the trade commission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Even as the negotiations continue, Facebook’s business remains robust. The company said Wednesday that its revenue increased 26 percent in the first quarter to $15 billion from a year earlier. Net income dropped 51 percent from a year ago to $2.4 billion because of the expected one-time charge related to the F.T.C. investigation. The company has more than $40 billion in cash reserves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;New users continue flocking to Facebook. More than 2.7 billion people use one of the company’s so-called family of apps — Facebook, Messenger, Instagram and WhatsApp — each month. The company said about 1.56 billion people use Facebook every day, up 8 percent from a year ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Last month, Mark Zuckerberg, Facebook’s founder and chief executive, said he planned to &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/03/06/technology/mark-zuckerberg-facebook-privacy.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;start shifting people toward private conversations&lt;/a&gt; and away from public broadcasting on social media, which is likely to help the company manage issues of toxic content and misinformation. On Wednesday in a conference call, Mr. Zuckerberg repeated that vision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“People want a platform that is as strong on privacy as possible,” Mr. Zuckerberg said. He added that “we just don’t know” how the change would affect the company’s business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Mr. Zuckerberg also said &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/03/30/technology/mark-zuckerberg-facebook-regulation-explained.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;he welcomed regulations&lt;/a&gt;, an idea that he has increasingly been vocal about this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“I think it’s necessary,” he said. “Getting these issues right is more important than our interests. And I believe that regulation will help establish trust when people know that the right systems of governance and accountability are in place.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 20:27:55 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Dangeranger</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/04/24/technology/facebook-ftc-fine-privacy.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Facebook Expects to Be Fined Up to $5 Billion by F.T.C. Over Privacy Issues</og:title>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/04/24/business/24FACEBOOK2/24FACEBOOK2-facebookJumbo.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>Facebook and the agency have been in negotiations over a financial penalty for claims that the company violated a 2011 consent decree.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/04/24/technology/facebook-ftc-fine-privacy.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The &amp;#039;Dark Ages&amp;#039; Weren&amp;#039;t as Dark as We Thought</title>
<link>https://lithub.com/the-dark-ages-werent-as-dark-as-we-thought/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://lithub.com/the-dark-ages-werent-as-dark-as-we-thought/</guid>
<description>&lt;span itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;There can be few more damning or more useless terms than “the Dark Ages.” They sound fun in an orcs‐and‐elves sort of way and suggest a very low benchmark from which we have since, as a race, raised ourselves up into the light—with the present day using as its soundtrack the last movement of Beethoven’s Ninth. But the damage the term does is immense. A simple little mental test is just to quickly imagine a European scene from that era. Now: was the sun shining? Of course not. The default way of thinking about the long, complex era that lasted from the final decades of the Roman Empire to somewhere around the Battle of Hastings is to assume it all looked like the cover of a heavy metal album.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One problem is that the older the period the more chances there are for its material production to be destroyed. Across Lotharingia [ed. note: one of three filial kingdoms born of the Carolingian Empire]  there has been century after century of rebuilding (with the re‐use of every available piece of old dressed stone) with most evidence of earlier churches and palaces removed in the process. In practical terms one cannot imagine that the vast, humorless bulk of Cologne Cathedral is merely the latest in a series stretching back to a Roman temple. Many of the great religious buildings of the Rhine have a display table showing somewhat conjectural models of their ancient predecessors, usually starting with a patronizing little wooden block, looking something like a skew‐whiff Wendy-house.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So great is the weight of “the Dark Ages” on our shoulders that it is almost impossible not to think of the makers of this wonky church slithering about on the mud floor cursing the way the roof was leaking and how nobody could design a door that shut properly, resigned to the occasional fiasco when the walls would simply fall in on the gurning, fur‐clad, battle‐axe‐wielding communicants. In practice, these now non‐existent buildings would have been extremely beautiful—drawing on Roman and Byzantine models, and stuffed with all kinds of wonderful stuff from the Roman Empire which now no longer exists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the related problem suffered by “the Dark Ages”—our towns often occupy exactly the same sites as they did then (the same river crossing, the same harbor) and are built on top of them, but there have been simply innumerable points at which older material has been destroyed. There is probably some rough mathematical calculation about how each passing century lowers your chance of anything much surviving at all. The famous fat boy of 1666—who was meant to be watching the baker’s oven, but instead gorged on pies, fell asleep and as a result burned down London—is only one of an elite group who caused mayhem through their momentary inattention over the centuries.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;insert-post-ads&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Article continues after advertisement&lt;/span&gt;&lt;!-- /76722702/in_article_banner_2 --&gt;&amp;#13;
&lt;div id=&quot;div-gpt-ad-1482941823113-0&quot;&gt;&amp;#13;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With every household routinely handling flames in wooden surroundings it is unsurprising that so many towns would often find themselves having to start again from scratch. We know far more about more recent horrors—for example, the gunpowder accident that destroyed much of Delft in 1654—but any 24‐hour period over the centuries was always fraught with some fumble‐fingered disaster somewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;The true “dark age,” of course, was the early 1940s when, simply as a side effect of industrial killing, great swathes of the past disappeared.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The unrelenting impact of warfare has of course done far more damage, wrecking town after town. Any breakdown in order or lunge for supremacy ends up with further pyres of the material past. Simply looking at recent disasters, many thousands of ancient records, treasures, histories, valued for centuries by custodians, were destroyed in the 1870 Siege of Strasbourg and the 1914 destruction of much of the Catholic University of Leuven.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The true “dark age,” of course, was the early 1940s when, simply as a side effect of industrial killing, great swathes of the past disappeared. One small yet major example—the extraordinary series of paintings of the visions of Hildegard of Bingen, made in the 1170s either by the saint herself or under her supervision, disappeared in the general catastrophe that unfolded in Dresden in early 1945. We only know what they looked like (except from black‐and‐white photos) through accurate and beautiful copies painted by a group of nuns, by sheer chance, in the 1930s. So these frail little works of disturbing genius survived nearly eight centuries before succumbing, and exist today only through the most ancient form of devotional copying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an over‐elaborate way of saying that in as much as the era after the Roman Empire is “dark” it is because it has been overlaid by many centuries of further things happening—and I have talked only about human agency rather than the terrors of mold, mice, lightning and damp. Our own “library” at home suffered catastrophic loss from a house‐rabbit called Dusty who in his short life ate the spines of innumerable books. My copy of Hermann Hesse’s &lt;em&gt;Narcissus and Goldmund&lt;/em&gt; is cherished, partly because I have owned it for so long, but also because of its memorial teeth marks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When was the very last beautiful Roman fabric so sun‐rotted that it was chucked away? And that is as nothing compared to the almost totally successful attempts during the early Christian centuries in Europe to erase all trace of native paganism. This last issue is often overlooked. At the back of our minds when thinking about the centuries when the Roman Empire mutated into medieval Europe we are unconsciously taking on the spurious guise of specific communities. We are happy to read about Charlemagne destroying the Avar Empire and taking all its gold because at some level we emotionally sneak ourselves into Charlemagne’s baggage‐train. But the Avars ruled Central Europe for over two centuries, and it is not a given that their civilization had no worth and did not represent a future we would have flourished in.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;insert-post-ads&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Article continues after advertisement&lt;/span&gt;&lt;!-- /76722702/in_article_banner_3 --&gt;&amp;#13;
&lt;div id=&quot;div-gpt-ad-1530020181920-0&quot;&gt;&amp;#13;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or earlier, there are the Alemanni in what is now south‐west Germany and Alsace (and after whom the French call Germany Allemagne) who were broken by the Frankish ruler Clovis. Of course, we are the heirs of Christianity, but only in a passive, non‐contributive way—to see ourselves on one specific side in these ancient contests is awkward. I might hiss at the antics of the Saxons and Vikings, but as someone part English and part Irish I am much more likely to have their genes than Frankish ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These issues become vivid in the town of Tournai—for centuries a French‐ruled enclave squeezed between the County of Flanders and the County of Hainaut and now part of Belgium, a classic crossroads through which every army has marched, from the legionaries of the Roman Empire to Allied troops in 1944. I may as well say here that Tournai is a fantastic historical palimpsest and somewhere that always puts a spring in my step. I once found myself changing trains there late at night and realizing that I had just enough time to haul my bag up the road through the freezing dark to look in renewed wonder at the vast, somber drum—like a stonebuilt gasometer—of the Henry VIII Tower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this current context, however, what makes Tournai so remarkable is the discovery during routine repairs to the Hospice of St Brice in the 1650s of the tomb of Childeric I. This accidental find catapulted everything back some 250 years before Charlemagne, to the century after the Western Roman Empire had collapsed, a world which must have still been densely Roman in its appearance, probably with much smaller populations in towns and more limited trade. Childeric’s son, Clovis I, was baptized, united the Frankish tribes and founded the Merovingian dynasty which lasted until Charlemagne’s dad put the last of them into a monastery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;It was downhill for the hoard from then on.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The management of Childeric’s tomb has not exactly been a curatorial model. It started well as by sheer good luck Tournai was then part of the Spanish Netherlands under the benign and intelligent leadership of Archduke Leopold Wilhelm, who as part of his vast expenditure on art objects commissioned a superb book on the tomb from Jean‐Jacques Chifflet, an antiquarian from the Spanish‐ruled Franche‐Comté. This has immaculate pictures of the heaps of extraordinary stuff Childeric was buried with—gold objects of great variety and beauty from a bull’s head to coins, buckles, a crystal globe, seal‐rings and intricate pieces of cloisonné. It was downhill for the hoard from then on. Leopold Wilhelm took everything back to Vienna when he retired and left it to his nephew the Emperor Leopold I. He gave it to Louis XIV as a present but, in one of the many instances where Louis is so disappointing, he took no interest in the gifts and simply stored them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They survived the Revolution but were stolen in 1831 and dispersed or melted down. The hoard’s great aesthetic intervention came from its including dozens of small gold bees (or possibly cicadas), which must have decorated some object which had since rotted away, perhaps a cloak. In his search for an appropriate new symbol for his dynasty (the ancient fleur‐de‐lys being patently unacceptable to a new era) Napoleon decided to make these bees the imperial motif, scattering them on everything from coats of arms to Josephine’s slippers. They cluster all over the decorations of the French Empire and it is one of the sadder aspects of Napoleon’s defeat and exile that they disappear from the decorative arts until their rather wan revival under his nephew Napoleon III.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What remains in Tournai now however (aside from some reproduction bees) is a too‐good‐to‐be true archaeological museum which lays out everything we can still know about the huge scale of Childeric’s tomb and several associated burials. As his son Clovis turned Christian this was the last of the fabulous, full‐blown pagan Frankish affairs, with 21 cavalry horses buried nearby in an associated mound and what was clearly a sprawling sacred space with Childeric’s body at its center. An aristocratic woman buried nearby slightly later had objects such as scissors, amber and a wine‐strainer which linked her to trade across Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, the more time spent looking at these shield‐bosses, necklaces and pins (and not least a debonair and alarming scramasax—a wonderful word for a long knife), the more clear it becomes that this was a highly sophisticated, confident civilization—which just happened to exist a very long time ago and whose achievements were about to be completely disregarded by the new Christian regime of Clovis, who moved his capital from Tournai to Paris. The process by which Childeric’s tomb became forgotten cannot be pieced together as his dynastic significance lasted so long. Somehow, the King of the Salian Franks and his favorite horses, his crystal globe, bees, scramasax and all sank into oblivion, eventually disappearing completely under church buildings, until being summoned back to the surface nearly twelve hundred years later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;__________________________________&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id=&quot;112200&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://lithub.com/the-dark-ages-werent-as-dark-as-we-thought/lotharingia/&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://s26162.pcdn.co/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/lotharingia.jpg&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;350,525&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;lotharingia&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://s26162.pcdn.co/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/lotharingia-200x300.jpg&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://s26162.pcdn.co/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/lotharingia.jpg&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-112200 size-medium&quot; src=&quot;https://s26162.pcdn.co/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/lotharingia-200x300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; srcset=&quot;https://s26162.pcdn.co/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/lotharingia-200x300.jpg 200w, https://s26162.pcdn.co/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/lotharingia.jpg 350w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Excerpted from&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://us.macmillan.com/books/9780374192181&quot; class=&quot;external&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Lotharingia: A Personal History of Europe’s Lost Country&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; by Simon Winder. Published by Farrar, Straus and Giroux on April 23, 2019. Copyright © 2019 by Simon Winder. All rights reserved.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;ctx-article-root&quot;&gt;&lt;!-- --&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 17:08:33 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>kjaleshire</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>The ‘Dark Ages’ Weren’t As Dark As We Thought</og:title>
<og:url>https://lithub.com/the-dark-ages-werent-as-dark-as-we-thought/</og:url>
<og:description>There can be few more damning or more useless terms than “the Dark Ages.” They sound fun in an orcs‐and‐elves sort of way and suggest a very low benchmark from which we have since, as a…</og:description>
<og:image>https://s26162.pcdn.co/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/middle-ages.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://lithub.com/the-dark-ages-werent-as-dark-as-we-thought/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>New version of Stripe Checkout</title>
<link>https://stripe.com/docs/payments/checkout</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://stripe.com/docs/payments/checkout</guid>
<description>&lt;header readability=&quot;5.52&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The quickest way to build beautiful, conversion-optimized payment forms, hosted on Stripe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;important neutral&quot; readability=&quot;3.3793103448276&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This overview is for the new version of Stripe Checkout. For the legacy version of Checkout, see &lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/docs/checkout&quot;&gt;Checkout Reference&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/header&gt;&lt;section readability=&quot;10.108506363027&quot;&gt;&lt;aside class=&quot;note&quot; readability=&quot;6.6666666666667&quot;&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;migrating&quot;&gt;Migrating?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/docs/checkout&quot;&gt;legacy version&lt;/a&gt; of Checkout, read the &lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/docs/payments/checkout/migration&quot;&gt;Migration Guide&lt;/a&gt; for how to upgrade your integration to use the new version of Checkout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;beta-user&quot;&gt;Beta user?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are currently on a beta of the new version of Checkout, read the &lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/docs/payments/checkout/migration-from-beta&quot;&gt;Beta Migration Guide&lt;/a&gt; to upgrade to the latest version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;Start accepting payments with just a few lines of code. Checkout is a smart payment page that works seamlessly across devices and is designed to increase your conversion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Checkout includes support for:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Payment methods:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;credit and debit cards&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apple Pay (with no additional setup required)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Payment types:&lt;/strong&gt; one-time and recurring payments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Payment authentication:&lt;/strong&gt; dynamic &lt;span class=&quot;tooltip-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;tooltip-content&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/docs/payments/3d-secure&quot;&gt;3D Secure&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;key-popover&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;3D Secure&lt;/em&gt; provides an additional layer of authentication for credit card transactions that protects merchants from liability for fraudulent card payments. During a transaction that incorporates the 3D Secure authorization process, the customer is prompted to supply a separate password or code to validate their purchase.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; (ready for &lt;span class=&quot;tooltip-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;tooltip-content&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/docs/strong-customer-authentication&quot;&gt;Strong Customer Authentication&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;key-popover&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Strong Customer Authentication&lt;/em&gt; (SCA) is a new regulatory requirement coming into effect on September 14, 2019 which will impact many European online payments. It requires customers to use two-factor authentication like 3D Secure to verify their purchase.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Localization:&lt;/strong&gt; localized for &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.stripe.com/questions/supported-languages-for-stripe-checkout&quot;&gt;14 languages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Email receipts:&lt;/strong&gt; automatically send &lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/docs/receipts&quot;&gt;email receipts&lt;/a&gt; to your customers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Checkout is currently in active development. Visit our &lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/docs/payments/checkout#checkout-roadmap&quot;&gt;Roadmap&lt;/a&gt; to see what’s coming up next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/img/docs/checkout/overview.gif&quot; class=&quot;zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://stripe.com/img/docs/checkout/overview.gif&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section readability=&quot;6.3231132075472&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;see-how&quot;&gt;See how it works&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can try out Checkout now by clicking the Preview Checkout button below. This sample integration is running in test mode, which means that it won’t create a real charge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use one of Stripe’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/docs/testing&quot;&gt;test card numbers&lt;/a&gt; with any three-digit CVC code and an expiration date in the future to try it out:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;&lt;button id=&quot;preview-button&quot; type=&quot;submit&quot;&gt;Preview Checkout&lt;/button&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section readability=&quot;4.4545454545455&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;choose-your-integration-path&quot;&gt;Choose your integration path&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two ways to integrate with the new version of Checkout. Both integrations support core features, with minor differences. Review the information below to determine which one works best for your business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;comparison-table&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;comparison-table-col&quot;&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;feature-list&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Add products and plans in the Dashboard, then integrate with a client-side snippet&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Cannot associate payments with existing &lt;span class=&quot;tooltip-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;tooltip-content&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/docs/api/customers&quot;&gt;Customers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;key-popover&quot;&gt;Stripe &lt;em&gt;Customer&lt;/em&gt; objects allow you to perform recurring charges, and to track multiple charges, that are associated with the same customer.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Cannot use separate authorization and capture for card payments&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;No &lt;span class=&quot;tooltip-wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;tooltip-content&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/docs/connect&quot;&gt;Connect&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;key-popover&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Connect&lt;/em&gt; is Stripe’s solution for any business that needs to process payments and pay out to sellers and service providers.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; support&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;comparison-table-col&quot;&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;feature-list&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Pass in one-time payment information or subscription data from your server&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Can associate one-time payments with existing Customers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Can use &lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/docs/payments/checkout/server#separate-auth-capture&quot;&gt;separate authorization and capture&lt;/a&gt; for card payments&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Works with Connect&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section readability=&quot;8.6569872958258&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;supported-languages&quot;&gt;Supported languages&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By default, Checkout detects the locale of the customer’s browser and displays a translated version of the page in their language if it is &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.stripe.com/questions/supported-languages-for-stripe-checkout&quot;&gt;supported&lt;/a&gt;. You can also provide a specific locale for Checkout to use instead via the &lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/docs/stripe-js/reference#stripe-redirect-to-checkout&quot;&gt;client&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/docs/api/checkout/sessions/create#create_checkout_session-locale&quot;&gt;server&lt;/a&gt; integrations. Checkout also uses the locale to format numbers and currencies. For example, when selling a product whose price is set in EUR with the locale set to auto, a browser configured to use English (en) would see €25.00 while one configured for German (de) would see 25,00 €.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;checkout-roadmap&quot;&gt;Checkout roadmap&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the coming months, we plan to add more features to Stripe Checkout. Here are some of the features we’re considering:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Support for Google Pay (in addition to Apple Pay, which is already supported)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support for coupons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support for iDEAL, SEPA Debit, and other European payment methods, with the most relevant payment methods surfaced to the customer based on their country&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shipping address support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Better support for saving customer details and reusing saved payment methods&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability to pre-fill more customer details, such as contact and shipping information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section class=&quot;collect-email-guide&quot; id=&quot;checkout-updates&quot; readability=&quot;1.8947368421053&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;mask-container container-lg&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;collect-email-partial&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;intro-copy column&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;

&lt;form class=&quot;collect-form&quot; action=&quot;https://stripemail.createsend.com/t/d/s/shduru/&quot; readability=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;input class=&quot;email-field&quot; required=&quot;required&quot; type=&quot;email&quot; name=&quot;cm-shduru-shduru&quot; placeholder=&quot;Email&quot; value=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;button class=&quot;submit-button&quot; type=&quot;submit&quot;&gt;Get updates&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;collect-error email&quot;&gt;Please enter a valid email address.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;collect-error connection&quot;&gt;You might have had an internet hiccup. Try again?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/form&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;collect-success column&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;icon&quot; src=&quot;https://stripe.com/img/v3/common/success.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Green checkmark&quot;/&gt;&lt;h3 class=&quot;common-BodyTitle&quot;&gt;Thank you!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;common-BodyText&quot;&gt;Check your inbox to confirm your email address. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:checkout-feedback@stripe.com&quot;&gt;let us know&lt;/a&gt; how you would like to use Checkout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section/&gt;&lt;footer readability=&quot;9.7595907928389&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 data-no-anchor=&quot;&quot;&gt;Questions?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're always happy to help with code or other questions you might have! &lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/docs/payments/checkout#&quot; id=&quot;search-link&quot; class=&quot;search-link&quot;&gt;Search&lt;/a&gt; our documentation, &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.stripe.com/contact&quot;&gt;contact support&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/contact/sales&quot;&gt;connect with our sales team&lt;/a&gt;. You can also chat live with other developers in &lt;a href=&quot;irc://irc.freenode.net/stripe&quot;&gt;#stripe&lt;/a&gt; on freenode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-csat-step=&quot;poll&quot; class=&quot;csat-widget&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;csat-widget-text&quot;&gt;Was this page helpful?&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span data-csat-poll=&quot;yes&quot; class=&quot;csat-button csat-button-yes common-Button&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span data-csat-poll=&quot;no&quot; class=&quot;csat-button csat-button-no common-Button&quot;&gt;No&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-csat-step=&quot;input&quot; class=&quot;csat-widget&quot;&gt;&lt;input id=&quot;csat-input-text&quot; placeholder=&quot;Feedback about this page?&quot; class=&quot;common-Input&quot;/&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;csat-input-submit&quot; class=&quot;csat-button common-Link&quot;&gt;Send&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-csat-step=&quot;reply&quot; class=&quot;csat-widget&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;csat-reply-main&quot;&gt;Thank you for helping improve Stripe's documentation.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;csat-reply-extended&quot;&gt;If you need help or have any questions, please consider &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.stripe.com/email&quot;&gt;contacting support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/footer&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 15:51:55 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>dfabulich</dc:creator>
<og:title>Checkout Overview | Stripe Checkout</og:title>
<og:url>https://stripe.com/docs/payments/checkout</og:url>
<og:description>Online payment processing for internet businesses. Stripe is a suite of payment APIs that powers commerce for businesses of all sizes.</og:description>
<og:image>https://stripe.com/img/v3/home/social.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://stripe.com/docs/payments/checkout</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Show HN: Applying the Unix philosophy to neural networks</title>
<link>https://github.com/cloudkj/layer</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/cloudkj/layer</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;Box-body&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;markdown-body entry-content p-5&quot; itemprop=&quot;text&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;layer&lt;/code&gt; is a program for doing neural network inference the Unix way. Many modern neural network operations can be represented as sequential, unidirectional streams of data processed by pipelines of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Filter_(software)&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;filters&lt;/a&gt;. The computations at each layer in these neural networks are equivalent to an invocation of the &lt;code&gt;layer&lt;/code&gt; program, and multiple invocations can be chained together to represent the entirety of such networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, performing inference on a neural network with two fully-connected layers might look something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;cat input | layer full -w w.1 --input-shape=2 -f tanh | layer full -w w.2 --input-shape=3 -f sigmoid
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;layer&lt;/code&gt; applies the Unix philosophy to neural network inference. Each type of a neural network layer is a distinct subcommand. Simple text streams of delimited numeric values serve as the interface between different layers of a neural network. Each invocation of &lt;code&gt;layer&lt;/code&gt; does one thing: it feeds the numeric input values forward through an instantiation of a neural network layer, then emits the resulting output numeric values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Usage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Example: a convolutional neural network for &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/CIFAR-10&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;CIFAR-10&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
$ cat cifar10_x.csv \
    &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; layer convolutional -w w0.csv -b b0.csv --input-shape=32,32,3  --filter-shape=3,3 --num-filters=32 -f relu \
    &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; layer convolutional -w w1.csv -b b1.csv --input-shape=30,30,32 --filter-shape=3,3 --num-filters=32 -f relu \
    &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; layer pooling --input-shape=28,28,32 --filter-shape=2,2 --stride=2 -f max
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Example: a multi-layer perceptron for XOR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
$ &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt; Fully connected layer with three neurons&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;-2.35546875,-2.38671875,3.63671875,3.521484375,-2.255859375,-2.732421875&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; layer1.weights
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;0.7958984375,0.291259765625,1.099609375&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; layer1.biases

$ &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt; Fully connected layer with one neuron&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;-5.0625,-3.515625,-5.0625&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; layer2.weights
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;1.74609375&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; layer2.biases

$ &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt; Compute XOR for all possible binary inputs&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; -e &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;0,0\n0,1\n1,0\n1,1&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; \
    &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; layer full -w layer1.weights -b layer1.biases --input-shape=2 -f tanh \
    &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; layer full -w layer2.weights -b layer2.biases --input-shape=3 -f sigmoid
0.00129012749948779
0.99147053740106
0.991243357927591
0.0111237568184365
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Requirements: BLAS 3.6.0+&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Download a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/cloudkj/layer/releases&quot;&gt;release&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install BLAS 3.6.0+&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;On Debian-based systems: &lt;code&gt;apt-get install -y libblas3&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On RPM-based system: &lt;code&gt;yum install -y blas&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On macOS 10.3+, BLAS is pre-installed as part of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/documentation/accelerate/blas&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Accelerate framework&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ol start=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;Unzip the release and run &lt;code&gt;[sudo] ./install.sh&lt;/code&gt;, or manually relocate the binaries to the path of your choice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h2&gt;About&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;layer&lt;/code&gt; is currently implemented as a proof-of-concept and supports a limited number of neural network layer types. The types of layers are currently limited to feed-forward layers that can be modeled as sequential, unidirectional pipelines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Input values, weights and biases for parameterized layers, and output values are all read and written in &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Row-_and_column-major_order&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;row-major order&lt;/a&gt;, based on the shape parameters specified for each layer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;layer&lt;/code&gt; is implemented in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.call-cc.org/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;CHICKEN Scheme&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Copyright © 2018-2019&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 14:46:12 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>cloudkj</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars1.githubusercontent.com/u/227462?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>cloudkj/layer</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/cloudkj/layer</og:url>
<og:description>Neural network inference the Unix way. Contribute to cloudkj/layer development by creating an account on GitHub.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/cloudkj/layer</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Private Key Extraction from Qualcomm Hardware-Backed Keystores</title>
<link>https://www.nccgroup.trust/us/our-research/private-key-extraction-qualcomm-keystore/?research=Technical+advisories</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nccgroup.trust/us/our-research/private-key-extraction-qualcomm-keystore/?research=Technical+advisories</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nccgroup.trust/us/our-research/private-key-extraction-qualcomm-keystore/?research=Technical+advisories&quot;&gt;https://www.nccgroup.trust/us/our-research/private-key-extraction-qualcomm-keystore/?research=Technical+advisories&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19738394&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19738394&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 260&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 52&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 13:59:50 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>griffinmb</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nccgroup.trust/us/our-research/private-key-extraction-qualcomm-keystore/?research=Technical+advisories</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>OpenBSD 6.5</title>
<link>http://openbsd.org/65.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://openbsd.org/65.html</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;title&gt;OpenBSD 6.5&lt;/title&gt;&lt;meta http-equiv=&quot;Content-Type&quot; content=&quot;text/html; charset=utf-8&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;description&quot; content=&quot;OpenBSD 6.5&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;copyright&quot; content=&quot;This document copyright 2019 by OpenBSD.&quot; /&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;viewport&quot; content=&quot;width=device-width, initial-scale=1&quot; /&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot; href=&quot;openbsd.css&quot; /&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;canonical&quot; href=&quot;https://www.openbsd.org/65.html&quot; /&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body bgcolor=&quot;#FFFFFF&quot; text=&quot;#000000&quot; link=&quot;#24248E&quot; id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot; readability=&quot;86.304364268966&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openbsd.org/images/Puffystock.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;img align=&quot;left&quot; width=&quot;227&quot; height=&quot;343&quot; hspace=&quot;24&quot; src=&quot;https://www.openbsd.org/images/Puffystock-s.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Released May 1, 2019&lt;br /&gt;Copyright 1997-2019, Theo de Raadt.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Artwork by Hans Tseng, Efrain Farias, and Natasha Allegri.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;0.421875&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;See the information on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openbsd.org/ftp.html&quot;&gt;the FTP page&lt;/a&gt; for a list of mirror machines.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to the &lt;span&gt;pub/OpenBSD/6.5/&lt;/span&gt; directory on one of the mirror sites.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have a look at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openbsd.org/errata65.html&quot;&gt;the 6.5 errata page&lt;/a&gt; for a list of bugs and workarounds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;See a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openbsd.org/plus65.html&quot;&gt;detailed log of changes&lt;/a&gt; between the 6.4 and 6.5 releases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;3.4730538922156&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/signify.1&quot;&gt;signify(1)&lt;/a&gt; pubkeys for this release:
&lt;table cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;3.2820512820513&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.54545454545455&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;openbsd-65-base.pub:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ftp.openbsd.org/pub/OpenBSD/6.5/openbsd-65-base.pub&quot;&gt;RWSZaRmt1LEQT9CtPygf9CvONu8kYPTlVEJdysNoUR62/NkeWgdkc3zY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;openbsd-65-fw.pub:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;RWQYdGVtTv5IvpH2c+TLQAC4iV7RjoGZ/v75q8MCuC9Mca7nFVCXRefy&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;openbsd-65-pkg.pub:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;RWS5D4+188RI6jULDOFzga0Cm1zrXYUAHT6xu0mLrZidbn6xrMB5aZeR&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;openbsd-65-syspatch.pub:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;RWT8U2yd3Aq5DnetILjmSoCQxmyt3VqfGS7GBh19oh4Xre4ywc31PEpw&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;All applicable copyrights and credits are in the src.tar.gz, sys.tar.gz, xenocara.tar.gz, ports.tar.gz files, or in the files fetched via ports.tar.gz.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;new&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;What's New&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a partial list of new features and systems included in OpenBSD 6.5. For a comprehensive list, see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openbsd.org/plus65.html&quot;&gt;changelog&lt;/a&gt; leading to 6.5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Improved hardware support, including:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/clang.1&quot;&gt;clang(1)&lt;/a&gt; is now provided on mips64.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The default linker has been switched from the binutils bfd-based linker to lld on amd64 and i386.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;octeon: Now the system automatically detects the number of available cores. However, manual setting of the numcores, or coremask, boot parameter is still needed to enable secondary cores.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;octeon: It is now possible to use the root disk's DUID as the value of the rootdev boot parameter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/octeon/octgpio.4&quot;&gt;octgpio(4)&lt;/a&gt; driver for the OCTEON GPIO controller.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/pvclock.4&quot;&gt;pvclock(4)&lt;/a&gt; driver for KVM paravirtual clock.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/ixl.4&quot;&gt;ixl(4)&lt;/a&gt; driver for Intel Ethernet 700 series controller devices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/abcrtc.4&quot;&gt;abcrtc(4)&lt;/a&gt; driver for Abracon AB1805 real-time clock.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/imxsrc.4&quot;&gt;imxsrc(4)&lt;/a&gt; driver for i.MX system reset controller.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/uxrcom.4&quot;&gt;uxrcom(4)&lt;/a&gt; driver for Exar XR21V1410 USB serial adapters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/mvgicp.4&quot;&gt;mvgicp(4)&lt;/a&gt; driver for Marvell ARMADA 7K/8K GICP controller.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support for QCA AR816x/AR817x in &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/alc.4&quot;&gt;alc(4)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support for isochronous transfers in &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/xhci.4&quot;&gt;xhci(4)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/uaudio.4&quot;&gt;uaudio(4)&lt;/a&gt; has been replaced by a new driver which supports USB audio class v2.0.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved support for &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/nmea.4&quot;&gt;nmea(4)&lt;/a&gt; devices, providing altitude and ground speed values as sensors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IEEE 802.11 wireless stack improvements:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Reduced usage of RTS frames improves overall throughput and latency.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved transmit rate selection in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/iwm.4&quot;&gt;iwm(4)&lt;/a&gt; driver.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved radio hardware calibration in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/athn.4&quot;&gt;athn(4)&lt;/a&gt; driver.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/bwfm.4&quot;&gt;bwfm(4)&lt;/a&gt; driver now provides more accurate device configuration information to userland.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added new routing socket message RTM_80211INFO to provide details of 802.11 interface state changes to &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/dhclient&quot;&gt;dhclient(8)&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/route&quot;&gt;route(8)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If an auto-join list is configured, wireless interfaces will no longer connect to unknown open networks by default. This behaviour must now be explicitly enabled by adding the empty network name to the auto-join list, e.g. &lt;tt&gt;ifconfig iwm0 join &quot;&quot;&lt;/tt&gt;, or &lt;tt&gt;join &quot;&quot;&lt;/tt&gt; in hostname.if files.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/iwn.4&quot;&gt;iwn(4)&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/iwm.4&quot;&gt;iwm(4)&lt;/a&gt; drivers will now automatically try to connect to a network if the radio kill switch is toggled to allow radio transmissions while the interface is marked UP.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generic network stack improvements:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;New &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/bpe.4&quot;&gt;bpe(4)&lt;/a&gt; Backbone Provider Edge pseudo-device.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/mpip.4&quot;&gt;mpip(4)&lt;/a&gt; MPLS IP layer 2 pseudowire driver.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MPLS encapsulation interfaces support configuration of alternative MPLS route domains.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/vlan.4&quot;&gt;vlan(4)&lt;/a&gt; driver bypasses queue processing and outputs directly to the parent interface.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New per SAD counters visible via &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/ipsecctl.8&quot;&gt;ipsecctl(8)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/bpf.4&quot;&gt;bpf(4)&lt;/a&gt; filter drop mechanism has been extended to allow dropping without capturing packets, and use of the mechanism with &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/tcpdump.8&quot;&gt;tcpdump(8)&lt;/a&gt; as a filtering mechanism early in the device receive path.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/ifconfig.8&quot;&gt;ifconfig(8)&lt;/a&gt; gains &lt;tt&gt;txprio&lt;/tt&gt; for controlling the encoding of priority in tunnel headers, and support in drivers including &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/vlan.4&quot;&gt;vlan(4)&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/gre.4&quot;&gt;gre(4)&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/gif.4&quot;&gt;gif(4)&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/etherip.4&quot;&gt;etherip(4)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Installer improvements:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/rdsetroot.8&quot;&gt;rdsetroot(8)&lt;/a&gt; (a build-time tool) is now available for general use.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;During upgrades, some components of old releases are deleted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Security improvements:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/unveil.2&quot;&gt;unveil(2)&lt;/a&gt; has been improved to understand and find covering unveil matches above the working directory of the running process for relative path accesses. As a result many programs now can use unveil in broad ways such as unveil(&quot;/&quot;, &quot;r&quot;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/unveil.2&quot;&gt;unveil(2)&lt;/a&gt; no longer silently allows &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/stat.2&quot;&gt;stat(2)&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/access.2&quot;&gt;access(2)&lt;/a&gt; to work on any unveiled path component.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now using &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/unveil.2&quot;&gt;unveil(2)&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/ospfd&quot;&gt;ospfd(8)&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/ospf6d&quot;&gt;ospf6d(8)&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/rebound&quot;&gt;rebound(8)&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/getconf&quot;&gt;getconf(1)&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/kvm_mkdb&quot;&gt;kvm_mkdb(8)&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/bdftopcf&quot;&gt;bdftopcf(1)&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/Xserver&quot;&gt;Xserver(1)&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/passwd&quot;&gt;passwd(1)&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/spamlogd&quot;&gt;spamlogd(8)&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/spamd&quot;&gt;spamd(8)&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/sensorsd&quot;&gt;sensorsd(8)&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/snmpd&quot;&gt;snmpd(8)&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/htpasswd&quot;&gt;htpasswd(1)&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/ifstated&quot;&gt;ifstated(8)&lt;/a&gt;. Some &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/pledge.2&quot;&gt;pledge(2)&lt;/a&gt; changes were required to accommodate unveil.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ROP mitigations in &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/clang-local.1&quot;&gt;clang(1)&lt;/a&gt; have been improved, resulting in a significant decrease in the number of polymorphic ROP gadgets in binaries on i386/amd64.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RETGUARD performance and security has been improved in &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/clang-local.1&quot;&gt;clang(1)&lt;/a&gt; by keeping data on registers instead of on the stack when possible, and lengthening the epilogue trapsled on amd64 to consume the rest of the cache line before the return.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RETGUARD replaces the stack protector on amd64 and arm64, since RETGUARD instruments every function that returns and provides better security properties than the traditional stack protector.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Routing daemons and other userland network improvements:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/pcap-filter.3&quot;&gt;pcap-filter(3)&lt;/a&gt; can now filter on MPLS packets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The routing priority for &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/ospfd.8&quot;&gt;ospfd(8)&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/ospf6d.8&quot;&gt;ospf6d(8)&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/ripd.8&quot;&gt;ripd(8)&lt;/a&gt; is now configurable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/ripd.8&quot;&gt;ripd(8)&lt;/a&gt; is now pledged.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First release of &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/unwind.8&quot;&gt;unwind(8)&lt;/a&gt;, a validating, recursive nameserver for 127.0.0.1. It is particularly suitable for laptops moving between networks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/ifconfig.8&quot;&gt;ifconfig(8)&lt;/a&gt; gains &lt;tt&gt;sff&lt;/tt&gt; and &lt;tt&gt;sffdump&lt;/tt&gt; modes, displaying diagnostic information from fibre transceivers and similar modules. Currently &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/ix.4&quot;&gt;ix(4)&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/ixl.4&quot;&gt;ixl(4)&lt;/a&gt; are supported.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/ldpd.8&quot;&gt;ldpd(8)&lt;/a&gt; now supports &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/ldpd.conf.5&quot;&gt;configuration of TCP MD5&lt;/a&gt; for networks, not just specific neighbors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/bgpd.8&quot;&gt;bgpd(8)&lt;/a&gt; improvements:
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assorted improvements:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/kcov.4&quot;&gt;kcov(4)&lt;/a&gt; gained support for &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/kcov#KCOV_MODE_TRACE_CMP&quot;&gt;KCOV_MODE_TRACE_CMP&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A 'video' promise was added to &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/pledge.2&quot;&gt;pledge(2)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;code&gt;kern.witnesswatch&lt;/code&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/sysctl.8&quot;&gt;sysctl(8)&lt;/a&gt; has been renamed to &lt;code&gt;kern.witness.watch&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New pthread &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/pthread_rwlock_init&quot;&gt;rwlock&lt;/a&gt; implementation improving latency of threaded applications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/kubsan.4&quot;&gt;kubsan(4)&lt;/a&gt; capable of detecting undefined behavior in the kernel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/signify.1&quot;&gt;signify&lt;/a&gt; -n option to zero date header in -z mode.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove OXTABS from default pty flags.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/install.1&quot;&gt;install(1)&lt;/a&gt; now always copies files safely (as with -S), avoiding race conditions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/syslog.conf.5&quot;&gt;syslog.conf(5)&lt;/a&gt; now supports program names containing dots and underscores.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/tcpdump.8&quot;&gt;tcpdump(8)&lt;/a&gt; already used privsep, &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/pledge.2&quot;&gt;pledge(2)&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/unveil.2&quot;&gt;unveil(2)&lt;/a&gt; containment. It now also drops root privileges completely (switching to a reserved uid).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The multi-threaded performance of &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/malloc.3&quot;&gt;malloc(3)&lt;/a&gt; has been improved.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/malloc.3&quot;&gt;malloc(3)&lt;/a&gt; now uses &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/sysctl.2&quot;&gt;sysctl(2)&lt;/a&gt; to get its settings, making it respect the system-wide settings in chroots as well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Various improvements to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/join.1&quot;&gt;join&lt;/a&gt; command.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work has started on a ISC-licensed rsync-compatible program called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openrsync.org&quot;&gt;OpenRSYNC&lt;/a&gt;. In this release it has basic functionality such as &lt;strong&gt;-a&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;--delete&lt;/strong&gt;, but lacks &lt;strong&gt;--exclude&lt;/strong&gt;. Work will continue.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New Spleen font 8x16, 12x24, 16x32 and 32x64 variants added and enabled in wsfont, along with font selection logic to allow selecting larger fonts when available at runtime in &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/rasops.9&quot;&gt;rasops(9)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OpenSMTPD 6.5.0
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;New Features
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Added the new matching criteria &quot;from rdns&quot; to &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/smtpd.conf.5&quot;&gt;smtpd.conf(5)&lt;/a&gt; to allow matching of sessions based on the reverse DNS of the client.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/regex.3&quot;&gt;regex(3)&lt;/a&gt; support to table lookups in &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/smtpd.conf.5&quot;&gt;smtpd.conf(5)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LibreSSL 2.9.1
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;API and Documentation Enhancements
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;CRYPTO_LOCK is now automatically initialized, with the legacy callbacks stubbed for compatibility.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added the SM3 hash function from the Chinese standard GB/T 32905-2016.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added the SM4 block cipher from the Chinese standard GB/T 32907-2016.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added more OPENSSL_NO_* macros for compatibility with OpenSSL.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Partial port of the OpenSSL EC_KEY_METHOD API for use by OpenSSH.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implemented further missing OpenSSL 1.1 API.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added support for XChaCha20 and XChaCha20-Poly1305.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added support for AES key wrap constructions via the EVP interface.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compatibility Changes
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Added pbkdf2 key derivation support to &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/openssl.1&quot;&gt;openssl(1)&lt;/a&gt; enc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed the default digest type of &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/openssl.1&quot;&gt;openssl(1)&lt;/a&gt; enc to sha256.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed the default digest type of &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/openssl.1&quot;&gt;openssl(1)&lt;/a&gt; dgst to sha256.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed the default digest type of &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/openssl.1&quot;&gt;openssl(1)&lt;/a&gt; x509 -fingerprint to sha256.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed the default digest type of &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/openssl.1&quot;&gt;openssl(1)&lt;/a&gt; crl -fingerprint to sha256.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Testing and Proactive Security
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Added extensive interoperability tests between LibreSSL and OpenSSL 1.0 and 1.1.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added additional Wycheproof tests and related bug fixes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Internal Improvements
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Simplified sigalgs option processing and handshake signing algorithm selection.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added the ability to use the RSA PSS algorithm for handshake signatures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added bn_rand_interval() and use it in code needing ranges of random bn values.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added functionality to derive early, handshake, and application secrets as per RFC8446.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added handshake state machine from RFC8446.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed some ASN.1 related code from libcrypto that had not been used since around 2000.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unexported internal symbols and internalized more record layer structs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed SHA224 based handshake signatures from consideration for use in a TLS 1.2 handshake.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Portable Improvements
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Added support for assembly optimizations on 32-bit ARM ELF targets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added support for assembly optimizations on Mingw-w64 targets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved Android compatibility&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bug Fixes
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Improved protection against timing side channels in ECDSA signature generation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coordinate blinding was added to some elliptic curves. This is the last bit of the work by Brumley et al. to protect against the Portsmash vulnerability.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ensure transcript handshake is always freed with TLS 1.2.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OpenSSH 8.0
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;New Features
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;ssh(1), ssh-agent(1), ssh-add(1): Add support for ECDSA keys in PKCS#11 tokens.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ssh(1), sshd(8): Add experimental quantum-computing resistant key exchange method, based on a combination of Streamlined NTRU Prime 4591^761 and X25519.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ssh-keygen(1): Increase the default RSA key size to 3072 bits, following NIST Special Publication 800-57's guidance for a 128-bit equivalent symmetric security level.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ssh(1): Allow &quot;PKCS11Provider=none&quot; to override later instances of the PKCS11Provider directive in ssh_config; bz#2974&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sshd(8): Add a log message for situations where a connection is dropped for attempting to run a command but a sshd_config ForceCommand=internal-sftp restriction is in effect; bz#2960&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ssh(1): When prompting whether to record a new host key, accept the key fingerprint as a synonym for &quot;yes&quot;. This allows the user to paste a fingerprint obtained out of band at the prompt and have the client do the comparison for you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ssh-keygen(1): When signing multiple certificates on a single command-line invocation, allow automatically incrementing the certificate serial number.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;scp(1), sftp(1): Accept -J option as an alias to ProxyJump on the scp and sftp command-lines.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ssh-agent(1), ssh-pkcs11-helper(8), ssh-add(1): Accept &quot;-v&quot; command-line flags to increase the verbosity of output; pass verbose flags though to subprocesses, such as ssh-pkcs11-helper started from ssh-agent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ssh-add(1): Add a &quot;-T&quot; option to allowing testing whether keys in an agent are usable by performing a signature and a verification.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sftp-server(8): Add a &quot;lsetstat@openssh.com&quot; protocol extension that replicates the functionality of the existing SSH2_FXP_SETSTAT operation but does not follow symlinks. bz#2067&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sftp(1): Add &quot;-h&quot; flag to chown/chgrp/chmod commands to request they do not follow symlinks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sshd(8): Expose $SSH_CONNECTION in the PAM environment. This makes the connection 4-tuple available to PAM modules that wish to use it in decision-making. bz#2741&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sshd(8): Add a ssh_config &quot;Match final&quot; predicate Matches in same pass as &quot;Match canonical&quot; but doesn't require hostname canonicalisation be enabled. bz#2906&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sftp(1): Support a prefix of '@' to suppress echo of sftp batch commands; bz#2926&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ssh-keygen(1): When printing certificate contents using &quot;ssh-keygen -Lf /path/certificate&quot;, include the algorithm that the CA used to sign the cert.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugfixes
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;sshd(8): Fix authentication failures when sshd_config contains &quot;AuthenticationMethods any&quot; inside a Match block that overrides a more restrictive default.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sshd(8): Avoid sending duplicate keepalives when ClientAliveCount is enabled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sshd(8): Fix two race conditions related to SIGHUP daemon restart. Remnant file descriptors in recently-forked child processes could block the parent sshd's attempt to listen(2) to the configured addresses. Also, the restarting parent sshd could exit before any child processes that were awaiting their re-execution state had completed reading it, leaving them in a fallback path.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ssh(1): Fix stdout potentially being redirected to /dev/null when ProxyCommand=- was in use.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sshd(8): Avoid sending SIGPIPE to child processes if they attempt to write to stderr after their parent processes have exited; bz#2071&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ssh(1): Fix bad interaction between the ssh_config ConnectTimeout and ConnectionAttempts directives - connection attempts after the first were ignoring the requested timeout; bz#2918&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ssh-keyscan(1): Return a non-zero exit status if no keys were found; bz#2903&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;scp(1): Sanitize scp filenames to allow UTF-8 characters without terminal control sequences; bz#2434&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sshd(8): Fix confusion between ClientAliveInterval and time-based RekeyLimit that could cause connections to be incorrectly closed. bz#2757&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ssh(1), ssh-add(1): Correct some bugs in PKCS#11 token PIN handling at initial token login. The attempt to read the PIN could be skipped in some cases, particularly on devices with integrated PIN readers. This would lead to an inability to retrieve keys from these tokens. bz#2652&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ssh(1), ssh-add(1): Support keys on PKCS#11 tokens that set the CKA_ALWAYS_AUTHENTICATE flag by requring a fresh login after the C_SignInit operation. bz#2638&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ssh(1): Improve documentation for ProxyJump/-J, clarifying that local configuration does not apply to jump hosts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ssh-keygen(1): Clarify manual - ssh-keygen -e only writes public keys, not private.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ssh(1), sshd(8): be more strict in processing protocol banners, allowing \r characters only immediately before \n.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Various: fix a number of memory leaks, including bz#2942 and bz#2938&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;scp(1), sftp(1): fix calculation of initial bandwidth limits. Account for bytes written before the timer starts and adjust the schedule on which recalculations are performed. Avoids an initial burst of traffic and yields more accurate bandwidth limits; bz#2927&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sshd(8): Only consider the ext-info-c extension during the initial key eschange. It shouldn't be sent in subsequent ones, but if it is present we should ignore it. This prevents sshd from sending a SSH_MSG_EXT_INFO for REKEX for buggy these clients. bz#2929&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ssh-keygen(1): Clarify manual that ssh-keygen -F (find host in authorized_keys) and -R (remove host from authorized_keys) options may accept either a bare hostname or a [hostname]:port combo. bz#2935&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ssh(1): Don't attempt to connect to empty SSH_AUTH_SOCK; bz#2936&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sshd(8): Silence error messages when sshd fails to load some of the default host keys. Failure to load an explicitly-configured hostkey is still an error, and failure to load any host key is still fatal. pr/103&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ssh(1): Redirect stderr of ProxyCommands to /dev/null when ssh is started with ControlPersist; prevents random ProxyCommand output from interfering with session output.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ssh(1): The ssh client was keeping a redundant ssh-agent socket (leftover from authentication) around for the life of the connection; bz#2912&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sshd(8): Fix bug in HostbasedAcceptedKeyTypes and PubkeyAcceptedKeyTypes options. If only RSA-SHA2 siganture types were specified, then authentication would always fail for RSA keys as the monitor checks only the base key (not the signature algorithm) type against *AcceptedKeyTypes. bz#2746&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ssh(1): Request correct signature types from ssh-agent when certificate keys and RSA-SHA2 signatures are in use.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mandoc 1.14.5
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Improved POSIX compliance in &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/apropos.1&quot;&gt;apropos(1)&lt;/a&gt; by accepting case-insensitive extended regular expressions by default.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New -O &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/mandoc.1#tag&quot;&gt;tag&lt;/a&gt; output option to open a page at the definition of a term.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/tbl.7&quot;&gt;tbl(7)&lt;/a&gt; improvements: line drawing, spanning, horizontal and vertical alignment in HTML output, improved column width calculations in terminal output, use of box drawing characters in UTF-8 output.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Much better HTML output, in particular with respect to paragraphs, line breaks, and vertical spacing in tagged lists. Tooltips are now implemented in pure CSS, the &lt;code&gt;title&lt;/code&gt; attribute is no longer abused.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Xenocara
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/Xorg.1&quot;&gt;Xorg(1)&lt;/a&gt;, the X window server, is no longer installed setuid. &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/xenodm.1&quot;&gt;xenodm(1)&lt;/a&gt; should be used to start X.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The radeonsi Mesa driver is now included for hardware acceleration on Southern Islands and Sea Islands &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/radeondrm.4&quot;&gt;radeondrm(4)&lt;/a&gt; devices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ports and packages:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;C++ ports for non-clang architectures are now compiled with ports gcc, so that more packages can be provided.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;dl&gt;&lt;dt&gt;Many pre-built packages for each architecture:&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; cellpadding=&quot;2&quot; width=&quot;95%&quot; readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; width=&quot;25%&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;aarch64: 9654&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;amd64: 10602&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;arm: XXXX&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; width=&quot;25%&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;i386: 10535&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;mips64: XXXX&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;mips64el: XXXX&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; width=&quot;25%&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;powerpc: XXXX&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sparc64: XXXX&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;dl&gt;&lt;dt&gt;Some highlights:&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; cellpadding=&quot;2&quot; width=&quot;95%&quot; readability=&quot;7.5&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;15&quot;&gt;&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; width=&quot;25%&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;AFL 2.52b&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Asterisk 16.2.1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Audacity 2.3.1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CMake 3.10.2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chromium 73.0.3683.86&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Emacs 26.1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FFmpeg 4.1.3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GCC 4.9.4 and 8.3.0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GHC 8.2.2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GNOME 3.30.2.1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go 1.12.1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Groff 1.22.4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JDK 8u202 and 11.0.2+9-3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; width=&quot;25%&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;LLVM/Clang 7.0.1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LibreOffice 6.2.2.2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lua 5.1.5, 5.2.4 and 5.3.5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MariaDB 10.0.38&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mono 5.18.1.0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mozilla Firefox 66.0.2 and ESR 60.6.1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mozilla Thunderbird 60.6.1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mutt 1.11.4 and NeoMutt 20180716&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Node.js 10.15.0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OCaml 4.07.1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OpenLDAP 2.3.43 and 2.4.47&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PHP 7.1.28, 7.2.17 and 7.3.4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Postfix 3.3.3 and 3.4.20190106&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; width=&quot;25%&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;PostgreSQL 11.2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python 2.7.16 and 3.6.8&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;R 3.5.3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ruby 2.4.6, 2.5.5 and 2.6.2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rust 1.33.0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sendmail 8.16.0.41&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SQLite3 3.27.2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sudo 1.8.27&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Suricata 4.1.3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tcl/Tk 8.5.19 and 8.6.8&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TeX Live 2018&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vim 8.1.1048 and Neovim 0.3.4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Xfce 4.12&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As usual, steady improvements in manual pages and other documentation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The system includes the following major components from outside suppliers:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Xenocara (based on X.Org 7.7 with xserver 1.19.7 + patches, freetype 2.9.1, fontconfig 2.12.4, Mesa 18.3.5, xterm 344, xkeyboard-config 2.20 and more)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LLVM/Clang 7.0.1 (+ patches)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GCC 4.2.1 (+ patches) and 3.3.6 (+ patches)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perl 5.28.1 (+ patches)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NSD 4.1.27&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unbound 1.9.1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ncurses 5.7&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Binutils 2.17 (+ patches)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gdb 6.3 (+ patches)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Awk Aug 10, 2011 version&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expat 2.2.6&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;install&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;How to install&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please refer to the following files on the mirror site for extensive details on how to install OpenBSD 6.5 on your machine:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Quick installer information for people familiar with OpenBSD, and the use of the &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/disklabel.8&quot;&gt;disklabel&lt;/a&gt; -E&quot; command. If you are at all confused when installing OpenBSD, read the relevant INSTALL.* file as listed above!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span&gt;OpenBSD/alpha:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Write &lt;em&gt;floppy65.fs&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;floppyB65.fs&lt;/em&gt; (depending on your machine) to a diskette and enter &lt;em&gt;boot dva0&lt;/em&gt;. Refer to INSTALL.alpha for more details.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure you use a properly formatted floppy with NO BAD BLOCKS or your install will most likely fail.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span&gt;OpenBSD/amd64:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;If your machine can boot from CD, you can write &lt;em&gt;install65.iso&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;cd65.iso&lt;/em&gt; to a CD and boot from it. You may need to adjust your BIOS options first.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If your machine can boot from USB, you can write &lt;em&gt;install65.fs&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;miniroot65.fs&lt;/em&gt; to a USB stick and boot from it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you can't boot from a CD, floppy disk, or USB, you can install across the network using PXE as described in the included INSTALL.amd64 document.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you are planning to dual boot OpenBSD with another OS, you will need to read INSTALL.amd64.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span&gt;OpenBSD/arm64:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Write &lt;em&gt;miniroot65.fs&lt;/em&gt; to a disk and boot from it after connecting to the serial console. Refer to INSTALL.arm64 for more details.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span&gt;OpenBSD/armv7:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Write a system specific miniroot to an SD card and boot from it after connecting to the serial console. Refer to INSTALL.armv7 for more details.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span&gt;OpenBSD/hppa:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Boot over the network by following the instructions in INSTALL.hppa or the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openbsd.org/hppa.html#install&quot;&gt;hppa platform page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span&gt;OpenBSD/i386:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;If your machine can boot from CD, you can write &lt;em&gt;install65.iso&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;cd65.iso&lt;/em&gt; to a CD and boot from it. You may need to adjust your BIOS options first.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If your machine can boot from USB, you can write &lt;em&gt;install65.fs&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;miniroot65.fs&lt;/em&gt; to a USB stick and boot from it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you can't boot from a CD, floppy disk, or USB, you can install across the network using PXE as described in the included INSTALL.i386 document.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you are planning on dual booting OpenBSD with another OS, you will need to read INSTALL.i386.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span&gt;OpenBSD/landisk:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Write &lt;em&gt;miniroot65.fs&lt;/em&gt; to the start of the CF or disk, and boot normally.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span&gt;OpenBSD/loongson:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Write &lt;em&gt;miniroot65.fs&lt;/em&gt; to a USB stick and boot bsd.rd from it or boot bsd.rd via tftp. Refer to the instructions in INSTALL.loongson for more details.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span&gt;OpenBSD/luna88k:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Copy `boot' and `bsd.rd' to a Mach or UniOS partition, and boot the bootloader from the PROM, and then bsd.rd from the bootloader. Refer to the instructions in INSTALL.luna88k for more details.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span&gt;OpenBSD/macppc:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Burn the image from a mirror site to a CDROM, and power on your machine while holding down the &lt;em&gt;C&lt;/em&gt; key until the display turns on and shows &lt;em&gt;OpenBSD/macppc boot&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alternatively, at the Open Firmware prompt, enter &lt;em&gt;boot cd:,ofwboot /6.5/macppc/bsd.rd&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span&gt;OpenBSD/octeon:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;After connecting a serial port, boot bsd.rd over the network via DHCP/tftp. Refer to the instructions in INSTALL.octeon for more details.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span&gt;OpenBSD/sgi:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;To install, burn cd65.iso on a CD-R, put it in the CD drive of your machine and select &lt;em&gt;Install System Software&lt;/em&gt; from the System Maintenance menu. Indigo/Indy/Indigo2 (R4000) systems will not boot automatically from CD-ROM, and need a proper invocation from the PROM prompt. Refer to the instructions in INSTALL.sgi for more details.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If your machine doesn't have a CD drive, you can setup a DHCP/tftp network server, and boot using &quot;bootp()/bsd.rd.IP##&quot; using the kernel matching your system type. Refer to the instructions in INSTALL.sgi for more details.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span&gt;OpenBSD/sparc64:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Burn the image from a mirror site to a CDROM, boot from it, and type &lt;em&gt;boot cdrom&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If this doesn't work, or if you don't have a CDROM drive, you can write &lt;em&gt;floppy65.fs&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;floppyB65.fs&lt;/em&gt; (depending on your machine) to a floppy and boot it with &lt;em&gt;boot floppy&lt;/em&gt;. Refer to INSTALL.sparc64 for details.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure you use a properly formatted floppy with NO BAD BLOCKS or your install will most likely fail.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can also write &lt;em&gt;miniroot65.fs&lt;/em&gt; to the swap partition on the disk and boot with &lt;em&gt;boot disk:b&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If nothing works, you can boot over the network as described in INSTALL.sparc64.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;upgrade&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;How to upgrade&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you already have an OpenBSD 6.4 system, and do not want to reinstall, upgrade instructions and advice can be found in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openbsd.org/faq/upgrade65.html&quot;&gt;Upgrade Guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;sourcecode&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Notes about the source code&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;tt&gt;src.tar.gz&lt;/tt&gt; contains a source archive starting at &lt;tt&gt;/usr/src&lt;/tt&gt;. This file contains everything you need except for the kernel sources, which are in a separate archive. To extract:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
# &lt;strong&gt;mkdir -p /usr/src&lt;/strong&gt;
# &lt;strong&gt;cd /usr/src&lt;/strong&gt;
# &lt;strong&gt;tar xvfz /tmp/src.tar.gz&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;tt&gt;sys.tar.gz&lt;/tt&gt; contains a source archive starting at &lt;tt&gt;/usr/src/sys&lt;/tt&gt;. This file contains all the kernel sources you need to rebuild kernels. To extract:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
# &lt;strong&gt;mkdir -p /usr/src/sys&lt;/strong&gt;
# &lt;strong&gt;cd /usr/src&lt;/strong&gt;
# &lt;strong&gt;tar xvfz /tmp/sys.tar.gz&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both of these trees are a regular CVS checkout. Using these trees it is possible to get a head-start on using the anoncvs servers as described &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openbsd.org/anoncvs.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Using these files results in a much faster initial CVS update than you could expect from a fresh checkout of the full OpenBSD source tree.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;ports&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Ports Tree&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A ports tree archive is also provided. To extract:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
# &lt;strong&gt;cd /usr&lt;/strong&gt;
# &lt;strong&gt;tar xvfz /tmp/ports.tar.gz&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go read the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openbsd.org/faq/ports/index.html&quot;&gt;ports&lt;/a&gt; page if you know nothing about ports at this point. This text is not a manual of how to use ports. Rather, it is a set of notes meant to kickstart the user on the OpenBSD ports system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;ports/&lt;/em&gt; directory represents a CVS checkout of our ports. As with our complete source tree, our ports tree is available via &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openbsd.org/anoncvs.html&quot;&gt;AnonCVS&lt;/a&gt;. So, in order to keep up to date with the -stable branch, you must make the &lt;em&gt;ports/&lt;/em&gt; tree available on a read-write medium and update the tree with a command like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
# &lt;strong&gt;cd /usr/ports&lt;/strong&gt;
# &lt;strong&gt;cvs -d anoncvs@server.openbsd.org:/cvs update -Pd -rOPENBSD_6_5&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Of course, you must replace the server name here with a nearby anoncvs server.]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that most ports are available as packages on our mirrors. Updated ports for the 6.5 release will be made available if problems arise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're interested in seeing a port added, would like to help out, or just would like to know more, the mailing list &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openbsd.org/mail.html&quot;&gt;ports@openbsd.org&lt;/a&gt; is a good place to know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 13:32:49 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>vetelko</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.openbsd.org/65.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>NYC scientist fired after raising questions about a DNA test gets $1M settlement</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/04/23/nyregion/dna-testing-nyc-medical-examiner.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2019/04/23/nyregion/dna-testing-nyc-medical-examiner.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;[What you need to know to start the day:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/newsletters/newyorktoday?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Get New York Today in your inbox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;css-2fg4z9 e1gzwzxm0&quot;&gt;.]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Officials from the chief medical examiner’s office in New York City were furious when they heard that Marina Stajic, one of their longest-serving laboratory directors, had openly questioned whether they had sufficiently verified the reliability of a novel form of DNA testing being used in criminal cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Ms. Stajic was concerned that incorrect use of the DNA testing technique could lead to wrongful convictions, she said. But her bosses took her questioning in a different light.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“Hold me down,” Dr. Barbara Sampson, the city’s medical examiner, wrote in an internal email to a colleague in 2014, when she found out that Ms. Stajic had voted on a state panel to compel the office to release a study proving the technique’s validity. “She sucks,” a lawyer for the office wrote about Ms. Stajic, in another internal email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Ms. Stajic, who was fired from the medical examiner’s office about six months later, sued in 2016, claiming she was pushed out in part because she had challenged the controversial DNA testing technique. On Monday, the city agreed to settle her case for $1 million.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Ms. Stajic, 69, said she felt vindicated. “As a forensic scientist, I am fully aware of the importance of validating each study,” she said in an interview. “My concern was if that study was not done, there could be wrongful convictions. And if the wrong people were convicted, that would mean the wrong person would be walking free.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The city and the Office of Chief Medical Examiner said Monday that the settlement did not mean that Ms. Stajic was treated inappropriately. In pretrial papers, its directors had argued that there had been some unrelated concerns over how she managed her laboratory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“The chief medical examiner’s decision was justified and appropriate,” said Nicholas Paolucci, the spokesman for the city’s Law Department. “However, based upon our legal assessment of the case, we determined that a settlement was in the best interest of the city.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Ms. Stajic’s case, even without going to trial, shed light on the inner workings of a city agency that is often assumed to be untouched by political pressure. But the case’s bigger legacy may be one bit of information that her attorneys say came out in the lawsuit: They said it proved the city had never performed the study of the DNA technique as it had claimed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1soubk3 epkadsg3&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-15g2oxy epkadsg2&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-2b3w4o e16ij5yr6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-i9gxme e16ij5yr4&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;css-1hma5rr e16ij5yr2&quot;&gt;New York DNA Crime Lab&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;time class=&quot;css-rqb9bm e16638kd0&quot; datetime=&quot;2017-09-07&quot;&gt;Sept. 7, 2017&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-rxyfbr e16ij5yr0&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2017/09/06/nyregion/06DNA1/29DNA1-videoLarge.jpg&quot; class=&quot;css-32rbo2 e16ij5yr1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The city argued it had conducted sufficient testing of the technique, known as Low Copy Number DNA testing. “OCME stands behinds its science,” Aja Worthy-Davis, a spokeswoman for the office of the chief medical examiner, said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Low Copy Number testing involves very minute amounts of DNA — often lifted from crime scene surfaces, such as weapon handles or bicycle handlebars, that multiple people have touched. The city first adopted this technique in 2006, and it is estimated to have been used in thousands of cases before it was phased out in January 2017. New York was the only crime lab in the country believed to have used the method.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Barry Scheck, a member of the state forensic panel and a criminal defense attorney known for his litigation on DNA technology, said that at a meeting of the State Commission on Forensic Science in October 2014, he had asked for a study proving that the method had been validated for use on extremely small genetic samples that contained DNA from more than one person, in conditions typical of a crime scene. Such samples were showing up in courtrooms as evidence, he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The medical examiner’s office had claimed it had done such a study, but refused to release it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Ms. Stajic voted with Mr. Scheck and another panel member, also a defense attorney, to compel the release of the study. Even though the measure failed to pass, internal emails among her bosses showed how upset they were by her decision to side against her own agency and with the defense attorneys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1soubk3 epkadsg3&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-15g2oxy epkadsg2&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-2b3w4o e16ij5yr6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-i9gxme e16ij5yr4&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1hma5rr e16ij5yr2&quot;&gt;Ex-Official Says Medical Examiner Forced Her Out Over DNA Technique&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;time class=&quot;css-rqb9bm e16638kd0&quot; datetime=&quot;2016-02-18&quot;&gt;Feb. 18, 2016&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-rxyfbr e16ij5yr0&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2016/02/19/nyregion/19CORONER1/19CORONER1-videoLarge.jpg&quot; class=&quot;css-32rbo2 e16ij5yr1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Ms. Stajic had been director of the toxicology laboratory at the city’s Office of the Chief Medical Examiner since 1986. She had served as a governor-appointed commissioner on the state forensics panel since 2004.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;As a commissioner, she oversaw some of the operations of her own agency, which at times led to tension with her bosses when she spoke her mind. She had also clashed with Dr. Sampson in 2013, when, in her role as commissioner, she had questioned whether the director of another lab at the city medical examiner’s office, Dr. Mechthild Prinz, had been forced out unfairly, her lawsuit said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;But her vote on the panel in 2014 seemed to be a tipping point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Kevin Mintzer, one of Ms. Stajic’s attorneys, said that scientific data released in pretrial discovery in Ms. Stajic’s case showed that the study voted on during the panel meeting had never actually been done, proving her suspicions right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Mr. Scheck said: “Not only is it wrong as a matter of science and good public policy to retaliate against someone who is just voting to disclose a validation study, but now it turns out they never did the study.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Timothy Kupferschmid, the chief of laboratories for the medical examiner’s office, wrote in a 2016 memo to his colleagues that Low Copy Number DNA testing was being replaced with a newer technique, without mentioning the controversy over its use or concerns over its reliability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Jessica Goldthwaite, a staff attorney with the DNA Unit of the Legal Aid Society in New York City, said that she believed the city actually stopped using the technique because “the risk of unreliable results was too high.” She noted that there may still be old cases that are using evidence analyzed with the technique.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“Dr. Stajic did the right thing,” she said. “She stood up for transparency, accountability and science as a member of the commission, but that’s what a good scientist would do. She said look, you are making a claim, show us the data to back it up.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1soubk3 epkadsg3&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-15g2oxy epkadsg2&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-2b3w4o e16ij5yr6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-i9gxme e16ij5yr4&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1hma5rr e16ij5yr2&quot;&gt;Traces of Crime: How New York’s DNA Techniques Became Tainted&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;time class=&quot;css-rqb9bm e16638kd0&quot; datetime=&quot;2017-09-04&quot;&gt;Sept. 4, 2017&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-rxyfbr e16ij5yr0&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2017/09/06/nyregion/06DNA1/29DNA1-videoLarge.jpg&quot; class=&quot;css-32rbo2 e16ij5yr1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 11:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ekovarski</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/04/23/nyregion/dna-testing-nyc-medical-examiner.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>She Was Fired After Raising Questions About a DNA Test. Now She’s Getting $1 Million.</og:title>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/04/24/nyregion/23dna/23dna-facebookJumbo.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>Marina Stajic, an official at the Office of Chief Medical Examiner in New York City, raised concerns that the test could lead to wrongful convictions. Her bosses were livid.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/04/23/nyregion/dna-testing-nyc-medical-examiner.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Reasons not to reveal your DNA</title>
<link>https://internethealthreport.org/2019/23-reasons-not-to-reveal-your-dna/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://internethealthreport.org/2019/23-reasons-not-to-reveal-your-dna/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Industry giants Ancestry.com, 23andMe, MyHeritage and FamilyTreeDNA market their services online, share test results on websites, and even offer tutorials on how to search for relatives in phone directories, or share results in social media. They often also claim rights to your genetic data and sell access to their databases to big pharmaceutical and medtech companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of internet health, it’s part of a worrying trend of corporations to acquire personal data about people and act in their own best interests, not yours. OK, so test results can also lead to important &lt;a href=&quot;http://time.com/5510009/23andme-fda-approval-cancer-test/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;discoveries about your personal health&lt;/a&gt;, and can also be shared for non-profit &lt;a href=&quot;https://dna.land/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;biomedical research&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://allofus.nih.gov/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;public interest&lt;/a&gt;. But before you give in to your curiosity, here are 23 reasons not to reveal your DNA – one for each pair of the chromosomes in a human cell.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;related-posts float-content float-content--right alternate-content d-none d-lg-block&quot;&gt;&lt;h4 class=&quot;related-posts-title&quot;&gt;Further reading&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The results may not be accurate.&lt;/strong&gt; Some outputs on personal health and nutrition have been &lt;a href=&quot;https://gizmodo.com/the-next-pseudoscience-health-craze-is-all-about-geneti-1792194708&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;discredited by scientists&lt;/a&gt;. One company, Orig3n, &lt;a href=&quot;https://gizmodo.com/report-a-dna-testing-company-could-not-tell-the-differ-1825715321&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;misidentified a Labrador Retriever dog’s DNA sample&lt;/a&gt; as being human in 2018. As Arwa Mahdawi &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2018/mar/28/what-did-i-learn-from-my-diy-dna-test-how-foolish-i-was-to-sign-my-life-away&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;wrote&lt;/a&gt; after taking the test, “Nothing I learned was worth the price-tag and privacy risks involved.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Heritage tests are less precise if you don’t have European roots.&lt;/strong&gt; DNA is analyzed in comparison to samples already on file. Because &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pcworld.com/article/3323366/dna-testing-for-ancestry-white-people.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;more people of European descent&lt;/a&gt; have taken tests so far, assessments of where your ancestors lived are usually &lt;a href=&quot;https://gizmodo.com/how-dna-testing-botched-my-familys-heritage-and-probab-1820932637&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;less detailed outside of Europe&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your DNA says nothing about your culture.&lt;/strong&gt; Genetic code can only tell you so much. As Sarah Zhang &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/science/archive/2016/12/genetics-race-ancestry-tests/510962/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;wrote&lt;/a&gt; in 2016, “DNA is not your culture and it certainly isn’t guaranteed to tell you anything about the places, history and cultures that shaped you.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Racists are weaponizing the results.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.statnews.com/2017/08/16/white-nationalists-genetic-ancestry-test/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;White nationalists have flocked&lt;/a&gt; to commercial DNA companies to vie for the highest race-purity points on extremist websites.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DNA tests can’t be anonymous.&lt;/strong&gt; You could jump through hoops to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.abine.com/blog/2016/23andmyidentity-how-to-safely-and-privately-take-a-genetic-test/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;attempt to mask your name and location&lt;/a&gt;, but your DNA is an unique marker of your identity that could be mishandled no matter what.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You will jeopardize the anonymity of family members.&lt;/strong&gt; By putting your own DNA in the hands of companies your (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vox.com/2014/9/9/5975653/with-genetic-testing-i-gave-my-parents-the-gift-of-divorce-23andme&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;known&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2018/sep/18/your-fathers-not-your-father-when-dna-tests-reveal-more-than-you-bargained-for&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;unknown&lt;/a&gt;) relatives could be identifiable to others, possibly against their wishes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You could become emotionally scarred.&lt;/strong&gt; You may discover things you weren’t prepared to find out. A fertility watchdog in the United Kingdom &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/society/2018/sep/18/watchdog-calls-for-warnings-on-dna-testing-sites&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;called for DNA testing companies to warn consumers&lt;/a&gt; of the risks of uncovering traumatic family secrets or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.popsci.com/23andme-is-probably-terrible-idea&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;disease risks&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anonymous sperm and egg donors could become a thing of the past.&lt;/strong&gt; The likelihood that anonymous donations will remain anonymous decreases with every test taken, which could &lt;a href=&quot;https://medicalxpress.com/news/2016-11-prohibiting-sperm-donor-anonymity-donors.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;dissuade donors&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cbc.ca/news/technology/sperm-donor-dna-testing-1.4500517&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;negatively affect some families&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Millions are spent on targeted ads to lure you.&lt;/strong&gt; DNA companies hand out &lt;a href=&quot;https://gizmodo.com/report-a-dna-testing-company-could-not-tell-the-differ-1825715321&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;free kits at sporting events&lt;/a&gt;, and create &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/science/archive/2018/09/your-dna-is-not-your-culture/571150/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;DNA specific music playlists&lt;/a&gt; on Spotify. In 2016 alone, Ancestry.com &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.technologyreview.com/s/610233/2017-was-the-year-consumer-dna-testing-blew-up/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;spent&lt;/a&gt; $109 million on ads. An ad by AncestryDNA &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GntV_xseqR8&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;capitalized on “Brexit” and British identity politics&lt;/a&gt;, with the slogan, “The average British person’s data is 60% European. We may be leaving Europe, but Europe will never leave us.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A pair of socks is a better gift.&lt;/strong&gt; You may be tempted by special offers around holidays &lt;a href=&quot;https://genealogybargains.com/save-30-on-dna-kits-at-23andme-during-fathers-day-sale/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;such as this one&lt;/a&gt;, offering 30% off genetic tests for Father’s Day: “What do you share with Dad? This Father’s Day, celebrate your DNA connection with Dad”. Perhaps the man who has everything would prefer not to become your science experiment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You will become the product.&lt;/strong&gt; Your genetic code is valuable. Once you opt in to sharing, you have &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.irishtimes.com/business/technology/don-t-buy-online-dna-ancestry-tests-you-are-the-real-product-1.3713619&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;no idea&lt;/a&gt; what company gets access to it, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/2018/06/16/5-biggest-risks-of-sharing-dna-with-consumer-genetic-testing-companies.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;nor for what purpose&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Big pharma wants your DNA.&lt;/strong&gt; 23andMe &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/science/archive/2018/07/big-pharma-dna/566240/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;revealed a $300 million USD deal&lt;/a&gt; with pharmaceutical giant GlaxoSmithKline in 2018 that gives them access to aggregate customer data. Calico Life Sciences, a medtech company owned by Google’s parent company, Alphabet, is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mcclatchydc.com/news/nation-world/article210692689.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;primary research partner of Ancestry.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Companies can change their privacy policies.&lt;/strong&gt; You might be asked to give your consent again, but policies of companies can still change in ways you may not like.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A company (and your DNA) can change hands.&lt;/strong&gt; Companies are bought, sold, go out of business or change their business models. And then what happens with your genetic info?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Destructing your DNA can be difficult.&lt;/strong&gt; An &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mcclatchydc.com/news/nation-world/article210692689.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;investigation&lt;/a&gt; into how to delete your DNA from Ancestry.com found that it is possible to erase your record and allegedly even destroy your physical sample. But they don’t make it easy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You have no idea how long they will keep your sample.&lt;/strong&gt; Some companies say they keep samples &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.23andme.com/en-eu/about/biobanking/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;for 1-10 years&lt;/a&gt;. Regulations governing DNA databases differ &lt;a href=&quot;http://dnapolicyinitiative.org/wiki/index.php?title=Main_Page&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;from country to country&lt;/a&gt;. Do you know the rules where you live?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Police can access your DNA.&lt;/strong&gt; There’s crime solving potential, but also &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2090536X14000239&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;human rights risks&lt;/a&gt;. Authorities can seek court approval &lt;a href=&quot;http://nymag.com/intelligencer/2018/10/dna-tests-bad-for-finding-identity-great-for-surveillance.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;to access&lt;/a&gt; consumer DNA databases, but investigators have also been known to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/04/27/us/golden-state-killer-case-joseph-deangelo.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;create fake profiles&lt;/a&gt; using a suspect’s DNA.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your results could become part of a global database.&lt;/strong&gt; Law enforcement in several countries have unrestricted access to genetic profiles. &lt;a href=&quot;http://science.sciencemag.org/content/362/6417/898&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Some scientists&lt;/a&gt; argue that creating a “universal genetic forensic database” would be the only way to &lt;a href=&quot;https://singularityhub.com/2018/11/27/would-a-universal-genetic-database-be-a-crime-solving-wonder-or-an-orwellian-nightmare/#sm.0001arsetsqbxdlq11lra4fq3rgxb&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;make unwanted intrusion less likely&lt;/a&gt; through regulation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your data could be hacked, leaked or breached.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://gizmodo.com/what-dna-testing-companies-terrifying-privacy-policies-1819158337&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Third party sharing&lt;/a&gt; is common practice among companies. The more people have access to your DNA, the more &lt;a href=&quot;https://gizmodo.com/dna-testing-data-is-disturbingly-vulnerable-to-hackers-1797695128&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;vulnerable&lt;/a&gt; it is to being &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2018/6/5/17430146/dna-myheritage-ancestry-accounts-compromised-hack-breach&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;hacked&lt;/a&gt;. As companies amass more data, they will become increasingly &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.investors.com/politics/commentary/dna-testing-kits-risks-privacy/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;attractive to criminals&lt;/a&gt; and vulnerable to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mcclatchydc.com/news/nation-world/article210692689.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;cyber theft&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Genes can be hacked.&lt;/strong&gt; Scientists have discovered how to store data and even &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/story/scientists-upload-a-galloping-horse-gif-into-bacteria-with-crispr/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;animated GIFs&lt;/a&gt; in DNA, and even believe &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/story/malware-dna-hack/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;malware could be placed&lt;/a&gt; in DNA to compromise the security of computers holding databases. Still trust them?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You are signing away rights.&lt;/strong&gt; When you use services like AncestryDNA &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ancestry.com/cs/legal/dnaterms_2017_05_22_us&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;the default agreement&lt;/a&gt; is to let them transfer your genetic information to others, royalty-free, for product development, personalized product offers, research and more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Companies profit from your DNA.&lt;/strong&gt; Testing isn’t the only way companies make money. They profit from data sharing agreements with research institutes and the pharmaceutical industry. If your DNA helps develop a cure for a disease, you’ll never know. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ancestry.com/cs/legal/dnaterms_2017_05_22_us&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;And you certainly won’t earn royalties from any related drug sales&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You may be discriminated against in the future.&lt;/strong&gt; In the United States, health insurers and workplaces &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eeoc.gov/laws/statutes/gina.cfm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;are not allowed to discriminate&lt;/a&gt; based on DNA. But the law &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fastcompany.com/3055710/if-you-want-life-insurance-think-twice-before-getting-genetic-testing&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;does not apply to life insurance or disability insurance&lt;/a&gt;. Who knows in your case, where you live? Some day you could be &lt;a href=&quot;https://gizmodo.com/why-a-dna-test-is-actually-a-really-bad-gift-1820934113&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;compelled&lt;/a&gt; to share genetic information with your own insurer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you still decide to submit your DNA for testing, the U.S. Federal Trade Commission offers &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.consumer.ftc.gov/blog/2017/12/dna-test-kits-consider-privacy-implications&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;sound advice to consumers&lt;/a&gt;: compare privacy policies before you pick a company, choose your account options carefully, recognize the risks, and report any concerns to authorities. To counteract the dominance of commercial companies, you can also contribute your data to non-profit research repositories like &lt;a href=&quot;https://allofus.nih.gov/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;All of Us&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://dna.land/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;DNA.Land&lt;/a&gt; that are open to public scrutiny.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you regret a choice you made in the past, you could &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.de/how-to-delete-dna-genetic-data-2018-5?r=US&amp;amp;IR=T&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;have your DNA data deleted&lt;/a&gt; and request that your sample be destroyed. Consumer DNA testing is an example of why strong data protection laws are so important. In Europe, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://internethealthreport.org/2019/filing-complaints-in-europe-after-gdpr/&quot;&gt;General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)&lt;/a&gt; offers some protections, but elsewhere you have few rights when you hand over sensitive data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 10:39:26 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>afshinmeh</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>23 reasons not to reveal your DNA — The Internet Health Report 2019</og:title>
<og:description>DNA testing is a booming global business enabled by the internet. Millions of people have sent samples of their saliva to commercial labs in hopes of learning something new about their personal health or heritage, primarily in the United States and Europe. In some places, commercial tests are banned. In France, you could face a... Read more »</og:description>
<og:url>https://internethealthreport.org/2019/23-reasons-not-to-reveal-your-dna/</og:url>
<og:image>https://internethealthreport.org/2019/wp-content/uploads/sites/7/2019/04/DNA-16-9.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://internethealthreport.org/2019/23-reasons-not-to-reveal-your-dna/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Made in China, Exported to the World: The Surveillance State</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/04/24/technology/ecuador-surveillance-cameras-police-government.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2019/04/24/technology/ecuador-surveillance-cameras-police-government.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;QUITO, Ecuador — The squat gray building in Ecuador’s capital commands a sweeping view of the city’s sparkling sprawl, from the high-rises at the base of the Andean valley to the pastel neighborhoods that spill up its mountainsides.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The police who work inside are looking elsewhere. They spend their days poring over computer screens, watching footage that comes in from 4,300 cameras across the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The high-powered cameras send what they see to 16 monitoring centers in Ecuador that employ more than 3,000 people. Armed with joysticks, the police control the cameras and scan the streets for drug deals, muggings and murders. If they spy something, they zoom in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;This voyeur’s paradise is made with technology from what is fast becoming the global capital of surveillance: China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Ecuador’s system, which was installed beginning in 2011, is a basic version of a program of computerized controls that Beijing has spent billions to build out over a decade of technological progress. According to Ecuador’s government, these cameras feed footage to the police for manual review.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;But a New York Times investigation found that the footage also goes to the country’s feared domestic intelligence agency, which under the previous president, Rafael Correa, had a lengthy track record of following, intimidating and attacking political opponents. Even as a new administration under President Lenín Moreno investigates the agency’s abuses, the group still gets the videos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Under President Xi Jinping, the Chinese government has vastly expanded domestic surveillance, fueling a new generation of companies that make sophisticated technology at ever lower prices. A global infrastructure initiative is spreading that technology even further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Ecuador shows how technology built for China’s political system is now being applied — and sometimes abused — by other governments. Today, 18 countries — including Zimbabwe, Uzbekistan, Pakistan, Kenya, the United Arab Emirates and Germany — are using Chinese-made intelligent monitoring systems, and 36 have received training in topics like “public opinion guidance,” which is typically a euphemism for censorship, according to an October report from Freedom House, a pro-democracy research group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;With China’s surveillance know-how and equipment now flowing to the world, critics warn that it could help underpin a future of tech-driven authoritarianism, potentially leading to a loss of privacy on an industrial scale. Often described as public security systems, the technologies have &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/04/14/technology/china-surveillance-artificial-intelligence-racial-profiling.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;darker potential uses&lt;/a&gt; as tools of political repression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“They’re selling this as the future of governance; the future will be all about controlling the masses through technology,” Adrian Shahbaz, research director at Freedom House, said of China’s new tech exports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Companies worldwide provide &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/rosiegray/exclusive-documents-illuminate-ecuadors-spying-practices&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;the components and code&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2018/may/15/revealed-ecuador-spent-millions-julian-assange-spy-operation-embassy-london&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;dystopian digital surveillance&lt;/a&gt; and democratic nations like Britain and the United States also &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/03/04/us/politics/nsa-phone-records-program-shut-down.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;have ways&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2019/04/13/us/google-location-tracking-police.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;watching their citizens&lt;/a&gt;. But China’s growing market dominance has changed things. Loans from Beijing have made surveillance technology available to governments that could not previously afford it, while China’s authoritarian system has diminished the transparency and accountability of its use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;For locals seeking to push back, there is little recourse. Chinese companies operate with less scrutiny and regard for corporate social responsibility than their Western counterparts. Activists in Ecuador say that while they have succeeded in working with civil society groups in Europe and America to oppose sales of surveillance technologies, similar campaigns in China have not been possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“We don’t have the capacity to demand information from China — it’s really difficult,” said the former Ecuadorean legislator Martha Roldós.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Ecuador’s system, called ECU-911, was largely made by two Chinese companies, the state-controlled C.E.I.E.C. and Huawei.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Replicas of the network have been sold to Venezuela, Bolivia and Angola, according to government announcements and Chinese state media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;C.E.I.E.C. and China’s Ministry of Foreign Affairs did not respond to requests for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;In a statement, Huawei said: “Huawei provides technology to support smart city and safe city programs across the world. In each case, Huawei does not get involved in setting public policy in terms of how that technology is used.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;In Ecuador, the cameras that are part of ECU-911 hang from poles and rooftops, from the Galápagos Islands to the Amazonian jungle. The system lets the authorities track phones and may soon get facial-recognition capabilities. Recordings allow the police to review and reconstruct past incidents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;While ECU-911 was sold to the public as a way to get a grip on dizzying murder rates and drug-related petty crime, it also served Mr. Correa’s &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/02/19/world/americas/ecuador-rafael-correa-lenin-moreno-guillermo-lasso.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;authoritarian streak&lt;/a&gt;, supporting his feared National Intelligence Secretariat, or Senain, according to a former head of the group. In a rare interview last year at Senain’s headquarters in a bunker outside Quito, its leader at the time, Jorge Costa, confirmed that the domestic intelligence group had access to a mirror of the Chinese-built surveillance system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The irony is that ECU-911 has not been effective at stopping crime, many Ecuadoreans said, though the system’s installation paralleled a period of falling crime rates. Ecuadoreans cite muggings and attacks that happened in front of the cameras without police response. Still, the police have built public support, partly by releasing clips on Twitter and television of thieves and muggers caught on camera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Left to choose between privacy and safety, many Ecuadoreans opt for the unblinking gaze of the electronic eyes. With the mass surveillance genie out of the bottle, community leaders have called for cameras to help secure their neighborhoods, even when their own experiences are that the devices do not work well. Concerns about the long-term political implications trail behind the pressing realities of violence and drugs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Mr. Moreno, who came to power in 2017 and has walked back some of Mr. Correa’s autocratic policies, has vowed to investigate Senain’s abuses and is remaking the intelligence collection agency under a new name. His government helped open up ECU-911 and Senain to The Times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“The government viewed espionage as a toolbox, and they could use any tool they wanted,” Ms. Roldós said. “They could spy on your emails, your phone calls, they would set microphones on your vehicle. At the same time, you had people following you. It was a whole system.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;css-11q3cgf e1mu4ftr0&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;css-1psfkbx etfikam0&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;css-8qgvsz ebyp5n10&quot;&gt;Interested in All Things Tech?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/newsletters/signup/TU&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Get the Bits newsletter&lt;/a&gt; delivered to your inbox weekly for the latest from Silicon Valley and the technology industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;css-11q3cgf e1mu4ftr0&quot;/&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;css-11v09nb eoo0vm40&quot; id=&quot;link-48e03609&quot;&gt;DESIGNED BY CHINA, FINANCED BY CHINA&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;css-11q3cgf e1mu4ftr0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;For a system that was supposed to fight drug dealers and murderers, ECU-911 traces its origins to a different security challenge: the 2008 Olympics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Before those Games, a delegation from Ecuador visited Beijing and toured the Chinese capital’s surveillance system. At the time, Beijing was pulling footage from 300,000 cameras to keep tabs on 17 million people. The Ecuadoreans left impressed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“For the Olympics, China developed emergency response centers which had state-of-the-art technology for its time,” Francisco Robayo, then the general director of ECU-911, said in an interview last year. “Our authorities saw these as ideal to bring to Ecuador.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The timing was fortuitous. Mr. Correa was newly in power and facing high crime rates. In January 2011, he made surveillance a priority.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Mr. Correa’s ministers turned to China. In two months, details to install a Chinese-made technology system were ironed out with the help of military attachés from the Chinese Embassy in Quito, according to a person familiar with the process and to publicly available documents from Ecuador’s comptroller. Ecuadorean officials traveled again to Beijing to scope out the system, which featured technology made by the parent company of the state-backed C.E.I.E.C.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;By February 2011, with guarantees of state funding from the attachés, Ecuador signed a deal with no public bidding process. The country got a Chinese-designed surveillance system financed by Chinese loans. In exchange, Ecuador provided one of its main exports, oil. The money for the cameras and computing flowed straight to C.E.I.E.C. and Huawei.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“The money always ends up going back to China,” Ms. Roldós said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;It became a pattern. In exchange for credit facilities that &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/12/24/world/americas/ecuador-china-dam.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;totaled more than $19 billion&lt;/a&gt;, Ecuador signed away &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2015/07/26/business/international/chinas-global-ambitions-with-loans-and-strings-attached.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;large portions of its oil reserves&lt;/a&gt;. A surge of Chinese-built infrastructure projects, including hydroelectric dams and refineries, followed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;By comparison, ECU-911 was a small line item.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;With an initial sticker price of more than $200 million, construction started near Guayaquil, a booming coastal city where crime rates are high, Mr. Robayo said. Over the next four years, the system expanded across Ecuador.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Cameras were hung anywhere that provided a good view. Operation centers were set up. Top Ecuadorean officials traveled to China for training, and Chinese engineers visited to teach their Ecuadorean counterparts how to work the system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The activity attracted attention from Ecuador’s neighbors. &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.gestionderiesgos.gob.ec/venezuela-replicara-modelo-ecuatoriano-del-sistema-integrado-de-seguridad-ecu-911/&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Venezuelan officials came to see&lt;/a&gt; the system, according to a 2013 account from an Ecuadorean official working on the project. In an effort led by the onetime head of intelligence for Hugo Chávez, Venezuela then sprang for a larger version of the system, with a goal of &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.noticias24.com/venezuela/noticia/188339/municipio-sucre-contara-con-camaras-de-seguridad-permitira-la-coleccion-de-informacion/&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;adding 30,000&lt;/a&gt; cameras. Bolivia followed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;section id=&quot;privacy-promo&quot; data-id=&quot;100000006461472&quot; class=&quot;interactive-content interactive-size-scoop css-7xzesj e13l8dds1&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;interactive-body css-17ih8de e13l8dds0&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;refer-text&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;refer-hed&quot;&gt;The Privacy Project&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;refer-summary&quot;&gt;The New York Times is launching an ongoing examination of privacy. We'll dig into the ideas, history and future of how our information navigates the digital ecosystem and what's at stake.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;refer-pic&quot; src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/04/10/opinion/sunday/10bennet-privacy-promo/10bennet-privacy-largeHorizontalJumbo.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Beijing’s ambitions &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/07/08/business/china-surveillance-technology.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;go much further&lt;/a&gt; than the abilities those countries bought. Today, the police across China gather material from tens of millions of cameras, and billions of records of travel, internet use and business activities, to keep tabs on citizens. The national watch list of would-be criminals and potential political agitators includes 20 million to 30 million people — more than Ecuador’s population of 16 million.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Chinese start-ups, backed in part by American investment, are competing to build methods for automated policing. They create algorithms that look for suspicious patterns in social media use and computer-vision software to track minorities and petitioners across cities. The spending spree has driven down prices for all types of &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/07/16/technology/china-surveillance-state.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;policing gadgets&lt;/a&gt;, as varied as identity-card checkers and high-resolution security cameras.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;In China, Ecuador’s project received praise. State media held it up as an example of a new China exporting advanced technology, instead of providing low-cost labor to assemble it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;In 2016, when President Xi visited Ecuador, he stopped by ECU-911 headquarters. Mr. Robayo said Mr. Xi had shown up for about five minutes, enough time for photo opportunities. The snapshots went up on C.E.I.E.C.’s website, a sign of official support from the most powerful Chinese leader in a generation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;css-11v09nb eoo0vm40&quot; id=&quot;link-369588f3&quot;&gt;A ZOOM WITH A VIEW&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;css-11q3cgf e1mu4ftr0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;To the government of Mr. Correa, Mario Pazmiño was a known man.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;A retired Ecuadorean Army colonel who adopted stray dogs — more than a dozen — to keep himself busy in the twilight of his career, Mr. Pazmiño kept up another pet hobby: criticizing the government of Mr. Correa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;He complained about police corruption. He argued that Mr. Correa’s government was complicit in Ecuador’s growing drug trade. He called out what he perceived as the administration’s incompetence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Mr. Pazmiño’s efforts earned him his own retinue of secret police. They set up in an apartment across from his house, and followed him when he went out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Just as Mr. Chávez had done in Venezuela, Mr. Correa tightened the reins in Ecuador. He eliminated presidential term limits, intimidated and ejected judges, and sent henchmen to follow and attack political opponents and activists, like Mr. Pazmiño and Ms. Roldós.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;His government also turned to ECU-911.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“I think few people know about it or are actually aware of the huge power of ECU-911,” Ms. Roldós said. “There are few people who really know the extent of the tracking.” She added that Senain used just about any technology it could get its hands on to harass and follow Mr. Correa’s political opponents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;A seasoned intelligence officer, Mr. Pazmiño, 59, said even he was surprised when, in 2013, a video camera that was part of ECU-911 was installed directly outside his house. It hung from a pole on a traffic divider in the middle of the street, with a full view through a window into his second-story apartment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“There is a direct collaboration between ECU-911, the Intelligence Secretariat and also those who surveil and persecute political or social actors,” said Mr. Pazmiño, citing his own experience, as well as documents and people who had worked in Senain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Mr. Pazmiño said that after the camera went in, surveillance teams following him backed off. The camera otherwise made no real sense where it was. Mr. Pazmiño lives in a relatively safe neighborhood, and no other ECU-911 cameras were installed nearby. It was a move out of the police playbook in China, where cameras are positioned outside the doors of high-profile activists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;A visit to Senain’s headquarters confirmed Mr. Pazmiño’s suspicion. On a wall of screens that served as a sort of agency control room, Times reporters recognized footage from the ECU-911 system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Mr. Costa, who was in charge of the transition between Senain and its successor, acknowledged the transmissions — but said he was not responsible for how they had been used in Mr. Correa’s administration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Mr. Pazmiño said he had an idea of who should be held accountable: China. He said the country had supported and emboldened Mr. Correa, just as it had leaders in neighboring Venezuela. As conditions deteriorated in Venezuela last year, Huawei engineers &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/VEN911Oficial/status/1003657444264996864&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;helped train Venezuelan engineers&lt;/a&gt; on how to maintain their version of Ecuador’s system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“I believe what the Chinese model generates is control over society,” he said. “A rigid control.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;css-11v09nb eoo0vm40&quot; id=&quot;link-12e96885&quot;&gt;THE LIMITS OF SURVEILLANCE&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;css-11q3cgf e1mu4ftr0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;El Tejar has some of the best views in Quito — and some of its worst crime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;As Lidia Rueda, a community organizer, walked the steep, winding streets of this neighborhood, where she has lived for 30 years, she pointed down the hill to where the bodies of several murdered women were found. Drug dealers come and go with impunity, she said. Muggings are common. Thieves break streetlights to get the cover of darkness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The crime has not subsided even though ECU-911 cameras arrived at the base of the hill several years ago. Ms. Rueda gestured to a pedestrian bridge there, where one man had grabbed her and threatened her with a knife while another had taken her money. The 2014 mugging happened directly beneath a police camera. No help came.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Ms. Rueda’s experience encapsulates the complex relationship many Ecuadoreans have with the cameras. While the authorities said the cameras had reduced crime, anecdotes of its dysfunction abound.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“Where there are cameras, they often don’t work,” said Ms. Rueda, 61. Another possibility was simply that no one was watching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The odds are against Ecuador’s police force. Quito has more than 800 cameras. But during a Times visit, 30 police officers were on duty to check the footage. In their gray building atop the hill, officers spend a few minutes looking at footage from one camera and then switch. Preventing crime is only part of the job. In a control room, dispatchers supported responses to emergency calls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Most of the time, no one was on the other side of the lens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;It was a reminder that the system, and others like it, are more easily used for snooping than crime prevention. Following someone on the streets requires a small team, while large numbers of well-coordinated police are necessary to stop crime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Mr. Robayo argued that ECU-911 had been responsible for a major drop in murders and an almost 13 percent drop in crime in 2018 from the previous year. The mere existence of a camera can also have a profound effect, he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Many Ecuadoreans agree. Despite Ms. Rueda’s mugging, she has called for the installation of more cameras in El Tejar. The best way to fix the neighborhood’s crime problems is to fix the surveillance system, she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The police have told her that the cameras are too expensive for her neighborhood. To that, Ms. Rueda took a fatalistic view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1ygdjhk evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“It is always the same problem, a budget shortage,” she said. “Only when someone is killed, then the authorities come and say, ‘Now we’re going to do it.’”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;css-11q3cgf e1mu4ftr0&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;css-1psfkbx etfikam0&quot;&gt;Arturo Torres Ramírez contributed reporting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1psfkbx etfikam0&quot;&gt;Melissa Chan is a reporter focused on transnational issues, often involving China’s influence beyond its borders. Based in Los Angeles and Berlin, she is a collaborator with the Global Reporting Centre, and previously worked for Al Jazeera English in China, and Al Jazeera America covering the rural American West. &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/melissakchan&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;@melissakchan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 10:18:41 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>petethomas</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/04/24/technology/ecuador-surveillance-cameras-police-government.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Made in China, Exported to the World: The Surveillance State</og:title>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/09/01/business/ECUADOR_17a/ECUADOR_17a-facebookJumbo-v2.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>In Ecuador, cameras capture footage to be examined by police and domestic intelligence. The surveillance system’s origin: China.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/04/24/technology/ecuador-surveillance-cameras-police-government.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>QEMU v4.0.0 released</title>
<link>https://www.qemu.org/2019/04/24/qemu-4-0-0/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.qemu.org/2019/04/24/qemu-4-0-0/</guid>
<description>&lt;header&gt;
&lt;p&gt;24 Apr 2019&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/header&gt;&lt;p&gt;We would like to announce the availability of the QEMU 4.0.0 release. This release contains 3100+ commits from 220 authors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can grab the tarball from our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.qemu.org/download/#source&quot;&gt;download page&lt;/a&gt;. The full list of changes are available &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.qemu.org/ChangeLog/4.0&quot;&gt;in the Wiki&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Highlights include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;ARM: ARMv8+ extensions for SB, PredInv, HPD, LOR, FHM, AA32HPD, PAuth, JSConv, CondM, FRINT, and BTI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ARM: new emulation support for “Musca” and “MPS2” development boards&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ARM: virt: support for &amp;gt;255GB of RAM and u-boot “noload” image types&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ARM: improved emulation of ARM PMU&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HPPA: support for TLB protection IDs and TLB trace events&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MIPS: support for multi-threaded TCG emulation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MIPS: emulation support for I7200 I6500 CPUs, QMP-base querying of CPU types, and improved support for SAARI and SAAR configuration registers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MIPS: improvements to Interthread Communication Unit, Fulong 2E machine types, and end-user documentation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PowerPC: pseries/powernv: support for POWER9 large decrementer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PowerPC: pseries: emulation support for XIVE interrupt controller&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PowerPC: pseries: support for hotplugging PCI host bridges (PHBs)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PowerPC: pseries: Spectre/Meltdown mitigations enabled by default, additional support for count-cache-flush mitigation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RISC-V: virt: support for PCI and USB&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RISC-V: support for TSR, TW, and TVM fields of mstatus, FS field now supports three stats (dirty, clean, and off)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RISC-V: built-in gdbserver supports register lists via XML files&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;s390: support for z14 GA 2 CPU model, Multiple-epoch and PTFF features now enabled in z14 CPU model by default&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;s390: vfio-ap: now supports hot plug/unplug, and no longer inhibits memory ballooning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;s390: emulation support for floating-point extension facility and vector support instructions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;x86: HAX accelerator now supported POSIX hosts other than Darwin, including Linux and NetBSD&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;x86: Q35: advertised PCIe root port speeds will now optimally default to maximum link speed (16GT/s) and width (x32) provided by PCIe 4.0 for QEMU 4.0+ machine types; older machine types will retain 2.5GT/x1 defaults for compatibility.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;x86: Xen PVH images can now be booted with “-kernel” option&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Xtensa: xtfpga: improved SMP support for linux (interrupt distributor, IPI, and runstall) and new SMP-capable test_mmuhifi_c3 core configuration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Xtensa: support for Flexible length instructions extension (FLIX)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GUI: new ‘-display spice-app’ to configure/launch a Spice client GUI with a similar UI to QEMU GTK. VNC server now supports access controls via tls-authz/sasl-authz options&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;QMP: support for “out-of-band” command execution, can be useful for postcopy migration recovery. Additional QMP commands for working with block devices and dirty bitmaps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VFIO: EDID interface for supported mdev (Intel vGPU for kernel 5.0+), allows resolution setting via xres/yres options.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Xen: new ‘xen-disk’ device which can create a Xen PV disk backend, and performance improvements for Xen PV disk backend.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Network Block Device: improved tracing and error diagnostics, improved client compatibility with buggy NBD server implementations, new –bitmap, –list, –tls-authz options for qemu-nbd&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;virtio-blk now supports DISCARD and WRITE_ZEROES&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pvrdma device now supports RDMA Management Datagram services (MAD)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and lots more…&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thank you to everyone involved!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 07:31:23 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ingve</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.qemu.org/2019/04/24/qemu-4-0-0/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>