<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>NSA’s top talent is leaving because of low pay, flagging morale, unpopular reorg</title>
<link>https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/national-security/the-nsas-top-talent-is-leaving-because-of-low-pay-and-battered-morale/2018/01/02/ff19f0c6-ec04-11e7-9f92-10a2203f6c8d_story.html?utm_term=.0388eaf826c3</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/national-security/the-nsas-top-talent-is-leaving-because-of-low-pay-and-battered-morale/2018/01/02/ff19f0c6-ec04-11e7-9f92-10a2203f6c8d_story.html?utm_term=.0388eaf826c3</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The National Security Agency is losing its top talent at a worrisome rate as highly skilled personnel, some disillusioned with the spy service’s leadership and an unpopular reorganization, take higher-paying, more flexible jobs in the private sector.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since 2015, the NSA has lost several hundred hackers, engineers and data scientists, according to current and former U.S. officials with knowledge of the matter. The potential impact on national security is significant, they said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Headquartered at Fort Meade in Maryland, the NSA employs a civilian workforce of about 21,000 there and is the largest producer of intelligence among the nation’s 17 spy agencies. The people who have left were responsible for collecting and analyzing the intelligence that goes into the president’s daily briefing. Their work also included monitoring a broad array of subjects including the Islamic State, Russian and North Korean hackers, and analyzing the intentions of foreign governments, and they were responsible for protecting the classified networks that carry such sensitive information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Some synonym of the word ‘epidemic’ is the best way to describe it,” said Ellison Anne Williams, a former senior researcher at the NSA who left in 2016 to start her own data-security firm, Enveil. More than 10 of her employees also came from the NSA, she said. “The agency is losing an amazing amount of its strongest technical talent, and to lose your best and brightest staff is a huge hit.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p channel=&quot;wp.com&quot; class=&quot;interstitial-link&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;[&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/capitalbusiness/departing-nsa-veterans-catch-the-eye-of-silicon-valley-investors/2017/11/12/ad5e8720-c61f-11e7-84bc-5e285c7f4512_story.html?utm_term=.b1ee60cffbf3&quot; shape=&quot;rect&quot; title=&quot;www.washingtonpost.com&quot;&gt;Departing NSA veterans catch the eye of Silicon Valley investors&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;inline-content inline-photo-left&quot;&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;unprocessed&quot; data-hi-res-src=&quot;https://img.washingtonpost.com/rf/image_1024w/2010-2019/WashingtonPost/2016/09/12/National-Security/Images/2016-09-08T180903Z_01_WAS502_RTRIDSP_3_USA-SECURITY.jpg?uuid=HnDuYHk0Eea9hre71T0rXQ&quot; data-low-res-src=&quot;https://img.washingtonpost.com/rf/image_480w/2010-2019/WashingtonPost/2016/09/12/National-Security/Images/2016-09-08T180903Z_01_WAS502_RTRIDSP_3_USA-SECURITY.jpg?uuid=HnDuYHk0Eea9hre71T0rXQ&quot; data-raw-src=&quot;https://img.washingtonpost.com/rw/2010-2019/WashingtonPost/2016/09/12/National-Security/Images/2016-09-08T180903Z_01_WAS502_RTRIDSP_3_USA-SECURITY.jpg?uuid=HnDuYHk0Eea9hre71T0rXQ&quot; src=&quot;https://img.washingtonpost.com/rf/image_480w/2010-2019/WashingtonPost/2016/09/12/National-Security/Images/2016-09-08T180903Z_01_WAS502_RTRIDSP_3_USA-SECURITY.jpg?uuid=HnDuYHk0Eea9hre71T0rXQ&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pb-caption&quot;&gt;National Security Agency Director Adm. Michael Rogers speaks during a national security conference in Washington in 2016. (Gary Cameron/Reuters)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The NSA would not disclose how many job vacancies it has. Agency officials said there is a 5.6 percent attrition rate among personnel who specialize in science, technology and math. The attrition rate is closer to 8 or 9 percent among hackers and those who staff the agency’s always-operating watch center monitoring for cyber attacks, a trend that has spanned the Obama and Trump administrations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;U12402093605118tjH&quot;&gt;Although the departure rates are low, compared with attrition levels in the civilian technology industry, and although the agency is filling its vacancies, most new personnel lack the experience of those who have left, said one senior intelligence official, who like others spoke on the condition of anonymity to offer candid insights about the secretive organization. That experience deficit can impede the NSA’s core mission of collecting and analyzing the masses of data the agency lifts from foreign networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some groups within the NSA have lost almost half of their staffs, one former official said. As a result, projects ­to make intelligence collection more effective­ have been cut or slowed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a turbulent moment in the NSA’s 65-year history. The agency continues to face public distrust after revelations, made by former contractor Edward Snowden in 2013, about the scope of its surveillance of American citizens. Morale dipped in the aftermath of those disclosures and has not fully recovered. More recently, the workforce was rattled by a series of breaches targeting the agency’s highly sensitive hacking tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p channel=&quot;wp.com&quot; class=&quot;interstitial-link&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;[&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/technology/nsa-officials-worried-about-the-day-its-potent-hacking-tool-would-get-loose-then-it-did/2017/05/16/50670b16-3978-11e7-a058-ddbb23c75d82_story.html?utm_term=.a9899735887c&quot; shape=&quot;rect&quot; title=&quot;www.washingtonpost.com&quot;&gt;NSA officials worried about the day its potent hacking tool would get loose. Then it did.&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another source of frustration is an ongoing reorganization that has merged the NSA’s highly secret electronic spying mission with its more public network-defense operation, along with other changes. NSA Director Michael S. Rogers, a Navy admiral who also oversees the military’s Cyber Command, launched NSA 21 to break down what he called the “walls of granite” among divisions whose missions, he believed, complement one another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Former employees have voiced a variety of complaints. Some say they feel their missions have been marginalized by the restructuring. One called the reorganization “an enormous distraction” and lamented what he characterized as an inefficient procurement process that made it difficult to obtain even simple open-source developer tools. Another faulted the agency’s pay structure and promotion system, saying it favors seniority over skill and competence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A series of breaches beginning with Snowden and including the arrest of former contractor Harold T. Martin III in 2016 have led to new security precautions. Such restrictions on accessing data have made work more difficult, and the internal hunt for would-be leakers has contributed to an environment of suspicion, said a number of current and former employees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It comes down to death by a thousand cuts,” said a former employee, adding that people “tend to quit in packs. One person hits their breaking point, and once they leave, the dominoes start falling.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p channel=&quot;wp.com&quot; class=&quot;interstitial-link&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;[&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/national-security/nsa-contractor-thought-to-have-taken-classified-material-the-old-fashioned-way/2016/10/12/ffc25e22-8cb1-11e6-875e-2c1bfe943b66_story.html?utm_term=.65d8c79bd67c&quot; shape=&quot;rect&quot; title=&quot;www.washingtonpost.com&quot;&gt;NSA contractor thought to have taken classified material the old-fashioned way&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The brain drain has been so pronounced that at one gathering in 2016 of the agency’s elite hacking division, one individual raised the concern with Rogers directly. According to several people familiar with the exchange, Rogers disputed that there was any increase in attrition and told his employees that they should stop complaining and get back to work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An NSA spokesman, Tommy Groves, did not challenge the account, saying that employees’ concerns about high attrition rates have led to changes, including increased pay, increased promotions and greater opportunities to work at all NSA sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rogers did not respond to a request for comment. More recently, though, he has made it a point in public to thank the agency’s workforce and acknowledge the “cultural challenge” its employees face. At a national security conference in September, for instance, he said that dealing with “the great men and women of the organization” is “the best part of the day for me.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;U12402093605118IoF&quot;&gt;He added: “If the price of security becomes that we drive away the very men and women that generate value in the first place, we now have a self-induced mission kill.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rogers has told colleagues he plans to retire in the spring, ending a four-year tenure that has been rocky at times. At one point in 2016, the defense secretary and director of national intelligence wanted him removed over various leadership concerns. Rogers survived the episode, and with Trump’s national security team still settling in, he was seen as an element of continuity at the agency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is not clear whom President Trump will nominate to succeed him, but whoever steps into the role will face a variety of challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“NSA is at this moment experiencing stress that is constant and unrelenting,” one former senior intelligence official said. He said the agency has weathered other high-anxiety periods “because there was cohesion in the workforce and a leader who could nurture them through it, if not inspire them. But this director hasn’t chosen to do that.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Skilled personnel have always left the NSA, in particular to work for defense contractors that support its work, said Deputy Director George Barnes, who has been at the agency for 31 years. “The big change these days is there’s a supply-demand imbalance between the outside and the inside,” he told The Washington Post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Barnes defended Rogers’s leadership and his handling of the reorganization. Rogers, he said, “is totally focused on ‘What’s the culture? How do we understand what causes stress?’ It’s the antithesis of the negative vibe” about which some employees complained.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Barnes also noted the allure of Silicon Valley and other cities that tech start-ups call home. The U.S. private sector is struggling to fill more than 270,000 jobs in cybersecurity, according to Burning Glass Technologies, a labor analytics firm. Total compensation for those jobs can reach $200,000 or more, meaning even relatively junior cyber professionals in the industry can make more than top officials at the NSA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some senior officials say that the outflow in part reflects a cultural shift in which millennials are not inclined to stay in one workplace for an entire career. And it also stems from a disproportionate number of retirements of people who entered the agency in the 1980s during a hiring boom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other former NSA personnel who have left or retired recently expressed confidence that the NSA would weather the storm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;U12402093605118jND&quot;&gt;“Yes, people will leave, but there are things you can do there that you can’t do anywhere else. It’s for God and country,” said Daniel Ennis, who oversaw the agency’s threat operations center before retiring in 2015 after 33 years. He now leads advanced cyberthreat intelligence for BlueteamGlobal, a private cybersecurity firm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“NSA always recovers,” Ennis said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2018 01:02:35 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>sea6ear</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/national-security/the-nsas-top-talent-is-leaving-because-of-low-pay-and-battered-morale/2018/01/02/ff19f0c6-ec04-11e7-9f92-10a2203f6c8d_story.html</og:url>
<og:image>https://www.washingtonpost.com/rf/image_1484w/2010-2019/WashingtonPost/2017/12/02/National-Security/Images/GettyImages-628396870.JPG?t=20170517</og:image>
<og:title>NSA’s top talent is leaving because of low pay, slumping morale and unpopular reorganization</og:title>
<og:description>Since 2015, the spy service has lost several hundred hackers, engineers and data scientists.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/national-security/the-nsas-top-talent-is-leaving-because-of-low-pay-and-battered-morale/2018/01/02/ff19f0c6-ec04-11e7-9f92-10a2203f6c8d_story.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Spotify hit with $1.6B copyright lawsuit</title>
<link>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-spotify-lawsuit/spotify-hit-with-1-6-billion-copyright-lawsuit-idUSKBN1ER1RX</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.reuters.com/article/us-spotify-lawsuit/spotify-hit-with-1-6-billion-copyright-lawsuit-idUSKBN1ER1RX</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;(Reuters) - Music streaming company Spotify was sued by Wixen Music Publishing Inc last week for allegedly using thousands of songs, including those of Tom Petty, Neil Young and the Doors, without a license and compensation to the music publisher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wixen, an exclusive licensee of songs such as “Free Fallin” by Tom Petty, “Light My Fire” by the Doors, (Girl We Got a) Good Thing by Weezer and works of singers such as Stevie Nicks, is seeking damages worth at least $1.6 billion along with injunctive relief.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spotify failed to get a direct or a compulsory license from Wixen that would allow it to reproduce and distribute the songs, Wixen said in the lawsuit, filed in a California federal court.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wixen also alleged that Spotify outsourced its work to a third party, licensing and royalty services provider the Harry Fox Agency, which was “ill-equipped to obtain all the necessary mechanical licenses”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spotify declined to comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In May, the Stockholm, Sweden-based company agreed to pay more than $43 million to settle a proposed class action alleging it failed to pay royalties for some of the songs it makes available to users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spotify, which is planning a stock market listing this year, has grown around 20 percent in value to at least $19 billion in the past few months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Attribution_attribution_o4ojT&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Attribution_content_27_rw&quot;&gt;Reporting by Sonam Rai and Eric Auchard in Bengaluru; Editing by Maju Samuel&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;StandardArticleBody_trustBadgeContainer_1gqgJ&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;StandardArticleBody_trustBadgeTitle_7sKLj&quot;&gt;Our Standards:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;trustBadgeUrl&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thomsonreuters.com/en/about-us/trust-principles.html&quot;&gt;The Thomson Reuters Trust Principles.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 21:58:56 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>uptown</dc:creator>
<og:title>Spotify hit with $1.6 billion copyright lawsuit</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-spotify-lawsuit/spotify-hit-with-1-6-billion-copyright-lawsuit-idUSKBN1ER1RX</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>Music streaming company Spotify was sued by Wixen Music Publishing Inc last week for allegedly using thousands of songs, including those of Tom Petty, Neil Young and the Doors, without a license and compensation to the music publisher.</og:description>
<og:image>https://s4.reutersmedia.net/resources/r/?m=02&amp;d=20180102&amp;t=2&amp;i=1218896173&amp;w=1200&amp;r=LYNXMPEE010XS</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-spotify-lawsuit/spotify-hit-with-1-6-billion-copyright-lawsuit-idUSKBN1ER1RX</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>After Equifax breach, anger but no action in Congress</title>
<link>https://www.politico.com/story/2018/01/01/equifax-data-breach-congress-action-319631</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.politico.com/story/2018/01/01/equifax-data-breach-congress-action-319631</guid>
<description>&lt;aside class=&quot;story-related cl-l db no-border&quot;&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;The massive Equifax data breach, which compromised the identities of more than 145 million Americans, prompted a telling response from Congress: It did nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some industry leaders and lawmakers thought September’s revelation of the massive intrusion — which took place months after the credit reporting agency failed to act on a warning from the Homeland Security Department — might be the long-envisioned incident that prompted Congress to finally fix the country’s confusing and ineffectual data security laws.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-continued&quot;&gt;Story Continued Below&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, the aftermath of the breach played out like a familiar script: white-hot, bipartisan outrage, followed by hearings and a flurry of proposals that went nowhere. As is often the case, Congress gradually shifted to other priorities — this time the most sweeping tax code overhaul in a generation, and another mad scramble to fund the federal government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s very frustrating,” said Rep. Jan Schakowsky of Illinois, the top Democrat on the House Energy and Commerce consumer protection subcommittee, who introduced legislation in the wake of the Equifax incident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Every time another shoe falls, I think, ‘Ah, this is it. This will get us galvanized and pull together and march in the same direction.’ Hasn’t happened yet,” said Sen. Tom Carper (D-Del.), a member of a broader Senate working group that has tinkered for years to come up with data breach legislation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;story-related cl-l db&quot;&gt;&lt;aside class=&quot;content-group inline-module-morning-cybersecurity&quot;&gt;&lt;section class=&quot;speedbump layout-bi&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;speedbump-item pos-alpha&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;spotlight spotlight--flex&quot; readability=&quot;5.2&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;summary link-alt fx1&quot; readability=&quot;6.4&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A daily briefing on politics and cybersecurity — weekday mornings, in your inbox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;speedbump-item pos-beta&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;js-tealium-newsletter&quot; data-subscription-module=&quot;newsletter_inline_standard_Morning Cybersecurity - POLITICO&quot; readability=&quot;6.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;dari-frame dari-frame-loaded&quot; name=&quot;inline-module-morning-cybersecurity-full-0000014f-1646-d88f-a1cf-5f46b23b0000&quot; data-insertion-mode=&quot;replace&quot; data-extra-form-data=&quot;_frame.path=5c388a2e37218b65f1db610df3d5c42a&amp;amp;_frame.name=inline-module-morning-cybersecurity-full-0000014f-1646-d88f-a1cf-5f46b23b0000&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;legal-disclaimer&quot;&gt;By signing up you agree to receive email newsletters or alerts from POLITICO. You can unsubscribe at any time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every time lawmakers punt on the issue, critics say, they are leaving Americans more exposed to ruinous identity theft scams — and allowing companies to evade responsibility. With no sign that mammoth data breaches like the one at Equifax are abating, the situation is only growing more dire, according to cyberspecialists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, companies and consumers are left to navigate 48 different state-level standards that govern how companies must protect sensitive data and respond to data breaches. Companies say the varying rules are costly and time-consuming, while cyberspecialists and privacy hawks argue they do little to keep Americans’ data safe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But while industry groups, security experts, privacy advocates and lawmakers of both parties agree that Congress must do something to unify these laws, no one has been able to agree on what that “something” should be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Capitol Hill, lawmakers have struggled to navigate an issue that touches several committees, while tussling over how strongly a federal law should preempt state regulations — Democrats worry a weak federal standard might supplant robust state laws, but Republicans don’t want to give too much power to federal regulators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the private sector, industries like banking — which already have strict, sector-specific data security rules on the books — have pushed to apply their regulations to broad swaths of the economy. But other industries, such as retailers, believe such a move would impose unnecessary standards on smaller businesses that don’t collect as much sensitive data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lawmakers told POLITICO that similar forces were at play post-Equifax.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carper’s working group is effectively “on hold” for now, he told POLITICO, falling victim to jurisdictional issues. The group features Republican leaders like Senate Commerce Chairman John Thune of South Dakota and Judiciary Chairman Chuck Grassley of Iowa, as well as senior Democrats like Intelligence ranking member Mark Warner of Virginia and Dianne Feinstein of California, ranking member on the the Judiciary panel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And long-running industry battles came roaring back, Warner said. While lawmakers mostly got the retail and banking industries on board, telecommunications firms — which are already subject to industry-specific privacy &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.law.cornell.edu/cfr/text/47/part-64/subpart-U&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;rules&lt;/a&gt; — became a sticking point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;story-related&quot;&gt;&lt;article class=&quot;story-frag format-sm&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;fig-graphic&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.politico.com/story/2017/12/29/2018-election-hacking-threat-government-help-231512&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot; data-tracking=&quot;mpos=inside-body&amp;amp;mid=parentheticalmodule&amp;amp;lindex=Unknown&amp;amp;lcol=Unknown&quot; class=&quot;js-tealium-tracking&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-lazy-img=&quot;https://static.politico.com/dims4/default/ad5943a/2147483647/legacy_thumbnail/90x49%3E/quality/90/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fstatic.politico.com%2F22%2Fbe%2F593bfc844bac91db0a895aa4fb46%2Fchristopher-krebs2-gty.jpg&quot; width=&quot;90&quot; height=&quot;49&quot; src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==&quot; alt=&quot;Christopher Krebs is pictured. | Getty Images&quot; data-size=&quot;promo_xsmall_rectangle&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I think one of the problems was telecom,” said Warner, himself a former telecom executive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“All industries have to be covered” by federal data breach laws, Warner added. “But then, how they’re covered could be tailored. … What you can’t do is start coming along and carving out. I think that still remains to be an issue.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lack of legislative response has industry groups and lawmakers, including Thune, uttering a familiar refrain: Wait until next year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a statement, Thune said that as much as he favors “an effective and coordinated approach on data security issues across industries, the reality is that our legislative progress has been much more incremental this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“There hasn’t been — and still isn’t — consensus among major stakeholders on data breach and data security legislation,” he added. “There isn’t a panacea for cybersecurity and the absolute worst thing we could do is pass an ineffective mandate that leads Americans to take our guard down.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those working on the issue also expressed cautious optimism about 2018, despite the fact that Congress has been bullish about “next year” for the last half-decade, to no avail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I think there is a political dynamic and clearly a policy interest in doing something to stop these breaches, by deterring them and helping people who are harmed by them,” said Sen. Richard Blumenthal (D-Conn.), who is backing legislation that would let prosecutors potentially seek jail time for companies that cover up data breaches. Ride-hailing giant Uber was recently caught mounting such a cover-up, when it &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.politico.com/story/2017/11/21/uber-coverup-data-breach-186597&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;disclosed&lt;/a&gt; it had paid $100,000 to keep hackers silent about a 2016 digital theft that compromised 57 million customers’ information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Certainly, every member here has had constituents that have been victims of these breaches, be it Target or Equifax or whoever, and you would think that they would be interested in moving ahead,” added Schakowsky, whose bill would set federal digital security benchmarks and require prompt notification and ongoing assistance to breach victims.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;House Energy and Commerce Chairman Greg Walden told POLITICO he was working on “a more consumer-first policy” that he plans to unveil after additional hearings in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The measure would create penalties in a way that “actually inures to the benefit of the consumer,” instead of “just another penalty to the government [where] the government gets paid,” said the Oregon Republican.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Industry representatives who track the negotiations said some progress is occurring on Capitol Hill, despite the lack of concrete steps in the past four months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lawmakers are trying to produce a bill that can actually move, said Jason Kratovil, vice president of government affairs for payments at the Financial Services Roundtable, which has backed proposals from a House Financial Services subpanel in the past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;story-related&quot;&gt;&lt;article class=&quot;story-frag format-sm&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;fig-graphic&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.politico.com/story/2017/12/29/nerdcast-defining-moments-of-2017-319616&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot; data-tracking=&quot;mpos=inside-body&amp;amp;mid=parentheticalmodule&amp;amp;lindex=Unknown&amp;amp;lcol=Unknown&quot; class=&quot;js-tealium-tracking&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-lazy-img=&quot;https://static.politico.com/dims4/default/d8ca621/2147483647/legacy_thumbnail/90x49%3E/quality/90/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fstatic.politico.com%2Fb1%2F25%2Fd028461d4446bcb4a092cf557fa8%2Fnerdcast-1229-ap.jpg&quot; width=&quot;90&quot; height=&quot;49&quot; src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==&quot; alt=&quot;nerdcast 1229_ap.jpg&quot; data-size=&quot;promo_xsmall_rectangle&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I think there’s a lot of energy being spent trying to get this one right and work toward a legislative outcome that isn’t just a product of one committee and one committee’s jurisdiction, but instead is something that is going to have a lot of interest and a lot of support from many different stakeholders,” he told POLITICO.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A retail industry representative told POLITICO that 2018 might be different because industries are increasingly not using data security as a proxy battle for other policy fights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“In this case, we think we can find some common ground,” said the individual, who requested anonymity to discuss behind-the-scenes negotiations. “I don’t think that was there before.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The overriding factor pressuring lawmakers and industry groups to take action will be the gobsmacking way companies have mishandled their data breaches — a trend that shows no signs of ending in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But if the Equifax breach — which featured basic security failures, allegations of insider trading and possible attempts to prevent consumers from suing the company — didn’t do the trick, some aren’t sure what will.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“When you’ve got 145 million people, you would think, but …” Schakowsky said, trailing off and throwing up her hands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;story-supplement&quot;&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;content-categories&quot;&gt;&lt;h6&gt;This article tagged under:&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;content-group&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;story-supplement&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;spotlight&quot; readability=&quot;6.0165289256198&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;summary fs-i&quot; readability=&quot;7.7355371900826&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Missing out on the latest scoops? Sign up for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.politico.com/subscribe/playbook?cid=su_stft_pb&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;POLITICO Playbook&lt;/a&gt; and get the latest news, every morning — in your inbox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 20:20:49 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>tareqak</dc:creator>
<og:title>After Equifax breach, anger but no action in Congress</og:title>
<og:description>The aftermath of the data breach played out like a familiar script: White-hot bipartisan outrage, then hearings and proposals that went nowhere.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>http://politi.co/2lwrLSz</og:url>
<og:image>https://static.politico.com/a2/68/f12ca23d4ea89e9e7eca649ced84/171221-equifax-1-gty-1160.jpg</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.politico.com/story/2018/01/01/equifax-data-breach-congress-action-319631</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Apple acquires Buddybuild</title>
<link>https://www.buddybuild.com/blog/buddybuild-is-now-part-of-apple</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.buddybuild.com/blog/buddybuild-is-now-part-of-apple</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;We're excited to share that the buddybuild team has joined the Xcode engineering group at Apple to build amazing developer tools for the entire iOS community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've always been proud to be a Canadian company, so we're also pleased that we will be staying right here in Vancouver — a hotbed of developer and engineering talent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The buddybuild service will remain available to existing customers to build, test, and ship iOS apps to testers through &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.buddybuild.com/&quot;&gt;buddybuild.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of today, we are no longer accepting new customers. Existing Free Starter plans and Android app development will be discontinued on March 1, 2018. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have questions about an existing account, please contact us at: &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:team@buddybuild.com&quot;&gt;team@buddybuild.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 20:02:04 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>uptown</dc:creator>
<og:title>The buddybuild team is now part of Apple!</og:title>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.buddybuild.com/blog/buddybuild-is-now-part-of-apple</og:url>
<og:image>https://superlonginternalblogdomain.buddybuild.com/content/images/2017/12/5a.png</og:image>
<og:description>We're excited to share that the buddybuild team has joined the Xcode engineering group at Apple to build amazing developer tools for the entire iOS community</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.buddybuild.com/blog/buddybuild-is-now-part-of-apple</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Using Java 9 Modularization to Ship Zero-Dependency Apps</title>
<link>https://steveperkins.com/using-java-9-modularization-to-ship-zero-dependency-native-apps/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://steveperkins.com/using-java-9-modularization-to-ship-zero-dependency-native-apps/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;When Java was first introduced, mainstream programming languages mostly either compiled to standalone executables (e.g. C/C++, COBOL), or else ran in an interpreter (e.g. Perl, Tcl). For many programmers, Java’s need for both a bytecode compiler &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; a runtime interpreter was a shift in thought. The compilation model made Java better suited for business programming than “scripting” languages. Yet the runtime model required a suitable JVM to be deployed and available on each target machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People bristled at this somewhat (at least &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; remember doing so!). Early web forums, and later StackOverflow questions, were full of developers looking for some way to ship their Java applications as “native” executables. To &lt;mark&gt;avoid the need for a Java runtime to be installed on the target machine&lt;/mark&gt; prior to deployment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There have been solutions from nearly the beginning. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.excelsiorjet.com/&quot;&gt;Excelsior JET&lt;/a&gt; is an ahead-of-time (AOT) Java compiler, providing a more-or-less C++ style experience. However, with licensing costs in the thousands of dollars, it has always been a niche option. On the free-as-in-beer end, there is &lt;a href=&quot;http://launch4j.sourceforge.net/&quot;&gt;Launch4j&lt;/a&gt;, and JDK 8’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.oracle.com/javase/8/docs/technotes/guides/deploy/packager.html&quot;&gt;javapackager&lt;/a&gt; tool. These allow you to bundle a Java Runtime Environment, with a launcher executable for starting your app with that JRE. However, &lt;mark&gt;embedding a JRE adds roughly 200 megabytes&lt;/mark&gt;. It’s difficult to trim that down, due to technical reasons as well as tricky licensing issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most publicized new feature in Java 9 is the new modularization system, known as &lt;a href=&quot;http://openjdk.java.net/projects/jigsaw/&quot;&gt;Project Jigsaw&lt;/a&gt;. The full scope of this warrants many blog articles, if not complete books. However, in a nutshell, the new module system is about isolating chunks of code and their dependencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This applies not only for external libraries, but even the Java standard library itself. Meaning that your application can declare which &lt;em&gt;parts&lt;/em&gt; of the standard library it really needs, and potentially &lt;em&gt;exclude all the other parts&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This potential is realized through the &lt;code&gt;jlink&lt;/code&gt; tool that &lt;a href=&quot;http://openjdk.java.net/jeps/282&quot;&gt;now ships with the JDK&lt;/a&gt;. At a superficial first glance, &lt;code&gt;jlink&lt;/code&gt; is similar to &lt;code&gt;javapackager&lt;/code&gt;. It generates a bundle, consisting of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;your application code and dependencies,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;an embedded Java Runtime Environment, and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a native launcher (i.e. bash script or Windows batch file) for launching your application with the embedded JRE.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, &lt;code&gt;jlink&lt;/code&gt; establishes “link time” as a new optional phase, in between compile-time and run-time, for performing optimizations such as removing unreachable code. Meaning that unlike &lt;code&gt;javapackager&lt;/code&gt;, which bundles the entire standard library, &lt;code&gt;jlink&lt;/code&gt; &lt;mark&gt;bundles a stripped-down JRE with only those modules that your application needs&lt;/mark&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The difference between &lt;code&gt;jlink&lt;/code&gt; and it’s older alternatives is striking. To illustrate, let’s look at a sample project:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/steve-perkins/jlink-demo&quot;&gt;https://github.com/steve-perkins/jlink-demo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-create-a-modularized-project&quot;&gt;(1) Create a modularized project&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This repo contains a multi-project Gradle build. The &lt;code&gt;cli&lt;/code&gt; subdirectory is a “Hello World” command-line application, while &lt;code&gt;gui&lt;/code&gt; is a JavaFX desktop app. For both, notice that the &lt;code&gt;build.gradle&lt;/code&gt; file configures each project for Java 9 compatibility with this line:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-groovy&quot;&gt;sourceCompatibility = 1.9
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This, along with creating a &lt;code&gt;module-info.java&lt;/code&gt; file, sets up each project for modularization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;/cli/src/main/java/module-info.java&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-java&quot;&gt;module cli {
}
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;/gui/src/main/java/module-info.java&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-java&quot;&gt;module gui {
    requires javafx.graphics;
    requires javafx.controls;

    exports gui;
}
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our CLI application is just a glorified &lt;code&gt;System.out.println()&lt;/code&gt; call, so it depends only on the &lt;code&gt;java.base&lt;/code&gt; module (which is always implicit, and needs no declaration).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not all applications use JavaFX, however, so our GUI app must declare its dependency on the &lt;code&gt;javafx.graphics&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;javafx.controls&lt;/code&gt; modules. Moreover, because of the way that JavaFX works, the low-level library needs access to our code. So the module’s &lt;code&gt;exports gui&lt;/code&gt; line grants this visibility to itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s going to take some time for Java developers (myself included!) to get a feel for the new standard library modules and what they contain. The JDK includes a &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.oracle.com/javase/9/tools/jdeps.htm#JSWOR690&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;jdeps&lt;/code&gt; tool&lt;/a&gt; that can help with this. However, &lt;mark&gt;once a project is setup for modularization, IntelliJ is great at recognizing missing declarations and helping auto-complete them&lt;/mark&gt;. I assume that if Eclipse and NetBeans don’t have similar support already, then they soon will.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-build-an-executable-jar&quot;&gt;(2) Build an executable JAR&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To build a deployable bundle with &lt;code&gt;jlink&lt;/code&gt;, you first want to package up your application into an executable JAR file. If your project has third-party library dependencies, then you’ll want to use your choice of “shaded” or “fat-JAR” plugins to generate a single JAR with all dependencies included. In this case, our examples use only the standard library. So building an executable JAR is a simple matter of telling Gradle’s &lt;code&gt;jar&lt;/code&gt; plugin to include a &lt;code&gt;META-INF/MANIFEST.MF&lt;/code&gt; file declaring the executable class:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-groovy&quot;&gt;jar {
    manifest {
        attributes 'Main-Class': 'cli.Main'
    }
}
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;3-run-jlink-on-it&quot;&gt;(3) Run jlink on it&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As far as I know, Gradle does not yet have a plugin offering clean and seemless integration with &lt;code&gt;jlink&lt;/code&gt;. So my build scripts use an &lt;code&gt;Exec&lt;/code&gt; task to run the tool in a completely separate process. It should be easy to follow, such that you can tell the command-line invocation would look like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;[JAVA_HOME]/bin/jlink --module-path libs:[JAVA_HOME]/jmods --add-modules cli --launcher cli=cli/cli.Main --output dist --strip-debug --compress 2 --no-header-files --no-man-pages
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;15&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;--module-path&lt;/code&gt; flag is analogous to the traditional CLASSPATH. It declares where the tool should look for compiled module binaries (i.e. JAR files, or the new JMOD format). Here, we tell it to look in the project’s &lt;code&gt;libs&lt;/code&gt; subdirectory (because that’s where Gradle puts our executable JAR), and in the JDK directory for the standard library modules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;--add-modules&lt;/code&gt; flag declares which modules to add to the resulting bundle. We only need to declare our own project modules (&lt;code&gt;cli&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;gui&lt;/code&gt;), because the modules that &lt;em&gt;it&lt;/em&gt; depends on will be pulled in as transitive dependencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The resulting bundle will include a &lt;code&gt;/bin&lt;/code&gt; subdirectory, with a bash script or Windows batch file for executing your application. The &lt;code&gt;--launcher&lt;/code&gt; flag allows you to specify a name for this script, and which Java class it should invoke (which seems a bit redundant as this is already specified in the an executable JAR). Above, we are saying to create a script named &lt;code&gt;bin/cli&lt;/code&gt;, which will invoke the class &lt;code&gt;cli.Main&lt;/code&gt; in module &lt;code&gt;cli&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;--output&lt;/code&gt; flag, intuitively enough, specifies a subdirectory in which to place the resulting bundle. Here, we are using a target directory named &lt;code&gt;dist&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These final flags, &lt;code&gt;--strip-debug&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;--compress 2&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;--no-header-files&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;--no-man-pages&lt;/code&gt;, are some &lt;mark&gt;optimizations I’ve tinkered with to further reduce the resulting bundle size&lt;/mark&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the project root level, this Gradle command builds and links both sub-projects:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;./gradlew linkAll
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The resulting deployable bundles can be found at:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;[PROJECT_ROOT]/cli/build/dist
[PROJECT_ROOT]/gui/build/dist
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s take a took at size of our linked CLI and GUI applications, with their stripped-down embedded JRE’s:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;App&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;Raw Size&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;Compressed with 7-zip&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;cli&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;21.7 MB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;10.8 MB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;gui&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;45.8 MB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;29.1 MB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is on a Windows machine, with a 64-bit JRE (Linux sizes are a bit larger, but still roughly proportionate). Some notes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;4.2230769230769&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For comparison, &lt;mark&gt;the full JRE on this platform is 203 megabytes.&lt;/mark&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;1.9470198675497&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A “Hello World” CLI written in Go compiles to around 2 MB. &lt;a href=&quot;https://gohugo.io/&quot;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;, the website generator used to publish this blog, is &lt;mark&gt;a 27.2 megabyte Go executable.&lt;/mark&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;3.6315789473684&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For cross-platform GUI development, &lt;mark&gt;a typical Qt or GTK application ships with around 15 megs of Windows DLL’s for the GUI functionality alone&lt;/mark&gt;. Plus any other shared libs, for functionality that Java provides in its base standard library. &lt;mark&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/electron/electron-quick-start&quot;&gt;Electron quick-start example&lt;/a&gt; produces a 131 MB deliverable&lt;/mark&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be fair, an application bundle with a launch script is not &lt;strong&gt;quite&lt;/strong&gt; as clean as “&lt;em&gt;just building an .EXE&lt;/em&gt;”, and having a single monolithic file. Also, the JRE is comparatively sluggish at startup, as its JIT compiler warms up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even so, &lt;mark&gt;Java is now at a place where you can ship self-contained, zero-dependency applications that are comparable in size to other compiled languages (and superior to web-hybrid options like Electron)&lt;/mark&gt;. Also, Java 9 &lt;a href=&quot;http://openjdk.java.net/jeps/295&quot;&gt;includes an experimental AOT compiler&lt;/a&gt;, that might eliminate sluggish startup. While only available for 64-bit Linux initially, this &lt;code&gt;jaotc&lt;/code&gt; tool will hopefully soon expand to other platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although Go has been very high-profile in the early wave of cloud infrastructure CLI tools (e.g. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.docker.com/&quot;&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://kubernetes.io/&quot;&gt;Kubernetes&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.consul.io/&quot;&gt;Consul&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vaultproject.io/&quot;&gt;Vault&lt;/a&gt;, etc)… Java is becoming a strong alternative, especially for shops with established Java experience. For cross-platform desktop GUI apps, I would argue that JavaFX combined with Java 9 modularization is hands-down the best choice available today.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 20:01:02 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>lfischer</dc:creator>
<og:title>Using Java 9 Modularization to Ship Zero-Dependency Native Apps</og:title>
<og:description>“Why can’t I just build an .EXE?“ When Java was first introduced, mainstream programming languages mostly either compiled to standalone executables (e.g. C/C++, COBOL), or else ran in an interpreter (e.g. Perl, Tcl). For many programmers, Java’s need for both a bytecode compiler and a runtime interpreter was a shift in thought. The compilation model made Java better suited for business programming than “scripting” languages. Yet the runtime model required a suitable JVM to be deployed and available on each target machine.</og:description>
<og:image>https://steveperkins.com/img/avatar.jpg</og:image>
<og:url>https://steveperkins.com/using-java-9-modularization-to-ship-zero-dependency-native-apps</og:url>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://steveperkins.com/using-java-9-modularization-to-ship-zero-dependency-native-apps/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Mapzen Shutdown</title>
<link>https://mapzen.com/blog/shutdown/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://mapzen.com/blog/shutdown/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, we have some sad news. Mapzen will cease operations at the end of January 2018. Our hosted APIs and all related support and services will turn off on February 1, 2018. You will not be charged for API usage in December/January. We know this is an inconvenience and have provided a &lt;a href=&quot;https://mapzen.com/blog/migration&quot;&gt;migration guide to similar services&lt;/a&gt; for our developer community. Our goal is to help as much as possible to ensure continuity in the services that you have built with us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, the core products of Mapzen are built entirely on open software and data. As a result, there are options to run Mapzen services yourself or to switch to other service providers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for being with us over the past four years. We’re grateful that the open work we’ve done can continue outside of Mapzen and while we know this is a sad day, we’re optimistic about what’s next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Preview image: Air Afrique Map of the World by M. Bourie from the David Rumsey Map Collection&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 17:19:39 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>morisy</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://mapzen.com/blog/shutdown/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Show HN: Sapper.js – towards a better web app framework</title>
<link>https://svelte.technology/blog/sapper-towards-the-ideal-web-app-framework</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://svelte.technology/blog/sapper-towards-the-ideal-web-app-framework</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;standfirst&quot; svelte-1097777898=&quot;&quot;&gt;Taking the next-plus-one step&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;byline&quot; svelte-1097777898=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Rich_Harris&quot;&gt;Rich Harris&lt;/a&gt; &lt;time datetime=&quot;2017-12-31&quot;&gt;Sun Dec 31 2017&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;3.3802816901408&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quickstart for the impatient: &lt;a href=&quot;https://sapper.svelte.technology&quot;&gt;the Sapper docs&lt;/a&gt;, and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sveltejs/sapper-template&quot;&gt;starter template&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you had to list the characteristics of the perfect Node.js web application framework, you'd probably come up with something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;It should do server-side rendering, for fast initial loads and no caveats around SEO&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As a corollary, your app's codebase should be universal — write once for server &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; client&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The client-side app should &lt;em&gt;hydrate&lt;/em&gt; the server-rendered HTML, attaching event listeners (and so on) to existing elements rather than re-rendering them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Navigating to subsequent pages should be instantaneous&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Offline, and other Progressive Web App characteristics, must be supported out of the box&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only the JavaScript and CSS required for the first page should load initially. That means the framework should do automatic code-splitting at the route level, and support dynamic &lt;code&gt;import(...)&lt;/code&gt; for more granular manual control&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No compromise on performance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First-rate developer experience, with hot module reloading and all the trimmings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The resulting codebase should be easy to grok and maintain&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It should be possible to understand and customise every aspect of the system — no webpack configs locked up in the framework, and as little hidden 'plumbing' as possible&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learning the entire framework in under an hour should be easy, and not just for experienced developers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/zeit/next.js&quot;&gt;Next.js&lt;/a&gt; is close to this ideal. If you haven't encountered it yet, I strongly recommend going through the tutorials at &lt;a href=&quot;https://learnnextjs.com&quot;&gt;learnnextjs.com&lt;/a&gt;. Next introduced a brilliant idea: all the pages of your app are files in a &lt;code&gt;your-project/pages&lt;/code&gt; directory, and each of those files is just a React component.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything else flows from that breakthrough design decision. Finding the code responsible for a given page is easy, because you can just look at the filesystem rather than playing 'guess the component name'. Project structure bikeshedding is a thing of the past. And the combination of SSR (server-side rendering) and code-splitting — something the React Router team &lt;a href=&quot;https://reacttraining.com/react-router/web/guides/code-splitting&quot;&gt;gave up on&lt;/a&gt;, declaring 'Godspeed those who attempt the server-rendered, code-split apps' — is trivial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it's not perfect. As churlish as it might be to list the flaws in something &lt;em&gt;so, so good&lt;/em&gt;, there are some:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Next uses something called 'route masking' to create nice URLs (e.g. &lt;code&gt;/blog/hello-world&lt;/code&gt; instead of &lt;code&gt;/post?slug=hello-world&lt;/code&gt;). This undermines the guarantee about directory structure corresponding to app structure, and forces you to maintain configuration that translates between the two forms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All your routes are assumed to be universal 'pages'. But it's very common to need routes that only render on the server, such as a 301 redirect or an &lt;a href=&quot;https://svelte.technology/api/blog/sapper-towards-the-ideal-web-app-framework&quot;&gt;API endpoint&lt;/a&gt; that serves the data for your pages, and Next doesn't have a great solution for this. You can add logic to your &lt;code&gt;server.js&lt;/code&gt; file to handle these cases, but it feels at odds with the declarative approach taken for pages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To use the client-side router, links can't be standard &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;a&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; tags. Instead, you have to use framework-specific &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;Link&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; components, which is impossible in the markdown content for a blog post such as this one, for example&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The real problem, though, is that all that goodness comes for a price. The simplest possible Next app — a single 'hello world' page that renders some static text — involves 66kb of gzipped JavaScript. Unzipped, it's 204kb, which is a non-trivial amount of code for a mobile device to parse at a time when performance is a critical factor determining whether or not your users will stick around. And that's the &lt;em&gt;baseline&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can do better!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-compiler-as-framework-paradigm-shift&quot;&gt;The compiler-as-framework paradigm shift&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://svelte.technology/blog/frameworks-without-the-framework&quot;&gt;Svelte introduced a radical idea&lt;/a&gt;: what if your UI framework wasn't a framework at all, but a compiler that turned your components into standalone JavaScript modules? Instead of using a library like React or Vue, which knows nothing about your app and must therefore be a one-size-fits-all solution, we can ship highly-optimised vanilla JavaScript. Just the code your app needs, and without the memory and performance overhead of solutions based on a virtual DOM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The JavaScript world is &lt;a href=&quot;https://tomdale.net/2017/09/compilers-are-the-new-frameworks/&quot;&gt;moving towards this model&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://stenciljs.com&quot;&gt;Stencil&lt;/a&gt;, a Svelte-inspired framework from the Ionic team, compiles to web components. &lt;a href=&quot;https://glimmerjs.com&quot;&gt;Glimmer&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;doesn't&lt;/em&gt; compile to standalone JavaScript (the pros and cons of which deserve a separate blog post), but the team is doing some fascinating research around compiling templates to bytecode. (React is &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/trueadm/status/944908776896978946&quot;&gt;getting in on the action&lt;/a&gt;, though their current research focuses on optimising your JSX app code, which is arguably more similar to the ahead-of-time optimisations that Angular, Ractive and Vue have been doing for a few years.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What happens if we use the new model as a starting point?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;introducing-sapper&quot;&gt;Introducing Sapper&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;aside&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://sapper.svelte.technology/guide#why-the-name-&quot;&gt;name comes from&lt;/a&gt; the term for combat engineers, and is also short for &lt;strong&gt;S&lt;/strong&gt;velte &lt;strong&gt;app&lt;/strong&gt; mak&lt;strong&gt;er&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sapper.svelte.technology&quot;&gt;Sapper&lt;/a&gt; is the answer to that question. &lt;strong&gt;Sapper is a Next.js-style framework that aims to meet the eleven criteria at the top of this article while dramatically reducing the amount of code that gets sent to the browser.&lt;/strong&gt; It's implemented as Express-compatible middleware, meaning it's easy to understand and customise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same 'hello world' app that took 204kb with React and Next weighs just 7kb with Sapper. That number is likely to fall further in the future as we explore the space of optimisation possibilities, such as not shipping any JavaScript &lt;em&gt;at all&lt;/em&gt; for pages that aren't interactive, beyond the tiny Sapper runtime that handles client-side routing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What about a more 'real world' example? Conveniently, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/gothinkster/realworld&quot;&gt;RealWorld&lt;/a&gt; project, which challenges frameworks to develop an implementation of a Medium clone, gives us a way to find out. The &lt;a href=&quot;http://svelte-realworld.now.sh/&quot;&gt;Sapper implementation&lt;/a&gt; takes 39.6kb (11.8kb zipped) to render an interactive homepage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside&gt;Code-splitting isn't free — if the reference implementation used code-splitting, it would be larger still&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;The entire app costs 132.7kb (39.9kb zipped), which is significantly smaller than the reference React/Redux implementation at 327kb (85.7kb), but even if was as large it would &lt;em&gt;feel&lt;/em&gt; faster because of code-splitting. And that's a crucial point. We're told we need to code-split our apps, but if your app uses a traditional framework like React or Vue then there's a hard lower bound on the size of your initial code-split chunk — the framework itself, which is likely to be a significant portion of your total app size. With the Svelte approach, that's no longer the case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But size is only part of the story. Svelte apps are also extremely performant and memory-efficient, and the framework includes powerful features that you would sacrifice if you chose a 'minimal' or 'simple' UI library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;trade-offs&quot;&gt;Trade-offs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biggest drawback for many developers evaluating Sapper would be 'but I like React, and I already know how to use it', which is fair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're in that camp, I'd invite you to at least try alternative frameworks. You might be pleasantly surprised! The &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sveltejs/realworld&quot;&gt;Sapper RealWorld&lt;/a&gt; implementation totals 1,201 lines of source code, compared to 2,377 for the reference implementation, because you're able to express concepts very concisely using Svelte's template syntax (which &lt;a href=&quot;https://svelte.technology/guide#template-syntax&quot;&gt;takes all of five minutes to master&lt;/a&gt;). You get &lt;a href=&quot;https://svelte.technology/blog/the-zen-of-just-writing-css&quot;&gt;scoped CSS&lt;/a&gt;, with unused style removal and minification built-in, and you can use preprocessors like LESS if you want. You no longer need to use Babel. SSR is ridiculously fast, because it's just string concatenation. And we recently introduced &lt;a href=&quot;https://svelte.technology/guide#state-management&quot;&gt;svelte/store&lt;/a&gt;, a tiny global store that synchronises state across your component hierarchy with zero boilerplate. The worst that can happen is that you'll end up feeling vindicated!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there are trade-offs nonetheless. Some people have a pathological aversion to any form of 'template language', and maybe that applies to you. JSX proponents will clobber you with the 'it's just JavaScript' mantra, and therein lies React's greatest strength, which is that it is infinitely flexible. That flexibility comes with its own set of trade-offs, but we're not here to discuss those.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then there's &lt;em&gt;ecosystem&lt;/em&gt;. The universe around React in particular — the devtools, editor integrations, ancillary libraries, tutorials, StackOverflow answers, hell, even job opportunities — is unrivalled. While it's true that citing 'ecosystem' as the main reason to choose a tool is a sign that you're stuck on a local maximum, apt to be marooned by the rising waters of progress, it's still a major point in favour of incumbents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;roadmap&quot;&gt;Roadmap&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're not at version 1.0.0 yet, and a few things may change before we get there. Once we do (soon!), there are a lot of exciting possibilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe the next frontier of web performance is 'whole-app optimisation'. Currently, Svelte's compiler operates at the component level, but a compiler that understood the boundaries &lt;em&gt;between&lt;/em&gt; those components could generate even more efficient code. The React team's &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/trueadm/status/944908776896978946&quot;&gt;Prepack research&lt;/a&gt; is predicated on a similar idea, and the Glimmer team is doing some interesting work in this space. Svelte and Sapper are well positioned to take advantage of these ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of Glimmer, the idea of compiling components to bytecode is one that we'll probably steal in 2018. A framework like Sapper could conceivably determine which compilation mode to use based on the characteristics of your app. It could even serve JavaScript for the initial route for the fastest possible startup time, then lazily serve a bytecode interpreter for subsequent routes, resulting in the optimal combination of startup size and total app size.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mostly, though, we want the direction of Sapper to be determined by its users. If you're the kind of developer who enjoys life on the bleeding edge and would like to help shape the future of how we build web apps, please join us on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sveltejs/svelte&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitter.im/sveltejs/svelte&quot;&gt;Gitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 15:57:08 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>rich_harris</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://svelte.technology/blog/sapper-towards-the-ideal-web-app-framework</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ask HN: Who is hiring? (January 2018)</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16052538</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16052538</guid>
<description>&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.55737704918033&quot;&gt;&lt;td bgcolor=&quot;#FF6600&quot;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6.7889502762431&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table class=&quot;fatitem&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;5.0917127071823&quot;&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing&quot; id=&quot;16052538&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;right&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;title&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16052538&quot; class=&quot;storylink&quot;&gt;Ask HN: Who is hiring? (January 2018)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.70588235294118&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;subtext&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;score&quot; id=&quot;score_16052538&quot;&gt;399 points&lt;/span&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/user?id=whoishiring&quot; class=&quot;hnuser&quot;&gt;whoishiring&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;age&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16052538&quot;&gt;16 hours ago&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span id=&quot;unv_16052538&quot;/&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/hide?id=16052538&amp;amp;goto=item%3Fid%3D16052538&quot;&gt;hide&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://hn.algolia.com/?query=Ask%20HN%3A%20Who%20is%20hiring%3F%20(January%202018)&amp;amp;sort=byDate&amp;amp;dateRange=all&amp;amp;type=story&amp;amp;storyText=false&amp;amp;prefix&amp;amp;page=0&quot; class=&quot;hnpast&quot;&gt;past&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=Ask%20HN%3A%20Who%20is%20hiring%3F%20(January%202018)&quot;&gt;web&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/fave?id=16052538&amp;amp;auth=3b173202dcec6176ab4cacc7944b8fa517384d47&quot;&gt;favorite&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16052538&quot;&gt;547 comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;13.193341869398&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;14.135723431498&quot;&gt;Please lead with the location of the position and include the keywords REMOTE, INTERNS and/or VISA when the corresponding sort of candidate is welcome. When remote work is not an option, include ONSITE. If it isn't a household name, please explain what your company does.
&lt;p&gt;Submitters: please only post if you personally are part of the hiring company—no recruiting firms or job boards. One post per company please.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Readers: please only email submitters if you personally are interested in the job—no recruiters or sales calls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also use kristopolous' console script to search the thread: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=10313519&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=10313519&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note for this month: please don't go through these posts and downvote them in bulk. Users who do that eventually lose downvoting rights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td&gt;

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;1.0096153846154&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;yclinks&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/newsguidelines.html&quot;&gt;Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/newsfaq.html&quot;&gt;FAQ&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:hn@ycombinator.com&quot;&gt;Support&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/HackerNews/API&quot;&gt;API&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/security.html&quot;&gt;Security&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/lists&quot;&gt;Lists&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/bookmarklet.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Bookmarklet&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/dmca.html&quot;&gt;DMCA&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ycombinator.com/apply/&quot;&gt;Apply to YC&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:hn@ycombinator.com&quot;&gt;Contact&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 15:55:08 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>whoishiring</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16052538</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Linux page table isolation is not needed on AMD processors</title>
<link>https://lkml.org/lkml/2017/12/27/2</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://lkml.org/lkml/2017/12/27/2</guid>
<description>&lt;pre itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
AMD processors are not subject to the types of attacks that the kernel&lt;br /&gt;page table isolation feature protects against.  The AMD microarchitecture&lt;br /&gt;does not allow memory references, including speculative references, that&lt;br /&gt;access higher privileged data when running in a lesser privileged mode&lt;br /&gt;when that access would result in a page fault.&lt;p&gt;Disable page table isolation by default on AMD processors by not setting&lt;br /&gt;the X86_BUG_CPU_INSECURE feature, which controls whether X86_FEATURE_PTI&lt;br /&gt;is set.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Signed-off-by: Tom Lendacky &amp;lt;thomas.lendacky@amd.com&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;---&lt;br /&gt;arch/x86/kernel/cpu/common.c |    4 ++--&lt;br /&gt;1 file changed, 2 insertions(+), 2 deletions(-)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;diff --git a/arch/x86/kernel/cpu/common.c b/arch/x86/kernel/cpu/common.c&lt;br /&gt;index c47de4e..7d9e3b0 100644&lt;br /&gt;--- a/arch/x86/kernel/cpu/common.c&lt;br /&gt;+++ b/arch/x86/kernel/cpu/common.c&lt;br /&gt;@@ -923,8 +923,8 @@ static void __init early_identify_cpu(struct cpuinfo_x86 *c)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;setup_force_cpu_cap(X86_FEATURE_ALWAYS);&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;-  /* Assume for now that ALL x86 CPUs are insecure */&lt;br /&gt;-      setup_force_cpu_bug(X86_BUG_CPU_INSECURE);&lt;br /&gt;+       if (c-&amp;gt;x86_vendor != X86_VENDOR_AMD)&lt;br /&gt;+          setup_force_cpu_bug(X86_BUG_CPU_INSECURE);&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;fpu__init_system(c);&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 15:43:03 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>fanf2</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://lkml.org/lkml/2017/12/27/2</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Stimulus: A modest JavaScript framework for the HTML you already have</title>
<link>https://github.com/stimulusjs/stimulus/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/stimulusjs/stimulus/</guid>
<description>&lt;h3&gt;README.md&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;markdown-body entry-content&quot; itemprop=&quot;text&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;A modest JavaScript framework for the HTML you already have&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stimulus is a JavaScript framework with modest ambitions. It doesn't seek to take over your entire front-end—in fact, it's not concerned with rendering HTML at all. Instead, it's designed to augment your HTML with just enough behavior to make it shine. Stimulus pairs beautifully with &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/turbolinks/turbolinks&quot;&gt;Turbolinks&lt;/a&gt; to provide a complete solution for fast, compelling applications with a minimal amount of effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How does it work? Sprinkle your HTML with magic controller, target, and action attributes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-text-html-basic&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&amp;lt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-ent&quot;&gt;div&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-e&quot;&gt;data-controller&lt;/span&gt;=&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;hello&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-ent&quot;&gt;input&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-e&quot;&gt;data-target&lt;/span&gt;=&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;hello.name&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-e&quot;&gt;type&lt;/span&gt;=&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;text&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-ent&quot;&gt;button&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-e&quot;&gt;data-action&lt;/span&gt;=&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;click-&amp;gt;hello#greet&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;Greet&amp;lt;/&lt;span class=&quot;pl-ent&quot;&gt;button&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/&lt;span class=&quot;pl-ent&quot;&gt;div&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then write a compatible controller. Stimulus brings it to life automatically:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-js&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;//&lt;/span&gt; hello_controller.js&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; { &lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;Controller&lt;/span&gt; } &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;stimulus&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;export&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;default&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;extends&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-e&quot;&gt;Controller&lt;/span&gt; {
  &lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;greet&lt;/span&gt;() {
    &lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;console&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;log&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;`&lt;/span&gt;Hello, &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pse&quot;&gt;${&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;this&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pse&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;!&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;`&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;)
  }

  &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;get&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-en&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;() {
    &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;this&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;targets&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;find&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;name&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;).&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;value&lt;/span&gt;
  }
}
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stimulus continuously watches the page, kicking in as soon as magic attributes appear or disappear. It works with any update to the DOM, regardless of whether it comes from a full page load, a Turbolinks page change, or an Ajax request. Stimulus manages the whole lifecycle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can write your first controller in five minutes by following along in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/stimulusjs/stimulus/blob/master/handbook/README.md&quot;&gt;The Stimulus Handbook&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can read more about why we created this new framework in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/stimulusjs/stimulus/blob/master/ORIGIN.md&quot;&gt;The Origin of Stimulus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Installing Stimulus&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stimulus integrates with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://webpack.js.org/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;webpack&lt;/a&gt; asset packager to automatically load controller files from a folder in your app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can use Stimulus with other asset packaging systems, too. And if you prefer no build step at all, just drop a &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;script&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; tag on the page and get right down to business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/stimulusjs/stimulus/blob/master/INSTALLING.md&quot;&gt;Installation Guide&lt;/a&gt; for detailed instructions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Contributing Back&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stimulus is &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/stimulusjs/stimulus/blob/master/LICENSE.md&quot;&gt;MIT-licensed&lt;/a&gt; open source software from &lt;a href=&quot;https://basecamp.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Basecamp&lt;/a&gt;, the creators of &lt;a href=&quot;http://rubyonrails.org&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Ruby on Rails&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have a question about Stimulus? Find a bug? Think the documentation could use some improvement? Head over to our &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/stimulusjs/stimulus/issues&quot;&gt;issue tracker&lt;/a&gt; and we'll do our best to help. We love pull requests, too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We expect all Stimulus contributors to abide by the terms of our &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/stimulusjs/stimulus/blob/master/CONDUCT.md&quot;&gt;Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;© 2018 Basecamp, LLC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 14:50:50 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>tmlee</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars2.githubusercontent.com/u/32970053?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>stimulusjs/stimulus</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/stimulusjs/stimulus</og:url>
<og:description>stimulus - A modest JavaScript framework for the HTML you already have</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/stimulusjs/stimulus/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>